<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:54:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum(II) Phenylpyridyl Schiff Base Complexes as Latent, Photoactivated, Alkene Hydrosilylation Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01353</link>
      <description>Helena G. Lancaster, Joe C. Goodall, Stephen P. Douglas, Laura J. Ashfield, Simon B. Duckett, Robin N. Perutz, Andrew S. Weller, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396495696

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Helena G. Lancaster, Joe C. Goodall, Stephen P. Douglas, Laura J. Ashfield, Simon B. Duckett, Robin N. Perutz, Andrew S. Weller</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Consequences of Hierarchical Pore Architectures within MFI and FAU Zeolites for Polyethylene Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01213</link>
      <description>Jun Zhi Tan, M. Ortega, Stephen J. Miller, Cole W. Hullfish, H.G. Kim, Sung M. Kim, Wenda Hu, Jianzhi Hu, Johannes A. Lercher, Bruce E. Koel, Michele L. Sarazen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396499244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Zhi Tan, M. Ortega, Stephen J. Miller, Cole W. Hullfish, H.G. Kim, Sung M. Kim, Wenda Hu, Jianzhi Hu, Johannes A. Lercher, Bruce E. Koel, Michele L. Sarazen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inducing Microstrain in Electrodeposited Pt through Polymer Addition for Highly Active Oxygen Reduction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01244</link>
      <description>Qi Hua, Xinyi Chen, Junfeng Chen, Nawal M. Alghoraibi, Yoon Min Lee, Toby J. Woods, Richard T. Haasch, Steven C. Zimmerman, Andrew A. Gewirth, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396506273

                We investigate an approach to tune the d-band center and enhance the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity of Pt material without relying on foreign metals or the process of alloying/dealloying. It is known that Pt exhibits suboptimal ORR catalytic activity due to its strong binding to oxygen, therefore requiring a downshift in the d-band center by approximately 0.2 eV to weaken the Pt-O binding energy and boost ORR kinetics. We found that the d-band center can be tuned by inducing microstrain in the Pt electrodeposit, simply achieved by introducing polymer into the electrodeposition bath. Pt electrodes (Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA) prepared with the addition of poly-N-(6-aminohexyl)acrylamide (P1) or poly-l-arginine (PLA) exhibit improved ORR activity compared to Pt electrodeposited without polymer addition (Pt-alone) in both acidic and basic environments, with the order of activity being Pt-P1 &gt; Pt-PLA &gt; Pt-alone. Pt-P1 exhibits a positive shift of E1/2 by 90 mV vs Pt-alone in basic solution, comparable to other reported high-activity ORR catalysts. Scanning electron microscopy shows the presence of agglomerates with diameters between 5 and 20 &#956;m and tip-splitting growth structure due to diffusion-limited aggregation on Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA. Characterization using X-ray photoemission spectroscopy and X-ray diffraction, combined with Rietveld refinement analysis reveal a trend of downshifted d-band center, increased microstrain, and slightly increased compressive strain as the ORR activity increased among the three catalysts. The presence of more defective sites on Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA is the cause of the increased microstrain, which further leads to the downshift of the Pt d-band center and enhancement of ORR activity.</description>
      <author>Qi Hua, Xinyi Chen, Junfeng Chen, Nawal M. Alghoraibi, Yoon Min Lee, Toby J. Woods, Richard T. Haasch, Steven C. Zimmerman, Andrew A. Gewirth</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Catalytic Performance of Cytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; through Tailored Carboxymethylation in Covalent Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01456</link>
      <description>Li-Lan Shi, Xiupeng Chen, Aitao Li, Xiaoling Wu, Xian Kong, Hongming Li, Zhixian Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396541527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li-Lan Shi, Xiupeng Chen, Aitao Li, Xiaoling Wu, Xian Kong, Hongming Li, Zhixian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complete Computational Reaction Mechanism for Foldamer-Catalyzed Aldol Condensation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00937</link>
      <description>Reilly Osadchey Brown, Darren Demapan, Qiang Cui, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396541583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Reilly Osadchey Brown, Darren Demapan, Qiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coproduction of Glyceric Acid and Glycolic Acid from Biomass-Based Sugars over a Ru/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00782</link>
      <description>Yancheng Liu, Shiwei Zhou, Xiaoyan Wang, Jingyu Qin, Changwei Hu, Jianmei Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396545491

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yancheng Liu, Shiwei Zhou, Xiaoyan Wang, Jingyu Qin, Changwei Hu, Jianmei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00782</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;Anion-Switchable&#8221; Pincer-Mn(I) Catalyst for the Reductive &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Methylation of Amines with Formic Acid and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01812</link>
      <description>Sebasti&#225;n Mart&#237;nez-Vivas, Sergio Gonell, Macarena Poyatos, Eduardo Peris, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396547089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sebasti&#225;n Mart&#237;nez-Vivas, Sergio Gonell, Macarena Poyatos, Eduardo Peris</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End High-Throughput Approach for Data-Driven Internal Donor Development in Heterogeneous Ziegler&#8211;Natta Propylene Polymerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01601</link>
      <description>Toshiaki Taniike, Felicia Daniela Cannavacciuolo, Mostafa Khoshsefat, Diego De Canditiis, Giuseppe Antinucci, Patchanee Chammingkwan, Roberta Cipullo, Vincenzo Busico, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396547510

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Toshiaki Taniike, Felicia Daniela Cannavacciuolo, Mostafa Khoshsefat, Diego De Canditiis, Giuseppe Antinucci, Patchanee Chammingkwan, Roberta Cipullo, Vincenzo Busico</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourier-Transformed Alternating Current Voltammetry (FTacV) for Analysis of Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01526</link>
      <description>Rifael Z. Snitkoff-Sol, Alan M. Bond, Lior Elbaz, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396547671

                Electrocatalysts play a critical role in energy technologies, but the development of active, efficient, and durable catalysts is impeded by the lack of methodologies to deconvolute the complex interplay between various aspects influencing the activity of the catalysts, e.g., the number of active sites, turnover frequency, and the reaction pathways. Fourier-transformed alternating current voltammetry (FTacV) is an emerging tool for the analysis of electroactive species and has been successfully applied to a variety of reactions such as the oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, hydrogen evolution reaction, and hydrogen oxidation reaction. The harmonics generated from FTacV measurements neatly detect underlaying processes not visible by other, more commonly employed techniques for analysis of electrocatalysts, such as the rotating disc electrode and dc voltammetry. The harmonic components enable separating overlapping processes based on differences in kinetics or linearity of response. This paper presents a review of FTacV applied for the analysis of electrocatalysts. It highlights the importance of determining the electrochemically active site density (EASD) to decipher the intrinsic activity of a catalyst and discusses the use of FTacV in dynamic determination of the EASD over the course of a catalyst's working life, as well as the use of FTacV to understand intricate catalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Rifael Z. Snitkoff-Sol, Alan M. Bond, Lior Elbaz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoinduced Copper-Catalyzed Regio- and Enantioselective Alkynylation of Epoxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00818</link>
      <description>Jianye Li, Sijia Li, Guihua Cui, Yuan Kou, Chenwei Wang, Chen Yang, Guozhu Zhang, Rui Guo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396554632

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianye Li, Sijia Li, Guihua Cui, Yuan Kou, Chenwei Wang, Chen Yang, Guozhu Zhang, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the CO Oxidation Mechanism over Highly Dispersed Pt Single Atom on Anatase TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (101)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01018</link>
      <description>Celine Tesvara, Md Raian Yousuf, Malik Albrahim, Diego Troya, Abhijit Shrotri, Eli Stavitski, Ayman M. Karim, Philippe Sautet, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396561689

                Catalysts with noble metals deposited as single atoms on metal oxide supports have recently been studied extensively due to their maximized metal utilization and potential for performing difficult chemical conversions owing to their unique electronic properties. Understanding of the reaction mechanisms on supported single-metal atoms is still limited but is highly important for designing more efficient catalysts. In this study, we report the complexity of the CO oxidation reaction mechanism on Pt single atoms supported on anatase TiO2 (PtSA/a-TiO2) by coupling density functional theory (DFT) calculations and microkinetic analysis with kinetic measurements, in situ/operando infrared, and X-ray absorption spectroscopies. Starting from the adsorbed PtSA occupying an O vacancy induced by reductive pretreatment, we show that CO oxidation follows a complex mechanism consisting of initiation steps to reorganize the active site and multibranch reactive cycles, with the PtSA/a-TiO2 catalyst not returning to its initial configuration. The initiation step consists of CO and O2 adsorption healing the O vacancy, followed by CO oxidation using gas-phase CO to form Pt(CO). The reactive cycle alternates O2 adsorption and dissociation to oxidize the catalyst to Pt(O)(O)(CO) and branching pathways of competing Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood (LH)- or Eley&#8211;Rideal (ER)-type CO oxidation steps to reduce it again to Pt(CO). In situ/operando infrared experiments, including cryogenic CO adsorption and isotopic CO exchange, confirm the combined involvement of strongly adsorbed CO and gas-phase CO in an Eley&#8211;Rideal step along the reaction cycle. Microkinetic modeling shows that Pt single atoms are present in a mixture of Pt(CO), Pt(CO)(O2), Pt(O)(CO)(O2), and Pt(CO)(CO3) structures as the main intermediates during steady-state CO oxidation, all having the C&#8211;O vibrational stretch close to the experimentally observed value of 2115 cm&#8211;1. Microkinetic modeling also shows that the fractional orders of CO and O2 measured experimentally originate from multiple steps with a high degree of rate control and not from a simple competitive adsorption. The results demonstrate the complex reaction pathways that even CO oxidation on a simple single-atom system can follow, providing mechanistic insights for designing efficient Pt-based single-atom catalysts. We further show that microkinetic modeling results are sensitive to changes in energies of intermediate and transition states within errors of density functional theory, which can ultimately lead to incorrect conclusions regarding the reaction pathways and most abundant reaction intermediates if not accounted for by experiments.</description>
      <author>Celine Tesvara, Md Raian Yousuf, Malik Albrahim, Diego Troya, Abhijit Shrotri, Eli Stavitski, Ayman M. Karim, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Formic Acid Production in Ni and NiFe Layered Hydroxides via Glycerol Electro-Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01250</link>
      <description>D. K. Kim, Cu Dang Van, Min Seok Lee, Minho Kim, Min Hyung Lee, Jihun Oh, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396575542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>D. K. Kim, Cu Dang Van, Min Seok Lee, Minho Kim, Min Hyung Lee, Jihun Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Mechanism of Plasma-Catalyzed Oxidation of Methane to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Oxygenates over Cu/UiO-66-NH&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00261</link>
      <description>Chao Qi, Yifu Bi, Yaolin Wang, Hong Yu, Yuanyu Tian, Peijie Zong, Qinhua Zhang, Haonan Zhang, Mingqing Wang, Tao Xing, Mingbo Wu, Xin Tu, Wenting Wu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396576901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Qi, Yifu Bi, Yaolin Wang, Hong Yu, Yuanyu Tian, Peijie Zong, Qinhua Zhang, Haonan Zhang, Mingqing Wang, Tao Xing, Mingbo Wu, Xin Tu, Wenting Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amino Acid Self-Regenerating Cell-Free Protein Synthesis System that Feeds on PLA Plastics, CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, Ammonium, and &#945;-Ketoglutarate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00992</link>
      <description>Shota Nishikawa, Wen&#8208;Yueh Yu, Tony Z. Jia, Meiling He, Anna N. Khusnutdinova, Alexander F. Yakunin, Yin-Ru Chiang, Kosuke Fujishima, Po-Hsiang Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396577832

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shota Nishikawa, Wen&#8208;Yueh Yu, Tony Z. Jia, Meiling He, Anna N. Khusnutdinova, Alexander F. Yakunin, Yin-Ru Chiang, Kosuke Fujishima, Po-Hsiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00992</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Alcohol Adsorption Modes for Boosting Electrooxidation-Assisted Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01078</link>
      <description>Peipei Zhu, Yongli Shen, Zhi&#8208;Ming Zhang, Dingsheng Wang, Shenglin Xiong, Xuguang An, Shenglin Xiong, Changhua An, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396581872

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) suffers from sluggish kinetics and results in the increasing cost of hydrogen production. The exploration of an appropriate anode organic reaction occurring at low potential represents a feasible strategy to accelerate the implementation of water splitting in practice. Herein, we develop a ligand-confining thermolysis strategy to fabricate a Ru single-atom catalyst (Ru-SA/NSC) on N,S-codoped carbon. The adsorption mode effects of substrate alcohols on the electrocatalytic oxidation of Ru-SA/NSC are unraveled through modulation of substituent groups. The horizontal adsorption through the O atom on Ru-SA/NSC significantly facilitates the benzyl alcohol oxidation, delivering ultralow potential of 0.97 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 with high yield (&#8764;96%), selectivity (&#8764;99%), and Faraday efficiency (&#8764;100%) to produce aldehydes. The vertical adsorption through the N atom in pyridine methanol over Ru-SA/NSC has no response to the reaction. Furthermore, in the coupling device of alcohol oxidation and hydrogen evolution reaction, hydrogen production with a low potential of 1.21 V at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 is achieved, surpassing that of benchmark Pt/C||IrO2 (1.56 V) and the state-of-the-art reports. This study provides insights into the design of nanocatalysts toward the rational conversion of organic molecules to value-added chemicals and concurrently produces clean energy carriers.</description>
      <author>Peipei Zhu, Yongli Shen, Zhi&#8208;Ming Zhang, Dingsheng Wang, Shenglin Xiong, Xuguang An, Shenglin Xiong, Changhua An</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>En Route to Recyclable Semi-Heterogeneous Photocatalysis with Photoinert CeCl&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01130</link>
      <description>Tarun Kumar Dinda, Anupam Manna, Prasenjit Mal, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396585142

                Our study proposes an approach to semiheterogeneous photocatalysis, focusing on recyclability challenges. We developed a method employing visible light with photoinert anhydrous CeCl3, rendering it into a reusable semiheterogeneous photocatalyst. Despite being photoinert and insoluble in organic solvents, anhydrous CeCl3 formed a transient charge transfer complex in acetonitrile, denoted as CeCl3 - NXS (NBS or NCS), due to the strong oxophilicity of trivalent cerium toward oxygen. This complex facilitated visible-light absorption, leading to the photoexcitation of the Ce(III) complexes and conversion of Ce(III) centers into potent reductants, donating electrons to NXS. As a proof of concept, we demonstrated organic reactions where NXS, upon accepting electrons, generated halide radicals, allowing the synthesis of gem-dihaloketones under sunlight from terminal aromatic alkynes via C&#8211;X cross-coupling reactions. Significantly, CeCl3 exhibited recyclability without notable decomposition, demonstrated by its regeneration and isolation through simple filtration postreaction, underscoring its potential for prolonged use.</description>
      <author>Tarun Kumar Dinda, Anupam Manna, Prasenjit Mal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Oxygen Activity of Perovskites to Promote Activity and Selectivity for Methanol Oxidation to Formaldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01222</link>
      <description>Karthik Akkiraju, Reshma R. Rao, Jonathan Hwang, Livia Giordano, Xiao Renshaw Wang, Ethan J. Crumlin, David S. Weinberger, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396585598

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karthik Akkiraju, Reshma R. Rao, Jonathan Hwang, Livia Giordano, Xiao Renshaw Wang, Ethan J. Crumlin, David S. Weinberger, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Energy Pathway Exploration of Catalytic Formic Acid Decomposition on Pt-Group Metals in Aqueous Surroundings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00959</link>
      <description>Ziyue Hu, Ling-Heng Luo, Cheng Shang, Zhi-Pan Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396592409

                Formic acid is an important platform molecule for hydrogen utilization, where Pt-group metals are the only catalyst candidates to achieve ambient condition formic acid (FA) decomposition (HCOOH &#8594; CO2 + H2). However, these catalysts suffer from severe long-term activity loss, the mechanism of which has been highly debated in the past two decades. By combining global structure search with umbrella sampling molecular dynamics based on global neural network potentials, here we quantitatively resolve the whole free energy profile for FA decomposition at the Pt&#8211;water and Pd&#8211;water interfaces. We show that while the two metals share the same FA decomposition mechanism, their catalytic deactivation rate do differ by more than 2 orders of magnitude&#9472;Pt is much more susceptible to CO poisoning due to the kinetics. The physical origin is attributed to the stronger affinity to surface atomic H and the lower adsorption to surface adsorbed bent CO2 (CO2 anion) on Pd, which leads to the slower rate of the secondary CO2 decomposition to the CO molecule, the poisoning species at ambient conditions. After comparing CO generation at the solid&#8211;gas and the solid&#8211;liquid interface, we propose simple strategies to achieve high activity without CO byproduct formation for FA decomposition.</description>
      <author>Ziyue Hu, Ling-Heng Luo, Cheng Shang, Zhi-Pan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Interfacial Reconstruction and Surface Polarization in a Compact ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;CdIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction for Enhanced Photocatalytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00924</link>
      <description>Yunxia Liu, Yueming Wu, Yuhui Liu, Yi Wang, Xin Sun, Peng Chen, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396596653

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunxia Liu, Yueming Wu, Yuhui Liu, Yi Wang, Xin Sun, Peng Chen, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-Selective C&#8211;H Arylation of 2-Pyridones via Pd/NBE Cooperative Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00690</link>
      <description>Zengguo Sun, Zhuhan Jiang, Feng He, Chenyue Li, Hai Xiong, Dan Yang, Hui Miao, Qinglin Li, Jinxiang Ye, Ching-Yong Wu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396604944

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zengguo Sun, Zhuhan Jiang, Feng He, Chenyue Li, Hai Xiong, Dan Yang, Hui Miao, Qinglin Li, Jinxiang Ye, Ching-Yong Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Low-Temperature Syngas Production via Surface Tailoring of Supported Intermetallic Nanocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01180</link>
      <description>Olusola Johnson, Yurong He, Isabella St. Pierre-Charles, J. Richter, Babu Joseph, John N. Kuhn, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396617198

                An active and coke-resistant silica-encapsulated intermetallic Ni3Zn nanoparticle catalyst was developed for low-temperature (450 &#176;C) dry reforming of methane (DRM). The catalyst exhibited a remarkable 4-fold increase in activity (4.5 s&#8211;1) with over 99% CO selectivity and 3 orders of magnitude less carbonaceous species and demonstrated remarkable stability (70 h) compared to that of a monometallic Ni catalyst. The key is the combined effect of surface ensemble structure and electronic interaction modulation through the surface composition tailoring achieved by off-stoichiometric Ni and Zn loading in controlling surface chemistry for achieving different activities and H2/CO ratios. Characterized by ion spectroscopy, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, and the neutron pair distribution function, it was revealed that paired Ni&#948;&#8722;&#8211;Zn&#948;+ active sites are crucial for DRM. Transient infrared spectroscopy and isotopic analysis uncovered the synergistic effect of Ni&#948;&#8722;&#8211;Zn&#948;+ sites in activating C&#8211;H bonds and dissociating CO2 to prevent coke formation under low-temperature conditions.</description>
      <author>Olusola Johnson, Yurong He, Isabella St. Pierre-Charles, J. Richter, Babu Joseph, John N. Kuhn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Covalent Organic Frameworks with Redox-Active Catechol Moieties for High-Performance Overall Photosynthesis of Hydrogen Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01411</link>
      <description>Shufan Feng, Hao Cheng, Feng Chen, Xinman Liu, Zhiqiang Wang, Hangxun Xu, Jianli Hua, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396617229

                Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) have emerged as promising candidates for solar-driven photosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2), yet the development of high-performance COFs tailored for practical applications presents substantial challenges. This research introduces the integration of the redox-active catechol moiety into a series of COFs (TPE-COF-OH, TPB-COF-OH, and TPP-COF-OH), serving as the pivotal active site for photocatalytic oxygen (O2) reduction to H2O2 through a reversible catechol-quinone interconversion mechanism. This process facilitates the transformation of catechol to o-benzoquinone in the presence of molecular O2, while photoexcited electrons are utilized to revert o-benzoquinone to catechol, reducing the energy barrier for H2O2 synthesis. Notably, TPB-COF-OH demonstrates an unparalleled H2O2 production rate of 6608 &#956;mol h&#8211;1 g&#8211;1, outperforming its molecular counterpart, TPB-COF-OMe, which lacks the redox-active catechol unit. Furthermore, TPB-COF-OH achieves a solar-to-chemical conversion efficiency of 0.84%, marking the highest value among COF-based photocatalysts in solar-driven H2O2 production. This investigation not only underscores the critical role of molecular engineering in enhancing COF performance but also broadens the horizon for solar-to-chemical energy conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Shufan Feng, Hao Cheng, Feng Chen, Xinman Liu, Zhiqiang Wang, Hangxun Xu, Jianli Hua</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i009_1797488</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396623784

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i009_1797488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i009_1797487</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396623887

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i009_1797487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buffer-Induced Electrocatalytic Nitrite Reduction: Impact on Catalytic Rate and Product Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05583</link>
      <description>Sheyda Partovi, Evan Z. Dalton, Jeremy M. Smith, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396626175

                The complex [Co(CR)Br2]+, where CR is the redox-active macrocycle 2,12-dimethyl-3,7,11,17-tetraazabicyclo-[11.3.1]-heptadeca-1(17),2,11,13,15-pentaene, is known as an electrocatalyst for the reduction of aqueous nitrite (NO2&#8211;). Here, we report that buffer induces a catalytic wave for NO2&#8211; reduction at a significantly more anodic potential than under unbuffered conditions. In addition, buffer increases the rate of electrocatalysis. This enhanced electrocatalytic activity is enabled by a number of buffering agents, with 3-(N-morpholino)propanesulfonic acid showing the largest catalytic current. In addition to the greater catalytic activity, buffering agents influence the selectivity of the reduction products, as well as catalyst longevity.</description>
      <author>Sheyda Partovi, Evan Z. Dalton, Jeremy M. Smith</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methane Activation through Single-Electron Transfer from Water Molecules to the Surface States of Semiconductor Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00984</link>
      <description>Fumiaki Amano, Kosuke Beppu, Yoshihisa Sakata, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396636838

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fumiaki Amano, Kosuke Beppu, Yoshihisa Sakata</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Catalytic and Oxygen Release Capability in LaFe&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; to Intensify Chemical Looping Reactions at Medium Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01386</link>
      <description>Rongjiang Zhang, Gen Liu, Chunyong Huo, Lijun Jia, Bo Zhang, Bolun Yang, Xiaoyong Tian, Zhiqiang Wu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396645619

                Perovskite oxygen carriers in a methane chemical looping partial oxidation process enable high reactivity over 850 &#176;C. Lowering the reaction temperature helps to circumvent energy dissipation and couple the above-mentioned process with energy-efficient systems. This paper demonstrates the attractive oxygen-donating capacity of Fe&#8211;Ni-based perovskite oxygen carriers for methane partial oxidation. The aforesaid process exhibits more than 70% methane conversion and 6.71 mmol&#183;g&#8211;1 unit syngas yield at 700 &#176;C, using LaFe0.5Ni0.5O3. This impressive high reactivity mainly originates from the lowered lattice oxygen bonding strength and the spontaneously constructed active Ni-rich surface of perovskite oxides by Ni doping. In addition to the outward migration of lattice oxygen, active metal elements, such as Ni, continuously segregate to the surface with the reduction of perovskite oxides, promoting methane partial oxidation. We speculate that the chemical looping reaction pathway consists of consecutive competitive reactions based on analysis of the real-time product distribution and the dynamic evolution of oxygen carriers. Highly selective syngas production can be achieved on LaFe0.5Ni0.5O3 by reducing reaction temperatures or increasing space velocity to balance methane dissociation and lattice oxygen release kinetics. Irreversible Ni segregation and phase-separation-induced inert La2O3 on the surface of perovskite oxides during redox cycles are responsible for the cyclic performance degradation of oxygen carriers. This work offers intriguing references to design perovskite oxygen carriers for intensifying the medium-temperature chemical looping partial oxidation process.</description>
      <author>Rongjiang Zhang, Gen Liu, Chunyong Huo, Lijun Jia, Bo Zhang, Bolun Yang, Xiaoyong Tian, Zhiqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01386</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Interfacial Charge Transfer Enables Nearly 100% Selectivity for Solar-Light-Driven CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01020</link>
      <description>Wangzhong Tang, Jie Meng, Tao Ding, Haisen Huang, Chuntian Tan, Qiuzi Zhong, Heng Cao, Qunxiang Li, Xiuli Xu, Jinlong Yang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396495893

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wangzhong Tang, Jie Meng, Tao Ding, Haisen Huang, Chuntian Tan, Qiuzi Zhong, Heng Cao, Qunxiang Li, Xiuli Xu, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA-Anchored Single-Molecule Iron Phthalocyanine As an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00795</link>
      <description>Yi Qin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, XIA LIU, Xian Liang, Linfeng Xie, Kuan Wang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yang Liu, Yawei Chen, Zhijun Lei, Pengfei Yan, Liang Wu, Shuhong Jiao, Qing Li, Ruiguo Cao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396512258

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Qin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, XIA LIU, Xian Liang, Linfeng Xie, Kuan Wang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yang Liu, Yawei Chen, Zhijun Lei, Pengfei Yan, Liang Wu, Shuhong Jiao, Qing Li, Ruiguo Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Electric Fields Drives the Proton-Coupled Electron Transfer within Cytochrome P450 Reductase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02215</link>
      <description>Ningning Li, Shengheng Yan, Peng Wu, Junfeng Li, Binju Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396665466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ningning Li, Shengheng Yan, Peng Wu, Junfeng Li, Binju Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intermolecular Allene&#8211;Alkyne Coupling: A Significantly Useful Synthetic Transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01333</link>
      <description>Tapas R. Pradhan, Jin Kyoon Park, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396668677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tapas R. Pradhan, Jin Kyoon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01333</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
