<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:44:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Reaction Triggered by Magnetic Induction Heating Mechanistically Distinguishes Itself from the Standard Thermal Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05989</link>
      <description>Alexander Adogwa, Ewa Chukwu, Alexander Malaj, Venkata Rohit Punyapu, Owen Chamness, Nicolas Glisson, Bridget Bruce, Sungwon Lee, Michael J. Zachman, David A. Bruce, Rachel B. Getman, O. Thompson Mefford, Ming Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392229964

                As a recent advancement in reaction engineering, magnetic induction heating (MIH) is utilized to initiate the intended reactions by enabling the self-heating of the ferromagnetic catalyst particles. While MIH can be energy-efficient and industrially scalable, its full potential has been underappreciated in catalysis because of the perception that MIH is merely an alternative heating approach. Unexpectedly, we show that the MIH-triggered reaction could go beyond standard thermal catalysis. Specifically, by probing the representative Pt/Fe3O4 catalysts with CO oxidation in both thermal and MIH modes with consistent temperature profiles and catalyst structures, we found that the MIH mode boosts the reactivity more than 25 times by modifying Pt&#8211;FeOx interfacial synergies and promoting facile oxidation of the adsorbed carbonyl species by atomic oxygen. As we preliminarily observed, this beneficial MIH catalysis can be translational to other thermal reactions, potentially paving the way to launch MIH catalysis as a distinct reaction category.</description>
      <author>Alexander Adogwa, Ewa Chukwu, Alexander Malaj, Venkata Rohit Punyapu, Owen Chamness, Nicolas Glisson, Bridget Bruce, Sungwon Lee, Michael J. Zachman, David A. Bruce, Rachel B. Getman, O. Thompson Mefford, Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantio- and Regioselective Dihydroboration of Enals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06135</link>
      <description>Kezhuo Zhang, Chenchen Li, Wanxiang Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392232802

                Asymmetric hydroboration is among the most powerful and straightforward methods to construct chiral organoboron compounds, which are extensively used in natural products, bioactive molecules, and materials science. Among them, enantioselective hydroboration of a single functional group has been well-established and experienced significant advances, but the asymmetric hydroboration of multiple functional groups is rarely developed due to the extremely challenging chemo-, regio-, and enantioselectivity control. Herein, we present a Co-catalyzed enantio- and regioselective dihydroboration of enals and achieved the chemo-, regio-, and enantioselective hydroboration of both the C&#9552;O bond and the C&#9552;C bond. This protocol features mild reaction conditions, wide substrate scope, and good functional group tolerance and provides a highly efficient method for the preparation of highly valuable chiral 1,4-borylethers and their downstream products such as 1,4-diols and amino alcohols. Preliminary mechanistic studies suggested that this Co-catalyzed dihydroboration involved a tandem 1,2-hydroboration/dissociative isomerization/asymmetric hydroboration process.</description>
      <author>Kezhuo Zhang, Chenchen Li, Wanxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversed Charge Transfer to Modulate the d-Band Center of Pd for Efficient Direct H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05910</link>
      <description>Ruilin Liu, C Y Wang, Yonggao Yan, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang, Ge Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392234322

                The direct hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) product from H2 and O2 is a promising anthraquinone replacement because it is environmentally friendly and has a high atom efficiency. Experimental and theoretical studies have proven that optimizing the adsorption of the critical intermediate OOH* on the metal site significantly promotes the further protonation of this intermediate and inhibits the O&#8211;O bond cleavage, thus enhancing the activity and selectivity. Redistributing the charge density of active sites to tuning the d-band center of the metal could effectively modulate the intermediates adsorption, and thus regulate the catalytic efficiency. Herein, we show that a Lewis acid (ZnCl2 solution) induces abundant oxygen vacancies (Ovs) on the TiO2 surface, which results in a reversal of charge transfer from TiO2&#8211;Ov support to the Pd atom, generating an electron-rich Pd configuration. Compared with pristine Pd/TiO2, Pd/TiO2&#8211;Ov possesses higher H2O2 selectivity and productivity, with values of 80.7% and 186 mol kgcat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1, respectively. In addition, Pd/TiO2&#8211;Ov maintains stability during the six cycles reaction due to its high resistance to the leaching of Pd species. Theoretical calculations reveal that the reversed charge transfer downshifts the d-band center of Pd, which promotes O2 adsorption on the Pd surface and weakens the OOH* intermediates adsorption. Thus, the energy barrier for the hydrogenation of the OOH* intermediate is significantly decreased, and the O&#8211;O band cleavage is inhibited. This study reports a reversal of charge transfer tuning the d-band center of the active site for efficient direct H2O2 synthesis, which may provide insight for designing high-performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ruilin Liu, C Y Wang, Yonggao Yan, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang, Ge Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Activation of Small Molecules and Free Radicals for the Deep Mineralization of Mixed VOCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06279</link>
      <description>Bangfu Chen, Youyu Duan, Shuang Chen, Yuhan Li, Yongfa Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392234361

                Deep mineralization of C7H8 is often impeded by an ambiguous understanding of the key contributors to active species and the mechanism of benzene ring activation. Herein, the implementation of ZnSn(OH)6 as a photocatalyst for the degradation of a mixture of C7H8 and C3H6O aims to investigate the synergistic activation effects between small molecules and reactive free radicals. Upon irradiation, the catalyst exhibits a remarkable average decomposition efficiency of 98.42% toward the mixture (C7H8:C3H6O = 50:20 ppm), with a 97.8% degradation rate for C7H8 and a 100% degradation rate for C3H6O. The molecular O2 is the main active species for the photocatalytic oxidation of C7H8 and C3H6O. Especially, activated C7H8 and C3H6O undergo direct dehydrogenative cross-coupling in a radical state to produce the key intermediate C10H12O. Compared with the primary intermediate benzyl alcohol (&#916;G = +1.52 eV), C10H12O (&#916;G = &#8722;0.47 eV) displays a lower ring-opening energy barrier under &#8226;O2&#8211; attack, thereby facilitating the selectivity of the photocatalytic oxidation ring-opening reaction of C7H8 and the photodegradation of the mixture. The present research delves into the collaborative interplay between small molecules and reactive free radicals during the mineralization process of C7H8, thereby shedding light on innovative strategies for the efficient treatment of mixed polluted gases under real-world conditions.</description>
      <author>Bangfu Chen, Youyu Duan, Shuang Chen, Yuhan Li, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A General Base-free Route toward the Building of Metal N-Heterocyclic Carbenes into Covalent Organic Frameworks for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00037</link>
      <description>Chang He, Duan&#8208;Hui Si, Lili Han, Zhusheng Xu, Ziao Chen, Rong Cao, Yuan&#8208;Biao Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392238066

                Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) would be a promising platform to immobilize metal N-heterocyclic carbenes (M-NHCs) for efficient CO2 conversion, but they are seldom reported. Herein, we develop a facile base-free strategy to prepare M-NHCs (M = Ir, Au, Pd) decorated M-NHC&#8211;COFs (Ir-NHC&#8211;COF, Au-NHC&#8211;COF, and Pd-NHC&#8211;COF) via the reactions of the imidazolium carboxylate functionalized NHC-based COF (NHC&#8211;CO2&#8211;COF) with the corresponding metal complexes under mild conditions. This facile synthesis method for the generation of the desired M-NHC single sites avoids the handling of the free carbenes and the use of strong bases. The obtained Ir-NHC&#8211;COF catalyst showed efficient catalytic activity and recyclability in the CO2 hydrogenation process, attaining a noteworthy turnover frequency of up to 17244 h&#8211;1, which placed it among the top-performing heterogeneous catalysts for this reaction. This study presents a universal and straightforward approach for attaching functional M-NHC single sites onto COFs, offering combined advantages and acting as highly efficient catalysts for CO2 hydrogenation reactions. This general strategy would be widely applicable to prepare other M-NHC-functionalized porous materials with covalently bound M-NHC single sites for various applications in the future.</description>
      <author>Chang He, Duan&#8208;Hui Si, Lili Han, Zhusheng Xu, Ziao Chen, Rong Cao, Yuan&#8208;Biao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Structure on the Activity, Selectivity, and Stability of Pt-Sn-DeAlBEA for Propane Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06047</link>
      <description>Natalie Lefton, Alexis T. Bell, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392239469

                Recent research has found that dealuminated zeolite BEA (DeAlBEA) is an attractive support for the dispersion of Pt and PtSn species that serve as catalysts for propane dehydrogenation (PDH). In this study, we report the preparation, structural characterization, and PDH activities of Pt-Sn-DeAlBEA catalysts as a function of the Pt/Al ratio (here Al represents the amount of Al present in the parent zeolite H-BEA). The support Sn-DeAlBEA was prepared by introduction of Sn to DeAlBEA. Characterization of this material by X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and UV&#8211;vis spectroscopy revealed that the Sn incorporated into the BEA framework as Sn(IV) cations. Pt-Sn-DeAlBEA catalysts were prepared with Pt/Al ratios (0.001&#8211;0.026) and were characterized with infrared (IR) spectroscopy of adsorbed probe molecules and XAS to understand the effect of changing Pt loading on the structure of Pt in Pt-Sn-DeAlBEA. Pt dispersion on DeAlBEA (i.e., Pt-DeAlBEA) produced Pt nanoparticles with an average Pt&#8211;Pt coordination number of 9 (&#8764;25 &#197;) for Pt/Al ratios of 0.001 and above. By contrast, dispersion of Pt on Sn-DeAlBEA (Sn/Al = 0.15) produced Pt oligomers with an average Pt&#8211;Pt coordination number of 3 for Pt/Al = 0.001, but for Pt/Al ratios &gt;0.013, Pt nanoparticles formed with a Pt&#8211;Pt coordination number of 9. Pt-Sn-DeAlBEA exhibited high selectivity to propene (&gt;97%) and high dehydrogenation rates. Forward rate constants were calculated and compared with values determined for various Pt and PtSn catalysts reported in the literature. The Pt-Sn-DeAlBEA catalysts prepared in this study exhibited significantly higher forward rate constants than those previously reported for Pt and PtSn catalysts. The kinetics of PDH were measured for Pt-Sn-DeAlBEA catalysts with different Pt/Al ratios but identical Sn/Al ratios. In all cases, the kinetics are described by a Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood rate expression, which is first order in propane and is inhibited by propane adsorption. The similarity of the apparent activation energies and enthalpies of propane adsorption for all three catalysts suggests that the active species are very small Pt3Sn clusters strongly bound to the framework of DeAlBEA.</description>
      <author>Natalie Lefton, Alexis T. Bell</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-Catalyzed Cyclization/Hydrosilylation Reaction of 1,6-Diynes Enabled by an Oxidative Cyclization&#8211;Hydrosilylation Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00473</link>
      <description>Jiaxing Dong, Xuebing Leng, Dongyang Wang, Liang Deng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392241564

                Transition-metal-catalyzed cyclization/hydrosilylation of 1,6-diynes is a useful method for the preparation of five-membered ring-fused silyl dienes that are useful reagents in organic synthesis. Only a handful of noble metal catalysts facilitating this transformation are known, and nonprecious metal catalysts effecting the reaction have remained elusive. Herein, we report that low-coordinate Co(0)-N-heterocyclic carbene complexes can catalyze the cyclization/hydrosilylation of 1,6-diynes with tertiary and secondary hydrosilanes, furnishing five-membered ring-fused (Z)-1-silyldienes in good yields and excellent stereoselectivity. Mechanistic study disclosed that the catalytic cycle likely has oxidative cyclization of 1,6-diynes with Co(0) species as the key step. This mechanism accounts for the high stereoselectivity and absence of uncyclized hydrosilylation byproducts in the cobalt-catalyzed cyclization/hydrosilylation reaction, which is different from the hydrosilylation-cyclization mechanism of the noble metal-catalyzed reactions.</description>
      <author>Jiaxing Dong, Xuebing Leng, Dongyang Wang, Liang Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Catalytic Ozonation Mediated by Dual Active Sites of Oxygen Vacancies and Defects in Biomass-Derived Composites for Long-Lasting Water Decontamination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05554</link>
      <description>Yizhen Cheng, Zhonglin Chen, Penghua Yan, Jiayi Shen, Jing Kang, Shaobin Wang, Xiaoguang Duan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392283250

                Environmental decontamination relies on low-cost, sustainable materials to drive diverse catalytic redox reactions. In this work, we used low-cost biomass to develop nanocomposites of N-doped carbon-supported zinc oxide (ZNC400) at a low temperature (400 &#176;C), which exhibited ultrahigh activity in heterogeneous catalytic ozonation (HCO) for organic water decontamination. Our experimental and computational studies revealed the collaborative functions of dual active centers of defective carbons and oxygen vacancies (OVs)-containing zinc oxide (ZnO) at the composite interface for successive ozone (O3) adsorption and catalytic decomposition, respectively. Inspiringly, OVs on ZnO will spontaneously dissociate water molecules (H2O) to form surface hydroxyl groups (&#8211;OH) as key intermediates to accelerate O3 decomposition. This synergistic interplay results in the continuous generation of hydroxyl radicals (&#8226;OH) and maintains over 90.2% atrazine (ATZ) removal over five successive cycles, endowing ZNC400 with substantial reusability. Furthermore, four ATZ degradation pathways were proposed, and the corresponding toxicity was evaluated by the embryonic development of zebrafish in the treated water. Overall, the engineered dual-function catalyst effectively addresses the long-standing issue of poor stability of carbon materials in HCO and offers high-performance, cheap, and green catalysts for advanced water purification.</description>
      <author>Yizhen Cheng, Zhonglin Chen, Penghua Yan, Jiayi Shen, Jing Kang, Shaobin Wang, Xiaoguang Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper/BINOL-Catalyzed Enantioselective C&#8211;H Functionalization toward Planar Chiral Ferrocenes Under Mild Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05955</link>
      <description>Zhuo&#8208;Zhuo Zhang, Gang Zhou, Qiang Yue, Qi&#8208;Jun Yao, Bing&#8208;Feng Shi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392286348

                Copper-catalyzed enantioselective C&#8211;H activation proceeding through an inner-sphere mechanism remains a huge challenge. Herein, a copper-catalyzed enantioselective C&#8211;H alkynylation with terminal alkynes assisted by 8-aminoquinoline using readily available (S)-BINOL as the chiral ligand was disclosed. The reaction proceeded under mild conditions with a catalytic amount of copper salt, providing a range of chiral ferrocenes in good yields and enantioselectivities (0 &#176;C, up to 77% yield and 94% ee). The alteration of the stoichiometric chemical oxidant with renewable electricity is also feasible at ambient temperature, demonstrating the robustness of this copper/BINOL catalysis. Notably, this is the first enantioselective cupraelectrocatalyzed C&#8211;H activation reaction. Gram-scale synthesis, versatile transformations, and application of the resulting oxazoline&#8211;olefin ligand in asymmetric synthesis also highlight the utility of the protocols.</description>
      <author>Zhuo&#8208;Zhuo Zhang, Gang Zhou, Qiang Yue, Qi&#8208;Jun Yao, Bing&#8208;Feng Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05955</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Synthesis of &lt;i&gt;Gem&lt;/i&gt;-&#946;,&#946;&#8242;-Bis(alkyl) Alcohols Using Nickel Catalysis via Sequential DCR Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00647</link>
      <description>Lalit Mohan Kabadwal, Atanu Bera, Debasis Banerjee, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392297357

                Chemoselective synthesis of functionalized gem-&#946;,&#946;&#8242;-bis(alkyl)alcohols by coupling of a &#946;-alkylated secondary alcohol with a primary alcohol is reported using nickel via sequential DCR (dehydrogenation&#8211;condensation&#8211;rehydrogenation) approach. Using our method, 1-arylethanol and benzyl alcohols undergo a one-pot successive double alkylation reaction to form functionalized alcohols. Methanol, C2&#8211;C12 alcohols, citronellol, and fatty acid-derived oleic alcohols are tolerated, including late-stage functionalization of steroid hormones (cholesterol and testosterone) and 5-pregnen-3&#946;-ol-20-one. The catalytic transformations enabled the synthesis of donepezil drug (used for Alzheimer&#8217;s disease), N-heteroarenes (quinoline and acridine), including chromane and intermediate flavan derivatives. Hammett kinetic plot analysis of differently p-substituted benzyl alcohols with 1-phenyl propanol indicated that the oxidation of benzyl alcohol might be the rate-determining step and expected a strong influence of substitution on the reaction kinetics. A negative &#961; value (&#8722;0.60) strongly signify the formation of the positive charge on benzyl alcohol. Preliminary mechanistic investigation revealed that the dehydrogenation of alcohol to aldehyde is the rate-determining step as it involves the C&#8211;H/D bond breaking of the alcohol, and a PH/PD value of 6.0 was calculated. Reaction profile studies, EPR experiments, Hammett-plot studies, cyclic voltammetry, and UV&#8211;visible experiments, including XPS analysis, indicated the structural and electronic changes at the Ni-center as well as the behavior of the catalysts and alcohols during the progress of the reactions.</description>
      <author>Lalit Mohan Kabadwal, Atanu Bera, Debasis Banerjee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00647</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold(I) Complex with a Photoactive Ligand Behaves as a Two-in-One Dual Metallaphotoredox Cross-Coupling Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05962</link>
      <description>C&#233;sar Ruiz&#8208;Zambrana, Macarena Poyatos, Eduardo Peris, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392299478

                We herein describe the use of a gold complex with a naphthalene-di-imide-functionalized N-heterocyclic carbene (NDI-NHC) ligand, which was used as a photocatalyst for a variety of reactions. Due to the presence of the naphthalene moiety in the ligand, the complex can be used for the photogeneration of singlet oxygen, behaving as a photocatalyst in the endoperoxidation and peroxidation of cyclic and acyclic alkenes, and also in the selective oxidation of a simulant of sulfur mustard to its related nontoxic sulfoxide. The same complex was used as catalyst for two model oxidative C&#8211;C coupling reactions, namely, the coupling of aryldiazonium salts with alkynylsilanes and with mesitylene. These two catalytic reactions are a good indication that the (NDI-NHC)-Au(I) complex can behave as an effective dual metallophotoredox catalyst but with the particular feature that both the photosensitizer and the metal catalyst are contained in the same compound, thus constituting a very rare type of a &#8220;two-in-one&#8221; metallophotoredox catalyst. The participation of the Au(I)/Au(III) couple in the catalytic process was demonstrated by the isolation of a Au(III) complex, which was obtained via a self-photoactivated photoredox reaction.</description>
      <author>C&#233;sar Ruiz&#8208;Zambrana, Macarena Poyatos, Eduardo Peris</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DalPhos on Demand: Facile Ligand Generation Enables New Ligand Discovery and Expedient Catalyst Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00249</link>
      <description>Joshua W. M. MacMillan, Ryan T. McGuire, A. Michal McMahon, Timothy S. Anderson, Katherine N. Robertson, Mark Stradiotto, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392354784

                DalPhos/Ni-based catalysts have emerged as top performers in C&#8211;N and C&#8211;O cross-couplings. Expedient means of generating such ligands would facilitate the discovery of effective DalPhos ligand variants as well as accelerate reaction development processes for end users. A protocol for generating structurally varied phosphine- and phosphonite-type DalPhos ligands from a single ligand precursor upon treatment with commercial reagents and without the need for chromatographic purification is disclosed. The formation of DalPhos ligands via this divergent synthetic strategy was exploited in the expedited screening of representative Ni-catalyzed C&#8211;N and C&#8211;O cross-couplings, leading to the identification of the DalPhos ligand variants (i.e., BnPAd-DalPhos, L4, and OAdPAd-DalPhos, L9) that, in turn, were carried forward for reaction scope analysis in challenging cross-couplings of fluoroalkylamines, by use of prepared (DalPhos)Ni(aryl)Cl precatalyst complexes. The reported methodology offers a user-friendly means of generating DalPhos variants in reaction development.</description>
      <author>Joshua W. M. MacMillan, Ryan T. McGuire, A. Michal McMahon, Timothy S. Anderson, Katherine N. Robertson, Mark Stradiotto</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00249</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i005_1776148</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392354997

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i005_1776148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogenation of Esters Catalyzed by Bis(&lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Heterocyclic Carbene) Molybdenum Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00019</link>
      <description>Niklas F. Both, Jannik Thaens, Anke Spannenberg, Haijun Jiao, Kathrin Junge, Matthias Beller, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392356777

                A series of Mo complexes bearing inexpensive bidentate bis(NHC) ligands have been synthesized and characterized by NMR and IR spectroscopy as well as single crystal XRD analysis. These complexes proved to be efficient for the catalytic hydrogenation of aliphatic and aromatic esters (&gt;35 examples) operating at low catalyst loadings (0.5&#8211;2 mol %) and temperatures (80&#8211;120 &#176;C). Various functional groups, e.g., C&#9552;C double bonds, nitriles, alcohols, tertiary amines, halides, and acetals, as well as heteroaromatic substrates, lactones, and diesters, are tolerated by the optimal catalyst system. Based on NMR spectroscopic investigations, control experiments and DFT computations a non-bifunctional outer-sphere hydrogenation mechanism is proposed.</description>
      <author>Niklas F. Both, Jannik Thaens, Anke Spannenberg, Haijun Jiao, Kathrin Junge, Matthias Beller</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aminations of Aryl Halides Using Nitroaromatics as Coupling Partners: Overcoming the Hydrodehalogenation Pathway under a Hydrogen Atmosphere in Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06351</link>
      <description>Tharique N. Ansari, Ramesh Hiralal Choudhary, Maarten Nachtegaal, Adam H. Clark, Scott Plummer, Jacek B. Jasi&#324;ski, Fabrice Gallou, Sachin Handa, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392358532

                While overcoming hydrodehalogenation in a reductive environment, a catalytic aqueous micellar technology has been developed for the C&#8211;N cross-coupling of nitroarenes with aryl halides. The bimetallic palladium&#8211;copper (Pd&#8211;Cu) nanocatalyst configuration in aqueous micelles selectively facilitates the highly selective amination pathway, possibly through in situ formation of Cu-hydride species as supported by the nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy. These species prevent Pd-hydride-mediated hydrodehalogenation even under a molecular hydrogen atmosphere. The nanocatalyst has been thoroughly characterized by using various spectroscopic and imaging tools, including 31P and 1H NMR, X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS), and high-resolution transmission electron microscopy. The oxidation states of Cu and Pd needed for the desired selectivity have been verified using X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, while metal&#8211;metal and metal&#8211;ligand interactions have been characterized by XAS. Control experiments have been performed to determine the significance of each constituent of the nanocatalyst on the desired reaction pathway. As revealed by control mass spectrometry, the reaction pathway does not involve azo- or nitroso-type intermediates. The catalytic methodology can be applied to numerous substrates with a broad functional and protecting group tolerance.</description>
      <author>Tharique N. Ansari, Ramesh Hiralal Choudhary, Maarten Nachtegaal, Adam H. Clark, Scott Plummer, Jacek B. Jasi&#324;ski, Fabrice Gallou, Sachin Handa</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06351</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-Exchange-Enabled Axially Chiral Recognition in Asymmetric Aminopalladation/Olefination of 2-Alkynylanilides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06032</link>
      <description>Gang Wang, N. Zhang, Bing&#8208;Xia Yan, Zhe-Wen Zhang, Shiwei Li, Gen Luo, Zhishi Ye, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392361459

                Chiral recognition for the synthesis of axially chiral biaryl units is a fundamental and challenging topic in organic synthesis. Herein, we documented that an efficient O-ligand exchange between the catalyst and substrate enabled axial chiral recognition in asymmetric aminopalladation/olefination of 2-alkynylanilides and vinyl trifluoromethanesulfonates, providing the axially chiral 3-alkenylindoles with up to 97% ee and 98% yield. This protocol features mild conditions, broad functional group tolerance, scalability, and late-stage modification of bioactive molecules. Experimental and computational studies hinted that O-ligand exchange between the (R)-BIDIME/Pd complex and the alkoxy group of 2-alkynylanilides was crucial to the success of stereoselectivity control.</description>
      <author>Gang Wang, N. Zhang, Bing&#8208;Xia Yan, Zhe-Wen Zhang, Shiwei Li, Gen Luo, Zhishi Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplification of Corticosteroids Biosynthetic Pathway by Engineering P450BM3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06137</link>
      <description>Qihang Chen, Zi&#8208;Sheng Chao, Ke Wang, Xinglong Wang, Hao Meng, Xirong Liu, Xiaoyu Shan, Jingwen Zhou, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392376597

                Synthesis of corticosteroids, particularly hydrocortisone, is challenging owing to the complex network requiring pairing of cytochrome P450s with cytochrome P450 reductase (CPR) for achieving regionally selective hydroxylation modifications at multiple sites. Herein, we engineered a self-sufficient P450BM3 (CYP102A1 from Bacillus megaterium) for effectively reducing the traditionally complex, multienzyme cascade process (three steps and six enzymes) of hydrocortisone synthesis from progesterone (PG) to a simplified two-step process involving at least two enzymes. Driven by computational simulation-guided substrate access channel and heme center pocket engineering, a series of P450BM3 variants were gradually designed with the ability to catalyze C16&#946;, C17&#945;, C21, and C17&#945;/21 oxidation of PG and C11&#945; oxidation of cortexolone (c). Subsequently, molecular dynamics simulations with an oxy-ferrous model of P450BM3 variants revealed that the glycine mutations of residues that are repulsive to the substrate allow for more stable exposure of the substrate above Fe&#9552;O. Finally, the developed P450 variants were employed to construct efficient Escherichia coli catalytic systems, which further achieved 11&#945;/&#946;-hydrocortisone (f/e) production in one pot from 1 g/L PG at a molar conversion rate of 81 and 84% (912 and 955 mg/L), respectively. Thus, this study provides feasible strategies for simplifying the biosynthetic steps and biocatalysts for steroidal pharmaceutical production.</description>
      <author>Qihang Chen, Zi&#8208;Sheng Chao, Ke Wang, Xinglong Wang, Hao Meng, Xirong Liu, Xiaoyu Shan, Jingwen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aqueous Phase Reforming over Platinum Catalysts on Doped Carbon Supports: Exploring Platinum&#8211;Heteroatom Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05385</link>
      <description>Monica Pazos Urrea, Simon Meilinger, Felix Herold, Jithin Gopakumar, Enrico Tusini, Andrea De Giacinto, Anna Zimina, Jan&#8208;Dierk Grunwaldt, De Chen, Magnus R&#248;nning, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392377956

                A series of platinum catalysts supported on carbon nanofibers with various heteroatom dopings were synthesized to investigate the effect of the local platinum environment on the catalytic activity and selectivity in aqueous phase reforming (APR) of ethylene glycol (EG). Typical carbon dopants such as oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus, and boron were chosen based on their ability to bring acidic or basic functional groups to the carbon surface. In situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) was used to identify the platinum oxidation state and platinum species formed during APR of EG through multivariate curve resolution alternating least-squares analysis, observing differences in activity, selectivity, and platinum local environment among the catalysts. The platinum-based catalyst on the nitrogen-doped carbon support demonstrated the most favorable properties for H2 production due to high Pt dispersion and basicity (H2 site time yield 22.7 h&#8211;1). Direct Pt&#8211;N&#8211;O coordination was identified by XAS in this catalyst. The sulfur-doped catalyst presented Pt&#8211;S contributions with the lowest EG conversion rate and minimal production of the gas phase components. Boron and phosphorus-doped catalysts showed moderate activity, which was affected by low platinum dispersion on the carbon support. The phosphorus-doped catalyst showed preferential selectivity to alcohols in the liquid phase, associated with the presence of acid sites and Pt&#8211;P contributions observed under APR conditions.</description>
      <author>Monica Pazos Urrea, Simon Meilinger, Felix Herold, Jithin Gopakumar, Enrico Tusini, Andrea De Giacinto, Anna Zimina, Jan&#8208;Dierk Grunwaldt, De Chen, Magnus R&#248;nning</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biological Reaction Engineering for the Preparation of C9 Chemicals from Oleic Acid: 9-Aminononanoic Acid, 1,9-Nonanediol, 9-Amino-1-nonanol, and 1,9-Diaminononane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00302</link>
      <description>Se&#8208;Yeun Hwang, Ji-Min Woo, Go Eun Choi, Deok&#8208;Kun Oh, Jung-Won Seo, Jin Byung Park, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392378338

                Engineering of native and recombinant enzyme reactions in whole-cell biocatalysis may allow the production of a variety of chemicals. In particular, fine-tuning of the reaction selectivity may enable the preparation of a desired product to a high conversion. Here, we demonstrated that various C9 chemicals such as 9-aminononanoic acid, 1,9-nonanediol, 9-amino-1-nonanol, and 1,9-diaminononane could be produced from renewable C18 oleic acid. As a representative example, activation of six recombinant enzyme reactions (e.g., fatty acid double bond hydratase, long-chain secondary alcohol dehydrogenase, Baeyer&#8211;Villiger monooxygenase, lipase, primary alcohol dehydrogenase, and &#969;-aminotransferases) with repression of one native enzyme reaction (i.e., aldehyde dehydrogenase) in Escherichia coli-based biocatalysis led to the formation of 9-aminononanoic acid with an isolation yield of 54% from oleic acid via 10-hydroxyoctadecanoic acid, 10-keto-octadecanoic acid, 9-(nonanoyloxy)nonanoic acid, 9-hydroxynonanoic acid, and 9-oxo-nonanoic acid. This study will contribute to biosynthesis of not only &#969;-aminoalkanoic acids but also &#969;-amino-1-alkanols and &#945;,&#969;-diaminoalkanes from renewable fatty acids (e.g., oleic acid and ricinoleic acid).</description>
      <author>Se&#8208;Yeun Hwang, Ji-Min Woo, Go Eun Choi, Deok&#8208;Kun Oh, Jung-Won Seo, Jin Byung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visible-Light-Mediated Macrocyclization for the Formation of Azetine-Based Dimers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04518</link>
      <description>Cody Ng, Scott L. Kim, Ilia Kevlishvili, Gianmarco G. Terrones, Emily Wearing, Heather J. Kulik, Corinna S. Schindler, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392381297

                Macrocyclic dimeric lactones have pharmacological activities that make them attractive synthetic targets, but typical synthetic strategies employ an iterative approach to construct the macrocycle. Herein, we report a visible-light-mediated approach that enables facile access to 1- and 2-azetine-based dimeric lactones of up to 30-membered ring macrocycles. These products form via four consecutive triplet energy transfers for 1-azetine dimeric products and two consecutive triplet energy transfers for 2-azetine dimeric products. Computational investigations provide insights into the mechanism of this reaction, consistent with an unexpected initial intermolecular [2 + 2]-cycloaddition being preferred under nonstandard Curtin&#8211;Hammett conditions over the corresponding intramolecular reaction, which ultimately enables an efficient reaction pathway for macrocyclic dimerization.</description>
      <author>Cody Ng, Scott L. Kim, Ilia Kevlishvili, Gianmarco G. Terrones, Emily Wearing, Heather J. Kulik, Corinna S. Schindler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04518</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving the Active Role of Isolated Transition Metal Species in Ni-Based Catalysts for Dry Reforming of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05737</link>
      <description>Chuan Zhou, Yafeng Zhang, Bai Li, Bing Yang, Lei Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392382117

                Ni-based catalysts have demonstrated high catalytic activity and stability toward the dry reforming of methane (DRM). However, the nature of the active sites and the origin of high catalytic activity remain unclear. Herein, we developed a three-step microkinetic model and constructed a volcano-type contour plot to study the catalytic activity of transition metal (TM) catalysts. Our findings revealed that the active sites in Ni&#8211;M (M = Mo, W, and Ru) catalysts predominantly consist of isolated M species, such as monomers (M1), dimers (M2), and trimers (M3), rather than uniformly distributed Ni&#8211;M species. Experimental observations validated our theoretical findings, demonstrating that the diluted Ni90Mo10 alloy containing isolated Mo1&#8211;3 species exhibits an activity significantly higher than those of NiMo alloys and Ni catalysts. We further confirmed that the superior catalytic activity originates from the highly localized electronic density, which enables continuous fine-tuning of the adsorption energies of C and O. These results demonstrate the critical role of precise surface composition manipulation in bimetallic catalysts. Furthermore, our three-step reaction model largely reduces the parameter dimension of DRM by requiring only the computation of 6 elementary steps rather than the original 38 elementary steps. These findings hold significant potential to facilitate the theoretical study of catalytic mechanisms and the rational design of DRM catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chuan Zhou, Yafeng Zhang, Bai Li, Bing Yang, Lei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Electron Transfer from CuInS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Quantum Dots to a Molecular Catalyst for Hydrogen Production: Challenging Diffusion Limitations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06216</link>
      <description>Andrew J. Bagnall, Nora Eliasson, Oskar Hansson, Murielle Chavarot&#8208;Kerlidou, Vincent Artero, Haining Tian, Leif Hammarstr&#246;m, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392382934

                Systems integrating quantum dots with molecular catalysts are attracting ever more attention, primarily owing to their tunability and notable photocatalytic activity in the context of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). CuInS2 (CIS) quantum dots (QDs) are effective photoreductants, having relatively high-energy conduction bands, but their electronic structure and defect states often lead to poor performance, prompting many researchers to employ them with a core&#8211;shell structure. Molecular cobalt HER catalysts, on the other hand, often suffer from poor stability. Here, we have combined CIS QDs, surface-passivated with l-cysteine and iodide from a water-based synthesis, with two tetraazamacrocyclic cobalt complexes to realize systems which demonstrate high turnover numbers for the HER (up to &gt;8000 per catalyst), using ascorbate as the sacrificial electron donor at pH = 4.5. Photoluminescence intensity and lifetime quenching data indicated a large degree of binding of the catalysts to the QDs, even with only ca. 1 &#956;M each of QDs and catalysts, linked to an entirely static quenching mechanism. The data was fitted with a Poissonian distribution of catalyst molecules over the QDs, from which the concentration of QDs could be evaluated. No important difference in either quenching or photocatalysis was observed between catalysts with and without the carboxylate as a potential anchoring group. Femtosecond transient absorption spectroscopy confirmed ultrafast interfacial electron transfer from the QDs and the formation of the singly reduced catalyst (CoII state) for both complexes, with an average electron transfer rate constant of  &#8776; (10 ps)&#8722;1. These favorable results confirm that the core tetraazamacrocyclic cobalt complex is remarkably stable under photocatalytic conditions and that CIS QDs without inorganic shell structures for passivation can act as effective photosensitizers, while their smaller size makes them suitable for application in the sensitization of, inter alia, mesoporous electrodes.</description>
      <author>Andrew J. Bagnall, Nora Eliasson, Oskar Hansson, Murielle Chavarot&#8208;Kerlidou, Vincent Artero, Haining Tian, Leif Hammarstr&#246;m</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i005_1776149</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392385097

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i005_1776149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective C&#8211;H Activation of Molecular Nanodiamonds via Photoredox Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00296</link>
      <description>Hoang T. Dang, Henry T. O&#8217;Callaghan, Mikayla M. Wymore, Jennifer Suarez, David B. C. Martin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392385839

                While substituted adamantanes have widespread use in medicinal chemistry, materials science, and ligand design, the use of diamantanes and higher diamondoids is limited to a much smaller number. Selective functionalization beyond adamantane is challenging, as the number of very similar types of C&#8211;H bonds (secondary, 2&#176;, and tertiary, 3&#176;) increases rapidly, and H atom transfer does not provide a general solution for site selectivity. We report a method using pyrylium photocatalysts that is effective for nanodiamond functionalization in up to 84% yield with exclusive 3&#176; selectivity and moderate levels of regioselectivity between 3&#176; sites. The proposed mechanism involving photooxidation, deprotonation, and radical C&#8211;C bond formation is corroborated through Stern&#8211;Volmer luminescence quenching, cyclic voltammetry, and EPR studies. Our photoredox strategy offers a versatile approach for the streamlined synthesis of diamondoid building blocks.</description>
      <author>Hoang T. Dang, Henry T. O&#8217;Callaghan, Mikayla M. Wymore, Jennifer Suarez, David B. C. Martin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterization and Engineering of a Fungal Poly(ethylene terephthalate) Hydrolyzing Enzyme from &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus fumigatiaffinis&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00299</link>
      <description>Seul Hoo Lee, Mijeong Kim, Hogyun Seo, Hwaseok Hong, Jiyoung Park, Dongwoo Ki, Kyung-Jin Kim, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392401502

                As our environmental pollution awareness increases, effective poly(ethylene terephthalate) (PET) waste management has become an important global goal, and biorecycling is considered as one of the strategies for PET recycling. Although several bacterial cutinases have been investigated with respect to PET hydrolysis, fungal cutinases and their potential still need to be explored. Here, we screened 15 fungal cutinases and discovered a cutinase from Aspergillus fumigatiaffinis (AfC), a potent PET hydrolase satisfying PET hydrolytic activity and thermal stability. Structural analysis of AfC revealed that the enzyme has an additional disulfide bond compared to known fungal cutinases. We also developed the AfCT37V/A84K/N117E/N124E/A171P/N182E variant (AfC6p), which showed enhanced thermal stability and a 4-fold increase in PET hydrolytic activity at 60 &#176;C compared with AfCWild-type. AfC6p completely decomposed the postconsumer PET film within 12 days at 60 &#176;C.</description>
      <author>Seul Hoo Lee, Mijeong Kim, Hogyun Seo, Hwaseok Hong, Jiyoung Park, Dongwoo Ki, Kyung-Jin Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00299</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
