<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:47:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Oxygen Evolution Reaction Kinetics with Titanium Incorporated Nickel Ferrite for Efficient Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05761</link>
      <description>Ki-Yong Yoon, Kyung&#8208;Bok Lee, Jaehoon Jeong, Myung&#8208;Jun Kwak, Dohyung Kim, Hyunchul Roh, Ji-Hoon Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Hosik Lee, Juchan Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392622761

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ki-Yong Yoon, Kyung&#8208;Bok Lee, Jaehoon Jeong, Myung&#8208;Jun Kwak, Dohyung Kim, Hyunchul Roh, Ji-Hoon Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Hosik Lee, Juchan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Thiophene&#8211;Sulfur Functional Groups in Carbon Catalysts for Highly Selective H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00419</link>
      <description>Rong-Hui Xie, Chuanqi Cheng, Ruguang Wang, Jisi Li, Erling Zhao, Zhao Yang, Yunlong Liu, Jiaxin Guo, Pengfei Yin, Tao Ling, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392645655

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rong-Hui Xie, Chuanqi Cheng, Ruguang Wang, Jisi Li, Erling Zhao, Zhao Yang, Yunlong Liu, Jiaxin Guo, Pengfei Yin, Tao Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt/Fe-TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Catalyzed Selective Carbonyl Hydrogenation: Fe-Promoted Hydrogen Spillover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05478</link>
      <description>Zhenchao Zhao, Xiang Li, Xin Liu, Hongxia Gao, Aiping Jia, Songhai Xie, Xiaojing Song, Xiaoyan Liu, Yang Fa, Qihua Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392649076

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenchao Zhao, Xiang Li, Xin Liu, Hongxia Gao, Aiping Jia, Songhai Xie, Xiaojing Song, Xiaoyan Liu, Yang Fa, Qihua Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Siteselective and Enantiocomplementary C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Oxyfunctionalization for Synthesis of &#945;-Hydroxy Acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00398</link>
      <description>Xin Lian, Yingle Mao, Zunyun Fu, Weijie Zhang, Jia-Yan Chen, Dan Zhuo, Mingyue Zheng, Jiunn&#8208;Tzong Wu, Cangsong Liao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392658327

                Oxyfunctionalization of abundant carboxylic acids represents a direct approach to synthesizing &#945;-hydroxy acids, which are valuable intermediates of various active pharmaceutical ingredients. Although ideal, the transformation is yet to be accomplished. Herein, enantiocomplementary C(sp3)&#8211;H oxyfunctionalization for the synthesis of &#945;-hydroxy acids was realized by a cooperative strategy of substrate engineering, homologue screening and protein engineering of &#945;-ketoglutarate-dependent nonheme iron aryloxyalkanoate dioxygenases. The reaction provided concise synthetic routes toward three types of 67 &#945;-hydroxy acids with high efficiency and selectivity (yield up to 90% and ee up to &gt;99%). The distinctive complementary reactions add to a growing repertoire of biocatalytic oxyfunctionalization reactions.</description>
      <author>Xin Lian, Yingle Mao, Zunyun Fu, Weijie Zhang, Jia-Yan Chen, Dan Zhuo, Mingyue Zheng, Jiunn&#8208;Tzong Wu, Cangsong Liao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expedient Synthesis of Axially and Centrally Chiral Diaryl Ethers via Cobalt-Catalyzed Photoreductive Desymmetrization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00001</link>
      <description>Yishou Wang, Ruijie Mi, Songjie Yu, Xingwei Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392682464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yishou Wang, Ruijie Mi, Songjie Yu, Xingwei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Doping Strategies to Improve Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Performance of Molybdenum Disulfide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05053</link>
      <description>Yuehan Jia, Yuchen Zhang, Huibin Xu, Jia Li, Ming Gao, Xiaotian Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392693992

                The exhaustion of fossil fuels and resultant pollution issues have prompted the world to look to clean, nonpolluting hydrogen energy. The promising approach of the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) presents a solution for addressing energy and environmental challenges. Consequently, creating high-performance and cost-effective electrocatalysts is essential for the efficient decomposition of water. Molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) has emerged as the most promising among potential electrocatalysts to replace platinum. However, only the edge-site of MoS2 is active for HER due to the MoS2 semiconductive nature and large inactive basal planes. Doping various substances, which significantly improves HER activity, can enhance MoS2's physical and chemical properties. Our Review encapsulates the latest strategies and research advancements in choosing heteroatomic-doped MoS2 for hydrogen production. Various doping elements impart unique physical and chemical properties to MoS2. Specifically, doping with noble metals (e.g., Ag, Pt, Ru, Pd, Rh) and transition metals (e.g., Fe, V, Ni, Mn, Co, Zn, W), as well as codoping with multiple metal atoms (e.g., Cu-Pd, Pt-Te, Co-Nb, Ni-Co), can significantly enhance conductivity and introduce new active sites. These dopants are recognized for activating the basal plane of MoS2, thereby enhancing the HER activity. Furthermore, doping with nonmetallic elements (e.g., N, F, P, An, O) and their codoping combinations (e.g., O-P, N-F, Se-O), as well as the codoping of nonmetal and metal atoms (e.g., Co-Se, Co-P, N-Pt, Ru-O), is crucial for inducing phase conversions and improving stability. Each dopant contributes distinctively, either by enhancing the stability of MoS2, serving as a catalytic site, or broadening the pH range for effective HER. In this discussion, we further explore the current challenges and outlook of this promising area. Furthermore, we discuss existing challenges and promising guidelines for future research on the MoS2-based catalyst, offering advice to translation from laboratory research to large-scale industrial hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Yuehan Jia, Yuchen Zhang, Huibin Xu, Jia Li, Ming Gao, Xiaotian Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-Driven Highly Effective Biomass-Derived Alcohols C&#8211;C Coupling Integrated with H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production by CdS Quantum Dots Modified Zn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05826</link>
      <description>Zongyi Huang, Pengfei Sun, Huizhen Zhang, Haikun Zhang, Shuhong Zhang, Zhou Chen, Xiaodong Yi, Shunji Xie, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392697716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongyi Huang, Pengfei Sun, Huizhen Zhang, Haikun Zhang, Shuhong Zhang, Zhou Chen, Xiaodong Yi, Shunji Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confined Trinuclear Ru Sites in Phosphine-Incorporated Porous Organic Polymers for the Direct Synthesis of Alcohols from Reductive Hydroformylation of Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06221</link>
      <description>Yuchuan Zhu, Zhaozhan Wang, Yuanjun Zhao, Xin Zhou, Yan Zhang, Yong Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392697742

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuchuan Zhu, Zhaozhan Wang, Yuanjun Zhao, Xin Zhou, Yan Zhang, Yong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics of Redox Half-Cycles on Bi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for the Selective Catalytic Combustion of Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05585</link>
      <description>Mark Jacob, Huy Ho&#224;ng Nguy&#7877;n, Matthew Neurock, Aditya Bhan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392697744

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mark Jacob, Huy Ho&#224;ng Nguy&#7877;n, Matthew Neurock, Aditya Bhan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Resolution of Activity-Related Solvation Dynamics in the TIM Barrel Enzyme Murine Adenosine Deaminase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02687</link>
      <description>Shuaihua Gao, Xin Wu, Wenju Zhang, Thomas Richardson, Samuel L. Barrow, Christian A. Thompson-Kucera, Anthony T. Iavarone, Judith P. Klinman, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392701608

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuaihua Gao, Xin Wu, Wenju Zhang, Thomas Richardson, Samuel L. Barrow, Christian A. Thompson-Kucera, Anthony T. Iavarone, Judith P. Klinman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02687</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genome Mining for New Enzyme Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06322</link>
      <description>Dinh Thanh Nguyen, Douglas A. Mitchell, Wilfred A. van der Donk, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392701824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dinh Thanh Nguyen, Douglas A. Mitchell, Wilfred A. van der Donk</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Oxygen Vacancy Site Mechanism of a Self-Assembly Hybrid Catalyst for Efficient Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05789</link>
      <description>Xinshui Lei, Jiang Chang, Qingjun Han, Xiao&#8208;Xin Zhang, Kai Zhao, Ning Yan, Haoxu Guo, Bing Tang, Yifan Li, Yi Cui, Shuhui Yu, Jianhui Li, Yanping Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392704093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinshui Lei, Jiang Chang, Qingjun Han, Xiao&#8208;Xin Zhang, Kai Zhao, Ning Yan, Haoxu Guo, Bing Tang, Yifan Li, Yi Cui, Shuhui Yu, Jianhui Li, Yanping Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active and Sulfur-Tolerant Ruthenium Phosphide Catalyst for Efficient Reductive Amination of Carbonyl Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06179</link>
      <description>Hiroya Ishikawa, Sho Yamaguchi, Tomoo Mizugaki, Takato Mitsudome, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392710185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hiroya Ishikawa, Sho Yamaguchi, Tomoo Mizugaki, Takato Mitsudome</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Hydrogenation of Furfural with Improved Activity and Selectivity at the Surface of Structured Copper Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05691</link>
      <description>Cl&#233;ment Spadetto, Cyril Hachemi, Maxime Nouaille-Degorce, Lo&#239;c Pendu, Lou Bossert, Robert H. Temperton, Andrey Shavorskiy, L. Cardenas, Mathieu S. Pr&#233;vot, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392710286

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cl&#233;ment Spadetto, Cyril Hachemi, Maxime Nouaille-Degorce, Lo&#239;c Pendu, Lou Bossert, Robert H. Temperton, Andrey Shavorskiy, L. Cardenas, Mathieu S. Pr&#233;vot</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silylarylation of Alkenes &lt;i&gt;via meta&lt;/i&gt;-Selective C&#8211;H Activation of Arenes under Ruthenium/Iron Cooperative Catalysis: Mechanistic Insights from Combined Experimental and Computational Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00034</link>
      <description>Sukanya Neogi, Sourav Bhunya, Asim Kumar Ghosh, Biswajit Sarkar, Lisa Roy, Alakananda Hajra, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392710750

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sukanya Neogi, Sourav Bhunya, Asim Kumar Ghosh, Biswajit Sarkar, Lisa Roy, Alakananda Hajra</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photosynthetic Activity of Covalent Organic Frameworks through Linkage Orientation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00278</link>
      <description>Jie-Yu Yue, Li-Ping Song, Zi-Xian Pan, Peng Yang, Yu Ma, Qing Xu, Bo Tang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392740340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie-Yu Yue, Li-Ping Song, Zi-Xian Pan, Peng Yang, Yu Ma, Qing Xu, Bo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functionally Diverse Peroxygenases by AlphaFold2, Design, and Signal Peptide Shuffling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00883</link>
      <description>Judith M&#252;nch, N.L. Dietz, S. Barber-Zucker, F. Seifert, Susanne Matschi, Pascal P&#252;llmann, Sarel J. Fleishman, Martin J. Weissenborn, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392744707

                Unspecific peroxygenases (UPOs) are fungal enzymes that attract significant attention for their ability to perform versatile oxyfunctionalization reactions using H2O2. Unlike other oxygenases, UPOs do not require additional reductive equivalents or electron transfer chains that complicate basic and applied research. Nevertheless, UPOs generally exhibit low to no heterologous production levels and only four UPO structures have been determined to date by crystallography limiting their usefulness and obstructing research. To overcome this bottleneck, we implemented a workflow that applies PROSS stability design to AlphaFold2 model structures of 10 unique and diverse UPOs followed by a signal peptide shuffling to enable heterologous production. Nine UPOs were functionally produced in Pichia pastoris, including the recalcitrant CciUPO and three UPOs derived from oomycetes&#9472;the first nonfungal UPOs to be experimentally characterized. We conclude that the high accuracy and reliability of new modeling and design workflows dramatically expand the pool of enzymes for basic and applied research.</description>
      <author>Judith M&#252;nch, N.L. Dietz, S. Barber-Zucker, F. Seifert, Susanne Matschi, Pascal P&#252;llmann, Sarel J. Fleishman, Martin J. Weissenborn</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition State Analysis of Key Steps in Dual Photoredox-Cobalt-Catalyzed Elimination of Alkyl Bromides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06324</link>
      <description>Victor O. Nyagilo, Sharath Chandra Mallojjala, Jennifer S. Hirschi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392746939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Victor O. Nyagilo, Sharath Chandra Mallojjala, Jennifer S. Hirschi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights on the Mechanism of Surface-Catalyzed Oxidative Nitrogen Fixation Based on Liquid-Phase Bubble Pin-Plate Discharge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05317</link>
      <description>Qingchuan Wang, Limin Liu, Guoxin Gao, Yuzhi Chen, Yuxin Ouyang, Dongyang Zhang, Yaqiong Su, Shujiang Ding, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392748786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingchuan Wang, Limin Liu, Guoxin Gao, Yuzhi Chen, Yuxin Ouyang, Dongyang Zhang, Yaqiong Su, Shujiang Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Sustainable Lattice Strains of Morphology-Tuned Nanowires in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00451</link>
      <description>Zhi Hui Kong, Zhi Peng Wu, Yazan Maswadeh, Gang Yu, Jorge Vargas, Dominic Caracciolo, Valeri Petkov, Shuang&#8208;Quan Zang, Tao Li, Shuangyin Wang, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392748981

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhi Hui Kong, Zhi Peng Wu, Yazan Maswadeh, Gang Yu, Jorge Vargas, Dominic Caracciolo, Valeri Petkov, Shuang&#8208;Quan Zang, Tao Li, Shuangyin Wang, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxylamine Umpolung in Copper-Catalyzed Cross-Coupling Reactions to Synthesize &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Arylhydroxylamine Derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06020</link>
      <description>Gary Mathieu, Emna Azek, Calvine Lai, H. Lebel, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392749973

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gary Mathieu, Emna Azek, Calvine Lai, H. Lebel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;De Novo&lt;/i&gt; Multienzyme Synthetic Pathways for Lactic Acid Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05489</link>
      <description>Xu-Wei Ding, Jian Rong, Zheng-fan Pan, Xin-Xin Zhu, Zhenqi Zhu, Qi Chen, Zhi Jun Zhang, Jian&#8208;He Xu, Chun-Xiu Li, Gao&#8208;Wei Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392750096

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xu-Wei Ding, Jian Rong, Zheng-fan Pan, Xin-Xin Zhu, Zhenqi Zhu, Qi Chen, Zhi Jun Zhang, Jian&#8208;He Xu, Chun-Xiu Li, Gao&#8208;Wei Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Catalytic Role of Native Glucagon Amyloid Fibrils</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00452</link>
      <description>Ashim Nandi, Aoxuan Zhang, Elad Arad, Raz Jelinek, Arieh Warshel, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392751169

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ashim Nandi, Aoxuan Zhang, Elad Arad, Raz Jelinek, Arieh Warshel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of Lattice Strain in CdS Promotes Photocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00016</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Liang, Xinkui Wang, Xinxin Zhang, Sisi Lin, Min Ji, Qinggang Liu, Min Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392760834

                The key to photocatalysis lies in the efficient separation and migration of photogenerated carriers to the surface for participation in the reaction. However, the recombination of electrons and holes is a major hindrance that reduces the photocatalysis activity. Herein, we developed a method to introduce lattice strain by regulating the crystallinity of the material, thus resulting in an intensive polarization internal electric field, which can promote the separation process of electrons and holes and improve the efficiency of photocatalysis. The degree of strain can be controlled by the solvothermal temperature. Compared with CdS-160 &#176;C, CdS-100 &#176;C with a larger lattice strain degree and internal electric field contributed to a 7-fold enhanced photocatalytic CO evolution from CO2; in addition, the CO/H2 ratio was also increased by 4 times. This study reports the important effects of lattice strain and internal electric field on photogenerated carrier separation and migration, providing valuable insights for designing efficient photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Liang, Xinkui Wang, Xinxin Zhang, Sisi Lin, Min Ji, Qinggang Liu, Min Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous Iridium-Catalyzed Carbene N&#8211;H Bond Insertion with &#945;-Alkyl Diazo Esters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05635</link>
      <description>Ping Guo, Yan Chen, Tao Lei, Shufang Ji, Ruixue Zhang, Zedong Zhang, Xiao Liang, Dingsheng Wang, Yadong Li, Jie Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392761569

                A heterogeneous iridium single-atom site catalyst (Ir-SA) was synthesized and investigated in catalyzing the carbene insertion reaction with challenging &#945;-alkyl diazo ester substrates. With only 0.23 mol % catalyst loading, our Ir-SA demonstrated remarkable performance in heterogeneous carbene N&#8211;H bond insertion reactions involving various (hetero) aryl amines coupled with &#945;-alkyl diazo esters. Notably, in the case of using a chiral diamino substrate with two reactive sites, Ir-SA exhibited high selectivity toward single carbene N&#8211;H insertion, leading to the generation of a class of unsymmetric chiral diamino ligands. Further mechanism study revealed that the lower activation barrier associated with the single N&#8211;H bond insertion step, as compared to either &#946;-hydride elimination or downstream dual N&#8211;H bond insertion, accounted for the remarkable selectivity observed in this carbene insertion reaction catalyzed by Ir-SA.</description>
      <author>Ping Guo, Yan Chen, Tao Lei, Shufang Ji, Ruixue Zhang, Zedong Zhang, Xiao Liang, Dingsheng Wang, Yadong Li, Jie Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05635</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
