<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 01:15:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Electronic Structure of IrO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Sub-2 nm Clusters via Tunable Metal Support Interaction for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06411</link>
      <description>Qingzhao Chu, Yanpu Niu, Haolan Tao, Honglai Liu, Quan Li, Cheng Lian, Jingkun Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406511916

                Iridium-based electrocatalysts are the most promising candidates for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Considering their high cost and scarcity, it is imperative to maximize atom utilization and enhance the intrinsic activity of iridium. In this work, IrOx sub-2 nm clusters are stabilized on TiO2 supports via metal support interaction (MSI) induced by vacancy defects in TiO2. The strength of MSI is readily tuned by the type of vacancies: oxygen vacancies in TiO2 (VO-TiO2) induce the adsorbed MSI with relatively weak strength, while titanium vacancies in TiO2 (VTi-TiO2) lead to the strong embedded MSI. The tunable MSI further modulates the electronic structure of IrOx sub-2 nm clusters. IrOx/VO-TiO2 with adsorbed MSI exhibits an optimized electronic structure with a downshifted d-band center of IrOx, resulting in a reduced binding energy with oxygen and a low energy barrier of the rate-determining step for OER. Consequently, IrOx/VO-TiO2 delivers an activity twice that of commercial IrO2 and a good stability for 120 h in a practical proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Our study provides a guideline for the rational design of acidic OER catalysts based on modulating the electronic structure of IrOx sub-2 nm clusters via tunable MSI.</description>
      <author>Qingzhao Chu, Yanpu Niu, Haolan Tao, Honglai Liu, Quan Li, Cheng Lian, Jingkun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visible-Light-Induced Energy-Transfer-Mediated Hydrofunctionalization and Difunctionalization of Unsaturated Compounds via Sigma-Bond Homolysis of Energy-Transfer Acceptors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07316</link>
      <description>Qiao Sun, Shaopeng Wang, Yuan Xu, Aihua Yin, Yang Liu, Jingheng Zhu, Chunling Zheng, Guowei Wang, Zheng Fang, Shanhong Sui, Daixi Wang, Yan Dong, Dongshun Zhang, Chang&#8208;Sheng Wang, Kai Guo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406524679

                Over the past decade, visible-light-mediated energy-transfer (EnT) catalysis, particularly triplet&#8211;triplet energy-transfer (TTEnT) catalysis, has emerged as a mild and environmentally friendly approach for diverse organic synthetic transformations. In contrast to photoredox catalysis, which typically requires sacrificial electron donors or acceptors to complete the catalytic cycle, EnT photocatalysis generally proceeds with high atom economy while minimizing the generation of wasteful byproducts. Furthermore, while successful photoredox catalysis is contingent upon the precise control of redox potentials of both photocatalysts and organic substrates, EnT strategies are primarily influenced by the triplet energy compatibility between these entities. Considering the growing importance of EnT photocatalysis, as well as hydrofunctionalization and difunctionalization reactions in organic synthesis, this review systematically summarizes significant advancements in EnT-enabled hydrofunctionalization and difunctionalization of unsaturated compounds via sigma-bond homolysis over the past decade. Special emphasis is placed on elucidating substrate scopes and mechanistic scenarios. Additionally, this review discusses versatile synthetic applications of these methodologies and addresses current challenges and opportunities within this evolving research field. This review is structured into six main categories based on different types of energy-transfer acceptors and the sigma-bonds undergoing homolysis. These categories include EnT-enabled hydrofunctionalization and difunctionalization transformations mediated by 1) N&#8211;O bond homolysis of oxime esters and other N,O-radical precursors; 2) N&#8211;S bond homolysis of N-sulfonyl imines and other N,S-radical precursors; 3) chalcogen&#8211;chalcogen bond homolysis of disulfides and oxy/thio/selenosulfonates; 4) C&#8211;S bond homolysis of tri/difluoromethylated sulfinates, acetylenic triflones, and arylsulfonium salts; 5) C&#8211;X (X = halogen) bond homolysis of organic halides; and 6) sigma-bond homolysis of other energy-transfer acceptors. Through providing theoretical backgrounds of EnT catalysis, along with a comprehensive overview of currently employed energy-transfer acceptors, photosensitizers, and contemporary strategies for EnT-induced hydrofunctionalization and difunctionalization of unsaturated compounds, this review aims to serve as an invaluable resource for future innovations in this rapidly evolving field.</description>
      <author>Qiao Sun, Shaopeng Wang, Yuan Xu, Aihua Yin, Yang Liu, Jingheng Zhu, Chunling Zheng, Guowei Wang, Zheng Fang, Shanhong Sui, Daixi Wang, Yan Dong, Dongshun Zhang, Chang&#8208;Sheng Wang, Kai Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous Engineering of the Thermostability and Activity of a Novel Aldehyde Dehydrogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06840</link>
      <description>Kangjie Xu, Qiming Chen, Haiyan Fu, Qihang Chen, Jiahao Gu, Xinglong Wang, Jingwen Zhou, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406526090

                Acetaldehyde is a toxic pollutant that can be detoxified by acetaldehyde dehydrogenases (ADAs) through its conversion to acetyl-CoA. This study developed an integrated approach combining virtual screening, rational design, and a dual scoring mechanism to identify and engineer hyperactive ADA variants. A library of 5000 Dickeya parazeae ADA (DpADA) homologues was created through protein BLAST, and deep learning tools predicted their Kcat values. The top 100 candidates were selected based on acetaldehyde binding affinity, evaluated through molecular docking and phylogenetic analysis. Among these, ADA6 from Buttiauxella sp. S04-F03 exhibited the highest activity, converting 57.6% of acetaldehyde to acetyl-CoA, which was 14.1 times higher than DpADA. To improve ADA6's thermostability, folding engineering was applied, resulting in the P443C variant with an 80.7% increase in residual activity after heat treatment. Molecular dynamics simulation pinpointed I440 as a bottleneck in the substrate tunnel, guiding the design of a dual-scoring system that integrates structural adjustments and electronic optimization to evaluate mutations for improved substrate exposure and activity. The final optimized variant, P443C-I440T, achieved a conversion efficiency of 93.2%. This study demonstrates the effectiveness of combining computational tools and rational mutagenesis to enhance enzyme activity and stability in enzyme engineering.</description>
      <author>Kangjie Xu, Qiming Chen, Haiyan Fu, Qihang Chen, Jiahao Gu, Xinglong Wang, Jingwen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of A-Site Defects on the Catalytic Activity of Perovskite LaCoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;: Insights from the Electronic Structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06142</link>
      <description>Hanlin Chen, Xiaoliang Liang, Zijuan You, Fuding Tan, Jingwen Zhou, Xiaoju Lin, Meiqin Chen, Peng Liu, Yiping Yang, Suhua Wang, Steven L. Suib, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406532106

                The development of highly active perovskite-based catalysts for the oxidation of volatile organic chemicals (VOCs) has drawn a great deal of attention. A-site defect regulation is found to be effective to improve the catalytic performance, but the relationship between structure variation and catalytic activity has not been clearly unveiled. Herein, this issue was interpreted by the variation of physicochemical properties and electronic structure (O p-band center). An in situ one-step calcination method with NH4HCO3 addition was adopted to prepare a series of A-site-deficient LaCoO3 perovskites (LxCO), which were characterized by XRD, TEM, EELS, ESR, XPS, UPS, H2-TPR, and O2-TPD and catalytic test toward toluene oxidation. The catalytic activity displayed a volcano-type relationship with an addition amount of NH4HCO3. The electronic structure determined the reducibility and active oxygen content and accordingly affected the catalytic activity of LxCO. The obtained results provide theoretical and technical support for the design of efficient VOC oxidation catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hanlin Chen, Xiaoliang Liang, Zijuan You, Fuding Tan, Jingwen Zhou, Xiaoju Lin, Meiqin Chen, Peng Liu, Yiping Yang, Suhua Wang, Steven L. Suib</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of &#946;-MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via Ir/Ru Co-substitution for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</link>
      <description>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406534076

                The efficiency of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media is severely limited by the poor stability, low activity, and high cost of available catalysts. Enhancing intrinsic activity while maintaining stability and reducing reliance on precious metals is crucial. The typical adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) leads to high overpotentials and low activity, making the transition to alternative mechanisms, such as the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) or oxide path mechanism (OPM), highly desirable due to their lower overpotentials. Here, we combine density functional theory (DFT) calculations with experimental validation to enhance the activity and stability of &#946;-MnO2 via co-substitution with ruthenium (Ru) and iridium (Ir), enabling the transition from AEM to OPM. DFT calculations reveal that AEM is hindered by the weak nucleophilicity of water, while LOM suffers from high kinetic barriers due to structural distortions. In contrast, OPM demonstrates a significantly lower kinetic barrier, facilitated by the synergistic interaction between Ru and Ir. Experimentally, IrRuMnOx was synthesized through co-precipitation and hydrothermal methods, showing an 80-fold improvement in mass activity and a 96-fold increase in stability compared to commercial IrO2, with minimal noble metal leaching, as confirmed by inductively coupled plasma optical emission spectroscopy (ICP-OES). IrRuMnOx exhibited an ultralow overpotential of 475 mV at 1 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 44.26 mV&#183;dec&#8211;1 in 0.5 M H2SO4, maintaining stable performance for over 100 h. Moreover, the IrRuMnOx-based membrane electrode, with a low Ir loading of 0.075 mgIr&#183;cm&#8211;2, achieved remarkable current densities of 1.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.66 V and 2.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.91 V at 80 &#176;C. This performance surpasses that of both unsupported and conventional supported Ir-based catalysts at comparable Ir loading levels. This study offers critical insights into OER mechanisms in acidic media and paves the way for developing efficient and durable OER electrocatalysts for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv015i002_1889649</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406540614

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv015i002_1889649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv015i002_1889648</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406540636

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv015i002_1889648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the Fungal Peroxygenase for Efficient and Regioselective Hydroxylation of Vitamin Ds and Sterols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06429</link>
      <description>Yawen Huang, Jie Zhang, Fuqiang Chen, Yu Fu, Han Liu, Zhiyou Zong, Quanshun Li, Yalan Zhang, Huanhuan Li, Xiang Sheng, Weidong Liu, Wuyuan Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406574048

                Hydroxylation of C25 C&#8211;H bonds (referring to sterols) is of great importance in vivo for metabolizing sterols and vitamin Ds. The biocatalytic hydroxylation of C25 C&#8211;H bonds is restricted by the selectivity and activity of the enzymes due to the inertness of these bulky compounds. Herein, we employed fungal unspecific peroxygenase from Agrocybe aegerita (AaeUPO) as the catalyst to develop efficient and selective AaeUPO variants through protein engineering. After three rounds of evolution using semirational design, 2 variants, G195A/G241V/G318V (Stev) and Q72K/G195A/G241V (Veco), were determined to be the ideal catalysts, showing a 25- to 27-fold increase in enzyme activity and an improvement in selectivity from 25% to over 93% in gram-scale conversion of vitamin D3 to 25-hydroxyvitamin D3. These two variants exhibited overall enhanced catalytic performance in hydroxylating the C25 C&#8211;H bonds of the other 24 sterol and vitamin D analogues. This work provides an enzymatic toolbox to synthesize the highly important vitamins and sterols into the compounds of interest under mild conditions with remarkable regioselectivity and enzyme activity.</description>
      <author>Yawen Huang, Jie Zhang, Fuqiang Chen, Yu Fu, Han Liu, Zhiyou Zong, Quanshun Li, Yalan Zhang, Huanhuan Li, Xiang Sheng, Weidong Liu, Wuyuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in Chiral Quaternary Ammonium Salt-Promoted Asymmetric Nucleophilic Additions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06497</link>
      <description>Xiaoqun Yang, Youlin Deng, Dan Ling, Tingting Li, Lingzhu Chen, Zhichao Jin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406618785

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoqun Yang, Youlin Deng, Dan Ling, Tingting Li, Lingzhu Chen, Zhichao Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06497</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reshaping the Substrate-Binding Pocket of Ene-Reductase for Enhanced and Inverted Stereoselectivity: A Concise Access to the Stereocomplementary Chiral GABA Derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06784</link>
      <description>An Huang, Xianheng Song, Linlin Song, Shuang-Shuang Pan, Jiaxin Tian, Pengfei Wang, Shuyun Ju, Yajun Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406632949

                Despite the availability of numerous natural and engineered ene-reductases (ERs), enantiocomplementary synthesis of the sterically hindered molecules by ERs is still limited by poor substrate acceptance, particularly due to the insufficient complementary stereoselectivity. Herein, we reshaped the substrate-binding pocket of SeER from Saccharomyces eubayanus through semirational design, enabling ERs capable of stereocomplementary hydrogenating of the challenging substituted &#946;-cyano cinnamic esters. Compared to the wild type, the variants exhibited enhanced activity (up to 161-fold) and catalytic efficiency kcat/KM (up to 358-fold), displaying potential in synthesizing various chiral &#946;-cyano esters with high stereoselectivity (up to 99% ee). Molecular dynamics simulations demonstrated that the key for the superior catalytic performance of variants is the well-tuned substrate-binding pocket, which strengthens and stabilizes substrate recognition. Furthermore, we elucidated the practicality of the SeER variants in asymmetric synthesis of the chiral GABA derivatives (e.g., Phenibut, Baclofen, and Tolibut) via chemo-enzymatic cascade reactions.</description>
      <author>An Huang, Xianheng Song, Linlin Song, Shuang-Shuang Pan, Jiaxin Tian, Pengfei Wang, Shuyun Ju, Yajun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time-Domain NMR: Generating Unique Insights into the Characterization of Heterogeneous Catalysis in Liquid Phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04789</link>
      <description>Murilo T. Suekuni, Carmine D&#8217;Agostino, Alan M. Allgeier, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406636099

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Murilo T. Suekuni, Carmine D&#8217;Agostino, Alan M. Allgeier</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin ZSM-5 Shell Constructed on an S-1 Crystal Surface for Prins Reaction to Boost Methanol Aromatization with High Catalytic Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07004</link>
      <description>Ma Qian, Tingjun Fu, Chuntao Cao, Xueqing Wu, Zhong Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406644119

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ma Qian, Tingjun Fu, Chuntao Cao, Xueqing Wu, Zhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Morphing of Hydroxyl Groups on Covalency Competing Spinel Oxides Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07014</link>
      <description>Jiali Gou, Xin Lei, Bifa Ji, Shanshan Zhang, Yongping Zheng, Yongbing Tang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406668219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiali Gou, Xin Lei, Bifa Ji, Shanshan Zhang, Yongping Zheng, Yongbing Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Syngas-To-Ethanol Conversion over Lithium-Promoted Rh/MgO Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05085</link>
      <description>Abdellah Ait El Fakir, Pengfei Du, Wan Li, H.&#8208;B. Pan, Shirun Zhao, Nazmul Hasan MD Dostagir, Akihiko Anzai, Shinya Mine, Evgeny A. Pidko, Ken&#8208;ichi Shimizu, Takashi Toyao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406676550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdellah Ait El Fakir, Pengfei Du, Wan Li, H.&#8208;B. Pan, Shirun Zhao, Nazmul Hasan MD Dostagir, Akihiko Anzai, Shinya Mine, Evgeny A. Pidko, Ken&#8208;ichi Shimizu, Takashi Toyao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diastereo- and Enantioselective Chemoenzymatic Synthesis of Chiral Tricyclic Intermediate of Anti-HIV Drug Lenacapavir</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07464</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Zhen Fu, An Liu, Yang Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406676579

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Zhen Fu, An Liu, Yang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encapsulating Ru Nanoclusters for Reductive Imination of Biomass-Based Furfural by Shape-Selective Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07371</link>
      <description>Hongtao Zou, Yuxin Jin, Limin Chen, Jinzhu Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406678574

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongtao Zou, Yuxin Jin, Limin Chen, Jinzhu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pickering Interfacial Tandem Catalysis of Alkenes to 1,2-Diols over Manganese Oxide Catalysts at Room Temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06225</link>
      <description>Shihao Su, Guojun Lv, Jialing Shen, Guanghui Wang, Lachgar Oussama, Yan Chen, Shengnan Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406679706

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shihao Su, Guojun Lv, Jialing Shen, Guanghui Wang, Lachgar Oussama, Yan Chen, Shengnan Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering the Origin of Catalyst Performance and Degradation of Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction through Interpretable Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05530</link>
      <description>Daeun Chloe Shin, Hakan Karasu, Kyojin Jang, Chang Soo Kim, Kyeongsu Kim, Dongjin Kim, Young Jin, Ki Bong Lee, Keun Hwa Chae, Il Moon, Da Hye Won, Jonggeol Na, Ung Lee, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406692538

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daeun Chloe Shin, Hakan Karasu, Kyojin Jang, Chang Soo Kim, Kyeongsu Kim, Dongjin Kim, Young Jin, Ki Bong Lee, Keun Hwa Chae, Il Moon, Da Hye Won, Jonggeol Na, Ung Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05530</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox-Neutral Photocatalytic Germylative Difunctionalization of Unactivated Olefins via Selective Radical Capture by Ge(II)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06681</link>
      <description>Wenjing Zhou, Zequn Yang, Bin Xiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406694927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjing Zhou, Zequn Yang, Bin Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A General Amino&#8211;(Hetero)arylation of Simple Olefins with (Hetero)aryl Sulfonamides Enabled by an &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Triazinyl Group</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00157</link>
      <description>Jaxon L. Barney, Andrew J. Wolfram, Rose Litvak, Eric D. Nacsa, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406698033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jaxon L. Barney, Andrew J. Wolfram, Rose Litvak, Eric D. Nacsa</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Photoelectrocatalysis of Glycerol to Dihydroxyacetone and Synergistic Hydrogen Generation via Dual Oxidation Pathways Using Co-LDH/Bi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Ternary Array</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05193</link>
      <description>Lu Niu, Rufeng Tian, Wanggang Zhang, Hongxia Wang, Jian Wang, Yiming Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406698920

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Niu, Rufeng Tian, Wanggang Zhang, Hongxia Wang, Jian Wang, Yiming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Catalytic Enantioselective C&#8211;H Bond Oxidation at Nonactivated Methylenes Through Predictive Statistical Modeling Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05659</link>
      <description>Arnau Call, Andrea Palone, Jordan P. Liles, Natalie P. Romer, Jacquelyne A. Read, Josep M. Luis, Matthew S. Sigman, Massimo Bietti, Miguel Costas, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406699296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arnau Call, Andrea Palone, Jordan P. Liles, Natalie P. Romer, Jacquelyne A. Read, Josep M. Luis, Matthew S. Sigman, Massimo Bietti, Miguel Costas</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethane Oxidative Dehydrogenation over TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and M/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts: Unraveling the Surface Structure Evolution, Oxygen Species Type, and Role of Doped Metal in Tuning Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07213</link>
      <description>Mifeng Xue, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406708054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mifeng Xue, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Three-Component Chloro-/Azido-Fluoroalkylation of Unactivated Alkenes via the Proximity Effect in a Heterogenous Metallaphotocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06960</link>
      <description>Xiaolin Shi, Maolin Li, Yuanjun Zhao, Yifan Liu, Xin Zhou, Bo Yu, Yong Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406709394

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaolin Shi, Maolin Li, Yuanjun Zhao, Yifan Liu, Xin Zhou, Bo Yu, Yong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Photocatalytic Two-Electron Halide Oxidation over p-Block Metal Bi- and Sb-Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07143</link>
      <description>Ruofan Li, Ling Zhang, Qin Xin, Shenyan Xu, Chunyu Che, Wenjing Wang, Chuanqi Zhang, Wenzhong Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406732853

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruofan Li, Ling Zhang, Qin Xin, Shenyan Xu, Chunyu Che, Wenjing Wang, Chuanqi Zhang, Wenzhong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07143</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mutagenesis of a Single Site Inverts the Stereopreference of Imine Reductase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00046</link>
      <description>Yitong Li, Yunyun Yang, Mengting Zhang, Xiaoping Yue, Rey&#8208;Ting Guo, Zedu Huang, Fen&#8208;Er Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406736803

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yitong Li, Yunyun Yang, Mengting Zhang, Xiaoping Yue, Rey&#8208;Ting Guo, Zedu Huang, Fen&#8208;Er Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Hydrogenolysis of C&#8211;O Bond over Pd/P-TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: The Generation and Role of Br&#248;nsted Acid Site Triggered by Spillover Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06939</link>
      <description>Tingting Xiao, Jingrong Li, Jian Li, Qihang Gong, Peikai Luo, Xinluona Su, Haiyang Cheng, Chao Zhang, Fengyu Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406738483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingting Xiao, Jingrong Li, Jian Li, Qihang Gong, Peikai Luo, Xinluona Su, Haiyang Cheng, Chao Zhang, Fengyu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06939</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmable Scaffold-Mediated Assembly Regulation Tool for Dynamic Control of a Multienzyme Biocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05420</link>
      <description>Mengkai Hu, Teng Bao, Zhen Qin, Qiang Wang, Hengwei Zhang, Yujue Wang, Jiajia You, Zhenglian Xue, Rongzhen Zhang, Shang&#8208;Tian Yang, Xian Zhang, Zhiming Rao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406745445

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengkai Hu, Teng Bao, Zhen Qin, Qiang Wang, Hengwei Zhang, Yujue Wang, Jiajia You, Zhenglian Xue, Rongzhen Zhang, Shang&#8208;Tian Yang, Xian Zhang, Zhiming Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05420</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
