<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 01:27:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant-Tuned Restructuring Kinetic for the Formation of Heterophase-Confined Metal-Nonmetal Diatomic Sites for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03060</link>
      <description>Xinyi Li, Feiyan Liu, Wenting Lu, Huafeng Fan, Meiling Xiao, Xiaoqiang Cui, Lu Li, Xiaoxin Zou, Weitao Zheng, Xiao Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405751831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyi Li, Feiyan Liu, Wenting Lu, Huafeng Fan, Meiling Xiao, Xiaoqiang Cui, Lu Li, Xiaoxin Zou, Weitao Zheng, Xiao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The &lt;i&gt;On&lt;/i&gt;/&lt;i&gt;Off&lt;/i&gt; pH-Dependent Electrocatalytic Activity of the Perfluorinated Iron Phthalocyanine for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Electrochemical Hardness as a Reactivity Descriptor: Experimental and Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06957</link>
      <description>Luis Acu&#241;a-Saavedra, Ana Mar&#237;a M&#233;ndez&#8208;Torres, Gloria C&#225;rdenas&#8208;Jir&#243;n, Rub&#233;n O&#241;ate, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Allende, Ricardo Venegas, Roberto Bernal, Francisco Melo, Elizabeth Imbarack, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Ingrid Ponce, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405755151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luis Acu&#241;a-Saavedra, Ana Mar&#237;a M&#233;ndez&#8208;Torres, Gloria C&#225;rdenas&#8208;Jir&#243;n, Rub&#233;n O&#241;ate, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Allende, Ricardo Venegas, Roberto Bernal, Francisco Melo, Elizabeth Imbarack, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Ingrid Ponce</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expeditious Synthesis of Highly Functional 4-Trifluoromethyl-Substituted Oxazoles Enabled by Cobalt(II) Metalloradical Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07209</link>
      <description>Hang Wang, Qingyun Duan, Baiquan Wang, Bin Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405775871

                A synthetic strategy for the catalytic cycloaddition of &#945;-trifluoromethyl-&#945;-diazoketones with nitriles has been achieved based on cobalt(II) metalloradical catalysis. The easily accessible starting materials, cost-effective catalyst, and experimental simplicity rendered this protocol a robust and practical approach to construct diverse functionalized 4-CF3-substituted oxazoles with high efficiency. A wide substrate scope of both &#945;-trifluoromethylated diazoketones and nitriles is amenable to this catalytic system. The high level of functional group tolerance of this protocol provides several opportunities for precise late-stage modifications of bioactive and drug-like molecules. Mechanistic experiments and spectroscopic investigations confirm the radical nature of the reaction and reveal the involvement of both monocarbene and biscarbene radical intermediates during the catalytic process.</description>
      <author>Hang Wang, Qingyun Duan, Baiquan Wang, Bin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07209</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Acidic Water Electrolysis via Local Electronic Regulation of Ru/TiO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst with Oxygen Coordination Unsaturated Ti Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06836</link>
      <description>Wei Xia, Kai Yuan, Xuejie Cao, Hongye Qin, Guangliang Lin, Jinyang Zhang, Ting Jin, Qing&#8208;Lun Wang, Lifang Jiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405783804

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Xia, Kai Yuan, Xuejie Cao, Hongye Qin, Guangliang Lin, Jinyang Zhang, Ting Jin, Qing&#8208;Lun Wang, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic and Thermodynamic Considerations in Thermocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05805</link>
      <description>Ting Lin, Elizabeth E. Bickel Rogers, Aditya Bhan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405798890

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef.SI ACS CatalysisASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse ViewpointDecember 26, 2024Kinetic and Thermodynamic Considerations in Thermocatalytic CO2 HydrogenationClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Ting C. LinTing C. LinDepartment of Chemical Engineering and Materials Science, University of Minnesota-Twin Cities, 421 Washington Ave. SE, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55455, United StatesMore by Ting C. LinElizabeth E. Bickel RogersElizabeth E. Bickel RogersDepartment of Chemical Engineering and Materials Science, University of Minnesota-Twin Cities, 421 Washington Ave. SE, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55455, United StatesMore by Elizabeth E. Bickel RogersAditya Bhan*Aditya BhanDepartment of Chemical Engineering and Materials Science, University of Minnesota-Twin Cities, 421 Washington Ave. SE, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55455, United States*E-mail: [email protected]. Fax: (+1) 612-626-7246.More by Aditya Bhanhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-6069-7626Open PDFSupporting Information (1)ACS CatalysisCite this: ACS Catal. 2025, 15, XXX, 780&#8211;788Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acscatal.4c05805https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05805Published December 26, 2024 Publication History Received 21 September 2024Accepted 11 December 2024Revised 10 December 2024Published online 26 December 2024article-commentary&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.AlcoholsChemical reactionsFree energySelectivityThermodynamics1. IntroductionClick to copy section linkSection link copied!A synthetic liquid hydrocarbon economy, one in which CO2 and H2O, the final products of combustion, serve as carbon and hydrogen sources for producing energy-dense fuels, would significantly augment efforts to decarbonize the fuel and chemical industries. Direct routes for the catalytic conversion of CO2, however, are impeded not only by its thermodynamic stability but also by our inability to direct CO2 hydrogenation pathways toward high-value products (e.g., methanol). This interplay of reaction thermodynamics and kinetics during CO2 hydrogenation confounds the underlying mechanistic origins of observed rates and selectivity and hampers efforts to establish structure&#8211;function relationships.CO2 hydrogenation proceeds through an interconnected reaction network involving reaction pathways to form methanol, CO (reverse water&#8211;gas shift (RWGS)), methane, and C2+ hydrocarbons and oxygenates (Scheme 1), as well as reaction pathways for interconversion among these products. Measured product formation rates cannot be treated as pathway-specific rates without further qualifications because products may be formed through more than one reaction pathway or consumed in secondary reactions; (1) mechanistic interpretations of measured rates in CO2 hydrogenation thus require knowledge of the reaction network connectivity and the ability to independently evaluate contributions from each reaction pathway. Efforts to obtain such insights, however, are hindered by the potential presence of product inhibition and by the ambiguity surrounding the atomic origin of products when multiple carbon-containing reactants are introduced (e.g., mixtures of CO/CO2). Additionally, these reaction pathways experience disparate thermodynamic (equilibrium) limitations, necessitating the deconvolution of kinetic and thermodynamic driving forces before mechanistic conclusions can be drawn.Scheme 1Scheme 1. Simplified CO2 Hydrogenation Reaction NetworkaHigh Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideaStoichiometric amounts of H2 and H2O were omitted.The purview of this Viewpoint is to address challenges and considerations in acquiring kinetic information necessary for advancing structure&#8211;function relationships for CO2-to-fuel processes. We provide an analytical framework underpinned by thermodynamics, relevant for assessing the kinetics of interconnected, reversible reaction systems, including and surpassing CO2 hydrogenation. We discuss approaches for elucidating network connectivity in interconnected reaction networks and describe protocols that enable the parsing of rates and selectivity between kinetic contributions, which can be attributed to catalyst properties, and those that arise solely due to thermodynamics, which are catalyst independent. These formalisms, in turn, allow for meaningful comparisons of catalyst performance among catalytic materials and guide ongoing efforts to develop catalyst formulations with improved rates and selectivity. Through this discourse, we aim to address the following questions:(i)How can the reaction network connectivity between CO2, CO, and hydrocarbon/oxygenate products be determined to assess pathway-specific rates?(ii)How can thermodynamic contributions to observed trends in rates and selectivity be identified and decoupled from kinetic contributions?(iii)How can relationships between and constraints imposed by thermodynamic driving forces be illustrated in energy diagrams?Together, the concepts described herein establish methods for interrogating the CO2 hydrogenation pathways without a priori knowledge of the reaction mechanism or the composition and chemical characteristics of the catalyst employed.2. Evaluating the Reaction Network of CO2 HydrogenationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!The underlying mechanistic origin of the observed rates and selectivity in CO2 hydrogenation is obscured by its network connectivity (Scheme 1). For example, in the absence of thermodynamic constraints, a lower rate of methanol formation during CO2 hydrogenation might reflect either slower kinetics for methanol synthesis from CO2, higher rates of methanol consumption via a secondary reaction, or some combination thereof. Similarly, apparent reaction orders for methanol synthesis measured during CO2 hydrogenation may reflect the kinetics of CO2 hydrogenation, secondary reactions of CO, or a convolution of both. Elucidation of catalyst characteristics thus requires distinguishing between such possibilities and quantifying pathway-specific rates within the CO2 hydrogenation network (i.e., rates for CO2 to methanol and CO to methanol). In this section, we outline three methods for determining the network connectivity in an interconnected reaction network and detail the limitations associated with each method in the context of CO2 hydrogenation.2.1. Ranks and Stability of ProductsA traditional approach to evaluate reaction network connectivity is delplot analysis, developed by Bhore, Klein, and Bischoff, (2) which provides information on product rank (i.e., primary, secondary, etc.) through a graphical assessment of the relationship between selectivity and conversion. In a first rank delplot, selectivity is plotted against conversion. Primary products are those for which the dependence of selectivity on conversion extrapolates to a finite, nonzero selectivity at zero conversion, while secondary and higher rank products have selectivities that extrapolate to zero at zero conversion. (2) To illustrate this method, we consider simulated values for a hypothetical system akin to CO2 hydrogenation, where a reactant (A) forms three products (B, C, D) and one side-product (E) through irreversible reactions (Scheme 1; Figure 1a). In case (i), C is formed only by secondary reactions of B and D (i.e., rA&#8594;C = 0) with no product inhibition present, and in case (ii), C is formed only as a primary product of A (i.e., rB&#8594;C = rD&#8594;C = 0) with E inhibiting the formation rates of B and D, analogous to the inhibition of methanol synthesis by water during CO2 hydrogenation. (3,4) The nonzero y-intercepts exhibited by primary products in the simulated first rank delplots (panels b and c of Figure 1 for cases (i) and (ii), respectively) correctly indicate B and D as the primary products in case (i) and B, C, and D as the primary products in case (ii). In general, an nth rank delplot can be constructed to identify products of rank n by plotting the selectivity of each species (Sm) divided by conversion (X) raised to the (n &#8211; 1)th power against conversion (eq 1), as shown by Bhore et al. (2)ym=SmXn&#8722;1(1)Here, Sm is given by rm(&#8721;p = products rp)&#8722;1, where rm is the net formation rate of species m. For first order reactions and an nth rank delplot, products of rank n will exhibit a finite, nonzero y-intercept, products of lower ranks will exhibit y-intercepts that diverge, and products of higher ranks will exhibit y-intercepts of zero. Notably, when reactions are not first order, the y-intercept of a (n &gt; 1)th rank product on a (n &gt; 1)th rank delplot diverges when the reaction order is less than one and is zero when the reaction order is greater than one (Figures S1&#8211;S3; section S2). As a result, apparent reaction orders should also be considered when evaluating higher rank delplots; analyzing higher rank delplots without knowledge of apparent reaction orders can lead to erroneous conclusions about the reaction pathways involved in forming higher rank products.Figure 1Figure 1. (a) Hypothetical reaction networks where A converts to B, C, D, and E following two cases: (i) C is a secondary product with no product inhibition present, and (ii) all species are primary products with E inhibiting the formation rates of B and D. Here, CE denotes the concentration of species E. (b, c) Simulated first rank delplots and (d, e) yields as a function of contact time for the two cases. Inset in (c) shows the selectivity to product C over the 0&#8211;3% conversion region of the first rank plot for case (ii). (f) Simulated TOFs as a function of contact time for case (i). Values of rate and equilibrium constants were chosen for illustrative purposes and do not impact the general trends shown. Arbitrary units are abbreviated as a.u. Simulation details are provided in section S1 (Supporting Information (SI)).High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideWhile delplot analysis is a practical method because it utilizes readily measurable parameters (i.e., selectivity, conversion), its efficacy is limited due to its reliance on the extrapolation of ym to zero conversion to determine the y-intercept. This limitation is particularly perilous for systems where reaction kinetics (e.g., product inhibition) result in a sharp increase in selectivity near zero conversion, as shown in Figure 1c. In this case, SC could appear to extrapolate to zero at zero conversion if insufficient data at low conversion (&#8818; 3%) were used, leading to the incorrect conclusion that C is a secondary product. More importantly, delplot analysis only provides information on product ranks based on the y-intercepts of delplots; mechanistic conclusions, in general, cannot be drawn from trends in selectivity with increasing conversion. This is shown through Figure 1b,c, where SB and SD decrease with increasing conversion for case (i) because B and D are consumed to form C, while SB and SD decrease with increasing conversion for case (ii) because of product inhibition by species E. Thus, without a priori information on the reaction kinetics, a decrease in Sm with increasing conversion could suggest that m is an unstable product, that the rate of synthesis of another product increases with reactant conversion, and/or that product inhibition disproportionately affects the formation rate of m. Delplot analysis must, therefore, be used in conjunction with other methods to formulate a complete picture of the reaction network, particularly for systems where product ranks cannot be unambiguously assigned due to complex dependencies of selectivity on conversion or where product inhibition is present.Evaluating product yields against contact time (Figure 1d,e), similar to the method described by John and Wojciechowski, (5) constitutes one such supplemental method. In these plots, slopes correspond to instantaneous turnover frequencies (TOFs); primary products thus exhibit positive TOFs (positive slopes) at zero conversion/contact time (e.g., B and D in Figure 1d,f), while higher rank products exhibit TOFs of zero at zero conversion/contact time (e.g., C in Figure 1d,f), congruent with delplot analysis. Product inhibition, product interconversion, or a combination thereof can then be identified by the changes in TOFs with increasing contact time. Specifically, product inhibition decreases the instantaneous TOF (a decrease in slope when yield is plotted as a function of contact time) (e.g., B vs C in Figure 1e), but the instantaneous TOF of a given product does not become negative (negative slope) unless it is consumed by a secondary reaction (e.g., B and D in Figure 1d,f). More intricate dependencies of rates on contact time may arise from a convolution of product inhibition and product interconversion. In such cases, evaluating the effects of cofeeding products in relevant concentrations on observed rates facilitates determining whether product interconversion and/or product inhibition influence a given product.2.2. Implications of Thermodynamic Constraints for Network ConnectivityReaction pathways proceed such that each constituent elementary step (i) abides by De Donder's inequality: (6,7)Airi=Ai(r+i&#8722;r&#8722;i)&#8805;0or&#916;Giri=&#916;Gi(r+i&#8722;r&#8722;i)&#8804;0(2)where Ai = &#8722;&#916;Gi is the affinity of reaction, &#916;Gi is the change in Gibbs free energy for elementary step i, and ri, r+i, and r&#8211;i are the net, forward, and reverse rates of elementary step i, respectively. Postulated reaction pathways can, therefore, be assessed for their adherence to De Donder's inequality and immediately excluded if they violate this thermodynamic constraint without the considerable experimental effort and potential ambiguity associated with the graphical methods described in the previous section.Evaluating a postulated reaction network against De Donder's inequality begins with recognizing the relationship between affinity and the reversibility (zi) or "approach to equilibrium" via De Donder's equality (eq 3):zi=r&#8722;ir+i=exp(&#8722;AikBT)=exp(&#916;GikBT)=&#8719;m=speciesam&#957;m,iKi(3)Here, am is the activity of species m, and &#957;m,i is the stoichiometric coefficient of species m in elementary step i. Equations 2 and 3 show that a step proceeding in the forward direction (r+i &#8805; r&#8211;i, ri &#8805; 0) must have a positive Ai, a negative &#916;Gi, and a reversibility value less than unity. This principle extends to overall reactions involving multiple elementary steps and to global reactions involving multiple overall reactions through the relationship between zi (for elementary steps) and the effective reversibility (Zeff; for overall reactions; eq 4):Zeff=&#8719;i=1Nzi=R&#8592;R&#8594;(4)where R&#8407; and R&#8406; are the forward and reverse rates of the overall reaction, respectively. Notably, the effective reversibility differs from the more readily measurable overall reversibility (Zov) in that Zeff is independent of the choice of elementary step stoichiometric numbers (&#963;i) associated with the overall reaction and is equal to Zov1/&#963;&#773; (eq 5):Zeff=Zov1/&#963;&#175;=(&#8719;m=speciesam&#957;m,ovKov)1/&#963;&#175; where&#963;&#175;=&#8721;i&#963;iAi&#8721;iAi(5)Zeff is equal to Zov only for reactions involving unity stoichiometric numbers (stoichiometrically regular). A more detailed discussion of this distinction is provided elsewhere. (7)De Donder's relations (eqs 2 and 3), together with eq 4, imply that the effective reversibility for an overall reaction must be lower than that for the formation of intermediate species in a sequential reaction pathway proceeding in the forward direction since the overall reaction involves additional elementary steps converting intermediates to the final product and zi for every elementary step must be less than one. We illustrate this principle with a hypothetical single-path reaction sequence from A to E (Scheme 2). Here, the effective reversibility for the overall reaction of A to E (Zeff,A&#8594;E) must necessarily be lower than the effective reversibility of A to C (i.e., Zeff,A&#8594;E &lt; Zeff,A&#8594;C; Scheme 2) as zC&#8594;D and zD&#8594;E are both subunity. In the context of CO2 hydrogenation, a proposed reaction pathway in which methanol is formed by sequential RWGS and CO hydrogenation can be eliminated as a possible reaction pathway if the effective reversibility for CO2 to methanol exceeds the effective reversibility from CO2 to CO, (3) thereby indicating distinct reaction pathways to form methanol and CO from CO2. Evaluating the thermodynamic feasibility of hypothetical reaction pathways against De Donder's inequality thus provides a straightforward method for excluding potential pathways of product interconversion, supplementing deductions of reaction network connectivity acquired via the graphical methods described in the previous section. We note that while violation of De Donder's inequality indicates the pathway is thermodynamically forbidden, adherence to De Donder's inequality does not mean that the reaction necessarily occurs through the proposed pathway but rather that the reaction may occur through the proposed pathway without violating thermodynamics. Furthermore, zi varies with the extent of reaction as the system approaches equilibrium (section 4.2), necessitating the evaluation of thermodynamic constraints across all conditions of interest.Scheme 2Scheme 2. A Hypothetical Single-Path Reaction Sequence Consisting of Consecutive Elementary Steps for the Conversion of A to Stable Products B, C, D, and EHigh Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint Slide2.3. Tracing Reaction Pathways with IsotopesThe use of isotopically labeled species (e.g., 14CO2/12CO/H2 feed) is another approach to experimentally evaluate the reaction network connectivity. This method directly circumvents ambiguities arising from product interconversion, the presence of multiple reactants, and convolution of kinetic and thermodynamic driving forces (section 3), as measured isotopic exchange rates not only identify the atomic origins of observed products but also reflect pathway-specific forward and reverse rates, (1) which are inherently devoid of thermodynamic contributions. The use of isotopically labeled reactants to elucidate reaction pathways during COx hydrogenation is exemplified by the work of Chinchen et al., (8) where 14CO2/12CO/H2 mixtures were used to determine the source of methanol as CO2 during COx hydrogenation. Isotopic measurements for the assessment of directional forward and reverse rates, however, require experimental conditions that mitigate the scrambling of labeled and unlabeled reagents. Significant interconversion of 14CO2 and 12CO during COx hydrogenation with a 14CO2/12CO/H2 feed, for example, would obscure the sources of 14CH3OH and 12CH3OH products. Meaningful mechanistic and kinetic insights from isotopic experiments should therefore only be drawn from results obtained in the limit of infinite space velocity and low contact time to prevent isotopic scrambling.The approaches outlined in section 2 reveal key aspects of reaction network connectivity in terms of product rank, product stability, branching intermediate(s), and atomic origin of products that together provide insights into the relationship between observed rates and pathway-specific rates in catalytic CO2 hydrogenation. We refer the reader to the work of Miller et al. (9) for a supplementary example of applying the methodologies outlined above to facilitate mechanistic investigations of reactions proceeding through complex networks.3. Deconvoluting Kinetic and Thermodynamic Contributions to Rate and SelectivityClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Having discussed strategies for assessing reaction network connectivity to relate product formation rates to rates of specific reaction pathways, we now underscore the potential influences of thermodynamic constraints on observed rates and selectivity. We also outline mathematical protocols for deconvoluting thermodynamic and kinetic driving forces across different length-scales to extract kinetic information from measured rates.3.1. Assessment of Thermodynamic Driving ForcesCatalysts alter reaction rates and selectivity but cannot affect equilibrium constraints. In the case of CO2 hydrogenation, no catalyst formulation, even during sorption-enhanced methanol synthesis, can achieve methanol yields/pressures that result in greater-than-unity reversibility values (eq 6 where P0 is the pressure at standard state) unless methanol is produced from a species other than CO2 in the feed or consumed in net rather than formed. This constraint relates to the use of reversibility values to elucidate the network connectivity (section 2.2).Notably, eq 6 must also be upheld when water is cofed with reactants, in which case any effects of water on the methanol synthesis rate could be attributable to kinetics (e.g., product inhibition), (3) thermodynamics (equilibrium limitations), or both depending on the reaction conditions employed.Assessment of the kinetics of reversible reactions based on measurements near equilibrium without corrections will thus lead to conclusions corrupted by thermodynamics. This is most clearly demonstrated by the fact that the observed (net) rate (R) is equal to the forward rate (R&#8407;) at conditions away from equilibrium (Zeff &#8776; 0) but is equal to 0 at equilibrium (Zeff = 1) (eq 7):R=R&#8594;&#8722;R&#8592;=R&#8594;(1&#8722;Zeff)=R&#8594;(1&#8722;Zov1/&#963;&#175;)(7)As selectivity reflects a ratio of net rates, selectivity also depends on the reversibility. This effect is particularly deleterious in systems such as CO2 hydrogenation, where reactions with drastically different equilibrium limitations are being compared (Scheme 1).We illustrate the potential convolution of kinetic and thermodynamic driving forces through simulated carbon selectivity for a hypothetical catalyst formulation on which methanol synthesis, RWGS, and ethanol synthesis proceed according to the same forward rate expression of R&#8407; = kappPCO2PH2 but with different apparent rate constants (5, 0.1, and 0.001 a.u., respectively; Figure 2; see details in section S3, SI). The formation of CO via RWGS is endothermic and roughly entropically neutral at 503 K (&#916;H0 = 39.8 kJ mol&#8211;1; &#916;S0 = 38.7 J mol&#8211;1 K&#8211;1; P0 = 1 bar; 503 K; calculated based on values from ref (10)). In contrast, ethanol synthesis from CO2 is exothermic but entropically unfavorable (&#916;H0 = &#8722;188 kJ mol&#8211;1; &#916;S0 = &#8722;402 J mol&#8211;1 K&#8211;1; P0 = 1 bar; 503 K). The energetics associated with these two reactions result in equilibrium constants that differ by almost an order of magnitude at 503 K (0.0077 for RWGS and 0.034 for ethanol synthesis). Consequently, the equilibrium CO yield under these conditions will necessarily be lower than that of ethanol solely due to thermodynamic constraints. A catalyst formulation that exhibits faster RWGS rates than ethanol synthesis rates (i.e., higher selectivity to CO kinetically, as in the case shown in Figure 2) can consequently appear as a selective ethanol synthesis catalyst based on data measured at long contact time near equilibrium (i.e., higher selectivity to ethanol at equilibrium; Figure 2a,b). Analogously, the thermodynamics of methanol synthesis from CO2 (&#916;H0 = &#8722;58.0 kJ mol&#8211;1; &#916;S0 = &#8722;199 J mol&#8211;1 K&#8211;1; P0 = 1 bar; 503 K) result in an equilibrium constant that is orders of magnitude lower than those of RWGS and ethanol synthesis (4.0 &#215; 10&#8211;5 for methanol synthesis, 0.0077 for RWGS, and 0.034 for ethanol synthesis). A catalyst formulation that is kinetically selective toward methanol, as in the case shown in Figure 2, can erroneously appear unselective toward methanol under equilibrium-limited conditions (Figure 2a,b). Because the equilibrium constant is dependent on temperature (eq 8; K|T=T* denotes the equilibrium constant for a reaction occurring at temperature T*) and the equilibrium composition is further dependent on pressure in the case of nonequimolar reactions (eq 9; &#966;meq denotes the equilibrium effluent mole fraction of species m), attempts to determine reaction orders and characterize catalyst behaviors based on rates and selectivity measured near equilibrium will also lead to temperature and pressure dependences corrupted by thermodynamic driving forces (Figure 2c).K|T=T*=exp(&#8722;&#916;G0|T=T*kBT*)=exp(&#8722;&#916;H0|T=T*kBT*+&#916;S0|T=T*kB)(8)KCO2&#8594;CH3OH=P02PCH3OHeqPH2OeqPCO2eq(PH2eq)3=(P0Ptot)2&#966;CH3OHeq&#966;H2Oeq&#966;CO2eq(&#966;H2eq)3(9)Evaluation of catalyst properties at disparate conversion and reversibility values therefore risks convolution not only from concentration gradients and product inhibition (section 2.1) but also from chemical equilibria. Accordingly, we next outline mathematical protocols for the independent assessment of kinetic driving forces for reversible reaction systems without an a priori mechanistic understanding of the catalytic system of interest.Figure 2Figure 2. Simulated (a) overall reversibility and (b) carbon selectivity as a function of contact time during CO2 hydrogenation to methanol, CO, and ethanol on a hypothetical catalyst kinetically selective toward methanol (30 bar; 503 K; 1 a.u. total inlet flow rate; H2:CO2 = 3). (c) Calculated equilibrium carbon selectivity (30 bar; H2:CO2 = 3) as a function of temperature, where the methanol selectivity is too low to be observed in the figure. The result at 503 K is highlighted and expectedly consistent with selectivity from (b) in the limit of infinite contact time. Simulation details are provided in section S3 (SI).High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint Slide3.2. Assessment of Kinetic Driving ForcesWhile the observed net rate of an overall reaction (R) can be influenced by thermodynamic limitations, its constitutive forward and reverse components (R&#8407; and R&#8406;) are devoid of thermodynamic contributions and thus reflect intrinsic kinetic driving forces derived from catalyst characteristics (eq 7). The most direct method to ensure observed trends in R reflect the underlying kinetic behavior is thus to operate at conditions away from equilibrium, verifiable through effective reversibility values that are sufficiently far away from unity. We note that effective reversibilities as low as Zeff = 0.1, however, will already lead to net rates that are 90% of the forward rates (eq 7). Importantly, this condition on reversibility is not satisfied simply by operating at conversions that are sufficiently low such that bed-scale changes in reactant concentration can be approximated as differential; rather, it requires operating at a conversion that is low relative to the equilibrium conversion of the reactant, as previously alluded to by Zhao et al. (11) For example, for CO2 hydrogenation to methanol on a hypothetical catalyst where no product inhibition is present, a 3% conversion of CO2 to methanol at 10 bar total pressure and 523 K (H2:CO2 = 3) may qualify as "differential", yet the equilibrium conversion to methanol is 5.8% at these conditions. Thus, 3% CO2 conversion to methanol corresponds to Zov,CO2 &#8594; CH3OH = 0.25, and the observed methanol synthesis rate consequently only reflects 75% of the methanol synthesis forward rate (assuming Zeff &#8776; Zov). This reversibility value will further increase with the co-occurrence of other reactions such as RWGS or methanation that increase water concentration, thereby further decreasing observed rates relative to forward rates.In cases where maintaining low conversion and reversibility values across all reaction conditions is impractical and/or infeasible, forward rates can be extracted from observed rates by rearranging eq 7 to yieldR&#8594;=R1&#8722;ZeffandR&#8592;=RZeff1&#8722;Zeff(10)For plug flow reactors (PFRs), however, effluent R and Zeff reflect disparate length-scales, with the former constituting an average over the catalyst bed and the latter corresponding only to the instantaneous and local composition in the effluent (Scheme 3). Equation 10 therefore cannot be applied as written to measurements from PFRs, and the discrepancy between length-scales represented in R and Zeff must first be resolved by (i) determining the instantaneous TOF by differentiating conversion with respect to contact time (differential model) or (ii) averaging reversibility over contact time (integral model) (Scheme 3). (7) Approach (i) can be especially advantageous in systems exhibiting significant product inhibition (e.g., H2O inhibition for methanol synthesis) (3) where variations in forward TOF with contact time are of interest, while approach (ii) may be applicable to systems where the variation in forward TOF with contact time is insignificant (e.g., methane dehydroaromatization on Mo/H-ZSM-5). (12) Regardless, both approaches require knowledge of how species concentrations change along the catalyst bed but do not require a full microkinetic model, provided that concentration measurements over a range of contact times are sufficiently dense for numerical differentiation, numerical integration, or approximation with a model function. Only from deconvoluted R&#8407; and R&#8406; values can intrinsic catalytic rates be evaluated and any underlying structure&#8211;function relations elucidated.Scheme 3Scheme 3. Differential Model and Integral Model for the Evaluation of Kinetic and Thermodynamic Contributions to Rates and Selectivity in Plug Flow ReactorsHigh Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint Slide4. Visualizing Reaction Driving Forces through Energy DiagramsClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Computational chemistry consti</description>
      <author>Ting Lin, Elizabeth E. Bickel Rogers, Aditya Bhan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into Potassium-Assistant Thermal-Catalytic Oxidation of Soot over Single-Crystalline SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanotubes with Ordered Mesopores</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06289</link>
      <description>Fan Fang, Fang Xu, Xue Li, Chong Chen, Nengjie Feng, Yijiao Jiang, Jun Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405813818

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fan Fang, Fang Xu, Xue Li, Chong Chen, Nengjie Feng, Yijiao Jiang, Jun Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study on the Effect of Ethylene Cofeeding in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CO Hydrogenation to Olefins over FeZnNa Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06550</link>
      <description>K. Zhu, Xingwu Liu, Haoyi Tang, Shuheng Tian, Junzhong Xie, Lingzhen Zeng, Tianye Wang, Hongwei Li, Meng Wang, Ding Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405827567

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Zhu, Xingwu Liu, Haoyi Tang, Shuheng Tian, Junzhong Xie, Lingzhen Zeng, Tianye Wang, Hongwei Li, Meng Wang, Ding Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Enantioselective Construction of Oxazolidinone Rings via Enzymatic C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Amination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06066</link>
      <description>Jadab Majhi, Satyajit Roy, Anwita Chattopadhyay, Rudi Fasan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405829817

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jadab Majhi, Satyajit Roy, Anwita Chattopadhyay, Rudi Fasan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Coupling Reactions with Nickel, Visible Light, and &lt;i&gt;tert&lt;/i&gt;-Butylamine as a Bifunctional Additive</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07185</link>
      <description>Jonas D&#252;ker, Maximilian Philipp, Thomas Lentner, Jamie A. Cadge, Jo&#227;o E. A. Lavarda, Ruth M. Gschwind, Matthew S. Sigman, Indrajit Ghosh, Burkhard Koenig, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405831894

                Transition metal catalysis is crucial for the synthesis of complex molecules, with ligands and bases playing a pivotal role in optimizing cross-coupling reactions. Despite advancements in ligand design and base selection, achieving effective synergy between these components remains challenging. We present here a general approach to nickel-catalyzed photoredox reactions employing tert-butylamine as a cost-effective bifunctional additive, acting as the base and ligand. This method proves effective for C&#8211;O and C&#8211;N bond-forming reactions with a diverse array of nucleophiles, including phenols, aliphatic alcohols, anilines, sulfonamides, sulfoximines, and imines. Notably, the protocol demonstrates significant applicability in biomolecule derivatization and facilitates sequential one-pot functionalizations. Spectroscopic investigations revealed the robustness of the dynamic catalytic system, while elucidation of structure&#8211;reactivity relationships demonstrated how computed molecular properties of both the nucleophile and electrophile correlated to reaction performance, providing a foundation for effective reaction outcome prediction.</description>
      <author>Jonas D&#252;ker, Maximilian Philipp, Thomas Lentner, Jamie A. Cadge, Jo&#227;o E. A. Lavarda, Ruth M. Gschwind, Matthew S. Sigman, Indrajit Ghosh, Burkhard Koenig</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07185</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and Challenges for Catalytic Recycling and Upgrading of Real-World Mixed Plastic Waste</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06344</link>
      <description>Yawen Shi, Xinyong Diao, Na Ji, Hu Ding, Zongyang Ya, Dong Xu, Rui Wei, Kejiang Cao, Shengbo Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405843775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yawen Shi, Xinyong Diao, Na Ji, Hu Ding, Zongyang Ya, Dong Xu, Rui Wei, Kejiang Cao, Shengbo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Selectivity of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoreduction by Regulating the Location of PtCu in a UiO-66@ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Core&#8211;Shell Nanoreactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05717</link>
      <description>Zengrong Li, Peng Wang, Chun-Xia Ren, Linyi Wu, Yue Yao, Shuxian Zhong, Hongjun Lin, Leihong Zhao, Yijing Gao, Song Bai, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405853698

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zengrong Li, Peng Wang, Chun-Xia Ren, Linyi Wu, Yue Yao, Shuxian Zhong, Hongjun Lin, Leihong Zhao, Yijing Gao, Song Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05717</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Ordered Oxophilic Tin Sites on Platinum to Achieve a High-Performance and Anti-CO Poisoning Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction under an Alkaline Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06469</link>
      <description>Chaoyi Yang, Guangqin Wang, Jianchao Yue, Zhifeng Dai, Wei Luo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405867615

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoyi Yang, Guangqin Wang, Jianchao Yue, Zhifeng Dai, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Substrate Acceptance of Phenylalanine Amine Dehydrogenase Enables the Asymmetric Synthesis of Pharmaceutical &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Heterocyclic Primary Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06478</link>
      <description>Tao Wu, Yao Nie, Jiaxing Xu, Xiaoqing Mu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405883541

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Wu, Yao Nie, Jiaxing Xu, Xiaoqing Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Insights into Novel Thiolases for Enhancing the Production of Tailored Biochemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05635</link>
      <description>Jiyeon Hong, Hyeoncheol Francis Son, Soyoung Park, Jiyoung Park, Hogyun Seo, Kwang&#8208;Hyeon Liu, Kyung&#8208;Jin Kim, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405892706

                Thiolase is essential in the first step of synthesizing many value-added biochemicals. However, only a few feasible THLs have been reported, and a limited understanding of these enzymes has restricted their broader application in valuable production processes. In this study, biochemical and structural analysis identified the specific properties of THLs belonging to three groups for synthesizing medium- to long-chain fatty acids, polyketide, and dicarboxylic acid, represented by adipic acid. We further demonstrated that hydrolysis activity, considered a rate-limiting step in the biosynthetic process, can be alleviated through flux balance and site-directed mutagenesis. Notably, we discovered two THLs with strong biosynthetic abilities and low hydrolysis: PaTHL4, effective for medium- to long-chain fatty acids and polyketides, and PaTHL7, tailored for adipic acid production. This study provides valuable insights into tailored THLs for specific biochemical production.</description>
      <author>Jiyeon Hong, Hyeoncheol Francis Son, Soyoung Park, Jiyoung Park, Hogyun Seo, Kwang&#8208;Hyeon Liu, Kyung&#8208;Jin Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05635</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatics and Computationally Supported Redesign of Aspartase for &#946;-Alanine Synthesis by Acrylic Acid Hydroamination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05525</link>
      <description>Alejandro Gran&#8208;Scheuch, Hein J. Wijma, Nikolas Capra, Hugo L. van Beek, Milo&#353; Trajkovi&#263;, Kai Baldenius, Michael Breuer, A.M.W.H. Thunnissen, Dick B. Janssen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405896055

                Aspartate ammonia lyases catalyze the reversible amination of fumarate to l-aspartate. Recent studies demonstrate that the thermostable enzyme from Bacillus sp. YM55&#8211;1 (AspB) can be engineered for the enantioselective production of substituted &#946;-amino acids. This reaction would be attractive for the conversion of acrylic acid to &#946;-alanine, which is an important building block for the preparation of bioactive compounds. Here we describe a bioinformatics and computational approach aimed at introducing the &#946;-alanine synthesis activity. Three strategies were used: First, we redesigned the &#945;-carboxylate binding pocket of AspB to introduce activity with the acrylic acid. Next, different template enzymes were identified by genome mining, equipped with a redesigned &#945;-carboxylate pocket, and investigated for &#946;-alanine synthesis, which yielded variants with better activity. Third, interactions of the SS-loop that covers the active site and harbors a catalytic serine were computationally redesigned using energy calculations to stabilize reactive conformations and thereby further increase the desired &#946;-alanine synthesis activity. Different improved enzymes were obtained and the best variants showed kcat values with acrylic acid of at least 0.6&#8211;1.5 s&#8211;1 with KM values in the high mM range. Since the &#946;-alanine production of wild-type enzyme was below the detection limit, this suggests that the kcat/Km was improved by at least 1000-fold. Crystal structures of the 6-fold mutant of redesigned AspB and the similarly engineered aspartase from Caenibacillus caldisaponilyticus revealed that their ligand-free structures have the SS-loop in a closed (reactive) conformation, which for wild-type AspB is only observed in the substrate-bound enzyme. AlphaFold-generated models suggest that other aspartase variants redesigned for acrylic acid hydroamination also prefer a 3D structure with the loop in a closed conformation. The combination of binding pocket redesign, genome mining, and enhanced active-site loop closure thus created effective &#946;-alanine synthesizing variants of aspartase.</description>
      <author>Alejandro Gran&#8208;Scheuch, Hein J. Wijma, Nikolas Capra, Hugo L. van Beek, Milo&#353; Trajkovi&#263;, Kai Baldenius, Michael Breuer, A.M.W.H. Thunnissen, Dick B. Janssen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Radical Intermediates in Photoactivated Palladium-Catalyzed Coupling of Aryl Halides to Arenes by an Aryl Radical Assay</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06913</link>
      <description>Seb Tyerman, Donald Mackay, Kenneth Clark, Alan R. Kennedy, Craig M. Robertson, Laura Evans, Robert M. Edkins, John A. Murphy, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405908083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seb Tyerman, Donald Mackay, Kenneth Clark, Alan R. Kennedy, Craig M. Robertson, Laura Evans, Robert M. Edkins, John A. Murphy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Catalyzed Synthesis of Silaindanes via Sequential C&#8211;H Activating 1,5-Nickel Migration and C&#8211;Si Activating 1,4-Nickel Migration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06910</link>
      <description>Donghyeon Lee, Ikuya Fujii, Ryo Shintani, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405908160

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Donghyeon Lee, Ikuya Fujii, Ryo Shintani</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06910</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
