<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 01:24:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Pd-Catalyzed Dehydrogenation Enhanced by Charge Transfer from MoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Promoter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04684</link>
      <description>Byung Gwan Park, Jihyeon Lee, Yoojin Lee, Hyeongeon Lee, Jueun Kim, Eonu Nam, Jong&#8208;Seong Bae, Jeong Woo Han, Kwangjin An, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406317251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Byung Gwan Park, Jihyeon Lee, Yoojin Lee, Hyeongeon Lee, Jueun Kim, Eonu Nam, Jong&#8208;Seong Bae, Jeong Woo Han, Kwangjin An</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water-Controlled Coking Dynamics during High-Pressure Methanol-to-Olefins Reaction over SAPO-34</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06239</link>
      <description>Chengwei Zhang, Xinqiang Wu, Yanan Zhang, Li Wang, Yan Jin, Mingbin Gao, Mao Ye, Yingxu Wei, Zhongmin Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406321093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chengwei Zhang, Xinqiang Wu, Yanan Zhang, Li Wang, Yan Jin, Mingbin Gao, Mao Ye, Yingxu Wei, Zhongmin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate Promiscuity Engineering of ScALDO Enables a Versatile Minimized Enzyme Cascade for Efficient Utilization of Various Sugars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07497</link>
      <description>Shiming Tang, Z Y Zhang, Daocheng Liao, Ying Lin, Yuan&#8208;Yuan Huang, Suiping Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406327422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiming Tang, Z Y Zhang, Daocheng Liao, Ying Lin, Yuan&#8208;Yuan Huang, Suiping Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07497</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Specialization of a Promiscuous Designer Enzyme</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06409</link>
      <description>Reuben B. Leveson&#8208;Gower, Laura Tiessler&#8208;Sala, H.J. Rozeboom, A.M.W.H. Thunnissen, Jean&#8208;Didier Mar&#233;chal, G&#233;rard Roelfes, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406328950

                The evolution of a promiscuous enzyme for its various activities often results in catalytically specialized variants. This is an important natural mechanism to ensure the proper functioning of natural metabolic networks. It also acts as both a curse and blessing for enzyme engineers, where enzymes that have undergone directed evolution may exhibit exquisite selectivity at the expense of a diminished overall catalytic repertoire. We previously performed two independent directed evolution campaigns on a promiscuous designer enzyme that leverages the unique properties of a noncanonical amino acid (ncAA) para-aminophenylalanine (pAF) as catalytic residue, resulting in two evolved variants which are both catalytically specialized. Here, we combine mutagenesis, crystallography, and computation to reveal the molecular basis of the specialization phenomenon. In one evolved variant, an unexpected change in quaternary structure biases substrate dynamics to promote enantioselective catalysis, while the other demonstrates synergistic cooperation between natural side chains and the pAF residue to form semisynthetic catalytic machinery.</description>
      <author>Reuben B. Leveson&#8208;Gower, Laura Tiessler&#8208;Sala, H.J. Rozeboom, A.M.W.H. Thunnissen, Jean&#8208;Didier Mar&#233;chal, G&#233;rard Roelfes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-Catalyzed Chemoselective &#960;&#8211;&#963;&#8211;&#960;-Type Tandem Reductive Coupling to Access Isoquinolines via Carbocobaltation of Nitriles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07667</link>
      <description>Ling Tang, Xueyu Liu, Xintong Wang, Xianmao Liu, Xinmiao Huang, Ni Qian, Chen He, Gen Luo, Yuanhong Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406362720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Tang, Xueyu Liu, Xintong Wang, Xianmao Liu, Xinmiao Huang, Ni Qian, Chen He, Gen Luo, Yuanhong Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helix Zipper Regulating Formolase Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07452</link>
      <description>Zijian Tan, Zijing Tang, Hongli Wei, R.&#8208;H. Zhang, Ling Sun, Weidong Liu, Haifeng Liu, Leilei Zhu, Yanhe Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406362725

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zijian Tan, Zijing Tang, Hongli Wei, R.&#8208;H. Zhang, Ling Sun, Weidong Liu, Haifeng Liu, Leilei Zhu, Yanhe Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Ethylene Production through Enhanced Monomolecular &#946;-Scission in Confined Catalytic Cracking of Olefin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05323</link>
      <description>Yanfen Zuo, Lei Ye, Wenjie Yang, Bo Peng, Jing Zhang, Xingtian Shu, Youhao Xu, Jichang Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406369344

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanfen Zuo, Lei Ye, Wenjie Yang, Bo Peng, Jing Zhang, Xingtian Shu, Youhao Xu, Jichang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05323</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
