<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 01:09:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Electrosynthesis of Ethanol via Asymmetric C&#8211;C Coupling in Tandem CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01579</link>
      <description>Peng Luan, Xue Dong, Linqi Liu, Jianping Xiao, Pengfei Zhang, Jie Zhang, Haibo Chi, Qingnan Wang, Chunmei Ding, Rengui Li, Fengyuan Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398159967

                Selective electroreduction of CO2 to ethanol has economic value and environmental significance. However, the activity and selectivity of CO2 reduction toward ethanol are still low due to the sluggish kinetics of C&#8211;C coupling and the intense competition of hydrocarbon production. Herein, we report a layered tandem catalyst consisting of Cu nanosheets with a Cu(111)-oriented surface and Ag nanoparticles, which can effectively shift the selectivity from hydrocarbons to ethanol. The Faradaic efficiency of ethanol was improved from less than 30% on bare Cu(111) to 56.5 &#177; 2.6% on the layered Cu/Ag tandem catalysts, with a partial current density of 356.7 &#177; 9.5 mA cm&#8211;2. In situ Raman spectroscopy results and density functional theory calculations suggest that the high selectivity toward ethanol can be attributed to the asymmetric *CH2&#8211;CO coupling mechanism, which is facilitated by the selective generation of *CH2 species on (111)-facet-exposed Cu nanosheets and the high local CO concentration supplied by the Ag catalyst.</description>
      <author>Peng Luan, Xue Dong, Linqi Liu, Jianping Xiao, Pengfei Zhang, Jie Zhang, Haibo Chi, Qingnan Wang, Chunmei Ding, Rengui Li, Fengyuan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atmosphere-Dependent Strong Metal&#8211;Support Interactions in Au/ZnO Catalysts and Their Overlayer Permeability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02124</link>
      <description>Guandong Wu, Yiwei Jiang, Yiming Niu, Bingsen Zhang, Lin Li, Guoji Liu, Yufei He, Junhu Wang, Dianqing Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398162683

                The oxidative strong metal&#8211;support interaction (O-SMSI) emerges as a pioneering approach for promoting the formation of overlayers, which has garnered significant interest in the exploration of the synthesis of O-SMSI materials. However, the manipulation of the overlayer is rarely discussed and presents a challenge due to its trace presence on the nanoparticle (NP) surface, which impedes the development and utilization of the O-SMSI. In this work, we demonstrate a strong correlation between the treatment atmosphere and the state of the permeable overlayer in the Au/ZnO catalyst. The ZnO overlayer can be formed in both oxidative and inert atmospheres, but the permeability of the overlayer occurs under an oxidative atmosphere. The difference in the permeabilities of the overlayer, at similar particle sizes, leads to a reaction rate difference of approximately 1.4 times. While the permeability of the ZnO overlayer is improved by an oxidative atmosphere treatment, it is also accompanied by an increase in the geometric strain in the ZnO matrix. The permeable ZnO formation is related to the process of gold species insertion into the ZnO matrix, as indicated by density functional theory calculations. This study is the first to describe the role of O2 in manipulating the O-SMSI and suboxide overlayers, offering a potential method for surface engineering.</description>
      <author>Guandong Wu, Yiwei Jiang, Yiming Niu, Bingsen Zhang, Lin Li, Guoji Liu, Yufei He, Junhu Wang, Dianqing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemosphere-Inspired Irradiation Reallocation Strategy Based on Mie Theory for Stable CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoreduction over Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05802</link>
      <description>Tongyu Wang, Kuan Deng, Hailing Huo, Chelsea X. Huang, Yiqin Du, Ming-Yuan Yu, Jingjing Ma, Erjun Kan, Ang Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398164278

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tongyu Wang, Kuan Deng, Hailing Huo, Chelsea X. Huang, Yiqin Du, Ming-Yuan Yu, Jingjing Ma, Erjun Kan, Ang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic and Kinetic Insights into Intermolecular [2+2] Photocycloadditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01678</link>
      <description>Gina Quach, Hasti Iranmanesh, Ena T. Luis, Jason B. Harper, Jonathon E. Beves, Evan G. Moore, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398164282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gina Quach, Hasti Iranmanesh, Ena T. Luis, Jason B. Harper, Jonathon E. Beves, Evan G. Moore</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of Cyclopropanes via CuH-Catalyzed Intramolecular Hydroalkylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02119</link>
      <description>Giovanni Lonardi, Santiago Franco, Mattia Sartorello, Carla De Faveri, Mariano Stivanello, Giulia Licini, Manuel Orlandi, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398172089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Giovanni Lonardi, Santiago Franco, Mattia Sartorello, Carla De Faveri, Mariano Stivanello, Giulia Licini, Manuel Orlandi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Chiral Polycyclic Indoles via Pd(II)-Catalyzed Sequential Cyclization and Carbonylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01325</link>
      <description>Long Chen, Hongyou Zhou, Yuan Xue, Lingyu Kong, Yi Wang, Xuyao Han, Hequan Yao, Aijun Lin, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398176145

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Long Chen, Hongyou Zhou, Yuan Xue, Lingyu Kong, Yi Wang, Xuyao Han, Hequan Yao, Aijun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secondary Alcohol-Driven &#945;-Olefination and &#945;-Alkylation of Nitriles: Introducing a Heterogeneous Ru&#8211;Fe Bimetallic Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01383</link>
      <description>Tianyu Li, Yue-Yi Da, Jing Chen, Zongyan Ma, Yu Jin, Jiantai Ma, Rong Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398210898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianyu Li, Yue-Yi Da, Jing Chen, Zongyan Ma, Yu Jin, Jiantai Ma, Rong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01383</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Excited State Photocatalysis: Divergent Energy Transfer vs Lewis Acid Mediated Phototransformations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01185</link>
      <description>Jayachandran Parthiban, Dipti Garg, Sapna Ahuja, Steffen Jockusch, Angel Ugrinov, Jayaraman Sivaguru, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398211034

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jayachandran Parthiban, Dipti Garg, Sapna Ahuja, Steffen Jockusch, Angel Ugrinov, Jayaraman Sivaguru</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01185</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemoenzymatic Sequential Catalysis with Carbonic Anhydrase for the Synthesis of Chiral Alcohols from Alkanes, Alkenes, and Alkynes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02481</link>
      <description>Zhenzhong Li, Zhonghui Wan, Wei Wang, Lihong Chen, Pengfei Ji, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398222184

                Chiral alcohols are important intermediates for various fine chemicals and pharmaceuticals. Integrating chemical catalysis and efficient enzyme catalysis in sequential systems for the synthesis of chiral alcohols is considered an ecofriendly and promising approach. Herein, employing a highly selective carbonic anhydrase II and different chemical catalysts, we constructed three general chemoenzymatic sequential systems for chiral alcohol compound synthesis from alkanes, alkenes, and alkynes, respectively. Compared to classical approaches, the combination of chemical catalysis and promiscuous carbonic anhydrase catalysis is simple and efficient since it requires only mild reaction conditions and avoids expensive chiral ligands and cumbersome operation steps. In this integrated approach, a wide variety of readily available aryl alkanes, alkenes, and alkynes are transformed into valuable chiral alcohols with excellent enantioselectivity of up to 99% (nearly all above 90%). This unified strategy of combining enzymatic and chemical catalyses advances the general chemoenzymatic process for powerful and important chemical transformations.</description>
      <author>Zhenzhong Li, Zhonghui Wan, Wei Wang, Lihong Chen, Pengfei Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#946;-Silicon Effect Enables Metal-Free Site-Selective Intermolecular Allylic C&#8211;H Amination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02393</link>
      <description>Shuang Lin, Yuan Liu, Gao Kun-yu, Zhihao Chen, Jiasheng Qian, Xiaobin Liu, Qingjiang Li, Honggen Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398248046

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuang Lin, Yuan Liu, Gao Kun-yu, Zhihao Chen, Jiasheng Qian, Xiaobin Liu, Qingjiang Li, Honggen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Precise Control of Silver Species Encaged in Zeolite Catalysts with Minimal Loading for Maximal Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01972</link>
      <description>Mengxi Han, Yi He, Tongwen Yu, Pai Peng, Jiangwei Shi, Hongxia Liu, Lei Liu, Chenliang Ye, Qiang Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398249717

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengxi Han, Yi He, Tongwen Yu, Pai Peng, Jiangwei Shi, Hongxia Liu, Lei Liu, Chenliang Ye, Qiang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation Effects on the Adsorbed Intermediates of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Are Systematic and Predictable</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00727</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Sargeant, Paramaconi Rodr&#237;guez, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398251204

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Sargeant, Paramaconi Rodr&#237;guez, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Understanding of Anthracene Hydrocracking over HY Zeolite Encapsulated Single-Atom Pt Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01706</link>
      <description>Wenru Zhao, Hui Yu, Shaozhong Peng, Wei Liu, Weiwei Zhang, Donghai Mei, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398251226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenru Zhao, Hui Yu, Shaozhong Peng, Wei Liu, Weiwei Zhang, Donghai Mei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Temperature Thermocatalytic Coupling of CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Ethanol over Zn&#8211;Ce/ZSM-5 by a Stepwise Technique</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00863</link>
      <description>Yongjun Liu, Chaoyu Zhang, Ruijia Wang, Yixiao Wu, Xueyu Zan, Tao Shen, Wei Huang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398251514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongjun Liu, Chaoyu Zhang, Ruijia Wang, Yixiao Wu, Xueyu Zan, Tao Shen, Wei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of Electrochemical Nitrogen Reduction Activity and Suppression of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction for Transition Metal Oxide Catalysts: The Role of Proton Intercalation and Heteroatom Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00223</link>
      <description>Qingdong Li, Oguz Kaan Kucukosman, Qingquan Ma, Junjie Ouyang, Pavel Kucheryavy, Hengfei Gu, Conor Long, Z. Y. Zhang, Joshua Young, Jenny V. Lockard, Eric Garfunkel, Jianan Gao, Zhang Wen, Huixin He, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398764852

                During the electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (eNRR) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), interstitial proton intercalation readily occurs in some transition metal oxide (TMO) catalysts and changes their d-band electronic structure. This work fabricated phosphorus (P)-doped tungsten oxide (WO3) with enriched oxygen vacancies (OVs) to study the impact of proton intercalation and heteroatom doping on eNRR and HER. Our results demonstrated that the electronic structure of the P-OV-WO3 catalyst was altered by in situ proton intercalation as indicated by the greater negative onset potential of eNRR at &#8722;0.05 V compared to the proton intercalation potential of 0.3 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). Compared to the non-P-doped WO3, the introduction of P doping in WO3 (e.g., 4.8 at. %) led to a reduction of more than 36% in proton intercalation. As a result, the HER activity of the P-OV-WO3 was significantly suppressed, as demonstrated by a considerably negative shift of the onset HER potential from &#8722;0.06 to &#8722;0.15 V and a slower HER kinetics with the Tafel slope increased from 129.0 to 343.1 mV/dec. Density functional theory calculations revealed the synergy of the proton intercalation, substitutional P doping, and the associated OVs in the improvement of N2 activation and hydrogenation in eNRR. The increased eNRR and the suppressed HER led to a high Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 64.1% and the NH3 yield of 24.5 &#956;g&#183;mg cat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.15 V versus RHE in H2SO4 (pH = 2) as the electrolyte. The specific NH3 yield is more than 20 times higher than that of C-WO3 (1.1 &#956;g&#183;mg cat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 with a FE of 20%). The results exceed most of the reported eNRR performances for TMO-based catalysts. Thus, the synergistic proton intercalation and P doping could lead to newer designs and applications of TMO-based catalysts for improved eNRR while suppressing the competing HER.</description>
      <author>Qingdong Li, Oguz Kaan Kucukosman, Qingquan Ma, Junjie Ouyang, Pavel Kucheryavy, Hengfei Gu, Conor Long, Z. Y. Zhang, Joshua Young, Jenny V. Lockard, Eric Garfunkel, Jianan Gao, Zhang Wen, Huixin He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Transition Metal Atom Catalyst for a High-Performance Li&#8211;S Battery with a Graphdiyne&#8211;Graphene Heterostructure Host: A DFT Investigation + ML Predictions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02066</link>
      <description>V G Abhijitha, Rohit Batra, B. R. K. Nanda, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398778565

                Shuttling of lithium polysulfides (LiPSs) and slow kinetics of the sulfur reduction reaction (SRR) are considered as the major roadblocks for achieving high-performance lithium&#8211;sulfur batteries (LSBs). The solution lies in optimizing the binding strength of LiPSs and catalyzing the SRR. In this work, with the aid of density functional theory calculations, ab initio molecular dynamics simulation, and machine learning (ML), we show that a heterostructure made out of graphene (Gra) and transition metal (TM) atom-anchored graphdiyne (GDY) effectively addresses both these issues. Our results show that the large triangular pores of GDY allow easy penetration of Li+ ions into the sulfur-intercalated TM-GDY/Gra heterostructures and result in LiPSs. The sparsely distributed TM atoms on the GDY surface tune the binding strength of LiPSs and act as catalysts for SRR. Based on the binding strength of LiPSs, TM atom catalysts are categorized into strong, moderate, and weak. Gibbs's free-energy calculations reveal that heterostructures with moderate binding strength are best suited for SRR catalytic activity with barriers smaller than &#8764;0.4 eV. Furthermore, a Li2S decomposition barrier for the charging process is 3 times lower in the moderate class compared to pristine Gra. Feature importance analysis based on a gradient boosting regression ML model shows that the binding strength of LiPSs in the heterostructures is closely related to intrinsic electronic properties of TM and sulfur atoms, i.e., valence electronic configuration of the TM atom, electronegativity ratio of S to TM atom, and ionic radii of TM and S atoms. Furthermore, it also reveals that the energy barriers for the elementary steps of the SRR are related to the difference in the binding strength of LiPSs corresponding to the conversion step. This study elucidates the suitability of moderate binding heterostructures for LSBs; Fe, Co, Mn, and Rh are preferred single-atom catalysts to serve the purpose.</description>
      <author>V G Abhijitha, Rohit Batra, B. R. K. Nanda</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Adsorption of Intermediates via the Sulfur Modulating Dual-Atomic Sites for Boosting CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02098</link>
      <description>Kai Huang, Ru Li, Qi Hu, Shuai Yang, Shuhao An, Cheng Lian, Qing Xu, Honglai Liu, Jun Hu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398783341

                The formation of dual-atom catalysts or heteroatom ligand modulation is the most promising strategy for optimizing single&#8211;atom catalysts (SACs) for the more efficient conversion of CO2 to valuable chemicals. However, heteroatom ligands introduced into the dual-atomic sites are expected but still under-explored. In this study, a dual-atom Fe&#8211;Ni pair electrocatalyst with N&#8211; and S&#8211;coordination in porous carbon nanosheets was conceptually predicted for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CO (CO2RR). In contrast to SACs and traditional diatomic catalysts (DACs), joined S&#8211;coordination can balance the cooperative activities of Fe and Ni sites, making the CO2 adsorption configuration bidentate at both Fe&#8211;Ni sites. This regulation leads to a substantial change in CO* adsorption from Fe to Ni sites, facilitating CO desorption and boosting the electrocatalytic CO2RR. Experimental results demonstrate that the obtained FeNi&#8211;NSC catalyst achieves high selectivity with the Faradaic efficiencies for CO of 96.1%, and a remarkable activity with the turnover frequency of 6526.9 h&#8211;1 at &#8722;1.0 V, which were over 4.5 and 2.5 times of those from the single Fe or Ni sites. This work gives us insight into designing highly effective catalysts guided by theoretical calculation.</description>
      <author>Kai Huang, Ru Li, Qi Hu, Shuai Yang, Shuhao An, Cheng Lian, Qing Xu, Honglai Liu, Jun Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biocatalytic Heteroaromatic Amide Formation in Water Enabled by a Catalytic Tetrad and Two Access Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01268</link>
      <description>E. Zukic, Daniel Mokos, Min&#233;ia Weber, Niklas Stix, Klaus Ditrich, Virgilio F. Ferrario, Henrik M&#252;ller, Christian Willrodt, Karl Gruber, Bastian Daniel, Wolfgang Kroutil, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399010432

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. Zukic, Daniel Mokos, Min&#233;ia Weber, Niklas Stix, Klaus Ditrich, Virgilio F. Ferrario, Henrik M&#252;ller, Christian Willrodt, Karl Gruber, Bastian Daniel, Wolfgang Kroutil</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01268</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Oxidation of Primary Alcohols at the Triple-Phase Boundary in an Anion-Exchange Membrane Reactor with Nickel, Cobalt, and Iron Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01097</link>
      <description>Yuka Furutani, Yoshihisa Shimizu, Juri Harada, Yusuke Muto, Akizumi Yonezawa, Shoji Iguchi, Naoki Shida, Mahito Atobe, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399049783

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuka Furutani, Yoshihisa Shimizu, Juri Harada, Yusuke Muto, Akizumi Yonezawa, Shoji Iguchi, Naoki Shida, Mahito Atobe</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01097</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
