<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 01:27:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Mechanism of SARS-CoV-2 3-Chymotrypsin-Like Protease as Determined by Steady-State and Pre-Steady-State Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04695</link>
      <description>Jiyun Zhu, A. Kemp, Balachandra Chenna, Vivek Kumar, Andrew Rademacher, Sangho Yun, Arthur Laganowsky, Thomas D. Meek, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404762047

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiyun Zhu, A. Kemp, Balachandra Chenna, Vivek Kumar, Andrew Rademacher, Sangho Yun, Arthur Laganowsky, Thomas D. Meek</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Corrosive Cl&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;-Induced Rapid Surface Reconstruction of Amorphous NiFeCoP Enables Efficient Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05704</link>
      <description>Yang Yu, Wei Zhou, Xiaohan Zhou, Junshu Yuan, Xuewei Zhang, Sheng Wang, Jingyu Li, Xiaoxiao Meng, Fei Sun, Jihui Gao, Guangbo Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404772438

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Yu, Wei Zhou, Xiaohan Zhou, Junshu Yuan, Xuewei Zhang, Sheng Wang, Jingyu Li, Xiaoxiao Meng, Fei Sun, Jihui Gao, Guangbo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Conversion of Biomass and Nitrate into Glycine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05235</link>
      <description>Peifeng Li, Biaobiao Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404799850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peifeng Li, Biaobiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Analysis of Cyclization by the Substrate-Tolerant Lanthipeptide Synthetase ProcM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06216</link>
      <description>Emily K. Desormeaux, Garrett J. Barksdale, Wilfred A. van der Donk, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404834790

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Emily K. Desormeaux, Garrett J. Barksdale, Wilfred A. van der Donk</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Investigations of MUC1 O-Glycosylation Process Reveal Initial Site Preference by the Polypeptide GalNAc Transferases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05719</link>
      <description>Han Zhang, Kaiyuan Song, Yihan Liu, Fang Yang, Congcong Lu, Rumeng Wei, Zhijue Xu, Xia Zou, Liang Lin, Ting Shi, Lin&#8208;Tai Da, Yan Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404843611

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Han Zhang, Kaiyuan Song, Yihan Liu, Fang Yang, Congcong Lu, Rumeng Wei, Zhijue Xu, Xia Zou, Liang Lin, Ting Shi, Lin&#8208;Tai Da, Yan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05719</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Surface and Penetrating Carbon in Fe-Based Catalysts to Balance the Activity and Stability of Fischer&#8211;Tropsch Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06014</link>
      <description>Xiaoxue Han, Shouying Huang, Chongyang Wei, Haoting Liang, Jing Lv, Yue Wang, Mei&#8208;Yan Wang, Yong Wang, Xinbin Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404857137

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoxue Han, Shouying Huang, Chongyang Wei, Haoting Liang, Jing Lv, Yue Wang, Mei&#8208;Yan Wang, Yong Wang, Xinbin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Transformation of Hydrazones via Remote NHC Catalysis: Activation Across C&#9552;N and N&#8211;N Bonds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06029</link>
      <description>Jiamiao Jin, Ya Lv, Wenli Tang, Kunpeng Teng, Yixian Huang, Jingxin Ding, Tingting Li, Guanjie Wang, Yonggui Robin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404877553

                The catalytic asymmetric transformation of nitrogen atoms to prepare heterocyclic molecules is of significant value in organic synthesis and biological applications. Here, we disclose the activation of the nitrogen atom in hydrazine-derived hydrazone via an N-heterocyclic carbene (NHC) organic catalyst for highly enantioselective formal cycloaddition reactions. The range of NHC catalysis extends across several (carbon and hetero) atoms and diverse chemical bonds (C&#9552;N and N&#8211;N bonds) to activate nitrogen atoms at remote sites with excellent reactivity and (stereo)selectivity control. Our strategy for nitrogen atom activation, along with the NHC-bound diaza-diene intermediate generated during the catalytic process, offers alternative solutions for organic synthesis.</description>
      <author>Jiamiao Jin, Ya Lv, Wenli Tang, Kunpeng Teng, Yixian Huang, Jingxin Ding, Tingting Li, Guanjie Wang, Yonggui Robin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Uncovering Hydroxynitrile Lyase Variants with Promiscuous Diastereoselective Nitroaldolase Activity toward the Highly Stereocontrolled Synthesis of &lt;i&gt;Anti&lt;/i&gt; &#946;-Nitroalcohols&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06888</link>
      <description>Ayon Chaterjee, G. Priyanka, N. Prakash Prabhu, Santosh Kumar Padhi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404905332

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef.SI ACS CatalysisASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse ORIGINAL ARTICLE. This notice is a correction.Addition/CorrectionDecember 2, 2024Correction to "Uncovering Hydroxynitrile Lyase Variants with Promiscuous Diastereoselective Nitroaldolase Activity toward the Highly Stereocontrolled Synthesis of Anti &#946;-Nitroalcohols"Click to copy article linkArticle link copied!Ayon ChaterjeeAyon ChaterjeeMore by Ayon ChaterjeeG. PriyankaG. PriyankaMore by G. PriyankaN. Prakash PrabhuN. Prakash PrabhuMore by N. Prakash Prabhuhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-3024-1142Santosh Kumar Padhi*Santosh Kumar PadhiMore by Santosh Kumar Padhihttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-5202-6702Open PDFSupporting Information (1)ACS CatalysisCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, XXX, 18406&#8211;18407Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acscatal.4c06888https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06888Published December 2, 2024 Publication History Received 8 November 2024Published online 2 December 2024correction&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyIt has come to our attention that the kinetic parameters were erroneously calculated during the change of their units from the data presented in the Supporting Information to the main article. While the Supporting Information correctly represented the kinetic parameters (Figure S76 and Figure S77), the units (KM in mM, kcat in min&#8211;1, and kcat /KM in min&#8211;1 mM&#8211;1) are different from those in the main article (Table 1, Page 12626). The corrected Table 1 and its corresponding description (Kinetic Studies, Page 12629) (corrections are in bold) as well as the corrected sections of the Supporting Information (Figure S76 and Figure S77) are provided with this Correction. It is important to note that these modified parameters do not impact any of the conclusions drawn in the original article.In addition, we erroneously typed T14 to represent the Y14 in Figure S85A and Figure S86A of the Supporting Information. The corrected figures are provided in the Supporting Information with this Correction.Kinetic StudiesClick to copy section linkSection link copied!In order to gain insights of kinetics information about the DHR, both the variants, Y14C and Y14A, along with the wild-type enzyme were taken for evaluation. The steady-state kinetic parameters of Y14C toward the synthesis of (1R,2S)-1a were determined by measuring the initial velocities against different concentrations of 1. In comparison to the wild-type, Y14C exhibited &gt;88-fold improved kcat, and &#8764;3-fold reduced KM (Table 1, Figure S77A,B). The single variant elicited a remarkable increase in catalytic efficiency of &gt;250-fold than the wild-type, as kcat/KM of Y14C and the wild-type were found to be 5.01 and 0.02 s&#8211;1 M&#8211;1, respectively. The kinetic parameters for Y14A toward (1R,2S)-9b were kcat = 0.06 s&#8211;1, KM = 40.2 mM (Table 1, Figure S77C). Selection of 9 for this study was based on the highest catalytic activity and stereoselectivity of Y14A achieved during asymmetric addition of 1-nitropropane to this substrate (Figure 4). Unfortunately, the kinetic data of the wild-type was not possible to measure toward the synthesis of 9b due to its extremely low activity. The catalytic efficiency (kcat/KM) of Y14A was found to be 1.49 s&#8211;1 M&#8211;1. Even though it is unfair to compare, the catalytic efficiency of Y14A toward (1R,2S)-9b, which is assumed to be highest among the molecules of Figure 4, appeared to be &#8764;3.5-fold less than the catalytic efficiency of Y14C toward the synthesis of 1a. The former case has demonstrated a &#8764;2-fold reduced kcat along with increased KM compared with data for the latter. This explains the overall reduced biocatalytic conversion to 1-nitropropane based &#946;-nitroalcohols as compared to nitroethane based &#946;-nitroalcohols. Due to lack of similar data the kinetics parameters could not be compared with other HNLs. However, the catalytic efficiency (kcat/KM) of Y14C catalyzed synthesis of 1a is &gt;580-fold and Y14A catalyzed synthesis of 9b is &gt;720-fold lower than the catalytic efficiency of one of the best AtHNL variants (F179N) toward nitromethane addition to 1 or 9.70 This suggests that stereoselective addition of longer nitroalkanes remains a challenge despite the use of the same aldehyde, 1 in the asymmetric Henry reaction.Table 1. Kinetic Data of Wild-Type AtHNL and Variants toward 1a and 9b SynthesisaEnzymeAldehydeNucleophilepHKM (mM)kcat (s&#8211;1)kcat/KM (s&#8211;1 M&#8211;1)wild-type1a5.570.12 &#177; 5.931.4 &#215; 10&#8211;3 &#177; 7.6 &#215; 10&#8211;50.02 &#177; 0.001Y14C1a5.525.14 &#177; 3.470.126 &#177; 0.0195.01 &#177; 0.16Wild-type1a8.276.85 &#177; 2.665.2 &#215; 10&#8211;4 &#177; 7 &#215; 10&#8211;50.0068 &#177; 0.0009Y14C1a8.256.87 &#177; 3.820.38 &#177; 0.0426.6 &#177; 0.73Wild-type9b5.5ndndndY14A9b5.540.2 &#177; 2.880.06 &#177; 0.0041.49 &#177; 0.1aThe Michaelis&#8211;Menten plots are shown in Figures S77 and S78. Each value represents the average of three independent measurements. nd: not determined.Supporting InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!The Supporting Information is available free of charge at https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acscatal.4c06888.Corrected versions of Figures S77, S78, S85, and S86 (PDF)cs4c06888_si_001.pdf (125.89 kb) Terms &amp; Conditions Most electronic Supporting Information files are available without a subscription to ACS Web Editions. Such files may be downloaded by article for research use (if there is a public use license linked to the relevant article, that license may permit other uses). Permission may be obtained from ACS for other uses through requests via the RightsLink permission system: http://pubs.acs.org/page/copyright/permissions.html. Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorSantosh Kumar Padhi; https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5202-6702; Email: AuthorsAyon ChaterjeeG. PriyankaN. Prakash Prabhu; https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3024-1142Cited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferencesSupporting Information Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsACS CatalysisCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, XXX, 18406&#8211;18407Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06888Published December 2, 2024 Publication History Received 8 November 2024Published online 2 December 2024&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesSupporting InfoThis publication has no figures.This publication has no References.Supporting InformationSupporting InformationThe Supporting Information is available free of charge at https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acscatal.4c06888.Corrected versions of Figures S77, S78, S85, and S86 (PDF)cs4c06888_si_001.pdf (125.89 kb) Terms &amp; Conditions Most electronic Supporting Information files are available without a subscription to ACS Web Editions. Such files may be downloaded by article for research use (if there is a public use license linked to the relevant article, that license may permit other uses). Permission may be obtained from ACS for other uses through requests via the RightsLink permission system: http://pubs.acs.org/page/copyright/permissions.html.</description>
      <author>Ayon Chaterjee, G. Priyanka, N. Prakash Prabhu, Santosh Kumar Padhi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Cubic versus Octahedral Morphology in Plasmonic Aluminum Nanoparticle Synthesis with Titanocene Catalysts: A Systematic Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06286</link>
      <description>Jae&#8208;Kwan Kim, Christian R. Jacobson, Naomi J. Halas, Ian A. Tonks, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404913495

                Ti precatalysts containing the titanocene moiety (Cp2Ti&#8211;, Cp = cyclopentadienyl) can, under certain conditions, selectively produce cubic Al nanocrystals through the dehydrocoupling of alane amine adducts such as AlH3&#183;NMe2Et. A systematic study of reaction conditions reveals that cubic Al nanoparticle formation occurs at a higher temperature (e.g., 65 &#176;C) and/or higher catalyst-concentration conditions (e.g., 0.5 mol % [Ti]). Kinetic studies reveal that under these conditions nanoparticle formation and alane consumption are much faster, and cubic nanoparticle formation takes place under kinetically controlled conditions. On the other hand, employing a wide suite of TiX4 (X = anionic ligand)-type precatalysts yielded only octahedral-shaped aluminum nanoparticles regardless of conditions. Finally, we report the synthesis of a hydride-bridged Ti&#8211;Al heterobimetallic compound from the reaction of Cp2TiCl2 with AlH3&#183;NMe2Et and characterized it to show that it is a reaction intermediate in the Ti-catalyzed aluminum nanoparticle synthesis.</description>
      <author>Jae&#8208;Kwan Kim, Christian R. Jacobson, Naomi J. Halas, Ian A. Tonks</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effectively Regulating Electrooxidation of Formic Acid over Bimetallic PtCo Alloys via the Integration of Theory and Experiment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06198</link>
      <description>Zhikeng Zheng, Bin Liu, Jiaxiang Qiu, Shaojun Xu, Yuchen Wang, Man Zhang, Ke Li, Zhongti Sun, Ziang Li, Yangyang Wan, C. Richard A. Catlow, Kai Yan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404831841

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhikeng Zheng, Bin Liu, Jiaxiang Qiu, Shaojun Xu, Yuchen Wang, Man Zhang, Ke Li, Zhongti Sun, Ziang Li, Yangyang Wan, C. Richard A. Catlow, Kai Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Coordination Environment of Cu Single Atoms for Achieving Regioselective C&#8211;C Bond Activation of Amides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05223</link>
      <description>Wunengerile Zhang, Chaolumen Bai, Dan Liu, Agula Bao, Tegshi Muschin, Yong&#8208;Sheng Bao, Jin Xie, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404917578

                C&#8211;C bond activation can provide a direct reconstruction strategy of carbon skeletons to furnish a number of structurally diverse molecules. In general, regioselectivity represents the state-of-the-art owing to the existence of several different carbon&#8211;carbon bonds, having a high BDE, &#8764;90 kcal/mol. Here, we report a directed strategy for amides for the concise synthesis of a range of urea derivatives and carbamates via regioselective C&#8211;C bond activation enabled by the heterogeneous single-atom copper catalyst (Cu-SAC), with a turnover frequency of 249 h&#8211;1, which is 19 times higher than that of the analogous homogeneous copper catalyst. Multitechnique characterization data show that single-atom Cu species are associated with an unsaturated coordination structure and plentiful oxygen vacancies on &#947;-Al2O3 that facilitate the adsorption of multiple coordinated amides and dioxygen, leading to high catalytic activity and selectivity. It would offer opportunities to speed up the heterogenized process of homogeneous catalysts in regioselective inert-bond activation reactions.</description>
      <author>Wunengerile Zhang, Chaolumen Bai, Dan Liu, Agula Bao, Tegshi Muschin, Yong&#8208;Sheng Bao, Jin Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru(II)-Catalyzed [1,4]-Sigmatropic Rearrangement and Intramolecular Concerted S&lt;sub&gt;N&lt;/sub&gt;Ar of Aryl and Heteroarylthio Derivatives using Quinoid Carbene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05272</link>
      <description>Subarna Pan, Md. Saimuddin Sk, B. SANYAL, Lisa Roy, Rajarshi Samanta, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404917688

                A Ru(II)-catalyzed straightforward and efficient strategy has been developed to construct O-alkylated arylnaphthyl thioether derivatives using arylthioacetates/arylalkylthioethers with diazonaphthoquinone via a [1,4]-oxa sigmatropic rearrangement. In a complementary method, heteroaryl thioacetate/heteroaryl alkylthioethers offer O-heteroaryl alkylnaphthyl thioether derivatives via an interesting concerted intramolecular SNAr-type reaction. Both of these methods proceed through the formation of Ru-based quinoid carbene and sulfur ylide, respectively. A detailed mechanistic study and DFT calculations reveal that the reaction is going via a concerted manner. Postsynthetic modifications of the synthesized compounds led to sulfur-containing polyaromatic heterocycles.</description>
      <author>Subarna Pan, Md. Saimuddin Sk, B. SANYAL, Lisa Roy, Rajarshi Samanta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Carboxylation of Terminal Alkynes with CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; over Metal&#8211;Porphyrin Framework Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06006</link>
      <description>Yanyue Wang, Jianling Zhang, Sha Wang, Zhonghao Tan, Yisen Yang, Yingzhe Zhao, Buxing Han, Qian Li, Junfeng Xiang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404920674

                To develop an environmentally benign and efficient route for converting CO2 into value-added chemicals is of great importance. Here, we demonstrate the photocatalytic carboxylation of terminal alkynes with CO2 at room temperature and atmospheric pressure, by copper-based porphyrinic framework photocatalysts Cu2TCPP(M) (TCPP = 5,10,15,20-tetrakis(4-carboxyphenyl)porphyrin; M = Fe, Co, Ni, Cu). The Cu2TCPP(Cu) nanosheets (with a small thickness of &#8764;5.1 nm) exhibit an extremely high performance for the reaction of 1-ethynylbenzene with CO2 to produce 3-phenylpropiolic acid. The turnover frequency is up to 3.33 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 at 10 h, which is much higher than those of the photothermally and thermally driven routes that are usually adopted for the carboxylation reactions catalyzed by metal&#8211;organic frameworks. The mechanism for the superior activity of Cu2TCPP(Cu) nanosheets was investigated by a series of experiments and theoretical calculations. It is revealed that the Cu2TCPP(Cu) nanosheets not only possess good photoelectronic properties but have desired molecular structure for boosting CO2 activation, alkyne activation, and carboxylation reactions.</description>
      <author>Yanyue Wang, Jianling Zhang, Sha Wang, Zhonghao Tan, Yisen Yang, Yingzhe Zhao, Buxing Han, Qian Li, Junfeng Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disrupted Spin Degeneracy Promoted C&#8801;C Triple Bond Activation for Efficient Electrochemical Acetylene Semihydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06191</link>
      <description>Menglei Yuan, Hongyu Jiang, Ruyi Jiang, Zhao Wang, Zhihao Zhao, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Jian Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404924221

                Disrupting the spin degeneracy of the electrocatalyst and further manipulating the related orbital electron arrangement are highly desirable for activating acetylene molecules. Herein, a squarate cobalt-based metal&#8211;organic framework (Co-MOF) ([Co3(C4O4)2(OH)2]&#183;3H2O) is post-treated to accelerate the evolution from CoO6 octahedron to CoO5 pentahedron and further utilized for the electrochemical acetylene semihydrogenation reaction. Comprehensive analyses corroborate that the disrupted spin degeneracy of active sites originated from the breakage of the Co&#8211;O bond, which promotes the cleavage of the orbital energy level and the rearrangement of the d-orbital electron. The newly emerged half-occupied dx2&#8211;y2 orbitals and empty dz2 orbitals in CoO5 pentahedron concerted interplay with the bonding and antibonding orbitals of acetylene, which reduces the adsorption energy of acetylene and facilitates the activation of the inert C&#8801;C triple bond. Thus, the defective Co-MOF exhibits the superior ethylene Faradaic efficiency of 96% and partial current density of 128 mA cm&#8211;2 at &#8722;1.0 V vs RHE compared to that of pristine Co-MOF (FEC2H4: 60%; JC2H4: 66 mA cm&#8211;2). This work delivers inspiration for spin-state regulation of active sites and sparks renewed interest in designing highly efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Menglei Yuan, Hongyu Jiang, Ruyi Jiang, Zhao Wang, Zhihao Zhao, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence-Driven Development of Nickel-Catalyzed Enantioselective Cross-Coupling Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04277</link>
      <description>Yadong Gao, Kunjun Hu, Jianhang Rao, Qiang Zhu, Kuangbiao Liao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404941646

                The conventional approach to developing asymmetric synthetic methods relies heavily on empirical optimization. However, the integration of artificial intelligence (AI) and high-throughput experimentation (HTE) technology presents a paradigm shift with immense potential to revolutionize the discovery and optimization of asymmetric reactions. In this study, we present an efficient workflow for the development of a series of nickel-catalyzed asymmetric cross-coupling reactions, leveraging AI and HTE technology. Many nickel-catalyzed enantioselective cross-coupling reactions share a common Ni(III) intermediate, which dictates the enantioselectivity. To harness this mechanistic insight, we embarked on developing a predictive model for nickel-catalyzed enantioselective coupling reactions, elucidating the general rules governing enantioselectivity. Through the application of data science tools and HTE technology, we curated a data set to construct an AI-based model. This model was subsequently utilized to facilitate the discovery of efficient nickel hydride-catalyzed enantioselective and regioselective cross-coupling reactions. Employing AI-assisted virtual ligand screening and HTE-enabled condition optimization, we successfully identified optimal ligands for eight coupling reactions. Consequently, a series of chiral sp3 C&#8211;C bonds were synthesized with high yield and enantioselectivity.</description>
      <author>Yadong Gao, Kunjun Hu, Jianhang Rao, Qiang Zhu, Kuangbiao Liao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Product Selectivity in Photochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction with the Redox Potential of the Photosensitizer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03845</link>
      <description>Lei Zhang, Andressa V. M&#252;ller, Sai Puneet Desai, David C. Grills, Dmitry E. Polyansky, Renato N. Sampaio, Javier J. Concepcion, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404944465

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zhang, Andressa V. M&#252;ller, Sai Puneet Desai, David C. Grills, Dmitry E. Polyansky, Renato N. Sampaio, Javier J. Concepcion</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron Designer Enzyme with a Hybrid Catalytic Dyad</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06052</link>
      <description>Lars Longwitz, Marijn D. Kamer, Bart Brouwer, A.M.W.H. Thunnissen, G&#233;rard Roelfes, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404961214

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lars Longwitz, Marijn D. Kamer, Bart Brouwer, A.M.W.H. Thunnissen, G&#233;rard Roelfes</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Enzymes for Catalysis under Industrial Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05265</link>
      <description>Elif Erdem, John M. Woodley, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404974317

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elif Erdem, John M. Woodley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Faujasite Zeolite Dealumination at the Atomic Scale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03036</link>
      <description>Zhuoran Wang, Thomas Jarrin, Micka&#235;l Rivallan, Isabelle Cl&#233;men&#231;on, Emmanuel Soyer, Theodorus de Bruin, L. Lema&#238;tre, Virgile Rouchon, David Gajan, Gerhard D. Pirngruber, C&#233;line Chizallet, Anne Lesage, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404974759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhuoran Wang, Thomas Jarrin, Micka&#235;l Rivallan, Isabelle Cl&#233;men&#231;on, Emmanuel Soyer, Theodorus de Bruin, L. Lema&#238;tre, Virgile Rouchon, David Gajan, Gerhard D. Pirngruber, C&#233;line Chizallet, Anne Lesage</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03036</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
