<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 01:37:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial Biosynthesis of Nitrile-Containing Natural Products: Basis for Recognition of Diversified Substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06581</link>
      <description>Ming Peng, Qiaoling Wu, Lele Ma, Zhao&#8208;Jie Teng, Xuben Hou, Hongjie Zhu, Jianhua Ju, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404449383

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming Peng, Qiaoling Wu, Lele Ma, Zhao&#8208;Jie Teng, Xuben Hou, Hongjie Zhu, Jianhua Ju</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06581</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Lattice Oxygen in Nitrogen-Doped High-Entropy Oxide Nanosheets for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05997</link>
      <description>Shengqin Guan, Baoen Xu, Xingbo Yu, Yong&#8208;Hong Ye, Yuting Liu, Taotao Guan, Yang Yu, Jiali Gao, Kaixi Li, Jianlong Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404459898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengqin Guan, Baoen Xu, Xingbo Yu, Yong&#8208;Hong Ye, Yuting Liu, Taotao Guan, Yang Yu, Jiali Gao, Kaixi Li, Jianlong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05997</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In(OTf)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Catalyzed (3 + 3) Dipolar Cyclization of Bicyclo[1.1.0]butanes with &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Nucleophilic 1,3-Dipoles: Access to 2,3-Diazabicyclo[3.1.1]heptanes, 2,3-Diazabicyclo[3.1.1]heptenes, and Enantiopure 2-Azabicyclo[3.1.1]heptanes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05622</link>
      <description>Jian Zhang, Jia-Yi Su, Hanliang Zheng, Hao Li, Wei&#8208;Ping Deng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404474976

                The investigation into the synthesis of azabicyclo[3.1.1]heptanes (azaBCHeps) as bioisosteres to flat aza-aromatics has garnered increasing attention, while it encounters significant challenges. Herein, we have demonstrated the In(OTf)3-catalyzed (3 + 3) dipolar cyclization of bicyclo[1.1.0]butanes (BCBs) with hydrazones and &#960;-allyl-iridium 1,3-dipoles, engendering a diverse array of azaBCHeps. The cyclization of hydrazones and BCBs furnished densely substituted 2,3-diazabicyclo[3.1.1]heptanes and 2,3-diazabicyclo[3.1.1]heptenes under nitrogen and oxygen atmospheres, respectively. A combination of experimental and computational investigations lends robust support for the proton-transfer-interposed sequential mechanism. More importantly, by integrating In(OTf)3/iridium relay catalysis, enantiopure 2-azabicyclo[3.1.1]heptanes were constructed through the (3 + 3) cyclization of BCBs with aza-&#960;-allyl-iridium 1,3-dipoles, in situ generated from N-allyl carbonates. Both methodologies exhibit mild reaction conditions and good tolerance for various functional groups. Moreover, the copious derivatization of products highlights the utility of the newly synthesized heterobicyclic motifs as versatile building blocks in synthetic chemistry.</description>
      <author>Jian Zhang, Jia-Yi Su, Hanliang Zheng, Hao Li, Wei&#8208;Ping Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Dehydrogenation of Propane to Propene over PtIn Nanoclusters Encapsulated in Hollow-Structured Silicalite-1</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05135</link>
      <description>Shiying Li, Decheng Li, Baichao Li, Xiao Chen, Hongbin Wu, Sen Wang, Mei Dong, Jianguo Wang, Weibin Fan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404483179

                Pt-based catalysts have been widely used for propane dehydrogenation to propene. However, the high reaction temperature generally induces serious sintering and agglomeration of metal species, thus leading to rapid deactivation of the catalysts. Herein, PtIn nanoclusters (NCs) encapsulated in hollow-structured silicalite-1 (designated as PtIn@S1&#8211;H) was prepared using recrystallization method. This material shows high catalytic performance in propane dehydrogenation. The propane conversion and propene selectivity reach &#8764;45&#8211;47.5% and &#8764;99%, respectively, at 547 &#176;C at least within 167.6 h. As a result, it displays a significantly higher specific activity for C3H6 formation (0.37&#8211;0.59 s&#8211;1) than Pt@S1, Pt@S1&#8211;H, and other reported Pt-based catalysts. Notably, its catalytic performance is well maintained for more than 3600 h, with propane conversion of &#8764;31&#8211;34% and propene selectivity of &#8764;91&#8211;95%, when pure propane is fed. More interestingly, this catalyst can be reused through regeneration. EXAFS, HAADF-STEM and DFT calculation, and AIMD simulation results show that hollow-structured silicalite-1 crystal morphology not only facilitates the formation of Pt5In3 alloy NCs but also inhibits NC aggregation and growth. PtIn@S1&#8211;H showed a TON &#8805; 38996 in contrast to 5367, 4928, 798, and 542 obtained on PtIn@S1, PtSn@S1, PtSn/Al2O3, and PtIn/Al2O3, respectively, if the catalysts were considered to be deactivated when the propane conversion was decreased by 15%. This is because alloying of In into Pt NCs weakens the interaction of C3H7* intermediates with metallic Pt NCs and the adsorption of C3H6 on the catalyst surface, thus suppressing the C3H7* cleavage reaction and enhancing propane activation and propene selectivity.</description>
      <author>Shiying Li, Decheng Li, Baichao Li, Xiao Chen, Hongbin Wu, Sen Wang, Mei Dong, Jianguo Wang, Weibin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium Photoredox-Catalyzed Stereoselective &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;-Glycosylation with Tetrafluoropyridin-4-yl Thioglycosides: A Facile Synthesis of &lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;-&#945;/&#946;-Glucogallins and Their Antioxidant Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05257</link>
      <description>Shenghao Li, Han Ding, Ruge Cao, Xiao-Lin Zhang, Jingxin Li, Xingchun Sun, Yaying Li, Kan Zhong, Peng Wang, Chao Cai, Hongzhi Cao, Ming Li, Xue&#8208;Wei Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404486254

                We demonstrate an efficient, scalable, and stereoselective C-glycosylation with thioglycosides possessing a unique photoactive tetrafluoropyridin-4-yl (TFPy) thio radical leaving group, affording editable and medicinally and biologically essential C-&#945;-glucogallin derivatives. In the presence of silyl enol ether acceptors, the desulfurative coupling reaction performs smoothly under mild conditions upon exposure to blue light irradiation. This versatile protocol permits the synthesis of sugar-drug chimeras by C1 ketonylation of complex drug-derived silyl enol ethers. The scale-up synthesis, anomeric epimerization, and post-C-glycosylation modification of ketone sugars showcase the reaction's potential utilities. Furthermore, the reaction could be applied to direct carbohydrate skeleton editing by equipping the leaving group on the nonanomeric position. The ketonylation is viable for unprotected TFPy thioglycoside, affording a direct route to unprotected ketonyl sugars. The concise six-step assembly of both configurated C-glucogallins from commercially cheap glucose pentaacetate and their antioxidant reactivity investigations underline the promising medicinal relevance of our current protocols. The reaction mechanism was investigated through a radical trapping experiment, an oxocarbenium trapping experiment, a fluorescence quenching experiment, and Stern&#8211;Volmer analysis, confirming that the major glycosyl radical intermediates are generated from the thioglycoside donors, whose tetrafluoropyridin-4-yl thio group could effectively quench the fluorescence of excited Ir(ppy)3 through an oxidative quenching process, and C-glycosylation with oxocarbenium is a complementary route to the product, accounting for examples with moderate selectivities.</description>
      <author>Shenghao Li, Han Ding, Ruge Cao, Xiao-Lin Zhang, Jingxin Li, Xingchun Sun, Yaying Li, Kan Zhong, Peng Wang, Chao Cai, Hongzhi Cao, Ming Li, Xue&#8208;Wei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Associate Configuration of Nb Single Atoms Coupled Bi&#8211;O Vacancy Pairs Boosting CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04407</link>
      <description>Jun Di, Yao Wu, Jun Xiong, Hongwei Shou, Ran Long, Hailong Chen, Peng Zhou, Peng Zhang, Xingzhong Cao, Li Song, Wei Jiang, Zheng Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404486667

                Precisely designing the atomic coordination structure of the catalytic center is highly desired to lower the energy barrier of CO2 photoreduction. The present work shows that engineering Nb single atom coupled Bi&#8211;O vacancy pairs (VBi&#8211;O) into Bi24O31Br10 (BOB) atomic layers can create a preferential local asymmetric structure. This configuration can result in a stronger local polarization electric field and thus prolong the carrier lifetime, as proved by ultrafast transient absorption spectroscopy. Meantime, this unique Nb SA-VBi&#8211;O associate favors the formation of strong chemical interaction between key *COOH intermediate and catalytic center, thus lowering the energy barrier of the rate-limiting step. Benefiting from these features, a high CO generation rate of 76.4 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 for CO2 photoreduction can be achieved over Nb SA-VBi&#8211;O BOB atomic layers in pure water, roughly 5.4 and 92.7 times higher than those of BOB atomic layers or bulk BOB, respectively. This work discloses an important paradigm for designing single atom coupled defect associates to optimize photocatalysis performance.</description>
      <author>Jun Di, Yao Wu, Jun Xiong, Hongwei Shou, Ran Long, Hailong Chen, Peng Zhou, Peng Zhang, Xingzhong Cao, Li Song, Wei Jiang, Zheng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Key Factors on Structure&#8211;Property&#8211;Activity Correlations for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Production of Covalent Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04968</link>
      <description>Pengyu Dong, Cunxia Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Jinkang Pan, Boyuan Zhang, Jinlong Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404488626

                It has been a challenging task to clearly elucidate various structural features and how their interactions affect the photocatalytic hydrogen production performance. In this work, various factors, including crystallinity, specific surface area associated with morphology, energy band gap and energy levels, surface charge, and hydrophilicity, were employed to investigate the structure&#8211;property&#8211;activity correlations of &#946;-ketoenamine-linked covalent organic framework (TpPa-1-COF) for photocatalytic H2 production, which could influence the light harvesting, charge separation and transfer, and surface catalytic active sites. By using different methods to prepare TpPa-1-COFs, we can regulate these influencing factors to investigate their relationship with activity. It is found that the TpPa-1-COF prepared by a molecular organization method (labeled as TpPa-1 (MO)) exhibits the highest photocatalytic H2 evolution activity compared with the TpPa-1-COF samples prepared by solvothermal methods using acetic acid (HOAc) as a catalyst (TpPa-1 (ST-HOAc)) and KOH solution as a catalyst (TpPa-1 (ST-KOH)), which is associated with the highest crystallinity, the optimal energy levels, the largest BET-specific surface area, and the best hydrophilicity for TpPa-1 (MO). Moreover, our findings suggest that the enhanced total photocatalytic H2 evolution efficiency (&#951;total) of TpPa-1 (MO) may be mainly attributed to the efficient separation and migration of photogenerated charges (&#951;2) and the vibrant surface catalytic active sites (&#951;3). Overall, this work provides some deep insights into the structure&#8211;property&#8211;activity relation of TpPa-1-COF photocatalysts, which offers valuable inspiration and guidance for the thoughtful design of COF-based photocatalysts for H2 evolution.</description>
      <author>Pengyu Dong, Cunxia Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Jinkang Pan, Boyuan Zhang, Jinlong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the Reaction Network of Ethylene Epoxidation on Partially Oxidized Silver Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04521</link>
      <description>Adhika Setiawan, Tiancheng Pu, Israel E. Wachs, Srinivas Rangarajan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404513109

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adhika Setiawan, Tiancheng Pu, Israel E. Wachs, Srinivas Rangarajan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04521</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a Pore-Confined Catalyst in a Vinylene-Linked Covalent Organic Framework for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05827</link>
      <description>Xuewen Li, Shuai Yang, Xiubei Yang, Shuang Zheng, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng, Zheng Jiang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404519758

                Two-dimensional metal-containing covalent organic frameworks (COFs) have been employed as electrocatalysts. However, the metal sites were stacked within the layers with strong interactions, which hindered mass transport to them in the catalytic process. Herein, we constructed a pore-confined catalyst in a vinylene-linked COF for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) via the Katritzky reaction. By anchoring the catalytic sites along the pore walls with covalent bonds, the catalytic units were well-exposed during the catalytic process and retained crystallinity and porosity, facilitating mass access to the metal sites. In addition, the electron/charge transported from the framework to the metal units modulated the electronic states, thus improving the catalytic activity. The catalytic COF exhibited a half-wave potential of 0.85 V and a mass activity of 109.7 A g&#8211;1, which are better than those of other reported COFs. Theoretical calculations revealed that the interaction between the framework and metal sites contributed to the easy formation of OOH* and OH*, resulting in high activity. This work provides insights into designing catalytic COFs based on C&#9552;C linkages.</description>
      <author>Xuewen Li, Shuai Yang, Xiubei Yang, Shuang Zheng, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng, Zheng Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlated Operando Electron Microscopy and Photoemission Spectroscopy in Partial Oxidation of Ethylene over Nickel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04437</link>
      <description>Claudiu Colbea, Milivoj Plodinec, Man Guo, Luca Artiglia, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, Claudiu Colbea, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404522986

                The production of syngas from light hydrocarbons is a viable way of converting under-utilized hydrocarbon sources into valuable products until a full transition to renewable energy sources is achieved. However, current heterogeneous catalysts for syngas production suffer from deactivation, either by coking or oxidation. Here, we report on the behavior of model nickel catalysts within the context of ethylene partial oxidation and observe the catalyst-environment interaction as a function of reactant feed and temperature. Using a combination of operando microscopy and spectroscopy and focusing on a reaction regime characterized by synchronized self-sustained oscillatory dynamics, we are able to gain additional insights into the dynamic interplay between reactive species and active catalyst surfaces of varying reactivity. Real-time secondary electron imaging coupled with online mass spectrometry and thermal data shows that the oscillatory behavior is characterized by a highly active half-period during which the surface of the nickel catalyst is metallic and a less active half-period during which the surface is oxidized. Complementing the direct surface imaging, operando X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy provides missing information about the alternating chemical state of the catalyst surface in the oscillating reaction regime. It reveals that changes in the gas phase composition (C2H4/O2 ratio) alter the population of reaction intermediates (e.g., carbides) on the nickel surface, which in turn drives the selectivity of the reaction toward different products. The observed chemical dynamics involve changes in gas-phase composition, rate-dependent heat of reaction, the chemical state of the catalyst, and the formation of reaction products, all of which are interconnected. Ultimately, the complex oscillations and catalytic behavior are attributed to a multistep mechanism that involves complete ethylene oxidation, dry and wet reforming of ethylene, and the reverse water gas shift reaction.</description>
      <author>Claudiu Colbea, Milivoj Plodinec, Man Guo, Luca Artiglia, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, Claudiu Colbea</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoted Electrochemical Ammonia Synthesis from Nitrate at the Ag&#8211;Cu Biphasic Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05465</link>
      <description>Xinyang Gao, Chenyuan Zhu, Chunlei Yang, Guoshuai Shi, Qinshang Xu, Liming Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404522993

                Electrochemical nitrate reduction (NO3&#8211;R) presents a promising pathway for carbon-neutral ammonia (NH3) synthesis. Enhancing NH3 selectivity through a tandem process can be achieved by combining Cu with a secondary metal, which allows for an adjustable binding energy between the bimetallic catalyst and key nitrogen intermediates. Herein, we developed a biphasic Ag&#8211;Cu heterostructure with a controllable elemental composition, which significantly improved NH3 production through tandem NO3&#8211;R. In-situ infrared spectroscopy and finite element simulations revealed that Ag serves as the active site for converting NO3&#8211; to NO2&#8211;, leading to a high localized concentration of NO2&#8211;, which is subsequently reduced to NH3 on adjacent Cu sites. Density functional theory calculations further confirmed the critical role of the Ag&#8211;Cu biphasic interface in promoting tandem NH3 production. This work offers valuable insights into the tandem NO3&#8211;R pathway in bimetallic heterostructures, providing a foundation for optimizing catalysts and advancing large-scale sustainable NH3 synthesis.</description>
      <author>Xinyang Gao, Chenyuan Zhu, Chunlei Yang, Guoshuai Shi, Qinshang Xu, Liming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Functional Nucleic Acid Enzymes: Nucleic Acid-Based Catalytic Factories&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06741</link>
      <description>Min Yang, Yushi Xie, Longjiao Zhu, Xiangyang Li, Wentao Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404523123

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. ACS CatalysisASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse ORIGINAL ARTICLE. This notice is a correction.Addition/CorrectionNovember 19, 2024Correction to "Functional Nucleic Acid Enzymes: Nucleic Acid-Based Catalytic Factories"Click to copy article linkArticle link copied!Min YangMin YangMore by Min YangYushi XieYushi XieMore by Yushi XieLongjiao ZhuLongjiao ZhuMore by Longjiao ZhuXiangyang LiXiangyang LiMore by Xiangyang LiWentao Xu*Wentao XuMore by Wentao Xuhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-8572-8257Open PDFACS CatalysisCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, XXX, 17879Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acscatal.4c06741https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06741Published November 19, 2024 Publication History Received 5 November 2024Published online 19 November 2024correction&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyThe caption for Figure 2 should read as follows:Figure 2. Classifications and applications of FNAzymes.P 16394, the last sentence of the first paragraph of section 2 should read as follows:In general, catalytic functions of ribozymes could be divided into these categories: cleaving, splicing, ligation, polymerization and others.Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorWentao Xu; https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8572-8257; Email: AuthorsMin YangYushi XieLongjiao ZhuXiangyang LiCited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferences Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsACS CatalysisCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, XXX, 17879Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06741Published November 19, 2024 Publication History Received 5 November 2024Published online 19 November 2024&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesThis publication has no figures.This publication has no References.</description>
      <author>Min Yang, Yushi Xie, Longjiao Zhu, Xiangyang Li, Wentao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometrically Constrained Cofacial Bi-Titanium Olefin Polymerization Catalysts: Tuning and Enhancing Comonomer Incorporation Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05888</link>
      <description>Junhui Bao, Yufang Li, Chun&#8208;Ming Chan, Kwok-Chung Law, Shek&#8208;Man Yiu, Michael C. W. Chan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404531727

                A series of shape-persistent bis-[C(sp3)-chelating] Ti2 (plus Zr2 and Hf2) complexes with a rigid linker component (xanthene or dibenzofuran) are presented. These structurally diverse assemblies display limited yet different conformational flexibility, and crucially, such geometric constraints confer access to a range of intermetallic separations and orientations to potentially enhance catalytic activity and cooperative effects. For ethylene polymerizations, the Ti2 catalysts (in conjunction with trityl borate) exhibit greater efficiencies and produced polymers with higher Mw than mononuclear controls, which is significant considering the more crowded environment for cofacial bimetallic sites. Proficient 1-hexene incorporations were observed for ethylene-(&#945;-olefin) copolymerization reactions. The F-substituted m-aryl/dibenzofuran-linked catalyst (5), which is revealed by NMR analysis to be conformationally dissimilar to its F-absent congener, produced copolymers with higher Mw and elevated 1-hexene incorporation levels (up to 44%), when compared with its mono-Ti control (19%). These results suggest that catalyst frameworks with suitably adjustable conformations and Ti&#183;&#183;&#183;Ti distances can facilitate bimetallic enchainment interactions with &#945;-olefin substrates and their insertion.</description>
      <author>Junhui Bao, Yufang Li, Chun&#8208;Ming Chan, Kwok-Chung Law, Shek&#8208;Man Yiu, Michael C. W. Chan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Mechanism of Biomimetic Arene Hydroxylation: When a Diiron Metal Center Meets a Sulfur-Containing Ligand</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04662</link>
      <description>Yu Sheng, Bo Bi, Lu Cheng, Wei Han, Hui Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404539817

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Sheng, Bo Bi, Lu Cheng, Wei Han, Hui Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04662</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ancestral Sequence Reconstruction Meets Machine Learning: Ene Reductase Thermostabilization Yields Enzymes with Improved Reactivity Profiles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03738</link>
      <description>Caroline K. Brennan, Jovan Livada, Carlos Alberto Mart&#237;nez, Russell D. Lewis, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404541678

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Caroline K. Brennan, Jovan Livada, Carlos Alberto Mart&#237;nez, Russell D. Lewis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Combustion of Methane over Noble Metal Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05650</link>
      <description>Huimei Duan, Fanxin Kong, Xinze Bi, Lei Chen, Hangrong Chen, Dongjiang Yang, Weixin Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404551760

                As one of the cleanest fossil fuel resources, methane is also the second largest greenhouse gas after CO2 owing to its strong greenhouse effect. The direct emission of large quantities of trace and unburned methane causes a serious energy loss and greenhouse effect. Catalytic methane combustion is a promising strategy in eliminating methane slip to address the urgent environmental issue. However, the current methane abatement catalysts still face great challenges in thermal stability, water resistance, and sulfur tolerance. In this review, we focus on the popular noble metal-based catalysts, discuss the distinct reaction mechanisms including the Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood model, Eley&#8211;Rideal model, Mars&#8211;van Krevelen model, and two-term mechanisms. The deactivation mechanisms induced by sintering, sulfur, and water on popular Pd-based catalysts are then analyzed. Then, we outline the promotion strategies from two aspects, i.e., construction of a core&#8211;shell structure and electronic engineering of the active phase to improve thermal stability and poisoning resistance. Finally, a summary and prospects with an emphasis on the newly developed oxide-metal interfaces and photothermal catalysis for highly efficient methane combustion are addressed.</description>
      <author>Huimei Duan, Fanxin Kong, Xinze Bi, Lei Chen, Hangrong Chen, Dongjiang Yang, Weixin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical Synthesis of Benzo[&lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;]phosphole Oxides via Sequential P&#8211;H/C&#8211;H Bond Functionalizations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06292</link>
      <description>N. K. SAHA, Burkhard Koenig, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404563322

                Benzo[b]phosphole oxides are important P-heterocycles that find applications in optoelectronics due to their inherent photophysical properties. Traditional routes for the synthesis of such molecules from readily available precursors require stoichiometric amounts of transition metal salts, bases, oxidants, and additives, thereby lacking efficiency. Photochemical pathways still need a terminal oxidant to complement the photocatalytic cycle, whereas electricity may be a viable oxidant. Hence, photoelectrochemistry (PEC), combining photocatalysis and synthetic organic electrochemistry, was used to simplify the synthetic protocols. We use the potency of 4CzIPN for the consecutive P&#8211;H/C&#8211;H bond functionalizations for preparing benzo[b]phosphole oxides from secondary phosphine oxides and nonactivated internal alkynes with up to 93% yields and with good functional group tolerance. Detailed mechanistic investigations confirm an intermolecular electron transfer between 4CzIPN and aryl secondary phosphine oxides upon photoexcitation. The photocatalyst is regenerated by anodic oxidation.</description>
      <author>N. K. SAHA, Burkhard Koenig</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organocatalytic Asymmetric Electrophilic Amination of Allylic Boronates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05237</link>
      <description>Giovanni Centonze, Arianna Grandi, Andrea Pellegrini, Paolo Righi, Chiara Portolani, Giorgio Bencivenni, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404563337

                The asymmetric addition of allylic boronates to electrophiles is a powerful method for preparing chiral molecules bearing synthetically valuable allylic moieties. While effective catalytic methods exist, they have so far been limited to the enantioselective allyl- and crotyl-boration of carbonyl compounds and imines, thereby forming C&#8211;C bonds. Here, we present a strategy that expands the scope of this catalytic asymmetric platform to include the stereoselective formation of C&#8211;N bonds. We have identified an inexpensive and readily available chiral diol that catalyzes the addition of allylic boronates to azodicarboxylates, affording chiral allylic hydrazides with high stereocontrol. This electrophilic amination chemistry shows a broad substrate scope and requires mild conditions, proceeding at ambient temperature. Mechanistic studies reveal that the chiral diol catalyst facilitates the formation of a chiral allylic boronate through the reversible exchange of the boron's achiral alkoxy ligand. By coordination with the electrophilic azodicarboxylate, the substrates mutually activate each other, allowing for the stereoselective transfer of the allyl group.</description>
      <author>Giovanni Centonze, Arianna Grandi, Andrea Pellegrini, Paolo Righi, Chiara Portolani, Giorgio Bencivenni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SiO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Interfacial Engineering of UV/Ozone Oxidation for an Efficient Water-Reduction Metal&#8211;Insulator&#8211;Semiconductor Silicon Photocathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05792</link>
      <description>Chenxiao Jiang, Siqin Zhou, Jinlu Han, Guancai Xie, Jian Gong, Juan Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404563346

                A metal&#8211;insulator&#8211;semiconductor (MIS) structure is an attractive interfacial structure for efficient photoelectrochemical (PEC) water-splitting reactions. However, developing a cost-effective and highly active photoelectrode for the PEC water-splitting reaction is still a major challenge. In this study, we use an easy-to-operate and economical UV/ozone (UV/O3) oxidation process to prepare ultrathin SiOx oxide as an insulating layer, which is integrated with the bilayer non-precious-metal collector Al/Ni serving as the catalyst and the p-Si semiconductor to obtain a cost-effective and efficient MIS structure photocathode. The outcomes demonstrate that the ultrathin SiOx insulation layer significantly improves the PEC hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), through comparing the photovoltage and photocurrent density of the MIS system. The inner metal Al in the bilayer collector Al/Ni regulates the degree of band bending at the semiconductor&#8211;metal interface. Additionally, the presence of the ultrathin Al2O3 insulation layer effectively reduces Fermi-level pinning, which promotes the efficient transfer of photoelectrons to electrolytes. These were confirmed through photoelectric performance testing of the MIS system. The generation of a photocurrent of 15 mA cm&#8211;2 at a potential level of 0 V (vs reversible hydrogen electrode) has been obtained by optimizing the thickness of the SiOx and bilayer non-precious-metal collector. This study presents an economical and efficient strategy for enhancing PEC-HER performance in silicon-based photocathodes using an MIS structure.</description>
      <author>Chenxiao Jiang, Siqin Zhou, Jinlu Han, Guancai Xie, Jian Gong, Juan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>{TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(B)} Quantum Dot Hybrids: A Comprehensible Route toward High-Performance [&amp;gt;0.1 mol gr&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;1&lt;/sup&gt; h&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;1&lt;/sup&gt;] Photocatalytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production from H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05001</link>
      <description>Christos Dimitriou, Loukas Belles, Nikos Boukos, Yiannis Deligiannakis, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404567183

                Industrial-scale photocatalytic H2 production from H2O is a forward-looking aim in research and technology. To this end, understanding the key properties of TiO2 as a reference H2 production photocatalyst paves the way. Herein, we explore the TiO2 nanosize limits, in conjunction with the TiO2(B) nanophase, as a strategy to enhance the photocatalytic H2 production at &gt;150 mmol/g/h. We present a targeted engineering realm on the synthesis of quantum dots (QDs) of TiO2 consisting of an anatase core (3 nm) interfaced with a nanometric shell of the TiO2(B) phase, synthesized through a modified flame spray pyrolysis (FSP) process. The {TiO2-anatase/TiO2(B)} core&#8211;shell QDs, with high specific surface area SSA = 360 m2/gr, achieve a milestone H2 production yield of 156 mmol/g/h and solar-to-H2 efficiency nSTH = 24.2%. We demonstrate that diligent control of the TiO2-anatase/TiO2(B) heterojunction, in tandem with lattice microstrain, are key factors that contribute to the superior H2 production, i.e., not only the high SSA of the QDs. At these quantum-size limits, the formation of lattice dislocations and interstitial Ti centers enhances photon absorption at &#8764;2.3 eV (540 nm), resulting in the generation of midgap states around the Fermi energy. EPR spectroscopy provides direct evidence that the photoinduced holes are preferentially localized on the TiO2(B) shell, while the photoinduced electrons accumulate on the anatase nanophase. Combined electrochemical and photocatalytic analyses demonstrate that the presence of an optimal TiO2(B) phase is significant for the photoactivity of TiO2 in all QD materials. High SSA does contribute to enhanced photocatalytic H2 production; however, its role is not the key-determinant. TiO2 lattice-dislocations in QDs provide extra DOS that can additionally assist in the photon utilization efficiency. Overall, the present work reveals a general concept, that is, at the quantum-size scale, lattice microstrain engineering and interstitial-states' formation are spontaneously facilitated by nanolattice physics. Diligent optimization of these properties offers a pathway toward high-end photocatalytic efficacy.</description>
      <author>Christos Dimitriou, Loukas Belles, Nikos Boukos, Yiannis Deligiannakis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cofactor-Inspired Quinone Catalysis Following a One-Electron Hydrogen Atom Transfer Pathway</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05988</link>
      <description>Amreen K. Bains, Harshit Jain, Abhishek Kundu, Rahul Singh, Sudha Yadav, Yadav Ankit, Debashis Adhikari, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404572577

                Alcohol dehydrogenation catalysts in an aerobic atmosphere are often inspired by biological cofactors, which play a major role in controlling the redox chemistry. A large body of work mimicking quinone-containing cofactors established two major mechanistic routes, addition&#8211;elimination or transamination. Both of these pathways are completely regulated by two-electron processes, despite the possibility of the cofactor motif being reduced by one electron. In stark contrast to the established mechanisms, we demonstrate a one-electron pathway in quinone catalysis toward dehydrogenating alcohols. The described pyrene dione molecule is efficient in catalytic dehydrogenation of primary, secondary, and aliphatic alcohols. The process starts with the photoexcitation of the dione motif which becomes photoreduced by KOtBu to generate a persistent semiquinonate radical. The substrate alcohol interacts with the quinone backbone to forge a hydrogen-bonded intermediate, which leads to a crucial hydrogen atom transfer (HAT) step, to accomplish the dehydrogenation reaction. A series of kinetic experiments including Bell&#8211;Evans&#8211;Polanyi correlation with the bond dissociation enthalpy firmly establish HAT to be rate-determining during dehydrogenation reactions. A kinetic isotope effect measured for the dehydrogenation process at 30 &#176;C is 7.7 &#177; 0.9. Interception of a series of intermediates by a radical quencher in conjunction with a radical-probe substrate further affirms the radical-mediated, one-electron pathway to be operative that is in striking contrast to two-electron-driven quinone catalysis established so far.</description>
      <author>Amreen K. Bains, Harshit Jain, Abhishek Kundu, Rahul Singh, Sudha Yadav, Yadav Ankit, Debashis Adhikari</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Promotion of Catalysis by Lithium-Ion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04622</link>
      <description>Ju Wang, Shuo Yan, Kholoud E. Salem, Christopher Panaritis, Mohamed S.E. Houache, Yaser Abu&#8208;Lebdeh, Drew Higgins, Elena A. Baranova, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404579251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ju Wang, Shuo Yan, Kholoud E. Salem, Christopher Panaritis, Mohamed S.E. Houache, Yaser Abu&#8208;Lebdeh, Drew Higgins, Elena A. Baranova</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Molybdate Oxyanion Boosts Self-Optimization and Self-Healing on the NiMoFe Heterostructure for Water Splitting in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05108</link>
      <description>Qing Zhang, Wei Xiao, Jia Shi, Jing Lei, Qi Xiao, Hong Qun Luo, Nian Bing Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404609586

                NiMo-based alloys and NiFe layered double hydroxides (NiFe-LDHs) are the most promising nonprecious-metal electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER) under alkaline conditions. However, the ready leaching of Mo and Fe during electrolysis may cause dynamic variation of the surface composition and structure of the catalysts. Here, we developed a NiMoFe heterostructure consisting of NiMoFe alloy and MoO42&#8211;-intercalated NiFe-LDH (NiMoFe HI), which enables self-optimization of HER and self-healing of OER through the dynamic exchange of MoO42&#8211; species. During the HER process, the leaching and readsorption of MoO42&#8211; optimizes the electronic structure of NiFe-LDH, facilitating H2O adsorption and dissociation. Simultaneously, the repulsion of OH&#8211; by accumulated MoO42&#8211; in the electric double layer can more rapidly drive the transfer kinetics of *OH + e &#8652; OH&#8211; to promote the desorption of *OH from the active sites, thus continuously enhancing the HER activity. During the OER process, the dynamic equilibrium of MoO42&#8211; facilitates the readsorption of active Fe(OH)x species on the NiFeOOH surface and reduces the energy barrier of the OER rate-determining step, achieving self-healing of the OER activity. Benefiting from the self-optimization and self-healing properties for HER and OER, NiMoFe LDH exhibits promising performance in alkaline water splitting, with a low cell voltage of 1.528 V at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 and stable operation at a high current density of 100 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 for 150 h.</description>
      <author>Qing Zhang, Wei Xiao, Jia Shi, Jing Lei, Qi Xiao, Hong Qun Luo, Nian Bing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Monoalkylation or Dialkylation of Indenes with Alcohols by Bis-&lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Heterocyclic Carbene Manganese</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05200</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Yinwu Li, Zhe Chen, Cunyuan Zhao, Zhuofeng Ke, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404616756

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Yinwu Li, Zhe Chen, Cunyuan Zhao, Zhuofeng Ke</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper(I)-Catalyzed &#945;,&#946;-Dehydrogenative [2 + 3] Heteroannulation of Saturated Amines with Diaziridinone via Hydrogen Atom Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05973</link>
      <description>Zihang Du, Jiahao Zhang, Xueli Lv, Kun Zhang, Wei Ji, Minyan Wang, Su Jing, Jiefeng Hu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404625202

                The site-selective functionalization of carbon(sp3)&#8211;hydrogen bonds in saturated amines remains a persistent challenge owing to their intrinsic electronic deficiency, particularly in activating the &#945; and &#946; positions simultaneously for annulation reactions. Herein, we report a copper(I)-catalyzed dehydrogenation and [2 + 3] cycloaddition of commercially available amines with diaziridinone, which facilitated the direct synthesis of highly valuable imidazolidone derivatives. Operationally simple methodology has a broad substrate scope and convenient scalability, providing an effective and complementary platform for the rapid incorporation of N-heterocycles into amine molecules. Furthermore, comprehensive mechanistic investigations and computational studies indicated the pathway of the radical-type hydrogen atom transfer and [2 + 3] cycloaddition, which were promoted by a four-membered copper(III) species.</description>
      <author>Zihang Du, Jiahao Zhang, Xueli Lv, Kun Zhang, Wei Ji, Minyan Wang, Su Jing, Jiefeng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05973</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
