<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:36:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ ORR Dynamics of Non-Precious Transition Metal Electrocatalysts: the Case of Manganese Antimony X-ides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03260</link>
      <description>Gaurav A. Kamat, Melissa E. Kreider, Johanna Schr&#246;der, Roulince Bobby Dukuly, Joseph T. Perryman, Bj&#248;rt Joensen, Jesse E. Matthews, Ashton M. Aleman, Michaela Burke Stevens, Thomas F. Jaramillo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403213342

                Electrocatalysts enable the efficient conversion of molecules for applications in energy devices, but due to their material stability, the electrochemical performance tends to change over time under operating conditions. For the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), transition metal x-ides (oxides, nitrides, sulfides) are a class of highly tunable, low-cost catalysts being considered as possible alternatives to expensive Pt-based materials. In this work, we take a multimodal characterization approach to investigate manganese antimony (MnSb) oxide, nitride, and sulfide nanoparticles for the ORR and characterize their performance in both acidic and alkaline conditions. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and transmission electron microscopy confirm that the three materials are of comparable morphology and polycrystallinity while having distinct elemental compositions. In pH 13 electrolyte, the nitride demonstrates a &#8764;40 mV higher ORR onset potential (at &#8722;0.1 mA cm&#8211;2geo) than both the oxide and sulfide and has nearly 100% selectivity toward H2O. In comparison, in pH 1 electrolyte, the nitride and sulfide are &#8764;300 mV higher in ORR onset (at &#8722;0.1 mA cm&#8211;2geo) than the oxide and both exhibit greater selectivity to H2O than the oxide. In situ Mn K-edge synchrotron X-ray absorption reveals that, despite significant material changes to the MnSb sulfide and nitride under electrochemical conditions, their Mn-oxidation state and ligand environment do not converge to those found in the MnSb oxide. Furthermore, online inductively coupled plasma&#8211;mass spectrometry of the materials elucidates distinct mechanisms of continuous dissolution and nanoparticle detachment that are functions of pH, potential, and material composition. Measuring changes in complex, nonprecious materials under dynamic electrochemical operation conditions provides insight into how an as-synthesized material can transform into a distinct active catalytic species. Moreover, correlating orthogonal online/operando/in situ measurement techniques in similar catalyst operation conditions is a powerful method for resolving mechanistic information about degradation and performance changes.</description>
      <author>Gaurav A. Kamat, Melissa E. Kreider, Johanna Schr&#246;der, Roulince Bobby Dukuly, Joseph T. Perryman, Bj&#248;rt Joensen, Jesse E. Matthews, Ashton M. Aleman, Michaela Burke Stevens, Thomas F. Jaramillo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grain Boundary-Derived Local Amorphization Enhances Acidic OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03746</link>
      <description>Mingze Sun, Helai Huang, Xiangfu Niu, Shuyan Gong, Zhengwen Li, Jinjie Fang, Xiang Liu, Yanjun Chen, Haohong Duan, Zhongbin Zhuang, Shigeaki Nagao, Yuki Aoki, Liang Zhang, Zhiqiang Niu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403244892

                IrOx of the amorphous phase has long been recognized to exhibit higher catalytic activity than crystalline analogues toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER) but always at the expense of reduced stability. Here, we report an ultrathin Ir surface with high-density grain boundaries (GBs), which transforms into locally stabilized amorphous IrOx by forming an Ir/IrOx interface under OER conditions. The catalyst displays a low overpotential of 263 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and a mass activity (5.8 A mgIr&#8211;1 at 1.53 V) of over 90-fold higher than that of commercial IrO2, along with long-term stability for over 350 h. The activity enhancement arises from the stronger binding strength of *OOH on the amorphous GBs relative to the crystalline region, thus breaking the scaling relationship between *OH and *OOH and reducing the energy barrier for the potential determining step of the OER. Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis using this catalyst achieves 2.7 A cm&#8211;2 at 2 V cell voltage and operates stably at 1 A cm&#8211;2 for over 200 h. The stabilization of the amorphous IrOx phase at GBs may accelerate the development of more active and robust acidic OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Mingze Sun, Helai Huang, Xiangfu Niu, Shuyan Gong, Zhengwen Li, Jinjie Fang, Xiang Liu, Yanjun Chen, Haohong Duan, Zhongbin Zhuang, Shigeaki Nagao, Yuki Aoki, Liang Zhang, Zhiqiang Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Medium-Sized Rings by &lt;i&gt;Z&lt;/i&gt;-Retentive Asymmetric Allylic Substitution-Enabled Intermolecular Cascade Cyclization under Iridium/Cinchona Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05266</link>
      <description>Yang&#8208;Zi Liu, Chao Zheng, Shu&#8208;Li You, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403250785

                Medium-sized rings are important structural units in organic molecules of significant interest. However, their efficient synthesis, especially in a highly enantioselective manner, has been a formidable challenge. Herein, we report an enantioselective synthesis of medium-sized aza-rings by a Z-retentive asymmetric allylic substitution-enabled intermolecular cascade cyclization via iridium/cinchona dual catalysis. The reaction was performed under mild conditions and with good functional group tolerance. Various nine- to eleven-membered aza-rings can be afforded in moderate to high yields (up to 98%) and enantioselectivities (up to 93% ee). The utilization of both Z-linear allylic dipole precursor and iridium/cinchona binary catalyst is critical for the desired reactivity.</description>
      <author>Yang&#8208;Zi Liu, Chao Zheng, Shu&#8208;Li You</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis from N&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; Compounds by Photocatalytic Technology: Promotion Mechanism, Reaction Pathways, and Efficiency Evaluation Criteria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04732</link>
      <description>Chunling Zhang, Jieyuan Li, Ruimin Chen, Shujie Shen, Jielin Wang, Yanjuan Sun, Fan Dong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403252707

                Ammonia (NH3) is one of the most important chemicals in high demand in human society. Given the high-energy consumption and environmental impact associated with the Haber&#8211;Bosch process, an environmentally friendly method for NH3 synthesis under ambient conditions should be developed. The reduction of N1 compounds, including nitrate (NO3&#8211;), nitrite (NO2&#8211;), and nitric oxide (NOx), are more energetically favorable than that of nitrogen (N2), avoiding the activation of inert N&#8801;N bonds. Photocatalytic NH3 synthesis from N1 compounds' reduction, which utilizes sunlight to convert contaminants into value-added chemicals, offers an intriguing approach to NH3 synthesis. This review offers a comprehensive overview of the progress of research in photocatalysis technology for reduction of N1 compounds to NH3 synthesis. Insight into the efficiency promotion mechanism is provided, particularly focusing on the optimization of the photocatalyst, the activation and mass transfer of reactants, and the redox synergistic promotion. Moreover, the reaction pathways are summarized. The efficiency evaluation criteria, including accurate quantification of the NH3 yield, comprehensive performance evaluation indicators, and NH3 separation and recovery, are discussed to guide systematic and reliable NH3 synthesis. Finally, the current achievements and future challenges of photocatalytic N1 compounds to NH3 synthesis are critically discussed.</description>
      <author>Chunling Zhang, Jieyuan Li, Ruimin Chen, Shujie Shen, Jielin Wang, Yanjuan Sun, Fan Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate and Product Selective Supramolecular Catalysis by Pillar[5]arene in the Alkylation of Primary Linear Amines with Allyl Bromide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04836</link>
      <description>Chiara Buranello, Marta Da Pian, Tommaso Lorenzetto, Fabrizio Fabris, Cristiano Zonta, Alessandro Scarso, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403293338

                We report the supramolecular catalysis exerted by the cavity of pillar[5]arene on the classic nucleophilic substitution reaction of primary alkyl amines on allyl bromide. The tubular nanocatalyst imparts both substrate selectivity for linear amines and product selectivity in favor of secondary amine products. The reaction turned out to be very sensitive to the size of the cavity and the nature of the alkoxy residues on the rim of the cylindrical nanometric catalyst. The acceleration observed was due to the stabilization of the developing charge on the N atom by an electrostatic interaction with the aromatic units of the cavity of the pillararene. Recycling of the supramolecular organocatalyst was also demonstrated.</description>
      <author>Chiara Buranello, Marta Da Pian, Tommaso Lorenzetto, Fabrizio Fabris, Cristiano Zonta, Alessandro Scarso</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Cu&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Catalytic Binding Pocket for Near-Unity Nitrate-to-Ammonia Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03006</link>
      <description>Liying Zhang, Wenzhe Shang, Sen Qiao, Wei Liu, Yantao Shi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403299253

                Electrocatalytic nitrate reduction reaction (NO3RR) provides unique opportunities to mitigate nitrate wastewater pollution and green ammonia production, yet the sluggish kinetics regarding 8e&#8211; transfer and collective activation of multiple reactants and intermediates remain a fundamental challenge. In this study, we present a cooperative catalyst design of atomically dispersed Cu1 species embedding onto reduced anatase TiO2&#8211;x with rich multistage pores and oxygen vacancies (POVs), affording the target POVs-Cu&#948;+-TiO2 with a multisite nature. Particularly, the oxygen vacancies and Cu1 sites in proximity feature a conformational enzyme-mimicking nanopocket, which essentially governs the binding fit of mutative nitrogenate intermediates in the context of synergistic catalysis. The POVs-Cu&#948;+-TiO2 delivers a near-unity Faradaic efficiency (product basis 95.0%) and remarkable ammonia yield rate up to 1321.2 &#956;mol h&#8211;1 mgcat&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.7 V vs RHE. This study underscores the surface topography engineering on reduced metal oxides and the promising synergistic effects over the NO3RR electrocatalysis, providing a better alternative for nitrate wastewater pollution treatment and ammonia production.</description>
      <author>Liying Zhang, Wenzhe Shang, Sen Qiao, Wei Liu, Yantao Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Organic Framework-Derived B/N Co-Doped Carbon FLPs Metal-Free Catalysts for the Selective Hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-Unsaturated Aldehydes to Unsaturated Alcohols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04537</link>
      <description>Linhao Zhong, Xindi Liao, Haishuai Cui, Jinmei Huang, He&#8217;an Luo, Yang Lv, Pingle Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403299654

                An ongoing challenge is to precisely tailor the frustrated Lewis pairs (FLPs) sites to construct all-solid-state FLPs metal-free catalysts that are as effective as or even more effective than homogeneous/metal catalysts in H2 activation. In this study, B/N codoped carbon (SNW-BCN) catalysts were prepared by precisely tailoring FLPs sites by targeted doping of B atoms in the nitrogen-rich covalent organic framework (SNW-1) using the ligand-exchange strategy and self-templated carbonization. The catalysts were then applied in the selective hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes to unsaturated alcohols. It was found that a significant amount of pyridinic-N sites could be obtained from nitrogen-rich SNW-1. Moreover, targeted doping of B atoms can be accomplished by introducing organic ligands (4-formylphenylboronic acid) with Lewis acid heteroatoms to pre-empt the ligand site of SNW-1. Additionally, the B&#8211;N covalent bond, which preferentially forms between B and neighboring N at high temperature, can function as a Lewis acid site. DFT calculations and in situ characterizations show that the neighboring electron-rich pyridinic-N and the electron-deficient B&#8211;N site can form B&#8211;N/pyridinic-N FLPs sites, which can effectively activate H2 and the C&#9552;O of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes, with only 0.36 eV of H&#8211;H bond dissociation energy. This work encourages the environmentally friendly synthesis of unsaturated alcohols and offers fresh concepts for the development and synthesis of all-solid-state FLPs metal-free catalysts. Additionally, experiments on catalyst scale-up were also investigated because they might shed light on catalyst production on a large scale.</description>
      <author>Linhao Zhong, Xindi Liao, Haishuai Cui, Jinmei Huang, He&#8217;an Luo, Yang Lv, Pingle Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active-Site Mutagenesis of Fatty Acid Photodecarboxylase: Experimental and Computational Insight into Substrate Chain-Length Specificity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02970</link>
      <description>Santiago Nahuel Chanquia, Jan Philipp Bittner, Paul Santner, L&#225;szl&#243; Kriszti&#225;n Szab&#243;, Julie Nielsen, Marcus Lyngdahl &#216;hlenschl&#230;ger, Ahmad Gheis Sarvari, Aske H&#248;j Merrild, Kathrine Gravlund Fo&#823;nss, Daily Jaron, Linnea Ute Lutz, Selin Kara, Bekir Engin Eser, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403319354

                Fatty acid photodecarboxylase (FAP), a microalgal enzyme, is one of the rare photoenzymes found in nature. Since its discovery in 2017, FAP has made a huge impact in the field of photobiocatalysis, being so far the only photoenzyme with potential applicability for organic synthesis. Furthermore, among all studied enzymes to date, FAP is one of the most promising candidates for in vitro feasible biofuel production from oil. One field of study for FAP has been broadening its substrate scope and modulating substrate selectivity. In order to get insight into the enzyme's substrate selectivity, as well as to generate a toolbox of mutant enzymes with distinct substrate preferences toward medium- and long-chain fatty acids, in this work, we carried out extensive mutagenesis of the active-site residues of FAP from Chlorella variabilis (CvFAP). Particularly, we performed partial-site saturation mutagenesis for the Y466 position due to its key location at the active site. Our experimental and computational analysis indicated a correlation between the exchanged amino acid type and the observed activity, demonstrating that the conventional binding mode of long-chain fatty acids is destabilized by charged amino acid residues, leading to a nonproductive binding conformation characterized by a compact folded form. Mutagenesis of other key residues around the substrate binding site led to variants with selectivity toward medium-chain or long-chain fatty acids. For example, we obtained enzyme variants that are highly selective toward either C12:0, C14:0, or C18:0/C18:1 fatty acids. Selectivity patterns agreed very well with the distances between the FAD cofactor and substrate, as calculated by our molecular dynamics simulations. Furthermore, we report unexplored activity of the wild-type CvFAP toward C20:1 and C22:1 fatty acids, which are major components of jojoba oil and rapeseed oil, respectively.</description>
      <author>Santiago Nahuel Chanquia, Jan Philipp Bittner, Paul Santner, L&#225;szl&#243; Kriszti&#225;n Szab&#243;, Julie Nielsen, Marcus Lyngdahl &#216;hlenschl&#230;ger, Ahmad Gheis Sarvari, Aske H&#248;j Merrild, Kathrine Gravlund Fo&#823;nss, Daily Jaron, Linnea Ute Lutz, Selin Kara, Bekir Engin Eser</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suzuki&#8211;Miyaura Cross-Couplings of Alkylboranes: Transmetalation Studies and Synthesis of Model Organopalladium Pretransmetalation Species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05053</link>
      <description>Angus Olding, Curtis C. Ho, Nigel T. Lucas, Brian F. Yates, Allan J. Canty, Alex C. Bissember, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403347353

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Angus Olding, Curtis C. Ho, Nigel T. Lucas, Brian F. Yates, Allan J. Canty, Alex C. Bissember</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Species Heterogeneity and Synergy to Boost Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03593</link>
      <description>Jiankang Zhang, Panzhe Qiao, Hao Tan, Lin Cui, Zhan Zhou, Dong Lin, Yongxiao Tuo, Yong Qin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403208208

                Integrating different reaction sites, such as single atom (SA), nanocluster (NC), and oxygen vacancy (Ov), in a specific photocatalyst affords a new prospect to break through the limitations of SA catalysis. However, the intrinsic influence mechanisms of cocatalyst size and Ov on the photocatalytic performance and synergy are still not well unraveled. Herein, we report the synthesis and investigation of atomically dispersed Pt-based photocatalysts surface-confined in Ov-containing porous TiO2 nanoflowers via atomic layer deposition. The SA&#8211;NC coexisting PtSA+NC@TiO2 photocatalysts exhibit optimized hydrogen evolution activity (2260 h&#8211;1), which is 3.6-fold higher than that of PtSA@TiO2 counterparts. Moreover, the activity can be further remarkably enhanced to 3645 h&#8211;1 by engineering the cocatalyst size and Ov concentration. We identify the ad-/desorption sites of the reacting molecules and unravel the synergistic catalytic mechanisms of the active speciesthrough characterizations and density functional theory calculations: Pt NC is responsible for the adsorption&#8211;dissociation of H2O molecules preferentially adsorbed on Ti sites and meanwhile lowers the d-band center of Pt SA responsible for the desorption of H2 molecules, and the adjacent Ov can stabilize the cocatalysts and modify the electronic energy distribution of Pt NC, achieving the optimized adsorption state toward the *OH intermediate. The present multiple-site engineering concept and mechanistic insights are expected to shed light on the rational design of atomically dispersed photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jiankang Zhang, Panzhe Qiao, Hao Tan, Lin Cui, Zhan Zhou, Dong Lin, Yongxiao Tuo, Yong Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of &#945;-Quaternary Aldehydes via a Dual Ni/Rh-Catalyzed Tandem Isomerization&#8211;Propargylation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05021</link>
      <description>Justin Ching, Megan Jaschinski, Eun Seo Choi, Mark Lautens, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403213785

                A dual Ni/Rh catalysis sequence toward &#945;-quaternary aldehydes is reported. An intramolecular approach from allyl propargyl carbonates alongside the intermolecular transformation from allylic alcohols and propargyl carbonates is described. Initial decarboxylative oxidative addition into the propargyl group by nickel generates the electrophilic Ni&#8211;allenyl species, and the resulting allylic alkoxide is isomerized into the nucleophilic Rh&#8211;enolate species. Upon recombination, the &#945;-propargylated aldehyde is obtained. Preliminary enantioselective results are reported, with varying protocols using either a dual metal single ligand or a dual metal dual ligand system.</description>
      <author>Justin Ching, Megan Jaschinski, Eun Seo Choi, Mark Lautens</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Irreversible Catalyst Deactivation Mechanisms of PdO/&#947;-Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for Lean Methane Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03690</link>
      <description>Hai-Ying Chen, Yuliana K. Lugo-Jos&#233;, Joseph M. Fedeyko, Todd J. Toops, Jacqueline Fidler, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403245003

                PdO/&#947;-Al2O3 catalysts suffer from gradual and irreversible catalyst deactivation under lean CH4 oxidation conditions, especially in a wet feed. Time-resolved CO chemisorption DRIFTS measurements are conducted systematically on a series of PdO/&#947;-Al2O3 catalysts to probe the surface reactivity of PdO nanoparticles after various in situ pretreatments. At 80 &#176;C, CO barely adsorbs on fully oxidized PdO surfaces but interacts with coordinatively unsaturated Pd sites, causing gradual reduction of the PdO surfaces. This results in the formation of characteristic IR bands on various metallic Pd0 sites. By monitoring and comparing the formation kinetics of these IR bands on samples before and after CH4 oxidation, we theorize that the irreversible catalyst deactivation during CH4 oxidation is caused by PdO surface reconstruction, in which coordinatively unsaturated Pd sites gradually become fully coordinated by oxygen. Effectively, the surface reconstruction leads to the formation of a passivation layer on the PdO nanoparticles, which hinders their ability in activating CH4, and hence the subsequent oxidation reaction. Temperature-programmed reduction with CO as the reductant (CO-TPR) reveals that the passivation layer formed during CH4 oxidation is significant enough to increase the reduction temperature of PdO nanoparticles of the 3.0% PdO/&#947;-Al2O3 samples, although such an effect is less obvious for the 0.4% PdO/&#947;-Al2O3 samples. On the other hand, it is also discovered that the passivation layer is not completely inert. Under certain reaction conditions, with some being relatively mild, such as low-temperature CO oxidation in a net lean atmosphere and in the presence of H2O, the passivation layer can undergo structure change which results in regeneration or even activation of CH4 oxidation activity of an already deactivated catalyst. Additionally, it is discovered that the fully coordinated Pd&#8211;O surface is a metastable phase under CH4 oxidation conditions. In the presence of H2O and at ambient temperatures, surfaces with coordinatively unsaturated Pd sites are thermodynamically more favorable.</description>
      <author>Hai-Ying Chen, Yuliana K. Lugo-Jos&#233;, Joseph M. Fedeyko, Todd J. Toops, Jacqueline Fidler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03690</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
