<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 01:11:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>P-Block Elements Activate Pt Surfaces for the Electrooxidation of Alcohols and Polyols When Promoting the &#8722;OH formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02443</link>
      <description>Matheus B. C. de Souza, Gabriela Soffiati, Victor S. Lemos, Victor Y. Yukuhiro, Miguel A. San&#8208;Miguel, Pablo S. Fern&#225;ndez, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401633729

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matheus B. C. de Souza, Gabriela Soffiati, Victor S. Lemos, Victor Y. Yukuhiro, Miguel A. San&#8208;Miguel, Pablo S. Fern&#225;ndez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstitution of Myoglobin with Iron Porphycene Generates an Artificial Aldoxime Dehydratase with Expanded Catalytic Activities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03220</link>
      <description>Shunsuke Kato, Masatoshi Abe, Harald Gr&#246;ger, Takashi Hayashi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647230

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shunsuke Kato, Masatoshi Abe, Harald Gr&#246;ger, Takashi Hayashi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogenation of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by a Tripodal Palladium Pincer Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02523</link>
      <description>Nandita Biswas, Peter L&#246;nnecke, E. Kirillov, Dmitri Gelman, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401660020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nandita Biswas, Peter L&#246;nnecke, E. Kirillov, Dmitri Gelman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkene Isomerization Catalyzed by a Mn(I) Bisphosphine Borohydride Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03364</link>
      <description>Ines Blaha, Stefan Weber, Robin D&#252;lger, Lu&#305;&#769;s F. Veiros, Karl Kirchner, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401660026

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ines Blaha, Stefan Weber, Robin D&#252;lger, Lu&#305;&#769;s F. Veiros, Karl Kirchner</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Effect of Dopants in Zirconia-Based Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03206</link>
      <description>Raffaele Cheula, Tuan Anh Tran, Mie Andersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401631981

                The doping of zirconia to enhance its activity and selectivity for the hydrogenation of CO2 to methanol has been studied intensively in experiments, but a thorough theoretical understanding of the factors that decide whether a dopant has a positive or negative influence on the reactivity is lacking. In this work, we conduct a mechanistic investigation using density functional theory and microkinetic modeling, considering the ZrO2(101) surface doped with 16 different metals. This analysis elucidates the following two criteria for enhanced reactivity. One, the ability of the surface to facilitate the dissociation of H2 and provide the H* species necessary for the catalytic reaction is deemed a necessary but not sufficient criterion. Two, dopants that are thermodynamically stable under reaction conditions in a 2+ or 3+ oxidation state are beneficial, since this entails the introduction of O vacancies, which stabilize O-containing reaction intermediates such as formate and lower key transition states. We construct linear scaling relations that can reliably predict transition state energies in terms of less computationally costly adsorption energies. It is revealed that dopants that are stable in the 4+ state (e.g., Ti), and thereby lack O vacancies, follow a different scaling relation with a higher intercept for formate formation, which can explain their reduced reactivity. Overall, our microkinetic models can successfully predict the trends for dopants that have been found active in experiments (Zn2+, Cd2+, Ga3+, In3+) and not. Together with the established reactivity criteria, this paves the way for computational screening of oxides for the important CO2-to-methanol process.</description>
      <author>Raffaele Cheula, Tuan Anh Tran, Mie Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intermolecular Anti-Markovnikov Hydroamination of Alkenes with Sulfonamides, Sulfamides, and Sulfamates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03960</link>
      <description>A. T. Lin, Mathis J. Karrasch, Qiaolin Yan, Jacob M. Ganley, Benjamin G. Hejna, Robert R. Knowles, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401635760

                A general method for the light-driven intermolecular anti-Markovnikov hydroamination of alkenes with primary sulfonamides, sulfamides, and sulfamates is presented. The reaction is mediated by a ternary catalyst system composed of an iridium(III) chromophore, a fluorinated alkoxide base, and a thiol H-atom donor. We hypothesize that the reactions proceed via a proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) mechanism wherein implementation of the alkoxide base imparts additional thermochemical driving force for the homolytic activation of strong N&#8211;H bonds that were previously inaccessible using this methodology. This furnishes electrophilic N-centered radicals that subsequently interface with a wide range of unactivated alkenes for C&#8211;N bond formation. This protocol exhibits a broad substrate scope and great functional group tolerance, further highlighting the advantages of excited-state PCET as a platform for catalytic radical generation from common organic functional groups.</description>
      <author>A. T. Lin, Mathis J. Karrasch, Qiaolin Yan, Jacob M. Ganley, Benjamin G. Hejna, Robert R. Knowles</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Dispersed Cu Atoms Induce Alternating Surface Microstrain in PtCu Concave Octahedral Nanoparticles Accelerating Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02973</link>
      <description>Xiashuang Luo, Cehuang Fu, Shuiyun Shen, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang, Junliang Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401643081

                A comprehensive understanding of the intricate surface environments of practical nanocatalysts at the atomic level is essential for advancing our knowledge of catalytic mechanisms. In this study, we investigate PtCu octahedral nanoparticles with varying microstrains engineered by Cu dispersion. A detailed analysis of the atom configuration and corresponding microstrain is conducted. The intimate mixing of Cu and Pt results in increased randomness in atom displacement within the lattice and a more pronounced distribution of alternating microstrain on the surfaces. Specifically, we observe that the PtCu concave octahedral nanoparticles with alternating microstrain demonstrate a substantial oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity of 3.95 mA cm&#8211;2 in area-specific activity. The significant impact of shear microstrain is further underscored, as evidenced by an 86.9% decrease in the ORR activity upon the removal of the alternating shear microstrain. This study sheds light on the effects of microstrain toward the ORR and provides valuable insights into designing advanced Pt-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiashuang Luo, Cehuang Fu, Shuiyun Shen, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Chemical Origin of Dual-Atom Sites for Enhanced Oxygen Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03068</link>
      <description>Xiannong Tang, Yuqin Zhang, Shaobin Tang, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647130

                Dual-atom catalysts have garnered widespread attention for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), yet achieving an in-depth comprehension of the reaction mechanism and the structure&#8211;activity relationship remains challenging. Herein, carbon nanosheets with FeCo&#8211;N6 active sites (FeCo-NCNS) are prepared via a straightforward self-sacrificing template and cascade anchoring strategy. Delicate structural control enables hierarchical porosity, providing adequate active site density (2.5 &#215; 1019 sites g&#8211;1) and fast mass transfer, as revealed by in situ scanning electrochemical microscopy. Moreover, the structural and chemical origin of the dual-atom site for enhanced ORR activity is uncovered. FeCo&#8211;N6 can be spontaneously transformed to an oxygen-bridging structure (FeCo&#8211;N6&#8211;O) in the KOH electrolyte, triggering improved charge polarization, downshifted d-band center, and optimized adsorption behavior for oxygen-intermediates, thereby reducing the free energy barrier. Therefore, the FeCo-NCNS exhibits enhanced ORR activity regarding the half-wave potential (0.90 V), mass specific kinetic current density (9.54 A g&#8211;1), turnover frequency (2.35 e&#8211; site&#8211;1 s&#8211;1), and improved stability. This work not only provides an effective methodology to construct efficient electrocatalysts for energy conversation but also highlights the dynamic structural evolution and charge polarization in improving the electrocatalytic activity of dual-atom sites.</description>
      <author>Xiannong Tang, Yuqin Zhang, Shaobin Tang, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i016_1834783</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401650251

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i016_1834783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i016_1834784</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401652163

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i016_1834784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bidirectional Electron Transfer Strategies for Anti-Markovnikov Olefin Aminofunctionalization via Arylamine Radicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04110</link>
      <description>Pritam Roychowdhury, Samya Samanta, Lauren R. Brown, Saim Waheed, David C. Powers, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401658377

                Arylamines are common structural motifs in pharmaceuticals, natural products, and materials precursors. While olefin aminofunctionalization chemistry can provide entry to arylamines, classical polar reactions typically afford Markovnikov products. Nitrogen-centered radical intermediates provide the opportunity to access anti-Markovnikov selectivity; however, anti-Markovnikov arylamination is unknown in large part due to the lack of arylamine radical precursors. Here, we introduce bidirectional electron transfer processes to generate arylamine radical intermediates from N-pyridinium arylamines: Single-electron oxidation provides arylamine radicals that engage in anti-Markovnikov olefin aminopyridylation; single-electron reduction unveils arylamine radicals that engage in anti-Markovnikov olefin aminofunctionalization. The development of bidirectional redox processes complements classical design principles for radical precursors, which typically function via a single redox manifold. Demonstration of both oxidative and reductive mechanisms to generate arylamine radicals from a common N-aminopyridinium precursor provides complementary methods to rapidly construct and diversify arylamine scaffolds from readily available radical precursors.</description>
      <author>Pritam Roychowdhury, Samya Samanta, Lauren R. Brown, Saim Waheed, David C. Powers</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the Parallel Biosynthetic Pathways of the Cyclohexanone and Phenol Rings in Cycloheximide and Actiphenol by Tailoring Redox Enzymes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03332</link>
      <description>Jun Tang, Xiaowei Guo, Jing Yang, Yongjiang Wang, Jianying Luo, Min Yin, Yijun Yan, Sheng&#8208;Xiong Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401658412

                The eukaryotic translation inhibitor cycloheximide (CHX) and its analogue actiphenol (APN) feature a glutarimide moiety and a six-membered carbocyclic ring system. The biosynthesis of CHX and APN is not yet fully understood, particularly with respect to the mechanism of formation of the fully reduced cyclohexanone ring in CHX and the aromatic phenol ring in APN. In this work, a combination of gene inactivation, chemical synthesis, and in vitro biochemical experiments highlighted an ensemble of three tailoring redox enzymes as being responsible for the biosynthesis of the six-membered carbocyclic ring systems. Specifically, two redox enzymes (ChxJ and ChxI) alone can generate an active intermediate that undergoes a cascade of non-enzymatic transformations to create APN, while a reductive enzyme (ChxG) acts as a gatekeeper, directing the same intermediate down a different pathway toward CHX. Finally, the full nature of each biosynthetic pathway was established in detail, including the formation mechanisms of six-membered carbocyclic rings.</description>
      <author>Jun Tang, Xiaowei Guo, Jing Yang, Yongjiang Wang, Jianying Luo, Min Yin, Yijun Yan, Sheng&#8208;Xiong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Catalyzed Site-Selective C(sp&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Alkynylation of Allenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03688</link>
      <description>Duan Xiu, Qihao Jin, Sheng Wang, Yifan Sun, Youhao Wei, Li Wang, Jiang&#8208;Kai Qiu, Kai Guo, Xiaoguang Bao, Xinxin Wu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401691251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Duan Xiu, Qihao Jin, Sheng Wang, Yifan Sun, Youhao Wei, Li Wang, Jiang&#8208;Kai Qiu, Kai Guo, Xiaoguang Bao, Xinxin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Multihalogenation of a Non-native Substrate by the SyrB2 Iron Halogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02816</link>
      <description>R. Hunter Wilson, Sourav Chatterjee, Elizabeth R. Smithwick, Anoop R. Damodaran, Ambika Bhagi&#8208;Damodaran, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401694293

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Hunter Wilson, Sourav Chatterjee, Elizabeth R. Smithwick, Anoop R. Damodaran, Ambika Bhagi&#8208;Damodaran</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Oxyalkynylation of Unactivated Alkenes Enabled by Hypervalent Iodine(III) Reagents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02977</link>
      <description>Hanzhang Qin, Zhengyi Liu, Yixin Zhang, Yiyun Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401697138

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hanzhang Qin, Zhengyi Liu, Yixin Zhang, Yiyun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective N-Heterocyclic Carbene-Catalyzed Hauser-Kraus Annulations for the Construction of C&#8211;N Axially Chiral Phthalimde Derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03263</link>
      <description>Panlong Ren, Qing Zhao, Kang Xu, Tingshun Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401701297

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Panlong Ren, Qing Zhao, Kang Xu, Tingshun Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anion-Doping-Mediated Metal&#8211;Support Interactions in CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported Pd Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02874</link>
      <description>Luyang Qiao, Xi-guang Wang, Shanshan Zong, Zhi Gao Huang, Zhangfeng Zhou, Maohong Fan, Yuan&#8208;Gen Yao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401707800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luyang Qiao, Xi-guang Wang, Shanshan Zong, Zhi Gao Huang, Zhangfeng Zhou, Maohong Fan, Yuan&#8208;Gen Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring and Visualizing Macropores of the Zeolite Monolith to Reveal the Coke Resistance Performance for Bio-oil Hydrodeoxygenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02914</link>
      <description>Fengli Gan, Xia Jiang, Ziheng Jin, Mingwu Tan, Xindi Xie, Qinjun Peng, Guang&#8208;Mei Cao, Shenggui Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401732939

                Mass transport in conventional microporous zeolite catalysts can be enhanced by introducing secondary mesopores during hydrodeoxygenation (HDO). However, the impact of the macropore architecture with intrinsic mass transfer advantages over mesopores on HDO performance remains elusive. In this study, a macroporous zeolite monolith catalyst without a template and binder was synthesized using a crystal space-confined growth method. This catalyst exhibited a 1.3 times higher macropore volume (0.566 m3/g) than a conventional zeolite catalyst, while the microporous structure was similar. Moreover, the high degree macropore connectivity was directly visualized and quantified with an advanced nanocomputed tomography technique. The macroporous catalyst achieved a higher guaiacol conversion rate of 93% and better coke resistance (3.2 wt % coke) than the conventional zeolite catalyst, which showed a 90% guaiacol conversion rate and 5.6 wt % coke. This improvement was primarily due to faster diffusion rates and an increased number of acid sites in the macropores.</description>
      <author>Fengli Gan, Xia Jiang, Ziheng Jin, Mingwu Tan, Xindi Xie, Qinjun Peng, Guang&#8208;Mei Cao, Shenggui Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stereocomplementary Unspecific Peroxygenases for Asymmetric Anti-Markovnikov Wacker-Type Oxidation and Epoxidation of Styrenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02169</link>
      <description>Alexander Swoboda, Zerina Duhovi&#263;, Isabella E. E. Kroschel, Moritz B&#252;rgler, Katharina Ebner, Anton Glieder, Wolfgang Kroutil, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401733354

                The Wacker reaction gives access to carbonyls from olefins and is traditionally relying on metals, mostly palladium. Here, unspecific peroxygenases (UPOs) are spotlighted as palladium-free biocatalysts for asymmetric anti-Markovnikov Wacker-type oxidation of styrenes, moving them beyond their traditional role in C&#8211;H oxidation and stereoselective epoxidation. Screening 53 wild-type UPOs for the oxidation of styrene and derivatives revealed examples of high reaction selectivity leading mostly to the epoxide with an epoxide selectivity of up to &gt;99%. For selected UPOs and styrene derivatives, aldehyde formation was found with an aldehyde selectivity of up to 86%. Conversions of up to 89% were reached (preferring epoxidation). Stereocomplementary UPOs were identified for the epoxidation, giving access to the (R)- and (S)-epoxides with ee values of up to 94%. Also, for the anti-Markovnikov Wacker-type oxidation of &#945;-methylstyrene, stereocomplementary enzymes were identified, leading to an excess of either the (R)- or (S)-enantiomer of 2-phenylpropanal. Most interestingly, it was found that the absolute configuration of the aldehyde formed does not necessarily correlate with the absolute configuration of the epoxide; thus, aldehyde and epoxide may have the same or the opposite absolute configurations.</description>
      <author>Alexander Swoboda, Zerina Duhovi&#263;, Isabella E. E. Kroschel, Moritz B&#252;rgler, Katharina Ebner, Anton Glieder, Wolfgang Kroutil</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Carbon Equivalent: Design and Application to Diversity-Generating Skeletal Editing from Indoles to 3-Functionalized Quinolines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03868</link>
      <description>Fu&#8208;Peng Wu, Jasper L. Tyler, Constantin G. Daniliuc, Frank Glorius, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401733426

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fu&#8208;Peng Wu, Jasper L. Tyler, Constantin G. Daniliuc, Frank Glorius</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Alloy-Induced Modifications in the Oxygen Reduction Reaction Mechanism on PtPd Single Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03565</link>
      <description>Pepe Jord&#225;-Faus, Rub&#233;n Rizo, Enrique Herrero, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401733612

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pepe Jord&#225;-Faus, Rub&#233;n Rizo, Enrique Herrero, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoinduced Surface Oxidation of GaN Nanowires Facilitates Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00308</link>
      <description>Jan Paul Menzel, Wan Jae Dong, Elijah Gruszecki, Ke Yang, Zetian Mi, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401733800

                Gallium nitride nanowires (GaN NWs) have shown great potential in applications to photocatalysis, including photocatalytic hydrogen evolution for solar energy storage. Previous studies have shown that GaN NWs can undergo self-improvement under light irradiation, which is attributed to surface oxidation, forming gallium oxynitride (GaON). However, the exact oxidation pathways and the effect of surface oxidation on catalytic performance remain to be understood at the molecular level. In this study, we combine computational modeling at the density functional theory (DFT) level with linear sweep voltammetry and chronoamperometric measurements to investigate the photoinduced surface oxidation of GaN NWs. We find that the oxidation of GaN to GaON is competitive with water oxidation. The oxidized surface shows almost no change in its water oxidation capabilities, although the potential required for hydrogen evolution is significantly reduced. Oxidation of the surface also leads to changes in the electronic structure, shifting the valence band edge states toward the surface adsorbed hydroxide, making hole localization there more likely. Calculations are consistent with the observation of shifts in the onset potential for photoelectrochemical hydrogen evolution toward more positive potentials over an extended 18 h period. The reported findings on the mechanism of photoinduced surface oxidation of GaN NWs and the effect of surface oxidation on hydrogen evolution provide valuable insights for the development of more efficient GaN NW-based photocatalytic surfaces for hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Jan Paul Menzel, Wan Jae Dong, Elijah Gruszecki, Ke Yang, Zetian Mi, V&#237;ctor S. Batista</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Catalyzed Enantioselective &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt;S&lt;/i&gt;-Rearrangement of Propargylic Xanthates: Efficient Synthesis of Chiral Propargylic Sulfur Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04509</link>
      <description>Cheng Wang, Mengwu Xiao, Wei Li, Li&#8208;Jie Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401733990

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Wang, Mengwu Xiao, Wei Li, Li&#8208;Jie Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral Br&#248;nsted Acid-Catalyzed Regio-, Diastereo-, and Enantioselective Formal [2 + 2 + 2] Cycloaddition of 3-Vinyl-1&lt;i&gt;H&lt;/i&gt;-indoles with Nitrosobenzenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05041</link>
      <description>Lei Yu, Jorge Aurelio D&#237;az, Asja A. Kroeger, Michelle L. Coote, Philip Wai Hong Chan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401734759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Yu, Jorge Aurelio D&#237;az, Asja A. Kroeger, Michelle L. Coote, Philip Wai Hong Chan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Local Structural Changes of Orthorhombic Mo&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;VO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Induced by High-Temperature Heat Treatment on Catalytic Ammoxidation of Propane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02923</link>
      <description>Kosuke Shimoda, Satoshi Ishikawa, Ken&#8208;ichi Shimizu, Wataru Ueda, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401742552

                The orthorhombic Mo3VOx (MoVO) crystal catalyst has a crystal structure analogous to that of the industrial catalyst for propane ammoxidation. However, it has been observed that MoVO exhibits poor selectivity for the formation of acrylonitrile (AN). Here, we found that a higher AN yield was attainable over the MoVO heat-treated at higher temperatures (600 &#176;C) in a pure nitrogen stream. Structural analyses revealed that high-temperature heat treatment caused local structural changes through the migration and the segregation of VO2+ without altering the basic crystal structure of MoVO. This resulted in the change in the chemical formula from Mo30.66V11.34O114 to Mo30.66V7.22O104. The kinetic analysis revealed that the local structure after the segregation of VO2+ exhibited improved catalytic activity for the ammoxidation of propylene as the primary product for this reaction, resulting in a high AN yield in the propane ammoxidation. The obtained results offer a new insight into the catalytically active structure of the Mo&#8211;V-based mixed metal oxide for the ammoxidation of propane.</description>
      <author>Kosuke Shimoda, Satoshi Ishikawa, Ken&#8208;ichi Shimizu, Wataru Ueda</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02923</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Clicking of Alkynyl Dipolarophiles and Nitrones Catalyzed by a Well-Defined Chiral Iron Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03508</link>
      <description>Zhen&#8208;Ni Zhao, Fengkai He, Yuhao Wang, Yichao Li, Zi&#8208;Han Li, Xiaoyu Yang, Uwe Schneider, Yiyong Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401793206

                The enantioselective 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition of alkynes and &#945;-aliphatic nitrones has long been recognized as an important challenge, while considerable progress has been made for the alkenes and aromatic nitrones. We herein report an example of an earth-abundant iron-catalyzed enantioselective click-approach 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition of nonterminal alkynyl imides and &#945;-aliphatic nitrones, and highly functionalized chiral 4-isoxazolines having a 3-alkyl-substituted stereogenic carbon center are modularly generated in up to &gt;99% yield and 98% ee (54 examples). Although the steric bulk substituent on the nitrone plays a key role in achieving effective enantiocontrol, the challenge of steric bias differentiation between linear alkyl chain (Me, Et, etc.) and H of nitrones is also successfully overcome. The enantioface discrimination is presumably rooted in the well-defined octahedral mononuclear ferrous complex containing dual tridentate ligands (L*&#183;Fe(OTf)2&#183;L*, L* = (R,R)-DBFOX-Ph) and possible dual-mode &#963;,&#960;-binding activation, which is evidenced by ESI-HRMS and single crystal X-ray analysis, as well as the L*/Fe ratio effect and DFT calculations. Arguably, the most interesting aspect is that the chiral iron complex can induce a superpositive nonlinear effect and the chiral bisoxazoline ligand with a low enantiopurity of 22% ee results in an 84% ee for the cycloadduct. Practicability and utility are demonstrated by the gram-scale synthesis and ready downstream functionalization based on the chiral 4-isoxazoline core and imide functional group.</description>
      <author>Zhen&#8208;Ni Zhao, Fengkai He, Yuhao Wang, Yichao Li, Zi&#8208;Han Li, Xiaoyu Yang, Uwe Schneider, Yiyong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03508</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
