<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 01:35:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into Nitrile and Alkyne Covalent Inhibitors of the SARS-CoV-2 Main Protease</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06020</link>
      <description>Ashim Nandi, Mojgan Asadi, Aoxuan Zhang, Zhen T. Chu, Arieh Warshel, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406091634

                The treatment of SARS-CoV-2 can be accomplished by effective suppression of its 3CL protease (3CLpro), also known as the main protease (Mpro) and nonstructural protein 5 (nsp5). Covalent inhibitors can irreversibly and selectively disable the protease, particularly when they are highly exothermic. Herein we investigated the distinct kinetic behaviors exhibited by two covalently linked SARS-CoV-2 inhibitors. One of these inhibitors features a nitrile reactive group, while the other has this group replaced by an alkyne group, a less reactive electrophile. Our investigations involve the assessment of the free energy surfaces of the key feasible mechanisms: that is, direct and water-assisted mechanisms involved in the rate-determining proton-transfer nucleophilic attack step through the utilization of both ab initio and empirical valence bond (EVB) simulations. The calculated free energy profiles show that substituting the nitrile group with alkyne increases the chemical barrier but leads to very exothermic reaction energy and is an irreversible process as opposed to nitrile, which is moderately exothermic and reversible. We also examine the time dependence of IC50 inhibition by applying an innovative kinetic simulation approach, which is particularly important in studies of covalent inhibitors with a very exothermic bonding step. Our computational approach provides a good agreement between the calculated and observed values of the time dependence results for the nitrile and alkyne inhibitors. Our approach, which is rather unique in combining calculations of the chemical barriers and the binding energy is likely to be very effective in studies of the effectiveness of other covalent inhibitors related cases.</description>
      <author>Ashim Nandi, Mojgan Asadi, Aoxuan Zhang, Zhen T. Chu, Arieh Warshel</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inducing Cu Charge Redistribution by Modulating Proximity with Zr(OH)&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Selective Synthesis of Imines and Secondary Amines with Stoichiometric Benzyl Alcohol and Nitrobenzene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05785</link>
      <description>Jie Song, Chunxia Che, Yiwei Dai, Jiaheng Qin, Cong Yang, Ziqiu Chen, Kexin Ma, Yuhui Han, Yu Long, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406093746

                The one-pot synthesis of amines from benzyl alcohol (BA) and nitrobenzene (NB) represents a step-economic method. However, reported works typically require more than 3 equiv of BA to complete the transfer hydrogenation of NB, and few studies can achieve selective synthesis of imines and secondary amines. In our previous work, Zr(OH)4 demonstrated both hydrogenation and dehydrogenation capabilities. Building on this, another component Cu was introduced to enhance its catalytic performance for catalyzing coupling reaction between stoichiometric BA and NB under a H2 atmosphere. The physical hybrid catalyst Cu + Zr(OH)4 selectively produced imines, while the supported catalyst Cu/Zr(OH)4 yielded secondary amines. Characterization and mechanism experiments revealed that modulating the proximity between Cu and Zr(OH)4 leads to (1) different adsorption abilities of the catalyst for N-benzylideneaniline (NBA) and (2) interactions between Zr(OH)4 and Cu in close contact, which stabilized the electronic structure of Cu forming more Cu+/Cu0 ion pairs with strong H2 activation ability. This work presents a catalyst design strategy and offers an approach for the selective preparation of N-benzylideneaniline and N-benzylaniline.</description>
      <author>Jie Song, Chunxia Che, Yiwei Dai, Jiaheng Qin, Cong Yang, Ziqiu Chen, Kexin Ma, Yuhui Han, Yu Long</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AuCu Nanodendrite for Enhancing Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction Applications via Two-stage Microfluidic Fabrication Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06559</link>
      <description>Hengyuan Liu, Yongqi Jia, Xintong Huang, Yingzhe Liu, Qiang Yang, Zhuo Chen, Jianhong Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406115611

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hengyuan Liu, Yongqi Jia, Xintong Huang, Yingzhe Liu, Qiang Yang, Zhuo Chen, Jianhong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Carboxylation via Carbene/Photoredox Cooperative Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06791</link>
      <description>Cullen R. Schull, Jing Cao, Sophia R. Mitton-Fry, Mara Mrksich, Karl A. Scheidt, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406119626

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cullen R. Schull, Jing Cao, Sophia R. Mitton-Fry, Mara Mrksich, Karl A. Scheidt</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06791</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Synthesis of Glycodiversified Nucleoside Analogues by a Thermophilic Promiscuous Glycosyltransferase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06506</link>
      <description>Zhuqing Wang, Jiahui Li, Xueyun Wang, Bo Jin, Liwei Zhou, Zili Zhao, Meijia Gu, Xuemin Song, Jiahong Wang, Zixin Deng, Shuwen Wu, Zhengyu Zhang, Wenqing Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406124998

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhuqing Wang, Jiahui Li, Xueyun Wang, Bo Jin, Liwei Zhou, Zili Zhao, Meijia Gu, Xuemin Song, Jiahong Wang, Zixin Deng, Shuwen Wu, Zhengyu Zhang, Wenqing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Catalysis Multiscale Simulations for Nonoxidative Coupling of Methane Using Light and Heat</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04312</link>
      <description>Juganta K. Roy, Mona Abdelgaid, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck, Giannis Mpourmpakis, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406125357

                Methane (CH4) activation and conversion under mild reaction conditions are a great challenge for the chemical industry. Photocatalysis is attractive for activating inert C&#8211;H bonds of CH4 at room temperature. Specifically, photocatalytic nonoxidative coupling of CH4 (NOCM) is a promising process to produce ethane (C2-hydrocarbon) and H2. Different oxide-based photocatalysts have been used for room-temperature NOCM, and TiO2 is a potential photocatalyst with a bandgap that can capture photons in the UV region. However, a fundamental understanding of the NOCM mechanism on TiO2 is still missing. Herein, we apply multiscale modeling, combining density functional theory (DFT) calculations with kinetic Monte Carlo (kMC) simulations to investigate the photocatalytic NOCM on a rutile TiO2(110) surface. DFT calculations revealed that the photogenerated holes mediate the homolytic activation of CH4 via the formation of methyl radicals with an activation barrier that is 70% lower than that of the conventional thermocatalytic route. The generated methyl radicals further recombine to form ethane. The detailed reaction pathway energetics investigated with DFT-based kMC simulations revealed that ethane can be formed at 315.15 K, but the dissociated hydrogens poison the catalyst surface. Further thermocatalytic simulations revealed that increasing the temperature by thermal heating (ca. 690.15 K) facilitated H2 formation and catalyst regeneration. Importantly, we demonstrate how photo- and thermocatalytic modes can be combined, facilitating NOCM on TiO2 and a route to enable dynamic catalysis simulations through multiscale modeling, opening alternative avenues in computational catalyst discovery.</description>
      <author>Juganta K. Roy, Mona Abdelgaid, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck, Giannis Mpourmpakis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling-Assisted Elucidation of the Organosolv Lignin Depolymerization: Lessons Learned from &#946;-Ether Cleavage over Ni/C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06058</link>
      <description>Tina Ro&#269;nik Kozmelj, Edita Jasiukaityt&#279;-Grojzdek, Matej Hu&#353;, Miha Grilc, Bla&#382; Likozar, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406125366

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tina Ro&#269;nik Kozmelj, Edita Jasiukaityt&#279;-Grojzdek, Matej Hu&#353;, Miha Grilc, Bla&#382; Likozar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt&#8211;Co Single-Atom Alloy toward Furfural Hydrogenation&#8211;Rearrangement Tandem Reaction in the Aqueous Phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07190</link>
      <description>Yuanjing Zhang, Guanyi Zhang, Quandong Hou, Shiquan Zhao, Si Wang, Enze Xu, Lei Wang, Xin Zhang, Feng Li, Yusen Yang, Min Wei, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406125406

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanjing Zhang, Guanyi Zhang, Quandong Hou, Shiquan Zhao, Si Wang, Enze Xu, Lei Wang, Xin Zhang, Feng Li, Yusen Yang, Min Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07190</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Conversion of Carbon Dioxide to Propylene Carbonate: Catalyst Design and Industrialization Progress</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06638</link>
      <description>Jun Wu, Yaxuan Du, Xiejun Wang, Fuying Zhao, Mingxuan Zhu, Jing Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406133755

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Wu, Yaxuan Du, Xiejun Wang, Fuying Zhao, Mingxuan Zhu, Jing Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dearomative 1,4-Difunctionalization of Non-Activated Arenes Enabled by Boryl Radical-Mediated Halogen-Atom Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06628</link>
      <description>Chengliang Deng, Hao Wu, Sheng Li, Chen Li, Xiaozu Liu, Peijun Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406134178

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chengliang Deng, Hao Wu, Sheng Li, Chen Li, Xiaozu Liu, Peijun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Insights into the N&#8211;N Bond-Formation Mechanism of the Heme-Dependent Piperazate Synthase KtzT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06124</link>
      <description>Yunyun Yang, Yanling Li, Licheng Yao, Kaoshan Dai, Xiaolong Fu, Aoyue Ge, Jian&#8208;Wen Huang, Rey&#8208;Ting Guo, Chun&#8208;Chi Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406140994

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunyun Yang, Yanling Li, Licheng Yao, Kaoshan Dai, Xiaolong Fu, Aoyue Ge, Jian&#8208;Wen Huang, Rey&#8208;Ting Guo, Chun&#8208;Chi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homolytic versus Heterolytic Methane Hydroxylation in Copper Zeolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06246</link>
      <description>Quan Manh Phung, Takeshi Yanai, Dieter Plessers, Bert F. Sels, Robert A. Schoonheydt, Kristine Pierloot, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406141889

                Oxygen-activated copper zeolites are capable of selectively converting methane to methanol at mild conditions, using a mono-oxygen bridged Cu(II) site [CuOCu]2+ as the active core. Based on previous DFT reports on the [CuOCu]2+ + CH4 reaction a general consensus was reached concerning the methane oxidation mechanism, where the rate-limiting step involves homolytic C&#8211;H bond cleavage to form [Cu(OH)Cu]2+ with a physisorbed &#8226;CH3. An alternative possibility, i.e. heterolytic H-abstraction passing through a four-center transition state to give an intermediate with a Cu&#8211;CH3 bond, was given consideration only in a few recent DFT studies, but was found less favorable than radical C&#8211;H activation. In this contribution methane-to-methanol conversion by Cu&#8211;CHA is investigated using large cluster models and employing either DFT, with an extensive list of 97 functionals, or the high-level correlated DMRG/cu(4)-CASPT2 method. In all cases homolytic C&#8211;H dissociation most favorably proceeds via a (S = 1) transition state TS1r, whereas the transition state of heterolytic H-abstraction, TS1n, has an (S = 0) ground state. The DMRG/cu(4)-CASPT2 results convincingly point to the heterolytic route, with a calculated activation enthalpy of 12.3 kcal/mol, as compared to 21.1 kcal/mol for homolytic C&#8211;H dissociation. In contrast, the results obtained with DFT are strongly functional dependent. Conform with previous DFT studies, homolytic H-abstraction is preferred by the B3LYP functional (almost exclusively used in previous cluster model studies). However, many other functionals, hybrid meta-GGA functionals in particular, agree with DMRG/cu(4)-CASPT2 on heterolytic C&#8211;H activation. The present results reopen the debate on the general validity of the radical rebound mechanism for methane hydroxylation by a [CuOCu]2+ core in copper zeolites and also highlight the need for caution when relying on a specific DFT functional to elucidate oxidation reaction mechanisms in metal-based catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Quan Manh Phung, Takeshi Yanai, Dieter Plessers, Bert F. Sels, Robert A. Schoonheydt, Kristine Pierloot</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Rutile TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Endowed by Electron-Capturing Center and Plasma Effect for Enhanced Solar Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04380</link>
      <description>Xin Tao, Yihai Zhou, Meng Pan, Shenghui Liu, Yong Zhou, Renchun Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406143470

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Tao, Yihai Zhou, Meng Pan, Shenghui Liu, Yong Zhou, Renchun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Asynchronous, Concerted Mechanism for Cytochrome P450-Catalyzed Dehydrogenation: A Combined Deuterium Labeling and QM/MM Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06278</link>
      <description>Alicia M. Kirk, Jeanette E. Stok, Siew Hoon Wong, Tom Coleman, Victoria L. Challinor, Joel N. Herring, J.B. Bruning, Paul V. Bernhardt, Stephen G. Bell, Elizabeth H. Krenske, James J. De Voss, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406155163

                Cytochromes P450 (P450s) commonly catalyze hydroxylation but can also be responsible for dehydrogenation reactions, important in drug metabolism and biosynthesis; the mechanism of the latter transformation remains poorly understood. The well-characterized bacterial CYP199A4 catalyzes both hydroxylation and dehydrogenation of p-alkylbenzoic acids and thus provides an ideal model system in which to investigate the mechanism of P450-catalyzed aliphatic dehydrogenation. Through use of enantioselectively deuterated probes, metabolite analysis, protein crystallography, molecular dynamics simulations and QM/MM (ONIOM) modeling, CYP199A4-catalyzed dehydrogenation was found to be completely enantioselective and postulated to occur through an asynchronous proton coupled electron transfer. No definitive evidence of a cationic intermediate was uncovered but instead, the positioning of the substrate was postulated to be key in directing the chemoselectivity of the reaction i.e., dehydrogenation versus hydroxylation. This knowledge could be exploited to control dehydrogenation in other P450s and helps explain the common occurrence of P450-desaturated drug metabolites alongside hydroxylated ones.</description>
      <author>Alicia M. Kirk, Jeanette E. Stok, Siew Hoon Wong, Tom Coleman, Victoria L. Challinor, Joel N. Herring, J.B. Bruning, Paul V. Bernhardt, Stephen G. Bell, Elizabeth H. Krenske, James J. De Voss</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Catalyst Surfaces at Work: Introducing Mixed Isotope Operando Infrared Spectroscopy (MIOIRS)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06308</link>
      <description>Matteo Monai, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406170106

                This Perspective focuses on the characterization of supported metal catalysts by operando and CO infrared (IR) spectroscopy. CO IR spectroscopy is a powerful technique for probing catalyst surfaces and is used to identify single-atom catalysts, estimate metal surface availability to the gas phase, and measure catalyst Lewis acidity. However, the interpretation of CO IR spectra on metal surfaces is not trivial and is influenced by dipole&#8211;dipole interactions among CO molecules at medium to high coverage. Such a phenomenon results in spectral distortions, such as intensity transfer among IR bands, the appearance of spurious bands, and shifts in band position. Dipole&#8211;dipole interactions were widely investigated and understood from the 1950s to 1990s, but the implications for operando spectroscopy have been seemingly overlooked in the literature, with a few exceptions. Inspired by seminal studies in the field, I propose here the use of mixed isotopic streams, such as diluted 13CO in 12CO, to reduce dipole coupling effects and retrieve more information from operando IR spectra in reactions involving CO, such as CO oxidation or hydrogenation reactions. Similarly, mixed 13CO2/12CO2 streams may be applied in CO2 hydrogenation, where adsorbed CO is commonly observed. The proposed name of the technique is Mixed Isotope Operando IR Spectroscopy, MIOIRS. In this Perspective, I will first summarize the nature of dipole&#8211;dipole interactions in adsorbed CO layers and their effects on CO IR spectra. Then, I will briefly describe how diluted isotopic mixtures of CO can partially break the coupling among adsorbates and reduce spectral distortion. In both sections, I will give a few showcases of the implications of vibrational coupling in the characterization of heterogeneous catalysts. Finally, I will discuss the possible implications of MIOIRS for the detection and quantification of defect and surface sites on metal nanoparticles, the characterization of bimetallic nanoparticles surfaces, and the kinetics of CO intermediates adsorbed on different active sites. Notably, MIOIRS may be expanded to other reactions in which adsorbates have strong permanent dipoles, such as in self-catalytic reduction for NOx abatement.</description>
      <author>Matteo Monai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Insights into the Roles of Surface and Lattice Hydrogen in Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06133</link>
      <description>Pengcheng Zhao, Li Deng, Chang Sun, Xiang Li, Xiaoyu Tian, Zhuo Li, Wenchao Sheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406183003

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengcheng Zhao, Li Deng, Chang Sun, Xiang Li, Xiaoyu Tian, Zhuo Li, Wenchao Sheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decorating Cu Nanoparticles with Pd Clusters for Enhanced Nitrile Electro-Hydrogenation to Primary Amines by Effective Hydrogen Spillover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06206</link>
      <description>Peipei Zhu, Mingzhu Shi, Bing Wu, Xunfan Liao, Mengning Ding, Longbin Li, Yiwang Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406187801

                The H2O-participating electrochemical hydrogenation (ECH) of benzonitrile represents a mild and efficient method for benzylamine synthesis, but the kinetics and Faraday efficiency are still limited. Herein, the developed Pd clusters dispersed Cu nanoparticles encapsulated in porous carbon (Pdn-Cu@C) achieves efficient ECH of benzonitrile (C6H5CN) to benzylamines (C6H5CH2NH2). In situ infrared spectroscopy and theoretical studies reveal that the Pd/Cu interface functions as the active site for active hydrogen (*H) generated by H2O dissociation, enhances the adsorption of C6H5CN, and weakens the adsorption of C6H5CH2NH2. Moreover, the Gibbs free energy barriers for *H spillover are much lower than that of *H self-coupling. As expected, Pdn-Cu@C exhibits efficient electro-hydrogenation of C6H5CN with the conversion of 97.42%, a high C6H5CH2NH2 selectivity of 97.21%, and Faradaic efficiency of 92.10% under a specific voltage. This finding blazes a feasible trail to suppress the competitive *H self-coupling and offers insights for multistep protonation ECH reactions.</description>
      <author>Peipei Zhu, Mingzhu Shi, Bing Wu, Xunfan Liao, Mengning Ding, Longbin Li, Yiwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactions of Surface Peroxides Contribute to Rates and Selectivities for C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Epoxidation on Silver</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06945</link>
      <description>Ching&#8208;Tien Chen, Anna Sviripa, Sandeep Verma, Christopher Paolucci, David W. Flaherty, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406196996

                Partial oxidation of ethylene over silver catalysts produces more than 30 million metric tons of ethylene oxide (EO) annually. However, the form of active silver surfaces, reactive oxygen species, and dominant pathways of this chemical reaction remains controversial despite decades of research. Here, we use operando Raman spectroscopy and transient kinetic measurements to demonstrate that higher coverages of peroxide species, present only upon Ag oxide surfaces that form in situ, correlate with greater selectivities to EO. Ab initio calculations reveal that the reconstructed Ag oxides preferentially stabilize diatomic oxygen species (peroxide and superoxide) under relevant conditions, and these species contribute to the selective formation of EO. The dominant reaction pathways change with surface coverages; however, bound O2 consistently activates by reaction with C2H4, and products form subsequently through peroxo- and oxometallacycle surface complexes. Taken together, density functional theory calculations and kinetic and transient experimental measurements show that the formation of peroxide intermediates requires oxidation of the Ag surface (via subsurface oxygen), and an increase in surface peroxides coincides with the highest EO selectivity for the unpromoted Ag catalyst. These findings suggest that the promoters ubiquitous for ethylene epoxidation (e.g., chlorine, transition metals, and alkali metals) may succeed by oxidation of Ag and increasing coverages of peroxides at industrial conditions.</description>
      <author>Ching&#8208;Tien Chen, Anna Sviripa, Sandeep Verma, Christopher Paolucci, David W. Flaherty</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pendant Catechol Group Improves the Performance of Iron Porphyrin CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05531</link>
      <description>Ana Sonea, Jeffrey J. Warren, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406199451

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ana Sonea, Jeffrey J. Warren</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen-Assisted Dissociation of N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Prevalence and Consequences for Ammonia Synthesis on Supported Ru Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06966</link>
      <description>Yukun Bai, Yuanbao Zhang, Jianhua Hu, Li Jiang, Shaolong Wan, Jingdong Lin, Yong Wang, Shuai Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406201945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yukun Bai, Yuanbao Zhang, Jianhua Hu, Li Jiang, Shaolong Wan, Jingdong Lin, Yong Wang, Shuai Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06966</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the Adjacent Microenvironment of Atomically Dispersed FeN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Sites via Cross-Link-Induced 3D Carbon Nest for Efficient Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06546</link>
      <description>Tonghui Zhao, Guangjin Wang, Dongdong Xiao, Min Young Song, Yanmin Hu, Tingting Chao, Yapeng Li, Zedong Zhang, Yun Lu, Mingxing Gong, Tao Shen, Deli Wang, Huile Jin, Dingsheng Wang, Wei Chen, Yadong Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210421

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tonghui Zhao, Guangjin Wang, Dongdong Xiao, Min Young Song, Yanmin Hu, Tingting Chao, Yapeng Li, Zedong Zhang, Yun Lu, Mingxing Gong, Tao Shen, Deli Wang, Huile Jin, Dingsheng Wang, Wei Chen, Yadong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06546</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Catalytic Asymmetric Ketone Allylations and Their Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07194</link>
      <description>Lie Wang, Ruoshi Jin, Yiyuan Peng, Qiuping Ding, Xing&#8208;Ping Zeng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210431

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lie Wang, Ruoshi Jin, Yiyuan Peng, Qiuping Ding, Xing&#8208;Ping Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Br&#248;nsted Acid-Facilitated Thioetherification Cross-Coupling Reactions with Nickel and Visible Light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06734</link>
      <description>Maksim Nikitin, S&#225;ndor B. &#214;tv&#246;s, Indrajit Ghosh, Maximilian Philipp, Ruth M. Gschwind, C. Oliver Kappe, Burkhard Koenig, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210452

                Transition metal-catalyzed cross-coupling reactions are essential in modern organic synthesis, facilitating the rapid creation of complex molecular structures. Traditionally, these reactions rely heavily on conventional bases, with only a few exceptions reported. Recently, we developed adaptive dynamic homogeneous catalysis (AD-HoC), a method that enables C(sp2)&#8211;S cross-couplings without needing traditional ligands, bases, or additives. Given the growing demand for protocols compatible with acidic conditions in metal-catalyzed cross-couplings, we revisited AD-HoC to pioneer acid-facilitated transition metal-catalyzed thioetherification. Our method enables the swift synthesis of thioethers using nickel and visible light, with a substoichiometric amount of Br&#248;nsted acid acting as an enabler. NMR kinetic studies indicate that in the absence of acid, the system displays an induction period characteristic of autocatalysis. Introducing the acid as a simple additive eliminates this induction period and significantly accelerates the reaction. Moreover, the protocol has been successfully scaled to gram-level synthesis using continuous flow technology, achieving productivities of over 100 g per hour in a commercially available lab-scale photoreactor. This highlights the method's robustness and scalability, making it a powerful tool for large-scale applications.</description>
      <author>Maksim Nikitin, S&#225;ndor B. &#214;tv&#246;s, Indrajit Ghosh, Maximilian Philipp, Ruth M. Gschwind, C. Oliver Kappe, Burkhard Koenig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exceptionally Low-Coordinated Bismuth&#8211;Oxygen Vacancy Defect Clusters for Generating Black In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Photocatalysts with Superb CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03491</link>
      <description>Farzin Nekouei, Christopher J. Pollock, Tianyi Wang, Zhong Zheng, Yanzhao Zhang, Zelio Fusco, Huanyu Jin, Thrinathreddy Ramireddy, Ary Anggara Wibowo, Teng L&#252;, Shahram Nekouei, Farzaneh Keshtpour, Julien Langley, Elwy H. Abdelkader, Nicholas J. Cox, Zongyou Yin, Hieu T. Nguyen, Alexey M. Glushenkov, Siva Krishna Karuturi, Zongwen Liu, Wei Li, Hao Li, Yun Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406217331

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Farzin Nekouei, Christopher J. Pollock, Tianyi Wang, Zhong Zheng, Yanzhao Zhang, Zelio Fusco, Huanyu Jin, Thrinathreddy Ramireddy, Ary Anggara Wibowo, Teng L&#252;, Shahram Nekouei, Farzaneh Keshtpour, Julien Langley, Elwy H. Abdelkader, Nicholas J. Cox, Zongyou Yin, Hieu T. Nguyen, Alexey M. Glushenkov, Siva Krishna Karuturi, Zongwen Liu, Wei Li, Hao Li, Yun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Enantioselective Tandem C&#8211;H Indolization toward Biindolyl Atropisomers: Reaction Development and Mechanistic Insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06594</link>
      <description>Zhi&#8208;Huan Peng, Ping Huang, Ao-Long Li, Mingkai Yang, Zhikang Li, Yuanyuan Li, Qin Shi, Jiating Cai, Shengdong Wang, Zhi Zhou, Wei Yi, Hui Gao, Zhongyi Zeng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406218794

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhi&#8208;Huan Peng, Ping Huang, Ao-Long Li, Mingkai Yang, Zhikang Li, Yuanyuan Li, Qin Shi, Jiating Cai, Shengdong Wang, Zhi Zhou, Wei Yi, Hui Gao, Zhongyi Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled Growth of Silver Nanoparticles by Metal&#8211;Support Interaction for Enhanced Tandem Catalytic Oxidation of HCHO at Low Temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05879</link>
      <description>Yue Ding, Hui Wang, Bin Huang, Yuchun Chang, Hua Yang, Zhenping Qu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406219352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue Ding, Hui Wang, Bin Huang, Yuchun Chang, Hua Yang, Zhenping Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lowering the Kinetic Barrier via the Synergistic Catalysis of N-CNTs Supported RhP Subnanoclusters and Confined Co Nanoparticles for Olefins Hydroformylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06822</link>
      <description>Jiamei Wei, Peng Gao, Shen Wang, Yue Ma, Dong Cao, Daojian Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406219626

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiamei Wei, Peng Gao, Shen Wang, Yue Ma, Dong Cao, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06822</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
