<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:38:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of Catalysis by the [Ga&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;L&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;]&lt;sup&gt;12&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; Metallocage on the Prins Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04696</link>
      <description>Iker Zapirain-Gysling, Gantulga Norjmaa, Jean&#8208;Didier Mar&#233;chal, Gregori Ujaque, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405181903

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Iker Zapirain-Gysling, Gantulga Norjmaa, Jean&#8208;Didier Mar&#233;chal, Gregori Ujaque</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Chemistry and Machine Learning-Assisted Screening of Supported Amorphous Metal Oxide Nanoclusters for Methane Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04021</link>
      <description>Xijun Wang, Kaihang Shi, Anyang Peng, Randall Q. Snurr, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405197131

                Activating the C&#8211;H bond in methane represents a cornerstone challenge in catalytic research. While several supported metal oxide nanoclusters (MeO-NCs) have shown promise for this reaction, their optimal composition remains underexplored primarily due to the large number of possible compositions and their amorphous nature. This study addresses these challenges using computational approaches. Leveraging density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we began with a previously studied supported tetra-copper oxide nanocluster and systematically substituted its Cu sites with first-row transition metals (Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, and Zn). This process allowed us to examine the catalytic activity of 162 MeO-NCs with a variety of geometric and electronic structures, leading to 12 new compositions that outperformed the base nanocluster. Exploring the structure&#8211;activity relationships with machine learning, our analysis uncovered correlations between the intrinsic electronic and structural properties of the nanoclusters and the free energy barriers for methane activation despite the challenges posed by the structural flexibility of these amorphous nanoclusters. The results offer insights into the optimization of MeO-NCs for methane activation. Additionally, we developed a clustering model capable of distinguishing high-performing nanoclusters from less effective ones with strong tolerance to the interference from the structural flexibility of these amorphous nanoclusters. These findings help narrow down the material design space for more time-consuming high-level quantum chemical calculations, offering a promising pathway toward advancing eco-friendly methane conversion.</description>
      <author>Xijun Wang, Kaihang Shi, Anyang Peng, Randall Q. Snurr</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diastereodivergent Parallel Kinetic Resolution of Racemic 2-Substituted Pyrrolidines via Iridium-Catalyzed C(&lt;i&gt;sp&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Borylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06245</link>
      <description>Maosheng He, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Lili Chen, Senmiao Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405197232

                Chiral 2,5-disubstituted pyrrolidines are ubiquitous subunits in natural products, bioactive compounds, pharmaceuticals, and chiral catalysts. However, their asymmetric synthesis still presents a formidable challenge. We herein report a rare example of diastereodivergent parallel kinetic resolution of racemic 2-substituted pyrrolidines via C(sp3)&#8211;H borylation. A vast array of enantioenriched cis- and trans-2,5-disubstituted pyrrolidines were obtained with high enantioselectivities. The synthetic utility was demonstrated by downstream transformations, including the synthesis of optically active pyrrolidine 197B and cis-pyrrolidine 225H.</description>
      <author>Maosheng He, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Lili Chen, Senmiao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Hydrodeoxygenation of Lignin via Aryl Ether C&#8211;O Bond Cleavage: Cs-Mediated Cu Surface Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05146</link>
      <description>Xiaofei Wang, Mei&#8208;Yan Wang, Maoshuai Li, Yue Wang, Xuliang Lin, Yanlin Qin, Xinbin Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405222542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaofei Wang, Mei&#8208;Yan Wang, Maoshuai Li, Yue Wang, Xuliang Lin, Yanlin Qin, Xinbin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of &lt;i&gt;E&lt;/i&gt;-3-Alkenyl 2&lt;i&gt;H&lt;/i&gt;-Indazoles via Pd/Cu-Catalyzed Cross-coupling/Cyclization of 2-Iodoazoarenes with Terminal Allylenes and Visible-Light-Promoted Isomerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06448</link>
      <description>Kalin Mei, Rui Huang, Haiyang Huang, Hongli Bao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405226277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kalin Mei, Rui Huang, Haiyang Huang, Hongli Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium-Catalyzed Formal Asymmetric Reductive Isomerization of &#945;-Hydroxyenones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05378</link>
      <description>Wennan Dong, Caiyi Ren, Lixuan Zhu, Peng Luo, Zhifei Zhao, Shouang Lan, Jinggong Liu, Shuang Yang, Qi Zhang, Xinqiang Fang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405236100

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wennan Dong, Caiyi Ren, Lixuan Zhu, Peng Luo, Zhifei Zhao, Shouang Lan, Jinggong Liu, Shuang Yang, Qi Zhang, Xinqiang Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Oxide-Oriented Ethanol Synthesis via Dimethyl Oxalate Hydrogenation from Syngas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06219</link>
      <description>Yannan Sun, Ke Fu, Jian Wei, Qingjie Ge, Qingxiang Ma, Guofeng Wang, Jian Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405240108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yannan Sun, Ke Fu, Jian Wei, Qingjie Ge, Qingxiang Ma, Guofeng Wang, Jian Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Catalyzed Asymmetric Synthesis of &#946;- or &#946;,&#947;-Substituted GABA Derivatives Enabled by Photoactive Ternary Electron Donor&#8211;Acceptor Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06549</link>
      <description>Ying Xie, Zemin Lai, Albert S. C. Chan, Jing Guo, Gui Lu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405246639

                Enantiopure &#947;-amino butyric acids (GABA) and derivatives have important applications in medicinal chemistry, especially for the treatment of central nervous system diseases. Many marketed drugs feature this moiety. In this context, we have developed a highly enantioselective catalytic strategy for rapidly forging &#946;- or &#946;,&#947;-substituted GABA derivatives by exploiting an unexplored ternary electron donor&#8211;acceptor (EDA) complex simultaneously driven by visible light and chiral Ni catalyst. With this cooperative catalytic system, a range of structurally diverse &#946;- or &#946;,&#947;-substituted GABA derivatives have been achieved in high yields with good enantio- and diastereoselectivities (up to 88% yield, &gt;99% ee, &gt;19:1 dr). Mechanistic studies indicate that the key to success is the dual role of the chiral Ni catalyst, which not only promotes the formation of ternary EDA complexes generated from redox-active esters, Hantzsch esters, and chiral Ni catalyst but can also precisely provide asymmetric induction. The synthetic benefits of this method were proved by enabling easy synthetic access to pharmaceuticals or related bioactive molecules such as pregabalin, baclofen, rolipram, and phenibut.</description>
      <author>Ying Xie, Zemin Lai, Albert S. C. Chan, Jing Guo, Gui Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of Chiral Acyclic Nitriles Containing &#945;-All-Carbon Quaternary Stereocenters via Synergistic Palladium and Phase-Transfer Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06364</link>
      <description>Cheng Guo, Yunpeng Dong, Yi Wang, Xiaona Du, Runxia Ma, Choon&#8208;Hong Tan, Xinjun Luan, Jingyun Ren, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405265174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Guo, Yunpeng Dong, Yi Wang, Xiaona Du, Runxia Ma, Choon&#8208;Hong Tan, Xinjun Luan, Jingyun Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zwitterionic &#960;-Allyl-Pd Species Enabled [2&#963;+2&#960;] Cycloaddition Reactions of Vinylbicyclo[1.1.0]butanes (VBCBs) with Alkenes, Carbonyls, and Imines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06660</link>
      <description>Tianxiang Li, Sheng Wang, Jing Wang, Haosong Ren, Zhongren Lin, Zhenyue Li, Jun Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405273729

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianxiang Li, Sheng Wang, Jing Wang, Haosong Ren, Zhongren Lin, Zhenyue Li, Jun Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Gas Nanovessel Promotes Hydrogen Peroxide Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05357</link>
      <description>Junsheng He, Xiaoshan Zheng, Qunxing Huang, Zhenhua Pan, Chiheng Chu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405273771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junsheng He, Xiaoshan Zheng, Qunxing Huang, Zhenhua Pan, Chiheng Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of VldE (Spr1875), a Pneumococcal Two-State &lt;scp&gt;l&lt;/scp&gt;,&lt;scp&gt;d&lt;/scp&gt;-Endopeptidase with a Four-Zinc Cluster in the Active Site</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05090</link>
      <description>Vega Miguel-Ruano, Iv&#225;n Acebr&#243;n, Mijoon Lee, Antonio J. Mart&#237;n-Galiano, C&#233;line Freton, Ux&#237;a P. de Jos&#233;, Balajee Ramachandran, Federico Gago, Morten Kjos, Du&#353;an Hesek, Christophe Grangeasse, Leiv Sigve H&#229;varstein, Daniel Straume, Shahriar Mobashery, J.A. Hermoso, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274852

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vega Miguel-Ruano, Iv&#225;n Acebr&#243;n, Mijoon Lee, Antonio J. Mart&#237;n-Galiano, C&#233;line Freton, Ux&#237;a P. de Jos&#233;, Balajee Ramachandran, Federico Gago, Morten Kjos, Du&#353;an Hesek, Christophe Grangeasse, Leiv Sigve H&#229;varstein, Daniel Straume, Shahriar Mobashery, J.A. Hermoso</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd-Catalyzed C&#8211;H Activation vs &#946;-H Elimination: An Experimental and Computational Insight into the Reactivity of Tertiary Alkylamines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06160</link>
      <description>Jesus Rodrigalvarez, Matthew J. Gaunt, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jesus Rodrigalvarez, Matthew J. Gaunt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional and Structural Analyses of a Highly Multifunctional Enzyme TM1270 from the Hyperthermophile &lt;i&gt;Thermotoga maritima&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05275</link>
      <description>Tetsuya Miyamoto, S. Nitta, Hiroshi Homma, Shinya Fushinobu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405276133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tetsuya Miyamoto, S. Nitta, Hiroshi Homma, Shinya Fushinobu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Photothermal Tandem Catalysis for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Boosted by Zr&#8211;O&#8211;W Interfacial H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O Dissociation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06218</link>
      <description>Ruoxuan Peng, Yuqi Ren, Yitao Si, Kai Huang, Jiancheng Zhou, Lunbo Duan, Naixu Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405302796

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruoxuan Peng, Yuqi Ren, Yitao Si, Kai Huang, Jiancheng Zhou, Lunbo Duan, Naixu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Aromatic Cope Rearrangement with Gold(I) Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06662</link>
      <description>Pierre Locquet, R. Akilan, Raquel Pereira, Fabienne Grellepois, Jean&#8208;Marc Weibel, &#201;ric H&#233;non, Emmanuel Riguet, Aur&#233;lien Blanc, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405304851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pierre Locquet, R. Akilan, Raquel Pereira, Fabienne Grellepois, Jean&#8208;Marc Weibel, &#201;ric H&#233;non, Emmanuel Riguet, Aur&#233;lien Blanc</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06662</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Catalyzed Markovnikov-Selective Radical Hydrochalcogenation of Unactivated Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06770</link>
      <description>Jiayi Li, Lei Zhu, Zhaohui Liu, H. Liu, Si-Chen Tao, S. H. Zhu, Yan&#8208;Long Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405312226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayi Li, Lei Zhu, Zhaohui Liu, H. Liu, Si-Chen Tao, S. H. Zhu, Yan&#8208;Long Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation and Stabilization of Engineered Amine Dehydrogenase by Fatty Acids for Bioprocess Intensification of Asymmetric Reductive Amination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05904</link>
      <description>Weixi Kong, Jiawang Zhang, Liya Zhou, Guanhua Liu, Ying He, Li Ma, Frank Hollmann, Sheng Wang, Yunting Liu, Yanjun Jiang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405312334

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weixi Kong, Jiawang Zhang, Liya Zhou, Guanhua Liu, Ying He, Li Ma, Frank Hollmann, Sheng Wang, Yunting Liu, Yanjun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05904</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Indium&#8211;Palladium Intermetallic Catalysts for Selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04670</link>
      <description>Jiabao Lv, Hongman Sun, Guanying Liu, Tong Liu, Guofeng Zhao, Youhe Wang, Xin Tu, Zifeng Yan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405312574

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiabao Lv, Hongman Sun, Guanying Liu, Tong Liu, Guofeng Zhao, Youhe Wang, Xin Tu, Zifeng Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Photoredox-Catalyzed Divergent Strategy for the Site-Selective Arylation and Alkylation of Glycines and Peptides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06254</link>
      <description>Prahallad Meher, M. Siva Prasad, Karan Ramdas Thombare, Sandip Murarka, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405319097

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Prahallad Meher, M. Siva Prasad, Karan Ramdas Thombare, Sandip Murarka</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Step Construction of Atropisomers Bearing 1,5-Central and Axial Chirality via Catalytic Diastereo- and Atroposelective Remote Desymmetrizing Alkynylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06332</link>
      <description>Shan Wang, Long Li, Ming Jiang, Kaixin Zhao, Daming He, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang, Yingcheng Wang, Fangzhi Peng, Zhihui Shao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405333449

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shan Wang, Long Li, Ming Jiang, Kaixin Zhao, Daming He, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang, Yingcheng Wang, Fangzhi Peng, Zhihui Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous Tandem Catalysis Strategy for Additive-Free CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation into Formic Acid in Water: Crystal Plane Effect of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Cocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05484</link>
      <description>Kohsuke Mori, Jun Shinogi, Yuki Shimada, Hiromi Yamashita, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405333957

                The transformation of carbon dioxide (CO2) into formic acid (FA; HCOOH) in an aqueous phase is a promising method of realizing an environmentally friendly FA/CO2-mediated chemical hydrogen storage/supply cycle. Despite progress in the design of catalysts that operate under basic conditions, the development of efficient catalysts that operate under additive-free conditions lags behind owing to the difficulty in activating CO2 and the low solubility of CO2 in pure water. In the present study, we present a heterogeneous tandem catalysis strategy in which Co3O4 is used as a CO2 hydration cocatalyst to produce a HCO3&#8211; intermediate, in combination with our previously reported PdAg/TiO2 as a catalyst for the hydrogenation of HCO3&#8211; to afford FA. The turnover number based on Pd improved by a factor of more than 8 in the presence of the Co3O4 cocatalyst with a cubic particle morphology enclosed by (100) facets. A series of morphology-controlled Co3O4 cocatalysts was investigated to elucidate the effect of the exposed crystal facets (i.e., (100), (111), or (112)) on their physicochemical properties and catalytic activity in FA synthesis. A systematic comparison based on experimental and density functional theory calculations demonstrated that the substantial enhancement effect of the Co3O4 cubes is attributable to the in situ generation of the largest amount of surface Co&#8211;OH groups with strong basicity originating from the exposed (100) facets. In addition, the present tandem catalytic system displayed high recyclability without exhibiting a structural change or a significant loss of activity. These findings will allow the rational design of an environmentally benign catalytic system for the hydrogenation of CO2 to FA.</description>
      <author>Kohsuke Mori, Jun Shinogi, Yuki Shimada, Hiromi Yamashita</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ordered Adsorption of Oxygen via High-Density Low-Coordinated Ru Sites for Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03294</link>
      <description>Yu Zhang, Junguo Ma, Zewen Zhuang, Aijian Huang, Shuting Zhang, Wenbo Zhai, Yi Yu, Qing Peng, Hai Xiao, Caiyun Nan, Chen Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405333965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Zhang, Junguo Ma, Zewen Zhuang, Aijian Huang, Shuting Zhang, Wenbo Zhai, Yi Yu, Qing Peng, Hai Xiao, Caiyun Nan, Chen Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multisite CuNi/Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst Enabling High-Efficiency Reductive Amination of Biomass-Derived Levulinic Acid (Esters) to Pyrrolidones under Mild Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06035</link>
      <description>Xixi Liu, Peng Zhou, Zhihua Zhu, Yimeng Guo, Hang Lv, Zehui Zhang, Liangfang Zhu, Changwei Hu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405364003

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xixi Liu, Peng Zhou, Zhihua Zhu, Yimeng Guo, Hang Lv, Zehui Zhang, Liangfang Zhu, Changwei Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biocatalytic Formal Asymmetric &lt;i&gt;para&lt;/i&gt;-Aminoethylation of Unprotected Phenols to Chiral Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06475</link>
      <description>Jingqi Zhang, Xuan Deng, Xue Han, Shuangping Huang, Honghong Chang, Lili Gao, Jiandong Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405364941

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingqi Zhang, Xuan Deng, Xue Han, Shuangping Huang, Honghong Chang, Lili Gao, Jiandong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid/Base-Tuned Asymmetric Reductive Heck and Denitrogenative Heck Reactions of In Situ-Formed &#945;,&#946;-Unsaturated Hydrazone</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05561</link>
      <description>Shuling Yu, Xiaoyu Zhou, Xiaofeng Tong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405366807

                Despite significant progress in the catalytic asymmetric 1,4-additions between various Michael donors and acceptors, the exploration of organohalide donors remains elusive. Herein, we report the Pd(0)-catalyzed asymmetric intramolecular 1,4-additions of vinyl/aryl iodides to &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated hydrazones, featuring in situ-formed hydrazone and acid/base-tuned reaction pathways. Due to its strong coordination ability, the hydrazone is capable of steering the C&#8211;C bond formation to follow the 1,4-addition mechanism instead of the conventional alkene insertion, thus enabling the generation of vinylhydrazinyl&#8211;Pd2+ species via the Zimmerman&#8211;Traxler chairlike transition state. Notably, this species preferentially undergoes protonation under acidic conditions, furnishing a reductive Heck reaction with the aid of a native hydrazine reductant, while it is susceptible to &#946;-HN elimination under basic conditions to achieve a denitrogenative Heck reaction. The catalytic protocol affords highly enantioselective access to diverse heterocycles, with alkene and hydrazone groups poised for further chemical manipulations.</description>
      <author>Shuling Yu, Xiaoyu Zhou, Xiaofeng Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atroposelective Three-Component (Fluoro)methylative Alkylation of Terminal Alkynes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06100</link>
      <description>Yaheng Zhao, Liping Huo, Xiaoyu Zhao, Lingling Chu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405376697

                The development of synthetic methods for the selective installation of methyl and fluoromethyl groups is highly desired due to their critical role in drug development. While significant advances have been made in the methylation and difluoromethylation of aromatic compounds, the catalytic atroposelective (fluoro)methylative functionalization of alkynes to forge axially chiral alkenes remains underexploited. Herein, we report an enantioselective cross-electrophile strategy for the efficient 1,2-carbo-(fluoro)methylation of alkynes with two different alkyl halides via nickel catalysis. By integrating a one-electron radical process with a two-electron organometallic process, this protocol employs a simple chiral nickel catalyst to effectively discriminate between secondary and tertiary alkyl groups and (fluoro)methyl groups for alkyne difunctionalization. This protocol demonstrates good compatibility of activated secondary/tertiary alkyl bromides, terminal alkynes, and (fluoro)methyl halides, permitting the straightforward synthesis of a broad range of synthetically valuable axially chiral (fluoro)methyl-substituted alkenes with high chemo-, regio-, trans-, and atropo-selectivity. Preliminary mechanistic studies provide insight into the potential reaction pathway.</description>
      <author>Yaheng Zhao, Liping Huo, Xiaoyu Zhao, Lingling Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Interface-Dependent Active Sites Induced by Strong Metal&#8211;Support Interactions on Au/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in 2,5-Bis(hydroxymethyl)furan Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05341</link>
      <description>Enhui Du, Jie Yang, Liyuan Huai, Panpan Hao, Mingxin Lv, Zhilin Chen, Yuxiang Chen, Jian Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405378410

                Strong metal&#8211;support interactions (SMSI) typically induce the migration of a coverage layer to the metal surface accompanied by electron transfer, forming a unique metal&#8211;support interface. This dual modification in geometric and electronic structures reconstructs the active surface, adjusting the activity and stability of the catalyst. However, identifying and quantifying such newly formed interfacial sites remains a challenge. Herein, by varying the reduction temperature to control the TiO2&#8211;x coverage on Au nanoparticles, the catalytic activity of Au/TiO2 in 2,5-bis(hydroxymethyl)furan (BHMF) oxidation shows a volcano-shaped trend. Combined thiol titration and poisoning kinetics analysis to quantify the ratio of interfacial to surface sites and normalize it to intrinsic activity, revealing that Au-TiO2&#8211;x interfacial sites positively contribute to catalytic performance. This study offers valuable insights into the active sites in heterogeneous catalytic systems with SMSI effects.</description>
      <author>Enhui Du, Jie Yang, Liyuan Huai, Panpan Hao, Mingxin Lv, Zhilin Chen, Yuxiang Chen, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anionic Oxidation Activity/Stability Regulated by Transition Metals in Multimetallic (Oxy)hydroxides for Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03718</link>
      <description>Shuhao Wang, Kamran Dastafkan, Sicheng Wu, Qian Sun, Chengli Rong, Dazhi Yao, Chuan Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405378470

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuhao Wang, Kamran Dastafkan, Sicheng Wu, Qian Sun, Chengli Rong, Dazhi Yao, Chuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03718</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
