<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 01:16:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Ferromagnetic-Interaction-Induced Spin Symmetry Broken in Ruthenium Oxide for Enhanced Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02736</link>
      <description>Lei Tan, Xiaotong Wu, Haifeng Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Bingbao Mei, Xiangxiang Pan, Weibo Hu, Faiza Meharban, Qi Xiao, Yonghui Zhao, Chao Fu, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Wei Luo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400604797

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Tan, Xiaotong Wu, Haifeng Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Bingbao Mei, Xiangxiang Pan, Weibo Hu, Faiza Meharban, Qi Xiao, Yonghui Zhao, Chao Fu, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Surfaces and Confinement on Formic Acid Dehydrogenation Catalyzed by an Immobilized Ru&#8211;H Complex: Insights from Molecular Simulation and Neutron Scattering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02626</link>
      <description>Hoang-Huy Nguyen, Marc H&#246;gler, Nadine Schnabel, Niels Hansen, Thomas Sottmann, Deven P. Estes, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400606147

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hoang-Huy Nguyen, Marc H&#246;gler, Nadine Schnabel, Niels Hansen, Thomas Sottmann, Deven P. Estes</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02626</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into Substituent Effects on the Fundamental Photocatalytic Processes of Covalent Organic Frameworks toward H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Evolution and H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02827</link>
      <description>Yingying Gu, Junxia Wang, Qingqing Tang, Hongtao Wei, Jing Ning, Xuefang Lan, Xuefeng Wang, Xuehui Li, Yonggang Jia, Shaobin Wang, Long Hao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400613140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingying Gu, Junxia Wang, Qingqing Tang, Hongtao Wei, Jing Ning, Xuefang Lan, Xuefeng Wang, Xuehui Li, Yonggang Jia, Shaobin Wang, Long Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper- and Palladium-Cocatalyzed Chemo-, Regio-, Stereo-, and Atroposelective Arylboration of 1,3-Enynes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03301</link>
      <description>Wangyang Li, Haohua Chen, Yanping Zheng, Yong Lu, Jinhui Xie, Shanglin Chen, Yu Lan, Qiuling Song, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400646935

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wangyang Li, Haohua Chen, Yanping Zheng, Yong Lu, Jinhui Xie, Shanglin Chen, Yu Lan, Qiuling Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Bonding Promotes 1-Butanol-3-Carbocation to 4-Methyl-1,3-Dioxane in Prins Condensation of Formaldehyde with Propene on Solid Acid Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01427</link>
      <description>Kun Zhang, Junju Mu, Qiang Guo, Yehong Wang, Yinpan Zhang, Jian Zhang, Feng Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400651023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kun Zhang, Junju Mu, Qiang Guo, Yehong Wang, Yinpan Zhang, Jian Zhang, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epsilon-Iron Carbide for the Hydrogenation of Carbonyl Groups in Esters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02212</link>
      <description>Huijiang Huang, Xin Shang, Xin Li, Qiao Han, Li Wang, Junhu Wang, Shengping Wang, Peng Jin, Yujun Zhao, Xinbin Ma, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400651220

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huijiang Huang, Xin Shang, Xin Li, Qiao Han, Li Wang, Junhu Wang, Shengping Wang, Peng Jin, Yujun Zhao, Xinbin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru(II)-Catalyzed Deformylative C&#8211;C Activation and Carbene Insertion: Empowering Diversity-Oriented Synthesis of Unsymmetrical Biaryldiols and Heterobiaryl Amino Alcohols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02889</link>
      <description>Chandan Kumar Giri, Tejender Singh, Sudeshna Mondal, Soumya Ghosh, Mahiuddin Baidya, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400653989

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chandan Kumar Giri, Tejender Singh, Sudeshna Mondal, Soumya Ghosh, Mahiuddin Baidya</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Photocatalytic Redox Activity of Polymeric Carbon Nitride for Valuable Fluorinated Heterocycles through Fast-Track Electron Highways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02395</link>
      <description>Chong Wang, Shiru Lin, Yichun Lu, Yuchen Hou, Aleksandr Savateev, Jiajia Cheng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400650989

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chong Wang, Shiru Lin, Yichun Lu, Yuchen Hou, Aleksandr Savateev, Jiajia Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02395</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Photocatalytic Biological Cofactor Regeneration Fueled by Selective Alcohol Oxidation over Polarized ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01703</link>
      <description>Fangshu Xing, Wenjun Dong, Jiashu Li, Jianhua Liu, Wenshuo Wang, Wenjin Dong, Hualei Yuan, Jian Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400686223

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fangshu Xing, Wenjun Dong, Jiashu Li, Jianhua Liu, Wenshuo Wang, Wenjin Dong, Hualei Yuan, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow Au&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;Cu&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;(111) Bimetallic Catalyst Promotes the Selective Electrochemical Conversion of Glycerol into Glycolic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00483</link>
      <description>Lingqin Shen, Luyao Sun, Mark Douthwaite, Ouardia Akdim, Stuart H. Taylor, Graham J. Hutchings, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400692579

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingqin Shen, Luyao Sun, Mark Douthwaite, Ouardia Akdim, Stuart H. Taylor, Graham J. Hutchings</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Borrowing Hydrogen Mechanism in Amine Alkylation by Single Atom Nickel Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02182</link>
      <description>Aurore E. F. Denjean, Ainara Nova, David Balcells, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400692915

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aurore E. F. Denjean, Ainara Nova, David Balcells</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02182</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refining Metal&#8211;Support Interactions via Surface Modification of Irreducible Oxide Support for Enhanced Complete Propane Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01358</link>
      <description>You Yang, Xu Aiqun, Xuan Tang, Yanglong Guo, Wangcheng Zhan, Li Wang, Sheng Dai, Yun Guo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400726703

                No abstract</description>
      <author>You Yang, Xu Aiqun, Xuan Tang, Yanglong Guo, Wangcheng Zhan, Li Wang, Sheng Dai, Yun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Engineering of &lt;i&gt;meso&lt;/i&gt;-Diaminopimelate Dehydrogenase for Efficient Synthesis of Bulky &lt;scp&gt;d&lt;/scp&gt;-Amino Acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03164</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Qiang Geng, Haiping Liu, Yuqing Wang, Guofeng Zhang, Xiao&#8208;Long Qian, Hui&#8208;Lei Yu, Jian&#8208;He Xu, Zhi&#8208;Jun Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400729711

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Qiang Geng, Haiping Liu, Yuqing Wang, Guofeng Zhang, Xiao&#8208;Long Qian, Hui&#8208;Lei Yu, Jian&#8208;He Xu, Zhi&#8208;Jun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalysis on Hybrid Plasmonic Nanomaterials: From Catalytic Mechanism Study at Single-Particle Level to Materials Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03566</link>
      <description>Fengxia Tong, Xizhuang Liang, Xiaolei Bao, Zhaoke Zheng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400737092

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengxia Tong, Xizhuang Liang, Xiaolei Bao, Zhaoke Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Reduction of Esters over Zirconia-Supported Metal Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01025</link>
      <description>Javier E. Chavarrio, Kyle Kirkendall-Jones, Raka G. Dastidar, George W. Huber, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400737606

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Javier E. Chavarrio, Kyle Kirkendall-Jones, Raka G. Dastidar, George W. Huber</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Role of Particle Size and Nanostructuring on the Oxygen Evolution Activity of Fe-Doped NiO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02329</link>
      <description>Reshma R. Rao, Alberto Bucci, Sacha Corby, Benjamin Moss, Caiwu Liang, Aswin Gopakumar, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Julio Lloret&#8208;Fillol, James R. Durrant, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741431

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Reshma R. Rao, Alberto Bucci, Sacha Corby, Benjamin Moss, Caiwu Liang, Aswin Gopakumar, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Julio Lloret&#8208;Fillol, James R. Durrant</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconceptualizing the Ir&lt;sup&gt;III&lt;/sup&gt; Role in Metallaphotoredox Catalysis: From Strong Photooxidant to Potent Energy Donor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03350</link>
      <description>Stephen DiLuzio, Lakshmy Kannadi Valloli, Max Kudisch, David Chambers, Garry Rumbles, Ruipeng Li, Matthew J. Bird, Hannah J. Sayre, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741521

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stephen DiLuzio, Lakshmy Kannadi Valloli, Max Kudisch, David Chambers, Garry Rumbles, Ruipeng Li, Matthew J. Bird, Hannah J. Sayre</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity on the Melamine-Modified Pt-High-Entropy Alloy Single-Crystal Lattice Stacking Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02191</link>
      <description>Takumi Kobayshi, Yoshihiro Chida, Naoto Todoroki, Toshimasa Wadayama, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400768951

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Takumi Kobayshi, Yoshihiro Chida, Naoto Todoroki, Toshimasa Wadayama</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i014_1824225</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400834442

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i014_1824225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i014_1824224</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400834444

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i014_1824224</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
