<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 01:07:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Solar-to-Hydrogen Conversion and Hydrogen Isotope Separation through Interfacial Hydrogen-Bond Engineering and Homolytic O&#8211;H Cleavage on Multianionic Sulfides in Large-Scale Floating Nanocomposites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00903</link>
      <description>Xuefan Feng, Qisheng Zang, Xuezhen Feng, Bo Lv, Hao Yu, Tingting Sun, Zhenyu Yuan, Junliang Liu, Yu Yang, Fuqin Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399117417

                Hydrogen-atom transfer (HAT) is crucial for selective photocatalytic water splitting. We report a class of metal chalcogenide catalysts (CdxZn1&#8211;xS(OH)-SH) that feature mercapto groups (acid sites) and lattice oxygens/hydroxyls (base sites) to form acid&#8211;base pairs. Based on this structural design, we demonstrate lattice oxygen/hydroxyl activation and an HAT process under light irradiation and identify a rapid hydrogen-transfer pathway governed by the Grotthuss mechanism. The photocatalyst Cd0.5Zn0.5S(OH)-SH exhibited a rate of 205.8 mmol&#183;g&#8211;1&#183;h&#8211;1 under full-spectrum illumination and an apparent quantum efficiency of 12.4% at 420 nm without any cocatalyst. Based on the HAT process, this novel catalyst achieves a proton&#8211;deuteron separation factor of approximately 11. The energy consumption is projected to be orders of magnitude lower than that of existing technologies. The fabricated large-scale nanocomposites of these photocatalysts are expected to enable large-scale separation of substantial volumes of diluted tritium wastewater.</description>
      <author>Xuefan Feng, Qisheng Zang, Xuezhen Feng, Bo Lv, Hao Yu, Tingting Sun, Zhenyu Yuan, Junliang Liu, Yu Yang, Fuqin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linking Bulk and Surface Structures in Complex Mixed Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05230</link>
      <description>Liudmyla Masliuk, Kye Chun Nam, Maxwell W. Terban, Yonghyuk Lee, Pierre Kube, Daniel Delgado, Frank Girgsdies, Karsten Reuter, Robert Schl&#246;gl, Annette Trunschke, Christoph Scheurer, Mirijam Zobel, Thomas Lunkenbein, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399123593

                The interface between a solid catalyst and the reacting medium plays a crucial role in the function of the material in catalysis. In the present work, we show that the surface termination of isostructural molybdenum&#8211;vanadium oxides is strongly linked to the real structure of the bulk. This conclusion is based on comparing (scanning) transmission electron microscopy images with pair distribution function (PDF) data obtained for (Mo,V)Ox and (Mo,V,Te,Nb)Ox. Distance-dependent analyses of the PDF results demonstrate that (Mo,V,Te,Nb)Ox exhibits stronger deviations from the averaged orthorhombic crystal structure than (Mo,V)Ox in the short and intermediate regimes. These deviations are explained by higher structural diversity, which is facilitated by the increased chemical complexity of the quinary oxide and in particular by the presence of Nb. This structural diversity is seemingly important to form intrinsic bulk-like surface terminations that are highly selective in alkane oxidation. More rigid (Mo,V)Ox is characterized by defective surfaces that are more active but less selective for the same reactions. In line with machine learning interatomic potential (MLIP) calculations, we highlight that the surface termination of (Mo,V,Te,Nb)Ox is characterized by a reconfiguration of the pentagonal building blocks, causing a preferential exposure of Nb sites. The presented results foster hypotheses that chemical complexity is superior for the performance of multifunctional catalysts. The underlying principle is not the presence of multiple chemically different surface centers but instead the ability of structural diversity to optimally align and distribute the elements at the surface and, thus, to shape the structural environment around the active sites. This study experimentally evidences the origin of the structure-directing impact of the real structure of the bulk on functional interfaces and encourages the development of efficient surface engineering strategies toward improved high-performance selective oxidation catalysts.</description>
      <author>Liudmyla Masliuk, Kye Chun Nam, Maxwell W. Terban, Yonghyuk Lee, Pierre Kube, Daniel Delgado, Frank Girgsdies, Karsten Reuter, Robert Schl&#246;gl, Annette Trunschke, Christoph Scheurer, Mirijam Zobel, Thomas Lunkenbein</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05230</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Exploration of a Multi-Promoter Catalyst Composition Space with Limited Experiments: Non-Oxidative Propane Dehydrogenation to Propylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01740</link>
      <description>Christian K&#252;nkel, Frederik R&#252;ther, Frederic Felsen, Charles W. P. Pare, Arseniia TERZI, Robert Baumgarten, Esteban Gioria, Raoul Naumann d&#8217;Alnoncourt, Christoph Scheurer, Frank Rosowski, Karsten Reuter, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399126277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Christian K&#252;nkel, Frederik R&#252;ther, Frederic Felsen, Charles W. P. Pare, Arseniia TERZI, Robert Baumgarten, Esteban Gioria, Raoul Naumann d&#8217;Alnoncourt, Christoph Scheurer, Frank Rosowski, Karsten Reuter</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Reaction Network for Dimethyl Maleate Hydrogenation on the Active Sites of Cu/ZnO Catalysts Combining DFT with kMC Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01057</link>
      <description>Changdong Li, Weiwei Zhang, Haipeng Yu, Yingzhe Yu, Minhua Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399140883

                The Cu/zinc oxide (ZnO)/Al2O3 catalyst is highly favored in the hydrogenation of dimethyl maleate (HDMM) to coproduction of 1,4-butanediol (BDO), &#947;-butyrolactone (GBL), and tetrahydrofuran, and an in-depth study on its catalytic principle has a long-standing interest in the current study. Herein, by combining density functional theory and kinetic Monte Carlo simulations, we revealed the dominant pathways and reaction network of the HDMM process on the ZnO/Cu(111) surface. The effect of Cu&#8211;ZnO synergy is reflected in promoting the anchoring of ester carbonyls and decreasing the difficulty of hydroxyl group formation, which was clarified by mechanisms, density of states, and Bader charge analyses. From the perspective of constructive modification of active sites, a strategy was proposed to improve the GBL formation rate by decreasing the barrier of methanol removal based on the concepts of degree of rate control, and the BDO selectivity could be improved by increasing the barrier of the out-of-ring C&#8211;O bond cleavage in GBL hydrogenation. From the perspective of the external environment, the optimal reaction conditions of different target products were determined by manipulating the temperature and pressure. This study provides a guide for modifying active sites in Cu/ZnO/Al2O3 catalysts and potential possibilities for studying the complex reaction systems involving C4+ substances by multiscale simulation.</description>
      <author>Changdong Li, Weiwei Zhang, Haipeng Yu, Yingzhe Yu, Minhua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms of Photoredox Catalysis Featuring Nickel&#8211;Bipyridine Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02036</link>
      <description>David A. Cagan, Daniel B&#237;m, Nathanael P. Kazmierczak, Ryan G. Hadt, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399141343

                Metallaphotoredox catalysis can unlock useful pathways for transforming organic reactants into desirable products, largely due to the conversion of photon energy into chemical potential to drive redox and bond transformation processes. Despite the importance of these processes for cross-coupling reactions and other transformations, their mechanistic details are only superficially understood. In this review, we have provided a detailed summary of various photoredox mechanisms that have been proposed to date for Ni&#8211;bipyridine (bpy) complexes, focusing separately on photosensitized and direct excitation reaction processes. By highlighting multiple bond transformation pathways and key findings, we depict how photoredox reaction mechanisms, which ultimately define substrate scope, are themselves defined by the ground- and excited-state geometric and electronic structures of key Ni-based intermediates. We further identify knowledge gaps to motivate future mechanistic studies and the development of synergistic research approaches spanning the physical, organic, and inorganic chemistry communities.</description>
      <author>David A. Cagan, Daniel B&#237;m, Nathanael P. Kazmierczak, Ryan G. Hadt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unnatural Thiamine Radical Enzymes for Photobiocatalytic Asymmetric Alkylation of Benzaldehydes and &#945;-Ketoacids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02752</link>
      <description>Xin Liu, Shuai Xu, Heyu Chen, Yang Yang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399155612

                Despite substantial progress made toward elucidating the natural radical enzymology with thiamine pyrophosphate (TPP)-dependent pyruvate:ferredoxin oxidoreductases (PFORs) and pyruvate oxidases (POXs), repurposing naturally occurring two-electron TPP-dependent enzymes to catalyze single-electron transformations with significant synthetic value remains a daunting task. Enabled by the synergistic use of visible-light photocatalyst fluorescein and a set of engineered TPP-dependent enzymes derived from benzoylformate decarboxylase (BFD) and benzaldehyde lyase (BAL), we developed an asymmetric photobiocatalytic decarboxylative alkylation of benzaldehydes and &#945;-keto acids to produce highly enantioenriched &#945;-branched ketones. Mechanistically, we propose that this dual catalytic radical alkylation involves single-electron oxidation of the enzyme-bound Breslow intermediate and subsequent interception of the photoredox-generated transient alkyl radical. In conjunction with visible light photoredox catalysis, thiamine radical biocatalysis represents an emerging platform to discover and optimize asymmetric radical transformations that are unknown to biological systems and not amenable to small-molecule catalysis.</description>
      <author>Xin Liu, Shuai Xu, Heyu Chen, Yang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd/Cu Cooperative Catalysis for Heteroarylation of Vinyl C&#8211;H Bond-Forming Polyaryl Ethylenes via C&#8211;O/Dual C&#8211;H Cleavage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02195</link>
      <description>Qihang Tan, Chenglong Li, Lei Yang, Zirun Wang, Yuxuan Huang, C. Wang, Long Liu, Wenhao Chen, Tieqiao Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399167230

                Polyaryl ethylenes find wide applications in synthetic, medicinal, and material fields; however, their stereo-selective synthesis is very challenging. In this paper, we describe a highly efficient bimetallic cooperative catalysis consisting of a palladium catalyst and a copper catalyst. This catalytic system enables the stereo-selective installation of a heteroaryl group onto the double bond of ortho-vinyl phenoxides via C&#8211;O cleavage and dual C&#8211;H activation. Extensive mechanistic studies show that copper-catalyzed C&#8211;H cleavage of heteroarenes is the rate-determining step. It can facilitate the formation of the key intermediate palladium cycle along with the ionic properties of arylpalladium species generated through oxidative addition, thus promoting the shift of Pd from the aryl to the vinyl group and ensuring the success of this reaction. This reaction overcomes the substrate limitation of previous aryl halide-based palladium shift systems well and provides an efficient method for preparing polyaryl ethylenes with high stereo-selectivity and a wide substrate scope. cis-Diaryl ethylenes, trans-diaryl ethylenes, triaryl ethylenes, and tetraaryl ethylenes all can be produced stereo-selectively. Considering the unique chemical and physical properties of poly-substituted ethylenes, especially the strong AIE effect, we anticipate that this powerful synthetic strategy will find wide applications in synthetic and material communities.</description>
      <author>Qihang Tan, Chenglong Li, Lei Yang, Zirun Wang, Yuxuan Huang, C. Wang, Long Liu, Wenhao Chen, Tieqiao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Methanol Fuel Cell with Porous Carbon-Supported PtRu Single-Atom Catalysts for Coproduction of Electricity and Value-Added Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02016</link>
      <description>Munir Ahmad, Muhammad Bilal Hussain, Jiahui Chen, Yang&#65533; Yang, Xuexian Wu, Hao Chen, Shahzad Afzal, Waseem Raza, Zhaowei Zeng, Fei Ye, Xueyang Zhao, Jiujun Zhang, Renfei Feng, Shuhui Yu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399172793

                Bottlenecks in direct methanol fuel cells (DMFCs) with conventional noble metals as anode catalysts involve the formation of valueless byproducts and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions. Carbon-supported Pt single atoms have demonstrated high performance in DMFCs. However, the adsorbed intermediates (COads) strongly bind to Pt single-atom sites, resulting in complete methanol oxidation to CO2 and low power densities. Herein, we have developed a DMFC for CO2-emission-free coproduction of electricity and valuable formate using metal organic framework (MOF)-derived N-doped porous carbon-supported PtRu single-atom (referred to as PtRuSA/NPC) catalysts. The DMFC produces current and power densities of 657 mA cm&#8211;2 and 97.4 mW cm&#8211;2, respectively, at a potential of 0.65 V with a 98.4% Faraday efficiency for formate at 80 &#176;C. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that CH3OH molecules preferentially adsorb onto the PtRu single atoms, but their oxidation to CO2 molecules on PtRuSA/NPC is kinetically unfavorable due to the large energy barrier. This study offers a pathway to developing high-performance and CO2-emission-free electrocatalysts for DMFCs.</description>
      <author>Munir Ahmad, Muhammad Bilal Hussain, Jiahui Chen, Yang&#65533; Yang, Xuexian Wu, Hao Chen, Shahzad Afzal, Waseem Raza, Zhaowei Zeng, Fei Ye, Xueyang Zhao, Jiujun Zhang, Renfei Feng, Shuhui Yu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Selectivity and Stability in Methane Dry Reforming by Atomic Layer Deposition on Ni-CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02019</link>
      <description>Jonathan Lucas, N. Raghavendra Naveen, Michael J. Janik, Konstantinos Alexopoulos, Gina Noh, Divakar R. Aireddy, Keqiang Ding, James Dorman, Kerry M. Dooley, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399173289

                Ni can be used as a catalyst for dry reforming of methane (DRM), replacing more expensive and less abundant noble metal catalysts (Pt, Pd, and Rh) with little sacrifice in activity. Ni catalysts deactivate quickly under realistic DRM conditions. Rare earth oxides such as CeO2, or as CeO2&#8211;ZrO2&#8211;Al2O3 (CZA), are supports that improve both the activity and stability of Ni DRM systems due to their redox activity. However, redox-active supports can also enhance the undesired reverse water gas shift (RWGS) reaction, reducing the hydrogen selectivity. In this work, Ni on CZA was coated with an ultrathin Al2O3 overlayer using atomic layer deposition (ALD) to study the effects of the overlayer on catalyst activity, stability, and H2/CO ratio. A low-conversion screening method revealed improved DRM activity and lower coking rate upon the addition of the Al2O3 ALD overcoat, and improvements were subsequently confirmed in a high-conversion reactor at long times onstream. The overcoated samples gave an H2/CO ratio of &#8764;1 at high conversion, much greater than uncoated catalysts, and no evidence of deactivation. Characterization of used (but still active) catalysts using several techniques suggests that active Ni is in formal oxidation state &gt;0, Ni&#8211;Ce&#8211;Al is most likely present as a mixed oxide at the surface, and a nominal thickness of 0.5 nm for the Al2O3 overcoat is optimal.</description>
      <author>Jonathan Lucas, N. Raghavendra Naveen, Michael J. Janik, Konstantinos Alexopoulos, Gina Noh, Divakar R. Aireddy, Keqiang Ding, James Dorman, Kerry M. Dooley</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstitial Zinc Defects Enriched ZnO Tuning O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Adsorption and Conversion Pathway for Superior Photocatalytic CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Oxygenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01758</link>
      <description>Zhen Xiao, Zhongping Wan, Jiangjie Zhang, Jianing Jiang, Dongmiao Li, Jinni Shen, Wenxin Dai, Yi Li, Xuxu Wang, Zizhong Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399177807

                Photocatalytic methane conversion into liquid oxygenates using O2 oxidants provides a promising approach for high-value chemicals. The generation of reactive oxygen species and their reaction pathway are key to determine the oxygenate selectivity. Here, an interstitial Zni defect ZnO (ZnO(Zni)) is developed through thermal decomposition of the ZnO2 precursor. Zni favors the O2 adsorption at a terminal adsorption configuration and induces effectively the conversion O2 into the desired &#8226;OOH instead of &#8226;OH for improving the yield and selectivity of oxygenates. For comparison, O2 adsorbed in a lateral configuration tends to be converted into excessive &#8226;OH on the typical Au/ZnO. As a result, ZnO(Zni) shows the liquid oxygenates yield of 6080 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 with 98.6% selectivity, which leads to 10 times lower than Au/ZnO for CO2 release of overoxidation. This work provides a pathway for O2 adsorption and activation to regulate the photocatalytic CH4 oxidation conversion into liquid oxygenates.</description>
      <author>Zhen Xiao, Zhongping Wan, Jiangjie Zhang, Jianing Jiang, Dongmiao Li, Jinni Shen, Wenxin Dai, Yi Li, Xuxu Wang, Zizhong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethylene Polymerization over Metal&#8211;Organic Framework-Supported Zirconocene Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01061</link>
      <description>Yaqi Wu, Joren M. Dorresteijn, Bert M. Weckhuysen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399180685

                Metallocene immobilization onto a solid support helps to overcome the drawbacks of homogeneous metallocene complexes in the catalytic olefin polymerization. In this study, valuable insights have been obtained into the effects of pore size, linker composition, and surface groups of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) on their role as support materials for metallocene-based ethylene polymerization catalysis. Three distinct Zn-based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), namely, MOF-5, IRMOF-3, and ZIF-8, with different linkers have been activated with methylaluminoxane (MAO) and zirconocene complexes, followed by materials characterization and testing for ethylene polymerization. Characterization has been performed by multiple analytical tools, including X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), gel permeation chromatography (GPC), differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), and CO Fourier transform infrared (FT-IR) spectroscopy. It was found that the interactions between MOFs, MAO, and the zirconocene complex not only lead to both catalyst activation and deactivation but also result in the creation of multiple active sites. By alteration of the MOF support, it is possible to obtain polyethylene with different properties. Notably, ultrahigh molecular weight polyethylene (UHMWPE, MW = 5.34 &#215; 106) was obtained using IRMOF-3 as support. This study reveals the potential of MOF materials as tunable porous supports for metallocene catalysts active in ethylene polymerization.</description>
      <author>Yaqi Wu, Joren M. Dorresteijn, Bert M. Weckhuysen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>K and Na Promotion Enables High-Pressure Low-Temperature Reverse Water Gas Shift over Copper-Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02293</link>
      <description>L Barberis, Christiaan I. Versteeg, Johannes D. Meeldijk, Joseph A. Stewart, Bart D. Vandegehuchte, Petra E. de Jongh, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399210748

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L Barberis, Christiaan I. Versteeg, Johannes D. Meeldijk, Joseph A. Stewart, Bart D. Vandegehuchte, Petra E. de Jongh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Degradation of Iron&#8211;Nitrogen&#8211;Carbon Heterogeneous Molecular Catalysts with Electron-Donating/Withdrawing Substituents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01752</link>
      <description>Fangzhou Liu, Di Zhang, Fangxin She, Zixun Yu, Leo Lai, Hao Li, Wei Li, Yuan Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399213497

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fangzhou Liu, Di Zhang, Fangxin She, Zixun Yu, Leo Lai, Hao Li, Wei Li, Yuan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclopropenium Sulfide as Lewis Base Catalyst for Chemoselective and Regioselective Electrophilic Selenylation of Phenols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01660</link>
      <description>Rui Chen, Tianyu Zheng, Xiaojian Jiang, Ying&#8208;Yeung Yeung, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399258939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Chen, Tianyu Zheng, Xiaojian Jiang, Ying&#8208;Yeung Yeung</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boundary Conditions for Promotion versus Poisoning in Copper&#8211;Gallium-Based CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-Methanol Hydrogenation Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01985</link>
      <description>Jan L. Alfke, Mar&#237;a Tejeda&#8208;Serrano, Sujay Phadke, Andrei A. Tereshchenko, Terry Z. H. Gani, Lukas Rochlitz, Seraphine B. X. Y. Zhang, Lin Lin, Christophe Cop&#233;ret, &#1054;lga V. Safonova, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399219589

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jan L. Alfke, Mar&#237;a Tejeda&#8208;Serrano, Sujay Phadke, Andrei A. Tereshchenko, Terry Z. H. Gani, Lukas Rochlitz, Seraphine B. X. Y. Zhang, Lin Lin, Christophe Cop&#233;ret, &#1054;lga V. Safonova</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01985</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Copper-Catalyzed Dearomative Spiroannulation of &#946;-Naphthols or Indoles with Yne-Allylic Esters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01756</link>
      <description>Ruinan Zhao, Shuang Deng, Rongkang Huang, Han&#8208;Han Kong, Yuepeng Lu, Tingrui Yin, Jiaqiang Wang, Ying Li, Cancan Zhu, Fangfang Pan, Xiaotian Qi, Hao Xu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399282118

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruinan Zhao, Shuang Deng, Rongkang Huang, Han&#8208;Han Kong, Yuepeng Lu, Tingrui Yin, Jiaqiang Wang, Ying Li, Cancan Zhu, Fangfang Pan, Xiaotian Qi, Hao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Dearomatization of Nonfunctionalized 1-Naphthols via Copper-Catalyzed Enantioselective [4 + 1] Spiroannulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01563</link>
      <description>Xingguang Li, Jiaxing Guo, J. Q. Zhang, Qingjun Chen, Yayi He, Feng Sha, Huijing Xiang, Peiyuan Yu, Pei Nian Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399282154

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingguang Li, Jiaxing Guo, J. Q. Zhang, Qingjun Chen, Yayi He, Feng Sha, Huijing Xiang, Peiyuan Yu, Pei Nian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Site Isolation and Enhanced Electron Transfer Facilitate Photocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction by A Multifunctional Metal&#8211;Organic Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02326</link>
      <description>Zitong Wang, Pierce Yeary, Yingjie Fan, Chao Deng, Wenbin Lin, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399291898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zitong Wang, Pierce Yeary, Yingjie Fan, Chao Deng, Wenbin Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organocatalytic Highly Enantioselective Formal [1,3] Sigmatropic Rearrangement of Indole Alkyl Ethers and Mechanistic Insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01584</link>
      <description>Haifeng Yu, Lingfei Hu, Junhao Zhang, Qingxing Yang, Gang L&#252;, Tao Xu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399292465

                Highly enantioselective [1,3] sigmatropic rearrangement represents a grand challenge in asymmetric organocatalysis. Herein, we disclose a chiral phosphoramide (R)-NPA-Cy mediated [1,3] sigmatropic rearrangement of 2-alkoxy indoles to access a diverse array of highly enantio-enriched oxindoles. The catalyst displayed good to high chiral control (89&#8211;99% ee) while maintaining a high efficiency (up to 99% yield). More than 60 examples were demonstrated. Mechanistic and computational studies revealed that the C&#8211;O bond cleavage of indole ether substrates can generate contact ion pairs stabilized by (R)-NPA-Cy via noncovalent interactions. Different catalyst&#8211;substrate noncovalent interactions were observed in the competing transition states leading to enantiomeric oxindoles, serving as the major factor determining enantioselectivity. In addition, this reaction was applied to the total syntheses of both enantiomers of (&#8722;)- and (+)-fusaspoid A in only five steps and reassigned their rotation values, correcting the original misassignments.</description>
      <author>Haifeng Yu, Lingfei Hu, Junhao Zhang, Qingxing Yang, Gang L&#252;, Tao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuNi Aerogels with Suppressed Water Activation for Efficient Nucleophilic Methanol Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01596</link>
      <description>Qie Fang, S. Ye, Lirong Zheng, Hengjia Wang, Lili Hu, Wenling Gu, Lijin Wang, Le Shi, Chengzhou Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301299

                Suppressing the competitive oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the critical prerequisite for efficient nucleophile oxidation in electrochemical biomass upgrading coupled with hydrogen production. Herein, Cu91Ni9 aerogels with atomically dispersed Ni are designed as effective nucleophile electrooxidation catalysts with significantly suppressed water activation performance, exhibiting a remarkable 99.3% Faradaic efficiency in the conversion of methanol to formic acid. Experimental and theoretical investigations reveal that the Cu support promotes the formation of Ni&#8211;O&#8211;Cu active pockets, where Ni3+ behaves as the main adsorbed sites and electrophilic lattice oxygen in Ni&#8211;O&#8211;Cu serves as a hydrogen acceptor, thus accelerating the electrochemical catalyst dehydrogenation reaction and the spontaneous nucleophilic dehydrogenation reaction. Furthermore, Cu integration exhibits weaker OER competition by inactivating the deprotonation capacity of OH* to O*, promoting the Faradaic efficiency of formic acid. This work paves the way for the development of advanced catalysts to achieve highly efficient biomass upgrading by modulating the OER activity.</description>
      <author>Qie Fang, S. Ye, Lirong Zheng, Hengjia Wang, Lili Hu, Wenling Gu, Lijin Wang, Le Shi, Chengzhou Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lignin-Derived Precious Metal-Free Electrocatalysts for Anion-Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02136</link>
      <description>Umber Sajjad, Ave Sarapuu, John C. Douglin, Arvo Kikas, Alexey Treshchalov, Maike K&#228;&#228;rik, Jekaterina Kozlova, Jaan Aruv&#228;li, Jaan Leis, Vambola Kisand, Kaupo Kukli, Dario R. Dekel, Kaido Tammeveski, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301334

                A facile method for the preparation of precious metal-free catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) from lignin, dicyandiamide, and transition metal salts is presented. Magnesium acetate was employed as a precursor for a sacrificial template, enhancing the porous structure of the catalysts. Iron content in the catalyst materials was optimized and a bimetallic catalyst containing Fe and Co was also prepared. The physicochemical analysis revealed uniform dispersion of various nitrogen moieties and transition metal centers on sheet-like carbon structures, along with some carbon-encapsulated metal-rich nanoparticles. Rotating disc electrode tests in an alkaline solution demonstrated the dependence of the ORR performance of the catalysts on their iron content and confirmed the high stability of both iron and bimetallic catalysts over 10,000 potential cycles. Anion-exchange membrane fuel cell (AEMFC) studies revealed that the bimetallic catalyst outperforms the Fe-containing material, achieving a very promising peak power density of 675 mW cm&#8211;2 at 60 &#176;C and 833 mW cm&#8211;2 at 80 &#176;C.</description>
      <author>Umber Sajjad, Ave Sarapuu, John C. Douglin, Arvo Kikas, Alexey Treshchalov, Maike K&#228;&#228;rik, Jekaterina Kozlova, Jaan Aruv&#228;li, Jaan Leis, Vambola Kisand, Kaupo Kukli, Dario R. Dekel, Kaido Tammeveski</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Activation Triggered by Ultrasonic Shock Significantly Improves NO Selective Catalytic Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02400</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Baoli Zhu, Songil Sin, Zhiqiang Zhang, Chong Tan, Zhiwen Gu, Song Wang, Chunkai Huang, Min Tao, Chenghua Zhang, Changjin Tang, Lin Dong, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399320398

                The precise regulation of lattice oxygen is crucial for many redox reactions, but it still remains a formidable challenge. Herein, we reported a facile strategy to induce generation of bulk phase defects in hematite (&#945;-Fe2O3) by ultrasonic treatment, thus achieving exclusive lattice oxygen activation without additional alternation of surface adsorbed oxygen species. This kind of unique lattice oxygen activation afforded negligible disturbance of NH3 adsorption but significant influence on NO2 generation via accelerated oxygen diffusion, resulting in enhanced activity contribution from the Fast-SCR reaction pathway. Particularly, the generation of bulk-phase defects was also found to be conducive to create thermally instable and chemically reactive surface nitrate species, which played a decisive role in activating NO reactant. Accordingly, a triple increment in the deNOx performance of the &#945;-Fe2O3 catalyst for the reaction of selective catalytic reduction of NO with NH3 (NH3&#8211;SCR) was achieved.</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Baoli Zhu, Songil Sin, Zhiqiang Zhang, Chong Tan, Zhiwen Gu, Song Wang, Chunkai Huang, Min Tao, Chenghua Zhang, Changjin Tang, Lin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Reductive Functionalization of Aryl Alkynes via Alkyne Radical Anions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02638</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Tong, Zugen Wu, Hwee Ting Ang, Yinxing Miao, Yixin L&#252;, Jie Wu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399322479

                The direct reductive functionalization of alkynes under mild conditions presents a promising yet challenging avenue for accessing value-added molecules. Alkyne radical anions represent a distinct class of reactive intermediates characterized by both a charge and an unpaired electron, thus holding great potential for facilitating diverse bond formations, particularly in alkyne reductive functionalization. However, the synthetic utility of alkyne radical anions is limited, primarily due to the difficulty in their generation and the formation of highly unstable vinyl radical intermediates. In this study, we accomplished the direct generation of alkyne radical anions from aryl alkyne feedstocks via single electron transfer (SET) reduction with photogenerated CO2 radical anion (CO2&#8226;&#8211;), enabling reductive hydroalkylation, arylalkenylation, and hydrocarboxylation of aryl alkynes. Our photocatalytic strategy features metal-free catalysis, mild reaction conditions, employment of a traceless reductant, good functional group compatibility, step- and atom-economy, and high regioselectivity. This study not only paves the way for leveraging the underexplored alkyne radical anions but also catalyzes the ongoing exploration of the bifunctional CO2&#8226;&#8211; species in synthetic chemistry.</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Tong, Zugen Wu, Hwee Ting Ang, Yinxing Miao, Yixin L&#252;, Jie Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02638</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
