<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 01:10:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Benzene Alkylation Conversion with CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via a Triple Composite Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02253</link>
      <description>Ruiwen Cao, Tingjun Fu, Yuyu Liu, Weichao Qin, Yuhang Guo, Caiyan Li, Shouying Huang, Zhong Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401014611

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruiwen Cao, Tingjun Fu, Yuyu Liu, Weichao Qin, Yuhang Guo, Caiyan Li, Shouying Huang, Zhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Electron Donors on the Charge Transfer Dynamics of Carbon Nanodots in Photocatalytic Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02327</link>
      <description>Stuart Macpherson, Takashi Lawson, Anna Abfalterer, Hope Bretscher, Ava Lage, Erwin Reisner, T. G. Euser, Samuel D. Stranks, Alexander S. Gentleman, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401015078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stuart Macpherson, Takashi Lawson, Anna Abfalterer, Hope Bretscher, Ava Lage, Erwin Reisner, T. G. Euser, Samuel D. Stranks, Alexander S. Gentleman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02327</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visible-Light-Induced Excited-State Copper Catalysis: Recent Advances and Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03238</link>
      <description>Nian Li, Bo Li, Kathiravan Murugesan, Arunachalam Sagadevan, Magnus Rueping, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401029926

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nian Li, Bo Li, Kathiravan Murugesan, Arunachalam Sagadevan, Magnus Rueping</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03238</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoredox-Neutral Deoxygenative Carboxylation of Acylated Alcohols with Tetrabutylammonium Oxalate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03396</link>
      <description>Chunbao Xu, Si-Yi Yan, Hui Xu, Yan Wang, L. L. Gu, Pei Xu, Long Yin, Xu Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401031512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunbao Xu, Si-Yi Yan, Hui Xu, Yan Wang, L. L. Gu, Pei Xu, Long Yin, Xu Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Organic Anions on Metal Hydroxide Oxygen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01907</link>
      <description>Shujin Hou, Li&#8208;Li Xu, Soumya Mukherjee, Jian Zhou, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Zhenyu Zhou, Shengli Zhang, Xiaoxin Ma, Julien Warnan, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Roland A. Fischer, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401074450

                Structural metamorphosis of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) eliciting highly active metal-hydroxide catalysts has come to the fore lately, with much promise. However, the role of organic ligands leaching into electrolytes during alkaline hydrolysis remains unclear. Here, we elucidate the influence of organic carboxylate anions on a family of Ni or NiFe-based hydroxide type catalysts during the oxygen evolution reaction. After excluding interfering variables, i.e., electrolyte purity, Ohmic loss, and electrolyte pH, the experimental results indicate that adding organic anions to the electrolyte profoundly impacts the redox potential of the Ni species versus with only a negligible effect on the oxygen evolution activities. In-depth studies demonstrate plausible reasons behind those observations and allude to far-reaching implications in controlling electrocatalysis in MOFs, mainly where compositional modularity entails fine-tuning organic anions.</description>
      <author>Shujin Hou, Li&#8208;Li Xu, Soumya Mukherjee, Jian Zhou, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Zhenyu Zhou, Shengli Zhang, Xiaoxin Ma, Julien Warnan, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Roland A. Fischer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of Secondary Homoallyl Borons by Copper-Catalyzed 1,1-Borylallylation of Terminal Alkynes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03735</link>
      <description>Haibo Liu, Kang Ding, Bo Su, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401140383

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibo Liu, Kang Ding, Bo Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Surface Concentration and Lifetime of Active Hydrogen in Cu-Based Layered Double Hydroxides for Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03245</link>
      <description>Hongmei Li, S Li, R.F. Guan, Zhaoyu Jin, Dan Xiao, Yong Guo, Panpan Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401157812

                Strategies incorporating heterometals to introduce surface-active hydrogen (*H) have been extensively utilized to enhance the electrocatalytic activity of Cu-based catalysts in the nitrate reduction reaction (NitRR). However, a comprehensive understanding of *H behavior and its specific impact on regulating the NitRR pathway remains elusive, particularly in a quantitative manner. In this study, we prepared a group of layered double hydroxides (LDHs) as model catalysts with diverse *H concentrations and lifetimes. Our findings reveal that the NitRR activity of Cu-based LDHs is highly dependent on the *H species that could be modulated by the incorporated heterometallic sites. Specifically, we conducted in situ analysis of different Cu-based LDH catalysts using time-resolved scanning electrochemical microscopy. The surface concentration and lifetime of *H at various applied potentials were quantified, enabling us to establish the relationship between the *H behavior and NitRR performance. Therefore, optimal NitRR performance was achieved with CuNi-LDHs, exhibiting a faradaic efficiency of 94.6% and yield rate of 2.7 mg h&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2 because of its appropriate *H surface concentration and lifetime. Additionally, we observe a trend of CuNi &gt; CuCo &gt; Cu &gt; CuRu &gt; CuFe &gt; CuMg in terms of the faradaic efficiency for NH3 production. These results suggest that by effectively utilizing the stable *H produced by the catalyst, one would allow favorable NitRR performance, offering a promising strategy for other electrocatalytic hydrogenation reactions.</description>
      <author>Hongmei Li, S Li, R.F. Guan, Zhaoyu Jin, Dan Xiao, Yong Guo, Panpan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Catalyzed Reductive Decarboxylative Coupling of Diacyl Peroxides with Aryl/Vinyl Halides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04002</link>
      <description>Canbin Qiu, Qifa Chen, Hegui Gong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401175043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Canbin Qiu, Qifa Chen, Hegui Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04002</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
