<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 01:03:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of 1&lt;i&gt;H&lt;/i&gt;-Isoindole-Containing Scaffolds Enabled by a Nitrile Trifunctionalization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00932</link>
      <description>&#192;lex D&#237;az-Jim&#233;nez, Roger Monreal-Corona, Miquel Sol&#224;, Albert Poater, Anna Roglans, Anna Pla&#8208;Quintana, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395659515

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#192;lex D&#237;az-Jim&#233;nez, Roger Monreal-Corona, Miquel Sol&#224;, Albert Poater, Anna Roglans, Anna Pla&#8208;Quintana</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00932</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Spillover Is Regulating Minority Rh&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; Active Sites on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in Room-Temperature Ethylene Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00482</link>
      <description>Linxiao Chen, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Libor Kova&#345;&#237;k, J&#225;nos Szanyi, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395659989

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linxiao Chen, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Libor Kova&#345;&#237;k, J&#225;nos Szanyi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00482</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidirectional Electron Transfer on Bismuth-Doped Pt/YMn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; for Efficient CO Oxidation as Diesel Oxidation Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00098</link>
      <description>Darong He, Yunfeng Chen, Shanshan Li, Yaxin Liu, Hailong Zhang, Yi Jiao, Ming Zhao, Jianli Wang, Yaoqiang Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395661226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Darong He, Yunfeng Chen, Shanshan Li, Yaxin Liu, Hailong Zhang, Yi Jiao, Ming Zhao, Jianli Wang, Yaoqiang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remarkable Synergy Effect of Cu&#8211;Nb Oxide Nanorods toward Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction: The Enhanced Mass and Electron Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01203</link>
      <description>Shuyue Wang, Chao Qian, Xinzhi Chen, Shaodong Zhou, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395673646

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuyue Wang, Chao Qian, Xinzhi Chen, Shaodong Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate-Dependent Mechanism Switch in the Desaturation Reactions of the Mononuclear Nonheme Iron Enzyme PtlD</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00757</link>
      <description>Linyue Chen, Qian Deng, Tingting Ma, Jing Gu, Juan Yang, Xuan Zhang, You&#8208;Quan Zou, Zixin Deng, Li Chen, Changming Zhao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395695873

                PtlD, a multifunctional mononuclear nonheme iron and &#945;-ketoglutarate-dependent (NHFe/&#945;-KG) dioxygenase involved in neopentalenoketolactone biosynthesis, catalyzes hydroxylation, desaturation, and olefin epoxidation reactions. Investigating desaturation reactions of nonactivated carbons mediated by NHFe/&#945;-KG enzymes is intriguing, especially for understanding the fate of the substrate radicals formed after hydrogen atom abstraction by FeIV&#9552;O species. Here, we investigate the desaturation reaction mechanism of PtlD using two distinct substrates: neopentalenolactone D (1) features a lone pair-containing oxygen atom adjacent to the olefin-forming carbon atoms, whereas pentalenolactone D (7) harbors a carbonyl group at the corresponding position. For substrate 1, our isotope effect measurement and protein mutagenesis experiments suggest the formation of a carbocation intermediate, which is subsequently deprotonated by a base to generate the desaturation products. Residue K288 serves as the base, while Y113 likely stabilizes the carbocation via a &#960;-cation interaction. For substrate 7, oxygen incorporation patterns indicated that a carbocation intermediate is also formed but is unstable, leading to hydroxylation due to H2O quenching. Notably, substrate 7's desaturation exhibits a temperature-dependent large kinetic isotope effect (KIE) and an inverse solvent isotope effect (SIE), suggesting that hydrogen tunneling contributes to the electron&#8211;proton transfer (EPT) process. These findings collectively reveal the cases of NHFe/&#945;-KG enzymes, where distinct desaturation mechanisms switch with different substrates.</description>
      <author>Linyue Chen, Qian Deng, Tingting Ma, Jing Gu, Juan Yang, Xuan Zhang, You&#8208;Quan Zou, Zixin Deng, Li Chen, Changming Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size-Dependent Hydrogenation Activity of Cobalt Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00995</link>
      <description>Yi He, Andreas Goldbach, Jiake Wei, Wenjie Shen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395960647

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi He, Andreas Goldbach, Jiake Wei, Wenjie Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Dynamic Effects in Isobutanol to Linear Butene Conversion Catalyzed by Acid Zeolites Assessed by AIMD</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00736</link>
      <description>Monika Ge&#353;vandtnerov&#225;, Pascal Raybaud, C&#233;line Chizallet, Tom&#225;&#353; Bu&#269;ko, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396213937

                Dehydration of alcohols into alkenes is a key reaction for the production of fuels and chemicals from biomass. However, the mechanism of these reactions is highly questionable, hindering the rational optimization of efficient catalysts. In the present work, the formation of linear butenes starting from isobutanol catalyzed by proton-exchanged zeolites is unraveled by ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD). Comparison with static calculations done for a gas phase reaction catalyzed by a proton and for the prototypical chabazite zeolite framework shows that AIMD estimations of the free energy barriers are significantly different from the static ones. Moreover, a common transition state (TS) is found for two competing reactions, namely, the isomerization of isobutanol into butan-2-ol (the dehydration of the latter yielding linear butenes) and the synchronous dehydration and isomerization of isobutanol into products related to linear butenes in a single step. The existence of a post-TS bifurcation prevents a traditional estimation of rates by transition state theory. To circumvent this problem, we quantify relative transmission coefficients using the Bennett&#8211;Chandler theory, which shows a clear tendency for decrease of relative frequency for isobutanol isomerization and increase of that for synchronous dehydration and isomerization when switching from 100 to 500 K. This work represents a step forward for the accurate determination of rates for key reactions in alcohol dehydration reactions.</description>
      <author>Monika Ge&#353;vandtnerov&#225;, Pascal Raybaud, C&#233;line Chizallet, Tom&#225;&#353; Bu&#269;ko</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Changes of Ni and Ni&#8211;Pt Methane Steam Reforming Catalysts During Activation, Reaction, and Deactivation Under Dynamic Reaction Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05847</link>
      <description>Enrico Tusini, Maria Casapu, Anna Zimina, Dmitry E. Doronkin, Heike St&#246;rmer, Laurent Barthe, St&#233;phanie Belin, Jan&#8208;Dierk Grunwaldt, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396214752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enrico Tusini, Maria Casapu, Anna Zimina, Dmitry E. Doronkin, Heike St&#246;rmer, Laurent Barthe, St&#233;phanie Belin, Jan&#8208;Dierk Grunwaldt</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05847</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights on the Challenging Trifluoromethylation of Ni&lt;sup&gt;(II)&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00907</link>
      <description>Mathilde Rigoulet, Sebastian Wellig, Franziska Schoenebeck, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396219028

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mathilde Rigoulet, Sebastian Wellig, Franziska Schoenebeck</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Peroxygenase Activity into Cytochrome P450 Monooxygenases through Modification of the Oxygen Binding Region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01326</link>
      <description>Matthew N. Podgorski, Jinia Akter, Luke R. Churchman, John B. Bruning, James J. De Voss, Stephen Bell, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396219751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matthew N. Podgorski, Jinia Akter, Luke R. Churchman, John B. Bruning, James J. De Voss, Stephen Bell</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volcano-Shaped Correlation Dictated Superior Activity for Ultralow Al-Doped Iron Oxide toward High-Temperature Water&#8211;Gas Shift Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01403</link>
      <description>Binbin Qian, Yan Xue, Sasha Yang, Jianghao Zhang, Cheng Liu, Zongtang Liu, Zhenghao Fei, Baiqian Dai, Jefferson Zhe Liu, Yong Wang, Lian Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396220980

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Binbin Qian, Yan Xue, Sasha Yang, Jianghao Zhang, Cheng Liu, Zongtang Liu, Zhenghao Fei, Baiqian Dai, Jefferson Zhe Liu, Yong Wang, Lian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Effects of FeN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Active Sites Surrounded by Fourteen-Membered Ring Ligands on Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity and Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01122</link>
      <description>Zhiqing Feng, Shizuyo Honda, Junya Ohyama, Y. Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Hiroshi Yoshida, Masato Machida, K&#245;tar&#245; Higashi, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Ryoichi Kojima, Makoto Moriya, Hideo Notsu, Seiji Nagata, Manabu Miyoshi, Teruaki Hayakawa, Yuta Nabae, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396222845

                FeN4 active sites have been studied as non-Pt group metal (non-PGM) catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The authors recently developed Fe(II) 1,14:7,8-ditethenotetrapyrido-[2,1,6-de:2&#8242;,1&#8242;6&#8242;-gh:2&#8243;,1&#8243;,6&#8243;-na][1,3,5,8,10,12] hexaazacyclotetradecine (Fe-14MR) as an FeN4 complex incorporating a 14-membered ring. This complex exhibited higher ORR activity and greater durability than Fe phthalocyanine, a conventional FeN4 complex having a 16-membered ring. In the present study, the ORR activity and durability of this Fe-14MR complex supported on C (Fe-14MR/C) were enhanced through modification of the active site structure by heating at 600 &#176;C and removing protons on amine groups in the Fe-14MR. Density functional theory calculations indicated that the Fe-14MR/C structure generated by heating resulted in oxygen species absorption energies close to optimal values for the ORR. The improved durability of the heat-treated Fe-14MR/C was attributed to reduced distortion of the FeN4 sites. The results suggest that designing Fe-14MR structures can be a promising approach to developing non-PGM catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhiqing Feng, Shizuyo Honda, Junya Ohyama, Y. Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Hiroshi Yoshida, Masato Machida, K&#245;tar&#245; Higashi, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Ryoichi Kojima, Makoto Moriya, Hideo Notsu, Seiji Nagata, Manabu Miyoshi, Teruaki Hayakawa, Yuta Nabae</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum(II) Phenylpyridyl Schiff Base Complexes as Latent, Photoactivated, Alkene Hydrosilylation Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01353</link>
      <description>Helena G. Lancaster, Joe C. Goodall, Stephen P. Douglas, Laura J. Ashfield, Simon B. Duckett, Robin N. Perutz, Andrew S. Weller, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396495696

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Helena G. Lancaster, Joe C. Goodall, Stephen P. Douglas, Laura J. Ashfield, Simon B. Duckett, Robin N. Perutz, Andrew S. Weller</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Interfacial Charge Transfer Enables Nearly 100% Selectivity for Solar-Light-Driven CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01020</link>
      <description>Wangzhong Tang, Jie Meng, Tao Ding, Haisen Huang, Chuntian Tan, Qiuzi Zhong, Heng Cao, Qunxiang Li, Xiuli Xu, Jinlong Yang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396495893

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wangzhong Tang, Jie Meng, Tao Ding, Haisen Huang, Chuntian Tan, Qiuzi Zhong, Heng Cao, Qunxiang Li, Xiuli Xu, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Consequences of Hierarchical Pore Architectures within MFI and FAU Zeolites for Polyethylene Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01213</link>
      <description>Jun Zhi Tan, M. Ortega, Stephen J. Miller, Cole W. Hullfish, H.G. Kim, Sung M. Kim, Wenda Hu, Jianzhi Hu, Johannes A. Lercher, Bruce E. Koel, Michele L. Sarazen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396499244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Zhi Tan, M. Ortega, Stephen J. Miller, Cole W. Hullfish, H.G. Kim, Sung M. Kim, Wenda Hu, Jianzhi Hu, Johannes A. Lercher, Bruce E. Koel, Michele L. Sarazen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inducing Microstrain in Electrodeposited Pt through Polymer Addition for Highly Active Oxygen Reduction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01244</link>
      <description>Qi Hua, Xinyi Chen, Junfeng Chen, Nawal M. Alghoraibi, Yoon Min Lee, Toby J. Woods, Richard T. Haasch, Steven C. Zimmerman, Andrew A. Gewirth, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396506273

                We investigate an approach to tune the d-band center and enhance the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity of Pt material without relying on foreign metals or the process of alloying/dealloying. It is known that Pt exhibits suboptimal ORR catalytic activity due to its strong binding to oxygen, therefore requiring a downshift in the d-band center by approximately 0.2 eV to weaken the Pt-O binding energy and boost ORR kinetics. We found that the d-band center can be tuned by inducing microstrain in the Pt electrodeposit, simply achieved by introducing polymer into the electrodeposition bath. Pt electrodes (Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA) prepared with the addition of poly-N-(6-aminohexyl)acrylamide (P1) or poly-l-arginine (PLA) exhibit improved ORR activity compared to Pt electrodeposited without polymer addition (Pt-alone) in both acidic and basic environments, with the order of activity being Pt-P1 &gt; Pt-PLA &gt; Pt-alone. Pt-P1 exhibits a positive shift of E1/2 by 90 mV vs Pt-alone in basic solution, comparable to other reported high-activity ORR catalysts. Scanning electron microscopy shows the presence of agglomerates with diameters between 5 and 20 &#956;m and tip-splitting growth structure due to diffusion-limited aggregation on Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA. Characterization using X-ray photoemission spectroscopy and X-ray diffraction, combined with Rietveld refinement analysis reveal a trend of downshifted d-band center, increased microstrain, and slightly increased compressive strain as the ORR activity increased among the three catalysts. The presence of more defective sites on Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA is the cause of the increased microstrain, which further leads to the downshift of the Pt d-band center and enhancement of ORR activity.</description>
      <author>Qi Hua, Xinyi Chen, Junfeng Chen, Nawal M. Alghoraibi, Yoon Min Lee, Toby J. Woods, Richard T. Haasch, Steven C. Zimmerman, Andrew A. Gewirth</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA-Anchored Single-Molecule Iron Phthalocyanine As an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00795</link>
      <description>Yi Qin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, XIA LIU, Xian Liang, Linfeng Xie, Kuan Wang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yang Liu, Yawei Chen, Zhijun Lei, Pengfei Yan, Liang Wu, Shuhong Jiao, Qing Li, Ruiguo Cao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396512258

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Qin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, XIA LIU, Xian Liang, Linfeng Xie, Kuan Wang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yang Liu, Yawei Chen, Zhijun Lei, Pengfei Yan, Liang Wu, Shuhong Jiao, Qing Li, Ruiguo Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Catalytic Performance of Cytochrome &lt;i&gt;c&lt;/i&gt; through Tailored Carboxymethylation in Covalent Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01456</link>
      <description>Li-Lan Shi, Xiupeng Chen, Aitao Li, Xiaoling Wu, Xian Kong, Hongming Li, Zhixian Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396541527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li-Lan Shi, Xiupeng Chen, Aitao Li, Xiaoling Wu, Xian Kong, Hongming Li, Zhixian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complete Computational Reaction Mechanism for Foldamer-Catalyzed Aldol Condensation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00937</link>
      <description>Reilly Osadchey Brown, Darren Demapan, Qiang Cui, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396541583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Reilly Osadchey Brown, Darren Demapan, Qiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coproduction of Glyceric Acid and Glycolic Acid from Biomass-Based Sugars over a Ru/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00782</link>
      <description>Yancheng Liu, Shiwei Zhou, Xiaoyan Wang, Jingyu Qin, Changwei Hu, Jianmei Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396545491

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yancheng Liu, Shiwei Zhou, Xiaoyan Wang, Jingyu Qin, Changwei Hu, Jianmei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00782</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;Anion-Switchable&#8221; Pincer-Mn(I) Catalyst for the Reductive &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Methylation of Amines with Formic Acid and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01812</link>
      <description>Sebasti&#225;n Mart&#237;nez-Vivas, Sergio Gonell, Macarena Poyatos, Eduardo Peris, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396547089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sebasti&#225;n Mart&#237;nez-Vivas, Sergio Gonell, Macarena Poyatos, Eduardo Peris</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End High-Throughput Approach for Data-Driven Internal Donor Development in Heterogeneous Ziegler&#8211;Natta Propylene Polymerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01601</link>
      <description>Toshiaki Taniike, Felicia Daniela Cannavacciuolo, Mostafa Khoshsefat, Diego De Canditiis, Giuseppe Antinucci, Patchanee Chammingkwan, Roberta Cipullo, Vincenzo Busico, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396547510

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Toshiaki Taniike, Felicia Daniela Cannavacciuolo, Mostafa Khoshsefat, Diego De Canditiis, Giuseppe Antinucci, Patchanee Chammingkwan, Roberta Cipullo, Vincenzo Busico</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourier-Transformed Alternating Current Voltammetry (FTacV) for Analysis of Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01526</link>
      <description>Rifael Z. Snitkoff-Sol, Alan M. Bond, Lior Elbaz, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396547671

                Electrocatalysts play a critical role in energy technologies, but the development of active, efficient, and durable catalysts is impeded by the lack of methodologies to deconvolute the complex interplay between various aspects influencing the activity of the catalysts, e.g., the number of active sites, turnover frequency, and the reaction pathways. Fourier-transformed alternating current voltammetry (FTacV) is an emerging tool for the analysis of electroactive species and has been successfully applied to a variety of reactions such as the oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, hydrogen evolution reaction, and hydrogen oxidation reaction. The harmonics generated from FTacV measurements neatly detect underlaying processes not visible by other, more commonly employed techniques for analysis of electrocatalysts, such as the rotating disc electrode and dc voltammetry. The harmonic components enable separating overlapping processes based on differences in kinetics or linearity of response. This paper presents a review of FTacV applied for the analysis of electrocatalysts. It highlights the importance of determining the electrochemically active site density (EASD) to decipher the intrinsic activity of a catalyst and discusses the use of FTacV in dynamic determination of the EASD over the course of a catalyst's working life, as well as the use of FTacV to understand intricate catalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Rifael Z. Snitkoff-Sol, Alan M. Bond, Lior Elbaz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoinduced Copper-Catalyzed Regio- and Enantioselective Alkynylation of Epoxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00818</link>
      <description>Jianye Li, Sijia Li, Guihua Cui, Yuan Kou, Chenwei Wang, Chen Yang, Guozhu Zhang, Rui Guo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396554632

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianye Li, Sijia Li, Guihua Cui, Yuan Kou, Chenwei Wang, Chen Yang, Guozhu Zhang, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the CO Oxidation Mechanism over Highly Dispersed Pt Single Atom on Anatase TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (101)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01018</link>
      <description>Celine Tesvara, Md Raian Yousuf, Malik Albrahim, Diego Troya, Abhijit Shrotri, Eli Stavitski, Ayman M. Karim, Philippe Sautet, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396561689

                Catalysts with noble metals deposited as single atoms on metal oxide supports have recently been studied extensively due to their maximized metal utilization and potential for performing difficult chemical conversions owing to their unique electronic properties. Understanding of the reaction mechanisms on supported single-metal atoms is still limited but is highly important for designing more efficient catalysts. In this study, we report the complexity of the CO oxidation reaction mechanism on Pt single atoms supported on anatase TiO2 (PtSA/a-TiO2) by coupling density functional theory (DFT) calculations and microkinetic analysis with kinetic measurements, in situ/operando infrared, and X-ray absorption spectroscopies. Starting from the adsorbed PtSA occupying an O vacancy induced by reductive pretreatment, we show that CO oxidation follows a complex mechanism consisting of initiation steps to reorganize the active site and multibranch reactive cycles, with the PtSA/a-TiO2 catalyst not returning to its initial configuration. The initiation step consists of CO and O2 adsorption healing the O vacancy, followed by CO oxidation using gas-phase CO to form Pt(CO). The reactive cycle alternates O2 adsorption and dissociation to oxidize the catalyst to Pt(O)(O)(CO) and branching pathways of competing Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood (LH)- or Eley&#8211;Rideal (ER)-type CO oxidation steps to reduce it again to Pt(CO). In situ/operando infrared experiments, including cryogenic CO adsorption and isotopic CO exchange, confirm the combined involvement of strongly adsorbed CO and gas-phase CO in an Eley&#8211;Rideal step along the reaction cycle. Microkinetic modeling shows that Pt single atoms are present in a mixture of Pt(CO), Pt(CO)(O2), Pt(O)(CO)(O2), and Pt(CO)(CO3) structures as the main intermediates during steady-state CO oxidation, all having the C&#8211;O vibrational stretch close to the experimentally observed value of 2115 cm&#8211;1. Microkinetic modeling also shows that the fractional orders of CO and O2 measured experimentally originate from multiple steps with a high degree of rate control and not from a simple competitive adsorption. The results demonstrate the complex reaction pathways that even CO oxidation on a simple single-atom system can follow, providing mechanistic insights for designing efficient Pt-based single-atom catalysts. We further show that microkinetic modeling results are sensitive to changes in energies of intermediate and transition states within errors of density functional theory, which can ultimately lead to incorrect conclusions regarding the reaction pathways and most abundant reaction intermediates if not accounted for by experiments.</description>
      <author>Celine Tesvara, Md Raian Yousuf, Malik Albrahim, Diego Troya, Abhijit Shrotri, Eli Stavitski, Ayman M. Karim, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Energy Pathway Exploration of Catalytic Formic Acid Decomposition on Pt-Group Metals in Aqueous Surroundings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00959</link>
      <description>Ziyue Hu, Ling-Heng Luo, Cheng Shang, Zhi-Pan Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396592409

                Formic acid is an important platform molecule for hydrogen utilization, where Pt-group metals are the only catalyst candidates to achieve ambient condition formic acid (FA) decomposition (HCOOH &#8594; CO2 + H2). However, these catalysts suffer from severe long-term activity loss, the mechanism of which has been highly debated in the past two decades. By combining global structure search with umbrella sampling molecular dynamics based on global neural network potentials, here we quantitatively resolve the whole free energy profile for FA decomposition at the Pt&#8211;water and Pd&#8211;water interfaces. We show that while the two metals share the same FA decomposition mechanism, their catalytic deactivation rate do differ by more than 2 orders of magnitude&#9472;Pt is much more susceptible to CO poisoning due to the kinetics. The physical origin is attributed to the stronger affinity to surface atomic H and the lower adsorption to surface adsorbed bent CO2 (CO2 anion) on Pd, which leads to the slower rate of the secondary CO2 decomposition to the CO molecule, the poisoning species at ambient conditions. After comparing CO generation at the solid&#8211;gas and the solid&#8211;liquid interface, we propose simple strategies to achieve high activity without CO byproduct formation for FA decomposition.</description>
      <author>Ziyue Hu, Ling-Heng Luo, Cheng Shang, Zhi-Pan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00959</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
