<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:44:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Carbonic Anhydrase-Ruthenium Enzyme for Photocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05183</link>
      <description>Ehider A Polanco, Laura V Opdam, Matthijs L. A. Hakkennes, Luuk Stringer, Anjali Pandit, Sylvestre Bonnet, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392448899

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ehider A Polanco, Laura V Opdam, Matthijs L. A. Hakkennes, Luuk Stringer, Anjali Pandit, Sylvestre Bonnet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Low-Temperature OHC and RHC in NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;SCR over Cu-CHA Catalysts: Effects of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O and SAR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00118</link>
      <description>Nicole Daniela Nasello, Umberto Iacobone, Nicola Usberti, Andrea Gjetja, Isabella Nova, Enrico Tronconi, Roberta Villamaina, Maria Pia Ruggeri, Djamela Bounechada, Andrew P. E. York, Jillian Collier, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392452437

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicole Daniela Nasello, Umberto Iacobone, Nicola Usberti, Andrea Gjetja, Isabella Nova, Enrico Tronconi, Roberta Villamaina, Maria Pia Ruggeri, Djamela Bounechada, Andrew P. E. York, Jillian Collier</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoarchitectonics of Non-Noble-Metal-Based Heterogeneous Catalysts for Transfer Hydrogenation Reactions: Detailed Insights on Different Hydrogen Sources</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05844</link>
      <description>Devendra Sharma, Priyanka Choudhary, Payal Mittal, Sahil Kumar, Ashrumochan Gouda, Venkata Krishnan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392459269

                Catalytic transfer hydrogenation (CTH) methodology has drawn profound attention of researchers as an economical and environmentally benign alternate to conventional hydrogenation method. Unlike conventional method, CTH exhibits better reaction efficiency and atom economy, and it makes use of simple, easily accessible, low-cost hydrogen sources. Current research on CTH reactions is oriented toward the development of non-noble-metal-based catalysts due to their high abundance and potential large-scale applicability. In this Review, different organic transformation reactions, such as hydrogenation of nitroarenes, nitriles, alkenes, alkynes, and carbonyl compounds, hydrogenolysis, reductive amination, and reductive formylation reaction using different hydrogen sources have been summarized comprehensively. In addition, synthesis strategies of the non-noble-metal-based heterogeneous catalysts and the structure&#8211;activity relationship involving metal&#8211;support interaction, single-atom catalysis, and synergistic effect are highlighted. Furthermore, the optimization of the reaction parameters&#9472;such as temperature, time, solvents, and additives&#9472;for enhancing the catalytic activity and selectivity of the product are discussed in detail. This Review provides detailed insights into the recent progress made in CTH reactions using non-noble-metal-based heterogeneous catalysts with a specific focus on catalyst development, hydrogen sources, and mechanistic exploration.</description>
      <author>Devendra Sharma, Priyanka Choudhary, Payal Mittal, Sahil Kumar, Ashrumochan Gouda, Venkata Krishnan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-Heterocyclic Carbene-Catalyzed Imine Umpolung/Semipinacol Rearrangement Cascade for the Synthesis of Indoxyls</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00793</link>
      <description>Rohan Chandra Das, Soumen Barik, Anusree A. Kunhiraman, Anubhav Goswami, Avijit Mondal, Mrinmoy De, Akkattu T. Biju, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392461593

                Aldimine umpolung using N-heterocyclic carbenes (NHCs) is less explored compared to the well-known polarity reversal of aldehydes. Described herein is the NHC-catalyzed aldimine umpolung/semipinacol rearrangement cascade for the atom- and pot-economic synthesis of fluorescent active, N&#8211;H unprotected indoxyl derivatives. Moreover, conditions are identified for the NHC-catalyzed enantioselective synthesis of &#945;-iminols by the umpolung of aldimines. The nucleophilic aza-Breslow intermediates are intercepted with carbonyl electrophiles. Preliminary DFT studies shed light on the rearomative proton transfer coupled aryl migration in an ortho-quinonemethide intermediate facilitating the semipinacol rearrangement. In addition, the antibacterial activity of the synthesized indoxyls has been evaluated.</description>
      <author>Rohan Chandra Das, Soumen Barik, Anusree A. Kunhiraman, Anubhav Goswami, Avijit Mondal, Mrinmoy De, Akkattu T. Biju</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-Catalyzed Reductive Deoxygenation of Aldehydes, Ketones, Alcohols, and Ethers to Alkanes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05666</link>
      <description>Anurag Kumar, Sandip Pattanaik, Gaurav Joshi, Manas Kumar Sahu, Eluvathingal D. Jemmis, Chidambaram Gunanathan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392472807

                The development of simple and general catalytic methods using abundant base metal catalysts for the deoxygenation of organic compounds for the valorization of biomass and chemical synthesis remains a formidable challenge. Cobalt pincer-catalyzed reductive deoxygenation of aldehydes, ketones, alcohols, and ethers to their corresponding alkanes is reported. Biomass-derived compounds were deoxygenated to their corresponding methylarenes. This catalytic system employs diethylsilane as a reductant and requires a substoichiometric amount of base. Investigations revealed the initial deprotonation of the amine arm on the catalyst, and catalysis begins with Si&#8211;H activation of silane facilitated by amine-amide metal&#8211;ligand cooperation. In situ-formed Co&#8211;H species carry out the hydrosilylation of carbonyl compounds, dehydrosilylation of alcohols, and hydrosilanolysis of ethers, resulting in common arylmethylsilyl or alkylsilyl ether intermediates. Further, the reaction of diethylsilane with arylmethylsilyl or alkylsilyl ether leads to deoxygenation and the formation of siloxane oligomers. Further, a DFT study reveals closely lying singlet&#8211;triplet electronic states of different intermediates facilitating the mechanism on different spin surfaces, verified through the located minimum energy crossing points (MECPs). In the case of alcohol, another low energy pathway is located where the amide arm of pincer, instead of hydride, can abstract the hydroxy proton and enable metal&#8211;ligand cooperation.</description>
      <author>Anurag Kumar, Sandip Pattanaik, Gaurav Joshi, Manas Kumar Sahu, Eluvathingal D. Jemmis, Chidambaram Gunanathan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Facile Synthesis of Vinyl Boronate Esters via Dehydrogenative Borylation of Alkenes Enabled by Co-MOF Catalyst: An Additive Free Approach&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01116</link>
      <description>Suma Basappa, Aishwarya Prakash, Sanjana S. Talekar, Manoj V. Mane, Shubhankar Kumar Bose, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392499978

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ARTICLES ASAPPREVCorrectionNEXTORIGINAL ARTICLEThis notice is a correctionCorrection to &#8220;Facile Synthesis of Vinyl Boronate Esters via Dehydrogenative Borylation of Alkenes Enabled by Co-MOF Catalyst: An Additive Free Approach&#8221;Suma BasappaSuma BasappaCentre for Nano and Material Sciences (CNMS), JAIN (Deemed-to-be University), Jain Global Campus, Bangalore-562112, IndiaMore by Suma Basappa, Aishwarya PrakashAishwarya PrakashCentre for Nano and Material Sciences (CNMS), JAIN (Deemed-to-be University), Jain Global Campus, Bangalore-562112, IndiaMore by Aishwarya Prakash, Sanjana S. TalekarSanjana S. TalekarCentre for Nano and Material Sciences (CNMS), JAIN (Deemed-to-be University), Jain Global Campus, Bangalore-562112, IndiaMore by Sanjana S. Talekar, Manoj V. Mane*Manoj V. ManeCentre for Nano and Material Sciences (CNMS), JAIN (Deemed-to-be University), Jain Global Campus, Bangalore-562112, India*Email: [email protected]More by Manoj V. Mane, and Shubhankar Kumar Bose*Shubhankar Kumar BoseCentre for Nano and Material Sciences (CNMS), JAIN (Deemed-to-be University), Jain Global Campus, Bangalore-562112, India*Email: [email protected]More by Shubhankar Kumar Bosehttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-1057-2403Cite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, XXX, 4301&#8211;4302Publication Date (Web):March 6, 2024Publication History Received20 February 2024Published online6 March 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01116&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InRedditEmail PDF (725 KB) Get e-AlertscloseSUBJECTS:Borylation,Catalysts,Hydrocarbons,Hydrogenation,Organic compounds Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author>Suma Basappa, Aishwarya Prakash, Sanjana S. Talekar, Manoj V. Mane, Shubhankar Kumar Bose</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Catalyzed Chemoselective (Amino)fluorosulfonylation of Hydrocarbons via Intramolecular Fluorine-Atom Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00116</link>
      <description>Shiyao Qu, Xiao Xi Li, Xingwei Li, Lin Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392503323

                Sulfonyl fluorides have found increasing applications as functional molecules in chemistry and biology. We herein report a copper-catalyzed atom-economical access to two categories of sulfonyl fluorides through a radical relay strategy in the presence of an SO2 surrogate. The aliphatic C(sp3)&#8211;H bond in N-fluoro-N-alkyl sulfonamides reacted via a 1,5-hydrogen atom transfer (HAT) process, affording alkanesulfonyl fluorides with a proximal amino group. On the other hand, utilizing substrates containing a proper C&#9552;C double bond resulted in intramolecular olefin aminofluorosulfonylation, allowing the synthesis of fluorosulfonyl-functionalized pyrrolidines and piperidines via atom-transfer radical addition (ATRA). Both reaction systems proceeded under mild conditions, requiring no additional fluorine source. Experimental and computational studies suggest that S&#8211;F coupling is likely achieved through an intramolecular radical-rebound pathway. By taking advantage of the SuFEx chemistry and multifunctionality of the products, the method is applicable to the late-stage modification of bioactive compounds, drug ligation chemistry, and organic synthesis.</description>
      <author>Shiyao Qu, Xiao Xi Li, Xingwei Li, Lin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Catalyzed Intramolecular C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)-H Lactonization of Hydroxamate Derivatives Promoted by a 1,5-HAT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04900</link>
      <description>Hugo Esteves, Tania Xavier, Sonia Lajnef, Fabienne Peyrot, Guillaume Lef&#232;vre, Guillaume Prestat, Farouk Berhal, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392503558

                An iron-catalyzed lactonization reaction via intramolecular C(sp3)-H functionalization is described. The process employs easily accessible hydroxamate derivatives from which the noncommon insertion of the oxygen occurred through a 1,5-hydrogen atom transfer. A mixture of water and hexafluoroisopropanol as solvent appeared to be the key parameter of this transformation to reach a high selectivity and efficiency.</description>
      <author>Hugo Esteves, Tania Xavier, Sonia Lajnef, Fabienne Peyrot, Guillaume Lef&#232;vre, Guillaume Prestat, Farouk Berhal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04900</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilization of the Active Ruthenium Oxycarbonate Phase for Low-Temperature CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Methanation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05679</link>
      <description>Carmen T&#233;bar-Soler, Vlad Martin&#8208;Diaconescu, Laura Simonelli, Alexander Missyul, Virg&#237;nia P&#233;rez-Dieste, Ignacio J. Villar&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Daviel G&#243;mez, Jean&#8208;Blaise Brubach, Pascale Le Roy, Avelino Corma, Patricia Concepci&#243;n, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392517574

                Interstitial carbon-doped RuO2 catalyst with the newly reported ruthenium oxycarbonate phase is a key component for low-temperature CO2 methanation. However, a crucial factor is the stability of interstitial carbon atoms, which can cause catalyst deactivation when removed during the reaction. In this work, the stabilization mechanism of the ruthenium oxycarbonate active phase under reaction conditions is studied by combining advanced operando spectroscopic tools with catalytic studies. Three sequential processes: carbon diffusion, metal oxide reduction, and decomposition of the oxycarbonate phase and their influence by the reaction conditions, are discussed. We present how the reaction variables and catalyst composition can promote carbon diffusion, stabilizing the oxycarbonate catalytically active phase under steady-state reaction conditions and maintaining catalyst activity and stability over long operation times. In addition, insights into the reaction mechanism and a detailed analysis of the catalyst composition that identifies an adequate balance between the two phases, i.e., ruthenium oxycarbonate and ruthenium metal, are provided to ensure an optimum catalytic behavior.</description>
      <author>Carmen T&#233;bar-Soler, Vlad Martin&#8208;Diaconescu, Laura Simonelli, Alexander Missyul, Virg&#237;nia P&#233;rez-Dieste, Ignacio J. Villar&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Daviel G&#243;mez, Jean&#8208;Blaise Brubach, Pascale Le Roy, Avelino Corma, Patricia Concepci&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05679</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjusting the Operational Potential Window as a Tool for Prolonging the Durability of Carbon-Supported Pt-Alloy Nanoparticles as Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06251</link>
      <description>Tina &#272;uki&#263;, L&#233;onard Moriau, Iva Klofutar, Martin &#352;ala, Luka Pavko, Francisco Javier Gonz&#225;lez L&#243;pez, Francisco Ru&#237;z-Zepeda, Andra&#382; Pavli&#353;i&#269;, Miha Hotko, Matija Gatalo, Nejc Hodnik, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392520370

                A current trend in the investigation of state-of-the-art Pt-alloys as proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) electrocatalysts is to study their long-term stability as a bottleneck for their full commercialization. Although many parameters have been appropriately addressed, there are still certain issues that must be considered. Here, the stability of an experimental Pt-Co/C electrocatalyst is investigated by high-temperature accelerated degradation tests (HT-ADTs) in a high-temperature disk electrode (HT-DE) setup, allowing the imitation of close-to-real operational conditions in terms of temperature (60 &#176;C). Although the US Department of Energy (DoE) protocol has been chosen as the basis of the study (30,000 trapezoidal wave cycling steps between 0.6 and 0.95 VRHE with a 3 s hold time at both the lower potential limit (LPL) and the upper potential limit (UPL)), this works demonstrates that limiting both the LPL and UPL (from 0.6&#8211;0.95 to 0.7&#8211;0.85 VRHE) can dramatically reduce the degradation rate of state-of-the-art Pt-alloy electrocatalysts. This has been additionally confirmed with the use of an electrochemical flow cell coupled to inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (EFC-ICP-MS), which enables real-time monitoring of the dissolution mechanisms of Pt and Co. In line with the HT-DE methodology observations, a dramatic decrease in the total dissolution of Pt and Co has once again been observed upon narrowing the potential window to 0.7&#8211;0.85 VRHE rather than 0.6&#8211;0.95 VRHE. Additionally, the effect of the potential hold time at both LPL and UPL on metal dissolution has also been investigated. The findings demonstrate that the dissolution rate of both metals is proportional to the hold time at UPL regardless of the applied potential window, whereas the hold time at the LPL does not appear to be as detrimental to the stability of metals.</description>
      <author>Tina &#272;uki&#263;, L&#233;onard Moriau, Iva Klofutar, Martin &#352;ala, Luka Pavko, Francisco Javier Gonz&#225;lez L&#243;pez, Francisco Ru&#237;z-Zepeda, Andra&#382; Pavli&#353;i&#269;, Miha Hotko, Matija Gatalo, Nejc Hodnik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction with Atomically Precise Au&lt;sub&gt;13&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters: Effect of Ligand Shell on Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06114</link>
      <description>Tetyana I. Levchenko, Hong Yi, Mark D. Aloisio, Ngoc Kim Dang, Guofu Gao, Sachil Sharma, Cao-Thang Dinh, Cathleen M. Crudden, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392550903

                Supported gold nanoclusters of the formula [Au13(L)5Cl2]3+ where L = N-heterocyclic carbene (NHC) or phosphine ligands are examined in the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) in a membrane electrode assembly cell configuration. Gold nanoclusters bearing bisNHC ligands are shown to exhibit improved catalytic performance compared with diphosphine-stabilized nanoclusters after activation at the optimum treatment temperatures. The thermal properties of the nanoclusters are shown to have a significant impact on their catalytic activity. Thermogravimetric analysis, UV&#8211;vis absorption spectroscopy, and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy revealed that thermal treatment of [Au13(diphosphine)5Cl2]3+ nanoclusters results in complete loss of diphosphine ligands while [Au13(bisNHC)5Cl2]3+ nanoclusters show stepwise and partial removal of bisNHC ligands. We propose that the partial removal of bisNHC ligands enables efficient activation of [Au13(bisNHC)5Cl2]3+ clusters while conserving the core structure. This leads to the implication that intact clusters retaining at least some ligands in their coordination environment are more active than ligand-free clusters.</description>
      <author>Tetyana I. Levchenko, Hong Yi, Mark D. Aloisio, Ngoc Kim Dang, Guofu Gao, Sachil Sharma, Cao-Thang Dinh, Cathleen M. Crudden</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revving up a Designed Copper Nitrite Reductase Using Noncoded Active Site Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06159</link>
      <description>Winston C Pitts, Aniruddha Deb, James E. Penner&#8208;Hahn, Vincent L. Pecoraro, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392551437

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Winston C Pitts, Aniruddha Deb, James E. Penner&#8208;Hahn, Vincent L. Pecoraro</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfite-Enhanced Aerobic Methane Oxidation to Methanol over Reduced Phosphomolybdate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00234</link>
      <description>Sikai Wang, Hua An, Max J. H&#252;lsey, Geng Sun, Qian He, Ning Yan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392551491

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sikai Wang, Hua An, Max J. H&#252;lsey, Geng Sun, Qian He, Ning Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Dual Activation of Lattice Oxygen and Molecule Oxygen over CoMn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for VOC Oxidation: Promoting the Role of Oxygen Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06237</link>
      <description>Yewei Ren, Caixia Song, Hui Wang, Zhenping Qu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392552229

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yewei Ren, Caixia Song, Hui Wang, Zhenping Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Charge Transfer via Heterogeneous Doping Promotes Hematite Photoelectrodes for Efficient Solar H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06110</link>
      <description>Fang Guo, Jinwei Bai, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Kai Su, Yang Yang, Xianhu Liu, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392564717

                Photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting into hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) and hydrogen (H2) is a promising alternative to energy and environmentally intensive production. Bulk electronic and surface structures affect the charge transport efficiency and catalytic activity of the photoelectrode. Herein, we design and investigate a hematite (Fe2O3) nanorod photoelectrode with hafnium and titanium binary dopants for highly selective H2O2 production. The resultant photoanode shows a H2O2 yield of 0.41 &#956;mol min&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2 at 1.5 VRHE with a Faradaic efficiency of 72.2%. Experimental investigations and theoretical calculations demonstrate the synergistic effect of Hf and gradient Ti doping on the hematite for the promising H2O2 performance. Hf doping effectively improves the crystallinity of Fe2O3, which favors improving the charge transport and reducing the charge recombination. Gradient Ti doping inhibits the collapse of the nanorod structure, increases the specific surface area, and introduces a large number of active sites on the surface. Ti- and Hf-codoped Ti/Hf:Fe2O3 photoanode improves the kinetics of H2O2 generation, leading to the high selectivity for H2O2 production and suppression of O2 production. This work provides the importance of hematite-based photoanodes toward the regulation of competition reactions for H2O2 production.</description>
      <author>Fang Guo, Jinwei Bai, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Kai Su, Yang Yang, Xianhu Liu, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel as Electrocatalyst for CO&lt;sub&gt;(2)&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction: Effect of Temperature, Potential, Partial Pressure, and Electrolyte Composition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00009</link>
      <description>Rafa&#235;l E. Vos, Marc T. M. Koper, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392578646

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rafa&#235;l E. Vos, Marc T. M. Koper</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Conformational Transitions Underpin the Activation Heat Capacity in the Temperature Dependence of Enzyme Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05584</link>
      <description>Emma J. Walker, Carlin J. Hamill, Rory Crean, Michael S. Connolly, Annmaree K. Warrender, Kirsty L. Kraakman, Erica J. Prentice, Alistair Steyn-Ross, Moira L. Steyn-Ross, Christopher R. Pudney, Marc W. van der Kamp, Louis A. Schipper, Adrian J. Mulholland, Vickery L. Arcus, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392597789

                Many enzymes display non-Arrhenius behavior with curved Arrhenius plots in the absence of denaturation. There has been significant debate about the origin of this behavior and recently the role of the activation heat capacity (&#916;CP&#10727;) has been widely discussed. If enzyme-catalyzed reactions occur with appreciable negative values of &#916;CP&#10727; (arising from narrowing of the conformational space along the reaction coordinate), then curved Arrhenius plots are a consequence. To investigate these phenomena in detail, we have collected high precision temperature-rate data over a wide temperature interval for a model glycosidase enzyme MalL, and a series of mutants that change the temperature-dependence of the enzyme-catalyzed rate. We use these data to test a range of models including macromolecular rate theory (MMRT) and an equilibrium model. In addition, we have performed extensive molecular dynamics (MD) simulations to characterize the conformational landscape traversed by MalL in the enzyme&#8211;substrate complex and an enzyme-transition state complex. We have crystallized the enzyme in a transition state-like conformation in the absence of a ligand and determined an X-ray crystal structure at very high resolution (1.10 &#197;). We show (using simulation) that this enzyme-transition state conformation has a more restricted conformational landscape than the wildtype enzyme. We coin the term &#8220;transition state-like conformation (TLC)&#8221; to apply to this state of the enzyme. Together, these results imply a cooperative conformational transition between an enzyme&#8211;substrate conformation (ES) and a transition-state-like conformation (TLC) that precedes the chemical step. We present a two-state model as an extension of MMRT (MMRT-2S) that describes the data along with a convenient approximation with linear temperature dependence of the activation heat capacity (MMRT-1L) that can be used where fewer data points are available. Our model rationalizes disparate behavior seen for MalL and previous results for a thermophilic alcohol dehydrogenase and is consistent with a raft of data for other enzymes. Our model can be used to characterize the conformational changes required for enzyme catalysis and provides insights into the role of cooperative conformational changes in transition state stabilization that are accompanied by changes in heat capacity for the system along the reaction coordinate. TLCs are likely to be of wide importance in understanding the temperature dependence of enzyme activity and other aspects of enzyme catalysis.</description>
      <author>Emma J. Walker, Carlin J. Hamill, Rory Crean, Michael S. Connolly, Annmaree K. Warrender, Kirsty L. Kraakman, Erica J. Prentice, Alistair Steyn-Ross, Moira L. Steyn-Ross, Christopher R. Pudney, Marc W. van der Kamp, Louis A. Schipper, Adrian J. Mulholland, Vickery L. Arcus</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Directed Nickel-Catalyzed Three-Component Reductive Arylalkylation of Alkenes via the Carbometalation/Radical Cross-Coupling Sequence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00477</link>
      <description>Zhan Dong, Changyu Xu, Jianchao Chang, Sitian Zhou, Peipei Sun, Yuqiang Li, Liang&#8208;An Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392600216

                Asymmetric reductive three-component arylalkylation of alkenes via the radical relay method has been well established, while asymmetric arylalkylation via the migratory insertion strategy remains unexplored. We report enantioselective nickel-catalyzed cross-electrophile arylalkylation of alkenes with aryl- and alkyl halides via an integrated Heck carbometalation/radical cross-coupling sequence. This protocol employing a chiral Ni/PHOX catalytic system allows terminal and internal alkenes to successfully engage the arylalkylation with exquisite control of regio-, chemo-, and stereoselectivity. More importantly, this reductive arylalkylation undergoes regio- and enantioselective arylnickelation followed by radical cross-coupling via Csp3&#8211;Csp3 reductive elimination, thus exhibiting reverse regioselectivity to the radical relay method. Mild reaction conditions and exceptional functional group tolerance facilitate this method&#8217;s compatibility with bioactive motifs and the modular synthesis of biologically active compounds. The control experiments and density functional theory calculations provide insights into the mechanism and origin of regio- and stereoselectivity, and the hemilabile nature of the PHOX ligand is critical for achieving this enantioselective arylalkylation.</description>
      <author>Zhan Dong, Changyu Xu, Jianchao Chang, Sitian Zhou, Peipei Sun, Yuqiang Li, Liang&#8208;An Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glycyl Radical Enzymes Catalyzing the Dehydration of Two Isomers of &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Methyl-4-hydroxyproline</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00216</link>
      <description>Li Jiang, Yiqian Yang, Lin Huang, Yan Zhang, Jingkun An, Yu Zheng, Yiwei Chen, Yanhong Liu, Jianhui Huang, Ee Lui Ang, Suwen Zhao, Huimin Zhao, Rong&#8208;Zhen Liao, Yifeng Wei, Yan Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392601584

                The various isomers of hydroxyproline (HP) are widely distributed in nature, serving as key components of structural proteins, while their quaternized betaine derivatives function as osmoprotectants in many organisms. Aerobic bacteria degrade HPs through a variety of well-studied mechanisms. Recent studies show that certain anaerobic bacteria degrade HPs through distinct mechanisms, involving the O2-sensitive glycyl radical enzymes (GREs) t4L-HP dehydratase (HypD) and t4D-HP C&#8211;N lyase (HplG). Here, we report the discovery of two more GREs, N-methyl c4L-HP dehydratase (HpyG) and N-methyl c4D-HP dehydratase (HpzG), which catalyze radical-mediated dehydration of the two N-methyl-c4HP enantiomers, while also displaying significant activities toward their unmethylated substrates. Both GREs are associated with homologues of pyrroline-5-carboxylate reductase, which catalyze reduction of their products N-methyl-pyrroline-5-carboxylate to form N-methyl-proline. Crystal structures of HpyG and HpzG in complex with their substrates revealed active site architectures distinct from that of HypD and provided insights into the mechanism of enantioselective radical-mediated dehydration. Our research further expands the repertoire of diverse chemical mechanisms involved in the bacterial metabolism of highly prevalent HP isomers and derivatives in the anaerobic biosphere.</description>
      <author>Li Jiang, Yiqian Yang, Lin Huang, Yan Zhang, Jingkun An, Yu Zheng, Yiwei Chen, Yanhong Liu, Jianhui Huang, Ee Lui Ang, Suwen Zhao, Huimin Zhao, Rong&#8208;Zhen Liao, Yifeng Wei, Yan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental Insights on the Electrochemical Nitrogen Oxidation over Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05307</link>
      <description>J. V. P. Long, Dong Luan, Xihong Fu, Huan Li, Huijuan Jing, Jianping Xiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392602509

                Electrocatalytic nitrogen oxidation reaction (eN2OR) has emerged as a sustainable strategy for nitrogen fixation. In this work, density functional theory calculations were performed to rationalize the reaction mechanisms, activity, and selectivity of eN2OR on metal dioxides. The anatase (101), anatase (100), and rutile (110) surfaces were investigated to obtain more generalized insights. Based on the reaction phase diagram analysis, the thermochemical mechanisms were identified as most energetically favorable for N2 and *N2O oxidation, and a theoretical activity map was constructed for eN2OR, explaining well the experimental activity trend. Anatase PtO2(100) was screened as the most active catalyst for nitrate production, which could be covered by a monolayer of *OH under the reaction conditions according to the Pourbaix diagram. A method of electric field controlling constant potential was used to calculate the electrochemical barriers on anatase PtO2(100). It was found that the electrochemical barriers of the oxygen evolution reaction will increase with the decrease of potential, while the thermochemical limiting step of the eN2OR is insensitive to potential. Thus, the eN2OR selectivity can be improved by lowering the applied potential. This work unveils fundamental insights into eN2OR and provides a unified understanding to experiments.</description>
      <author>J. V. P. Long, Dong Luan, Xihong Fu, Huan Li, Huijuan Jing, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Decoration of Platinum Catalysts by ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters for Durable Fuel Cell Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05297</link>
      <description>Nagappan Ramaswamy, Zixiao Shi, Barr Zulevi, Geoff McCool, Nathan P. Mellott, Anusorn Kongkanand, Swami Kumaraguru, Michele L. Ostraat, David A. Muller, Nancy N. Kariuki, Deborah J. Myers, A. Jeremy Kropf, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392615762

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nagappan Ramaswamy, Zixiao Shi, Barr Zulevi, Geoff McCool, Nathan P. Mellott, Anusorn Kongkanand, Swami Kumaraguru, Michele L. Ostraat, David A. Muller, Nancy N. Kariuki, Deborah J. Myers, A. Jeremy Kropf</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Oxygen Evolution Reaction Kinetics with Titanium Incorporated Nickel Ferrite for Efficient Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05761</link>
      <description>Ki-Yong Yoon, Kyung&#8208;Bok Lee, Jaehoon Jeong, Myung&#8208;Jun Kwak, Dohyung Kim, Hyunchul Roh, Ji-Hoon Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Hosik Lee, Juchan Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392622761

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ki-Yong Yoon, Kyung&#8208;Bok Lee, Jaehoon Jeong, Myung&#8208;Jun Kwak, Dohyung Kim, Hyunchul Roh, Ji-Hoon Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Hosik Lee, Juchan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Thiophene&#8211;Sulfur Functional Groups in Carbon Catalysts for Highly Selective H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00419</link>
      <description>Rong-Hui Xie, Chuanqi Cheng, Ruguang Wang, Jisi Li, Erling Zhao, Zhao Yang, Yunlong Liu, Jiaxin Guo, Pengfei Yin, Tao Ling, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392645655

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rong-Hui Xie, Chuanqi Cheng, Ruguang Wang, Jisi Li, Erling Zhao, Zhao Yang, Yunlong Liu, Jiaxin Guo, Pengfei Yin, Tao Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt/Fe-TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Catalyzed Selective Carbonyl Hydrogenation: Fe-Promoted Hydrogen Spillover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05478</link>
      <description>Zhenchao Zhao, Xiang Li, Xin Liu, Hongxia Gao, Aiping Jia, Songhai Xie, Xiaojing Song, Xiaoyan Liu, Yang Fa, Qihua Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392649076

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenchao Zhao, Xiang Li, Xin Liu, Hongxia Gao, Aiping Jia, Songhai Xie, Xiaojing Song, Xiaoyan Liu, Yang Fa, Qihua Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Siteselective and Enantiocomplementary C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Oxyfunctionalization for Synthesis of &#945;-Hydroxy Acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00398</link>
      <description>Xin Lian, Yingle Mao, Zunyun Fu, Weijie Zhang, Jia-Yan Chen, Dan Zhuo, Mingyue Zheng, Jiunn&#8208;Tzong Wu, Cangsong Liao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392658327

                Oxyfunctionalization of abundant carboxylic acids represents a direct approach to synthesizing &#945;-hydroxy acids, which are valuable intermediates of various active pharmaceutical ingredients. Although ideal, the transformation is yet to be accomplished. Herein, enantiocomplementary C(sp3)&#8211;H oxyfunctionalization for the synthesis of &#945;-hydroxy acids was realized by a cooperative strategy of substrate engineering, homologue screening and protein engineering of &#945;-ketoglutarate-dependent nonheme iron aryloxyalkanoate dioxygenases. The reaction provided concise synthetic routes toward three types of 67 &#945;-hydroxy acids with high efficiency and selectivity (yield up to 90% and ee up to &gt;99%). The distinctive complementary reactions add to a growing repertoire of biocatalytic oxyfunctionalization reactions.</description>
      <author>Xin Lian, Yingle Mao, Zunyun Fu, Weijie Zhang, Jia-Yan Chen, Dan Zhuo, Mingyue Zheng, Jiunn&#8208;Tzong Wu, Cangsong Liao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00398</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
