<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 01:20:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Association Enforced by the Confinement Effect To Boost the Regioselectivity of Vinyl Acetate Hydroformylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03932</link>
      <description>Guoqing Wang, Miao Jiang, Benhan Fan, Zhao Sun, Leilei Qian, Guangjun Ji, Lei Ma, Cunyao Li, Zhaozhan Wang, Guifa Long, Yong Yang, Yan Li, Yunjie Ding, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403452090

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guoqing Wang, Miao Jiang, Benhan Fan, Zhao Sun, Leilei Qian, Guangjun Ji, Lei Ma, Cunyao Li, Zhaozhan Wang, Guifa Long, Yong Yang, Yan Li, Yunjie Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03932</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oriented Conversion of HMF to FDCA under Mild Conditions over Lignin-Tailored Co Single-Atom Catalyst with Enhanced Co Loadings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04419</link>
      <description>Junkai Li, Guanhua Wang, Li Wang, Yutong Zhao, Yuze Zhao, Wenjie Sui, Dingsheng Wang, Chuanling Si, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403455838

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junkai Li, Guanhua Wang, Li Wang, Yutong Zhao, Yuze Zhao, Wenjie Sui, Dingsheng Wang, Chuanling Si</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#8217;s Toolbox for the Hydrolysis of Lactams and Cyclic Imides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04474</link>
      <description>Peter Stockinger, Rebecca Buller, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403461793

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peter Stockinger, Rebecca Buller</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Enzyme Activity in Biomass Conversion by Modulating the Hydrolysis Process of Cellobiohydrolases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05393</link>
      <description>Han Liu, Yu Ding, Scott Mazurkewich, Wenwen Pei, Wei Xu, Johan Larsbrink, Christophe Chipot, Zhangyong Hong, Wensheng Cai, Zhiyou Zong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403461885

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Han Liu, Yu Ding, Scott Mazurkewich, Wenwen Pei, Wei Xu, Johan Larsbrink, Christophe Chipot, Zhangyong Hong, Wensheng Cai, Zhiyou Zong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Well-Defined Catalytic System for Integrating Homogeneous and Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03701</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Jiashu Sun, Dongcheng He, Kang Zhao, Bo Qian, Feng Shi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403462873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Jiashu Sun, Dongcheng He, Kang Zhao, Bo Qian, Feng Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoexcited Palladium-Catalyzed Synthesis of Chiral Allenes from Alkynes via Isomerization and Deracemization Sequence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04956</link>
      <description>Changhua Song, Shouyun Yu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403464269

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changhua Song, Shouyun Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Hydrogenolysis of Lignin into Propenyl-monophenol over Ru Single Atoms Supported on CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with Rich Oxygen Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03184</link>
      <description>Kaili Zhang, Jianchun Jiang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Jun Ye, Ran Tao, Hao Xu, Jingcong Xie, Jing Yang, Jian Zhao, Ning Zhang, Kui Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403479149

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaili Zhang, Jianchun Jiang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Jun Ye, Ran Tao, Hao Xu, Jingcong Xie, Jing Yang, Jian Zhao, Ning Zhang, Kui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Conductivity Lignin-Derived Carbon Fiber-Embedded CuFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for Electrooxidation of HMF into FDCA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04227</link>
      <description>Haohan Wu, Bowen Liu, Yi Qi, Xueqing Qiu, Liheng Chen, Yanlin Qin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403483893

                The electrocatalytic oxidation of 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) provides a viable pathway for the efficient utilization of biomass resources. However, designing and regulating the activity and selectivity of the corresponding electrocatalysts remain significant challenge. Spinel compounds show great potential as catalysts due to their adjustable electronic structures and notable catalytic properties, but their intrinsic low conductivity has limited their further application. Herein, a lignin-based carbon fiber (LCF) embedded CuFe2O4 catalyst (CuFe2O4/LCF) is successfully constructed using an electrospinning technique. The catalyst can efficiently and selectively synthesize 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) at a relatively low potential. The experimental results and theoretical simulations demonstrate that the introduction of lignin can significantly optimize the pregraphitic turbine carbon microstructure of the carbon fibers and facilitate rapid electron transfer between CuFe2O4 and the carbon layer. Furthermore, the ATd&#8211;O&#8211;BOh interactions on the surface of the CuFe2O4 spinel structure significantly enhance the adsorption capacity for the substrates and OH&#8211; species, effectively promoting the catalytic reaction. The findings hope to provide a unique perspective to improve the catalytic activity of lignin carbon fiber spinel catalysts and the stability of biomass value-added mechanism.</description>
      <author>Haohan Wu, Bowen Liu, Yi Qi, Xueqing Qiu, Liheng Chen, Yanlin Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic 1,9-Proton-Transfer-Driven Cycloaddition: Synthesis and Stereoselective Contraction of Nine-Membered Heterocycles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05514</link>
      <description>Sekwang Baek, Ju Young Lee, Min Jae Kang, Min Ho Kim, Eun Jeong Yoo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403487799

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sekwang Baek, Ju Young Lee, Min Jae Kang, Min Ho Kim, Eun Jeong Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigations via Kinetics and Multivariate Linear Regression Models of the Mechanism and Origins of Regioselectivity in a Palladium-Catalyzed Aryne Annulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04873</link>
      <description>Erin Plasek, Brylon N. Denman, Courtney C. Roberts, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403489219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Erin Plasek, Brylon N. Denman, Courtney C. Roberts</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04873</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Dynamic Catalysis at ab Initio Accuracy: The Need for Free-Energy Calculation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05372</link>
      <description>Qiyuan Fan, Fu&#8208;Qiang Gong, Yun&#8208;Pei Liu, Hui Zhu, Jun Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403490084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiyuan Fan, Fu&#8208;Qiang Gong, Yun&#8208;Pei Liu, Hui Zhu, Jun Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A van der Waals&#8211;Covalent Bonding-Inspired Typical Coordination with Ultrahigh Lattice Mismatch as Active Sites for Hydrogen Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04046</link>
      <description>Xinying Luo, Junjie Xiong, Xiaolong Liu, Zhichang Xiao, Qinghua Zhang, Yuchen Cai, Bowen Liu, Yang Gao, Tao Liang, Qiang Zheng, Jichen Dong, Ting Tan, Zhenxing Wang, Yunqi Liu, Bin Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403494720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinying Luo, Junjie Xiong, Xiaolong Liu, Zhichang Xiao, Qinghua Zhang, Yuchen Cai, Bowen Liu, Yang Gao, Tao Liang, Qiang Zheng, Jichen Dong, Ting Tan, Zhenxing Wang, Yunqi Liu, Bin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptors for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction in Imidazolium-Based Electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05012</link>
      <description>Federico Dattila, Alessia Fortunati, Federica Zammillo, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403505029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Federico Dattila, Alessia Fortunati, Federica Zammillo, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pore-Structure Engineering of Hierarchical &#946; Zeolites for the Enhanced Hydrocracking of Waste Plastics to Liquid Fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05354</link>
      <description>Muhammad Usman Azam, Auguste Fernandes, M.J. Ferreira, Waheed Afzal, In&#234;s Gra&#231;a, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403510371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Usman Azam, Auguste Fernandes, M.J. Ferreira, Waheed Afzal, In&#234;s Gra&#231;a</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molybdenum-Catalyzed Reductive &lt;i&gt;Ortho&lt;/i&gt;-Allylation of Nitroarenes with 1,3-Dienes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04404</link>
      <description>Jin&#8208;Liang Lu, Zhi Zhang, Jing&#8208;Tong Deng, Jin&#8208;Bao Peng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403512934

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jin&#8208;Liang Lu, Zhi Zhang, Jing&#8208;Tong Deng, Jin&#8208;Bao Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P450DA Monooxygenase-Catalyzed Chemoselective and Enantiodivergent Epoxidation of Unactivated Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04941</link>
      <description>Jiajing Li, Xiaojian Zhou, Juan Ao, Jintao Gao, Anni Wang, Zhuanglin Shen, Yang Gu, Jiahai Zhou, Yong&#8208;Zheng Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403514864

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiajing Li, Xiaojian Zhou, Juan Ao, Jintao Gao, Anni Wang, Zhuanglin Shen, Yang Gu, Jiahai Zhou, Yong&#8208;Zheng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Atomic-Scale Synergy for Selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysis to CO over CuNi Dual-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05169</link>
      <description>Bin Chen, Dehuan Shi, Rui Deng, Xin Xu, Wenxia Liu, Wei Yang, Zheyuan Liu, Shenghong Zhong, Jianfeng Huang, Yan Yu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403537276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Chen, Dehuan Shi, Rui Deng, Xin Xu, Wenxia Liu, Wei Yang, Zheyuan Liu, Shenghong Zhong, Jianfeng Huang, Yan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of the Properties of Hydrogen Dissociation and Transfer in the Presence of S Atoms for Efficient Hydrogenations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05501</link>
      <description>H. Liu, Mingyuan Zhang, Xin Liu, Jiali Liu, Huicong Dai, Wenhao Luo, Jian Liu, Rui Gao, Qihua Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403542795

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Liu, Mingyuan Zhang, Xin Liu, Jiali Liu, Huicong Dai, Wenhao Luo, Jian Liu, Rui Gao, Qihua Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05501</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the d-Band Center of Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for Efficient Nitrate Reduction Reaction and Zinc-Nitrate Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04340</link>
      <description>Yuanhui Yao, Xiaofei Wei, Haiqiao Zhou, Kai Wei, Bin Kui, Fangfang Wu, Liang Chen, Wei Wang, Fangna Dai, Peng Gao, Nana Wang, Wei Ye, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403543782

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanhui Yao, Xiaofei Wei, Haiqiao Zhou, Kai Wei, Bin Kui, Fangfang Wu, Liang Chen, Wei Wang, Fangna Dai, Peng Gao, Nana Wang, Wei Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics, Mechanism, and Thermodynamics of Ceria-Zirconia Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04771</link>
      <description>Andrew Hwang, Andrew &#8220;Bean&#8221; Getsoian, Enrique Iglesia, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403544458

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrew Hwang, Andrew &#8220;Bean&#8221; Getsoian, Enrique Iglesia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i020_1857514</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403550324

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i020_1857514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i020_1857513</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403551257

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i020_1857513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the Electrochemical Microenvironment of Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by Cr Doping for Highly Efficient Methanol Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05729</link>
      <description>Hongye Qin, Yukun Ye, Guangliang Lin, Jinyang Zhang, Wenqi Jia, Wei Xia, Lifang Jiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403555556

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongye Qin, Yukun Ye, Guangliang Lin, Jinyang Zhang, Wenqi Jia, Wei Xia, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Furan-Based HTCC/In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction Achieves Fast Charge Separation To Boost the Photocatalytic Generation of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in Pure Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04341</link>
      <description>Xiaolong Tang, Changlin Yu, Jiaming Zhang, Kaiwei Liu, Debin Zeng, Fang Li, Feng Li, Guijun Ma, Yanbin Jiang, Yongfa Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403558316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaolong Tang, Changlin Yu, Jiaming Zhang, Kaiwei Liu, Debin Zeng, Fang Li, Feng Li, Guijun Ma, Yanbin Jiang, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Peroxidase Based on the Biotin&#8211;Streptavidin Technology that Rivals the Efficiency of Natural Peroxidases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03208</link>
      <description>Manjistha Mukherjee, Val&#233;rie Waser, E.R. Morris, Nico V. Igareta, Alec H. Follmer, R.P. Jakob, Dilbirin &#220;z&#252;mc&#252;, Timm Maier, Thomas R. Ward, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403558630

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manjistha Mukherjee, Val&#233;rie Waser, E.R. Morris, Nico V. Igareta, Alec H. Follmer, R.P. Jakob, Dilbirin &#220;z&#252;mc&#252;, Timm Maier, Thomas R. Ward</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of Helically Chiral Molecules Enabled by Asymmetric Organocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05345</link>
      <description>Qingqin Huang, Yuping Tang, Cong-Zhen Zhang, Zhen Wang, Lei Dai, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403565410

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingqin Huang, Yuping Tang, Cong-Zhen Zhang, Zhen Wang, Lei Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05345</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
