<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 01:06:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Combined Photocatalysis and Lewis Acid Catalysis Strategy for the Oxa-Pictet&#8211;Spengler Reactions of Ethers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01595</link>
      <description>Nao Tanaka, Sophia R. Mitton-Fry, Mi-Lim Hwang, Joshua Zhu, Karl A. Scheidt, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nao Tanaka, Sophia R. Mitton-Fry, Mi-Lim Hwang, Joshua Zhu, Karl A. Scheidt</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly(ionic liquid) Ionomers Help Prevent Active Site Aggregation, in Single-Site Oxygen Reduction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01418</link>
      <description>Silvia Favero, Alain Li, Mengnan Wang, Fahim Uddin, Bora Kuzuoglu, Arthur Georgeson, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Davood Nasrabadi, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396693235

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silvia Favero, Alain Li, Mengnan Wang, Fahim Uddin, Bora Kuzuoglu, Arthur Georgeson, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Davood Nasrabadi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethane Dehydrogenation to Ethylene: Engineering the Surface Structure of Pt-Based Alloy Catalysts to Tune the Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06100</link>
      <description>Lulu Ping, Mifeng Xue, Yuan Zhang, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396697728

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lulu Ping, Mifeng Xue, Yuan Zhang, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Near 100% Faradaic Efficiency of Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia on Symmetry-Broken Medium-Entropy-Alloy Metallene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00879</link>
      <description>Yuanbo Zhou, Lifang Zhang, Mengfan Wang, Zhi&#8208;Jun Zhu, Najun Li, Tao Qian, Chenglin Yan, Jianmei Lu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396698133

                Electrochemical nitrate reduction (NO3RR) offers an ecofriendly way for ammonia production. However, improving the sluggish kinetics of such a multistep reaction still remains challenging. Herein, an asymmetry strategy is proposed to adjust the charge distribution of the active centers on metallene by presenting novel symmetry-broken medium-entropy-alloy (MEA) metallene via heteroatom alloying. Benefiting from the maximized exposure of the well-regulated active sites, proof-of-concept PdCuCo MEA metallene delivers near 100% NH3 Faradaic efficiency in both neutral and alkaline electrolytes, along with a record-high NH3 yield rate over 532.5 mg h&#8211;1 mgcat&#8211;1. Moreover, it enables 99.7% conversion of nitrate from an industrial wastewater level of 6200 ppm to a drinkable water level. Detailed studies further revealed that charge redistribution is induced by the elemental electronegativity difference on symmetry-broken MEA metallene, which will weaken the N&#8211;O bond of *NO, thus reducing the energy barrier of the rate-determining step. Meanwhile, the competitive HER and the formation of NO2&#8211; are also hindered. We believe that our strategy proposed in this work will shed light on the design of efficient NO3RR catalysts to a more practical level.</description>
      <author>Yuanbo Zhou, Lifang Zhang, Mengfan Wang, Zhi&#8208;Jun Zhu, Najun Li, Tao Qian, Chenglin Yan, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Leverage in Activity and Stability toward CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to Formate over a Bismuth Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01519</link>
      <description>Wenbin Li, Chang Yu, Xin Tan, Yongwen Ren, Yafang Zhang, Song Chen, Yi Yang, Jieshan Qiu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720560

                The direct production of formate from CO2 over Bi-based catalysts offers a promising route for producing important chemicals using renewable electricity. Nevertheless, limited by the unstable structure and states of catalysts under electrochemical conditions, electroreduction of CO2 to formate is still facing a trade-off between activity and stability, especially at high current densities. Herein, we reported a metal&#8211;carbon interfacial modulation strategy to synthesize the cross-linked and defective carbon-modified Bi nanoparticle (Bi-DC) catalyst with a stable spatial structure and a unique CO2-philic and hydrophobic interface. As a result, the Bi-DC featured a remarkable ability for CO2 electroreduction to formate in a near neutral electrolyte (1 M KHCO3) and was even comparable to the CO2-to-formate activity in the strongly basic systems, along with a high partial current density and formation rate for formate of &#8722;378 mA cm&#8211;2 and 7 mmol cm&#8211;2 h&#8211;1, respectively. Also, it achieved a stable electrolysis for 120 h at 0.4 A in a membrane electrode assembly reactor and even operated stably at an industrial large current of 5 A. The carbon species promoted the reconstruction and dispersion of active component Bi, together with a spatial confinement effect that facilitated the formation of formate and achieved stable long-term electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Wenbin Li, Chang Yu, Xin Tan, Yongwen Ren, Yafang Zhang, Song Chen, Yi Yang, Jieshan Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B(C&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;F&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Catalyzed C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Alkylation of Tertiary Amines with Electron-Deficient Olefins: Determinants of Site Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01160</link>
      <description>Xin-Yue Zhou, Yuanhu Shao, Rui Guo, Yalin Zhang, Xiao&#8208;Song Xue, Xiao&#8208;Chen Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin-Yue Zhou, Yuanhu Shao, Rui Guo, Yalin Zhang, Xiao&#8208;Song Xue, Xiao&#8208;Chen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Urea Synthesis Rate on Ni Single-Atom Catalysts: The Impact of Acetonitrile Electrolyte in the Tandem CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction/Nucleophilic Addition Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01557</link>
      <description>Peize Li, Yan Wang, Xiaoju Yang, Yanbin Zhu, Zhiguo Zhang, Xuan Yang, Yan Shen, Mingkui Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396722222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peize Li, Yan Wang, Xiaoju Yang, Yanbin Zhu, Zhiguo Zhang, Xuan Yang, Yan Shen, Mingkui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01557</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Catalyzed Formal Dihydrosilylation of Terminal Alkynes: A C(sp)&#8211;H Silylation-Hydrosilylation-Hydrogenation Sequence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01813</link>
      <description>Jia Li, Siqiang Fang, Shaozhong Ge, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396722294

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Li, Siqiang Fang, Shaozhong Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Application of the Single-Module NRPS-like &lt;scp&gt;d&lt;/scp&gt;-Alanyltransferase in Maytansinol Biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00082</link>
      <description>Zhongyue Li, Zhangliang Zhu, Guangsen Xu, Wenhan Lin, Jiang Liu, Haoxin Wang, Ching&#8211;Liang Lu, Yaoyao Li, Deyu Zhu, Yuemao Shen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396723233

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongyue Li, Zhangliang Zhu, Guangsen Xu, Wenhan Lin, Jiang Liu, Haoxin Wang, Ching&#8211;Liang Lu, Yaoyao Li, Deyu Zhu, Yuemao Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barium Alginate Gel Beads: A Homochiral Porous Material from Brown Algae for Heterogeneous Asymmetric Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06036</link>
      <description>Pietro Pecchini, Daniel Aguilera, Alberto Soccio, Angelina Lombardi, F&#225;tima Sanz Azcona, Nicol&#242; Santarelli, Mariafrancesca Fochi, Pierrick Gaudin, Nathalie Tanchoux, Luca Bernardi, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396728497

                Asymmetric metal and organocatalysis typically relies on low-molecular-weight chiral compounds as enantioinducing elements. However, evoking biocatalysis, examples of inherently chiral natural (e.g., ds-DNA) and synthetic (e.g., chiral organic frameworks) macromolecules as enantioselective catalysts are rapidly emerging. In this context, we report barium alginate gel beads as heterogeneous and reusable catalysts for the benchmark addition of indoles to nitroalkenes, affording the corresponding adducts in moderate to good yields and enantioselectivities (up to 93% ee). This rare example of high enantioinduction offered by a polysaccharide in catalysis was realized thanks to the versatility of alginates, a family of biopolymers derived from brown algae. In the presence of multivalent metals, including abundant alkaline earth metal ones, alginates form gels featuring appealing properties for heterogeneous catalysis, such as high surface area and stability in different media.</description>
      <author>Pietro Pecchini, Daniel Aguilera, Alberto Soccio, Angelina Lombardi, F&#225;tima Sanz Azcona, Nicol&#242; Santarelli, Mariafrancesca Fochi, Pierrick Gaudin, Nathalie Tanchoux, Luca Bernardi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics for Catalysis Predictions: Are We Ready Yet?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05285</link>
      <description>Difan Zhang, Brett Smith, Haiyi Wu, Manh&#8208;Thuong Nguyen, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki Alexandra Glezakou, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396729186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Difan Zhang, Brett Smith, Haiyi Wu, Manh&#8208;Thuong Nguyen, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki Alexandra Glezakou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambiphilic Alcohol Dehydrogenation by BICAAC Mimicking Metal&#8211;Ligand Cooperativity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01723</link>
      <description>Shishir Bansal, Ayanangshu Biswas, Abhishek Kundu, Manu Adhikari, Sanjay Singh, Debashis Adhikari, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396731701

                In this report, an unusual bond activation strategy has been demonstrated by BICAAC, which essentially emulates the behavior of a transition metal. The ambiphilic nature of this specific carbene has facilitated a simultaneous proton and hydride capture from an alcohol molecule to carry out smooth dehydrogenation under mild conditions. The activation route closely follows the traditional metal&#8211;ligand bifunctional activation of a substrate. The hydrogen molecule extracted from the substrate alcohol becomes stored in the carbene carbon, which has been unambiguously ascertained by the isolation of this intermediate and its X-ray crystallographic characterization. Such an event has further been interrogated in detail by the deuterium-labeling experiment and DFT computations to substantiate the critical role of carbene's ambiphilicity. Additionally, the stored hydrogen in the carbene molecule has been delivered to an in situ-generated olefinic bond to completely mimic a borrowing hydrogen reaction in an organocatalytic fashion. Both dehydrogenation and rehydrogenation reactions have been conducted in a single pot using BICAAC as the catalyst that alkylates fluorene at its 9-position using a series of alcohols as the alkyl source. A thorough mechanistic sketch describes the involvement of a radical for the latter part of the reaction, overall bringing a different outlook to carbene-promoted small-molecule activation reactions.</description>
      <author>Shishir Bansal, Ayanangshu Biswas, Abhishek Kundu, Manu Adhikari, Sanjay Singh, Debashis Adhikari</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#960;&#8211;&#960; Interactions-Driven Ethylene Polymerization Using &#8220;Sandwich&#8221; Bis(imino)pyridyl Iron Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01248</link>
      <description>Z.-Y. Cheng, Haiyang Gao, Zonglin Qiu, Handou Zheng, Donghui Li, Long Jiang, Haiyang Gao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396746889

                Weak noncovalent interactions are an effective strategy for modulating catalytic olefin polymerization but have never been observed in bis(imino)pyridyl iron catalysts. In this paper, a series of "sandwich" bis(imino)pyridyl iron complexes with substituted 8-(p-R-phenyl)naphthylamine (R = OMe, Me, H, CF3) were designed and synthesized for ethylene polymerization. The &#960;&#8211;&#960; interactions between the capping aryl groups and the pyridyl ring are clearly observed in "sandwich" bis(imino)pyridyl iron complexes by single crystal X-ray diffraction analysis, UV&#8211;vis, and photoluminescence (PL) spectra. The intramolecular &#960;&#8211;&#960; interactions make the naphthyl rings tilt away from the iron center in the horizontal direction, thereby causing a more open horizontal space within iron complexes for ethylene coordination. Ethylene polymerization results show that &#960;&#8211;&#960; interactions are a crucial driving force rather than the electronic effects of ligands. Unprecedentedly, bulky "sandwich" bis(imino)pyridyl iron catalysts produce low-molecular-weight PE with a bimodal distribution, which originates from &#946;-H transfer to monomer modulated by the &#960;&#8211;&#960; interactions. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations mechanistically demonstrate that the coordination of ethylene to the iron center is a crucial step in ethylene polymerization.</description>
      <author>Z.-Y. Cheng, Haiyang Gao, Zonglin Qiu, Handou Zheng, Donghui Li, Long Jiang, Haiyang Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding the Kinetic Complexity of Pt-Catalyzed &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;-Butane Dehydrogenation by Machine Learning and Microkinetic Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00864</link>
      <description>Hu Yong, Cheng Gong, Ming Lei, Meng-Su Yang, De Chen, Xinggui Zhou, Yi&#8208;An Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396746891

                n-Butane dehydrogenation to butene and butadiene has recently gained increasing attention owing to the exploitation and development of shale gas as well as the rapid growth in the demand for synthetic rubber worldwide. In this work, the full n-butane dehydrogenation reaction network involving 568 elementary steps on Pt is established by using a chemical informatics approach to loop over all of the atoms and chemical bonds in n-butane. By combining density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the Morgan molecular fingerprint method, and machine learning techniques, we have identified 208 elementary steps that contribute to the kinetically important reaction network, which presents some general guidelines for the formulation of mechanisms of great complexity. A detailed microkinetic analysis that ensures thermodynamic consistency is then performed, without and with the presence of H2 cofeeding, to assess the n-butane catalytic activity and butene selectivity. It turns out that in the absence of H2, the high coverages of the coke precursors give rise to a low catalytic activity due to the occupancy of a large number of active sites. The turnover frequencies for n-butane consumption and butene production rise rapidly as the H2/n-C4H10 ratio goes up from 0 to 1.33. Meanwhile, the selectivity toward 1-butene increases as well, whereas the selectivities toward 2-butene and 1,3-butadiene are not sensitive to the H2 partial pressure. The flux analysis reveals that the dominant reaction pathways for 1-butene and 2-butene follow the reverse Horiuti&#8211;Polanyi mechanism, and the byproducts are formed primarily by the C&#8211;C bond cleavage in CH3CCHC*. The C&#8211;H bond activation in n-butane is identified by the sensitivity analysis as the rate-limiting step for the overall reaction while the selectivities toward butenes are found to be controlled dominantly by the ease with which n-butane can be activated and how readily butenes can be deeply dehydrogenated.</description>
      <author>Hu Yong, Cheng Gong, Ming Lei, Meng-Su Yang, De Chen, Xinggui Zhou, Yi&#8208;An Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bond Dissociation Energy-Controlled Regioselectivity in Hydrofunctionalization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00304</link>
      <description>Jie Peng, Xiaoqian He, Xiaoling Luo, Kangbao Zhong, Li&#8208;Li Liao, Ruopeng Bai, Yu Lan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396747447

                The bond dissociation energy (BDE) in reactants was found to be critical for determining the tunable pathways of low-valent tungsten-catalyzed chain-walking hydroboration and hydrogermylation of &#946;,&#947;-unsaturated amides, which is considered to be the key factor in the regioselective determination. Computational results revealed that the higher BDE of the H&#8211;B bond hampers the oxidative hydrogen migration, leading to borane reacting with tungsten later than alkenes. Thus, the generation of a &#946;-borylated product was found to be favorable through H&#8211;C&#946; bond oxidative addition, H&#8211;C&#948; bond reductive elimination, H&#8211;B bond oxidative hydrogen migration, and B&#8211;C&#946; bond reductive elimination. As a comparison, the lower BDE of H&#8211;Ge leads to a facile oxidative hydrogen migration of the H&#8211;Ge bond, which finally results in the formation of an &#945;-germylated product after germyl-assisted olefin walking. Further distortion&#8211;interaction analysis confirmed that the weak H&#8211;Ge bond was easier to distort for its reactions.</description>
      <author>Jie Peng, Xiaoqian He, Xiaoling Luo, Kangbao Zhong, Li&#8208;Li Liao, Ruopeng Bai, Yu Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing the Blowers&#8211;Masel Approximation to Scale Activation Energy Based on Reaction Enthalpy in Mean-Field Microkinetic Modeling for Catalytic Methane Partial Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05436</link>
      <description>Chao Xu, Emily Mazeau, Richard H. West, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760629

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Xu, Emily Mazeau, Richard H. West</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#947;-Amino C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Functionalization of Aliphatic Amines through a Light-Driven Triple Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02004</link>
      <description>Masanari Nakagawa, Kazunori Nagao, Hirohisa Ohmiya, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396770266

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Masanari Nakagawa, Kazunori Nagao, Hirohisa Ohmiya</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Particle Size-Dependent Charge Transfer Dynamics for Boosting CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoreduction over Ag/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01544</link>
      <description>Shicheng Liu, Qulan Zhou, Du Wen, Chenhao Wu, Yuqing Pan, Li Xiong, Zhong Huang, Na Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396773891

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shicheng Liu, Qulan Zhou, Du Wen, Chenhao Wu, Yuqing Pan, Li Xiong, Zhong Huang, Na Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01544</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced PtIn Catalyst via Ce-Assisted Confinement Effect in Propane Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02517</link>
      <description>Peng Wang, Huafei Liao, Yang Chen, Xin Tao, Yuyan Gan, Huihui Deng, Yajie Fu, Yu Tang, Lizhi Wu, Li Tan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396779672

                The PtIn nanoalloys with high surface energy are generally in a metastable state during harsh reaction conditions, and the ordered alloy structure is not conducive to exposure of surface Pt active sites. Herein, a strategy for restructuring the unfavorable PtIn alloy structure via heteroatom (Ce) doping is applied to advance an isolated Pt&#948;+ confined by the InCeOx nanoislands supported on SiO2. The as-synthesized catalyst with optimizing PtIn(Ce) ternary components exhibits &#8764;92.2% selectivity toward propylene and a stable propane conversion of &#8764;67.1% at 550 &#176;C (kd of 0.010 h&#8211;1). As demonstrated by the comprehensive characterizations, the introduced proper amount of Ce species leads to the reorganization of the disadvantaged PtIn nanoalloy structure into the robustness of the isolated Pt&#948;+ site confined by the InCeOx nanoislands via inhibiting the In0 species generation. The introduced Ce species modulate the electronic interaction between Pt, In, and carrier, stimulating the capability to activate reactive molecules and at the same time acting as spatial physical barriers to restrict the migration of the isolated Pt&#948;+ species. This work proposed a facile and efficient strategy to promote the capability against sintering and coking of the Pt-based catalyst in propane dehydrogenation.</description>
      <author>Peng Wang, Huafei Liao, Yang Chen, Xin Tao, Yuyan Gan, Huihui Deng, Yajie Fu, Yu Tang, Lizhi Wu, Li Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of a Physisorbed Tetrabutylammonium Cation Film on Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Pt Single-Crystal Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01765</link>
      <description>Julia Fern&#225;ndez-Vidal, Marc T. M. Koper, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780694

                The addition of tetrabutylammonium (TBA+) to alkaline electrolytes enhances the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity on Pt single-crystal electrodes. The concentration of TBA+ significantly influences the HER on Pt(111). Concentrations of &#8804;1 mM yield no significant effect on HER currents or the coverage of adsorbed hydrogen (H*) but exhibit an interaction with the OHads on the surface. Conversely, concentrations of &gt;1 mM result in an apparent site-blocking effect for underpotential-deposited H* caused by the physisorption of the organic cation, which counterintuitively leads to an increase in the HER activity. The physisorption of TBA+ is linked to its accumulation in the diffuse layer, as it can be reversibly removed by the addition of nonadsorbing cations such as sodium. Following the previous literature on the TBA+ interaction with electrode surfaces, we ascribe this effect to the formation of a two-dimensional TBA+ film in the double layer. On stepped Pt single-crystal surfaces, TBA+ enhances HER activity at all concentrations, primarily at step sites. Our findings not only highlight the complexities of TBA+ accumulation on Pt electrodes but also offer important molecular-level insights for optimizing the HER by organic film formation on various atomic-level electrode structures.</description>
      <author>Julia Fern&#225;ndez-Vidal, Marc T. M. Koper</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Controlling the Mizoroki&#8211;Heck Reaction of Cyclic Enones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00854</link>
      <description>Aishabibi Kassymbek, Francisco Jos&#233; Aguilar Troyano, Victoria Dimakos, Daniel P. Canterbury, S&#233;bastien Monfette, Philipp C. Roosen, Stephen G. Newman, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789234

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aishabibi Kassymbek, Francisco Jos&#233; Aguilar Troyano, Victoria Dimakos, Daniel P. Canterbury, S&#233;bastien Monfette, Philipp C. Roosen, Stephen G. Newman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Site-Level Deciphering of the Complexity of Electrochemical Oxygen Reduction on Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01640</link>
      <description>Geunsu Bae, Han Chang Kwon, Man Ho Han, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Chang Hyuck Choi, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789824

                Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts are emerging as potential alternatives to platinum in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) for fuel cell cathodes. The challenge in optimizing these catalysts lies in their structural complexity and the multiplicity of reaction pathways. Here, we employ a series of model catalysts with varying amounts of Fe&#8211;Nx and Fe nanoparticles (NPs) and estimate their turnover frequency (TOF) for apparent H2O and H2O2 production at different catalyst loadings. This approach highlights the importance of the surface site density (SD) of Fe&#8211;Nx moieties in determining the overall ORR activity, selectivity, and even stability. We uncover that increasing the SD of Fe&#8211;Nx moieties fosters the indirect 4e&#8211; ORR pathway and consequently promotes their TOF toward preferential H2O production. In contrast, Fe NPs, often formed at high Fe contents, behave as anticatalysts (or spectators) in this context. Indeed, an online inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) study reveals that a higher SD can lead to the faster leaching of Fe&#8211;Nx moieties during operation, resulting in accelerated activity decline. Taken together, the comprehensive understanding of the intricate dependence of catalytic activity and stability on the nature and amount of Fe species provides a basis for design principles of next-generation Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts.</description>
      <author>Geunsu Bae, Han Chang Kwon, Man Ho Han, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Chang Hyuck Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01640</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axially Chiral Bridged Biaryls by Ni-Catalyzed Kinetic Asymmetric C&#8211;O Bond Cleavage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02092</link>
      <description>Yijun Fang, Jingjing Hu, Tingting Sun, Yu Zhou, Gen Luo, Zhi&#8208;Chao Cao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396795922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yijun Fang, Jingjing Hu, Tingting Sun, Yu Zhou, Gen Luo, Zhi&#8208;Chao Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Enantioselective C&#8211;H Annulation by Achiral Rhodium(III)/Chiral Br&#248;nsted Base Domino Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01886</link>
      <description>Yanjun Li, Jiawei Xu, Jo&#227;o C. A. Oliveira, Alexej Scheremetjew, Lutz Ackermann, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396800102

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanjun Li, Jiawei Xu, Jo&#227;o C. A. Oliveira, Alexej Scheremetjew, Lutz Ackermann</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01886</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyrazino[2,3-&lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;][1,10]phenanthroline Derivatives as Robust Photocatalysts Enabling ppm-Level Organocatalyzed Photoinduced Electron/Energy Transfer Reversible Addition&#8211;Fragmentation Chain Transfer Polymerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01286</link>
      <description>Weiguo Hu, Jing Gao, Bingfeng Shi, Zhinan Xia, Yang Xiao, Yun Geng, Changli L&#252;, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396803695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiguo Hu, Jing Gao, Bingfeng Shi, Zhinan Xia, Yang Xiao, Yun Geng, Changli L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reprogramming the Microenvironment of Cobalt Phthalocyanine by a Targeted Multifunctional &#960;-Conjugated Modulator Enables Concerted CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00802</link>
      <description>Z. Wang, Jing Yang, Zichen Song, Meiting Lu, Wenqian Wang, Zhiyu Ren, Zhimin Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396805297

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Z. Wang, Jing Yang, Zichen Song, Meiting Lu, Wenqian Wang, Zhiyu Ren, Zhimin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00802</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
