<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 13:34:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of Single-Atom Fe&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; and Ce&#8211;O&lt;sub&gt;v&lt;/sub&gt; Sites on Mesoporous CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Efficient Selective Catalytic Reduction of NO with CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04682</link>
      <description>Y. Bai, Xupeng Zong, Jin Chen, Shu-Dong Wang, Sheng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390545888

                Nonprecious transition-metal oxides, especially Fe-, Cu-, Co-, and Mn-containing mixed oxides, have been regarded as promising alternatives for noble metal catalysts for the abatement of NOx contamination. However, the identification of the real catalytically active sites for these mixed oxides remains unclear in most cases, which limits our in-depth understanding of the intrinsic mechanism. Here, we comprehensively investigated an iron&#8211;cerium&#8211;aluminum oxide (Fe1/CeO2&#8211;Al2O3) prepared with a co-precipitation method. Structural identification confirmed that Fe sites are atomically dispersed, bonding with four O atoms in the first coordination shell and with two Ce atoms in the second shell on average. Highly efficient removal of NO with 100% selectivity toward N2 has been achieved over these sites at a temperature as low as 250 &#176;C. In situ characterizations and computational studies revealed that the high activity and N2 selectivity of Fe1/CeO2&#8211;Al2O3 can be attributed to the synergetic effect of the single-atomic Fe1 site and surrounding Ce&#8211;Ov, which intensively promotes the adsorption of NO molecules and N2O intermediates. Subsequently, Ce&#8211;Ov facilitates the N&#8211;O dissociation toward N2 and then is regenerated with CO, forming CO2 as a product. The present results provide valuable insights into the mechanism of transition-metal oxide catalysts for the NO&#8211;CO reaction and offer useful guidance for designing catalysts with high activity and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Y. Bai, Xupeng Zong, Jin Chen, Shu-Dong Wang, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Relevance of the Interfacial Water Reactivity for Electrochemical CO Reduction on Copper Single Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02700</link>
      <description>Daniel Winkler, Matthias Leitner, Andrea Auer, Julia Kunze&#8208;Liebh&#228;user, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390659412

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 is an important electrolysis reaction that enables the conversion of a waste gas to fuels or value-added chemicals. To make this reaction viable, a profound understanding of central intermediate steps, such as the CO electroreduction, is required. On Cu, the CO reduction reaction (CORR) is intimately linked to the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) that proceeds via the reduction of water in alkaline or neutral electrolytes. Here, we demonstrate that the interaction of water or more specifically the water reduction kinetics on differently smooth Cu(100) and Cu(111) surfaces during the CORR in alkaline media significantly governs the CORR. On Cu(111), faster HER kinetics and the highest CORR activity are observed, even though HER and CORR onsets are more negative. While on Cu(100) small Cu ad-island clusters form in the cathodic potential range only when CO is present, structural changes appear on a larger length scale on Cu(111) both under CORR conditions and when no CO is present. These differences in the reconstruction characteristics may be attributed to the dominance of either the CORR and its intermediates or the HER on the different Cu surfaces. Therefore, the interfacial water reactivity is considered an essential activity descriptor for the CORR on Cu in alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Daniel Winkler, Matthias Leitner, Andrea Auer, Julia Kunze&#8208;Liebh&#228;user</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Multimetallic Cooperativity in the Ring-Opening Polymerization of Cyclic Esters and Ethers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05103</link>
      <description>Utku Yolsal, Peter J. Shaw, Phoebe A. Lowy, Raju Chambenahalli, Jennifer A. Garden, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390673532

                The use of multimetallic complexes is a rapidly advancing route to enhance catalyst performance in the ring-opening polymerization of cyclic esters and ethers. Multimetallic catalysts often outperform their monometallic analogues in terms of reactivity and/or polymerization control, and these improvements are typically attributed to &#8220;multimetallic cooperativity&#8221;. Yet the origins of multimetallic cooperativity often remain unclear. This review explores the key factors underpinning multimetallic cooperativity, including metal&#8211;metal distances, the flexibility, electronics and conformation of the ligand framework, and the coordination environment of the metal centers. Emerging trends are discussed to provide insights into why cooperativity occurs and how to harness cooperativity for the development of highly efficient multimetallic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Utku Yolsal, Peter J. Shaw, Phoebe A. Lowy, Raju Chambenahalli, Jennifer A. Garden</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Characterization and Protein Engineering of a Glycosyltransferase GcCGT to Produce Flavone 6,8-Di-&lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;- and 6-&lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;-4&#8242;-&lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-Glycosides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05252</link>
      <description>Yang-Oujie Bao, Meng Zhang, Haoran Li, Zilong Wang, Jiajing Zhou, Yi Yang, Fudong Li, Lei Ye, Hongye Li, Hongwei Jin, Chao He, Min Ye, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390674506

                Herein, we discovered an efficient flavone 6-C-glycosyltransferase GcCGT from the medicinal plant Gentiana crassicaulis. GcCGT could catalyze consecutive two-step 6-C/4&#8242;-O-glycosylation of flavonoids. Homology modeling and site-directed mutagenesis yielded mutant F387K, which could catalyze the unprecedented 6-C-glycosylation of flavone 8-C-glycosides to produce 6,8-di-C-glycosides. To elucidate the catalytic mechanisms, the crystal structures of GcCGT-apo (2.10 &#197;) and GcCGT/UDP (2.40 &#197;) were resolved. Structural analysis and molecular dynamics simulations indicated that the lack of &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking interaction for F387 changed the protein conformation and expanded the entrance of the substrate binding pocket. This work provided an efficient method to synthesize flavone 6,8-di-C- and 6-C-4&#8242;-O-glycosides.</description>
      <author>Yang-Oujie Bao, Meng Zhang, Haoran Li, Zilong Wang, Jiajing Zhou, Yi Yang, Fudong Li, Lei Ye, Hongye Li, Hongwei Jin, Chao He, Min Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05252</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Mechanism for Oxidative Coupling of Methane Catalyzed by La&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;: Experimental and Microkinetic Modeling Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04714</link>
      <description>Zaili Xiong, Jijun Guo, Yuwen Deng, Bingzhi Liu, Hao Lou, Meirong Zeng, Zhandong Wang, Zhongyue Zhou, Wenhao Yuan, Fei Qi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390694581

                Oxidative coupling of methane (OCM) has been widely proposed to be one of the most promising methods for the direct conversion of methane to C2 products, such as ethane and ethene. Highly active free radicals play a crucial role, while accurate identifications are limited. To probe these free radicals and reveal their reactions, experiments focused on the OCM catalyzed by La2O3 were designed to be carried out in a packed bed reactor at low-pressure conditions over a wide temperature range. Dozens of species, including methyl radical, ethyl radical, and formaldehyde, were observed by using synchrotron vacuum ultraviolet photoionization mass spectrometry (SVUV-PIMS). A microkinetic model that coupled a detailed gas-phase and surface mechanism was developed and validated against the experimental results, especially to reveal the crucial roles of free radicals in the formation of C2 products as well as the oxygenated intermediates. The prediction results of the kinetic model agreed well with the experimental measurements. Rate of production and sensitivity analysis were performed to reveal the complex reaction network and key reactions of the OCM. Methyl was confirmed to play a key role based on both experimental and modeling perspectives, while ethyl is crucial in the transformation of C2 species and the formation of C3&#8211;C4 species. This indicates that the selective regulation of free radicals such as methyl and ethyl in OCM is worth paying attention to. The present work provides more detailed chemistry of OCM reactions, which would be helpful to improve product selectivity of OCM.</description>
      <author>Zaili Xiong, Jijun Guo, Yuwen Deng, Bingzhi Liu, Hao Lou, Meirong Zeng, Zhandong Wang, Zhongyue Zhou, Wenhao Yuan, Fei Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Monitoring of Heterogeneous Peroxygenase Reactions Unravels LPMO Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05194</link>
      <description>Lorenz Schwaiger, Florian Csarman, Hui S. Chang, Ole Golten, Vincent G. H. Eijsink, Roland Ludwig, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390697114

                Biological conversion of plant biomass depends on peroxygenases and peroxidases acting on insoluble polysaccharides and lignin. Among these are cellulose- and hemicellulose-degrading lytic polysaccharide monooxygenases (LPMOs), which have revolutionized our concept of biomass degradation. Major obstacles limiting mechanistic and functional understanding of these unique peroxygenases are their complex and insoluble substrates and the hard-to-measure H2O2 consumption, resulting in the lack of suitable kinetic assays. We report a versatile and robust electrochemical method for real-time monitoring and kinetic characterization of LPMOs and other H2O2-dependent interfacial enzymes based on a rotating disc electrode for the sensitive and selective quantitation of H2O2 at biologically relevant concentrations. The H2O2 sensor works in suspensions of insoluble substrates as well as in homogeneous solutions. Our characterization of multiple LPMOs provides unprecedented insights into the substrate specificity, kinetics, and stability of these enzymes. High turnover and total turnover numbers demonstrate that LPMOs are fast and durable biocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Lorenz Schwaiger, Florian Csarman, Hui S. Chang, Ole Golten, Vincent G. H. Eijsink, Roland Ludwig</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Alloy Catalysts for Alkyne Semihydrogenation via Descriptor-Based High-Throughput Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</link>
      <description>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701504

                Although alloying is a common approach to developing catalysts for alkyne selective hydrogenation, the geometric and electronic effects of active sites on the kinetics of alkyne selective hydrogenation are still ambiguous, hindering rational design of alloy catalysts. Herein, we construct structural descriptors to categorize and reorganize the roles of electronic and geometric factors in the kinetics of acetylene semihydrogenation. The prediction model based on our proposed structural descriptors successfully elucidates the activity and selectivity trends among Pd-based alloys and can also be extended to rationalize the kinetics trend among single-atom alloys and Ni-based alloys for semihydrogenation of acetylene and even other alkynes, in good agreement with available experimental references. Aided by thermodynamic stability analysis and structural descriptors, 489 Pd-based bimetallic alloys via a high-throughput screening protocol were evaluated, and finally, Pd1Nb3 and Pd1Hf3 were identified with a high yield of ethylene and inexpensive cost and validated by our experimental studies.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visible-Light Photocatalyzed C3&#8211;H Alkylation of 2&lt;i&gt;H&lt;/i&gt;-Indazoles/Indoles with Sulfoxonium Ylides via Diversified Mechanistic Pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04729</link>
      <description>Altman Yuzhu Peng, Yujing Wang, Kaifeng Wang, Qi Sun, Xiaoguang Bao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701516

                Herein, the C3&#8211;H alkylation of 2H-indazoles and indoles with sulfoxonium ylides is developed under visible-light photocatalysis. This protocol employs easily accessible reagents, and a wide range of 2H-indazoles, indoles, and sulfoxonium ylides are suitable for this reaction to afford the desired products under benign conditions. Synergistic experimental and computational studies suggest that the sulfoxonium ylides involving C3&#8211;H alkylation of 2H-indazoles and indoles under visible-light photocatalysis could proceed via different mechanistic pathways. For the C3-alkylation of 2H-indazoles, a triplet energy transfer mechanistic pathway of 2H-indazoles is proposed for quenching the excited photocatalyst. Subsequently, the formed excited triplet state of 2H-indazoles could undergo radical attack on the C&#9552;S moiety of sulfoxonium ylides. After the dissociation of DMSO and 1,2-H migration, the final product of C3-alkylation of 2H-indazoles could be yielded. However, such a mechanistic pathway is not applicable for indoles. Instead, sulfoxonium ylides could be converted to a C-centered radical in the presence of KH2PO4 under visible-light photoredox conditions. The formed C-centered radical can attack the C3-site of indoles and thus lead to the C3-alkylation product of indoles.</description>
      <author>Altman Yuzhu Peng, Yujing Wang, Kaifeng Wang, Qi Sun, Xiaoguang Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Unconventional Reduction of C&#9552;N Bonds by Old Yellow Enzymes Using QM/MM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04362</link>
      <description>Amit Singh, Nakia Polidori, Wolfgang Kroutil, Karl Gruber, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390704303

                The reduction of C&#9552;X (X = N, O) bonds is a cornerstone in both synthetic organic chemistry and biocatalysis. Conventional reduction mechanisms usually involve a hydride ion targeting the less electronegative carbon atom. In a departure from this paradigm, our investigation into Old Yellow Enzymes (OYEs) reveals a mechanism involving transfer of hydride to the formally more electronegative nitrogen atom within a C&#9552;N bond. Beyond their known ability to reduce electronically activated C&#9552;C double bonds, e.g., in &#945;, &#946;-unsaturated ketones, these enzymes have recently been shown to reduce &#945;-oximo-&#946;-ketoesters to the corresponding amines. It has been proposed that this transformation involves two successive reduction steps and proceeds via imine intermediates formed by the reductive dehydration of the oxime moieties. We employ advanced quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) simulations, enriched by a two-tiered approach incorporating QM/MM (UB3LYP-6-31G*/OPLS2005) geometry optimization, QM/MM (B3LYP-6-31G*/amberff19sb) steered molecular dynamics simulations, and detailed natural-bond-orbital analyses to decipher the unconventional hydride transfer to nitrogen in both reduction steps and to delineate the role of active site residues as well as of substituents present in the substrates. Our computational results confirm the proposed mechanism and agree well with experimental mutagenesis and enzyme kinetics data. According to our model, the catalysis of OYE involves hydride transfer from the flavin cofactor to the nitrogen atom in oximoketoesters as well as iminoketoesters followed by protonation at the adjacent oxygen or carbon atoms by conserved tyrosine residues and active site water molecules. Two histidine residues play a key role in the polarization and activation of the C&#9552;N bond, and conformational changes of the substrate observed along the reaction coordinate underline the crucial importance of dynamic electron delocalization for efficient catalysis.</description>
      <author>Amit Singh, Nakia Polidori, Wolfgang Kroutil, Karl Gruber</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active MnCoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst toward CO Preferential Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04654</link>
      <description>Jun Yu, Yusen Yang, Meng Zhang, Boyu Song, Yu Han, Si Wang, Zhihao Ren, Lei Wang, Ping Yin, Lirong Zheng, Xin Zhang, Min Wei, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390704389

                Preferential oxidation of CO (CO-PROX) is an efficient method to eliminate residual CO in the feed stream to avoid Pt poisoning in proton-exchange-membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs), in which the development of high-performance, low-cost catalysts remains a big challenge. Herein, we report highly active spinel-like MnCoOx catalysts derived from layered double hydroxide (LDH) precursors, which are featured with abundant octahedron-distorted lattice oxygen. Impressively, the optimal catalyst MnCoOx-300 achieves the selective and complete removal of CO from a H2-rich stream at 80 &#176;C, within a wide operation temperature window (80&#8211;200 &#176;C, matching well with PEMFCs) at a rather high space velocity (80,000 h&#8211;1). This performance, to the best of our knowledge, outperforms previously reported non-noble metal catalysts and even exceeds the state-of-the-art CuO/CeO2 system in the CO-PROX technology. A comprehensive investigation based on in situ Raman, in situ XAFS, in situ TPD-Mass, and in situ DRIFTS reveals that the Cooct3+&#8211;O2&#8211;&#8211;Mnoct4+ structure in MnCoOx-300 serves as the intrinsic active site that facilitates preferential oxidation: the lattice oxygen participates in the oxidation of CO to produce CO2 and oxygen vacancy (Ov), followed by the replenishment of oxygen species from aerial oxygen (the rate-determining step) to regenerate Cooct3+&#8211;O2&#8211;&#8211;Mnoct4+. Isotopic 18O kinetic studies and in situ DRIFTS substantiate that the reaction temperature plays a crucial role in the competitive oxidation of CO vs H2 at the same active site. This work provides a successful paradigm for the design and preparation of transition metal oxide catalysts toward the CO-PROX reaction, which shows potential applications in hydrogen purification for PEMFCs.</description>
      <author>Jun Yu, Yusen Yang, Meng Zhang, Boyu Song, Yu Han, Si Wang, Zhihao Ren, Lei Wang, Ping Yin, Lirong Zheng, Xin Zhang, Min Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Carbene Initiated O&#8211;H Insertion/Aldol Cascade for the Stereoselective Synthesis of Functionalized Tetrahydrofurans</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05040</link>
      <description>Prakash Kafle, B. N. Ghosh, Arianne C. Hunter, Rishav Mukherjee, Kenneth M. Nicholas, Indrajeet Sharma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390718518

                Given its earth abundance, cost-effectiveness, and ecofriendly qualities, iron serves as a promising alternative to precious metals in catalysis. This article presents an iron carbene-initiated cascade approach for synthesizing highly substituted tetrahydrofurans at the gram scale. This cascade reaction utilizes readily accessible &#946;-hydroxyketones and diazo compounds and works with iron catalyst loading as low as 5 mol %. This reaction proceeds through an O&#8211;H insertion into diazo-derived iron carbenes, followed by an intramolecular aldol reaction to access functionalized tetrahydrofurans in high yields and diastereoselectivity. The versatile nature of this domino sequence accommodates diverse &#946;-hydroxyketones and diazo compounds, streamlining access to synthetically challenging spiroethers. Furthermore, this cascade process offers a route to enantiopure tetrahydrofurans by utilizing a diazo ester bearing a chiral auxiliary, 8-phenylmenthol. Postmodifications of the tetrahydrofuran product provide access to various analogues, including a medicinally relevant oxetane motif. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations substantiate a stereospecific mechanism wherein the intramolecular aldol reaction proceeds via a fused six- and five-membered iron&#8211;oxygen transition-state complex, yielding the contrathermodynamic cis-aldol product.</description>
      <author>Prakash Kafle, B. N. Ghosh, Arianne C. Hunter, Rishav Mukherjee, Kenneth M. Nicholas, Indrajeet Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of &#8220;NO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#183;&#183;&#183;NH&#8221; Hydrogen Bond-Stabilized C&#8211;N Axially Chiral Diarylamines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04775</link>
      <description>Wei Lin, Yuanhu Shao, Zeyang Hao, Zhe Huang, Zhiyuan Ren, Li Chen, Xin Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390724252

                Herein, N-nucleophilic tandem oxidation&#8211;N-arylation&#8211;oxidation reaction and C-nucleophilic bromination reaction of substituted anilines have been developed using chiral phosphoric acid catalysis, enabling access to axially chiral diarylamines. The key feature of this strategy is that the &#8220;NO2&#183;&#183;&#183;H&#8211;N&#8221; hydrogen bond was successfully introduced into acyclic diaryl secondary amines, which contain two potential contiguous atropisomeric C&#8211;N axes, to stabilize one of the planar axial conformations. This methodology provided a series of optically pure diarylamine atropisomers containing this new hydrogen bond type in good yields (up to 99%) and high enantiomeric ratios (up to 99.5:0.5 e.r.). The synthetic utility was demonstrated through large-scale reactions and transformations of the products. Plausible models were proposed to explain the enantioselectivity of the products.</description>
      <author>Wei Lin, Yuanhu Shao, Zeyang Hao, Zhe Huang, Zhiyuan Ren, Li Chen, Xin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape Selectivity of AEL Channels for Anomalously Facilitating Biojet Fuel Production from Long-Chain &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;-Alkane Hydrocracking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04465</link>
      <description>Chao Mu, Junhao Sun, Chuang Xie, Jianming Bao, Xuan Guo, Haozhe Zhang, Yujun Zhao, Shengping Wang, Xinbin Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390732536

                Hydrocracking of long-chain n-alkanes from hydrotreating of vegetable oil is critical for biojet fuel production and requires selective C&#8211;C cleavage near the long-chain alkane end. Due to preferential cracking near the carbon chain end in AEL channels, SAPO-11 optionally produces heavy jet fuel fractions in hydrocracking of the model reactant n-C16. Also, the weak acidity of SAPO-11 promotes olefin desorption and markedly reduces the second cracking of jet fuel fractions formed. Compared to 10-MR Si&#8211;Al ZSM-22, ZSM-23, ZSM-5, and ZSM-35 zeolites, SAPO-11 significantly improves the jet fuel production performance. Surprisingly,10-membered rings (10-MR) SAPO-11 exhibits higher jet fuel yields than 12-membered rings (12-MR) HUSY (FAU topology), contrary to the general belief that larger pores are more conducive to heavy cracking product production. Further, theoretical molar cracking product distributions of C15&#8211;C18 fractions are proposed, highlighting the superior performance of SAPO-11 over that of HUSY and delineating the yield limits for jet fuel production. Higher than those of commercial biojet fuels, the isomer content of jet fuel fractions exceeds 89% at cracking yield above 70%. It indicates that weakly acidic SAPO-11 has potential for specific cracking reactions near the long-chain alkane end, which enriches the understanding of selective C&#8211;C cleavage by zeolites for high-value cracking products.</description>
      <author>Chao Mu, Junhao Sun, Chuang Xie, Jianming Bao, Xuan Guo, Haozhe Zhang, Yujun Zhao, Shengping Wang, Xinbin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the Structure of Mn-NiS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; during Urea Oxidation Using Combined In Situ X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy and Attenuated Total Reflectance Surface-Enhanced Infrared Absorption Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05369</link>
      <description>Niangao Duan, Tianxin Hou, Wei Zheng, Yafei Qu, Peichen Wang, Jun Yang, Yang Yang, Dongdong Wang, Jitang Chen, Qianwang Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390734560

                The urea electrocatalytic oxidation reaction (UOR) has enormous potential as an ideal alternative anode reaction for water splitting owing to its lower thermodynamic equilibrium potential of 0.37 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (vs RHE). Nickel-based materials, especially NiOOH, are considered to be one of the most promising non-noble metal catalysts for UOR due to their inexpensive cost and rich abundance. However, NiOOH displays a high overpotential and poor long-term stability. Herein, our density functional theory calculations show that the rate-determining step for UOR is desorption of CO2 on NiOOH, and Mn-doped NiOOH has the lowest energy for CO2 desorption. Hence, we prepared a Mn-NiS2 precatalyst that would transform into the active form of Mn-NiOOH during the electrochemical process. The catalyst exhibits good performance for UOR, achieving 100 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.426 V (vs RHE, without IR correction) for 200 h with no significant voltage change, which is rarely reported for nonprecious-metal UOR catalysts. X-ray absorption near-edge spectroscopy and X-ray diffraction characterization show the transformation from sulfide to oxyhydroxide when a voltage is applied, while in situ attenuated total reflectance surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy (ATR-SEIRAS) proves that Mn-NiOOH accelerates the desorption of CO2 compared to NiOOH.</description>
      <author>Niangao Duan, Tianxin Hou, Wei Zheng, Yafei Qu, Peichen Wang, Jun Yang, Yang Yang, Dongdong Wang, Jitang Chen, Qianwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of Electronic Metal-Support Interaction between Cu and ZnO by Er for Effective Low-Temperature CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04608</link>
      <description>Chaojie Huang, Shunan Zhang, Ke Wang, Haozhi Zhou, Zilong Shao, Lin Xia, Hui Wang, Yuhan Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390752746

                Methanol produced by CO2 hydrogenation is an essential carrier for a sustainable carbon cycle. However, achieving an efficient methanol synthesis on traditional CuZnO catalysts at low temperatures remains challenging due to the inertness of CO2. Herein, we designed Er&#8211;CuZnO catalysts that exhibited remarkable activity for low-temperature methanol synthesis. At 170 &#176;C, the catalyst achieved a methanol selectivity of 89.8% at a CO2 conversion of 8.5% on Er0.2CuZnO, which outperformed most CuZnO-based catalysts. The particle size of ZnO was reduced after Er was added to the lattice, which increased the Cu&#8211;ZnO interfaces and created a strong electronic metal-support interaction (EMSI) between Cu and ZnO. The electron was transferred from ZnO to Cu, forming Cu&#948;&#8722;. Cu&#948;&#8722; with more negative charges enhanced CO2 adsorbed species and intermediates activation, while facilitating surface carbonate activation and the hydrogenation of *CO intermediates into *HCO species, promoting the methanol formation at low temperatures.</description>
      <author>Chaojie Huang, Shunan Zhang, Ke Wang, Haozhi Zhou, Zilong Shao, Lin Xia, Hui Wang, Yuhan Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Stability Mechanism of Cu Active Sites in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction via Suppression of Antibonding Orbital Occupancy in the O 2p-Cu 3d Hybridization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04710</link>
      <description>Youxian Sun, Xiaojun Wang, Huiying Zhang, Xueying Gao, Xiaoxuan Wang, Shiyu Wang, Zheng Tang, Shuyuan Li, Kaiqi Nie, Jiangzhou Xie, Zhiyu Yang, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390753980

                Copper-based catalysts, hallmarked by their ideal C&#8211;C coupling energy facilitated by the symbiotic presence of Cu+ and Cu0 active sites, are poised to revolutionize the selective electrochemical reduction of CO2 to C2H4. Regrettably, these catalysts are beleaguered by the unavoidable diminution of Cu+ to Cu0 during the reaction process, resulting in suboptimal C2H4 yields. To circumvent this limitation, we have judiciously mitigated the antibonding orbital occupancy in the O 2p and Cu+ 3d hybridization by introducing Cu defects into Cu2O, thereby augmenting the Cu&#8211;O bond strength to stabilize Cu+ sites and further decipher the stabilization mechanism of Cu+. This structural refinement, illuminated by meticulous DFT calculations, fosters a heightened free energy threshold for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), while orchestrating a thermodynamically favorable milieu for enhanced C&#8211;C coupling within the Cu-deficient Cu2O (Cuv-Cu2O). Empirically, Cuv-Cu2O has outperformed its pure Cu2O counterpart, exhibiting a prominent C2H4/CO ratio of 1.69 as opposed to 1.01, without conceding significant ground in C2H4 production over an 8 h span at &#8722;1.3 V vs RHE. This endeavor not only delineates the critical influence of antibonding orbital occupancy on bond strength and reveals the deep mechanism about Cu+ sites but also charts a pioneering pathway in the realm of advanced materials design.</description>
      <author>Youxian Sun, Xiaojun Wang, Huiying Zhang, Xueying Gao, Xiaoxuan Wang, Shiyu Wang, Zheng Tang, Shuyuan Li, Kaiqi Nie, Jiangzhou Xie, Zhiyu Yang, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04710</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymer Tacticity Control for Stereoselective Ring-Opening Polymerization of Racemic &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;-Propylglycolide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04798</link>
      <description>Guojie Li, Guiying Xu, Guo Xuan-hua, Rong Yang, Hongwei Sun, Qinggang Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390778848

                The synthesis of stereoregular aliphatic polyesters with superior (bio)degradability and recyclability has been one of the promising areas in material science, which can be achieved through the stereoselective polymerization of cyclic esters. However, it remains a long-standing challenge to achieve tacticity (isotactic and heterotactic) control of aliphatic polyesters in one catalytic system through modulation of the polymerization mechanism. Here we reported a tunable and controllable method for stereoselective polymerization of racemic n-propylglycolide (nPrgl) based on the analysis of the enantiomorphic site control (ESC) and chain-end control (CEC) mechanisms in the polymerization. The enantiomorphic site control and chain-end control-dominated stereoregular polymerization processes were achieved via adjustable polymerization conditions, producing isotactic poly(nPrgl) with a Pm of up to 0.88 (based on ESC) and heterotactic poly(nPrgl) with a Pr of up to 0.94 (based on CEC). This understanding of ESC and CEC mechanisms might provide a compelling guidance to the design of stereoselective polymerization.</description>
      <author>Guojie Li, Guiying Xu, Guo Xuan-hua, Rong Yang, Hongwei Sun, Qinggang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Low Z-Elements in a Ni/MgFeAlO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst during Reaction: Insight from In Situ XRS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05563</link>
      <description>Souvik Das, Lennert D&#8217;ooghe, Nadadur Veeraraghavan Srinath, Stavros Alexandros Theofanidis, Alessandro Longo, Christoph J. Sahle, Kevin Van Geem, Hilde Poelman, Dirk Poelman, Vladimir Galvita, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390806369

                Ni/MgFeAlO4 displays promising activity and stability in the dry reforming of methane. In order to establish a correlation between its performance and structural changes, an in-depth analysis of the Ni/MgFeAlO4 catalyst&#8217;s constituent elements is conducted using in situ techniques, specifically combined X-ray emission spectroscopy (XES) and X-ray Raman scattering (XRS) spectroscopy. This investigation spans sequential treatments involving H2 reduction, CO2 reoxidation, and methane dry reforming. XES valence-to-core signals for Fe and Ni retrace the applied treatments. After the reaction, Ni is fully metallic, while Fe shows a mixed metal-oxide state. Comparing these XES spectroscopic data with ab initio simulations indicates that dry reforming of methane does not form metal carbide. C K-edge XRS data recorded after the reaction do not protrude above the noise, proving the capability of the Ni/MgFeAlO4 catalyst to mitigate carbon deposition. O K-edge spectra exhibit variations corresponding to each treatment, effectively replicated through simulations with semiempirical screening parameters. These parameters represent electron transfer between oxygen and neighboring 3d transition metal elements and offer insights into the acid&#8211;base properties of the material. Furthermore, the Al L2,3-edge spectra provide valuable information about the impact of treatments on the spinel arrangement, indicating an increasing tetrahedral occupancy of Al3+ in the support. By employing a comprehensive approach that combines XRS with XES, this study provides a holistic understanding of the evolution of low Z-elements, O and Al, alongside Fe and Ni, in the Ni/MgFeAlO4 catalyst throughout the reduction, reoxidation, and methane dry reforming processes.</description>
      <author>Souvik Das, Lennert D&#8217;ooghe, Nadadur Veeraraghavan Srinath, Stavros Alexandros Theofanidis, Alessandro Longo, Christoph J. Sahle, Kevin Van Geem, Hilde Poelman, Dirk Poelman, Vladimir Galvita</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorinated Defect-Engineered Acetylenic Polymers with Separated Active Centers for Switching the Photosensitized Activation Pathway of Peroxymonosulfate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03830</link>
      <description>Tao Zeng, Xiaojun Tang, Xiaoyan Cai, Sijia Jin, Zhu Yang, Wenhua Xu, Lingxiangyu Li, Haiyan Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390807239

                The engineering of conjugated acetylenic polymers (CAPs) has great potential for photosensitized oxyanion activation, wherein their catalytic performance can be further advanced by incorporating artificial defects, while relevant reports are rare. Herein, we deliberately introduce the fluorinated defect into the structure of poly(1,3,5-triethynylbenzene) (PTEB) via copper-surface mediated Glaser polycondensation (denote as PTEB-Fx). PTEB-Fx exhibits a surface with an abundance of acetylene moieties that possess a strong affinity for capturing oxyanions through preferential binding to peroxy-bonds of oxyanions. Meanwhile, the adjacent fluorinated defects effectively delocalize &#960;-electrons, narrow the optical bandgap, and facilitate charge separation, thereby optimizing kinetics and thermodynamics of peroxymonosulfate (PMS) activation. Such spatial separated active centers leads to a synergistic effect involving the enhanced oxidation ability of holes (h+) and the elongation of the O&#8211;H bond in PMS, which triggers a switch in the activation pathway toward oxidative activation for the generation of singlet oxygen (1O2), as opposed to the conventional reductive activation course yielding radical species (&#8226;OH and SO4&#8226;&#8211;). Additionally, PTEB-Fx featuring inherent self-standing merit overcomes challenges associated with limited light energy utilization and the cumbersome retrieval of powder photosensitizers, thus broadening its potential for large-scale application.</description>
      <author>Tao Zeng, Xiaojun Tang, Xiaoyan Cai, Sijia Jin, Zhu Yang, Wenhua Xu, Lingxiangyu Li, Haiyan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Highly Active Pd&#8211;Ti&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; Sites in Defective Pd/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for Efficient Hydrogenation of Styrene&#8211;Butadiene&#8211;Styrene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04811</link>
      <description>Shidong Wang, Bingqing Ge, Zhiliang Yang, Hongwei Zhang, Qin Yang, Cejun Hu, Xiaojun Bao, Pei Yuan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390818780

                Defect-rich Pd/TiO2 catalysts are intensively adopted in heterogeneous hydrogenation reactions; however, the complexity of the defect structure makes it difficult to precisely identify which Pd-defect combination dominates the catalytic activity. Herein, defective TiO2 nanoflakes with tunable ratios of Vo to Ti3+ defects were synthesized and used to construct Pd&#8211;Vo and Pd&#8211;Ti3+ active sites after loading Pd to investigate the role of defects in regulating the structural and catalytic properties of defective Pd/TiO2 catalysts. Combining the experimental results and theoretical calculations, we reveal that both Vo and Ti3+ defects act as the electron donors for Pd and induce the strong metal&#8211;support interaction. When compared to the Vo defect, the Ti3+ defect behaves more significantly and donates more electrons, causing the Pd species on the catalysts to be better dispersed and more rich in electrons. These unique features endow the Pd&#8211;Ti3+ active centers with enhanced adsorption&#8211;activation ability toward C&#9552;C and H2 as well as reduced energy barrier of the rate-limiting step, thus improving the intrinsic activity. The Pd&#8211;Ti3+ site manifests a high turnover frequency of 348 h&#8211;1 and hydrogenation degree of 97% for hydrogenation of C&#9552;C in styrene&#8211;butadiene&#8211;styrene, which significantly outperforms the Pd&#8211;Vo site (254 h&#8211;1 and 78%) and Pd nanoparticle (217 h&#8211;1 and 53%). This work provides deep insight into the role of defects in regulating the properties of metal active sites, which can be used to guide the development of high-performance Pd/TiO2 catalysts for versatile applications.</description>
      <author>Shidong Wang, Bingqing Ge, Zhiliang Yang, Hongwei Zhang, Qin Yang, Cejun Hu, Xiaojun Bao, Pei Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effects of Co&#8211;Fe Boosts the Transformation of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; into C&lt;sub&gt;6+&lt;/sub&gt; Dicarboxylic Acids up to Gram-Scale under Mild Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05395</link>
      <description>Ying Zhang, Junjun Mao, Bo Zhang, Dan Wang, Chenchen Zhang, Yang Lou, Chengsi Pan, Yongfa Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390841453

                Electrochemical carboxylation of 1,3-dienes with carbon dioxide (CO2) is a feasible method to obtain dicarboxylic derivatives, which are important synthetic intermediates of polymers and pharmaceuticals. However, due to unavoidable byproducts and unfriendly conditions, the formation of pure dicarboxylic acids has been limited. In this work, we report that a bimetallic phosphating CoFeP catalyst on nickel foam (CoFeP/NF) served as a remarkable electrode, which transforms CO2 into multicarbon (C6+) dicarboxylic acids. The synergistic effects of CoFeP catalyst between Co and Fe allow activation of 1,3-dienes mainly, in which electron transfer easier to the 1,3-dienes proceeded to afford radical anion of the diene, pursuant carboxylation with CO2 and further electron transfer formed the ultimate carboxylated products. The reaction can occur in a commercial flow cell with gram-scale amplification. The dicarboxylic acid obtained was up to 1.08 g at a 5 mmol scale of 1,3-dienes, illustrating high electrocatalytic activity and practical application of CoFeP/NF.</description>
      <author>Ying Zhang, Junjun Mao, Bo Zhang, Dan Wang, Chenchen Zhang, Yang Lou, Chengsi Pan, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05395</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palladium-Catalyzed Aminations in Flow ... &lt;i&gt;on Water&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05257</link>
      <description>Madison J Wong, Erfan Oftadeh, John Saunders, Alex B. Wood, Bruce H. Lipshutz, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390907051

                Aminations can be efficiently run, under plug flow conditions on water, catalyzed by low levels of a recyclable palladium precatalyst. General protocols to couple amines, both aryl and aliphatic, with aryl/heteroaryl bromides have been developed. Further highlights include &#8220;on water&#8221; conditions, short reaction times, recycling of the reaction medium, low levels of residual Pd in the isolated products, and low E factors as a green metric, all of these features showcasing this alternative to amination reactions typically run in batch mode.</description>
      <author>Madison J Wong, Erfan Oftadeh, John Saunders, Alex B. Wood, Bruce H. Lipshutz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligands Defect-Induced Structural Self-Reconstruction of Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;Co-Hydroxyl Oxides with Crystalline/Amorphous Heterophase from a 2D Metal&#8211;Organic Framework for an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05314</link>
      <description>Hongqi Chu, Rujin Li, Panpan Feng, Dongyan Wang, Chunxiang Li, Yanling Yu, Min Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390907090

                The two-dimensional (2D) Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;Co-MOF is synthesized using a simple double ligand strategy at room temperature. The surface reconstruction process transforms it into a crystalline&#8211;amorphous heterojunction composed of polycrystalline metal (oxy)hydroxide (MOOH) and amorphous metal oxides/hydroxides with terephthalic acid (TPA) by coordination covalent bonding. In situ Raman spectroscopy discloses the dynamic structure conversion. Density functional theory (DFT), Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), and solid-state nuclear magnetic resonance (SSNMR) reveal the induction of the ligand defects on surface reconstruction and the enhancing effect of TPA on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance through a covalent interaction. The amorphous&#8211;crystalline heterojunction of Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;CoOOH-TPA has numerous structural defects and high electrical conductivity, resulting in an efficient and stable OER performance with overpotentials of 236 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2. It has also been observed that the catalyst processes self-healing in an idle state, arising from the reversible conversion of MOOH to M(OH)2. This work reveals the structural and compositional transformation of the 2D Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;Co-MOF during surface reconstruction, elucidating the relationship between electrocatalytic reconstruction and water-splitting performance of metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF)-based catalysts. It has been proven that appropriate covalent interactions enhance the OER of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongqi Chu, Rujin Li, Panpan Feng, Dongyan Wang, Chunxiang Li, Yanling Yu, Min Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Catalyzed Regioselective Reductive Fluoroalkylalkenylation of Unactivated Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05690</link>
      <description>Siyu Wang, Baochuan Guo, Tong Mu, Zhengli Liu, Yun He, Xiao&#8208;Song Xue, Zhihai Feng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390929188

                The example of iron-catalyzed reductive fluoroalkylalkenylation of unactivated alkenes has been disclosed, affording the stereodefined homoallylic fluoroalkanes with high efficiency and regioselectivity. This three-component cross-electrophile coupling features directing groups free, good functional group tolerance, broad substrate scope, and late-stage difunctionalization of biorelevant molecules. Moreover, this protocol sheds light on the distinct reactivity disparities between fluoroalkyl and nonfluoroalkyl radicals in three-component reductive cross-coupling reactions, highlighting the unique nature of iron/B2pin2 systems.</description>
      <author>Siyu Wang, Baochuan Guo, Tong Mu, Zhengli Liu, Yun He, Xiao&#8208;Song Xue, Zhihai Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Insights into a Side Chain Cross-Linking Biarylitide P450 from RiPP Biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05417</link>
      <description>Mathias Henning Hansen, Angus B. Keto, Maxine Treisman, Vishnu Mini Sasi, Laura Coe, Yongwei Zhao, Leo Padva, Caroline He&#223;, Victor Leichthammer, Daniel L. Machell, Ralf B. Schittenhelm, Colin J. Jackson, Julien Tailhades, Max Cr&#252;semann, James J. De Voss, Elizabeth H. Krenske, Max J. Cryle, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390537464

                Peptide side chain cross-linking is an important feature of many natural products, with an increasing number of examples catalyzed by cytochrome P450s being reported from ribosomal biosynthesis pathways in addition to well-known examples from nonribosomal peptide antibiotics. Despite the dramatic recent increase in the number of enzymes and reactions catalyzed, substrate bound structures of such P450s have proven elusive to date. Here, we report the structural characterization of the biarylitide cross-linking enzyme P450Blt in complex with its pentapeptide substrate MRYLH. This structure, in combination with computational and biochemical experiments, shows the importance of key I-helix residues in this P450 in coordinating to the histidine residue of the substrate and further that this appears to be central to the specificity of this enzyme for generating a C&#8211;N link between the tyrosine and histidine residues in the MRYLH substrate. The structure of the P450Blt-MRYLH complex provides the first insight into how peptide substrates can be accommodated within P450s and offers insights into how other examples of related P450s can accept the varied substrates that have recently been identified using bioinformatic methods.</description>
      <author>Mathias Henning Hansen, Angus B. Keto, Maxine Treisman, Vishnu Mini Sasi, Laura Coe, Yongwei Zhao, Leo Padva, Caroline He&#223;, Victor Leichthammer, Daniel L. Machell, Ralf B. Schittenhelm, Colin J. Jackson, Julien Tailhades, Max Cr&#252;semann, James J. De Voss, Elizabeth H. Krenske, Max J. Cryle</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of Single-Atom Fe&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; and Ce&#8211;O&lt;sub&gt;v&lt;/sub&gt; Sites on Mesoporous CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Efficient Selective Catalytic Reduction of NO with CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04682</link>
      <description>Y. Bai, Xupeng Zong, Jin Chen, Shu-Dong Wang, Sheng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390545888

                Nonprecious transition-metal oxides, especially Fe-, Cu-, Co-, and Mn-containing mixed oxides, have been regarded as promising alternatives for noble metal catalysts for the abatement of NOx contamination. However, the identification of the real catalytically active sites for these mixed oxides remains unclear in most cases, which limits our in-depth understanding of the intrinsic mechanism. Here, we comprehensively investigated an iron&#8211;cerium&#8211;aluminum oxide (Fe1/CeO2&#8211;Al2O3) prepared with a co-precipitation method. Structural identification confirmed that Fe sites are atomically dispersed, bonding with four O atoms in the first coordination shell and with two Ce atoms in the second shell on average. Highly efficient removal of NO with 100% selectivity toward N2 has been achieved over these sites at a temperature as low as 250 &#176;C. In situ characterizations and computational studies revealed that the high activity and N2 selectivity of Fe1/CeO2&#8211;Al2O3 can be attributed to the synergetic effect of the single-atomic Fe1 site and surrounding Ce&#8211;Ov, which intensively promotes the adsorption of NO molecules and N2O intermediates. Subsequently, Ce&#8211;Ov facilitates the N&#8211;O dissociation toward N2 and then is regenerated with CO, forming CO2 as a product. The present results provide valuable insights into the mechanism of transition-metal oxide catalysts for the NO&#8211;CO reaction and offer useful guidance for designing catalysts with high activity and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Y. Bai, Xupeng Zong, Jin Chen, Shu-Dong Wang, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Relevance of the Interfacial Water Reactivity for Electrochemical CO Reduction on Copper Single Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02700</link>
      <description>Daniel Winkler, Matthias Leitner, Andrea Auer, Julia Kunze&#8208;Liebh&#228;user, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390659412

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 is an important electrolysis reaction that enables the conversion of a waste gas to fuels or value-added chemicals. To make this reaction viable, a profound understanding of central intermediate steps, such as the CO electroreduction, is required. On Cu, the CO reduction reaction (CORR) is intimately linked to the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) that proceeds via the reduction of water in alkaline or neutral electrolytes. Here, we demonstrate that the interaction of water or more specifically the water reduction kinetics on differently smooth Cu(100) and Cu(111) surfaces during the CORR in alkaline media significantly governs the CORR. On Cu(111), faster HER kinetics and the highest CORR activity are observed, even though HER and CORR onsets are more negative. While on Cu(100) small Cu ad-island clusters form in the cathodic potential range only when CO is present, structural changes appear on a larger length scale on Cu(111) both under CORR conditions and when no CO is present. These differences in the reconstruction characteristics may be attributed to the dominance of either the CORR and its intermediates or the HER on the different Cu surfaces. Therefore, the interfacial water reactivity is considered an essential activity descriptor for the CORR on Cu in alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Daniel Winkler, Matthias Leitner, Andrea Auer, Julia Kunze&#8208;Liebh&#228;user</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Multimetallic Cooperativity in the Ring-Opening Polymerization of Cyclic Esters and Ethers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05103</link>
      <description>Utku Yolsal, Peter J. Shaw, Phoebe A. Lowy, Raju Chambenahalli, Jennifer A. Garden, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390673532

                The use of multimetallic complexes is a rapidly advancing route to enhance catalyst performance in the ring-opening polymerization of cyclic esters and ethers. Multimetallic catalysts often outperform their monometallic analogues in terms of reactivity and/or polymerization control, and these improvements are typically attributed to &#8220;multimetallic cooperativity&#8221;. Yet the origins of multimetallic cooperativity often remain unclear. This review explores the key factors underpinning multimetallic cooperativity, including metal&#8211;metal distances, the flexibility, electronics and conformation of the ligand framework, and the coordination environment of the metal centers. Emerging trends are discussed to provide insights into why cooperativity occurs and how to harness cooperativity for the development of highly efficient multimetallic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Utku Yolsal, Peter J. Shaw, Phoebe A. Lowy, Raju Chambenahalli, Jennifer A. Garden</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Characterization and Protein Engineering of a Glycosyltransferase GcCGT to Produce Flavone 6,8-Di-&lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;- and 6-&lt;i&gt;C&lt;/i&gt;-4&#8242;-&lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt;-Glycosides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05252</link>
      <description>Yang-Oujie Bao, Meng Zhang, Haoran Li, Zilong Wang, Jiajing Zhou, Yi Yang, Fudong Li, Lei Ye, Hongye Li, Hongwei Jin, Chao He, Min Ye, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390674506

                Herein, we discovered an efficient flavone 6-C-glycosyltransferase GcCGT from the medicinal plant Gentiana crassicaulis. GcCGT could catalyze consecutive two-step 6-C/4&#8242;-O-glycosylation of flavonoids. Homology modeling and site-directed mutagenesis yielded mutant F387K, which could catalyze the unprecedented 6-C-glycosylation of flavone 8-C-glycosides to produce 6,8-di-C-glycosides. To elucidate the catalytic mechanisms, the crystal structures of GcCGT-apo (2.10 &#197;) and GcCGT/UDP (2.40 &#197;) were resolved. Structural analysis and molecular dynamics simulations indicated that the lack of &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking interaction for F387 changed the protein conformation and expanded the entrance of the substrate binding pocket. This work provided an efficient method to synthesize flavone 6,8-di-C- and 6-C-4&#8242;-O-glycosides.</description>
      <author>Yang-Oujie Bao, Meng Zhang, Haoran Li, Zilong Wang, Jiajing Zhou, Yi Yang, Fudong Li, Lei Ye, Hongye Li, Hongwei Jin, Chao He, Min Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05252</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Mechanism for Oxidative Coupling of Methane Catalyzed by La&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;: Experimental and Microkinetic Modeling Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04714</link>
      <description>Zaili Xiong, Jijun Guo, Yuwen Deng, Bingzhi Liu, Hao Lou, Meirong Zeng, Zhandong Wang, Zhongyue Zhou, Wenhao Yuan, Fei Qi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390694581

                Oxidative coupling of methane (OCM) has been widely proposed to be one of the most promising methods for the direct conversion of methane to C2 products, such as ethane and ethene. Highly active free radicals play a crucial role, while accurate identifications are limited. To probe these free radicals and reveal their reactions, experiments focused on the OCM catalyzed by La2O3 were designed to be carried out in a packed bed reactor at low-pressure conditions over a wide temperature range. Dozens of species, including methyl radical, ethyl radical, and formaldehyde, were observed by using synchrotron vacuum ultraviolet photoionization mass spectrometry (SVUV-PIMS). A microkinetic model that coupled a detailed gas-phase and surface mechanism was developed and validated against the experimental results, especially to reveal the crucial roles of free radicals in the formation of C2 products as well as the oxygenated intermediates. The prediction results of the kinetic model agreed well with the experimental measurements. Rate of production and sensitivity analysis were performed to reveal the complex reaction network and key reactions of the OCM. Methyl was confirmed to play a key role based on both experimental and modeling perspectives, while ethyl is crucial in the transformation of C2 species and the formation of C3&#8211;C4 species. This indicates that the selective regulation of free radicals such as methyl and ethyl in OCM is worth paying attention to. The present work provides more detailed chemistry of OCM reactions, which would be helpful to improve product selectivity of OCM.</description>
      <author>Zaili Xiong, Jijun Guo, Yuwen Deng, Bingzhi Liu, Hao Lou, Meirong Zeng, Zhandong Wang, Zhongyue Zhou, Wenhao Yuan, Fei Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Monitoring of Heterogeneous Peroxygenase Reactions Unravels LPMO Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05194</link>
      <description>Lorenz Schwaiger, Florian Csarman, Hui S. Chang, Ole Golten, Vincent G. H. Eijsink, Roland Ludwig, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390697114

                Biological conversion of plant biomass depends on peroxygenases and peroxidases acting on insoluble polysaccharides and lignin. Among these are cellulose- and hemicellulose-degrading lytic polysaccharide monooxygenases (LPMOs), which have revolutionized our concept of biomass degradation. Major obstacles limiting mechanistic and functional understanding of these unique peroxygenases are their complex and insoluble substrates and the hard-to-measure H2O2 consumption, resulting in the lack of suitable kinetic assays. We report a versatile and robust electrochemical method for real-time monitoring and kinetic characterization of LPMOs and other H2O2-dependent interfacial enzymes based on a rotating disc electrode for the sensitive and selective quantitation of H2O2 at biologically relevant concentrations. The H2O2 sensor works in suspensions of insoluble substrates as well as in homogeneous solutions. Our characterization of multiple LPMOs provides unprecedented insights into the substrate specificity, kinetics, and stability of these enzymes. High turnover and total turnover numbers demonstrate that LPMOs are fast and durable biocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Lorenz Schwaiger, Florian Csarman, Hui S. Chang, Ole Golten, Vincent G. H. Eijsink, Roland Ludwig</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Alloy Catalysts for Alkyne Semihydrogenation via Descriptor-Based High-Throughput Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</link>
      <description>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701504

                Although alloying is a common approach to developing catalysts for alkyne selective hydrogenation, the geometric and electronic effects of active sites on the kinetics of alkyne selective hydrogenation are still ambiguous, hindering rational design of alloy catalysts. Herein, we construct structural descriptors to categorize and reorganize the roles of electronic and geometric factors in the kinetics of acetylene semihydrogenation. The prediction model based on our proposed structural descriptors successfully elucidates the activity and selectivity trends among Pd-based alloys and can also be extended to rationalize the kinetics trend among single-atom alloys and Ni-based alloys for semihydrogenation of acetylene and even other alkynes, in good agreement with available experimental references. Aided by thermodynamic stability analysis and structural descriptors, 489 Pd-based bimetallic alloys via a high-throughput screening protocol were evaluated, and finally, Pd1Nb3 and Pd1Hf3 were identified with a high yield of ethylene and inexpensive cost and validated by our experimental studies.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visible-Light Photocatalyzed C3&#8211;H Alkylation of 2&lt;i&gt;H&lt;/i&gt;-Indazoles/Indoles with Sulfoxonium Ylides via Diversified Mechanistic Pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04729</link>
      <description>Altman Yuzhu Peng, Yujing Wang, Kaifeng Wang, Qi Sun, Xiaoguang Bao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701516

                Herein, the C3&#8211;H alkylation of 2H-indazoles and indoles with sulfoxonium ylides is developed under visible-light photocatalysis. This protocol employs easily accessible reagents, and a wide range of 2H-indazoles, indoles, and sulfoxonium ylides are suitable for this reaction to afford the desired products under benign conditions. Synergistic experimental and computational studies suggest that the sulfoxonium ylides involving C3&#8211;H alkylation of 2H-indazoles and indoles under visible-light photocatalysis could proceed via different mechanistic pathways. For the C3-alkylation of 2H-indazoles, a triplet energy transfer mechanistic pathway of 2H-indazoles is proposed for quenching the excited photocatalyst. Subsequently, the formed excited triplet state of 2H-indazoles could undergo radical attack on the C&#9552;S moiety of sulfoxonium ylides. After the dissociation of DMSO and 1,2-H migration, the final product of C3-alkylation of 2H-indazoles could be yielded. However, such a mechanistic pathway is not applicable for indoles. Instead, sulfoxonium ylides could be converted to a C-centered radical in the presence of KH2PO4 under visible-light photoredox conditions. The formed C-centered radical can attack the C3-site of indoles and thus lead to the C3-alkylation product of indoles.</description>
      <author>Altman Yuzhu Peng, Yujing Wang, Kaifeng Wang, Qi Sun, Xiaoguang Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Unconventional Reduction of C&#9552;N Bonds by Old Yellow Enzymes Using QM/MM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04362</link>
      <description>Amit Singh, Nakia Polidori, Wolfgang Kroutil, Karl Gruber, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390704303

                The reduction of C&#9552;X (X = N, O) bonds is a cornerstone in both synthetic organic chemistry and biocatalysis. Conventional reduction mechanisms usually involve a hydride ion targeting the less electronegative carbon atom. In a departure from this paradigm, our investigation into Old Yellow Enzymes (OYEs) reveals a mechanism involving transfer of hydride to the formally more electronegative nitrogen atom within a C&#9552;N bond. Beyond their known ability to reduce electronically activated C&#9552;C double bonds, e.g., in &#945;, &#946;-unsaturated ketones, these enzymes have recently been shown to reduce &#945;-oximo-&#946;-ketoesters to the corresponding amines. It has been proposed that this transformation involves two successive reduction steps and proceeds via imine intermediates formed by the reductive dehydration of the oxime moieties. We employ advanced quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) simulations, enriched by a two-tiered approach incorporating QM/MM (UB3LYP-6-31G*/OPLS2005) geometry optimization, QM/MM (B3LYP-6-31G*/amberff19sb) steered molecular dynamics simulations, and detailed natural-bond-orbital analyses to decipher the unconventional hydride transfer to nitrogen in both reduction steps and to delineate the role of active site residues as well as of substituents present in the substrates. Our computational results confirm the proposed mechanism and agree well with experimental mutagenesis and enzyme kinetics data. According to our model, the catalysis of OYE involves hydride transfer from the flavin cofactor to the nitrogen atom in oximoketoesters as well as iminoketoesters followed by protonation at the adjacent oxygen or carbon atoms by conserved tyrosine residues and active site water molecules. Two histidine residues play a key role in the polarization and activation of the C&#9552;N bond, and conformational changes of the substrate observed along the reaction coordinate underline the crucial importance of dynamic electron delocalization for efficient catalysis.</description>
      <author>Amit Singh, Nakia Polidori, Wolfgang Kroutil, Karl Gruber</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active MnCoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst toward CO Preferential Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04654</link>
      <description>Jun Yu, Yusen Yang, Meng Zhang, Boyu Song, Yu Han, Si Wang, Zhihao Ren, Lei Wang, Ping Yin, Lirong Zheng, Xin Zhang, Min Wei, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390704389

                Preferential oxidation of CO (CO-PROX) is an efficient method to eliminate residual CO in the feed stream to avoid Pt poisoning in proton-exchange-membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs), in which the development of high-performance, low-cost catalysts remains a big challenge. Herein, we report highly active spinel-like MnCoOx catalysts derived from layered double hydroxide (LDH) precursors, which are featured with abundant octahedron-distorted lattice oxygen. Impressively, the optimal catalyst MnCoOx-300 achieves the selective and complete removal of CO from a H2-rich stream at 80 &#176;C, within a wide operation temperature window (80&#8211;200 &#176;C, matching well with PEMFCs) at a rather high space velocity (80,000 h&#8211;1). This performance, to the best of our knowledge, outperforms previously reported non-noble metal catalysts and even exceeds the state-of-the-art CuO/CeO2 system in the CO-PROX technology. A comprehensive investigation based on in situ Raman, in situ XAFS, in situ TPD-Mass, and in situ DRIFTS reveals that the Cooct3+&#8211;O2&#8211;&#8211;Mnoct4+ structure in MnCoOx-300 serves as the intrinsic active site that facilitates preferential oxidation: the lattice oxygen participates in the oxidation of CO to produce CO2 and oxygen vacancy (Ov), followed by the replenishment of oxygen species from aerial oxygen (the rate-determining step) to regenerate Cooct3+&#8211;O2&#8211;&#8211;Mnoct4+. Isotopic 18O kinetic studies and in situ DRIFTS substantiate that the reaction temperature plays a crucial role in the competitive oxidation of CO vs H2 at the same active site. This work provides a successful paradigm for the design and preparation of transition metal oxide catalysts toward the CO-PROX reaction, which shows potential applications in hydrogen purification for PEMFCs.</description>
      <author>Jun Yu, Yusen Yang, Meng Zhang, Boyu Song, Yu Han, Si Wang, Zhihao Ren, Lei Wang, Ping Yin, Lirong Zheng, Xin Zhang, Min Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Carbene Initiated O&#8211;H Insertion/Aldol Cascade for the Stereoselective Synthesis of Functionalized Tetrahydrofurans</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05040</link>
      <description>Prakash Kafle, B. N. Ghosh, Arianne C. Hunter, Rishav Mukherjee, Kenneth M. Nicholas, Indrajeet Sharma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390718518

                Given its earth abundance, cost-effectiveness, and ecofriendly qualities, iron serves as a promising alternative to precious metals in catalysis. This article presents an iron carbene-initiated cascade approach for synthesizing highly substituted tetrahydrofurans at the gram scale. This cascade reaction utilizes readily accessible &#946;-hydroxyketones and diazo compounds and works with iron catalyst loading as low as 5 mol %. This reaction proceeds through an O&#8211;H insertion into diazo-derived iron carbenes, followed by an intramolecular aldol reaction to access functionalized tetrahydrofurans in high yields and diastereoselectivity. The versatile nature of this domino sequence accommodates diverse &#946;-hydroxyketones and diazo compounds, streamlining access to synthetically challenging spiroethers. Furthermore, this cascade process offers a route to enantiopure tetrahydrofurans by utilizing a diazo ester bearing a chiral auxiliary, 8-phenylmenthol. Postmodifications of the tetrahydrofuran product provide access to various analogues, including a medicinally relevant oxetane motif. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations substantiate a stereospecific mechanism wherein the intramolecular aldol reaction proceeds via a fused six- and five-membered iron&#8211;oxygen transition-state complex, yielding the contrathermodynamic cis-aldol product.</description>
      <author>Prakash Kafle, B. N. Ghosh, Arianne C. Hunter, Rishav Mukherjee, Kenneth M. Nicholas, Indrajeet Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of &#8220;NO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#183;&#183;&#183;NH&#8221; Hydrogen Bond-Stabilized C&#8211;N Axially Chiral Diarylamines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04775</link>
      <description>Wei Lin, Yuanhu Shao, Zeyang Hao, Zhe Huang, Zhiyuan Ren, Li Chen, Xin Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390724252

                Herein, N-nucleophilic tandem oxidation&#8211;N-arylation&#8211;oxidation reaction and C-nucleophilic bromination reaction of substituted anilines have been developed using chiral phosphoric acid catalysis, enabling access to axially chiral diarylamines. The key feature of this strategy is that the &#8220;NO2&#183;&#183;&#183;H&#8211;N&#8221; hydrogen bond was successfully introduced into acyclic diaryl secondary amines, which contain two potential contiguous atropisomeric C&#8211;N axes, to stabilize one of the planar axial conformations. This methodology provided a series of optically pure diarylamine atropisomers containing this new hydrogen bond type in good yields (up to 99%) and high enantiomeric ratios (up to 99.5:0.5 e.r.). The synthetic utility was demonstrated through large-scale reactions and transformations of the products. Plausible models were proposed to explain the enantioselectivity of the products.</description>
      <author>Wei Lin, Yuanhu Shao, Zeyang Hao, Zhe Huang, Zhiyuan Ren, Li Chen, Xin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape Selectivity of AEL Channels for Anomalously Facilitating Biojet Fuel Production from Long-Chain &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;-Alkane Hydrocracking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04465</link>
      <description>Chao Mu, Junhao Sun, Chuang Xie, Jianming Bao, Xuan Guo, Haozhe Zhang, Yujun Zhao, Shengping Wang, Xinbin Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390732536

                Hydrocracking of long-chain n-alkanes from hydrotreating of vegetable oil is critical for biojet fuel production and requires selective C&#8211;C cleavage near the long-chain alkane end. Due to preferential cracking near the carbon chain end in AEL channels, SAPO-11 optionally produces heavy jet fuel fractions in hydrocracking of the model reactant n-C16. Also, the weak acidity of SAPO-11 promotes olefin desorption and markedly reduces the second cracking of jet fuel fractions formed. Compared to 10-MR Si&#8211;Al ZSM-22, ZSM-23, ZSM-5, and ZSM-35 zeolites, SAPO-11 significantly improves the jet fuel production performance. Surprisingly,10-membered rings (10-MR) SAPO-11 exhibits higher jet fuel yields than 12-membered rings (12-MR) HUSY (FAU topology), contrary to the general belief that larger pores are more conducive to heavy cracking product production. Further, theoretical molar cracking product distributions of C15&#8211;C18 fractions are proposed, highlighting the superior performance of SAPO-11 over that of HUSY and delineating the yield limits for jet fuel production. Higher than those of commercial biojet fuels, the isomer content of jet fuel fractions exceeds 89% at cracking yield above 70%. It indicates that weakly acidic SAPO-11 has potential for specific cracking reactions near the long-chain alkane end, which enriches the understanding of selective C&#8211;C cleavage by zeolites for high-value cracking products.</description>
      <author>Chao Mu, Junhao Sun, Chuang Xie, Jianming Bao, Xuan Guo, Haozhe Zhang, Yujun Zhao, Shengping Wang, Xinbin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the Structure of Mn-NiS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; during Urea Oxidation Using Combined In Situ X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy and Attenuated Total Reflectance Surface-Enhanced Infrared Absorption Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05369</link>
      <description>Niangao Duan, Tianxin Hou, Wei Zheng, Yafei Qu, Peichen Wang, Jun Yang, Yang Yang, Dongdong Wang, Jitang Chen, Qianwang Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390734560

                The urea electrocatalytic oxidation reaction (UOR) has enormous potential as an ideal alternative anode reaction for water splitting owing to its lower thermodynamic equilibrium potential of 0.37 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (vs RHE). Nickel-based materials, especially NiOOH, are considered to be one of the most promising non-noble metal catalysts for UOR due to their inexpensive cost and rich abundance. However, NiOOH displays a high overpotential and poor long-term stability. Herein, our density functional theory calculations show that the rate-determining step for UOR is desorption of CO2 on NiOOH, and Mn-doped NiOOH has the lowest energy for CO2 desorption. Hence, we prepared a Mn-NiS2 precatalyst that would transform into the active form of Mn-NiOOH during the electrochemical process. The catalyst exhibits good performance for UOR, achieving 100 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.426 V (vs RHE, without IR correction) for 200 h with no significant voltage change, which is rarely reported for nonprecious-metal UOR catalysts. X-ray absorption near-edge spectroscopy and X-ray diffraction characterization show the transformation from sulfide to oxyhydroxide when a voltage is applied, while in situ attenuated total reflectance surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy (ATR-SEIRAS) proves that Mn-NiOOH accelerates the desorption of CO2 compared to NiOOH.</description>
      <author>Niangao Duan, Tianxin Hou, Wei Zheng, Yafei Qu, Peichen Wang, Jun Yang, Yang Yang, Dongdong Wang, Jitang Chen, Qianwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of Electronic Metal-Support Interaction between Cu and ZnO by Er for Effective Low-Temperature CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04608</link>
      <description>Chaojie Huang, Shunan Zhang, Ke Wang, Haozhi Zhou, Zilong Shao, Lin Xia, Hui Wang, Yuhan Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390752746

                Methanol produced by CO2 hydrogenation is an essential carrier for a sustainable carbon cycle. However, achieving an efficient methanol synthesis on traditional CuZnO catalysts at low temperatures remains challenging due to the inertness of CO2. Herein, we designed Er&#8211;CuZnO catalysts that exhibited remarkable activity for low-temperature methanol synthesis. At 170 &#176;C, the catalyst achieved a methanol selectivity of 89.8% at a CO2 conversion of 8.5% on Er0.2CuZnO, which outperformed most CuZnO-based catalysts. The particle size of ZnO was reduced after Er was added to the lattice, which increased the Cu&#8211;ZnO interfaces and created a strong electronic metal-support interaction (EMSI) between Cu and ZnO. The electron was transferred from ZnO to Cu, forming Cu&#948;&#8722;. Cu&#948;&#8722; with more negative charges enhanced CO2 adsorbed species and intermediates activation, while facilitating surface carbonate activation and the hydrogenation of *CO intermediates into *HCO species, promoting the methanol formation at low temperatures.</description>
      <author>Chaojie Huang, Shunan Zhang, Ke Wang, Haozhi Zhou, Zilong Shao, Lin Xia, Hui Wang, Yuhan Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Stability Mechanism of Cu Active Sites in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction via Suppression of Antibonding Orbital Occupancy in the O 2p-Cu 3d Hybridization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04710</link>
      <description>Youxian Sun, Xiaojun Wang, Huiying Zhang, Xueying Gao, Xiaoxuan Wang, Shiyu Wang, Zheng Tang, Shuyuan Li, Kaiqi Nie, Jiangzhou Xie, Zhiyu Yang, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390753980

                Copper-based catalysts, hallmarked by their ideal C&#8211;C coupling energy facilitated by the symbiotic presence of Cu+ and Cu0 active sites, are poised to revolutionize the selective electrochemical reduction of CO2 to C2H4. Regrettably, these catalysts are beleaguered by the unavoidable diminution of Cu+ to Cu0 during the reaction process, resulting in suboptimal C2H4 yields. To circumvent this limitation, we have judiciously mitigated the antibonding orbital occupancy in the O 2p and Cu+ 3d hybridization by introducing Cu defects into Cu2O, thereby augmenting the Cu&#8211;O bond strength to stabilize Cu+ sites and further decipher the stabilization mechanism of Cu+. This structural refinement, illuminated by meticulous DFT calculations, fosters a heightened free energy threshold for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), while orchestrating a thermodynamically favorable milieu for enhanced C&#8211;C coupling within the Cu-deficient Cu2O (Cuv-Cu2O). Empirically, Cuv-Cu2O has outperformed its pure Cu2O counterpart, exhibiting a prominent C2H4/CO ratio of 1.69 as opposed to 1.01, without conceding significant ground in C2H4 production over an 8 h span at &#8722;1.3 V vs RHE. This endeavor not only delineates the critical influence of antibonding orbital occupancy on bond strength and reveals the deep mechanism about Cu+ sites but also charts a pioneering pathway in the realm of advanced materials design.</description>
      <author>Youxian Sun, Xiaojun Wang, Huiying Zhang, Xueying Gao, Xiaoxuan Wang, Shiyu Wang, Zheng Tang, Shuyuan Li, Kaiqi Nie, Jiangzhou Xie, Zhiyu Yang, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04710</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymer Tacticity Control for Stereoselective Ring-Opening Polymerization of Racemic &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;-Propylglycolide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04798</link>
      <description>Guojie Li, Guiying Xu, Guo Xuan-hua, Rong Yang, Hongwei Sun, Qinggang Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390778848

                The synthesis of stereoregular aliphatic polyesters with superior (bio)degradability and recyclability has been one of the promising areas in material science, which can be achieved through the stereoselective polymerization of cyclic esters. However, it remains a long-standing challenge to achieve tacticity (isotactic and heterotactic) control of aliphatic polyesters in one catalytic system through modulation of the polymerization mechanism. Here we reported a tunable and controllable method for stereoselective polymerization of racemic n-propylglycolide (nPrgl) based on the analysis of the enantiomorphic site control (ESC) and chain-end control (CEC) mechanisms in the polymerization. The enantiomorphic site control and chain-end control-dominated stereoregular polymerization processes were achieved via adjustable polymerization conditions, producing isotactic poly(nPrgl) with a Pm of up to 0.88 (based on ESC) and heterotactic poly(nPrgl) with a Pr of up to 0.94 (based on CEC). This understanding of ESC and CEC mechanisms might provide a compelling guidance to the design of stereoselective polymerization.</description>
      <author>Guojie Li, Guiying Xu, Guo Xuan-hua, Rong Yang, Hongwei Sun, Qinggang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Low Z-Elements in a Ni/MgFeAlO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst during Reaction: Insight from In Situ XRS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05563</link>
      <description>Souvik Das, Lennert D&#8217;ooghe, Nadadur Veeraraghavan Srinath, Stavros Alexandros Theofanidis, Alessandro Longo, Christoph J. Sahle, Kevin Van Geem, Hilde Poelman, Dirk Poelman, Vladimir Galvita, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390806369

                Ni/MgFeAlO4 displays promising activity and stability in the dry reforming of methane. In order to establish a correlation between its performance and structural changes, an in-depth analysis of the Ni/MgFeAlO4 catalyst&#8217;s constituent elements is conducted using in situ techniques, specifically combined X-ray emission spectroscopy (XES) and X-ray Raman scattering (XRS) spectroscopy. This investigation spans sequential treatments involving H2 reduction, CO2 reoxidation, and methane dry reforming. XES valence-to-core signals for Fe and Ni retrace the applied treatments. After the reaction, Ni is fully metallic, while Fe shows a mixed metal-oxide state. Comparing these XES spectroscopic data with ab initio simulations indicates that dry reforming of methane does not form metal carbide. C K-edge XRS data recorded after the reaction do not protrude above the noise, proving the capability of the Ni/MgFeAlO4 catalyst to mitigate carbon deposition. O K-edge spectra exhibit variations corresponding to each treatment, effectively replicated through simulations with semiempirical screening parameters. These parameters represent electron transfer between oxygen and neighboring 3d transition metal elements and offer insights into the acid&#8211;base properties of the material. Furthermore, the Al L2,3-edge spectra provide valuable information about the impact of treatments on the spinel arrangement, indicating an increasing tetrahedral occupancy of Al3+ in the support. By employing a comprehensive approach that combines XRS with XES, this study provides a holistic understanding of the evolution of low Z-elements, O and Al, alongside Fe and Ni, in the Ni/MgFeAlO4 catalyst throughout the reduction, reoxidation, and methane dry reforming processes.</description>
      <author>Souvik Das, Lennert D&#8217;ooghe, Nadadur Veeraraghavan Srinath, Stavros Alexandros Theofanidis, Alessandro Longo, Christoph J. Sahle, Kevin Van Geem, Hilde Poelman, Dirk Poelman, Vladimir Galvita</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorinated Defect-Engineered Acetylenic Polymers with Separated Active Centers for Switching the Photosensitized Activation Pathway of Peroxymonosulfate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03830</link>
      <description>Tao Zeng, Xiaojun Tang, Xiaoyan Cai, Sijia Jin, Zhu Yang, Wenhua Xu, Lingxiangyu Li, Haiyan Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390807239

                The engineering of conjugated acetylenic polymers (CAPs) has great potential for photosensitized oxyanion activation, wherein their catalytic performance can be further advanced by incorporating artificial defects, while relevant reports are rare. Herein, we deliberately introduce the fluorinated defect into the structure of poly(1,3,5-triethynylbenzene) (PTEB) via copper-surface mediated Glaser polycondensation (denote as PTEB-Fx). PTEB-Fx exhibits a surface with an abundance of acetylene moieties that possess a strong affinity for capturing oxyanions through preferential binding to peroxy-bonds of oxyanions. Meanwhile, the adjacent fluorinated defects effectively delocalize &#960;-electrons, narrow the optical bandgap, and facilitate charge separation, thereby optimizing kinetics and thermodynamics of peroxymonosulfate (PMS) activation. Such spatial separated active centers leads to a synergistic effect involving the enhanced oxidation ability of holes (h+) and the elongation of the O&#8211;H bond in PMS, which triggers a switch in the activation pathway toward oxidative activation for the generation of singlet oxygen (1O2), as opposed to the conventional reductive activation course yielding radical species (&#8226;OH and SO4&#8226;&#8211;). Additionally, PTEB-Fx featuring inherent self-standing merit overcomes challenges associated with limited light energy utilization and the cumbersome retrieval of powder photosensitizers, thus broadening its potential for large-scale application.</description>
      <author>Tao Zeng, Xiaojun Tang, Xiaoyan Cai, Sijia Jin, Zhu Yang, Wenhua Xu, Lingxiangyu Li, Haiyan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Highly Active Pd&#8211;Ti&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; Sites in Defective Pd/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for Efficient Hydrogenation of Styrene&#8211;Butadiene&#8211;Styrene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04811</link>
      <description>Shidong Wang, Bingqing Ge, Zhiliang Yang, Hongwei Zhang, Qin Yang, Cejun Hu, Xiaojun Bao, Pei Yuan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390818780

                Defect-rich Pd/TiO2 catalysts are intensively adopted in heterogeneous hydrogenation reactions; however, the complexity of the defect structure makes it difficult to precisely identify which Pd-defect combination dominates the catalytic activity. Herein, defective TiO2 nanoflakes with tunable ratios of Vo to Ti3+ defects were synthesized and used to construct Pd&#8211;Vo and Pd&#8211;Ti3+ active sites after loading Pd to investigate the role of defects in regulating the structural and catalytic properties of defective Pd/TiO2 catalysts. Combining the experimental results and theoretical calculations, we reveal that both Vo and Ti3+ defects act as the electron donors for Pd and induce the strong metal&#8211;support interaction. When compared to the Vo defect, the Ti3+ defect behaves more significantly and donates more electrons, causing the Pd species on the catalysts to be better dispersed and more rich in electrons. These unique features endow the Pd&#8211;Ti3+ active centers with enhanced adsorption&#8211;activation ability toward C&#9552;C and H2 as well as reduced energy barrier of the rate-limiting step, thus improving the intrinsic activity. The Pd&#8211;Ti3+ site manifests a high turnover frequency of 348 h&#8211;1 and hydrogenation degree of 97% for hydrogenation of C&#9552;C in styrene&#8211;butadiene&#8211;styrene, which significantly outperforms the Pd&#8211;Vo site (254 h&#8211;1 and 78%) and Pd nanoparticle (217 h&#8211;1 and 53%). This work provides deep insight into the role of defects in regulating the properties of metal active sites, which can be used to guide the development of high-performance Pd/TiO2 catalysts for versatile applications.</description>
      <author>Shidong Wang, Bingqing Ge, Zhiliang Yang, Hongwei Zhang, Qin Yang, Cejun Hu, Xiaojun Bao, Pei Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effects of Co&#8211;Fe Boosts the Transformation of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; into C&lt;sub&gt;6+&lt;/sub&gt; Dicarboxylic Acids up to Gram-Scale under Mild Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05395</link>
      <description>Ying Zhang, Junjun Mao, Bo Zhang, Dan Wang, Chenchen Zhang, Yang Lou, Chengsi Pan, Yongfa Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390841453

                Electrochemical carboxylation of 1,3-dienes with carbon dioxide (CO2) is a feasible method to obtain dicarboxylic derivatives, which are important synthetic intermediates of polymers and pharmaceuticals. However, due to unavoidable byproducts and unfriendly conditions, the formation of pure dicarboxylic acids has been limited. In this work, we report that a bimetallic phosphating CoFeP catalyst on nickel foam (CoFeP/NF) served as a remarkable electrode, which transforms CO2 into multicarbon (C6+) dicarboxylic acids. The synergistic effects of CoFeP catalyst between Co and Fe allow activation of 1,3-dienes mainly, in which electron transfer easier to the 1,3-dienes proceeded to afford radical anion of the diene, pursuant carboxylation with CO2 and further electron transfer formed the ultimate carboxylated products. The reaction can occur in a commercial flow cell with gram-scale amplification. The dicarboxylic acid obtained was up to 1.08 g at a 5 mmol scale of 1,3-dienes, illustrating high electrocatalytic activity and practical application of CoFeP/NF.</description>
      <author>Ying Zhang, Junjun Mao, Bo Zhang, Dan Wang, Chenchen Zhang, Yang Lou, Chengsi Pan, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05395</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palladium-Catalyzed Aminations in Flow ... &lt;i&gt;on Water&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05257</link>
      <description>Madison J Wong, Erfan Oftadeh, John Saunders, Alex B. Wood, Bruce H. Lipshutz, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390907051

                Aminations can be efficiently run, under plug flow conditions on water, catalyzed by low levels of a recyclable palladium precatalyst. General protocols to couple amines, both aryl and aliphatic, with aryl/heteroaryl bromides have been developed. Further highlights include &#8220;on water&#8221; conditions, short reaction times, recycling of the reaction medium, low levels of residual Pd in the isolated products, and low E factors as a green metric, all of these features showcasing this alternative to amination reactions typically run in batch mode.</description>
      <author>Madison J Wong, Erfan Oftadeh, John Saunders, Alex B. Wood, Bruce H. Lipshutz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligands Defect-Induced Structural Self-Reconstruction of Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;Co-Hydroxyl Oxides with Crystalline/Amorphous Heterophase from a 2D Metal&#8211;Organic Framework for an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05314</link>
      <description>Hongqi Chu, Rujin Li, Panpan Feng, Dongyan Wang, Chunxiang Li, Yanling Yu, Min Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390907090

                The two-dimensional (2D) Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;Co-MOF is synthesized using a simple double ligand strategy at room temperature. The surface reconstruction process transforms it into a crystalline&#8211;amorphous heterojunction composed of polycrystalline metal (oxy)hydroxide (MOOH) and amorphous metal oxides/hydroxides with terephthalic acid (TPA) by coordination covalent bonding. In situ Raman spectroscopy discloses the dynamic structure conversion. Density functional theory (DFT), Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), and solid-state nuclear magnetic resonance (SSNMR) reveal the induction of the ligand defects on surface reconstruction and the enhancing effect of TPA on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance through a covalent interaction. The amorphous&#8211;crystalline heterojunction of Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;CoOOH-TPA has numerous structural defects and high electrical conductivity, resulting in an efficient and stable OER performance with overpotentials of 236 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2. It has also been observed that the catalyst processes self-healing in an idle state, arising from the reversible conversion of MOOH to M(OH)2. This work reveals the structural and compositional transformation of the 2D Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;Co-MOF during surface reconstruction, elucidating the relationship between electrocatalytic reconstruction and water-splitting performance of metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF)-based catalysts. It has been proven that appropriate covalent interactions enhance the OER of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongqi Chu, Rujin Li, Panpan Feng, Dongyan Wang, Chunxiang Li, Yanling Yu, Min Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Catalyzed Regioselective Reductive Fluoroalkylalkenylation of Unactivated Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05690</link>
      <description>Siyu Wang, Baochuan Guo, Tong Mu, Zhengli Liu, Yun He, Xiao&#8208;Song Xue, Zhihai Feng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390929188

                The example of iron-catalyzed reductive fluoroalkylalkenylation of unactivated alkenes has been disclosed, affording the stereodefined homoallylic fluoroalkanes with high efficiency and regioselectivity. This three-component cross-electrophile coupling features directing groups free, good functional group tolerance, broad substrate scope, and late-stage difunctionalization of biorelevant molecules. Moreover, this protocol sheds light on the distinct reactivity disparities between fluoroalkyl and nonfluoroalkyl radicals in three-component reductive cross-coupling reactions, highlighting the unique nature of iron/B2pin2 systems.</description>
      <author>Siyu Wang, Baochuan Guo, Tong Mu, Zhengli Liu, Yun He, Xiao&#8208;Song Xue, Zhihai Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Insights into a Side Chain Cross-Linking Biarylitide P450 from RiPP Biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05417</link>
      <description>Mathias Henning Hansen, Angus B. Keto, Maxine Treisman, Vishnu Mini Sasi, Laura Coe, Yongwei Zhao, Leo Padva, Caroline He&#223;, Victor Leichthammer, Daniel L. Machell, Ralf B. Schittenhelm, Colin J. Jackson, Julien Tailhades, Max Cr&#252;semann, James J. De Voss, Elizabeth H. Krenske, Max J. Cryle, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390537464

                Peptide side chain cross-linking is an important feature of many natural products, with an increasing number of examples catalyzed by cytochrome P450s being reported from ribosomal biosynthesis pathways in addition to well-known examples from nonribosomal peptide antibiotics. Despite the dramatic recent increase in the number of enzymes and reactions catalyzed, substrate bound structures of such P450s have proven elusive to date. Here, we report the structural characterization of the biarylitide cross-linking enzyme P450Blt in complex with its pentapeptide substrate MRYLH. This structure, in combination with computational and biochemical experiments, shows the importance of key I-helix residues in this P450 in coordinating to the histidine residue of the substrate and further that this appears to be central to the specificity of this enzyme for generating a C&#8211;N link between the tyrosine and histidine residues in the MRYLH substrate. The structure of the P450Blt-MRYLH complex provides the first insight into how peptide substrates can be accommodated within P450s and offers insights into how other examples of related P450s can accept the varied substrates that have recently been identified using bioinformatic methods.</description>
      <author>Mathias Henning Hansen, Angus B. Keto, Maxine Treisman, Vishnu Mini Sasi, Laura Coe, Yongwei Zhao, Leo Padva, Caroline He&#223;, Victor Leichthammer, Daniel L. Machell, Ralf B. Schittenhelm, Colin J. Jackson, Julien Tailhades, Max Cr&#252;semann, James J. De Voss, Elizabeth H. Krenske, Max J. Cryle</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05417</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
