<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:43:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Potential and Active-Site Environment on Single-Iron-Atom-Catalyzed Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction from Accurate Quantum Many-Body Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05999</link>
      <description>Jincheng Lei, Tianyu Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392185788

                Single iron atoms supported on nitrogen-doped graphene (Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C) have shown promise in catalyzing electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO with low overpotential and high selectivity. However, the nature of its rate-limiting step and the effect of active-site environment on catalytic activity are still under debate. Previous theoretical studies exclusively rely on density functional theory (DFT), but their predictions are limited by inherent errors in DFT functionals, leading to diverging conclusions on catalytic mechanisms. Herein, we employ an efficient quantum embedding strategy to enable high-level coupled-cluster (CCSD(T)) simulations of the thermodynamics of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C-catalyzed CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) and its competing hydrogen evolution reaction. Our calculations accurately predict experimental CO binding energy, onset potential, and potential of maximal Faradaic efficiency (FE) with FeN4 as the catalytic active site. We find that the thermodynamic-limiting step is the formation of a *COOH intermediate at low overpotential, which becomes CO2 adsorption and CO desorption at higher overpotential. Our simulation reveals that the potential-dependent high selectivity of FeN4 originates from the higher charge capacity of *COOH compared to *H. Furthermore, our calculations elucidate distinct roles of active-site environments, including vacancy defect and nitrogen doping. Particularly, graphitic nitrogen doping simultaneously lowers the CO2RR onset potential and allows a wider potential range for high CO FE. This work highlights the importance of robust many-body quantum chemical simulations in achieving quantitative understanding of multistep electrocatalytic reaction mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Jincheng Lei, Tianyu Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i005_1776148</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392354997

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i005_1776148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i005_1776149</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392385097

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i005_1776149</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
