<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 01:13:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese as Electron Reservoir Stabilized RuMnO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;@RuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; with Enhanced Activity and Robust Durability for Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01707</link>
      <description>Qin Yue, Xiaopo Niu, Rong Zhao, Jiuyi Sun, Zhi-Hui Xu, Zhenguo Chi, Danni Liu, Lili Guo, Chang Liu, Junfeng Zhang, Qingfa Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401565261

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qin Yue, Xiaopo Niu, Rong Zhao, Jiuyi Sun, Zhi-Hui Xu, Zhenguo Chi, Danni Liu, Lili Guo, Chang Liu, Junfeng Zhang, Qingfa Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insight into the Superior Catalytic Activity of Au/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Interface in Glucose Sensors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03419</link>
      <description>Yun Xie, Guang&#8208;Jie Xia, Weiping Gong, Fanglong Zhu, Zhenting Zhao, Yang&#8722;Gang Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401567137

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yun Xie, Guang&#8208;Jie Xia, Weiping Gong, Fanglong Zhu, Zhenting Zhao, Yang&#8722;Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Screening Descriptors of Metal&#8211;Organic Framework-Supported Single-Atom Catalysts for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reactions: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03937</link>
      <description>Li-Hui Mou, Jiahui Du, Yanbo Li, Jun Jiang, Linjiang Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401575850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li-Hui Mou, Jiahui Du, Yanbo Li, Jun Jiang, Linjiang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Catalysts for the Hydrolysis of Glycosidic Bonds in Oligosaccharides Using a Spectrophotometric Screening Assay</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03261</link>
      <description>Susanne Striegler, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401590676

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Susanne Striegler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of the Tetraalkylammonium Cation in the Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction on Copper Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02297</link>
      <description>Connor Deacon-Price, Louis Changeur, C&#225;ssia Sidney Santana, Amanda C. Garcia, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401591465

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Connor Deacon-Price, Louis Changeur, C&#225;ssia Sidney Santana, Amanda C. Garcia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Selective Dual-Atom Pd Heterogeneous Catalyst Prepared by Size-Selected Cluster Beam</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02500</link>
      <description>Wenka Zhu, Wen Wu Xu, Xingen Lin, S.F. Hu, Sichen Tang, Syed Adil Shah, Zixiang Zhao, Yongxin Zhang, Siqi Lu, X. F. Lu, J. G. Wan, Wen Wu Xu, Huang Zhou, Kuo&#8208;Juei Hu, Zhongkang Han, Yuen Wu, Fengqi Song, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401606577

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenka Zhu, Wen Wu Xu, Xingen Lin, S.F. Hu, Sichen Tang, Syed Adil Shah, Zixiang Zhao, Yongxin Zhang, Siqi Lu, X. F. Lu, J. G. Wan, Wen Wu Xu, Huang Zhou, Kuo&#8208;Juei Hu, Zhongkang Han, Yuen Wu, Fengqi Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhodium-Catalyzed Asymmetric Hydroselenation of 1-Alkynylindoles for Atroposelective Synthesis of Vinyl Selenoethers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03710</link>
      <description>Yu-Long Kang, Fen Wang, Xingwei Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401608966

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Long Kang, Fen Wang, Xingwei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03710</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stereoselective Fe-Catalyzed Decoupled Cross-Couplings: Chiral Vinyl Oxazolidinones as Effective Radical Lynchpins for Diastereoselective C(sp&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;) Bond Formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04568</link>
      <description>Tapas Maity, &#193;ngel Renter&#237;a&#8208;G&#243;mez, Osvaldo Guti&#233;rrez, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401611031

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tapas Maity, &#193;ngel Renter&#237;a&#8208;G&#243;mez, Osvaldo Guti&#233;rrez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grignard Reagent Addition to Pyridinium Salts: A Catalytic Approach to Chiral 1,4-Dihydropyridines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03520</link>
      <description>Siriphong Somprasong, Marta Casti&#241;eira Reis, Syuzanna R. Harutyunyan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401613110

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siriphong Somprasong, Marta Casti&#241;eira Reis, Syuzanna R. Harutyunyan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03520</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid&#8211;Base Bifunctional Catalysis of the Lewis Acidic Isolated Co(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Basic N Anion Generated from CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and 2-Cyanopyridine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02378</link>
      <description>Masazumi Tamura, Masanobu Haga, Anchalee Junkaew, Daiki Asada, Riko Ichikawa, Ryo Toyoshima, Akira Nakayama, Hiroshi Kondoh, Yoshinao Nakagawa, Keiichi Tomishige, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401613654

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Masazumi Tamura, Masanobu Haga, Anchalee Junkaew, Daiki Asada, Riko Ichikawa, Ryo Toyoshima, Akira Nakayama, Hiroshi Kondoh, Yoshinao Nakagawa, Keiichi Tomishige</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confinement Effect and Application in Catalytic Oxidation&#8211;Reduction Reaction of Confined Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02113</link>
      <description>X.&#8208;B. Fan, Donghao Li, Yuanxiang Shu, Yimeng Feng, Fengxiang Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401614499

                No abstract</description>
      <author>X.&#8208;B. Fan, Donghao Li, Yuanxiang Shu, Yimeng Feng, Fengxiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchtop-Stable Carbyl Iminopyridyl Ni&lt;sup&gt;II&lt;/sup&gt; Complexes for Olefin Polymerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02708</link>
      <description>Hasaan Rauf, Yu&#8208;Sheng Liu, Muhammad Arslan, Surya Pratap S. Solanki, &#201;ric Deydier, Rinaldo Poli, Lars C. Grabow, Eva Harth, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401629582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hasaan Rauf, Yu&#8208;Sheng Liu, Muhammad Arslan, Surya Pratap S. Solanki, &#201;ric Deydier, Rinaldo Poli, Lars C. Grabow, Eva Harth</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02708</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P-Block Elements Activate Pt Surfaces for the Electrooxidation of Alcohols and Polyols When Promoting the &#8722;OH formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02443</link>
      <description>Matheus B. C. de Souza, Gabriela Soffiati, Victor S. Lemos, Victor Y. Yukuhiro, Miguel A. San&#8208;Miguel, Pablo S. Fern&#225;ndez, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401633729

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matheus B. C. de Souza, Gabriela Soffiati, Victor S. Lemos, Victor Y. Yukuhiro, Miguel A. San&#8208;Miguel, Pablo S. Fern&#225;ndez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstitution of Myoglobin with Iron Porphycene Generates an Artificial Aldoxime Dehydratase with Expanded Catalytic Activities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03220</link>
      <description>Shunsuke Kato, Masatoshi Abe, Harald Gr&#246;ger, Takashi Hayashi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647230

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shunsuke Kato, Masatoshi Abe, Harald Gr&#246;ger, Takashi Hayashi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogenation of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by a Tripodal Palladium Pincer Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02523</link>
      <description>Nandita Biswas, Peter L&#246;nnecke, E. Kirillov, Dmitri Gelman, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401660020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nandita Biswas, Peter L&#246;nnecke, E. Kirillov, Dmitri Gelman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkene Isomerization Catalyzed by a Mn(I) Bisphosphine Borohydride Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03364</link>
      <description>Ines Blaha, Stefan Weber, Robin D&#252;lger, Lu&#305;&#769;s F. Veiros, Karl Kirchner, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401660026

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ines Blaha, Stefan Weber, Robin D&#252;lger, Lu&#305;&#769;s F. Veiros, Karl Kirchner</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Electron or Four-Electron Nanocatalysis for Aerobic Glucose Oxidation: A Mechanism-Driven Prediction Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03226</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Qiao-Zhi Li, Jia&#8208;Jia Zheng, Xingfa Gao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401611661

                The nanomaterial-catalyzed oxidation of glucose can produce H2O2 or H2O as the oxygen reduction products. However, the theoretical model predicting the selection between H2O2 and H2O products is still lacking, which limits the rational design of aerobic glucose oxidation nanocatalysts for H2O2-targeted applications in disease diagnoses and therapies. In this work, a mechanism-driven prediction model that can predict whether a nanocatalyst preferably undergoes the 2e-catalysis to produce H2O2 or the 4e-catalysis to produce H2O is developed. The development of the model is first based on the reaction thermodynamics, and then a correction constant is introduced in conjunction with experimental reports to compensate to some extent for the lack of consideration of other influencing factors such as the reaction kinetics. The predictive power of the model is verified by density functional theory investigations on the mechanisms and kinetics of the experimentally reported noble metal nanocatalysts. Using the model, binary alloy nanomaterials, which preferably undergo 2e-catalysis to produce H2O2, have been predicted. This work provides theoretical guidelines for the rational design of aerobic glucose oxidation nanocatalysts capable of producing H2O2 and facilitates their application in H2O2-targeted biomedicine.</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Qiao-Zhi Li, Jia&#8208;Jia Zheng, Xingfa Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Cooperation of Dual-Phase Redox Catalysts in Chemical Looping Oxidative Coupling of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03001</link>
      <description>Leo Brody, Bar Mosevitzky Lis, Abigail P&#233;rez Ortiz, Mohammadreza Kosari, Kyle Vogt&#8208;Lowell, Sam Portillo, Reinhard Schom&#228;cker, Israel E. Wachs, Fanxing Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401628374

                Chemical looping oxidative coupling of methane (CL-OCM) presents a promising route for light olefin production, offering a simpler alternative to conventional methane steam reforming approaches. The selection of the redox catalyst used in CL-OCM is critical since it must achieve high C2+ yields (&gt;25%) while maintaining longevity in harsh reaction environments. We present a comprehensive performance evaluation and characterization of an understudied, yet highly effective redox catalyst capable of achieving and maintaining a C2+ yield of 26.8% at 840 &#176;C. Through extensive ex situ and in situ analyses, including X-ray diffraction, near-ambient pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (NAP-XPS), and Raman spectroscopy, we have characterized the catalyst and identified two distinct bulk, crystalline phases: cubic LixMg6&#8211;xMnO8 and orthorhombic Mg3&#8211;xMnx(BO3)O2. Calcination at 1200 &#176;C, as opposed to a typical calcination temperature of 900 &#176;C, increased the orthoborate oxide phase to &#8764;45 wt % while reducing the BET surface area by 65%. By investigating performance differences between these catalysts in their "sintered" and "presintered" states, we have unveiled surprising cooperative effects between the two phases. Experiments with physical mixing of these two phases (granular stacking and mortar mixing) revealed that observed differences in CL-OCM efficacy cannot be solely due to sintering-induced loss of surface area but are also the result of synergistic, dual-phase interactions that enhance overall C2+ yield. H2-temperature programmed reduction measurements and ex situ XPS analysis demonstrate that the sintered catalyst has a lower average Mn-oxidation state, enabling more selective lattice oxygen release and limiting overoxidation to COx species. Additionally, NAP-XPS and in situ Raman characterization suggest that boron&#8211;oxygen coordinated sites (BOx) may also play a role in improving selectivity. Leveraging insights from our phase mixture CL-OCM performance tests, steady-state experiments with cofed O2, and corroborative in situ characterizations, we propose that the synergistic interplay between LixMg6&#8211;xMnO8 and Mg3&#8211;xMnx(BO3)O2 may be the result of facile oxygen release from the more redox-active LixMg6&#8211;xMnO8 phase combined with Li+ migration to the orthoborate oxide phase.</description>
      <author>Leo Brody, Bar Mosevitzky Lis, Abigail P&#233;rez Ortiz, Mohammadreza Kosari, Kyle Vogt&#8208;Lowell, Sam Portillo, Reinhard Schom&#228;cker, Israel E. Wachs, Fanxing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Effect of Dopants in Zirconia-Based Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03206</link>
      <description>Raffaele Cheula, Tuan Anh Tran, Mie Andersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401631981

                The doping of zirconia to enhance its activity and selectivity for the hydrogenation of CO2 to methanol has been studied intensively in experiments, but a thorough theoretical understanding of the factors that decide whether a dopant has a positive or negative influence on the reactivity is lacking. In this work, we conduct a mechanistic investigation using density functional theory and microkinetic modeling, considering the ZrO2(101) surface doped with 16 different metals. This analysis elucidates the following two criteria for enhanced reactivity. One, the ability of the surface to facilitate the dissociation of H2 and provide the H* species necessary for the catalytic reaction is deemed a necessary but not sufficient criterion. Two, dopants that are thermodynamically stable under reaction conditions in a 2+ or 3+ oxidation state are beneficial, since this entails the introduction of O vacancies, which stabilize O-containing reaction intermediates such as formate and lower key transition states. We construct linear scaling relations that can reliably predict transition state energies in terms of less computationally costly adsorption energies. It is revealed that dopants that are stable in the 4+ state (e.g., Ti), and thereby lack O vacancies, follow a different scaling relation with a higher intercept for formate formation, which can explain their reduced reactivity. Overall, our microkinetic models can successfully predict the trends for dopants that have been found active in experiments (Zn2+, Cd2+, Ga3+, In3+) and not. Together with the established reactivity criteria, this paves the way for computational screening of oxides for the important CO2-to-methanol process.</description>
      <author>Raffaele Cheula, Tuan Anh Tran, Mie Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intermolecular Anti-Markovnikov Hydroamination of Alkenes with Sulfonamides, Sulfamides, and Sulfamates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03960</link>
      <description>A. T. Lin, Mathis J. Karrasch, Qiaolin Yan, Jacob M. Ganley, Benjamin G. Hejna, Robert R. Knowles, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401635760

                A general method for the light-driven intermolecular anti-Markovnikov hydroamination of alkenes with primary sulfonamides, sulfamides, and sulfamates is presented. The reaction is mediated by a ternary catalyst system composed of an iridium(III) chromophore, a fluorinated alkoxide base, and a thiol H-atom donor. We hypothesize that the reactions proceed via a proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) mechanism wherein implementation of the alkoxide base imparts additional thermochemical driving force for the homolytic activation of strong N&#8211;H bonds that were previously inaccessible using this methodology. This furnishes electrophilic N-centered radicals that subsequently interface with a wide range of unactivated alkenes for C&#8211;N bond formation. This protocol exhibits a broad substrate scope and great functional group tolerance, further highlighting the advantages of excited-state PCET as a platform for catalytic radical generation from common organic functional groups.</description>
      <author>A. T. Lin, Mathis J. Karrasch, Qiaolin Yan, Jacob M. Ganley, Benjamin G. Hejna, Robert R. Knowles</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Dispersed Cu Atoms Induce Alternating Surface Microstrain in PtCu Concave Octahedral Nanoparticles Accelerating Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02973</link>
      <description>Xiashuang Luo, Cehuang Fu, Shuiyun Shen, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang, Junliang Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401643081

                A comprehensive understanding of the intricate surface environments of practical nanocatalysts at the atomic level is essential for advancing our knowledge of catalytic mechanisms. In this study, we investigate PtCu octahedral nanoparticles with varying microstrains engineered by Cu dispersion. A detailed analysis of the atom configuration and corresponding microstrain is conducted. The intimate mixing of Cu and Pt results in increased randomness in atom displacement within the lattice and a more pronounced distribution of alternating microstrain on the surfaces. Specifically, we observe that the PtCu concave octahedral nanoparticles with alternating microstrain demonstrate a substantial oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity of 3.95 mA cm&#8211;2 in area-specific activity. The significant impact of shear microstrain is further underscored, as evidenced by an 86.9% decrease in the ORR activity upon the removal of the alternating shear microstrain. This study sheds light on the effects of microstrain toward the ORR and provides valuable insights into designing advanced Pt-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiashuang Luo, Cehuang Fu, Shuiyun Shen, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Chemical Origin of Dual-Atom Sites for Enhanced Oxygen Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03068</link>
      <description>Xiannong Tang, Yuqin Zhang, Shaobin Tang, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647130

                Dual-atom catalysts have garnered widespread attention for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), yet achieving an in-depth comprehension of the reaction mechanism and the structure&#8211;activity relationship remains challenging. Herein, carbon nanosheets with FeCo&#8211;N6 active sites (FeCo-NCNS) are prepared via a straightforward self-sacrificing template and cascade anchoring strategy. Delicate structural control enables hierarchical porosity, providing adequate active site density (2.5 &#215; 1019 sites g&#8211;1) and fast mass transfer, as revealed by in situ scanning electrochemical microscopy. Moreover, the structural and chemical origin of the dual-atom site for enhanced ORR activity is uncovered. FeCo&#8211;N6 can be spontaneously transformed to an oxygen-bridging structure (FeCo&#8211;N6&#8211;O) in the KOH electrolyte, triggering improved charge polarization, downshifted d-band center, and optimized adsorption behavior for oxygen-intermediates, thereby reducing the free energy barrier. Therefore, the FeCo-NCNS exhibits enhanced ORR activity regarding the half-wave potential (0.90 V), mass specific kinetic current density (9.54 A g&#8211;1), turnover frequency (2.35 e&#8211; site&#8211;1 s&#8211;1), and improved stability. This work not only provides an effective methodology to construct efficient electrocatalysts for energy conversation but also highlights the dynamic structural evolution and charge polarization in improving the electrocatalytic activity of dual-atom sites.</description>
      <author>Xiannong Tang, Yuqin Zhang, Shaobin Tang, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i016_1834783</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401650251

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i016_1834783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i016_1834784</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401652163

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i016_1834784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bidirectional Electron Transfer Strategies for Anti-Markovnikov Olefin Aminofunctionalization via Arylamine Radicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04110</link>
      <description>Pritam Roychowdhury, Samya Samanta, Lauren R. Brown, Saim Waheed, David C. Powers, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401658377

                Arylamines are common structural motifs in pharmaceuticals, natural products, and materials precursors. While olefin aminofunctionalization chemistry can provide entry to arylamines, classical polar reactions typically afford Markovnikov products. Nitrogen-centered radical intermediates provide the opportunity to access anti-Markovnikov selectivity; however, anti-Markovnikov arylamination is unknown in large part due to the lack of arylamine radical precursors. Here, we introduce bidirectional electron transfer processes to generate arylamine radical intermediates from N-pyridinium arylamines: Single-electron oxidation provides arylamine radicals that engage in anti-Markovnikov olefin aminopyridylation; single-electron reduction unveils arylamine radicals that engage in anti-Markovnikov olefin aminofunctionalization. The development of bidirectional redox processes complements classical design principles for radical precursors, which typically function via a single redox manifold. Demonstration of both oxidative and reductive mechanisms to generate arylamine radicals from a common N-aminopyridinium precursor provides complementary methods to rapidly construct and diversify arylamine scaffolds from readily available radical precursors.</description>
      <author>Pritam Roychowdhury, Samya Samanta, Lauren R. Brown, Saim Waheed, David C. Powers</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the Parallel Biosynthetic Pathways of the Cyclohexanone and Phenol Rings in Cycloheximide and Actiphenol by Tailoring Redox Enzymes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03332</link>
      <description>Jun Tang, Xiaowei Guo, Jing Yang, Yongjiang Wang, Jianying Luo, Min Yin, Yijun Yan, Sheng&#8208;Xiong Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401658412

                The eukaryotic translation inhibitor cycloheximide (CHX) and its analogue actiphenol (APN) feature a glutarimide moiety and a six-membered carbocyclic ring system. The biosynthesis of CHX and APN is not yet fully understood, particularly with respect to the mechanism of formation of the fully reduced cyclohexanone ring in CHX and the aromatic phenol ring in APN. In this work, a combination of gene inactivation, chemical synthesis, and in vitro biochemical experiments highlighted an ensemble of three tailoring redox enzymes as being responsible for the biosynthesis of the six-membered carbocyclic ring systems. Specifically, two redox enzymes (ChxJ and ChxI) alone can generate an active intermediate that undergoes a cascade of non-enzymatic transformations to create APN, while a reductive enzyme (ChxG) acts as a gatekeeper, directing the same intermediate down a different pathway toward CHX. Finally, the full nature of each biosynthetic pathway was established in detail, including the formation mechanisms of six-membered carbocyclic rings.</description>
      <author>Jun Tang, Xiaowei Guo, Jing Yang, Yongjiang Wang, Jianying Luo, Min Yin, Yijun Yan, Sheng&#8208;Xiong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Catalyzed Site-Selective C(sp&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Alkynylation of Allenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03688</link>
      <description>Duan Xiu, Qihao Jin, Sheng Wang, Yifan Sun, Youhao Wei, Li Wang, Jiang&#8208;Kai Qiu, Kai Guo, Xiaoguang Bao, Xinxin Wu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401691251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Duan Xiu, Qihao Jin, Sheng Wang, Yifan Sun, Youhao Wei, Li Wang, Jiang&#8208;Kai Qiu, Kai Guo, Xiaoguang Bao, Xinxin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Multihalogenation of a Non-native Substrate by the SyrB2 Iron Halogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02816</link>
      <description>R. Hunter Wilson, Sourav Chatterjee, Elizabeth R. Smithwick, Anoop R. Damodaran, Ambika Bhagi&#8208;Damodaran, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401694293

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Hunter Wilson, Sourav Chatterjee, Elizabeth R. Smithwick, Anoop R. Damodaran, Ambika Bhagi&#8208;Damodaran</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Oxyalkynylation of Unactivated Alkenes Enabled by Hypervalent Iodine(III) Reagents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02977</link>
      <description>Hanzhang Qin, Zhengyi Liu, Yixin Zhang, Yiyun Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401697138

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hanzhang Qin, Zhengyi Liu, Yixin Zhang, Yiyun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective N-Heterocyclic Carbene-Catalyzed Hauser-Kraus Annulations for the Construction of C&#8211;N Axially Chiral Phthalimde Derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03263</link>
      <description>Panlong Ren, Qing Zhao, Kang Xu, Tingshun Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401701297

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Panlong Ren, Qing Zhao, Kang Xu, Tingshun Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anion-Doping-Mediated Metal&#8211;Support Interactions in CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported Pd Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02874</link>
      <description>Luyang Qiao, Xi-guang Wang, Shanshan Zong, Zhi Gao Huang, Zhangfeng Zhou, Maohong Fan, Yuan&#8208;Gen Yao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401707800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luyang Qiao, Xi-guang Wang, Shanshan Zong, Zhi Gao Huang, Zhangfeng Zhou, Maohong Fan, Yuan&#8208;Gen Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02874</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
