<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:43:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A Water-Promoted Mars&#8722;van Krevelen Reaction Dominates Low-Temperature CO Oxidation over Au-Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; but Not over Au-TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05978</link>
      <description>Alexander Holm, Bernadette Davies, Sara Boscolo Bibi, F&#233;lix Moncada, Joakim Halldin-Stenlid, Laurynas Pa&#353;kevi&#269;ius, Vincent Claman, Adam Slabon, Cheuk&#8208;Wai Tai, Egon Campos dos Santos, Sergey Koroidov, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391806007

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alexander Holm, Bernadette Davies, Sara Boscolo Bibi, F&#233;lix Moncada, Joakim Halldin-Stenlid, Laurynas Pa&#353;kevi&#269;ius, Vincent Claman, Adam Slabon, Cheuk&#8208;Wai Tai, Egon Campos dos Santos, Sergey Koroidov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05978</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subnanometer Cu Clusters on Porous Ag Enhancing Ethanol Production in Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03469</link>
      <description>Jiwon Park, Chaehwa Jeong, Moony Na, Yusik Oh, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Yongsoo Yang, Hye Ryung Byon, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391806039

                Controlling the electrochemical CO2 reduction process for multicarbon production is challenging. Ethanol is typically produced with lower selectivity compared to ethylene. In addition, ill-defined catalytic active sites and elusive mechanisms of C&#8211;C coupling further hinder the enhancement of ethanol generation. Here, we carefully regulated the quantity of the Cu atoms and deposited them onto a Ag inverse-opal structure (AgIOs) using the pulse-electrodeposition method. Subnanometer Cu clusters demonstrated a 2.5 times higher Faradaic efficiency for ethanol production compared to that for ethylene at &#8722;1.05 V vs RHE. Conversely, as the size of Cu increased to nanometers, ethylene became the dominant product. Excessive adsorption of CO on Cu clusters, which migrates from the Ag surface, is attributed to the improved ethanol production. Abundant Ag/Cu boundaries and adjacent spacing between Ag and Cu clusters may enhance the surface migration of CO. In contrast, the preferential site-selective CO adsorption on large Cu nanoparticles is associated with solution-mediated CO migration. Operando shell-isolated nanoparticle-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SHINERS) revealed a high coverage of the CO on the Cu clusters. The initial intermediate *OCCOH by C&#8211;C coupling appeared for both Cu clusters and nanoparticles. However, Cu clusters accommodated more carbonaceous intermediates, highlighting the critical role of CO and intermediate coverages on Cu in ethanol production.</description>
      <author>Jiwon Park, Chaehwa Jeong, Moony Na, Yusik Oh, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Yongsoo Yang, Hye Ryung Byon</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy-Transfer-Enabled Radical Acylation Using Free Alkyl Boronic Acids through Photo and NHC Dual Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06027</link>
      <description>W.&#8211;B. Liu, Xiang Zhang, Lin Chen, Rong Zeng, Yu Tian, Ernest Ma, Yapeng Wang, Bin Zhang, Jun&#8208;Long Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391807503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W.&#8211;B. Liu, Xiang Zhang, Lin Chen, Rong Zeng, Yu Tian, Ernest Ma, Yapeng Wang, Bin Zhang, Jun&#8208;Long Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Mechanistic Insights into CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CO Electroreduction to Acetate by Combining Computations and Experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05825</link>
      <description>Xiaowan Bai, Ming He, Yifei Xu, Bingjun Xu, Qi L&#252;, Jinlan Wang, Chongyi Ling, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391807606

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaowan Bai, Ming He, Yifei Xu, Bingjun Xu, Qi L&#252;, Jinlan Wang, Chongyi Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Hydrogen Storage: Metal Hydrides for Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05696</link>
      <description>Haoming Yu, Xingguo Li, Jianlong Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391812707

                Metal hydrides (MHs) are featured for their reversible hydrogen absorption and desorption properties, which are conventionally used as hydrogen storage materials. MHs can also be used for catalysis, particularly for chemical reactions that involve hydrogen. This Review summarizes the historical and recent progress in the catalytic application of MHs. The focus topic is how the reversible hydrogen absorption and desorption properties of MHs enable their catalytic effect in hydrogen involving chemical reactions. We start with the basic properties of MHs, and their applications in hydrogen storage and related fields. The application of MHs in four important catalytic reactions: olefin hydrogenation, reversible hydrogen storage in liquid organic hydrogen carriers, CO2 hydrogenation, and NH3 synthesis are discussed. Finally, we compare MH-based catalysts with their analogues, including hydrogen spillover, oxyhydrides, mixed-anion hydrides, and electrides in catalysis. The Review demonstrates the inherent relationship between MH catalysis and their intrinsic hydrogen absorption and desorption properties, providing insights into diverse applications of MHs beyond hydrogen storage.</description>
      <author>Haoming Yu, Xingguo Li, Jianlong Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Site Diversity and Connectivity in Electrochemical CO Reduction on Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05904</link>
      <description>Chansol Kim, Nitish Govindarajan, Sydney Hemenway, Jun Ho Park, Anya Zoraster, Calton J. Kong, Rajiv Ramanujam Prabhakar, Joel B. Varley, Hee&#8208;Tae Jung, Christopher Hahn, Joel W. Ager, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391821487

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction on Cu is a promising approach to produce value-added chemicals using renewable feedstocks, yet various Cu preparations have led to differences in activity and selectivity toward single and multicarbon products. Here, we find, surprisingly, that the effective catalytic activity toward ethylene improves when there is a larger fraction of less active sites acting as reservoirs of *CO on the surface of Cu nanoparticle electrocatalysts. In an adaptation of chemical transient kinetics to electrocatalysis, we measure the dynamic response of a gas diffusion electrode (GDE) cell when the feed gas is abruptly switched between Ar (inert) and CO. When switching from Ar to CO, CO reduction (COR) begins promptly, but when switching from CO to Ar, COR can be maintained for several seconds (delay time) despite the absence of the CO reactant in the gas phase. A three-site microkinetic model captures the observed dynamic behavior and shows that Cu catalysts exhibiting delay times have a less active *CO reservoir that exhibits fast diffusion to active sites. The observed delay times and the estimated *CO reservoir sizes are affected by catalyst preparation, applied potential, and microenvironment (electrolyte cation identity, electrolyte pH, and CO partial pressure). Notably, we estimate that the *CO reservoir surface coverage can be as high as 88 &#177; 7% on oxide-derived Cu (OD-Cu) at high overpotentials (&#8722;1.52 V vs SHE) and this increases in reservoir coverage coincide with increased turnover frequencies to ethylene. We also estimate that *CO can travel substantial distances (up to 10s of nm) prior to desorption or reaction. It appears that active C&#8211;C coupling sites by themselves do not control selectivity to C2+ products in electrochemical COR; the supply of CO to those sites is also a crucial factor. More generally, the overall activity of Cu electrocatalysts cannot be approximated from linear combinations of individual site activities. Future designs must consider the diversity of the catalyst network and account for intersite transportation pathways.</description>
      <author>Chansol Kim, Nitish Govindarajan, Sydney Hemenway, Jun Ho Park, Anya Zoraster, Calton J. Kong, Rajiv Ramanujam Prabhakar, Joel B. Varley, Hee&#8208;Tae Jung, Christopher Hahn, Joel W. Ager</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05904</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation Activity via Regulating the Strong Metal&#8211;Support Interactions of the Ni/Sm&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06345</link>
      <description>Jianxiong Zhao, Xiaozhi Liu, Zhengwen Li, Kai Feng, Yue Pan, Pengxiang Ji, Kangning Zhao, Binhang Yan, Dan Zhou, Dong Su, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391823363

                Strong metal&#8211;support interactions (SMSIs), characterized by the encapsulation of metal nanoparticles by the support oxide, have a significant impact on various heterogeneous catalytic reactions. In this study, we present our investigations on tuning the catalytic performance of CO2 hydrogenation through regulating the SMSI in a Ni/Sm2O3 catalyst. Our results demonstrate that the complete encapsulation of Ni nanoparticles with amorphous Sm2O3, achieved through H2 reduction, leads to nearly full selectivity to CO. In contrast, with controlled in situ thermal postannealing in an H2/CO2/N2 mixture, the encapsulated Sm2O3 layer can be partially removed and crystallized, as revealed by atomic-resolution transmission electron microscopy analyses, which results in enhanced activity and a full selectivity toward CH4. In addition, the prolonged postannealing durations completely remove the Sm2O3 overlayer, causing a decline in CO2 methanation activity. These findings underscore the critical role of the SMSI effect in CO2 hydrogenation activity and offer valuable insights for regulating SMSI to produce targeted value-added chemicals.</description>
      <author>Jianxiong Zhao, Xiaozhi Liu, Zhengwen Li, Kai Feng, Yue Pan, Pengxiang Ji, Kangning Zhao, Binhang Yan, Dan Zhou, Dong Su</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Searching for the Rules of Electrochemical Nitrogen Fixation&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00448</link>
      <description>Romain Tort, Alexander Bagger, Olivia Westhead, Yasuyuki Kondo, Artem Khobnya, Anna Winiwarter, Bethan J. V. Davies, Aron Walsh, Yu Katayama, Yuki Yamada, Mary P. Ryan, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Ifan E. L. Stephens, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391823418

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ARTICLES ASAPPREVCorrectionNEXTORIGINAL ARTICLEThis notice is a correctionCorrection to &#8220;Searching for the Rules of Electrochemical Nitrogen Fixation&#8221;Romain TortRomain TortMore by Romain Tort, Alexander Bagger*Alexander BaggerMore by Alexander Baggerhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-6394-029X, Olivia WestheadOlivia WestheadMore by Olivia Westhead, Yasuyuki KondoYasuyuki KondoMore by Yasuyuki Kondohttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-1103-3329, Artem KhobnyaArtem KhobnyaMore by Artem Khobnya, Anna WiniwarterAnna WiniwarterMore by Anna Winiwarter, Bethan J. V. DaviesBethan J. V. DaviesMore by Bethan J. V. Davieshttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-3789-8462, Aron WalshAron WalshMore by Aron Walshhttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-5460-7033, Yu KatayamaYu KatayamaMore by Yu Katayamahttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-7842-2938, Yuki YamadaYuki YamadaMore by Yuki Yamadahttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-7191-7129, Mary P. RyanMary P. RyanMore by Mary P. Ryanhttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-8582-3003, Maria-Magdalena TitiriciMaria-Magdalena TitiriciMore by Maria-Magdalena Titiricihttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-0773-2100, and Ifan E. L. Stephens*Ifan E. L. StephensMore by Ifan E. L. StephensCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, XXX, 3169&#8211;3170Publication Date (Web):February 14, 2024Publication History Received29 January 2024Published online14 February 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00448&#169; 2024 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society. This publication is licensed under CC-BY 4.0. License Summary*You are free to share (copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format and to adapt (remix, transform, and build upon) the material for any purpose, even commercially within the parameters below:Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license.Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.View full license*DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. This publication is Open Access under the license indicated. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InRedditEmail PDF (1 MB) Get e-AlertscloseSupporting Info (1)&#187;Supporting Information Supporting Information SUBJECTS:Binding energy,Electrical energy,Elements,Metals,Nitrides Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author>Romain Tort, Alexander Bagger, Olivia Westhead, Yasuyuki Kondo, Artem Khobnya, Anna Winiwarter, Bethan J. V. Davies, Aron Walsh, Yu Katayama, Yuki Yamada, Mary P. Ryan, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Ifan E. L. Stephens</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Lattice Matching Strategy Enables Robust Water Oxidation Electrocatalysis in Acidic Media via Two Distinct Oxygen Evolution Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06182</link>
      <description>Haoqiang Song, Xue Yong, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Jingkun Yu, Hao Wang, Jinmeng Cai, Zhiyong Tang, Bai Yang, Jiangwei Chang, Siyu Lu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391836369

                The discovery of acid-stable and highly active electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial in the quest for high-performance water-splitting technologies. Herein, a heterostructured RuO2&#8211;CeO2 electrocatalyst was constructed by using a lattice-matching strategy. The interfacial Ru&#8211;O&#8211;Ce bridge structure provided a channel for electron transfer between Ru and Ce, creating a lattice stress that distorts the local structure of RuO2. The resulting RuO2&#8211;CeO2 catalyst exhibited attractive stability with negligible decay after 1000 h of the OER in 0.5 M H2SO4, along with high activity with an overpotential of only 180 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2. In situ attenuated total reflectance surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy (ATR-SEIRAS), in situ differential electrochemical mass spectrometry (DEMS), and density functional theory (DFT) calculations were used to reveal that the interface and noninterface RuO2 sites enabled an oxide path mechanism (OPM) and the enhanced adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM-plus), respectively, during the OER. The simultaneous and independent OER pathways accessible by lattice matching guides improved electrocatalyst design for the OER in acidic media.</description>
      <author>Haoqiang Song, Xue Yong, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Jingkun Yu, Hao Wang, Jinmeng Cai, Zhiyong Tang, Bai Yang, Jiangwei Chang, Siyu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06182</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Electrosynthesis of Cyclohexanone Oxime through Nitrate Reduction on a Zn&#8211;Cu Alloy Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05388</link>
      <description>Jonathan O. Sharp, Anna Ciotti, Hayley Andrews, Shaktiswaran R. Udayasurian, Max Garc&#237;a&#8208;Melchor, Tengfei Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391839397

                Cyclohexanone oxime is an important precursor for Nylon-6 and is typically synthesized via the nucleophilic addition&#8211;elimination of hydroxylamine with cyclohexanone. Current technologies for hydroxylamine production are, however, not environment-friendly due to the requirement of harsh reaction conditions. Here, we report an electrochemical method for the one-pot synthesis of cyclohexanone oxime under ambient conditions with aqueous nitrate as the nitrogen source. A series of Zn&#8211;Cu alloy catalysts are developed to drive the electrochemical reduction of nitrate, where the hydroxylamine intermediate formed in the electroreduction process can undergo a chemical reaction with the cyclohexanone present in the electrolyte to produce the corresponding oxime. The best performance is achieved on a Zn93Cu7 electrocatalyst with a 97% yield and a 27% Faradaic efficiency for cyclohexanone oxime at 100 mA/cm2. By analyzing the catalytic activities/selectivities of the different Zn&#8211;Cu alloys and conducting in-depth mechanistic studies via in situ Raman spectroscopy and theoretical calculations, we demonstrate that the adsorption of nitrogen species plays a central role in catalytic performance. Overall, this work provides an attractive strategy to build the C&#8211;N bond in oxime and drive organic synthesis through electrochemical nitrate reduction, while highlighting the importance of controlling surface adsorption for product selectivity in electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Jonathan O. Sharp, Anna Ciotti, Hayley Andrews, Shaktiswaran R. Udayasurian, Max Garc&#237;a&#8208;Melchor, Tengfei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantiocovergent Cross-Coupling Reaction with 1,4-Dihydropyridine Derivatives via Photoinduced Nickel Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05521</link>
      <description>Tongtong Li, Luo Liu, Xiaokai Cheng, Zhan Lu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391839433

                Herein, we reported the enantioconvergent Csp3&#8211;Csp2 cross-coupling reaction with 1,4-dihydropyridine (DHP) derivatives via photoredox/nickel dual catalysis to access chiral products with good yield and enantioselectivity. The operationally simple reaction was carried out under mild conditions with good functional group tolerance. Due to the use of a stoichiometric equivalent of aryl/alkenyl halides as coupling partners, the sequential and iterative synthesis could be achieved smoothly in one pot for the synthesis of position isomers and stereoisomers. In the proposed mechanism, kinetic experiments and mechanistic studies indicated that the radical generation, depended on the excited photocatalyst and DHP, was the rate-determining step.</description>
      <author>Tongtong Li, Luo Liu, Xiaokai Cheng, Zhan Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05521</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Vacancy-Induced Built-In Electric Field across MoCo Dual-Atomic Site Catalyst for Promoting Hydrogen Spillover in Hydrocracking and Hydrodesulfurization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05911</link>
      <description>Guangxun Sun, Dongyuan Liu, Hongfu Shi, Junxi Li, Liting Yang, Fengyu Tian, Yuchen Cui, Chunlin Wang, Feiyang Li, Tiansheng Zhao, Houyu Zhu, Bin Liu, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Yunqi Liu, Yuan Pan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391842855

                The design and construction of highly efficient catalytic active sites for promoting hydrogen spillover are of great significance for improving hydrocracking (HCK) and hydrodesulfurization (HDS) performance in slurry-phase hydrogenation of vacuum residue (VR) but are still challenging. Herein, we report a carbon-supported MoCo dual-atomic site catalyst (MoCo DAC/C) and propose an oxygen-vacancy-induced built-in electric field (BIEF) regulation mechanism for promoting hydrogen spillover in HCK and HDS. It was found that the coordination structure of the MoCo dual-atomic was reconstructed and formed O vacancies in situ during hydrogenation process. The formation of O vacancies not only provided macromolecular adsorption sites but also broke the electronic balance and formed a weak BIEF between the Mo and Co atoms. Meanwhile, H2 was activated at the Mo sites to form active hydrogen species. The formation of BIEF promoted the active hydrogen spillover from Mo to Co sites by a Mo&#8211;C&#8211;Co bridging bond, thus improving the hydrogenation performance greatly. In HCK of VR, the MoCo DAC/C demonstrates remarkable catalytic hydrogenation activity with TOFT calculated for total metals up to 0.77 s&#8211;1 (two times enhancement than that of Mo single atoms (SAs)/C), the per pass conversion of VR of 76 wt %, liquid product yield of 92 wt %, and coke content of only 0.55 wt %. It also shows robust HDS performance with dibenzothiophene (DBT) conversion of 70 wt %. Density functional theory reveals that the formation of the O vacancies leads to the discrepancy of Bader charge between Mo and Co atoms, and the resulting local electric field can favor the diffusion of the positively charged (+0.10 e&#8722;) H atom. This work proposes an oxygen-vacancy-induced BIEF regulation mechanism from an atomic scale for enhancing the catalytic reaction process by promoting hydrogen spillover, which provided novel insights for the design and development of high-performance hydrogenation catalysts.</description>
      <author>Guangxun Sun, Dongyuan Liu, Hongfu Shi, Junxi Li, Liting Yang, Fengyu Tian, Yuchen Cui, Chunlin Wang, Feiyang Li, Tiansheng Zhao, Houyu Zhu, Bin Liu, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Yunqi Liu, Yuan Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05911</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indium-Catalyzed Reductive Coupling Enabled Efficient Synthesis of Acylphosphine Oxides and Diphosphines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05947</link>
      <description>Dongdong Xu, Ming Yu Jin, Yu Chen, Daoqing Han, Lizhi Tao, Xiangyou Xing, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391843736

                The unique low level of the ionization potential of indium(0) to indium(I) makes it an appealing metal for organic synthesis. Here, we present an indium-catalyzed reductive cross-coupling between chlorophosphines (R2PCl) or dichlorophosphines (RPCl2) with acyl chlorides (RCOCl). This one-pot approach, using indium-catalysis followed by oxidation, generates a variety of mono- or bis-acylphosphine oxides in good yields. Additionally, this protocol offers a convenient pathway to obtain the photoinitiators, Luricin TPO and IRGACURE 819, that are widely used in the industry. Experimental and computational studies indicate the intermediacy of phosphorus-based radical species that dimerize to diphosphines, which then couple with acyl chlorides through a four-membered transition state. Furthermore, we also explore indium-catalyzed reductive homocoupling of R2PCl or RPCl2, which provides facile access to various P&#8211;P bond formations.</description>
      <author>Dongdong Xu, Ming Yu Jin, Yu Chen, Daoqing Han, Lizhi Tao, Xiangyou Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distinct Site Motifs Activate O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on Supported Au Nanoparticles in Liquid Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05072</link>
      <description>Jason S. Adams, H Chen, Tomas Ricciardulli, Sucharita Vijayaraghavan, Abinaya Sampath, David W. Flaherty, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391843796

                Au nanoparticles catalyze the activation and conversion of small molecules with rates and kinetic barriers that depend on the dimensions of the nanoparticle, composition of the support, and presence of catalytically culpable water molecules that solvate these interfaces. Here, molecular interpretations of steady-state rate measurements, kinetic isotope effects, and structural characterizations reveal how the interface of Au nanoparticles, liquid water, and metal oxide supports mediate the kinetically relevant activation of H2 and sequential reduction of O2-derived intermediates during the formation of H2O2 and H2O. Rates of H2 consumption are 10&#8211;100 fold greater on Au nanoparticles supported on metal oxides (e.g., titania) compared to more inert and hydrophobic materials (carbon, boron nitride). Similarly, Au nanoparticles on reducible and Lewis acidic supports (e.g., lanthana) bind dioxygen intermediates more strongly and present lower barriers (&lt;22 kJ mol&#8211;1) for O&#8211;O bond dissociation than inert interfaces formed with silica (&gt;70 kJ mol&#8211;1). Selectivities for H2O2 formation increase significantly as the diameters of the Au nanoparticles increase because differences in nanoparticle size change the relative fractions of exposed sites that exist at Au&#8211;support interfaces. In contrast, site-normalized rates and barriers for H2 activation depend weakly on the size of Au nanoparticles and the associated differences in active site motifs. These findings suggest that H2O aids the activation of H2 at sites present across all surface Au atoms when nanoparticles are solvated by water. However, molecular O2 preferentially binds and dissociates at Au&#8211;support interfaces, leading to greater structure sensitivity for barriers of O&#8211;O dissociation across different support identities and sizes of Au nanoparticles. These insights differ from prior knowledge from studies of gas-phase reactions of H2 and O2 upon Au nanoparticle catalysts within dilute vapor pressures of water (10&#8211;4 to 0.1 kPa H2O), in which catalysis occurs at the perimeter of the Au&#8211;support interface. In contrast, contacting Au catalysts with liquid water (55.5 M H2O) expands catalysis to all surface Au atoms and enables appreciable H2O2 formation.</description>
      <author>Jason S. Adams, H Chen, Tomas Ricciardulli, Sucharita Vijayaraghavan, Abinaya Sampath, David W. Flaherty</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catch-and-Release: The Assembly, Immobilization, and Recycling of Redox-Reversible Artificial Metalloenzymes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05294</link>
      <description>Alex Henrique Miller, E.V. Blagova, Benjamin Large, Rosalind L. Booth, K.S. Wilson, Anne&#8208;Kathrin Duhme&#8208;Klair, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391846627

                Technologies to improve the applicability of artificial metalloenzymes (ArMs) are gaining considerable interest; one such approach is the immobilization of these biohybrid catalysts on support materials to enhance stability and enable their retention, recovery, and reuse. Here, we describe the immobilization of polyhistidine-tagged ArMs that allow the redox-controlled replacement of catalytic cofactors that have lost activity, e.g., due to poisoning or decomposition, on immobilized metal affinity chromatography resins. By using periplasmic siderophore-binding protein scaffolds that originate from thermophilic bacteria (GstCeuE and PthCeuE) in combination with a siderophore-linked imine reduction catalyst, reaction rates were achieved that are about 3.5 times faster than those previously obtained with CjCeuE, the analogous protein of Campylobacter jejuni. Upon immobilization, the GstCeuE-derived ArM showed a decrease in turnover frequency in the reduction of dehydrosalsolidine by 3.4-fold, while retaining enantioselectivity (36%) and showing improved stability that allowed repeat recovery and recycling cycles. Catalytic activity was preserved over the initial four cycles. In subsequent cycles, a gradual reduction of activity was evident. Once the initial activity decreased to around 40% of the initial activity (23rd recycling cycle), the redox-triggered artificial cofactor release permitted the subsequent recharging of the immobilized protein scaffold with fresh, active cofactor, thereby restoring the initial catalytic activity of the immobilized ArM and allowing its reuse for several more cycles. Furthermore, the ArM could be assembled directly from protein present in crude cell extracts, avoiding time-consuming and costly protein purification steps. Overall, this study demonstrates that the immobilization of redox-reversible ArMs facilitates their &#8220;catch-and-release&#8221; assembly and disassembly and the recycling of their components, improving their potential commercial viability and environmental footprint.</description>
      <author>Alex Henrique Miller, E.V. Blagova, Benjamin Large, Rosalind L. Booth, K.S. Wilson, Anne&#8208;Kathrin Duhme&#8208;Klair</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;b&gt;Size and Structure Effects of Carbon-Supported Ruthenium Nanoparticles on Waste Polypropylene Hydrogenolysis Activity, Selectivity, and Product Microstructure&lt;/b&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05927</link>
      <description>Jessie A. Sun, Pavel A. Kots, Zachary R. Hinton, Neboj&#353;a Marinkovi&#263;, Lu Ma, Steven N. Ehrlich, Weiqing Zheng, Thomas H. Epps, LaShanda T. J. Korley, Dionisios G. Vlachos, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391847083

                Hydrogenolysis of plastic waste using Ru-based catalysts is promising for deconstructing polyolefins into lower molecular weight products. Yet, the effect of catalyst atomic structure and size on activity and product selectivity is poorly understood. Herein, we expose the effect of metal particle size and atomic structure on isotactic-polypropylene (i-PP) hydrogenolysis over Ru supported on carbon. Despite similar molecular weight distributions of solid and liquid products, their physical properties are distinct due to different chain regio-irregular CH3 sequences of steric pentads containing racemo configurations. We propose that i-PP hydrogenolysis entails an interplay of C&#8211;C bond scission and stereoisomerization. The active site&#8217;s local electronic environment and structure dictate the former, whereas polymer&#8211;catalyst surface interactions creating suitable polymer conformations control the latter. C&#8211;C scission and stereoisomerization are structure-sensitive. Small, disordered nanoclusters are effective in C&#8211;C bond scission, whereas larger metal nanoparticles promote stereoisomerization. We hypothesize that a heterogeneous distribution of metal active sites is essential for deconstruction and product (lubricant base oil) quality control.</description>
      <author>Jessie A. Sun, Pavel A. Kots, Zachary R. Hinton, Neboj&#353;a Marinkovi&#263;, Lu Ma, Steven N. Ehrlich, Weiqing Zheng, Thomas H. Epps, LaShanda T. J. Korley, Dionisios G. Vlachos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twin Heterostructure Engineering and Facet Effect Boosts Efficient Reduction CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-Ethanol at Low Potential on Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O@Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05857</link>
      <description>Jing Li, Rong Cai, Haiqiang Mu, Jia-Xing Guo, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang, Xin Du, Jie Zhang, Feng Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391847445

                Copper oxide (Cu2O) is considered a promising catalyst that can effectively reduce the overpotential of the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2 RR) and increase the selectivity for C2+ products. However, developing high-performance and stable of CO2-to-ethanol (C2H5OH) based-Cu2O electrocatalysts remains challenging. In this work, Cu2O@Cu2S twin heterojunction catalysts with multitwin boundaries are designed to afford C2H5OH productivity at low potential through the electrocatalytic CO2 RR, and the C2H5OH selectivity is highly dependent on the facet of Cu2O@Cu2S with nanocubes outperforming octahedra. Detailed electrochemical experiments, density functional theory (DFT) calculations and in situ infrared spectroscopy reveals that the introduction of Cu2S boosts the high coverage of *CO, which can easily spillover to the twin boundaries to generate C2H5OH through the *CHOH_*CO coupling reaction pathway. A C2H5OH production begins at an ultralow potential of &#8722;0.45 V vs RHE and reaches 34 and 43.9% Faradaic efficiencies (FE) at &#8722;0.65 V vs RHE in an H-cell and a flow cell, respectively. Meanwhile, this heterojunction constructed with an interface coherent structure and suitable band structure can facilitate electron transfer from Cu2O to Cu2S, leading to the stability of Cu+ valence states. This work provides an avenue to precisely design C2H5OH production catalysts by regulating the interface configuration.</description>
      <author>Jing Li, Rong Cai, Haiqiang Mu, Jia-Xing Guo, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang, Xin Du, Jie Zhang, Feng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the On-Pathway Reaction Intermediates for Metal-Free Atom Transfer Radical Addition to Olefins through Photogenerated Phenalenyl Radical Anion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05688</link>
      <description>Paramita Datta, D. Roy, Divya Jain, Shiv Datt Kumar, Swagata Sil, Anup Bhunia, Jyotishman Dasgupta, Swadhin K. Mandal, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391874588

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Paramita Datta, D. Roy, Divya Jain, Shiv Datt Kumar, Swagata Sil, Anup Bhunia, Jyotishman Dasgupta, Swadhin K. Mandal</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Catalytic Merits of LaV&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt; over Conventional LaVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Polymorphs to Boost Desired Kinetics of Humid NO&lt;sub&gt;X&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction and Poison Disintegration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04828</link>
      <description>Seokhyun Lee, Jeongeun Choi, Heon Phil Ha, Jung Hyun Lee, Jongwook Park, Jongsik Kim, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391879043

                SOZ2&#8211; (Z = 3&#8211;4)-functionalized metal vanadates vary with the type of metal cations (Mn+) for the Mn+-O2&#8211;-V5+ channels that fragment to impart Br&#246;nsted acidic bonds (BA&#8211;-H+; SOZ2&#8211;-H+) and labile/mobile oxygens (OL/OM) with distinct populations and affinities for NOX/O2/H2O/SO2. SOZ2&#8211;-modified Mn+-O2&#8211;-V5+ fragments bind with NH3 to activate Eley&#8211;Rideal (ER)-type selective catalytic NOX reduction (SCR), yet, hardly enable OL coordination with NOX and are often hydrophilic, thereby limiting the activities of SCR or ammonium (bi)sulfate (AS/ABS) fragmentation, as gauged by the NOX consumption (-rNOX) and AS/ABS degradation rates (-rAS/ABS), respectively. Here, we justified the use of nonreducible La3+-containing La3+-O2&#8211;-V5+ channels, whose merits in accelerating SCR and AS/ABS fragmentation were found to be more pronounced for SOZ2&#8211;-modified LaV3O9 (LaV3O9-S) than for conventional/polymorphic LaVO4 analogues (LaVO4-S). Besides activating the ER-type SCR, LaV3O9-S bound with NO and activated Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood-type SCR, as opposed to LaVO4-S. The pre-exponential factor (k&#8242;APP,0) and -rNOX were thus higher for LaV3O9-S than for LaVO4-S and were coupled with the greater amount of OM in the former, leading to superior SCR performance under wet gases. Moreover, compared to LaV3O9-S, its Sb2O5-promoted analogue (LaV3O9-Sb2O5-S) provided a larger number of NH3-accessible BA&#8211;-H+ bonds to achieve higher k&#8242;APP,0/-rNOX alongside higher OM mobility. Furthermore, the LaV3O9-S and Sb2O5-S of LaV3O9-Sb2O5-S elevated the hydrophobicity and number of ABS-accessible BA&#8211;-H+ bonds, respectively. LaV3O9-Sb2O5-S thus revealed a lower energy barrier and higher k&#8242;APP,0 in AS/ABS pyrolysis than a commercial control (V2O5-WO3-S), resulting in a higher -rAS/ABS for the former. Consequently, LaV3O9-Sb2O5-S displayed superior SCR performance and greater hydrothermal resistance under SO2-containing wet gases in comparison with V2O5-WO3-S.</description>
      <author>Seokhyun Lee, Jeongeun Choi, Heon Phil Ha, Jung Hyun Lee, Jongwook Park, Jongsik Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Impact of Pulsed Laser-Produced Single-Pd Nanoparticles on a Bimetallic NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst for Energy-Saving Hydrogen Production via Hybrid Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05051</link>
      <description>Raja Arumugam Senthil, Sieon Jung, Ahreum Min, Anuj Kumar, Cheol Joo Moon, M N Singh, Myong Yong Choi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391879183

                Nowadays, the assembling of hybrid water electrolysis using a hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR) instead of a slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been established as a favorable technology for efficient hydrogen (H2) production. Nevertheless, it is still critical to develop highly effective bifunctional electrocatalysts for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and HzOR. In this work, we propose a facile approach for the design and synthesis of single-Pd-nanoparticles-decorated bimetallic NiCo2O4 nanoplates as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for both HER and HzOR. Initially, the NiCo2O4 nanoplates are synthesized by a combination of hydrothermal reaction and high-temperature calcination. Subsequently, single-Pd nanoparticles with varying proportions are decorated on NiCo2O4 nanoplates via facile pulsed laser irradiation (PLI), leading to the formation of Pd/NiCo2O4 composites. The optimized Pd/NiCo2O4 composite shows a remarkable electrocatalytic ability with a low overpotential of 294 mV for the HER and an ultrasmall working potential of &#8722;6 mV (vs RHE) for the HzOR at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in a 1 M KOH electrolyte. Thus, an overall hydrazine splitting (OHzS) electrolyzer with the Pd/NiCo2O4&#8741;Pd/NiCo2O4 system presents the current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8211;2 at respective low cell voltages of 0.35 and 0.94 V. Notably, in situ/operando Raman spectroscopy confirms the surface formation of &#945;-Co(OH)2 during the HER and &#947;-NiOOH during the HzOR. Furthermore, the density function theory (DFT) calculations demonstrate that the decoration of Pd onto NiCo2O4 facilitates the optimization of both the hydrogen adsorption free energy (&#916;GH*) and enhancement of hydrazine dehydrogenation kinetics. This work introduces a facile strategy for fabricating bifunctional electrocatalysts, potentially useful in energy-saving H2 production.</description>
      <author>Raja Arumugam Senthil, Sieon Jung, Ahreum Min, Anuj Kumar, Cheol Joo Moon, M N Singh, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Photoredox/Cobalt-Catalyzed Reductive Cyclization of Alkynals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06206</link>
      <description>Kento Nakamura, Hina Nishigaki, Yoshihiro Sato, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391879203

                Substituted cyclic alcohol is one of the pharmaceutically essential scaffolds. Here, we report photoredox/cobalt-catalyzed reductive cyclization of alkynals using H2O for the catalyst turnover. This method was applied to aliphatic and aromatic aldehydes for five-, six-, and seven-membered (heterocyclic) ring formation with various substitutions on alkyne units. This H2O-added protocol was further developed into a one-pot transformation from acetals through in situ generated aldehydes, which shortened the synthetic path of the reaction.</description>
      <author>Kento Nakamura, Hina Nishigaki, Yoshihiro Sato</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reply to Comment on &#8220;Heterogeneous Catalyst&#8211;Microbiome Hybrids for Efficient CO-Driven C6 Carboxylic Acid Synthesis via Metabolic Pathway Manipulation&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05832</link>
      <description>Chao Liu, Jiacheng Ji, Yi Zhang, Wen Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391879335

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ARTICLES ASAPPREVCorrespondence/Rebut...Correspondence/RebuttalNEXTReply to Comment on &#8220;Heterogeneous Catalyst&#8211;Microbiome Hybrids for Efficient CO-Driven C6 Carboxylic Acid Synthesis via Metabolic Pathway Manipulation&#8221;Chao LiuChao LiuCollege of Chemical Engineering, Beijing University of Chemical Technology, Beijing 100029, ChinaBiomass Energy and Environmental Engineering Research Center, Beijing University of Chemical Technology, Beijing 100029, ChinaMore by Chao Liu, Jiacheng JiJiacheng JiCollege of Chemical Engineering, Beijing University of Chemical Technology, Beijing 100029, ChinaMore by Jiacheng Ji, Yi Zhang*Yi ZhangCollege of Chemical Engineering, Beijing University of Chemical Technology, Beijing 100029, China*Email: [email protected] (Y. Zhang); Tel: +86-010-64436991.More by Yi Zhang, and Wen Wang*Wen WangCollege of Chemical Engineering, Beijing University of Chemical Technology, Beijing 100029, ChinaBiomass Energy and Environmental Engineering Research Center, Beijing University of Chemical Technology, Beijing 100029, China*Email: [email protected] (W. Wang); Tel: +86-010-64429591.More by Wen Wanghttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-5100-8315Cite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, XXX, 2981&#8211;2984Publication Date (Web):February 16, 2024Publication History Received30 November 2023Accepted25 January 2024Revised11 January 2024Published online16 February 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05832&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyRequest reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InRedditEmail PDF (792 KB) Get e-AlertscloseSUBJECTS:Bacteria,Catalysts,Chemical reactions,Fourier transforms,Iron Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author>Chao Liu, Jiacheng Ji, Yi Zhang, Wen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i004_1771303</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391879670

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i004_1771303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i004_1771304</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391882672

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i004_1771304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of Toxin-Degrading Enzymes with Positive Unlabeled Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04461</link>
      <description>Dachuan Zhang, Huadong Xing, Dongliang Li, Mengying Han, Pengli Cai, Huikang Lin, Yu Tian, Y. Jay Guo, Bin Sun, Yingying Le, Ye Tian, Aibo Wu, Qian-Nan Hu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391883895

                Identifying functional enzymes for the catalysis of specific biochemical reactions is a major bottleneck in the de novo design of biosynthesis and biodegradation pathways. Conventional methods based on microbial screening and functional metagenomics require long verification periods and incur high experimental costs; recent data-driven methods apply only to a few common substrates. To enable rapid and high-throughput identification of enzymes for complex and less-studied substrates, we propose a robust enzyme&#8217;s substrate promiscuity prediction model based on positive unlabeled learning. Using this model, we identified 15 new degrading enzymes specific for the mycotoxins ochratoxin A and zearalenone, of which six could degrade &gt;90% mycotoxin content within 3 h. We anticipate that this model will serve as a useful tool for identifying new functional enzymes and understanding the nature of biocatalysis, thereby advancing the fields of synthetic biology, metabolic engineering, and pollutant biodegradation.</description>
      <author>Dachuan Zhang, Huadong Xing, Dongliang Li, Mengying Han, Pengli Cai, Huikang Lin, Yu Tian, Y. Jay Guo, Bin Sun, Yingying Le, Ye Tian, Aibo Wu, Qian-Nan Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04461</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
