<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 01:22:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Tetrahydroxybenzoquinone-Based Two-Dimensional Conductive Metal&#8211;Organic Framework via &#960;-d Conjugation Modulation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04977</link>
      <description>Yantao Wang, Xiaowan Bai, Junfeng Huang, Wangzu Li, Jinhua Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403671924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yantao Wang, Xiaowan Bai, Junfeng Huang, Wangzu Li, Jinhua Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Low-Temperature CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Methanation Activity on Ru/Anatase-TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Via Mn Doping: Revealing the Crucial Role of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Dissociation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03801</link>
      <description>Shaorong Deng, Zijian Qian, Chen Zhu, Baochang Cheng, Wei Wang, Xiuzhong Fang, Xianglan Xu, Xiang Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403673434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaorong Deng, Zijian Qian, Chen Zhu, Baochang Cheng, Wei Wang, Xiuzhong Fang, Xianglan Xu, Xiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unified Enantioselective Allylations and Vinylogous Reactions Enabled by Visible Light-Driven Chiral Lewis Acid Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04638</link>
      <description>Fuyuan Li, Fang&#8208;Hua Liu, Xiaowei Zhao, Yanli Yin, Bin Yu, Junmin Zhang, Zhiyong Jiang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403682881

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fuyuan Li, Fang&#8208;Hua Liu, Xiaowei Zhao, Yanli Yin, Bin Yu, Junmin Zhang, Zhiyong Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autocatalytic Activation of a Ruthenium-PNN-Pincer Hydrogenation Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04475</link>
      <description>Jose Fernando Carbajal Perez, Fallyn Kirlin, Eamon F. Reynolds, Cole Jarczyk, Benjamin T. Joseph, Jason M. Keith, A. Chianese, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403683083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jose Fernando Carbajal Perez, Fallyn Kirlin, Eamon F. Reynolds, Cole Jarczyk, Benjamin T. Joseph, Jason M. Keith, A. Chianese</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique Electron Donor&#8211;Acceptor Complex Conformation Ensures Both the Efficiency and Enantioselectivity of Photoinduced Radical Cyclization in a Non-natural Photoenzyme</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05046</link>
      <description>Matteo Capone, Gianluca Dell&#8217;Orletta, Claire G. Page, Todd K. Hyster, Gregory D. Scholes, Isabella Daidone, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403683096

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matteo Capone, Gianluca Dell&#8217;Orletta, Claire G. Page, Todd K. Hyster, Gregory D. Scholes, Isabella Daidone</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Palladium Structures on Ceria Obtained by Tuning Pd&#8211;Pd Distance for Efficient Methane Combustion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04985</link>
      <description>Weiwei Yang, Haohong Song, Lihua Zhang, Junyan Zhang, Felipe Polo&#8208;Garzon, Haodong Wang, Harry M. Meyer, De&#8208;en Jiang, Zili Wu, Yuanyuan Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403686341

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiwei Yang, Haohong Song, Lihua Zhang, Junyan Zhang, Felipe Polo&#8208;Garzon, Haodong Wang, Harry M. Meyer, De&#8208;en Jiang, Zili Wu, Yuanyuan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04985</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Mechanisms and Applications of Single Atom Catalysts for Thermal-Catalytic Carbon Dioxide Hydrogenation Toward Oxygenates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06065</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Yicheng Liu, Mengke Peng, Mengyao Yang, Yuanyuan Chen, Juan Du, Aibing Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403686886

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Yicheng Liu, Mengke Peng, Mengyao Yang, Yuanyuan Chen, Juan Du, Aibing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Activity on Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C and Promoting C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Product by Grain Boundary Engineering: Insights from First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03202</link>
      <description>Yuxing Lin, Fang-Qi Yu, Lei Li, Yameng Li, Rao Huang, Yu&#8208;Hua Wen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403687778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxing Lin, Fang-Qi Yu, Lei Li, Yameng Li, Rao Huang, Yu&#8208;Hua Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Nucleic Acid Enzymes: Nucleic Acid-Based Catalytic Factories</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02670</link>
      <description>Min Yang, Yushi Xie, Longjiao Zhu, Xiangyang Li, Wentao Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403689350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Yang, Yushi Xie, Longjiao Zhu, Xiangyang Li, Wentao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Chemical and Catalytic Activity of Metal Surface Sites by Controlling Strain and Ligand Effects in Nonmodel Nanoparticle Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03857</link>
      <description>Bill Yan, Suljo Linic, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403692782

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bill Yan, Suljo Linic</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Reduction of Carbon Monoxide to Liquid Fuels with Recyclable Hydride Donors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05083</link>
      <description>Javier J. Concepcion, Renato N. Sampaio, Gerald J. Meyer, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403715975

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Javier J. Concepcion, Renato N. Sampaio, Gerald J. Meyer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvent-Free Benzyl Alcohol Oxidation Using Spatially Separated Carbon-Supported Au and Pd Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05019</link>
      <description>Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Liang Zhao, Mark Douthwaite, Kai Wang, Ouardia Akdim, Isaac T. Daniel, Rena Oh, Lei Liu, Zhe Wang, Fanhui Meng, Samuel Pattisson, &#193;ngeles L&#243;pez&#8208;Mart&#237;n, Jian Yang, Xiaoyang Huang, Richard J. Lewis, Graham J. Hutchings, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403732761

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Liang Zhao, Mark Douthwaite, Kai Wang, Ouardia Akdim, Isaac T. Daniel, Rena Oh, Lei Liu, Zhe Wang, Fanhui Meng, Samuel Pattisson, &#193;ngeles L&#243;pez&#8208;Mart&#237;n, Jian Yang, Xiaoyang Huang, Richard J. Lewis, Graham J. Hutchings</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Temperature Dependence of Titania Photocatalysis: Kinetic Competition between Water Oxidation Catalysis and Back Electron&#8211;Hole Recombination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03685</link>
      <description>Yohei Cho, Tianhao He, Benjamin Moss, Daniele Benetti, Caiwu Liang, Lei Tian, Lucy J. F. Hart, Anna A. Wilson, Y. Taniguchi, Junyi Cui, Mengya Yang, Salvador Eslava, Akira Yamaguchi, Masahiro Miyauchi, James R. Durrant, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403733579

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yohei Cho, Tianhao He, Benjamin Moss, Daniele Benetti, Caiwu Liang, Lei Tian, Lucy J. F. Hart, Anna A. Wilson, Y. Taniguchi, Junyi Cui, Mengya Yang, Salvador Eslava, Akira Yamaguchi, Masahiro Miyauchi, James R. Durrant</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Carbene-Directed Intramolecular Vinylogous Reactions of Vinyldiazoacetates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05839</link>
      <description>Marlyn S. Rada, Dmitry M. Bystrov, Diana Victoria Navarrete Carriola, Daniel Wherritt, Michael P. Doyle, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403750908

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marlyn S. Rada, Dmitry M. Bystrov, Diana Victoria Navarrete Carriola, Daniel Wherritt, Michael P. Doyle</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Ir&lt;sup&gt;III&lt;/sup&gt; Photosensitizer Incorporated in the Metal&#8211;Organic Framework with the Bis-lophine-bipyridine Motif for C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)-C/N&#8211;H Cross-Coupling Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04666</link>
      <description>Yuan Chen, Ao-gang Liu, Zi-Tong Chen, Xiao&#8208;Huan Liang, Juntao Yan, Bao Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403760602

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan Chen, Ao-gang Liu, Zi-Tong Chen, Xiao&#8208;Huan Liang, Juntao Yan, Bao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce Promotion of In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Electrochemical Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02619</link>
      <description>Tim Wissink, Floriane A. Rollier, Valery Muravev, Jason M. J. J. Heinrichs, Rim C. J. van de Poll, Jiadong Zhu, Dimitra Anastasiadou, Nikolay Kosinov, Marta C. Figueiredo, Emiel J. M. Hensen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403762662

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tim Wissink, Floriane A. Rollier, Valery Muravev, Jason M. J. J. Heinrichs, Rim C. J. van de Poll, Jiadong Zhu, Dimitra Anastasiadou, Nikolay Kosinov, Marta C. Figueiredo, Emiel J. M. Hensen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02619</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of LiOH in Aqueous Electrocatalytic Defluorination of Perfluorooctanoic Sulfonate: Efficient Li&#8211;F Ion Pairing Prevents Anode Fouling by Produced Fluoride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04523</link>
      <description>Ziyi Meng, Madeleine K. Wilsey, Astrid M. Mueller, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403768680

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyi Meng, Madeleine K. Wilsey, Astrid M. Mueller</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Catalyzed Regio- and Stereoselective Hydroalkylation of Allenes: Exploiting the Unique Reactivity of Diazo Compounds as an Alkylating Source</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05410</link>
      <description>Ujjwal Karmakar, Jae&#8208;Han Bae, Jin A. Kim, Seoyeon Kim, Won&#8208;Geun Yang, Eun Jin Cho, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403774607

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ujjwal Karmakar, Jae&#8208;Han Bae, Jin A. Kim, Seoyeon Kim, Won&#8208;Geun Yang, Eun Jin Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Different Roles of Adsorbed Oxygen and Lattice Oxygen Species in the Distinct Catalytic Performance of Metal Oxides for &lt;i&gt;o&lt;/i&gt;-Xylene Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04284</link>
      <description>Ying Ma, Lian Wang, Jinzhu Ma, Guangzhi He, Daiqiang Li, Hong He, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403784543

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Ma, Lian Wang, Jinzhu Ma, Guangzhi He, Daiqiang Li, Hong He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04284</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Impact of Sn Lewis Acid Sites on the Dehydration of Cyclohexanol&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05977</link>
      <description>Karen A. Resende, Ruixue Zhao, Yue Liu, Eszter Bar&#225;th, Johannes A. Lercher, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403813756

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karen A. Resende, Ruixue Zhao, Yue Liu, Eszter Bar&#225;th, Johannes A. Lercher</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closing the Loop of Cyclopolymerization of Nonconjugated &#945;,&#969;-Diolefin Diasteroselectivity and &#945;-Olefin Polymerization Enantioselectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05020</link>
      <description>Olga D&#8217;Anania, Fabio De Stefano, Claudio De Rosa, Giovanni Talarico, Rocco Di Girolamo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403839947

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Olga D&#8217;Anania, Fabio De Stefano, Claudio De Rosa, Giovanni Talarico, Rocco Di Girolamo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stereodivergent Synthesis of Atropisomeric Indole-Fused &#948;-Lactams Bearing All-Carbon Quaternary Stereocenters via Cu-Catalyzed Desymmetric Arene Amidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04504</link>
      <description>Bo&#8208;Han Zhu, Yu-Jie Ye, Guanzhi Liu, Shuyin Wu, Xiu-Yuan Zou, Long Li, Chengzhe Huang, Qing Sun, Long&#8208;Wu Ye, Peng&#8208;Cheng Qian, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403840106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo&#8208;Han Zhu, Yu-Jie Ye, Guanzhi Liu, Shuyin Wu, Xiu-Yuan Zou, Long Li, Chengzhe Huang, Qing Sun, Long&#8208;Wu Ye, Peng&#8208;Cheng Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect-Rich Carbon-Blocked Delocalized Sulfur Quantum Dots for Efficient Catalytic Acetylene Hydrochlorination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04906</link>
      <description>Renqin Chang, Guangyu Cheng, Tao Feng, Saisai Wang, Jiale Huang, Yu&#8208;Chen Zhang, Chunxiao Jin, Yili Yue, Yuxue Yue, Xiao&#8208;Nian Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403852868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Renqin Chang, Guangyu Cheng, Tao Feng, Saisai Wang, Jiale Huang, Yu&#8208;Chen Zhang, Chunxiao Jin, Yili Yue, Yuxue Yue, Xiao&#8208;Nian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Manganese-Based Catalysts for the Oxidative Dehydrogenation of Propane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06021</link>
      <description>Carly Byron, Patricia Anne Ignacio-de Leon, Jacob T. Bryant, Ryan R. Langeslay, Louisa Savereide, Jianguo Wen, Jeffrey Camacho-Bunquin, Justin M. Notestein, Massimiliano Delferro, Magali Ferrandon, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403862583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Carly Byron, Patricia Anne Ignacio-de Leon, Jacob T. Bryant, Ryan R. Langeslay, Louisa Savereide, Jianguo Wen, Jeffrey Camacho-Bunquin, Justin M. Notestein, Massimiliano Delferro, Magali Ferrandon</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06021</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
