<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 01:04:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Low-Temperature Syngas Production via Surface Tailoring of Supported Intermetallic Nanocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01180</link>
      <description>Olusola Johnson, Yurong He, Isabella St. Pierre-Charles, J. Richter, Babu Joseph, John N. Kuhn, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396617198

                An active and coke-resistant silica-encapsulated intermetallic Ni3Zn nanoparticle catalyst was developed for low-temperature (450 &#176;C) dry reforming of methane (DRM). The catalyst exhibited a remarkable 4-fold increase in activity (4.5 s&#8211;1) with over 99% CO selectivity and 3 orders of magnitude less carbonaceous species and demonstrated remarkable stability (70 h) compared to that of a monometallic Ni catalyst. The key is the combined effect of surface ensemble structure and electronic interaction modulation through the surface composition tailoring achieved by off-stoichiometric Ni and Zn loading in controlling surface chemistry for achieving different activities and H2/CO ratios. Characterized by ion spectroscopy, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, and the neutron pair distribution function, it was revealed that paired Ni&#948;&#8722;&#8211;Zn&#948;+ active sites are crucial for DRM. Transient infrared spectroscopy and isotopic analysis uncovered the synergistic effect of Ni&#948;&#8722;&#8211;Zn&#948;+ sites in activating C&#8211;H bonds and dissociating CO2 to prevent coke formation under low-temperature conditions.</description>
      <author>Olusola Johnson, Yurong He, Isabella St. Pierre-Charles, J. Richter, Babu Joseph, John N. Kuhn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Covalent Organic Frameworks with Redox-Active Catechol Moieties for High-Performance Overall Photosynthesis of Hydrogen Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01411</link>
      <description>Shufan Feng, Hao Cheng, Feng Chen, Xinman Liu, Zhiqiang Wang, Hangxun Xu, Jianli Hua, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396617229

                Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) have emerged as promising candidates for solar-driven photosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2), yet the development of high-performance COFs tailored for practical applications presents substantial challenges. This research introduces the integration of the redox-active catechol moiety into a series of COFs (TPE-COF-OH, TPB-COF-OH, and TPP-COF-OH), serving as the pivotal active site for photocatalytic oxygen (O2) reduction to H2O2 through a reversible catechol-quinone interconversion mechanism. This process facilitates the transformation of catechol to o-benzoquinone in the presence of molecular O2, while photoexcited electrons are utilized to revert o-benzoquinone to catechol, reducing the energy barrier for H2O2 synthesis. Notably, TPB-COF-OH demonstrates an unparalleled H2O2 production rate of 6608 &#956;mol h&#8211;1 g&#8211;1, outperforming its molecular counterpart, TPB-COF-OMe, which lacks the redox-active catechol unit. Furthermore, TPB-COF-OH achieves a solar-to-chemical conversion efficiency of 0.84%, marking the highest value among COF-based photocatalysts in solar-driven H2O2 production. This investigation not only underscores the critical role of molecular engineering in enhancing COF performance but also broadens the horizon for solar-to-chemical energy conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Shufan Feng, Hao Cheng, Feng Chen, Xinman Liu, Zhiqiang Wang, Hangxun Xu, Jianli Hua</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i009_1797488</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396623784

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i009_1797488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i009_1797487</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396623887

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i009_1797487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buffer-Induced Electrocatalytic Nitrite Reduction: Impact on Catalytic Rate and Product Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05583</link>
      <description>Sheyda Partovi, Evan Z. Dalton, Jeremy M. Smith, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396626175

                The complex [Co(CR)Br2]+, where CR is the redox-active macrocycle 2,12-dimethyl-3,7,11,17-tetraazabicyclo-[11.3.1]-heptadeca-1(17),2,11,13,15-pentaene, is known as an electrocatalyst for the reduction of aqueous nitrite (NO2&#8211;). Here, we report that buffer induces a catalytic wave for NO2&#8211; reduction at a significantly more anodic potential than under unbuffered conditions. In addition, buffer increases the rate of electrocatalysis. This enhanced electrocatalytic activity is enabled by a number of buffering agents, with 3-(N-morpholino)propanesulfonic acid showing the largest catalytic current. In addition to the greater catalytic activity, buffering agents influence the selectivity of the reduction products, as well as catalyst longevity.</description>
      <author>Sheyda Partovi, Evan Z. Dalton, Jeremy M. Smith</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methane Activation through Single-Electron Transfer from Water Molecules to the Surface States of Semiconductor Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00984</link>
      <description>Fumiaki Amano, Kosuke Beppu, Yoshihisa Sakata, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396636838

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fumiaki Amano, Kosuke Beppu, Yoshihisa Sakata</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-Selective C&#8211;H Arylation of 2-Pyridones via Pd/NBE Cooperative Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00690</link>
      <description>Zengguo Sun, Zhuhan Jiang, Feng He, Chenyue Li, Hai Xiong, Dan Yang, Hui Miao, Qinglin Li, Jinxiang Ye, Ching-Yong Wu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396604944

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zengguo Sun, Zhuhan Jiang, Feng He, Chenyue Li, Hai Xiong, Dan Yang, Hui Miao, Qinglin Li, Jinxiang Ye, Ching-Yong Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Catalytic and Oxygen Release Capability in LaFe&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; to Intensify Chemical Looping Reactions at Medium Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01386</link>
      <description>Rongjiang Zhang, Gen Liu, Chunyong Huo, Lijun Jia, Bo Zhang, Bolun Yang, Xiaoyong Tian, Zhiqiang Wu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396645619

                Perovskite oxygen carriers in a methane chemical looping partial oxidation process enable high reactivity over 850 &#176;C. Lowering the reaction temperature helps to circumvent energy dissipation and couple the above-mentioned process with energy-efficient systems. This paper demonstrates the attractive oxygen-donating capacity of Fe&#8211;Ni-based perovskite oxygen carriers for methane partial oxidation. The aforesaid process exhibits more than 70% methane conversion and 6.71 mmol&#183;g&#8211;1 unit syngas yield at 700 &#176;C, using LaFe0.5Ni0.5O3. This impressive high reactivity mainly originates from the lowered lattice oxygen bonding strength and the spontaneously constructed active Ni-rich surface of perovskite oxides by Ni doping. In addition to the outward migration of lattice oxygen, active metal elements, such as Ni, continuously segregate to the surface with the reduction of perovskite oxides, promoting methane partial oxidation. We speculate that the chemical looping reaction pathway consists of consecutive competitive reactions based on analysis of the real-time product distribution and the dynamic evolution of oxygen carriers. Highly selective syngas production can be achieved on LaFe0.5Ni0.5O3 by reducing reaction temperatures or increasing space velocity to balance methane dissociation and lattice oxygen release kinetics. Irreversible Ni segregation and phase-separation-induced inert La2O3 on the surface of perovskite oxides during redox cycles are responsible for the cyclic performance degradation of oxygen carriers. This work offers intriguing references to design perovskite oxygen carriers for intensifying the medium-temperature chemical looping partial oxidation process.</description>
      <author>Rongjiang Zhang, Gen Liu, Chunyong Huo, Lijun Jia, Bo Zhang, Bolun Yang, Xiaoyong Tian, Zhiqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01386</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partial Oxidation of Methanol on Gold: How Selectivity Is Steered by Low-Coordinated Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04578</link>
      <description>Salma Eltayeb, Lenard L Carroll, Lukas Dippel, Mersad Mostaghimi, Wiebke Riedel, Lyudmila V. Moskaleva, Thomas Risse, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396665108

                Partial methanol oxidation proceeds with high selectivity to methyl formate (MeFo) on nanoporous gold (npAu) catalysts. As low-coordinated sites on npAu were suggested to affect the selectivity, we experimentally investigated their role in the isothermal selectivity for flat Au(111) and stepped Au(332) model surfaces using a molecular beam approach under well-defined conditions. Direct comparison shows that steps enhance desired MeFo formation and lower undesired overoxidation. DFT calculations reveal differences in oxygen distribution that enhance the barriers to overoxidation at steps. Thus, these results provide an atomic-level understanding of factors controlling the complex reaction network on gold catalysts, such as npAu.</description>
      <author>Salma Eltayeb, Lenard L Carroll, Lukas Dippel, Mersad Mostaghimi, Wiebke Riedel, Lyudmila V. Moskaleva, Thomas Risse</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Electric Fields Drives the Proton-Coupled Electron Transfer within Cytochrome P450 Reductase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02215</link>
      <description>Ningning Li, Shengheng Yan, Peng Wu, Junfeng Li, Binju Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396665466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ningning Li, Shengheng Yan, Peng Wu, Junfeng Li, Binju Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Requirements for Selectivity Enhancement During Forced Dynamic Operation of the Oxidative Dehydrogenation of Ethane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06066</link>
      <description>Austin Morales, Michael P. Harold, Praveen Bollini, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396665961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Austin Morales, Michael P. Harold, Praveen Bollini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piezocatalytic Performances of Conjugated Microporous Polymers with Donor&#8211;Acceptor Structures for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00918</link>
      <description>Jianping Chen, Lu Xie, Wan-Hong Huang, Ling Niu, Qing&#8208;Ling Ni, T. Huang, Liu-Cheng Gui, Xiu&#8208;Jian Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396666388

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianping Chen, Lu Xie, Wan-Hong Huang, Ling Niu, Qing&#8208;Ling Ni, T. Huang, Liu-Cheng Gui, Xiu&#8208;Jian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intermolecular Allene&#8211;Alkyne Coupling: A Significantly Useful Synthetic Transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01333</link>
      <description>Tapas R. Pradhan, Jin Kyoon Park, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396668677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tapas R. Pradhan, Jin Kyoon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liquid Metal-Assisted Acylation of Phenols over Zeolite Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00104</link>
      <description>Zhou Yong, Geqian Fang, Deizi V. Peron, Maya Marinova, Vladimir L. Zholobenko, Andre&#239; Y. Khodakov, Vitaly V. Ordomsky, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396669250

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhou Yong, Geqian Fang, Deizi V. Peron, Maya Marinova, Vladimir L. Zholobenko, Andre&#239; Y. Khodakov, Vitaly V. Ordomsky</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO to Isonitrile Substitution in Iron Cyclopentadienone Complexes: A Class of Active Iron Catalysts for Borrowing Hydrogen Strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01506</link>
      <description>Ga&#235;tan Quintil, L&#233;a Diebold, Gibrael Fadel, Jacques P&#233;caut, Christian Philouze, Martin Cl&#233;mancey, Genevi&#232;ve Blondin, Ragnar Bj&#246;rnsson, Adrien Quintard, Am&#233;lie Kochem, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396671481

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ga&#235;tan Quintil, L&#233;a Diebold, Gibrael Fadel, Jacques P&#233;caut, Christian Philouze, Martin Cl&#233;mancey, Genevi&#232;ve Blondin, Ragnar Bj&#246;rnsson, Adrien Quintard, Am&#233;lie Kochem</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Nickel-Catalyzed Carbon&#8211;Oxygen Cross-Coupling of (Hetero)aryl Halides with Alcohols Enabled by the Use of a Silane Reductant Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01283</link>
      <description>Liu Yang, Haijun Jiao, Geyang Song, Yanru Huang, Nan Ji, Xue Duan, Wei He, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396674501

                Herein, we disclose a highly efficient thermal Ni-catalyzed C&#8211;O cross-coupling of aryl halides with primary and secondary alcohols, without the need for photo- or electrocatalysis. The protocol is simple and has a wide substrate scope, particularly for challenging electron-rich aryl halides. Additionally, this methodology has been successfully applied to the late-stage functionalization of drugs and natural products, as well as the synthesis of pharmaceuticals such as pramoxine and the delamanid key intermediate. Preliminary mechanistic studies suggest the in situ generation of active Ni(I) species from inexpensive NiBr2-bipyridine and PhSiH3.</description>
      <author>Liu Yang, Haijun Jiao, Geyang Song, Yanru Huang, Nan Ji, Xue Duan, Wei He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01283</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Pt Single-Atom and Cluster/FeOOH Synergistic Active Sites for Efficient Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01133</link>
      <description>Yong&#8208;Chao Zhang, Ming&#8208;Hui Zhao, Jian Wu, Yingnan Wang, Lufan Zheng, Fangwei Gu, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Jian Gao, Xiaodong Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396674745

                The design of efficient catalysts that synergistically promote *H2O decomposition, H2 formation, and desorption is critical to accelerate hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) kinetics but remains a significant challenge. Herein, we design an efficient catalyst of Pt/FeOOH@NiFe LDHs with Pt single-atom and cluster distribution induced by amorphous FeOOH. The Pt/FeOOH@NiFe LDHs with a low Pt content of 2 wt % exhibit ultralow HER overpotentials of 20 and 85 mV in alkaline media (5 and 40 mV in acidic media) to achieve the current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8211;2. The overpotentials of specific activity normalized by the electrochemically active surfaces (ECSA) are 100 mV@0.2 mA cmECSA&#8211;2 and 140 mV@0.4 mA cmECSA&#8211;2. The Tafel slope is 51 mV dec&#8211;1, and the HER process follows the Volmer-Hyrovsky mechanism. Moreover, the overall water splitting requires only low voltages of 1.46 V@10 mA cm&#8211;2 and 1.61 V@100 mA cm&#8211;2, which are better than most reported catalysts. Experimental and theoretical studies show that the amorphous FeOOH can induce the formation of Pt single-atom and cluster with electron redistribution, and the formed Pt single-atom and cluster/FeOOH synergistic active sites exhibit superior HER performance. The amorphous FeOOH in Pt/FeOOH@NiFe LDHs facilitates the adsorption and activation of H2O, and the Pt single-atom and cluster play a key role in the formation and desorption of H2, synergistically accelerating the HER kinetics.</description>
      <author>Yong&#8208;Chao Zhang, Ming&#8208;Hui Zhao, Jian Wu, Yingnan Wang, Lufan Zheng, Fangwei Gu, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Jian Gao, Xiaodong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combined Photocatalysis and Lewis Acid Catalysis Strategy for the Oxa-Pictet&#8211;Spengler Reactions of Ethers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01595</link>
      <description>Nao Tanaka, Sophia R. Mitton-Fry, Mi-Lim Hwang, Joshua Zhu, Karl A. Scheidt, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nao Tanaka, Sophia R. Mitton-Fry, Mi-Lim Hwang, Joshua Zhu, Karl A. Scheidt</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly(ionic liquid) Ionomers Help Prevent Active Site Aggregation, in Single-Site Oxygen Reduction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01418</link>
      <description>Silvia Favero, Alain Li, Mengnan Wang, Fahim Uddin, Bora Kuzuoglu, Arthur Georgeson, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Davood Nasrabadi, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396693235

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silvia Favero, Alain Li, Mengnan Wang, Fahim Uddin, Bora Kuzuoglu, Arthur Georgeson, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Davood Nasrabadi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethane Dehydrogenation to Ethylene: Engineering the Surface Structure of Pt-Based Alloy Catalysts to Tune the Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06100</link>
      <description>Lulu Ping, Mifeng Xue, Yuan Zhang, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396697728

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lulu Ping, Mifeng Xue, Yuan Zhang, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Near 100% Faradaic Efficiency of Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia on Symmetry-Broken Medium-Entropy-Alloy Metallene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00879</link>
      <description>Yuanbo Zhou, Lifang Zhang, Mengfan Wang, Zhi&#8208;Jun Zhu, Najun Li, Tao Qian, Chenglin Yan, Jianmei Lu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396698133

                Electrochemical nitrate reduction (NO3RR) offers an ecofriendly way for ammonia production. However, improving the sluggish kinetics of such a multistep reaction still remains challenging. Herein, an asymmetry strategy is proposed to adjust the charge distribution of the active centers on metallene by presenting novel symmetry-broken medium-entropy-alloy (MEA) metallene via heteroatom alloying. Benefiting from the maximized exposure of the well-regulated active sites, proof-of-concept PdCuCo MEA metallene delivers near 100% NH3 Faradaic efficiency in both neutral and alkaline electrolytes, along with a record-high NH3 yield rate over 532.5 mg h&#8211;1 mgcat&#8211;1. Moreover, it enables 99.7% conversion of nitrate from an industrial wastewater level of 6200 ppm to a drinkable water level. Detailed studies further revealed that charge redistribution is induced by the elemental electronegativity difference on symmetry-broken MEA metallene, which will weaken the N&#8211;O bond of *NO, thus reducing the energy barrier of the rate-determining step. Meanwhile, the competitive HER and the formation of NO2&#8211; are also hindered. We believe that our strategy proposed in this work will shed light on the design of efficient NO3RR catalysts to a more practical level.</description>
      <author>Yuanbo Zhou, Lifang Zhang, Mengfan Wang, Zhi&#8208;Jun Zhu, Najun Li, Tao Qian, Chenglin Yan, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Leverage in Activity and Stability toward CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to Formate over a Bismuth Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01519</link>
      <description>Wenbin Li, Chang Yu, Xin Tan, Yongwen Ren, Yafang Zhang, Song Chen, Yi Yang, Jieshan Qiu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720560

                The direct production of formate from CO2 over Bi-based catalysts offers a promising route for producing important chemicals using renewable electricity. Nevertheless, limited by the unstable structure and states of catalysts under electrochemical conditions, electroreduction of CO2 to formate is still facing a trade-off between activity and stability, especially at high current densities. Herein, we reported a metal&#8211;carbon interfacial modulation strategy to synthesize the cross-linked and defective carbon-modified Bi nanoparticle (Bi-DC) catalyst with a stable spatial structure and a unique CO2-philic and hydrophobic interface. As a result, the Bi-DC featured a remarkable ability for CO2 electroreduction to formate in a near neutral electrolyte (1 M KHCO3) and was even comparable to the CO2-to-formate activity in the strongly basic systems, along with a high partial current density and formation rate for formate of &#8722;378 mA cm&#8211;2 and 7 mmol cm&#8211;2 h&#8211;1, respectively. Also, it achieved a stable electrolysis for 120 h at 0.4 A in a membrane electrode assembly reactor and even operated stably at an industrial large current of 5 A. The carbon species promoted the reconstruction and dispersion of active component Bi, together with a spatial confinement effect that facilitated the formation of formate and achieved stable long-term electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Wenbin Li, Chang Yu, Xin Tan, Yongwen Ren, Yafang Zhang, Song Chen, Yi Yang, Jieshan Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B(C&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;F&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Catalyzed C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Alkylation of Tertiary Amines with Electron-Deficient Olefins: Determinants of Site Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01160</link>
      <description>Xin-Yue Zhou, Yuanhu Shao, Rui Guo, Yalin Zhang, Xiao&#8208;Song Xue, Xiao&#8208;Chen Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin-Yue Zhou, Yuanhu Shao, Rui Guo, Yalin Zhang, Xiao&#8208;Song Xue, Xiao&#8208;Chen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Urea Synthesis Rate on Ni Single-Atom Catalysts: The Impact of Acetonitrile Electrolyte in the Tandem CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction/Nucleophilic Addition Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01557</link>
      <description>Peize Li, Yan Wang, Xiaoju Yang, Yanbin Zhu, Zhiguo Zhang, Xuan Yang, Yan Shen, Mingkui Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396722222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peize Li, Yan Wang, Xiaoju Yang, Yanbin Zhu, Zhiguo Zhang, Xuan Yang, Yan Shen, Mingkui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01557</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Catalyzed Formal Dihydrosilylation of Terminal Alkynes: A C(sp)&#8211;H Silylation-Hydrosilylation-Hydrogenation Sequence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01813</link>
      <description>Jia Li, Siqiang Fang, Shaozhong Ge, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396722294

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Li, Siqiang Fang, Shaozhong Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Application of the Single-Module NRPS-like &lt;scp&gt;d&lt;/scp&gt;-Alanyltransferase in Maytansinol Biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00082</link>
      <description>Zhongyue Li, Zhangliang Zhu, Guangsen Xu, Wenhan Lin, Jiang Liu, Haoxin Wang, Ching&#8211;Liang Lu, Yaoyao Li, Deyu Zhu, Yuemao Shen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396723233

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongyue Li, Zhangliang Zhu, Guangsen Xu, Wenhan Lin, Jiang Liu, Haoxin Wang, Ching&#8211;Liang Lu, Yaoyao Li, Deyu Zhu, Yuemao Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics for Catalysis Predictions: Are We Ready Yet?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05285</link>
      <description>Difan Zhang, Brett Smith, Haiyi Wu, Manh&#8208;Thuong Nguyen, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki Alexandra Glezakou, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396729186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Difan Zhang, Brett Smith, Haiyi Wu, Manh&#8208;Thuong Nguyen, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki Alexandra Glezakou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambiphilic Alcohol Dehydrogenation by BICAAC Mimicking Metal&#8211;Ligand Cooperativity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01723</link>
      <description>Shishir Bansal, Ayanangshu Biswas, Abhishek Kundu, Manu Adhikari, Sanjay Singh, Debashis Adhikari, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396731701

                In this report, an unusual bond activation strategy has been demonstrated by BICAAC, which essentially emulates the behavior of a transition metal. The ambiphilic nature of this specific carbene has facilitated a simultaneous proton and hydride capture from an alcohol molecule to carry out smooth dehydrogenation under mild conditions. The activation route closely follows the traditional metal&#8211;ligand bifunctional activation of a substrate. The hydrogen molecule extracted from the substrate alcohol becomes stored in the carbene carbon, which has been unambiguously ascertained by the isolation of this intermediate and its X-ray crystallographic characterization. Such an event has further been interrogated in detail by the deuterium-labeling experiment and DFT computations to substantiate the critical role of carbene's ambiphilicity. Additionally, the stored hydrogen in the carbene molecule has been delivered to an in situ-generated olefinic bond to completely mimic a borrowing hydrogen reaction in an organocatalytic fashion. Both dehydrogenation and rehydrogenation reactions have been conducted in a single pot using BICAAC as the catalyst that alkylates fluorene at its 9-position using a series of alcohols as the alkyl source. A thorough mechanistic sketch describes the involvement of a radical for the latter part of the reaction, overall bringing a different outlook to carbene-promoted small-molecule activation reactions.</description>
      <author>Shishir Bansal, Ayanangshu Biswas, Abhishek Kundu, Manu Adhikari, Sanjay Singh, Debashis Adhikari</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#960;&#8211;&#960; Interactions-Driven Ethylene Polymerization Using &#8220;Sandwich&#8221; Bis(imino)pyridyl Iron Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01248</link>
      <description>Z.-Y. Cheng, Haiyang Gao, Zonglin Qiu, Handou Zheng, Donghui Li, Long Jiang, Haiyang Gao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396746889

                Weak noncovalent interactions are an effective strategy for modulating catalytic olefin polymerization but have never been observed in bis(imino)pyridyl iron catalysts. In this paper, a series of "sandwich" bis(imino)pyridyl iron complexes with substituted 8-(p-R-phenyl)naphthylamine (R = OMe, Me, H, CF3) were designed and synthesized for ethylene polymerization. The &#960;&#8211;&#960; interactions between the capping aryl groups and the pyridyl ring are clearly observed in "sandwich" bis(imino)pyridyl iron complexes by single crystal X-ray diffraction analysis, UV&#8211;vis, and photoluminescence (PL) spectra. The intramolecular &#960;&#8211;&#960; interactions make the naphthyl rings tilt away from the iron center in the horizontal direction, thereby causing a more open horizontal space within iron complexes for ethylene coordination. Ethylene polymerization results show that &#960;&#8211;&#960; interactions are a crucial driving force rather than the electronic effects of ligands. Unprecedentedly, bulky "sandwich" bis(imino)pyridyl iron catalysts produce low-molecular-weight PE with a bimodal distribution, which originates from &#946;-H transfer to monomer modulated by the &#960;&#8211;&#960; interactions. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations mechanistically demonstrate that the coordination of ethylene to the iron center is a crucial step in ethylene polymerization.</description>
      <author>Z.-Y. Cheng, Haiyang Gao, Zonglin Qiu, Handou Zheng, Donghui Li, Long Jiang, Haiyang Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bond Dissociation Energy-Controlled Regioselectivity in Hydrofunctionalization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00304</link>
      <description>Jie Peng, Xiaoqian He, Xiaoling Luo, Kangbao Zhong, Li&#8208;Li Liao, Ruopeng Bai, Yu Lan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396747447

                The bond dissociation energy (BDE) in reactants was found to be critical for determining the tunable pathways of low-valent tungsten-catalyzed chain-walking hydroboration and hydrogermylation of &#946;,&#947;-unsaturated amides, which is considered to be the key factor in the regioselective determination. Computational results revealed that the higher BDE of the H&#8211;B bond hampers the oxidative hydrogen migration, leading to borane reacting with tungsten later than alkenes. Thus, the generation of a &#946;-borylated product was found to be favorable through H&#8211;C&#946; bond oxidative addition, H&#8211;C&#948; bond reductive elimination, H&#8211;B bond oxidative hydrogen migration, and B&#8211;C&#946; bond reductive elimination. As a comparison, the lower BDE of H&#8211;Ge leads to a facile oxidative hydrogen migration of the H&#8211;Ge bond, which finally results in the formation of an &#945;-germylated product after germyl-assisted olefin walking. Further distortion&#8211;interaction analysis confirmed that the weak H&#8211;Ge bond was easier to distort for its reactions.</description>
      <author>Jie Peng, Xiaoqian He, Xiaoling Luo, Kangbao Zhong, Li&#8208;Li Liao, Ruopeng Bai, Yu Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00304</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
