<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:40:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Indole Synthesis by Cobalt-Catalyzed Intramolecular Amidation via the Oxidatively Induced Reductive Elimination Pathway</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05706</link>
      <description>Aleksandrs Cizikovs, Emils E. Basens, Paula A. Zagorska, Artis Kin&#275;ns, Liene Grigorjeva, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390938469

                C&#8211;H bond activation and functionalization using high-valent cobalt catalysis typically involves a Co(III)/Co(I) catalytic cycle. Because of the lack of evidence and challenges associated with the high reactivity and instability of Co(IV) intermediates, reports on the C&#8211;H functionalization mechanism investigation involving Co(IV) intermediacy are still underexplored. Herein, we report an efficient synthesis of indole-2-carboxylic esters via intramolecular amidation of &#945;-amidoacrylates and experimental and computational studies of the reaction mechanism, which involves oxidatively induced reductive elimination from Co(IV) species.</description>
      <author>Aleksandrs Cizikovs, Emils E. Basens, Paula A. Zagorska, Artis Kin&#275;ns, Liene Grigorjeva</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Hydrothermal Stability of Potential NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-SCR Catalyst Cu-KFI Zeolite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05155</link>
      <description>Zhongqi Liu, Yu Fu, Yulong Shan, Tongliang Zhang, Yingjie Wang, Junjie Du, Yangyang Sun, Guo&#8208;Zhong He, Hong He, Yunbo Yu, Hong He, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390938490

                Al-rich Cu-KFI was found to withstand hydrothermal aging (HTA) at 800 &#176;C, while Cu-CHA with a similar Si/Al ratio was deactivated since a much higher energy barrier was required to transform Cu2+ ions to CuOx during HTA in KFI. Specifically, the rate-determining step is the hydrolysis of Cu2+ in KFI but the cross-cage migration of Cu(OH)2 in CHA. Therefore, the inclusion of two Cu2+ ions in one repeat unit of KFI does not significantly promote CuOx production. However, the accumulated CuOx cannot be completely avoided under such severe hydrothermal aging. It may originate from Cu2+ in the same cage or adjacent cages. This shorter diffusion effectively mitigated the structural integrity deterioration of KFI in comparison to CHA. Nevertheless, HTA reduced the number as well as the reactivity of residual Cu2+ ions in Cu-KFI zeolite catalysts. Quantitative results determined that the activity and stability of the catalyst were maximized when the average lta cage contained about 1.4 Cu2+ ions.</description>
      <author>Zhongqi Liu, Yu Fu, Yulong Shan, Tongliang Zhang, Yingjie Wang, Junjie Du, Yangyang Sun, Guo&#8208;Zhong He, Hong He, Yunbo Yu, Hong He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron(I) and Iron(II) Amido-imidazolin-2-imine Complexes as Catalysts for H/D Exchange in Hydrosilanes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05355</link>
      <description>Noor U Din Reshi, Dirk Bockfeld, Dirk Baabe, Lars Denker, Jos&#233; Luis Garc&#237;a Mart&#237;nez, Bartosz Trzaskowski, Ren&#233; Frank, Matthias Tamm, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390966679

                The unsymmetrical amino-imidazolin-2-imine ligand [HAmIm, 1,2-(DippNH)&#8211;C6H4&#8211;N=C(NiPrCMe)2] is employed in the synthesis of the iron(I) arene complex [(AmIm)Fe(&#951;6-C6H6)] and the iron(II) neosilyl complex [(AmIm)Fe(CH2SiMe3)]. These compounds are highly efficient precatalysts in H/D exchange reactions with deuterium (D2) in hydrosilanes. The scope comprises primary to tertiary silanes at a catalyst loading of 1 mol % at ambient temperature. In-depth mechanistic studies including various control experiments and the syntheses of isolated iron-hydride and iron-silyl compounds are performed. These studies reveal that the activation of both Fe(I) and Fe(II) complexes generates Fe&#8211;H/D species as key catalytic intermediates. An alternative catalytic pathway involving an iron-silyl intermediate, although shown to be less feasible by DFT calculations, may also be operative.</description>
      <author>Noor U Din Reshi, Dirk Bockfeld, Dirk Baabe, Lars Denker, Jos&#233; Luis Garc&#237;a Mart&#237;nez, Bartosz Trzaskowski, Ren&#233; Frank, Matthias Tamm</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum&#8211;Nickel Alloy Nanowire Electrocatalysts Transform into Pt-Skin Beads-on-Nanowires Keeping Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity During Potential Cycling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04709</link>
      <description>Yu Zhou, Yoshimi Iguchi, Tianchi Li, Masaru Kato, Yasir Arafat Hutapea, Akari Hayashi, Takeshi Watanabe, Ichizo Yagi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390966737

                We synthesized PtNi alloy nanowires (PtNi NWs) at three different temperatures of 433, 494, and 533 K (NW433 K, NW494 K, and NW533 K, respectively) and then investigated their catalytic activity and durability for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in acidic media. Ni contents in the PtNi NWs increase as the synthesis temperatures increase from below 5 at. % for NW433 K up to about 15 at. % for NW493 K and NW553 K. PtNi nanoparticles (PtNi NPs), which are the unconsumed intermediate during the NW growth, also coexist for NW433 K and NW494 K but not for NW533 K. NW494 K and NW533 K show similar initial activity for the ORR but higher than NW433 K, suggesting that higher Ni contents are critical to achieving higher initial ORR activity. Accelerated durability tests (ADTs) show that NW493 K is the most durable, suggesting that the copresence of PtNi NPs is critical to durability. Only NW493 K, with a high Ni content of 15 at. % and coexisting PtNi NPs, gave better results in both cases. Scanning transmission electron microscopy and energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy of PtNi NWs reveal a structural transformation of NW493 K into Pt-skin beads-on-nanowires, involving the Ostwald ripening of coexisting PtNi NPs. This structural transformation is coupled with changes in surface composition and surface electronic structure, as confirmed by the CO stripping voltammogram and in situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy, resulting in high durability and suppression of Pt and Ni dissolution. Understanding such structural transformation during potential cycling will help us to design and develop highly active and durable Pt-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yu Zhou, Yoshimi Iguchi, Tianchi Li, Masaru Kato, Yasir Arafat Hutapea, Akari Hayashi, Takeshi Watanabe, Ichizo Yagi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Cascade Cyclization of Enynamides with Photogenerated Ketenes via Relay Gold and &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Oxide Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05731</link>
      <description>Dan Li&#250;, Zhen&#8208;Cao Shu, Zhihan Zhang, Ze-Tian Wang, Liang Wang, Ming&#8208;Sheng Xie, Hai&#8208;Ming Guo, Liang&#8208;Qiu Lu, Wen&#8208;Jing Xiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390974006

                An asymmetric cascade cyclization of enynamides and &#945;-diazoketones to produce chiral bicyclic lactams bearing chiral all-carbon quaternary stereocenters is realized with up to 95% yield, 98% ee, and &gt;19:1 dr. The combination of visible light photoactivation and the relay of gold and N-oxide catalysis in a cascade process enabled the facile generation and controlled assembly of two reactive intermediates, ketene and aza-o-quinone methide. Theoretical calculations revealed a stepwise [4 + 2] cycloaddition mechanism, with the stereochemistry controlled by the amide group of the catalyst. Remarkably, this study presents the first example of chiral N-oxides serving as catalysts for asymmetric ketene cycloaddition and illustrates how a cascade strategy could be a promising means to access significant chiral heterocyclic scaffolds.</description>
      <author>Dan Li&#250;, Zhen&#8208;Cao Shu, Zhihan Zhang, Ze-Tian Wang, Liang Wang, Ming&#8208;Sheng Xie, Hai&#8208;Ming Guo, Liang&#8208;Qiu Lu, Wen&#8208;Jing Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05731</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanadium-Containing Chloroperoxidase-Catalyzed Versatile Valorization of Phenols and Phenolic Acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05333</link>
      <description>Huanhuan Li, Pei-Gao Duan, Yue Huang, Chengsen Cui, Frank Hollmann, Yunjian Ma, Yonghua Wang, Jie Zhang, Weidong Liu, Wuyuan Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390974179

                The downstream product transformation of lignin depolymerization is of great interest in the production of high-value aromatic chemicals. However, this transformation is often impeded by chemical oxidation under harsh reaction conditions. In this study, we demonstrate that hypohalites generated in situ by the vanadium-containing chloroperoxidase from Curvularia inaequalis (CiVCPO) can halogenate various electron-rich and electron-poor phenol and phenolic acid substrates. Specifically, CiVCPO enabled decarboxylative halogenation, deformylative halogenation, halogenation, and direct oxidation reactions. The versatile transformation routes for the valorization of phenolic compounds showed up to 99% conversion and 99% selectivity, with a turnover number of 60,700 and a turnover frequency of 60 s&#8211;1 for CiVCPO. This study potentially expands the biocatalytic toolbox for lignin valorization.</description>
      <author>Huanhuan Li, Pei-Gao Duan, Yue Huang, Chengsen Cui, Frank Hollmann, Yunjian Ma, Yonghua Wang, Jie Zhang, Weidong Liu, Wuyuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Pd Atom&#8211;In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyzes Production of CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;CH&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;OH from Atom-Economic C&#8211;C Coupling of HCHO and CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05163</link>
      <description>Yuntao Zhao, Natalie Fontillas, Hua Wang, Xinli Zhu, Donghai Mei, Qingfeng Ge, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390974718

                Using methane as a reagent to synthesize high-value chemicals and high-energy density fuels through C&#8211;C coupling has attracted intense attention in recent decades, as it avoids completely breaking all C&#8211;H bonds in CH4. In the present study, we demonstrated that the coupling of HCHO with the CH3 species from CH4 activation to produce ethanol can be accomplished on the single Pd atom&#8211;In2O3 catalyst based on the results of density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The results show that the supported single Pd atom stabilizes the CH3 species following the activation of one C&#8211;H bond of CH4, while HCHO adsorbs on the neighboring In site. Facile C&#8211;C coupling of HCHO with the methyl species is achieved with an activation barrier of 0.56 eV. We further examined the C&#8211;C coupling on other single metal atoms, including Ni, Rh, Pt, and Ag, supported on In2O3 by following a similar pathway and found that a balance of the three key steps for ethanol formation, i.e., CH4 activation, C&#8211;C coupling, and ethoxy hydrogenation, was achieved on Pd/In2O3. Taking the production of acetaldehyde and ethylene on the Pd/In2O3 catalyst into consideration, the DFT-based microkinetic analysis indicates that ethanol is the dominant product on the Pd/In2O3 catalyst. The facile C&#8211;C coupling between HCHO and dissociated CH4 makes formaldehyde a potential C1 source in the conversion and utilization of methane through an energy- and atom-efficient process.</description>
      <author>Yuntao Zhao, Natalie Fontillas, Hua Wang, Xinli Zhu, Donghai Mei, Qingfeng Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently Enhanced Selectivity of Electrocatalyzing Ethanol to High Value-Added Acetaldehyde Through Tuning the Cobalt Valence State</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03326</link>
      <description>Yintong Zhang, Junhao Wu, Tao Li, H.J. Li, Yongcai Zhang, Xuepeng Wu, Yong Zhou, Zhigang Zou, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390975321

                Using electrochemical oxidation of alcohols to substitute the oxygen evolution reaction is beneficial to reduce the energy consumption of hydrogen production. Converting alcohols into high value-added products with high efficiency and selectivity by designing a proper electrocatalyst is economical and has promising applications. In this work, two types of spinel cubic phase Co3O4 with different contents of oxygen vacancies were obtained by annealing the same precursor in air and argon gas atmosphere, respectively. The results of X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and in situ Raman spectra reveal that abundant Co4+ sites were formed on the surface of Co3O4&#8211;air under the electrocatalysis condition, while main Co3+ sites were formed on the surface of Co3O4&#8211;Ar. The electrocatalytic ethanol oxidation tests and density functional theory calculation reveal that the Co4+ sites exhibit more proper adsorption energy to the O&#9552;*CCH3 intermediate, which benefits the formation of high-value-added acetaldehyde products instead of common acetic acid products with a higher degree of oxidation. The Faradaic efficiency of the Co3O4&#8211;air catalyst to acetaldehyde achieves 60.02%, and the selectivity to acetaldehyde reaches 79.63% at an oxidation overpotential of 1.46 V. This work provides the possibility and guidance for electrochemical oxidation of alcohols into high value-added products.</description>
      <author>Yintong Zhang, Junhao Wu, Tao Li, H.J. Li, Yongcai Zhang, Xuepeng Wu, Yong Zhou, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Conversion of Lipid to Diesel and Syngas via Engineering the Surface Proton Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04818</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Chen, Hongru Zhou, Fangfang Kong, Zhaolin Dou, Min Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390977302

                Photocatalysis provides a promising pathway for the production of fuels and chemicals from biomass, where the slow proton reduction by surface-confined photoinduced electrons limits the efficiency. Herein, we propose to engineer the surface structure to facilitate the proton transfer on the catalyst surface and thus promote the proton reduction by the confined photoinduced electrons. We found introducing NH4+ on TiO2 (NH4&#8211;TiO2) could improve the proton conductivity. The NH4+ group effectively minimizes the proton transfer distance and promotes proton transfer by forming hydrogen-bond networks. Consequently, NH4&#8211;TiO2 shows a high yield of (&#8805;80%) alkanes from bio-derived fatty acids which is about 3.8 times that of pristine TiO2. Glycerol can be reformed to syngas with a generation rate [CO (0.69 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1)/H2 (0.21 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1)]. Moreover, industrial palm oil can be converted into 59% alkanes and syngas [4% CO and H2 (0.04 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1)] via a hydrolysis-photocatalysis two-step process. This work provides an efficient approach for biomass upgrading via a rationally controlled proton transfer process.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Chen, Hongru Zhou, Fangfang Kong, Zhaolin Dou, Min Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Catalyzed General and Selective &#945;-C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Silylation of Amides via 1,5-Hydrogen Atom Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05651</link>
      <description>Zheng Ji, Zhimin He, Sunwoo Kong, Ma Yin, Qianqian Du, Bao Lian Yi, Guozhu Zhang, R.T. Guo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390984822

                The development of a general and selective method for &#945;-C(sp3)&#8211;H silylation of feedstock amines has been a long-standing challenge. In this paper, we disclose a mild, general, practical, and highly regio- and diastereoselective &#945;-C(sp3)&#8211;H silylation of various readily available acyclic, cyclic, and aromatic amines with silylboranes through a copper-catalyzed intramolecular 1,5-hydrogen atom transfer (HAT) strategy. The mild activation of 2-iodobenzamide to generate an aryl radical enabled by a ligand-coordinated silyl copper complex without additional heating or photoinduced conditions, as well as the intramolecular selective 1,5-HAT process to produce the crucial &#945;-aminoalkyl radical species, is the key to the success of this chemistry. This silylation protocol has demonstrated its potential utility in the late-stage modification of structurally complex drugs and bioactive molecules. Therefore, it is expected that this method will find applications in synthetic chemistry and drug discovery.</description>
      <author>Zheng Ji, Zhimin He, Sunwoo Kong, Ma Yin, Qianqian Du, Bao Lian Yi, Guozhu Zhang, R.T. Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Selective Photocatalytic Methane Coupling by Au-Modified Bi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;WO&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05534</link>
      <description>Muchun Fei, Benjamin P. Williams, Lizhuo Wang, Haoyi Li, Yucheng Yuan, James R. Wilkes, Tianying Liu, Yu Mu, Jier Huang, James Nyakuchena, Jun Huang, Wei Li, Dunwei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391014312

                Photocatalytic oxidative coupling of methane (OCM) to ethane promises a route to value-added C2 products from an abundant and low-cost feedstock. However, selective activation of the C&#8211;H bond of CH4 without overoxidation to CO2 has been a major challenge. In this work, we present the use of Au-modified Bi2WO6 as a prototypical photocatalyst, demonstrating a high performance of OCM through photocatalysis. A C2H6 production rate at 1.69 &#215; 103 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8211;1&#183;h&#8211;1 with approximately 85% selectivity was achieved, which ranks among the top-performing photocatalytic OCM systems. Efforts were also made in establishing a correlation between improved OCM performance and the photocatalyst system by examining the nature of the oxide photocatalyst. Our findings indicated that oxygen within the oxide surface, likely from adsorbed and subsequently dissociated oxygen at the vacancy sites, afforded a desired reactivity to selectively activate the C&#8211;H bond without significant overoxidation. Surprisingly, it was revealed that the Au cocatalyst plays dual roles of activating the oxide photocatalyst for enhanced CH4 activation and promoting C&#8211;C coupling to yield C2H6 as the main product.</description>
      <author>Muchun Fei, Benjamin P. Williams, Lizhuo Wang, Haoyi Li, Yucheng Yuan, James R. Wilkes, Tianying Liu, Yu Mu, Jier Huang, James Nyakuchena, Jun Huang, Wei Li, Dunwei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05534</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Pot Sequential Two-Step Photo-Biocatalytic Deracemization of &lt;i&gt;sec&lt;/i&gt;-Alcohols Combining Photocatalytic Oxidation and Bioreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05100</link>
      <description>Aleksandra Rudzka, Natalia Antos, Tamara Reiter, Wolfgang Kroutil, Pawe&#322; Borowiecki, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391025463

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aleksandra Rudzka, Natalia Antos, Tamara Reiter, Wolfgang Kroutil, Pawe&#322; Borowiecki</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation with High Selectivity by Single Bi Atoms on MXenes Enabled by a Concerted Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04480</link>
      <description>Kaifeng Niu, Lin Chen, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391025688

                Developing efficient catalysts for the capture and direct conversion of CO2 into various chemicals is essential to alleviate CO2 emissions and minimize the negative environmental effects of fossil fuels. Combining density functional theory calculations and microkinetic analysis, we propose that single Bi atoms supported on V2CO2 MXenes (Bi@V2CO2) are promising single-atom catalysts (SAC) for CO2 hydrogenation. The catalytic performance of Bi SACs is ensured by the stable single-atom dispersion of Bi atoms on V2CO2 and enhanced adsorption of CO2. Of importance, Bi@V2CO2 exhibits remarkable selectivity toward the synthesis of formic acid (HCOOH), in which the main competing reaction, namely, the reverse water gas shift (RWGS) and the formation of CO, is strictly prohibited. In contrast to conventional Cu or In2O3 catalysts, CO2 hydrogenation exhibits a unique mechanism on Bi@V2CO2, in which the formic acid is directly generated via a concerted pathway. As a result, the formation of both intermediate HCOO and COOH is prevented, leading to high selectivity (nearly 100%) toward HCOOH on Bi@V2CO2. Moreover, analysis of the kinetic behavior suggests that the stabilization of HCOOH adsorption would be an effective approach to promote catalyst performance toward methanol synthesis.</description>
      <author>Kaifeng Niu, Lin Chen, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jonas Bj&#246;rk</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Oxygen Surface Coverage and Carbidic Carbon on the Activity and Selectivity of Two-Dimensional Molybdenum Carbide (2D-Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C) in Fischer&#8211;Tropsch Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03956</link>
      <description>Evgenia Kountoupi, Alan J. Barrios, Zixuan Chen, Christoph R. M&#252;ller, Vitaly V. Ordomsky, Aleix Comas&#8208;Vives, Alexey Fedorov, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391025708

                Transformations of oxygenates (CO2, CO, H2O, etc.) via Mo2C-based catalysts are facilitated by the high oxophilicity of the material; however, this can lead to the formation of oxycarbides and complicate the identification of the (most) active catalyst state and active sites. In this context, the two-dimensional (2D) MXene molybdenum carbide Mo2CTx (Tx are passivating surface groups) contains only surface Mo sites and is therefore a highly suitable model catalyst for structure&#8211;activity studies. Here, we report that the catalytic activity of Mo2CTx in Fischer&#8211;Tropsch (FT) synthesis increases with a decreasing coverage of surface passivating groups (mostly O*). The in situ removal of Tx species and its consequence on CO conversion is highlighted by the observation of a very pronounced activation of Mo2CTx (pretreated in H2 at 400 &#176;C) under FT conditions. This activation process is ascribed to the in situ reductive defunctionalization of Tx groups reaching a catalyst state that is close to 2D-Mo2C (i.e., a material containing no passivating surface groups). Under steady-state FT conditions, 2D-Mo2C yields higher hydrocarbons (C5+ alkanes) with 55% selectivity. Alkanes up to the kerosine range form, with value of &#945; = 0.87, which is ca. twice higher than the &#945; value reported for 3D-Mo2C catalysts. The steady-state productivity of 2D-Mo2C to C5+ hydrocarbons is ca. 2 orders of magnitude higher relative to a reference &#946;-&#924;o2C catalyst that shows no in situ activation under identical FT conditions. The passivating Tx groups of Mo2CTx can be reductively defunctionalized also by using a higher H2 pretreatment temperature of 500 &#176;C. Yet, this approach leads to a removal of carbidic carbon (as methane), resulting in a 2D-Mo2C1&#8211;x catalyst that converts CO to CH4 with 61% selectivity in preference to C5+ hydrocarbons that are formed with only 2% selectivity. Density functional theory (DFT) results attribute the observed selectivity of 2D-Mo2C to C5+ alkanes to a higher energy barrier for the hydrogenation of surface alkyl species relative to the energy barriers for C&#8211;C coupling. The removal of O* is the rate-determining step in the FT reaction over 2D-Mo2C, and O* is favorably removed in the form of CO2 relative to H2O, consistent with the observation of a high CO2 selectivity (ca. 50%). The absence of other carbon oxygenates is explained by the energetic favoring of the direct over the hydrogen-assisted dissociative adsorption of CO.</description>
      <author>Evgenia Kountoupi, Alan J. Barrios, Zixuan Chen, Christoph R. M&#252;ller, Vitaly V. Ordomsky, Aleix Comas&#8208;Vives, Alexey Fedorov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partially Bonded Aluminum Site on the External Surface of Post-treated Au/ZSM-5 Enhances Methane Oxidation to Oxygenates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05030</link>
      <description>Jun Cao, Guodong Qi, Bingqing Yao, Qian He, Richard J. Lewis, Lu Xu, Feng Deng, Jun Xu, Graham J. Hutchings, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391026262

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Cao, Guodong Qi, Bingqing Yao, Qian He, Richard J. Lewis, Lu Xu, Feng Deng, Jun Xu, Graham J. Hutchings</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu/Au(111) Surfaces and AuCu Intermetallics for Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in Ionic Liquid Electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04592</link>
      <description>Bj&#246;rn Ratschmeier, Christian Paulsen, Klaus Stallberg, Gina Ro&#223;, W. Daum, Rainer P&#246;ttgen, Bj&#246;rn Braunschweig, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391029986

                Room-temperature ionic liquids (RTIL) are important alternatives to aqueous electrolytes in electrocatalytic reactions, batteries, and fuel cells. They are known to reduce existing high overpotentials and increase CO2 solubility as well as product selectivity in CO2 reduction reactions (CO2RR). In our work, we have studied the activity for CO2RR of Au(111), Cu(111), and Cu-modified Au(111) electrodes with 1/3, 2/3, and 3/3 Cu monolayers, as well as of AuCu and AuCu3 intermetallics in contact with 1-butyl-3-methylimidazolium bis(trifluoromethylsulfonyl)imide [BMIM][NTf2] electrolytes with 1.5 M H2O. Using offline gas chromatography (GC), we demonstrate the formation of H2 and mainly CO as the only reduction products at Au(111), while exclusively H2 is formed at Cu(111). Synergistic electronic and geometric effects lead to higher levels of CO formation at Cu-modified Au(111) electrodes in comparison to neat Au(111). Operando IR absorption spectroscopy (IRAS) of the bulk electrolyte shows the formation of a 2-imidazolium carboxylic acid intermediate that can lower the overpotential for CO2 reduction and does not require stabilization of a CO2&#8211; radical anion as an alternative intermediate at the interface. Systematic variation of the copper content at the catalysts&#8217; surfaces enables us to adjust the H2/CO syngas ratio to a maximum of 1.8 for Cu-modified Au(111) electrodes and &#8764;3.2 for AuCu3 catalysts at electrolysis times of 20 min, demonstrating a large tunability of the syngas ratio with electrode potential. The observed range of H2/CO ratios includes the ideal ratio of 2 for the Fischer&#8211;Tropsch process to produce hydrocarbons and the ratio of 3 needed for methanation.</description>
      <author>Bj&#246;rn Ratschmeier, Christian Paulsen, Klaus Stallberg, Gina Ro&#223;, W. Daum, Rainer P&#246;ttgen, Bj&#246;rn Braunschweig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761788</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391030911

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ISSUEPREVArticleNEXTIssue Editorial MastheadCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 2, XXX-XXXPublication Date (Web):January 19, 2024Publication History Published online19 January 2024Published inissue 19 January 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761788Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyRequest reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InReddit PDF (198 KB) Get e-Alertsclose Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Full Dynamical and Reactivity Profiles of Acetylcholinesterase: A Comprehensive All-Atom Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05560</link>
      <description>Fr&#233;deric C&#233;lerse, Louis Lagard&#232;re, Yasmine Bouchibti, Florian Nachon, Laurent Verdier, Jean&#8208;Philip Piquemal, &#201;tienne Derat, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391030933

                Acetylcholinesterase is one of the most significant known serine hydrolases that governs the mammalian nervous system. Its high-rate speed, operating at the diffusion limit, combined with its buried active site feature, has made it a subject of extensive research over the last decades. Despite several studies focused on atomistic details of the different steps, a comprehensive theoretical investigation of the entire catalytic cycle has not yet been reported. In this work, we present an intuitive workflow aiming at describing the full dynamical and reactive profiles of AChE by coupling extensive steered molecular dynamics simulations for ligand diffusion and hybrid quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics computations to decipher the complete reactivity of the substrate within the enzyme. This comprehensive approach provides a broader view of the interconnections between each step that would not be readily accessible if the two steps were studied independently. Our simulations reveal that although individual steps do not indicate any strong limiting step, a solvent water molecule reorganization between the acylation and deacylation processes through the reactivity results in an energy cost of 20 kcal/mol. The observed barrier surpasses all others and discloses insights into a strong polarization effect acting on water molecules near the active site. An AMOEBA polarizable molecular dynamics simulation tends to confirm this assumption by capturing a substantial dipole moment (3.10 D) on the water molecule closest to the reaction site. These results shed light on the crucial correlation between this high-energy water reorganization and the polarization of confined water molecules. Consequently, carefully considering and modeling buried (polarizable) water molecules are of paramount importance when modeling full enzymatic activity. Therefore, this work will also provide valuable insights for future research on related enzymes with buried active sites.</description>
      <author>Fr&#233;deric C&#233;lerse, Louis Lagard&#232;re, Yasmine Bouchibti, Florian Nachon, Laurent Verdier, Jean&#8208;Philip Piquemal, &#201;tienne Derat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761787</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391034308

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ISSUEPREVArticleIssue Publication InformationCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 2, XXX-XXXPublication Date (Web):January 19, 2024Publication History Published online19 January 2024Published inissue 19 January 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761787Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyRequest reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InReddit PDF (153 KB) Get e-Alertsclose Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strongly Electron-Interacting Ru&#8211;Ce Pair Sites in RuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;HAP for Efficient Oxidation of MMF to FDCA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04329</link>
      <description>Gaobo Lin, Haoan Fan, Yiqiang Zhan, Chao Chen, Xing&#8208;Ming Zhao, Wenwen Lin, Bolong Li, Jianghao Wang, Jing Li, Weiyu Song, Jie Fu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391042081

                As a potential alternative to petroleum-derived terephthalic acid (TPA), the general production of 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) through 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) oxidation has fallen short of industrial expectations due to HMF&#8217;s storage instability and cost. Here, we propose a strategy involving Ru cation coordination manipulation to achieve efficient oxidation of 5-methoxymethylfurfural (MMF) to FDCA by constructing a Ru&#8211;Ce paired site on a CeO2-doped hydroxyapatite precursor (CeO2&#8211;HAP). By optimizing reaction conditions, the RuOx/CeO2&#8211;HAP catalyst demonstrated a complete MMF conversion of 100% and a high FDCA yield of 83.7% under base-free conditions (130 &#176;C, 5 bar O2 pressure, 15 h). Hydrogen temperature-programmed reduction (H2-TPR) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) revealed a strong interaction between Ru and Ce with electron transfer from Ce to Ru. Density functional theory (DFT) computations indicated that the strong d&#8211;d &#960; and &#963; orbital interactions between Ru and Ce provided sufficient electrons for the vacant orbitals of Ru, dispersing the density of states (DOS) of orbitals around the low energy level to facilitate MMF and FDCA adsorption with appropriate strength, thereby enhancing the MMF oxidation process. This study not only provides an MMF oxidation catalyst with high activity but also conducts a comprehensive investigation into the impact of the Ru&#8211;Ce interaction on MMF oxidation, offering insights into the subsequent production of high-value-added products such as FDCA.</description>
      <author>Gaobo Lin, Haoan Fan, Yiqiang Zhan, Chao Chen, Xing&#8208;Ming Zhao, Wenwen Lin, Bolong Li, Jianghao Wang, Jing Li, Weiyu Song, Jie Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion of Anatase/Rutile Junction to Direct Conversion of Syngas to Ethanol on the Rh/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05351</link>
      <description>Yang Feng, Yang Zhang, Jungang Wang, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, Maohong Fan, Bo Hou, Debao Li, Baojun Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391044381

                Although significant efforts have been made for the direct syngas conversion to ethanol, ethanol yield remains low. Herein, we studied syngas conversion on the Rh/TiO2 catalysts with different TiO2 phase compositions. The ethanol selectivity and yield reached 34.9 and 19.4%, respectively, at a 55.7% CO conversion on the Rh/P25 catalyst. Among the supported single Rh catalysts, this is currently the highest reported ethanol yield. The catalyst also shows good stability. The mixture of anatase&#8211;rutile phases in the P25 promotes the electron transfer from P25 to Rh species because of the strong metal&#8211;support interaction. It boosts the Rh0 active site generation, the CO dissociation, and CHx species formation, which is the significant intermediate for ethanol formation. In contrast, the Rh supported on the pure phase anatase or rutile TiO2 presents poor ethanol yield, which mainly produces the Rh+ species. This study provides an effective method to improve the ethanol yield for direct syngas conversion.</description>
      <author>Yang Feng, Yang Zhang, Jungang Wang, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, Maohong Fan, Bo Hou, Debao Li, Baojun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05351</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Oxygen Vacancies Induced by Calcium Substitution in Macroporous La&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Ce&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for Boosting Low-Temperature Oxidative Coupling of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05094</link>
      <description>Tongtong Wu, Peng Zhang, Yuechang Wei, Jing Xiong, Dawei Han, Tao Li, Yitao Yang, Zhao Zhang, Jian Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391044395

                Surface oxygen vacancies in the catalysts play a key role in improving the catalytic performances for low-temperature oxidative coupling of methane (OCM). Herein, macroporous La2Ce2&#8211;xCaxO7&#8722;&#948; (A2B2O7-type) catalysts with a disordered defective cubic fluorite phased structure were prepared by a citric acid sol&#8211;gel method. The macroporous structure improved the accessibility of the reactants (O2 and CH4) to the active sites. The partial substitution of the B site (Ce) with low-valence calcium (Ca) ions in La2Ce2&#8211;xCaxO7&#8722;&#948; catalysts induced the formation of surface oxygen vacancies, which facilitated the adsorption and activation of O2 molecules to generate the active oxygen species (O2&#8211; species). The O2&#8211; species can boost the activation of CH4 and govern the following step of the oxidative dehydrogenation of C2H6 to C2H4. La2Ce2&#8211;xCaxO7&#8722;&#948; catalysts have high catalytic activity for low-temperature OCM, and the La2Ce1.3Ca0.7O7&#8722;&#948; catalyst with the highest density of O2&#8211; species exhibits the highest catalytic activity during low-temperature OCM into C2H4 and C2H6 (C2) products, i.e., its CH4 conversion, selectivity, and yield of C2 products at 600 &#176;C are 31.0, 65.6, and 20.3%, respectively. Based on the results of multiple experimental characterizations and density functional theory calculations, the mechanism of La2Ce2&#8211;xCaxO7&#8722;&#948; catalysts for the OCM reaction is proposed: surface oxygen vacancies induced by the substitution of the Ce site with Ca ions significantly promote the critical steps of C&#8211;H bond breaking and C&#8211;C bond coupling during the low-temperature OCM reaction. It is important for the design of low-temperature and high-efficiency catalysts for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Tongtong Wu, Peng Zhang, Yuechang Wei, Jing Xiong, Dawei Han, Tao Li, Yitao Yang, Zhao Zhang, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Single-Layer Ir Clusters Enabling 100% Selective Chlorine Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05738</link>
      <description>Shuang Li, Xu Guo, Xiaofang Liu, Jianglan Shui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391096719

                The exclusive selectivity of the chlorine evolution reaction (CER) is crucial for the chlor-alkali industry to obtain pure chlorine gas and avoid the cost of separating the byproduct oxygen. However, 100% CER selectivity remains a challenge for the currently known CER catalysts. Here, we report a catalyst of atomic single-layer Ir clusters on CeO2 nanorods (IrSL/CeO2). Under the strong metal/support interaction, IrSL has a strong adsorption to oxygen, thereby suppressing the oxygen evolution reaction. Coupled with the uniform active sites of the single-layer Ir clusters, IrSL/CeO2 achieves almost 100% CER selectivity in acidic NaCl solution ranging from open circuit potential to practical current density levels. In addition, IrSL/CeO2 exhibits 1.7 times higher catalytic activity than its single-atom counterparts, and its noble metal efficiency is 84 times higher than that of commercial anodes (DSAs). Our finding provides a solution to the selective catalysis of chlor-alkali electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Shuang Li, Xu Guo, Xiaofang Liu, Jianglan Shui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Artificial Photosynthesis: CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Chemisorption and S-Scheme Charge Separation via Anchoring Inorganic QDs on COFs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00026</link>
      <description>Yuehui He, Peiyu Hu, J.C. Zhang, Guijie Liang, Yuanyuan Wang, Fei Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391101394

                Photocatalytic conversion of CO2 into valuable hydrocarbon fuels holds great promise in addressing emerging energy shortages and environmental crises while fulfilling pressing societal and national development demands. Nonetheless, its efficiency is hindered by restricted CO2 chemisorption, rapid electron&#8211;hole recombination, and weak redox capability. Drawing inspiration from the distinctive characteristics of Schiff-based covalent organic frameworks (COFs), including substantial specific surface area, unique pore structure, and an abundance of weakly alkaline nitrogen elements, we employ the TPA-COF to enhance the chemisorption and activation of acidic CO2 molecules, as validated by the CO2-temperature-programmed desorption analysis. Furthermore, anchoring CsPbBr3 quantum dots (QDs) onto the COF facilitates the effective spatial separation of photoinduced charge carriers with strong redox capability, resulting from the formation of S-scheme heterojunctions between the COF and QDs as substantiated by in situ irradiation X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, femtosecond transient absorption spectroscopy, and density functional theory simulations. As anticipated, the optimized COF/QDs heterostructures exhibit remarkable enhancements in CO2 photoreduction performance in the absence of any molecule cocatalyst or scavenger, yielding CO and CH4 at rates of 41.2 and 13.7 &#956;mol g&#8211;1, respectively. This work provides valuable insights into the development of novel organic/inorganic heterojunction photocatalysts with CO2 chemisorption and S-scheme charge separation, offering great potential for sustainable artificial photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Yuehui He, Peiyu Hu, J.C. Zhang, Guijie Liang, Yuanyuan Wang, Fei Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Restructuring of ZnCr&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Spinel Catalyst Alters Elementary Surface Reaction Kinetics and Catalytic Selectivity in CO Hydrogenation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05739</link>
      <description>Qiulin Nie, Jieqiong Ding, Dongdong Wang, Yang Liu, Wei Xiong, Yong Yang, Weixin Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391102226

                The CO hydrogenation reaction catalyzed by the ZnCr2O4 catalyst is studied using quasi-in situ XPS, temperature-programmed reaction spectroscopy, and temporal in situ diffuse reflectance Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy. At 573 K, the ZnCr2O4 catalyst selectively catalyzes the CH3OH formation reaction, in which the hydrogenation reaction of monodentate formate species is the rate-limiting step with an activation energy of approximately 60.5 kJ/mol. As the temperature increases to 673 K, CO2 and CH4 are produced at the expense of CH3OH, which can be attributed to in situ partial reduction of the ZnCr2O4 catalyst into metallic Zn. On one hand, the CO disproportionation reaction into CO2 and atomic carbon species occurs on the resulting metallic Zn, and the atomic carbon species is subsequently hydrogenated predominantly into CH4; on the other hand, the rate-limiting step of methanol synthesis on the resulting partially reduced ZnCr2O4 catalyst becomes the hydrogenation of the methoxy group with an activation energy of approximately 120.3 kJ/mol, considerably reducing the CH3OH formation rate. These results unveil that the changes in the elementary surface reaction network and the kinetics induced by in situ restructuring of the ZnCr2O4 catalyst in the CO hydrogenation reaction lead to the changes in catalytic selectivity.</description>
      <author>Qiulin Nie, Jieqiong Ding, Dongdong Wang, Yang Liu, Wei Xiong, Yong Yang, Weixin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05739</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
