<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:43:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Axially Chiral Copper Catalyst for Asymmetric Synthesis of Valuable Diversely Substituted BINOLs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00726</link>
      <description>Jun Gao, P.L. Wang, Ahui Shen, Xueyan Yang, Shouyi Cen, Zhipeng Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393308838

                Optically pure BINOL (1,1&#8242;-bi-2-naphthol) and diversely substituted BINOLs are highly valuable chiral motifs featuring axial chirality widely applied in various fields. Although unsubstituted BINOL is commercially available, the catalytic asymmetric synthesis of optically pure diversely substituted BINOLs is still very challenging. Herein, we report the development of a highly enantioselective dinuclear copper catalyst for oxidative homo- and cross-coupling of a variety of 2-naphthols to provide access to a broad range of highly valuable diversely substituted C2- and C1-symmetric BINOLs in up to 92% yield with high enantioselectivities (up to 99.5:0.5 er).</description>
      <author>Jun Gao, P.L. Wang, Ahui Shen, Xueyan Yang, Shouyi Cen, Zhipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choose Your Own Adventure: A Comprehensive Database of Reactions Catalyzed by Cytochrome P450 BM3 Variants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00086</link>
      <description>Douglas J. Fansher, Jonathan N. Besna, Ali Fendri, Joelle N. Pelletier, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393311212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Douglas J. Fansher, Jonathan N. Besna, Ali Fendri, Joelle N. Pelletier</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General, Modular Access toward Immobilized Chiral Phosphoric Acid Catalysts and Their Application in Flow Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00985</link>
      <description>Michael Laue, Maximilian Schneider, Markus G. Gebauer, Winfried B&#246;hlmann, Roger Gl&#228;ser, Christoph Schneider, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393316637

                Chiral phosphoric acids (CPAs) are among the most frequently used organocatalysts, with an ever-increasing number of applications. However, these catalysts are only obtained in a multistep synthesis and are poorly recyclable, which significantly deteriorates their environmental and economic performance. We herein report a conceptually different, general strategy for the direct immobilization of CPAs on a broad scope of solid supports including silica, polystyrene, and aluminum oxide. Solid-state catalysts were obtained in high yields and thoroughly characterized with elemental analysis by inductively coupled plasma-optical emission spectrometry (ICP-OES), nitrogen sorption measurements, thermogravimetric analysis, scanning transmission electron microscopy/energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (STEM/EDX) images, and solid-state NMR spectroscopy. Further, the immobilized catalysts were applied to a variety of synthetically valuable, highly stereoselective transformations under batch and flow conditions including transfer hydrogenations, a Friedl&#228;nder condensation/transfer hydrogenation sequence, and Mannich reactions under cryogenic flow conditions. Generally, high yields and stereoselectivities were observed along with robust catalyst stability and reusability. After being used for 10 runs under batch conditions, no loss of selectivity or catalytic activity was observed. Under continuous-flow conditions, the heterogeneous system was in operation for 19 h and the high enantioselectivity remained unchanged throughout the entire process. We expect our approach to extend the applicability of CPAs to a higher level, with a focus on flow chemistry and a more environmentally friendly and resource-efficient use of these powerful catalysts.</description>
      <author>Michael Laue, Maximilian Schneider, Markus G. Gebauer, Winfried B&#246;hlmann, Roger Gl&#228;ser, Christoph Schneider</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00985</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Complex Ligands for High Oxidation State Catalysis: Titanium Hydroamination with Unsymmetrical Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05658</link>
      <description>Zhilin Hou, Rashmi Jena, Tanner J. McDaniel, Brennan S. Billow, Seokjoo Lee, Hannah I. Barr, Aaron L. Odom, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393316892

                A method for modeling high oxidation state catalysts is used on precatalysts with unsymmetrical and symmetrical bidentate ligands to get a more detailed understanding of how changes to ancillary ligands affect the hydroamination of alkynes catalyzed by titanium. To model the electronic donor ability, the ligand donor parameter (LDP) was used, and to model the steric effects, percent buried volume (% Vbur) was employed. For the modeling study, 7 previously unpublished unsymmetrical Ti(XX&#8242;)(NMe2)2 precatalysts were prepared, where XX&#8242; is a chelating ligand with pyrrolyl/indolyl linkages. The rates of these unsymmetrical and 10 previously reported symmetrical precatalysts were used with the model kobs = a + b(LDP)1 + c(LDP)2 + d(% Vbur)1 + e(% Vbur)2, where a&#8211;e were found through least-squares refinement. The model suggests that (1) the two attachment points of the bidentate ligand XX&#8242; are in different environments on the metal (e.g., axial and equatorial in a trigonal bipyramidal or square pyramidal structure), (2) the position of the unsymmetrical ligand on the metal is determined by the electronics of the ligand rather than the sterics, and (3) that one side of the chelating ligand's electronics strongly influences the rate, while the other side's sterics more strongly influences the rate. From these studies, we were able to generate catalysts fitting to this model with rate constants larger than the fastest symmetrical catalyst tested.</description>
      <author>Zhilin Hou, Rashmi Jena, Tanner J. McDaniel, Brennan S. Billow, Seokjoo Lee, Hannah I. Barr, Aaron L. Odom</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benzylic C(sp3)&#8211;H Functionalization via Copper-Catalyzed [3+3] Radical Cycloaddition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00637</link>
      <description>Junsheng Shi, Xiong-Jiang Li, Shu-Yun Jiang, Wei Wu, Hai Ren, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393317410

                The development of benzylic C(sp3)&#8211;H functionalization methods for the assembly of benzylic derivatives has been extensively explored in recent years. However, the engagement of benzylic carbon and its adjacent C=C bond as a C3 synthon in the cycloaddition reaction via direct benzylic C&#8211;H activation is rare. Herein, we report a copper-catalyzed [3+3] radical cycloaddition reaction through benzylic C&#8211;H bond functionalization to construct six-membered cyclohexane-type rings. In this reaction, the 2-benzylic C&#8211;H bond of an indole is selectively activated and the indole serves as a C3 synthon that reacts through highly chemoselective intermolecular self-[3+3] and cross-[3+3] cycloaddition pathways. Multiple symmetric and nonsymmetric polycyclic hexahydrocarbazole scaffolds with hexacyclic 6/5/5/6/5/5/6 and pentacyclic 6/5/5/6/5/6 ring systems are synthesized with high efficiency and chemoselectivity using this strategy. Inspired by the unique radical addition pathway of cross-[3+3] cycloaddition, a highly controllable benzylic C&#8211;H functionalization for the construction of C3a-alkylated pyrroloindolines was also developed.</description>
      <author>Junsheng Shi, Xiong-Jiang Li, Shu-Yun Jiang, Wei Wu, Hai Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare-Earth-Catalyzed Regiodivergent Hydrosilylation of Aryl Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05747</link>
      <description>Wufeng Chen, N. Zhang, Zhengqi Chai, Junnian Wei, Gen Luo, Wen&#8208;Xiong Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393317760

                While transition-metal catalysts have shown the ability to regulate the Markovnikov or anti-Markovnikov regioselective hydrosilylation of aryl alkenes, the selective control of anti-Markovnikov hydrosilylation of aryl alkenes is still a huge challenge in rare-earth catalyst systems. In this study, we report the rare-earth-catalyzed regiodivergent hydrosilylation of aryl alkenes. Specifically, we achieved the highly regioselective anti-Markovnikov hydrosilylation of aryl alkenes with a scandium alkyl complex Cp*AmtBuScCH2SiMe3 (Cp* = pentamethylcyclopentadienyl, AmtBu = tBuNC(Me)NtBu, tBu = t-butyl) as a catalyst. Two key intermediates, e.g., the scandium hydride and scandium phenethyl complex for anti-Markovnikov hydrosilylation, were characterized. Guided by density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we successfully achieved the selective inversion of aryl alkenes in Markovnikov hydrosilylation using a neodymium halide complex [Cp*AmiPrNdCl]2 (AmiPr = iPrNC(Me)NiPr, iPr = isopropyl) with the larger ion radius and reduced steric hindrance in conjunction with LiCH2SiMe3. Interestingly, our study has demonstrated the significant influence of gradually increasing rare-earth ion radii on controlling the increasing Markovnikov selectivity of hydrosilylation reactions, possibly due to the enlargement of the coordination space around rare-earth metal ions. Furthermore, through a comparison of computational and experimental data, we have observed a high level of consistency, reaffirming the potential of using calculations to predict experimental outcomes and providing researchers with valuable insights.</description>
      <author>Wufeng Chen, N. Zhang, Zhengqi Chai, Junnian Wei, Gen Luo, Wen&#8208;Xiong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Catalyst Immediate Environment Enables Acidic Electrochemical Benzyl Alcohol Oxidation to Benzaldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00476</link>
      <description>G. Shiva Shanker, Arnab Ghatak, Shahar Binyamin, Rotem Balilty, Ran Shimoni, Itamar Liberman, Idan Hod, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393319141

                Electrocatalytic alcohol oxidation in acid offers a promising alternative to the kinetically sluggish water oxidation reaction toward low-energy H2 generation. However, electrocatalysts driving active and selective acidic alcohol electrochemical transformation are still scarce. In this work, we demonstrate efficient alcohol-to-aldehyde conversion achieved by reticular chemistry-based modification of the catalyst's immediate environment. Specifically, coating a Bi-based electrocatalyst with a thin layer of metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) substantially improves its performance toward benzyl alcohol electro-oxidation to benzaldehyde in a 0.1 M H2SO4 electrolyte. Detailed analysis reveals that the MOF adlayer influences catalysis by increasing the reactivity of surface hydroxides as well as weakening the catalyst-benzaldehyde binding strength. In turn, low-potential (0.65 V) cathodic H2 evolution was obtained through coupling it with anodic benzyl alcohol electro-oxidation. Consequently, the presented approach could be implemented in a wide range of electrocatalytic oxidation reactions for energy-conversion application.</description>
      <author>G. Shiva Shanker, Arnab Ghatak, Shahar Binyamin, Rotem Balilty, Ran Shimoni, Itamar Liberman, Idan Hod</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enlarging the Three-Phase Boundary to Raise CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Conversions on Exsolved Ni&#8211;Fe Alloy Perovskite Catalysts by Minimal Rh Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00151</link>
      <description>Xueli Yao, Qingpeng Cheng, Xueqin Bai, Bambar Davaasuren, Georgian Melinte, Natalia Morlan&#233;s, Jos&#233; Luis Cerrillo, Vijay Kumar Velisoju, Hend Omar Mohamed, Pewee Datoo Kolubah, Lirong Zheng, Yu Han, Osman M. Bakr, Jorge Gasc&#243;n, Pedro Casta&#241;o, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393319453

                Exsolved Ni&#8211;Fe alloy perovskite catalysts exhibit remarkable coking resistance during C&#8211;H and C&#8211;O activation. However, metallic utilization is typically incomplete, resulting in relatively low catalytic activity. Herein, we investigated minimal doping with Rh to boost the catalytic activity in the dry reforming of methane by promoting exsolution and enlargement of the three-phase boundary between the alloy, support, and reactants. The Rh influences the formation of the Ni&#8211;Fe alloy, as revealed by X-ray diffraction, and promotes the individual and collective CH4 and CO2 conversions, as revealed by packed bed reactor runs, temperature-programmed surface reactions, and in situ infrared spectroscopy. A minimal 0.21 wt % Rh addition enlarges the three-phase boundary while improving oxygen mobility and storage. The oxygen mobility is responsible for promoting CH4 dissociation and dynamic removal of carbon-containing intermediates, such that the catalyst remains stable for over 100 h under both 1 and 14 bar.</description>
      <author>Xueli Yao, Qingpeng Cheng, Xueqin Bai, Bambar Davaasuren, Georgian Melinte, Natalia Morlan&#233;s, Jos&#233; Luis Cerrillo, Vijay Kumar Velisoju, Hend Omar Mohamed, Pewee Datoo Kolubah, Lirong Zheng, Yu Han, Osman M. Bakr, Jorge Gasc&#243;n, Pedro Casta&#241;o</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Strong Metal&#8211;Support Interactions via Synergistic Alloying</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06171</link>
      <description>Yunlong Wang, Xiaobo Chen, Chaoran Li, Yaguang Zhu, Jing Li, Shiyao Shan, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, J. Anibal Boscoboinik, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, Guangwen Zhou, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393345356

                The encapsulation phenomenon associated with a strong metal&#8211;support interactions (SMSI) has been largely restricted to catalyst systems consisting of group VIII metals with high surface energy and reducible transition metal oxide supports with low surface energy. Here, we demonstrate an encapsulation phenomenon that, while sharing morphological similarities with conventional SMSI, follows a distinctive pathway. This is shown by the encapsulation of CuAu nanoparticles (NPs) supported on a highly ordered pyrolytic graphite (HOPG). Through dynamic monitoring of Cu, Au, and Cu50Au50 NPs in an oxidizing atmosphere using ambient-pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, we show that this spontaneous encapsulation is achieved through the synergistic effect of the alloying elements. Specifically, the surface segregation of Cu promotes dissociative O2 adsorption, leading to the formation of atomic O species, while the subsurface enrichment of Au hinders O incorporation of oxygen into the bulk of CuAu NPs. Consequently, O spillover onto the graphite support occurs, resulting in the oxidation of the HOPG surface into graphitic oxide species. The higher affinity of the graphitic oxide species toward the Cu-segregated surface prompts their migration from the HOPG support to encapsulate the CuAu NPs. These results transcend the conventional SMSI and bear practical implications for the design and development of heterogeneous catalysts, particularly in carbon-supported alloy systems.</description>
      <author>Yunlong Wang, Xiaobo Chen, Chaoran Li, Yaguang Zhu, Jing Li, Shiyao Shan, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, J. Anibal Boscoboinik, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, Guangwen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Engineering of Electrocatalytic Nanomaterials for Hydrogen Evolution: The Impact of Structural and Electronic Modifications of Anchoring Linkers on Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00336</link>
      <description>Andrew J. Bagnall, Matthieu Haake, Sergi Grau, Tatiana Straistari, Matthieu Koepf, Navid Jameei Moghaddam, Carolina Gimbert&#8208;Suri&#241;ach, Jordi Benet&#8208;Buchholz, Antoni Llobet, Murielle Chavarot&#8208;Kerlidou, Bertrand Reuillard, Vincent Artero, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393305578

                The anticipated shortage of an increasing number of critical elements, especially metals, requires a shift toward molecularly defined materials with low metal loadings. More particularly, surface-anchored molecular catalysts are attractive to prospectively enable cost-effective electrochemical hydrogen evolution. However, the design of ligands integrating specific anchoring unit(s) for the immobilization of molecular catalysts can be challenging and has direct consequences for the intrinsic properties of the grafted complex. In this work, two cobalt tetraazamacrocyclic complexes bearing pyrene anchoring groups at different positions on the macrocyclic ligands were synthesized. The pyrene unit allows for simple immobilization and electrochemical characterization of the two complexes on multi-walled carbon nanotube-based electrodes. Thorough electrochemical and electrocatalytic investigation demonstrates important differences between the two closely related catalysts in terms of catalyst loading, catalytic response, and stability over time, with a significantly higher stability observed at pH 7 than at pH 2.</description>
      <author>Andrew J. Bagnall, Matthieu Haake, Sergi Grau, Tatiana Straistari, Matthieu Koepf, Navid Jameei Moghaddam, Carolina Gimbert&#8208;Suri&#241;ach, Jordi Benet&#8208;Buchholz, Antoni Llobet, Murielle Chavarot&#8208;Kerlidou, Bertrand Reuillard, Vincent Artero</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Micropore Topology Influences the Structure and Location of Coke in Zeolite Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00025</link>
      <description>Przemys&#322;aw Rzepka, Denis Sheptyakov, Chao Wang, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, Vladimir Paunovi&#263;, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393309555

                Zeolite catalysts exhibit microporous structures, akin to the pockets in naturally occurring enzyme catalysts, which enable the confinement of reaction intermediates, thus facilitating chemical transformations. Nonetheless, the micropores also influence the formation of coke species, which is the main source of catalytic activity loss. Unveiling the relationships between the micropore topology and the internal structure and location of deactivating coke compounds is of high relevance for comprehending the deactivation mechanisms. In this study, we used an approach exploiting powder neutron diffraction to assess the location of coke and determine the dominating structures in the topologically distinct ZSM-5 (MFI topology), ZSM-35 (FER), and SSZ-13 (CHA) zeolite catalysts deactivated in industrially relevant methanol-to-hydrocarbon (MTH) conversion. In ZSM-5 and ZSM-35 catalysts, coke resides along the straight 10-membered ring (MR) channels and exhibits the highest concentration in their intersecting regions with sinusoidal 10 MR and straight 8 MR pores, respectively. In the SSZ-13 catalyst, coke is not only located in cages but also protrudes through their 8 MR windows, suggesting the interconnectivity of coke molecules between the large cavities. Notably, the coke-associated signals in the ZSM-5 and ZSM-35 catalysts show a strong planar arrangement that can be fitted by polycyclic and monocyclic arene structures, respectively. These averaged coke structures are consistent with the composition of coke assessed by gas chromatography&#8211;mass spectrometry, 13C and two-dimensional 1H double-quantum single-quantum magic-angle spinning nuclear magnetic resonance, and operando diffuse reflectance ultraviolet&#8211;visible spectroscopic analysis. The findings evidence that the pore topology directs the confinement and structure of coke, wherein the largest void zones of the micropore space are the most susceptible to coking.</description>
      <author>Przemys&#322;aw Rzepka, Denis Sheptyakov, Chao Wang, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, Vladimir Paunovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Synergistic Power of Ce&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; S-Scheme Heterojunctions for Profound C&#8211;O Bond Cleavage in Lignin Model Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00297</link>
      <description>Hongwu Liao, Yanmin Zhou, Zhuo Chen, Swellam W. Sharshir, Sameh M. Osman, Chong Wang, Meng An, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yusuke Asakura, Zhanhui Yuan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393316547

                In the context of achieving carbon neutrality, converting lignin-derived molecules into high-value products through photocatalytic technology provides an environmentally friendly pathway. Establishing energy-efficient processes for converting lignin derivatives requires the construction of highly active and selective photocatalysts. However, enhancing the efficiency and selectivity of photocatalysts for lignin degradation poses an ongoing challenge due to discrepancies in the redox potential and the rapid recombination of photogenerated carriers. To address these significant obstacles, we devised an innovative strategy by developing a Ce2S3 nanoparticle-anchored TiO2 nanorod (Ce2S3/TiO2). This advanced photocatalyst with the S-scheme heterojunction, enabling simultaneous control of carrier dynamics and band structure, was used to study the photocatalytic degradation of the lignin model compound 2-phenoxy-1-acetophenone. Moreover, the photocatalyst can cleave the C&#946;-O-4 bond selectively to convert the lignin model compound 2-phenoxy-1-acetophenone into phenol and acetophenone under visible-light irradiation. The yields are up to 94 and 80%, respectively, and 94 or 1.4 times greater than those obtained by pure TiO2 or Ce2S3 individually. In addition, our study for the increased activity in Ce2S3/TiO2 based on density functional theory calculations emphasizes the pivotal role of the S-scheme heterojunction generated between Ce2S3 and TiO2. This heterojunction significantly enhances carrier separation efficiency, thereby augmenting the efficacy of the photocatalytic process. The findings furnish valuable insights for developing advanced photocatalytic systems tailored to the efficient depolymerization of C&#946;-O-4 bonds in lignin.</description>
      <author>Hongwu Liao, Yanmin Zhou, Zhuo Chen, Swellam W. Sharshir, Sameh M. Osman, Chong Wang, Meng An, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yusuke Asakura, Zhanhui Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable Divergent Reactivity of Aziridinium Ylides in the Synthesis of Complex Piperidines and Azetidines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06173</link>
      <description>Mahzad Dehghany, Giuliana Pavaneli, Jacob W. Kailing, Olivia M. Duke, Ilia A. Guzei, Caroline Da Ros Montes D&#8217;Oca, Israel Fern&#225;ndez, Jennifer M. Schomaker, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393372078

                Nitrogenated heterocycles comprise the cores of a number of synthetically useful compounds, including pharmaceuticals, bioactive natural products, agrochemicals, and other drug-like molecules. The widespread interest in methods to increase the fraction of sp3 carbon atoms (Fsp3) of drug-like scaffolds in a stereocontrolled manner, while enabling explorations of unusual amine chemical space, inspired our efforts to tune the reactivity of aziridinium ylides. A sequential nitrene&#8211;carbene transfer of simple allenes leads to divergent product outcomes depending on the nature of the carbene precursor, furnishing products of different ring sizes. In addition, the catalyst control over the ring size via proposed hydrogen-bonding interactions between the catalyst and substrate was explored. Computational studies were employed to gain insight into the major features of substrates and catalysts that influence the tunable reactivity of aziridinium ylide intermediates formed in this chemistry.</description>
      <author>Mahzad Dehghany, Giuliana Pavaneli, Jacob W. Kailing, Olivia M. Duke, Ilia A. Guzei, Caroline Da Ros Montes D&#8217;Oca, Israel Fern&#225;ndez, Jennifer M. Schomaker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Visible-Light-Driven Water Oxidation by a Carbon Nitride Modified with Cobalt Polyoxometalate Molecular Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00627</link>
      <description>Yoshihiko Tomita, Natsuki Taira, Ken Sakai, Hidetoshi Ozawa, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393373284

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yoshihiko Tomita, Natsuki Taira, Ken Sakai, Hidetoshi Ozawa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competing Mechanisms in Palladium-Catalyzed Alkoxycarbonylation of Styrene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00966</link>
      <description>Jaya Mehara, Mariarosa Anania, Pavel Ko&#269;ovsk&#253;, Jana Roithov&#225;, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393375769

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jaya Mehara, Mariarosa Anania, Pavel Ko&#269;ovsk&#253;, Jana Roithov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00966</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Hydrogen-Switchable Dynamic Oxygen Vacancies in MoO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; upon Ru Nanoparticle Decoration for Boosting Photocatalytic Ammonia Synthesis Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05633</link>
      <description>Lulu Zhang, Rui Li, Lijun Guo, Longzhe Cui, Xiaochao Zhang, Yawen Wang, Yunfang Wang, Xuan Jian, Xiaoming Gao, Caimei Fan, Jiancheng Wang, Jianxin Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393376514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lulu Zhang, Rui Li, Lijun Guo, Longzhe Cui, Xiaochao Zhang, Yawen Wang, Yunfang Wang, Xuan Jian, Xiaoming Gao, Caimei Fan, Jiancheng Wang, Jianxin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05633</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Electrocatalytic Semihydrogenation of Alkynols to Alkenols over a Bimetallic CuAu Alloy Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05928</link>
      <description>Qinghui Ren, Leilei Hao, Jiangrong Yang, Mengyu Lv, Hua Zhou, Zhenhua Li, Haohong Duan, Mingfei Shao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393377866

                Electrocatalytic semihydrogenation of alkynols to alkenols under ambient conditions using H2O as a hydrogen source is highly attractive in synthetic chemistry. However, it is still challenging to achieve a high Faradaic efficiency (FE) in a wide potential window. Herein, we reported a bimetallic Cu3Au alloy as an efficient catalyst for electrocatalytic semihydrogenation of alkynols to alkenols. Specifically, during semihydrogenation of 2-butyne-1,4-diol (BYD) to 2-butene-1,4-diol (BED), the Cu3Au catalyst achieves 12.6-fold greater reaction rate and higher FE compared with pure Cu (99 vs 63%). Moreover, the Cu3Au maintains &gt;96% FEs in a wide potential window from &#8722;0.19 to &#8722;0.59 V vs RHE. We demonstrate that the competitive adsorptions of reactive hydrogen (H*) and BYD greatly influence the semihydrogenation processes. The presence of Au in Cu3Au facilitates H* formation and reduces BYD adsorption on Cu, thus enhancing the BYD hydrogenation performance. The Cu3Au catalyst affords a broad substrate scope from alkynols to aromatic alkynes, producing the corresponding alkenes in good selectivities. Finally, we coupled BYD semihydrogenation with glycerol oxidation to replace oxygen evolution reaction in a two-electrode system, showing 40% energy saving at 200 mA for BED production and coproduction of valuable formate at the anode, demonstrating an economical manner.</description>
      <author>Qinghui Ren, Leilei Hao, Jiangrong Yang, Mengyu Lv, Hua Zhou, Zhenhua Li, Haohong Duan, Mingfei Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Carrier Separation on a BiOBr/Bi&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;Br&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Direct Z-Scheme Heterojunction for Superior Photocatalytic Nitrogen Fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06169</link>
      <description>Huiqing Wang, Zhuohua Chen, Yaru Shang, Chade Lv, Xuhan Zhang, Fei Li, Qunzeng Huang, Xiaodi Liu, Wenmin Liu, Liang Zhao, Liqun Ye, Hongmei Xie, Xiaoli Jin, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393381136

                Photocatalytic dinitrogen (N2) fixation is regarded as an achievable technology for ammonia (NH3) production. However, the poor separation efficiency of the photoinduced carriers and ineffective N2 activation remain grand obstacles to high-performance NH3 photosynthesis. Designing advanced heterostructured systems to accelerate charge separation and activate the N2 molecule is a feasible strategy to optimize the photocatalytic N2 fixation activity. Herein, a direct Z-scheme configuration is established between BiOBr and Bi4O5Br2 through a facile one-step solvothermal reaction. This configuration enables effective spatial separation of electron&#8211;hole pairs and preserves the robust redox ability of carriers, concurrently promoting N&#8801;N bond activation and diminishing the energy barrier for the rate-determining step. The formation of direct Z-scheme BiOBr/Bi4O5Br2 heterojunctions is mostly attributed to the similarities in their lattice structures and crystal growth conditions. As a result, the direct Z-scheme BiOBr/Bi4O5Br2 heterojunction exhibits a high NH3 yield of 66.87 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 without using sacrificing reagents, surpassing that of the pristine BiOBr and Bi4O5Br2 by approximately 3.3 and 5.6 times, respectively. This study provides an achievable approach to construct direct Z-scheme heterojunction systems for implementing high-performance N2 fixation under mild conditions.</description>
      <author>Huiqing Wang, Zhuohua Chen, Yaru Shang, Chade Lv, Xuhan Zhang, Fei Li, Qunzeng Huang, Xiaodi Liu, Wenmin Liu, Liang Zhao, Liqun Ye, Hongmei Xie, Xiaoli Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Catalytic Nitrogen&#8211;Nitrogen Bond Formation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00718</link>
      <description>Jianglin Hu, Yichen Wu, Ying Gao, Yinglei Wang, Peng Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393385196

                The lack of effective strategies for direct construction of nitrogen&#8211;nitrogen bonds has hampered developments in the synthesis and application of molecules containing hydrazine or azo motifs. Attracted by their properties both in material science and in medicinal chemistry, more and more attention has been drawn to this area, resulting in fast growth in the design and synthesis of azaheterocycles and substituted hydrazines. This review focuses on efficient catalytic approaches toward the formation of N&#8211;N and N&#9552;N bonds through different strategies, including oxidative dehydrogenation, nitrene-transfer reaction, reductive coupling, and some other recently developed methods.</description>
      <author>Jianglin Hu, Yichen Wu, Ying Gao, Yinglei Wang, Peng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Reaction Network Exploration Scheme Based on Graph Theory Representation and Depth First Search Applied to CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation on Pd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Cu Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00067</link>
      <description>Hui Guo, Hong Zhu, Guan-Zhang Liu, Zhao-Xu Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393385723

                Reaction mechanisms are at the core of understanding reaction systems and designing high-performance catalysts. A complex reaction system often involves various species and elementary reactions, posing a great challenge to determining the reaction mechanism. Here, we proposed a scheme to automatically generate reaction intermediates and elementary reactions to construct a complete reaction network represented by graph theory and employed a depth first search algorithm in the scheme to prune the reaction network to reduce the complexity of the network. With this scheme, microkinetic simulations of CO2 hydrogenation on Pd2Cu using the barriers predicted with the linear thermodynamics&#8211;kinetics relations were performed on the network to determine the mechanism and rate- and selectivity-controlling steps of CO2 hydrogenation to ethanol and methanol. Analysis shows that the simulated selectivity of ethanol and methanol agrees well with the experimental results. CO2 + H &#8594; COOH is the rate-controlling step, and CHOH + H &#8594; CH + H2O, CH2OH + H &#8594; CH2 + H2O, and CH2OH + H &#8594; CH3OH dominate the ethanol selectivity. Both ethanol and methanol are generated via multiple reaction pathway mechanisms. Investigations of the pruned networks show that quantitatively correct results can be obtained from the pruned or pseudocomplete reaction network, as long as the key pathways are embodied in the network. 94% ethanol selectivity of the complete network can be obtained with the pruned network composed of 60 elementary steps, compared to 176 steps of the complete network. The present work articulates graph theory representation, depth first search algorithm, linear thermodynamics&#8211;kinetics relations, and microkinetic simulations to approach complicated heterogeneous reaction systems and exemplifies their comprehensive roles in exploring complex reaction networks.</description>
      <author>Hui Guo, Hong Zhu, Guan-Zhang Liu, Zhao-Xu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin Selectivity Induced by the Interface Effect for Boosted Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00142</link>
      <description>Zhigao Xue, Biao Wu, Zheng Zhang, Ching-Yu Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Qiuju Zhang, Kai Tao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393386676

                Creating highly effective electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) holds paramount importance in advancing carbon-neutral hydrogen production through water electrolysis. Recent research highlights the crucial role of spin effects on the OER, emphasizing that the manipulation of spin polarization is a promising strategy to augment the OER kinetics. Here, we present a core&#8211;shell heterostructure electrocatalyst, which leverages the strong coupling of the interface between antiferromagnetic Co3O4 and NiFe-layered double hydroxide (NiFe-LDH) to trigger a spontaneous magnetic response enhancement, which suggests the strong double exchange interaction at the interface of the core&#8211;shell heterostructure. This electrocatalyst displays a 26-fold increase in intrinsic OER activity compared to pristine NiFe-LDH at an overpotential of 0.25 V. Through experimental and computational analyses, we find that the strong double exchange interaction within the heterostructure creates polarized spin conduction channels at the interface, which enables efficient accumulation of electrons with appropriate spin states, thereby lowering the energy barrier for the generation of triplet O2. Our work presents a promising approach to designing high-performance OER catalysts by introducing spin selectivity in traditional metal oxide electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhigao Xue, Biao Wu, Zheng Zhang, Ching-Yu Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Qiuju Zhang, Kai Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reductive Aminomethylation Using Ammonium Formate and Methanol as N1 and C1 Source: Direct Synthesis of Mono- and Di-Methylated Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00346</link>
      <description>Ishani Borthakur, S. K. Nandi, Yuvraj Bilora, Biswajit Sadhu, Sabuj Kundu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393409196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ishani Borthakur, S. K. Nandi, Yuvraj Bilora, Biswajit Sadhu, Sabuj Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrophobic Surface Modification of Cu-Based Catalysts for Enhanced Semihydrogenation of Acetylene in Excess Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05466</link>
      <description>Ting Liu, Jinqi Xiong, Qian Luo, Shanjun Mao, Yong Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393409197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Liu, Jinqi Xiong, Qian Luo, Shanjun Mao, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Catalyst Self-Adjustment in C&#8211;S Cross-Coupling through Multiscale Liquid-Phase Electron Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06258</link>
      <description>Alexey S. Kashin, D. M. Arkhipova, Liliya T. Sahharova, Julia V. Burykina, Valentine P. Ananikov, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393500093

                Carbon&#8211;carbon and carbon&#8211;heteroatom bond formation mediated by transition metals is a powerful and convenient methodology for organic synthesis. To effectively meet the demands of catalyst design, an in-depth understanding of the reaction mechanisms and pathways of active species evolution is essential. Advances in electron microscopy now offer unprecedented multilevel visualization of liquid-phase chemical systems, providing a powerful tool for mechanistic studies. In this work, we found that the use of either nickel- or copper-based catalyst precursors with preinstalled thiolate groups in combination with pyridinium ionic liquid as the reaction medium leads to a positive synergistic effect, resulting in the formation of transition metal species with high catalytic activity in the C&#8211;S cross-coupling reaction between aryl halides and thiols or disulfides. Through multiscale in situ and operando electron microscopy in the liquid phase, we elucidated the self-adjustment of the catalytic system and revealed the simultaneous emergence of metallic nanoparticles and corresponding thiolate species, leading to the independent activation of the C- and S-substrates and the subsequent elimination of the product via organic group metathesis. The proposed methodology for the catalytic preparation of aromatic organosulfides was used for the design of synthetic routes to pharmacologically important substances.</description>
      <author>Alexey S. Kashin, D. M. Arkhipova, Liliya T. Sahharova, Julia V. Burykina, Valentine P. Ananikov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu&#8211;Sn Bimetallic Activated Carbon&#8211;Carbon Coupling for Efficient Furfural Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06346</link>
      <description>Xiaofeng Liu, Yuhan Sun, Hao Ren, Yuan Lin, Mingbo Wu, Zhong-Tao Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393536047

                Electrochemically driven carbon&#8211;carbon coupling utilizing renewable electricity under ambient conditions has emerged as an innovative approach for synthesizing high-value chemicals, which still faces inherent challenges such as low conversion rates and poor selectivity. While electroreducing furfural to hydrofuroin can produce high-quality biofuel, its efficiency need to be promoted. Herein, Cu&#8211;Sn bimetallic catalyst has been developed with a conversion rate of furfural of &gt;97% and hydrofuroin selectivity of &gt;67% through equilibrium of the interfacial intermediate *H and *fur-CHOH, which exhibits the greatest state-of-the-art overall performance. Characterization and theoretical calculation reveal that Cu serves as the active site for generating *fur-CHOH, whose electron density can be decreased by introducing Sn, and results in a higher *fur-CHOH coverage and a lower energy barrier of dimerization. Moreover, adding Sn also enables sluggish *H formation to balance interfacial *fur-CHOH and *H, leading to reduced hydrogenation byproducts. The as-developed approach provides valuable insights for optimizing other C&#8211;C electrocoupling reactions for the synthesis of high-value chemicals.</description>
      <author>Xiaofeng Liu, Yuhan Sun, Hao Ren, Yuan Lin, Mingbo Wu, Zhong-Tao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06346</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
