<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 18:49:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>One-Pot Sequential Two-Step Photo-Biocatalytic Deracemization of &lt;i&gt;sec&lt;/i&gt;-Alcohols Combining Photocatalytic Oxidation and Bioreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05100</link>
      <description>Aleksandra Rudzka, Natalia Antos, Tamara Reiter, Wolfgang Kroutil, Pawe&#322; Borowiecki, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391025463

                Chiral alcohols are versatile building blocks and are of particular interest in the asymmetric synthesis of nonracemic active pharmaceutical ingredients, agrochemicals, fragrances, flavors, natural products, etc. Herein, we report on a &#8220;one-pot sequential two-step&#8221; concurrent oxidation&#8211;reduction photobiocatalytic process to synthesize enantiomerically enriched alcohols. In this regard, an efficient photocatalytic system based on irradiation with 440 nm blue LEDs in the presence of 9-fluorenone as a metal-free photocatalyst and molecular oxygen as the terminal oxidant in dry DMSO as the hydrogen peroxide-neutralizing agent was used to oxidize a broad range of racemic (hetero)benzylic alcohols into prochiral ketones quantitively (&gt;99% conv.). The in situ formed carbonyl compounds were subsequently converted into the corresponding chiral alcohols via a sequential biocatalytic transhydrogenation catalyzed by lyophilized E. coli cells overexpressing highly stereoselective and stereocomplementary recombinant alcohol dehydrogenases (ADHs) originated from Rhodococcus ruber (E. coli/ADH-A) or Rhodococcus erythropolis (E. coli/ReADH) to obtain (S)-alcohols and Lactobacillus kefir (E. coli/Lk-ADH) or KRED-110 to obtain (R)-alcohols, respectively. Overall, the elaborated photobiocatalytic deracemization of racemic alcohols using a 9-fluorenone-O2-blue LED-DMSO-E. coli/ADH system carried out on a semipreparative scale (0.25 mmol; 63 mM final conc. in 4 mL) at room temperature yielded nonracemic aryl alcohols with 82&#8211;99.9% conv., in up to 92% isolated yield, with 97&#8211;99.9% ee and complementary chirality.</description>
      <author>Aleksandra Rudzka, Natalia Antos, Tamara Reiter, Wolfgang Kroutil, Pawe&#322; Borowiecki</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation with High Selectivity by Single Bi Atoms on MXenes Enabled by a Concerted Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04480</link>
      <description>Kaifeng Niu, Lin Chen, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391025688

                Developing efficient catalysts for the capture and direct conversion of CO2 into various chemicals is essential to alleviate CO2 emissions and minimize the negative environmental effects of fossil fuels. Combining density functional theory calculations and microkinetic analysis, we propose that single Bi atoms supported on V2CO2 MXenes (Bi@V2CO2) are promising single-atom catalysts (SAC) for CO2 hydrogenation. The catalytic performance of Bi SACs is ensured by the stable single-atom dispersion of Bi atoms on V2CO2 and enhanced adsorption of CO2. Of importance, Bi@V2CO2 exhibits remarkable selectivity toward the synthesis of formic acid (HCOOH), in which the main competing reaction, namely, the reverse water gas shift (RWGS) and the formation of CO, is strictly prohibited. In contrast to conventional Cu or In2O3 catalysts, CO2 hydrogenation exhibits a unique mechanism on Bi@V2CO2, in which the formic acid is directly generated via a concerted pathway. As a result, the formation of both intermediate HCOO and COOH is prevented, leading to high selectivity (nearly 100%) toward HCOOH on Bi@V2CO2. Moreover, analysis of the kinetic behavior suggests that the stabilization of HCOOH adsorption would be an effective approach to promote catalyst performance toward methanol synthesis.</description>
      <author>Kaifeng Niu, Lin Chen, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jonas Bj&#246;rk</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partially Bonded Aluminum Site on the External Surface of Post-treated Au/ZSM-5 Enhances Methane Oxidation to Oxygenates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05030</link>
      <description>Jun Cao, Guodong Qi, Bingqing Yao, Qian He, Richard J. Lewis, Lu Xu, Feng Deng, Jun Xu, Graham J. Hutchings, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391026262

                Au nanoparticles supported on the exterior surface of the ZSM-5 zeolite (Au/ZSM-5) have shown the ability to partially oxidize methane to methanol and acetic acid. However, further improvements to the catalyst activity are required. This study investigates the effect of modifying the acidic properties of the ZSM-5 support through a desilication&#8211;recrystallization (DR) process on the activity of Au/ZSM-5 catalysts toward methane oxidation. A DR treatment of 24 h leads to a 50% higher oxygenate yield compared to the analogous catalyst prepared using the untreated support. Characterization using solid-state 27Al NMR and FTIR adsorption of pyridine and 2,4,6-trimethylpyridine reveals that DR induces framework dealumination and redistribution of Br&#248;nsted acid sites to the zeolite external surface. Two-dimensional 27Al MQMAS NMR further identifies partially coordinated framework Al sites on the zeolite surface, correlating with a higher oxygenate yield. These external acid sites help stabilize the Au nanoparticles, enhancing catalyst stability for methane partial oxidation.</description>
      <author>Jun Cao, Guodong Qi, Bingqing Yao, Qian He, Richard J. Lewis, Lu Xu, Feng Deng, Jun Xu, Graham J. Hutchings</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu/Au(111) Surfaces and AuCu Intermetallics for Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in Ionic Liquid Electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04592</link>
      <description>Bj&#246;rn Ratschmeier, Christian Paulsen, Klaus Stallberg, Gina Ro&#223;, W. Daum, Rainer P&#246;ttgen, Bj&#246;rn Braunschweig, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391029986

                Room-temperature ionic liquids (RTIL) are important alternatives to aqueous electrolytes in electrocatalytic reactions, batteries, and fuel cells. They are known to reduce existing high overpotentials and increase CO2 solubility as well as product selectivity in CO2 reduction reactions (CO2RR). In our work, we have studied the activity for CO2RR of Au(111), Cu(111), and Cu-modified Au(111) electrodes with 1/3, 2/3, and 3/3 Cu monolayers, as well as of AuCu and AuCu3 intermetallics in contact with 1-butyl-3-methylimidazolium bis(trifluoromethylsulfonyl)imide [BMIM][NTf2] electrolytes with 1.5 M H2O. Using offline gas chromatography (GC), we demonstrate the formation of H2 and mainly CO as the only reduction products at Au(111), while exclusively H2 is formed at Cu(111). Synergistic electronic and geometric effects lead to higher levels of CO formation at Cu-modified Au(111) electrodes in comparison to neat Au(111). Operando IR absorption spectroscopy (IRAS) of the bulk electrolyte shows the formation of a 2-imidazolium carboxylic acid intermediate that can lower the overpotential for CO2 reduction and does not require stabilization of a CO2&#8211; radical anion as an alternative intermediate at the interface. Systematic variation of the copper content at the catalysts&#8217; surfaces enables us to adjust the H2/CO syngas ratio to a maximum of 1.8 for Cu-modified Au(111) electrodes and &#8764;3.2 for AuCu3 catalysts at electrolysis times of 20 min, demonstrating a large tunability of the syngas ratio with electrode potential. The observed range of H2/CO ratios includes the ideal ratio of 2 for the Fischer&#8211;Tropsch process to produce hydrocarbons and the ratio of 3 needed for methanation.</description>
      <author>Bj&#246;rn Ratschmeier, Christian Paulsen, Klaus Stallberg, Gina Ro&#223;, W. Daum, Rainer P&#246;ttgen, Bj&#246;rn Braunschweig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761788</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391030911

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ISSUEPREVArticleNEXTIssue Editorial MastheadCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 2, XXX-XXXPublication Date (Web):January 19, 2024Publication History Published online19 January 2024Published inissue 19 January 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761788Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyRequest reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InReddit PDF (198 KB) Get e-Alertsclose Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761787</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391034308

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ISSUEPREVArticleIssue Publication InformationCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 2, XXX-XXXPublication Date (Web):January 19, 2024Publication History Published online19 January 2024Published inissue 19 January 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761787Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyRequest reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InReddit PDF (153 KB) Get e-Alertsclose Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i002_1761787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strongly Electron-Interacting Ru&#8211;Ce Pair Sites in RuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;HAP for Efficient Oxidation of MMF to FDCA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04329</link>
      <description>Gaobo Lin, Haoan Fan, Yiqiang Zhan, Chao Chen, Xing&#8208;Ming Zhao, Wenwen Lin, Bolong Li, Jianghao Wang, Jing Li, Weiyu Song, Jie Fu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391042081

                As a potential alternative to petroleum-derived terephthalic acid (TPA), the general production of 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) through 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) oxidation has fallen short of industrial expectations due to HMF&#8217;s storage instability and cost. Here, we propose a strategy involving Ru cation coordination manipulation to achieve efficient oxidation of 5-methoxymethylfurfural (MMF) to FDCA by constructing a Ru&#8211;Ce paired site on a CeO2-doped hydroxyapatite precursor (CeO2&#8211;HAP). By optimizing reaction conditions, the RuOx/CeO2&#8211;HAP catalyst demonstrated a complete MMF conversion of 100% and a high FDCA yield of 83.7% under base-free conditions (130 &#176;C, 5 bar O2 pressure, 15 h). Hydrogen temperature-programmed reduction (H2-TPR) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) revealed a strong interaction between Ru and Ce with electron transfer from Ce to Ru. Density functional theory (DFT) computations indicated that the strong d&#8211;d &#960; and &#963; orbital interactions between Ru and Ce provided sufficient electrons for the vacant orbitals of Ru, dispersing the density of states (DOS) of orbitals around the low energy level to facilitate MMF and FDCA adsorption with appropriate strength, thereby enhancing the MMF oxidation process. This study not only provides an MMF oxidation catalyst with high activity but also conducts a comprehensive investigation into the impact of the Ru&#8211;Ce interaction on MMF oxidation, offering insights into the subsequent production of high-value-added products such as FDCA.</description>
      <author>Gaobo Lin, Haoan Fan, Yiqiang Zhan, Chao Chen, Xing&#8208;Ming Zhao, Wenwen Lin, Bolong Li, Jianghao Wang, Jing Li, Weiyu Song, Jie Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion of Anatase/Rutile Junction to Direct Conversion of Syngas to Ethanol on the Rh/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05351</link>
      <description>Yang Feng, Yang Zhang, Jungang Wang, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, Maohong Fan, Bo Hou, Debao Li, Baojun Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391044381

                Although significant efforts have been made for the direct syngas conversion to ethanol, ethanol yield remains low. Herein, we studied syngas conversion on the Rh/TiO2 catalysts with different TiO2 phase compositions. The ethanol selectivity and yield reached 34.9 and 19.4%, respectively, at a 55.7% CO conversion on the Rh/P25 catalyst. Among the supported single Rh catalysts, this is currently the highest reported ethanol yield. The catalyst also shows good stability. The mixture of anatase&#8211;rutile phases in the P25 promotes the electron transfer from P25 to Rh species because of the strong metal&#8211;support interaction. It boosts the Rh0 active site generation, the CO dissociation, and CHx species formation, which is the significant intermediate for ethanol formation. In contrast, the Rh supported on the pure phase anatase or rutile TiO2 presents poor ethanol yield, which mainly produces the Rh+ species. This study provides an effective method to improve the ethanol yield for direct syngas conversion.</description>
      <author>Yang Feng, Yang Zhang, Jungang Wang, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, Maohong Fan, Bo Hou, Debao Li, Baojun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05351</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Oxygen Vacancies Induced by Calcium Substitution in Macroporous La&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Ce&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ca&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for Boosting Low-Temperature Oxidative Coupling of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05094</link>
      <description>Tongtong Wu, Peng Zhang, Yuechang Wei, Jing Xiong, Dawei Han, Tao Li, Yitao Yang, Zhao Zhang, Jian Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391044395

                Surface oxygen vacancies in the catalysts play a key role in improving the catalytic performances for low-temperature oxidative coupling of methane (OCM). Herein, macroporous La2Ce2&#8211;xCaxO7&#8722;&#948; (A2B2O7-type) catalysts with a disordered defective cubic fluorite phased structure were prepared by a citric acid sol&#8211;gel method. The macroporous structure improved the accessibility of the reactants (O2 and CH4) to the active sites. The partial substitution of the B site (Ce) with low-valence calcium (Ca) ions in La2Ce2&#8211;xCaxO7&#8722;&#948; catalysts induced the formation of surface oxygen vacancies, which facilitated the adsorption and activation of O2 molecules to generate the active oxygen species (O2&#8211; species). The O2&#8211; species can boost the activation of CH4 and govern the following step of the oxidative dehydrogenation of C2H6 to C2H4. La2Ce2&#8211;xCaxO7&#8722;&#948; catalysts have high catalytic activity for low-temperature OCM, and the La2Ce1.3Ca0.7O7&#8722;&#948; catalyst with the highest density of O2&#8211; species exhibits the highest catalytic activity during low-temperature OCM into C2H4 and C2H6 (C2) products, i.e., its CH4 conversion, selectivity, and yield of C2 products at 600 &#176;C are 31.0, 65.6, and 20.3%, respectively. Based on the results of multiple experimental characterizations and density functional theory calculations, the mechanism of La2Ce2&#8211;xCaxO7&#8722;&#948; catalysts for the OCM reaction is proposed: surface oxygen vacancies induced by the substitution of the Ce site with Ca ions significantly promote the critical steps of C&#8211;H bond breaking and C&#8211;C bond coupling during the low-temperature OCM reaction. It is important for the design of low-temperature and high-efficiency catalysts for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Tongtong Wu, Peng Zhang, Yuechang Wei, Jing Xiong, Dawei Han, Tao Li, Yitao Yang, Zhao Zhang, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoexcited Nickel-Catalyzed Carbohalogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05994</link>
      <description>Ramon Arora, Mark Lautens, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391096631

                A nickel/blue light-catalyzed carbohalogenation reaction is reported. A nickel catalyst and an inexpensive phosphine ligand promote the reaction of aryl iodides and aryl bromides with &#960; systems to enable the construction of a library of halogenated heterocyclic scaffolds. Mechanistic studies provide insight regarding fundamental steps of the catalytic cycle, including the reversible C&#8211;X bond formation via deuterium labeling and EPR experiments, while preliminary enantioselective results suggest a two-electron migratory insertion.</description>
      <author>Ramon Arora, Mark Lautens</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05994</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Single-Layer Ir Clusters Enabling 100% Selective Chlorine Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05738</link>
      <description>Shuang Li, Xu Guo, Xiaofang Liu, Jianglan Shui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391096719

                The exclusive selectivity of the chlorine evolution reaction (CER) is crucial for the chlor-alkali industry to obtain pure chlorine gas and avoid the cost of separating the byproduct oxygen. However, 100% CER selectivity remains a challenge for the currently known CER catalysts. Here, we report a catalyst of atomic single-layer Ir clusters on CeO2 nanorods (IrSL/CeO2). Under the strong metal/support interaction, IrSL has a strong adsorption to oxygen, thereby suppressing the oxygen evolution reaction. Coupled with the uniform active sites of the single-layer Ir clusters, IrSL/CeO2 achieves almost 100% CER selectivity in acidic NaCl solution ranging from open circuit potential to practical current density levels. In addition, IrSL/CeO2 exhibits 1.7 times higher catalytic activity than its single-atom counterparts, and its noble metal efficiency is 84 times higher than that of commercial anodes (DSAs). Our finding provides a solution to the selective catalysis of chlor-alkali electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Shuang Li, Xu Guo, Xiaofang Liu, Jianglan Shui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Iterative Dual-Metal and Energy Transfer Catalysis Enables Stereodivergence in Alkyne Difunctionalization: Carboboration as Case Study&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00200</link>
      <description>Javier Corpas, Miguel Gomez&#8208;Mendoza, Enrique M. Arpa, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Bo Durbeej, Juan C. Carretero, Pablo Maule&#243;n, Ram&#243;n Gom&#233;z Array&#225;s, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391096721

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ARTICLES ASAPPREVCorrectionNEXTORIGINAL ARTICLEThis notice is a correctionCorrection to &#8220;Iterative Dual-Metal and Energy Transfer Catalysis Enables Stereodivergence in Alkyne Difunctionalization: Carboboration as Case Study&#8221;Javier CorpasJavier CorpasMore by Javier Corpashttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-8598-578X, Miguel Gomez-MendozaMiguel Gomez-MendozaMore by Miguel Gomez-Mendoza, Enrique M. ArpaEnrique M. ArpaMore by Enrique M. Arpahttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-1288-6059, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;SheaV&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;SheaMore by V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Sheahttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-5762-4787, Bo DurbeejBo DurbeejMore by Bo Durbeejhttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-5847-1196, Juan C. CarreteroJuan C. CarreteroMore by Juan C. Carreterohttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-4822-5447, Pablo Maule&#243;n*Pablo Maule&#243;nMore by Pablo Maule&#243;nhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-3116-2534, and Ram&#243;n G&#243;mez Array&#225;s*Ram&#243;n G&#243;mez Array&#225;sMore by Ram&#243;n G&#243;mez Array&#225;shttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-5665-0905Cite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, XXX, 1976Publication Date (Web):January 22, 2024Publication History Received10 January 2024Published online22 January 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00200&#169; 2024 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society. This publication is licensed under CC-BY 4.0. License Summary*You are free to share (copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format and to adapt (remix, transform, and build upon) the material for any purpose, even commercially within the parameters below:Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license.Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.View full license*DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. This publication is Open Access under the license indicated. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InReddit PDF (567 KB) Get e-AlertscloseSUBJECTS:Catalysis,Energy transfer,Hydrocarbons,Stereodivergence Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author>Javier Corpas, Miguel Gomez&#8208;Mendoza, Enrique M. Arpa, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Bo Durbeej, Juan C. Carretero, Pablo Maule&#243;n, Ram&#243;n Gom&#233;z Array&#225;s</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subsurface Mo Vacancy in Bismuth Molybdate Promotes Photocatalytic Oxidation of Lactate to Pyruvate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05263</link>
      <description>Haijun Chen, Ruohan Xu, Dan Chen, Tianliang Lu, H. Li, Min Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391096818

                Disclosing the role of subsurface metal defects in photocatalysts remains challenging, although defect engineering has been a fundamental method for manipulating the photocatalytic transformation performance. Herein, the subsurface Mo vacancy-rich Bi2MoO6 was prepared and the role of its effects on photocatalysis was revealed. The presence of metal vacancy enhances the separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers through both the holes captured by the oxygen atoms neighboring the Mo vacancy and the generation of an internal electric field, which is revealed by experimental results and density functional theory calculations. The boosted separation efficiency of electron&#8211;hole pairs improves the generation of 1O2, which is the final active species for photocatalytic oxidation of ethyl lactate. The conversion of ethyl lactate reaches to &gt;99% over the subsurface Mo vacancy-rich Bi2MoO6 after 3 h of illumination, much higher than that of bulk Bi2MoO6, which gives only 28.6%. Meanwhile, the yield of ethyl pyruvate is 90.2%, which is the highest value in heterogeneous systems using molecular oxygen as oxidant. Moreover, the catalyst is rather stable and can be applied for the selective oxidation of other hydroxyl compounds. This work unveils the role of metal defects engineering in affecting electron&#8211;hole separation, highlighting possible opportunities for highly efficient photocatalytic organic transformation.</description>
      <author>Haijun Chen, Ruohan Xu, Dan Chen, Tianliang Lu, H. Li, Min Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Artificial Photosynthesis: CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Chemisorption and S-Scheme Charge Separation via Anchoring Inorganic QDs on COFs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00026</link>
      <description>Yuehui He, Peiyu Hu, J.C. Zhang, Guijie Liang, Yuanyuan Wang, Fei Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391101394

                Photocatalytic conversion of CO2 into valuable hydrocarbon fuels holds great promise in addressing emerging energy shortages and environmental crises while fulfilling pressing societal and national development demands. Nonetheless, its efficiency is hindered by restricted CO2 chemisorption, rapid electron&#8211;hole recombination, and weak redox capability. Drawing inspiration from the distinctive characteristics of Schiff-based covalent organic frameworks (COFs), including substantial specific surface area, unique pore structure, and an abundance of weakly alkaline nitrogen elements, we employ the TPA-COF to enhance the chemisorption and activation of acidic CO2 molecules, as validated by the CO2-temperature-programmed desorption analysis. Furthermore, anchoring CsPbBr3 quantum dots (QDs) onto the COF facilitates the effective spatial separation of photoinduced charge carriers with strong redox capability, resulting from the formation of S-scheme heterojunctions between the COF and QDs as substantiated by in situ irradiation X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, femtosecond transient absorption spectroscopy, and density functional theory simulations. As anticipated, the optimized COF/QDs heterostructures exhibit remarkable enhancements in CO2 photoreduction performance in the absence of any molecule cocatalyst or scavenger, yielding CO and CH4 at rates of 41.2 and 13.7 &#956;mol g&#8211;1, respectively. This work provides valuable insights into the development of novel organic/inorganic heterojunction photocatalysts with CO2 chemisorption and S-scheme charge separation, offering great potential for sustainable artificial photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Yuehui He, Peiyu Hu, J.C. Zhang, Guijie Liang, Yuanyuan Wang, Fei Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Hydrogenation Kinetic Behavior of Transition Metal Oxides via Decoupling Dihydrogen Dissociation and Substrate Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05175</link>
      <description>Daowei Gao, Daowei Gao, Yipin Lv, Changxu Wang, Jianyu Ren, Peng Zheng, Lianghao Song, Aijun Duan, Xilong Wang, Guozhu Chen, Xu Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391101416

                Both noble metals and transition metal oxides are recognized as active centers for alkyne hydrogenation. However, it is still a &#8220;black box&#8221; how the catalytic behavior of oxides evolves upon the catalytic intervention of noble metals. Herein, we report a modularized strategy to track the hydrogenation mechanism of oxides (e.g., TiO2, CeO2, and ZrO2) using a core&#8211;shell micromesoporous zeolite as a structure model, in which the oxide and noble metal (Pt) are functionally separated within a mesopore shell and a micropore core (TS-1 zeolite), respectively. The Pt species are atomically distributed and stabilized by the oxygen atoms of five-membered rings in TS-1 zeolite, which facilitates the heterolytic activation of dihydrogen over Pt&#948;+&#183;&#183;&#183;O2&#8211; units. The active hydrogen species, i.e., H+ and H&#948;&#8722;, migrate to the oxide surface, where the adsorbed reactants are activated for hydrogenation. Mechanistic studies reveal that TiO2, CeO2, and ZrO2 possess efficient hydrogenation properties at near-room temperature with the assistance of spillover hydrogen species, demonstrating dihydrogen dissociation as the main rate-limiting step for pure oxide. Impressively, the adsorbed H2O molecule on TiO2, ZrO2, and CeO2 not only acts as a bridge of hydrogen spillover in reducing the proton diffusion barrier but also forms H3O+ species on the TiO2 (100) surface and endows TiO2 with extraordinary hydrogenation properties. This work opens the &#8220;black box&#8221; for the hydrogenation behavior of transition metal oxides and develops a molecule-assisted strategy for the rational design of hydrogenation catalysts.</description>
      <author>Daowei Gao, Daowei Gao, Yipin Lv, Changxu Wang, Jianyu Ren, Peng Zheng, Lianghao Song, Aijun Duan, Xilong Wang, Guozhu Chen, Xu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancy Optimized Coordination on Nickel Oxide for Selective Electrocatalytic Oxidation of Glycerol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04568</link>
      <description>Zhongcheng Xia, Chongyang Ma, Yun Fan, Yuxuan Lu, Yu&#8208;Cheng Huang, Yuping Pan, Yandong Wu, Qingyu Luo, Yuanqing He, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391101830

                The production of high-value-added organics by the glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) holds significant research importance for addressing the surplus production of glycerol and mitigating the energy crisis. In this study, we report a vacancy optimized coordination on nickel oxide for the selective electrocatalytic oxidation of glycerol. Using in situ Raman and electron paramagnetic resonance spectroscopy, the formation of vacancies was traced during the cationic leaching process. Subsequently, in situ attenuated total reflection surface-enhanced IR absorption spectroscopy and density functional theory calculations revealed a significantly enhanced adsorption capacity and optimized co-adsorption process of OH&#8211; and organics. Consequently, NiCrO with vacancies (NiCrO-VCr,O) exhibited GOR performance with conversion, formic acid selectivity, and faradaic efficiency values of 99%, 98%, and 96%, respectively. Notably, the conversion and selectivity in the flow electrolyzer remained above 90% during long-time continuous electrolysis, highlighting its industrial applicability. This study provides constructive guidance for the design of electrocatalysts, the optimization of the catalyst ligand environment, and the development of high-performance, metal-based catalysts for glycerol electro-oxidation.</description>
      <author>Zhongcheng Xia, Chongyang Ma, Yun Fan, Yuxuan Lu, Yu&#8208;Cheng Huang, Yuping Pan, Yandong Wu, Qingyu Luo, Yuanqing He, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Restructuring of ZnCr&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Spinel Catalyst Alters Elementary Surface Reaction Kinetics and Catalytic Selectivity in CO Hydrogenation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05739</link>
      <description>Qiulin Nie, Jieqiong Ding, Dongdong Wang, Yang Liu, Wei Xiong, Yong Yang, Weixin Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391102226

                The CO hydrogenation reaction catalyzed by the ZnCr2O4 catalyst is studied using quasi-in situ XPS, temperature-programmed reaction spectroscopy, and temporal in situ diffuse reflectance Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy. At 573 K, the ZnCr2O4 catalyst selectively catalyzes the CH3OH formation reaction, in which the hydrogenation reaction of monodentate formate species is the rate-limiting step with an activation energy of approximately 60.5 kJ/mol. As the temperature increases to 673 K, CO2 and CH4 are produced at the expense of CH3OH, which can be attributed to in situ partial reduction of the ZnCr2O4 catalyst into metallic Zn. On one hand, the CO disproportionation reaction into CO2 and atomic carbon species occurs on the resulting metallic Zn, and the atomic carbon species is subsequently hydrogenated predominantly into CH4; on the other hand, the rate-limiting step of methanol synthesis on the resulting partially reduced ZnCr2O4 catalyst becomes the hydrogenation of the methoxy group with an activation energy of approximately 120.3 kJ/mol, considerably reducing the CH3OH formation rate. These results unveil that the changes in the elementary surface reaction network and the kinetics induced by in situ restructuring of the ZnCr2O4 catalyst in the CO hydrogenation reaction lead to the changes in catalytic selectivity.</description>
      <author>Qiulin Nie, Jieqiong Ding, Dongdong Wang, Yang Liu, Wei Xiong, Yong Yang, Weixin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous Ruthenium&#8211;Selenium Nanoparticles as a pH-Universal Catalyst for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04498</link>
      <description>Ting Zhu, Junnan Han, Teng Sun, Junhua Zhao, Xiaodong Pi, Jun Xu, Kunji Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391105420

                In order to broaden the applications of water splitting for hydrogen production, it is highly desired to develop an ideal catalyst, which can operate in a wide pH range. In this work, we proposed amorphous RuSex nanoparticles (NPs) with a highly disordered structure to introduce abundant surface defects, which contribute to the enhanced HER activity. The optimized RuSe1.5 NPs exhibited the pH-universal activity, which only require an overpotential of 24, 30, and 12 mV to reach a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 (pH = 0), 1 M PBS (pH = 7), and 1 M KOH (pH = 14), respectively. By capitalizing on the synergistic effect between Ru and Se, we have successfully achieved a balance in the strong adsorption of reaction intermediates on Ru sites and significantly improved the performance of HER. This work highlights the crucial role of understanding and harnessing the elemental synergies in the development of optimized HER catalysts and paves the way for the advancement of hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Ting Zhu, Junnan Han, Teng Sun, Junhua Zhao, Xiaodong Pi, Jun Xu, Kunji Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Analysis of the Overpotential Losses in Polymer Electrolyte Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04797</link>
      <description>Meriem Fikry, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Juan Herranz, Pavel Khavlyuk, Alexander Eychm&#252;ller, Thomas J. Schmidt, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391106654

                Polymer electrolyte fuel cells (PEFCs) are expected to play a pivotal role in heavy-duty transportation, but careful benchmarking of the kinetics of the O2-reduction reaction (ORR) and mass transport properties dictating their performance is needed to render them market-competitive. This assessment generally relies on the extrapolation of the kinetic behavior observed at low current densities to the high currents at which mass transport limitations become significant. However, this kinetic regime is generally assumed to obey a simple Tafel law that does not consider the impact of the relative humidity (RH) on the availability of ORR-active sites. To shed light on the implications of this simplified approach, in this study, we compare the ORR parameters and mass transport losses derived from it with those computed using a more complex kinetic model that incorporates site-availability effects. Our results provide an original insight on the impact of the relative humidity on the ORR-performance of catalysts with different active site distributions and show that the mass transport resistances derived by these two quantification procedures are essentially identical as long as the slope of the kinetic Tafel line is adjusted according to the RH.</description>
      <author>Meriem Fikry, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Juan Herranz, Pavel Khavlyuk, Alexander Eychm&#252;ller, Thomas J. Schmidt</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt/Organophotoredox Dual-Catalysis-Enabled Cyclization of 1,5,10-Enediynes Involving Metallole-Mediated Remote C(&lt;i&gt;sp&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Bond Activation Leading to Axially Chiral Aryl Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05848</link>
      <description>Keiji Yamada, Nobuaki Koga, Takeshi Yasui, Yoshihiko Yamamoto, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391127033

                Transition-metal-catalyzed C(sp3)&#8211;H functionalization has been much less investigated compared to C(sp2)&#8211;H functionalization because the site-selectivity control in C(sp3)&#8211;H bond activation is much more challenging than that in C(sp2)&#8211;H bond activation. Site-selective C(sp3)&#8211;H functionalization without the assistance of directing groups is highly desirable, because the installation and removal of directing groups are not required. Hence, cycloaddition through a site-selective C&#8211;H bond activation triggered by the formation of metallacycles, such as metalloles, is a highly atom- and step-economical method for synthesizing complex carbo- and heterocycles from simple unsaturated substrates. Herein, we report the cobalt/photoredox dual-catalysis-enabled cyclization of 1,5,10-enediynes via remote C(sp3)&#8211;H bond activation triggered by metallole formation, affording axially chiral aryl alkenes. Several control experiments and theoretical calculations suggest that the C(sp3)&#8211;H bond cleavage proceeds through &#963;-complex-assisted metathesis (&#963;-CAM) in the metallole intermediate.</description>
      <author>Keiji Yamada, Nobuaki Koga, Takeshi Yasui, Yoshihiko Yamamoto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Interplay of Micropores/Mesopores of Hierarchical Zeolite in Chemical Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05170</link>
      <description>Susung Lee, Younghwan Park, Minkee Choi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391131566

                Zeolites are crystalline microporous aluminosilicates that play a crucial role as solid acid catalysts in refinery and petrochemical processes. Over the past decades, hierarchical zeolites containing secondary mesopores in addition to micropores have been extensively investigated to mitigate the mass transfer limitations of conventional zeolites and improve the catalytic activity, selectivity, and longevity. The hierarchical structuring of zeolites not only improves mass transfer but also changes the distribution of acid sites and adsorption of reaction intermediates, which collectively affect the final catalytic properties of zeolites. In this Perspective, we will discuss the distinctive structural features of hierarchical zeolites compared to conventional ones, as well as their catalytic consequences in industrially relevant reactions for efficient fuel and chemical production.</description>
      <author>Susung Lee, Younghwan Park, Minkee Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Insight into Characterizing the Metal&#8211;Support Interface in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04930</link>
      <description>Junhong Liu, Liwei Chen, Xi Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391136449

                Supported metal species are widely used as catalysts in heterogeneous catalysis. Apart from the extended metal surfaces, metal&#8211;support interfaces also play a crucial role in catalytic performance due to their distinct electronic and geometric structures. However, the complexity and diversity of the metal&#8211;support interfaces hinder further understanding of the nature of the active sites for catalytic reactions. Fortunately, recent advancements in characterization techniques have uncovered deeper insights. This Perspective aims to comprehensively summarize recent breakthroughs in characterizing metal&#8211;support interfaces in heterogeneous catalysts. This summary facilitates the interpretation of these interfaces from both macroscopic and microscopic aspects, ultimately contributing to a fundamental understanding of the structure&#8211;activity relationship.</description>
      <author>Junhong Liu, Liwei Chen, Xi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04930</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Synthesis of Complex Benzoxaboraheterocycles through Chelation-Assisted Rh-Catalyzed [2 + 2 + 2] Cycloaddition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05766</link>
      <description>John M. Halford-McGuff, Marek Varga, David B. Cordes, Aidan P. McKay, Allan J. B. Watson, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391157080

                Benzoxaboraheterocycles (BOBs) are moieties of increasing interest in the pharmaceutical industry; however, the synthesis of these compounds is often difficult or impractical due to the sensitivity of the boron moiety, the requirement for metalation&#8211;borylation protocols, and lengthy syntheses. We report a straightforward, modular approach that enables access to complex examples of the BOB framework through a Rh-catalyzed [2 + 2 + 2] cycloaddition using MIDA-protected alkyne boronic acids. The key to the development of this methodology was overcoming the steric barrier to catalysis by leveraging chelation assistance. We show the utility of the method through synthesis of a broad range of BOB scaffolds, mechanistic information on the chelation effect, intramolecular alcohol-assisted BMIDA hydrolysis, and linear/cyclic BOB limits as well as comparative binding affinities of the product BOB frameworks for ribose-derived biomolecules.</description>
      <author>John M. Halford-McGuff, Marek Varga, David B. Cordes, Aidan P. McKay, Allan J. B. Watson</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching the Oxygen Reduction Route on Pt Using S through d&#8211;p Hybridization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05362</link>
      <description>Maosong Huang, Zipei Cui, Zhuo Li, Wenchao Sheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391166858

                The development of electrocatalysts capable of selective two-electron oxygen reduction reactions (ORRs) has become a major obstacle in the electrochemical synthesis of H2O2. Herein, a series of platinum sulfide catalysts with different sulfur contents were synthesized by a chemical vapor deposition method. The two-electron ORR performance exhibited a &#8220;volcano&#8221; plot relationship with the sulfur content of the catalysts. The PtS1.38/C catalyst with optimal sulfur content achieved a two-electron ORR selectivity of 92% at near zero overpotential and a mass activity of 70.5 A gPt&#8211;1 [0.65 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE)]. Combined spectroscopic studies and density functional theory calculations showed that the introduction of sulfur changed the d band structure of the Pt surface and in turn the binding energy of oxygen-containing species. The PtS1.38/C catalyst was capable of stable batch electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide in an H-cell, maintaining a high productivity of 992 mmolH2O2 g&#8211;1cat h&#8211;1 (0.2 V vs RHE), which has great potential for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Maosong Huang, Zipei Cui, Zhuo Li, Wenchao Sheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steric Effects on CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction with Substituted Mn(bpy)(CO)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;X-Type Catalysts on Multiwalled Carbon Nanotubes Reveal Critical Mechanistic Details</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05771</link>
      <description>Emile E. DeLuca, Thomas C. K. Chan, James M. Taylor, Byunghoon Lee, Rajiv Ramanujam Prabhakar, Clifford P. Kubiak, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391166871

                A series of Mn(bpy-R)(CO)3Br (bpy-R = 4,4&#8242;-R-2,2&#8242;-bipyridine) complexes with systematic substituent variations (R = H, &#8211;Me, &#8211;Et, tBu, and &#8211;Ph) are immobilized on multiwalled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) and investigated as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction to study substituent effects on heterogenized molecular electrocatalysis. The electrochemical response and catalytic activity of each heterogenized complex are characterized, unveiling clear trends across the series investigated. Mn(bpy-Ph)(CO)3Br/MWCNT exhibited the best catalytic performance, producing CO with a Faradaic efficiency of 72% and a current density (JCO) of 7.0 mA/cm2 at low overpotential (&#951; = 0.65 V). Adding steric bulk to the bpy ligands is shown to restrict Mn0&#8211;Mn0 dimerization and cause a shift to two-electron reduction occurring at less negative potentials. The apparent quantity of electroactive catalyst scales inversely with steric bulk, where Mn(bpy-Ph)(CO)3Br exhibits no distinguishable Faradaic features in CV under normal conditions. These results indicate that catalytic performance is optimized by the confinement of electroactive species to the MWCNT interface.</description>
      <author>Emile E. DeLuca, Thomas C. K. Chan, James M. Taylor, Byunghoon Lee, Rajiv Ramanujam Prabhakar, Clifford P. Kubiak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05771</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
