<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:45:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photosynthetic Activity of Covalent Organic Frameworks through Linkage Orientation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00278</link>
      <description>Jie-Yu Yue, Li-Ping Song, Zi-Xian Pan, Peng Yang, Yu Ma, Qing Xu, Bo Tang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392740340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie-Yu Yue, Li-Ping Song, Zi-Xian Pan, Peng Yang, Yu Ma, Qing Xu, Bo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functionally Diverse Peroxygenases by AlphaFold2, Design, and Signal Peptide Shuffling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00883</link>
      <description>Judith M&#252;nch, N.L. Dietz, S. Barber-Zucker, F. Seifert, Susanne Matschi, Pascal P&#252;llmann, Sarel J. Fleishman, Martin J. Weissenborn, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392744707

                Unspecific peroxygenases (UPOs) are fungal enzymes that attract significant attention for their ability to perform versatile oxyfunctionalization reactions using H2O2. Unlike other oxygenases, UPOs do not require additional reductive equivalents or electron transfer chains that complicate basic and applied research. Nevertheless, UPOs generally exhibit low to no heterologous production levels and only four UPO structures have been determined to date by crystallography limiting their usefulness and obstructing research. To overcome this bottleneck, we implemented a workflow that applies PROSS stability design to AlphaFold2 model structures of 10 unique and diverse UPOs followed by a signal peptide shuffling to enable heterologous production. Nine UPOs were functionally produced in Pichia pastoris, including the recalcitrant CciUPO and three UPOs derived from oomycetes&#9472;the first nonfungal UPOs to be experimentally characterized. We conclude that the high accuracy and reliability of new modeling and design workflows dramatically expand the pool of enzymes for basic and applied research.</description>
      <author>Judith M&#252;nch, N.L. Dietz, S. Barber-Zucker, F. Seifert, Susanne Matschi, Pascal P&#252;llmann, Sarel J. Fleishman, Martin J. Weissenborn</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition State Analysis of Key Steps in Dual Photoredox-Cobalt-Catalyzed Elimination of Alkyl Bromides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06324</link>
      <description>Victor O. Nyagilo, Sharath Chandra Mallojjala, Jennifer S. Hirschi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392746939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Victor O. Nyagilo, Sharath Chandra Mallojjala, Jennifer S. Hirschi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights on the Mechanism of Surface-Catalyzed Oxidative Nitrogen Fixation Based on Liquid-Phase Bubble Pin-Plate Discharge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05317</link>
      <description>Qingchuan Wang, Limin Liu, Guoxin Gao, Yuzhi Chen, Yuxin Ouyang, Dongyang Zhang, Yaqiong Su, Shujiang Ding, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392748786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingchuan Wang, Limin Liu, Guoxin Gao, Yuzhi Chen, Yuxin Ouyang, Dongyang Zhang, Yaqiong Su, Shujiang Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Sustainable Lattice Strains of Morphology-Tuned Nanowires in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00451</link>
      <description>Zhi Hui Kong, Zhi Peng Wu, Yazan Maswadeh, Gang Yu, Jorge Vargas, Dominic Caracciolo, Valeri Petkov, Shuang&#8208;Quan Zang, Tao Li, Shuangyin Wang, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392748981

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhi Hui Kong, Zhi Peng Wu, Yazan Maswadeh, Gang Yu, Jorge Vargas, Dominic Caracciolo, Valeri Petkov, Shuang&#8208;Quan Zang, Tao Li, Shuangyin Wang, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxylamine Umpolung in Copper-Catalyzed Cross-Coupling Reactions to Synthesize &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Arylhydroxylamine Derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06020</link>
      <description>Gary Mathieu, Emna Azek, Calvine Lai, H. Lebel, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392749973

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gary Mathieu, Emna Azek, Calvine Lai, H. Lebel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;De Novo&lt;/i&gt; Multienzyme Synthetic Pathways for Lactic Acid Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05489</link>
      <description>Xu-Wei Ding, Jian Rong, Zheng-fan Pan, Xin-Xin Zhu, Zhenqi Zhu, Qi Chen, Zhi Jun Zhang, Jian&#8208;He Xu, Chun-Xiu Li, Gao&#8208;Wei Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392750096

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xu-Wei Ding, Jian Rong, Zheng-fan Pan, Xin-Xin Zhu, Zhenqi Zhu, Qi Chen, Zhi Jun Zhang, Jian&#8208;He Xu, Chun-Xiu Li, Gao&#8208;Wei Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Catalytic Role of Native Glucagon Amyloid Fibrils</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00452</link>
      <description>Ashim Nandi, Aoxuan Zhang, Elad Arad, Raz Jelinek, Arieh Warshel, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392751169

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ashim Nandi, Aoxuan Zhang, Elad Arad, Raz Jelinek, Arieh Warshel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of Lattice Strain in CdS Promotes Photocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00016</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Liang, Xinkui Wang, Xinxin Zhang, Sisi Lin, Min Ji, Qinggang Liu, Min Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392760834

                The key to photocatalysis lies in the efficient separation and migration of photogenerated carriers to the surface for participation in the reaction. However, the recombination of electrons and holes is a major hindrance that reduces the photocatalysis activity. Herein, we developed a method to introduce lattice strain by regulating the crystallinity of the material, thus resulting in an intensive polarization internal electric field, which can promote the separation process of electrons and holes and improve the efficiency of photocatalysis. The degree of strain can be controlled by the solvothermal temperature. Compared with CdS-160 &#176;C, CdS-100 &#176;C with a larger lattice strain degree and internal electric field contributed to a 7-fold enhanced photocatalytic CO evolution from CO2; in addition, the CO/H2 ratio was also increased by 4 times. This study reports the important effects of lattice strain and internal electric field on photogenerated carrier separation and migration, providing valuable insights for designing efficient photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Liang, Xinkui Wang, Xinxin Zhang, Sisi Lin, Min Ji, Qinggang Liu, Min Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous Iridium-Catalyzed Carbene N&#8211;H Bond Insertion with &#945;-Alkyl Diazo Esters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05635</link>
      <description>Ping Guo, Yan Chen, Tao Lei, Shufang Ji, Ruixue Zhang, Zedong Zhang, Xiao Liang, Dingsheng Wang, Yadong Li, Jie Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392761569

                A heterogeneous iridium single-atom site catalyst (Ir-SA) was synthesized and investigated in catalyzing the carbene insertion reaction with challenging &#945;-alkyl diazo ester substrates. With only 0.23 mol % catalyst loading, our Ir-SA demonstrated remarkable performance in heterogeneous carbene N&#8211;H bond insertion reactions involving various (hetero) aryl amines coupled with &#945;-alkyl diazo esters. Notably, in the case of using a chiral diamino substrate with two reactive sites, Ir-SA exhibited high selectivity toward single carbene N&#8211;H insertion, leading to the generation of a class of unsymmetric chiral diamino ligands. Further mechanism study revealed that the lower activation barrier associated with the single N&#8211;H bond insertion step, as compared to either &#946;-hydride elimination or downstream dual N&#8211;H bond insertion, accounted for the remarkable selectivity observed in this carbene insertion reaction catalyzed by Ir-SA.</description>
      <author>Ping Guo, Yan Chen, Tao Lei, Shufang Ji, Ruixue Zhang, Zedong Zhang, Xiao Liang, Dingsheng Wang, Yadong Li, Jie Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05635</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Guided Multiobjective Optimization of a Stereoconvergent Nickel-Catalyzed Reduction of Enol Tosylates to Access Trisubstituted Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00650</link>
      <description>Natalie P. Romer, Dong&#8208;Joo Min, Jason Y. Wang, R. C. Walroth, Kyle A. Mack, Lauren E. Sirois, Francis Gosselin, Daniel Zell, Abigail G. Doyle, Matthew S. Sigman, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392778422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Natalie P. Romer, Dong&#8208;Joo Min, Jason Y. Wang, R. C. Walroth, Kyle A. Mack, Lauren E. Sirois, Francis Gosselin, Daniel Zell, Abigail G. Doyle, Matthew S. Sigman</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemoselective Aerobic Oxidation of Alcohols Utilizing a Vanadium(V) Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05638</link>
      <description>Mitchell J Kitt, Emily Amir, Eleanor R. Sloane, Douglas G. Fraser, John E. Cerritelli, Caroline S. M. Sabanos, James McNeely, John K. Snyder, Linda H. Doerrer, Aaron B. Beeler, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392793212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mitchell J Kitt, Emily Amir, Eleanor R. Sloane, Douglas G. Fraser, John E. Cerritelli, Caroline S. M. Sabanos, James McNeely, John K. Snyder, Linda H. Doerrer, Aaron B. Beeler</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Alkyne Semihydrogenation Catalysis Enabled by Synergistic Chemical and Thermal Modifications of a PdIn MOF</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00310</link>
      <description>Jordan Santiago Martinez, Jaime Mazar&#237;o, Christian Wittee Lopes, Susana Trasobares, Jos&#233; J. Calvino, Giovanni Agostini, Pascual O&#241;a&#8208;Burgos, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392805147

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jordan Santiago Martinez, Jaime Mazar&#237;o, Christian Wittee Lopes, Susana Trasobares, Jos&#233; J. Calvino, Giovanni Agostini, Pascual O&#241;a&#8208;Burgos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple and Directed Immobilization of a Multicopper Oxidase on Flat Bare Gold Electrodes Provides High Catalytic Currents for O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00516</link>
      <description>F. Rizzo, V&#226;nia Brissos, S. Villain, L&#305;&#769;gia O. Martins, Felipe Conzuelo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392805894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>F. Rizzo, V&#226;nia Brissos, S. Villain, L&#305;&#769;gia O. Martins, Felipe Conzuelo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Co Species in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Assisted Ethane Dehydrogenation: Competing Cleavage of C&#8211;H and C&#8211;C Bonds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00324</link>
      <description>Yingbin Zheng, Junjie Li, Xinbao Zhang, Shaoguo Li, Jie An, Fucun Chen, Xiujie Li, Xiangxue Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392812312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingbin Zheng, Junjie Li, Xinbao Zhang, Shaoguo Li, Jie An, Fucun Chen, Xiujie Li, Xiangxue Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lewis Acid Sites in (110) Facet-Exposed BiOBr Promote C&#8211;H Activation and Selective Photocatalytic Toluene Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00877</link>
      <description>Zhou Guang-hong, Ben Lei, Fan Dong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392818266

                Solar photocatalytic technology has exhibited significant potential for upgrading the value-added chemicals industry through efficient C&#8211;H bond activation, such as selective photocatalytic toluene oxidation. However, improvement in the C&#8211;H bond activation of toluene is still a challenge. Herein, (110) facet-exposed BiOBr (EC-BiOBr) synthesized via a facile crystal facet control strategy exhibited an increasing exposure of Lewis acid sites, as confirmed by in situ Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR) using ammonia as a probe molecule. In situ FT-IR results substantiated the improved absorption capacity of EC-BiOBr for toluene. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicated that the Lewis acid&#8211;base pairs formed by Bi sites and O sites can adsorb toluene directionally, precisely matching the orbit spaces of the conduction band (Bi 6p state) and valence band (O 2p and Br 4p states). Benefiting from the oriented adsorption of toluene, the electron in the C&#8211;H bond could transfer to a photogenerated hole precisely, thus achieving C&#8211;H bond activation. Compared to (001) facet-exposed BiOBr (H&#8211;BiOBr), an 11-fold improvement in the toluene conversion rate (from 233 to 2460 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1) was observed in the EC-BiOBr group, and the benzaldehyde formation rate increased from 233 to 1623 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1. Active species identification and DFT calculations revealed that the superoxide radicals were involved as the primary reactive species in the subsequent oxidation of benzyl radicals generated from the C&#8211;H bond activation of toluene. This work highlights the importance of the surface acid sites regulated by the crystal facet control strategy, which is conducive to the rational design of photocatalysts with high performance in C&#8211;H bond activation.</description>
      <author>Zhou Guang-hong, Ben Lei, Fan Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lewis and Br&#248;nsted Acid Synergistic Catalysis for Efficient Synthesis of Hydroxylamine over Heteroatom Zeolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00179</link>
      <description>Nan Fang, Kai Huo, Yucheng Jin, Dongxu Li, Henry C. Lin, Haoyue Wu, Xuguang Liu, Yueming Liu, Min He, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392818365

                Environmental and efficient synthesis of NH2OH is challenging. Herein, we have provided a route for efficient NH2OH formation by NH3 oxidation via the synergistic catalysis of Lewis acid sites of the framework Ti (Ti LAS) and Br&#248;nsted acid sites of the framework Al (Al BAS) in Ti&#8211;Al-MOR zeolites. Ti LAS was the active center for formation of transition-state NH2OH, while Al BAS could provide the proton H to convert transition-state NH2OH absorbed on Ti LAS to a [NH3OH]+ species. Protonation effect would not only promote the catalytic cycle process resulting from accelerating the desorption of transition-state NH2OH, but also improve the stability of NH2OH, being less prone to oxidative decomposition. In this work, we presented the synergistic catalysis between LAS and BAS over Ti-containing heteroatom zeolites to accelerate the catalytic cycle, which provided an environmental and efficient method for NH2OH formation.</description>
      <author>Nan Fang, Kai Huo, Yucheng Jin, Dongxu Li, Henry C. Lin, Haoyue Wu, Xuguang Liu, Yueming Liu, Min He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Codecoration of Phosphate and Iron for Improving Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Layered Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/NiOOH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00229</link>
      <description>Yuexiang Li, Junliang Liu, Shuqi Li, Shaoqin Peng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392858728

                Hydrogen production through electrochemical water splitting (EWS) presents a viable solution for addressing the fossil energy crisis. However, the commercial viability of this approach is impeded by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). It is urgently needed to develop efficient, stable, and cost-effective OER electrocatalysts. Herein, we comprehensively design and investigate a phosphate ion and Fe3+ codecorating Ni(OH)2/NiOOH electrocatalyst (Pi-Fe:NiOH) for OER. This codecoration induces multiple synergistic effects, which include an increase in the interlayer water content for the internal OER, altering the OER mechanism, facilitating proton transport across the layers, and improving the stability of Pi-Fe:NiOH. Consequently, Pi-Fe:NiOH exhibits a high OER activity with overpotentials of 118 &#177; 1 and 222 &#177; 4 mV at current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8211;2, respectively. More impressively, it maintains stable operation at a high current density of around 300 mA cm&#8211;2 for at least 500 h, much better than the Ni(OH)2/NiOOH electrocatalyst (NiOH) for less than 6 h at a current density below 200 mA cm&#8211;2. These findings offer insights for the design of anion&#8211;cation codoped hydroxide eletrocatalysts, paving a way for the development of efficient and stable OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuexiang Li, Junliang Liu, Shuqi Li, Shaoqin Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Temperature &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Allylation of Allylic Alcohols via Synergistic Pd/Cu Catalysis: A Silica-Supported Dual-Metal-Complex Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00638</link>
      <description>Shun-ichi Sakai, Shingo Hasegawa, Siming Ding, Ryota Osuga, Kiyotaka Nakajima, Shinji Tanaka, Wang&#8208;Jae Chun, Ken Motokura, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392862288

                N-allylation is an important method for constructing C&#8211;N bonds in fine chemical synthesis. Accumulation of catalytically active species on the same support surface is a promising approach for achieving high catalytic efficiency. In this study, we developed a catalyst comprising Pd and Cu complexes immobilized on a silica surface. The dual-metal-complex catalyst catalyzed the N-allylation of aniline using allyl alcohol at the low temperature of 30 &#176;C with tunable selectivity toward mono- and disubstituted products. The coimmobilization of a Cu complex increased the turnover number of the Pd complex 5.3 times, which was much higher than those of reported heterogeneous catalysts used at reaction temperatures higher than 100 &#176;C. A wide substrate scope, recyclability, and suppression of aggregation and leaching were also confirmed. Whereas synergy was scarcely observed for the simple mixture of homogeneous Pd and Cu complexes, the dual-complex catalyst exhibited significant synergy, indicating concerted catalysis on the solid surface. Spectroscopic analysis, including XAFS, in situ IR, and DNP-enhanced 15N NMR, and density functional theory calculations indicated that an aniline molecule is activated by the Cu complex, resulting in the efficient nucleophilic attack to a &#960;-allylpalladium intermediate.</description>
      <author>Shun-ichi Sakai, Shingo Hasegawa, Siming Ding, Ryota Osuga, Kiyotaka Nakajima, Shinji Tanaka, Wang&#8208;Jae Chun, Ken Motokura</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i006_1781035</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392863198

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i006_1781035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i006_1781034</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392863485

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i006_1781034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Stable Self-Cleaning Paints Based on Waste-Valorized PNC-Doped TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06203</link>
      <description>Qaisar Maqbool, O. Favoni, Thomas Wicht, Niusha Lasemi, Simona Sabbatini, Michael St&#246;ger&#8208;Pollach, Maria Letizia Ruello, Francesca Tittarelli, G&#252;nther Rupprechter, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392864297

                Adding photocatalytically active TiO2 nanoparticles (NPs) to polymeric paints is a feasible route toward self-cleaning coatings. While paint modification by TiO2-NPs may improve photoactivity, it may also cause polymer degradation and release of toxic volatile organic compounds. To counterbalance adverse effects, a synthesis method for nonmetal (P, N, and C)-doped TiO2-NPs is introduced, based purely on waste valorization. PNC-doped TiO2-NP characterization by vibrational and photoelectron spectroscopy, electron microscopy, diffraction, and thermal analysis suggests that TiO2-NPs were modified with phosphate (P&#9552;O), imine species (R&#9552;N-R), and carbon, which also hindered the anatase/rutile phase transformation, even upon 700 &#176;C calcination. When added to water-based paints, PNC-doped TiO2-NPs achieved 96% removal of surface-adsorbed pollutants under natural sunlight or UV, paralleled by stability of the paint formulation, as confirmed by micro-Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) surface analysis. The origin of the photoinduced self-cleaning properties was rationalized by three-dimensional (3D) and synchronous photoluminescence spectroscopy, indicating that the dopants led to 7.3 times stronger inhibition of photoinduced e&#8211;/h+ recombination when compared to a benchmark P25 photocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Qaisar Maqbool, O. Favoni, Thomas Wicht, Niusha Lasemi, Simona Sabbatini, Michael St&#246;ger&#8208;Pollach, Maria Letizia Ruello, Francesca Tittarelli, G&#252;nther Rupprechter</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Photocatalyzed Divergent Access to Organic Thio- and Isothiocyanates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00565</link>
      <description>Youssef Abderrazak, Oliver Reiser, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392878350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youssef Abderrazak, Oliver Reiser</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atroposelective Synthesis of Diarylamines via Organocatalyzed Electrophilic Amination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00414</link>
      <description>Zidan Ye, Wansen Xie, Donglei Wang, Hua Lee, Xiaoyu Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392900769

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zidan Ye, Wansen Xie, Donglei Wang, Hua Lee, Xiaoyu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Poisoning Is Avoided in a Step of Relevance to the Haber&#8211;Bosch Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06201</link>
      <description>S. K. Tripathi, Luigi Bonati, Simone Perego, Michele Parrinello, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392906279

                For a catalyst to be efficient and durable, it is crucial that the reaction products do not poison the catalyst. In the case of the Haber&#8211;Bosch process, the rate-limiting step is believed to be the decomposition of nitrogen molecules on the Fe(111) surface. This step leads to the production on the surface of atomic nitrogen (N*), which, unless hydrogenated and eventually released as ammonia, remains adsorbed and occupies the active sites. Thus, it is important to ascertain how a high N* coverage affects the nitrogen dissociative chemisorption. To answer this question, we study the properties of the Fe(111) surface at different N* coverage both at room and operando temperature. In the latter regime, we have already found that Fe surface atoms exhibit a high mobility, promoting the formation of adatoms and vacancies, and causing the catalytic centers to acquire a finite lifetime [Bonati et al. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 2023, 120 (50), e2313023120]. We discover that the N* coverage reduces but does not eliminate the iron mobility. Remarkably, the N* atoms stabilize triangular surface structures associated with the formation of vacancies, which are a sign of a frustrated drive toward a more stable Fe4N phase. As a consequence, nitrogen atoms tend to cluster, reducing their poisoning effect. At the same time, the reduction in the number of catalytic centers is counteracted by an increase in their lifetime. The combined effect is that the dissociation barrier is not significantly altered in the range of coverages studied. These results bring to light the complex role that dynamics plays in catalytic reactivity under operando conditions.</description>
      <author>S. K. Tripathi, Luigi Bonati, Simone Perego, Michele Parrinello</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06201</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
