<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 01:07:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese-Catalyzed Synthesis of Polyketones Using Hydrogen-Borrowing Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03019</link>
      <description>Pavel S. Kulyabin, Oxana V. Magdysyuk, Aaron B. Naden, Daniel M. Dawson, Ketan Pancholi, Matthew Walker, Massimo Vassalli, Amit Kumar, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400111554

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pavel S. Kulyabin, Oxana V. Magdysyuk, Aaron B. Naden, Daniel M. Dawson, Ketan Pancholi, Matthew Walker, Massimo Vassalli, Amit Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Electrochemical Methane Oxidation Mechanism through the In Situ Detection of Reaction Intermediates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00675</link>
      <description>Tareq A. Al&#8208;Attas, Kannimuthu Karthick, Mohd Adnan Khan, Md Golam Kibria, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400111866

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tareq A. Al&#8208;Attas, Kannimuthu Karthick, Mohd Adnan Khan, Md Golam Kibria</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Career in Catalysis: Enrique Iglesia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02557</link>
      <description>David G. Barton, Aditya Bhan, Prashant Deshlahra, Rajamani Gounder, David Hibbitts, Beata A. Kilos, Gina Noh, Justin M. Notestein, Michele L. Sarazen, S. Soled, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400112900

                No abstract</description>
      <author>David G. Barton, Aditya Bhan, Prashant Deshlahra, Rajamani Gounder, David Hibbitts, Beata A. Kilos, Gina Noh, Justin M. Notestein, Michele L. Sarazen, S. Soled</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02557</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient and Selective Nitrogen Reduction Reaction Catalysis of Cluster-Modified MXene Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01369</link>
      <description>Yu Rong, Zhaorui Liu, Dominik Legut, J. Sun, Qianfan Zhang, Joseph S. Francisco, Ruifang Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400119996

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Rong, Zhaorui Liu, Dominik Legut, J. Sun, Qianfan Zhang, Joseph S. Francisco, Ruifang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Photocatalytic Activity of CaTaO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N for Overall Water Splitting through Surface Nitride Ion Enrichment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01590</link>
      <description>Xuecheng Liu, Linjie Yan, Wenpeng Li, Kaihong Chen, Faze Wang, Jiadong Xiao, Takashi Hisatomi, Tsuyoshi Takata, Kazunari Domen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400123390

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuecheng Liu, Linjie Yan, Wenpeng Li, Kaihong Chen, Faze Wang, Jiadong Xiao, Takashi Hisatomi, Tsuyoshi Takata, Kazunari Domen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Radical-Type 1,2-Alkoxy-Sulfenylation of Benzoxazole-2-Thiols to Vinylarenes Catalyzed by Chiral Vanadyl Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02460</link>
      <description>Yueh-Hua Liu, Hon&#8208;Chung Tsui, Pei-Hsuan Chien, Chien&#8208;Tien Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400129690

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yueh-Hua Liu, Hon&#8208;Chung Tsui, Pei-Hsuan Chien, Chien&#8208;Tien Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmable Wet-Interfacial Joule Heating to Rapidly Synthesize Metastable Protohematite Photoanodes: Metal and Lattice Oxygen Dual Sites for Improving Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02690</link>
      <description>Jiujun Deng, Guoqing Li, Dongpeng Yan, Wei Zhang, Kun Feng, Kaiqi Nie, Changhai Liu, Xiaoxin Lv, Jun Zhong, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400166207

                High-temperature sintering is critical for efficient hematite photoanodes in terms of improving the crystallinity and minimizing deficiencies. However, prolonged conventional furnace annealing requires high energy consumption and simultaneously results in serious damage to the transparent conducting oxide (TCO) substrate. This work demonstrates a universal wet-interfacial Joule heating strategy for rapidly synthesizing high-performance metastable protohematite photoanodes, which greatly decreases the power consumption and causes less damage to the TCO substrate by shortening the sintering time to &#8764;90 s. More importantly, the protohematite phase was found to effectively facilitate the charge dynamics in the bulk and surface of the as-resulting photoanode by increasing donor density and lowering the oxygen evolution reaction overpotential via offering dual active sites (lattice oxygen and Fe sites). Moreover, this annealing strategy could be well coupled with commonly used Ti-treatment to achieve a further performance enhancement and also shows high feasibility in rapidly fabricating efficient TiO2 and BiVO4 photoanodes. This study opens a facile, rapid, and reliable approach for fabricating efficient metal oxide photoanodes, contributing to the development of photoelectrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Jiujun Deng, Guoqing Li, Dongpeng Yan, Wei Zhang, Kun Feng, Kaiqi Nie, Changhai Liu, Xiaoxin Lv, Jun Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst in Sight: The Use of Benchtop NMR Spectrometers to Maintain the Activity of Pd-PPh&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02606</link>
      <description>Niklas Wessel, Rucha S. Medhekar, Markus Sonnenberg, Hannah Stieber, Walter Leitner, Andreas J. Vorholt, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400183750

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Niklas Wessel, Rucha S. Medhekar, Markus Sonnenberg, Hannah Stieber, Walter Leitner, Andreas J. Vorholt</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biocatalytic Construction of Spiro-Oxazolidinones via Halohydrin Dehalogenase-Catalyzed Ring Expansion of Spiro-Epoxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02122</link>
      <description>Jin-Mei Ma, Yuanfei Wang, Run&#8208;Ping Miao, Xiao Ling Jin, Huihui Wang, Yong&#8208;Zheng Chen, Nan&#8208;Wei Wan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400205640

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jin-Mei Ma, Yuanfei Wang, Run&#8208;Ping Miao, Xiao Ling Jin, Huihui Wang, Yong&#8208;Zheng Chen, Nan&#8208;Wei Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into the Selective C&#8211;S Bond Formation by P450 TleB</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03328</link>
      <description>Huiyuan Gao, Yongzhe Fan, Xiaozhou He, Xiaogang Peng, Zhen Li, Yao Zheng, Shengfu Ji, Long&#8208;Wu Ye, Aitao Li, Binju Wang, Jing Zhao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400212769

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huiyuan Gao, Yongzhe Fan, Xiaozhou He, Xiaogang Peng, Zhen Li, Yao Zheng, Shengfu Ji, Long&#8208;Wu Ye, Aitao Li, Binju Wang, Jing Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Size of TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported Co Nanoparticle Fischer&#8211;Tropsch Catalysts Using Mn Additions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02721</link>
      <description>M. W. Lindley, P. V. Stishenko, James W. M. Crawley, Fred Tinkamanyire, Matthew D. Smith, James Paterson, Mark Peacock, Zhuoran Xu, Christopher Hardacre, Alex S. Walton, Andrew J. Logsdail, Sarah J. Haigh, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400213310

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. W. Lindley, P. V. Stishenko, James W. M. Crawley, Fred Tinkamanyire, Matthew D. Smith, James Paterson, Mark Peacock, Zhuoran Xu, Christopher Hardacre, Alex S. Walton, Andrew J. Logsdail, Sarah J. Haigh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and Catalytic Performance of Bimetallic Oxide-Derived CuO&#8211;ZnO Electrocatalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01575</link>
      <description>Matt L. J. Peerlings, Kai Han, A. Longo, Kristiaan H. Helfferich, Mahnaz Ghiasi, Petra E. de Jongh, Peter Ngene, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400227941

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matt L. J. Peerlings, Kai Han, A. Longo, Kristiaan H. Helfferich, Mahnaz Ghiasi, Petra E. de Jongh, Peter Ngene</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen Vacancy-Rich C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-Confined Fe&#8211;Cu Diatomic Catalysts for the Direct Selective Oxidation of Methane at Low Temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01328</link>
      <description>Wencui Li, Zhi Li, Hongfang Shen, Jiaxin Cai, Hongyu Jing, Shigang Xin, Zengwen Cao, Zean Xie, Dong Liu, Hang Zhang, Zhao Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400228590

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wencui Li, Zhi Li, Hongfang Shen, Jiaxin Cai, Hongyu Jing, Shigang Xin, Zengwen Cao, Zean Xie, Dong Liu, Hang Zhang, Zhao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electric Field Stabilized Ru Single-Atom Catalysts for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01829</link>
      <description>Liu Yang, Zitao Ni, Yifan Zhao, Youyu Long, Min Xi, Anran Chen, Hua Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400274434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liu Yang, Zitao Ni, Yifan Zhao, Youyu Long, Min Xi, Anran Chen, Hua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Computational Insights into the Noncanonical Aromatization in Fungal Polyketide Biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01043</link>
      <description>Hang Wang, Chao Peng, Xiaoxuan Chen, Haoyang Wang, Run Yang, He Xiang, Qiu&#8208;Fen Hu, Ling Liu, Lung Wa Chung, Yudai Matsuda, Weiguang Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400281718

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hang Wang, Chao Peng, Xiaoxuan Chen, Haoyang Wang, Run Yang, He Xiang, Qiu&#8208;Fen Hu, Ling Liu, Lung Wa Chung, Yudai Matsuda, Weiguang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Dual Active Sites in Perovskite Oxide for Targeted Photocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02793</link>
      <description>Yibo Gao, Miaomiao Zhang, Yang Jin, Yanpeng Mao, Wenlong Wang, Zhanlong Song, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400288640

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yibo Gao, Miaomiao Zhang, Yang Jin, Yanpeng Mao, Wenlong Wang, Zhanlong Song</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reactive Oxygen from Support Corrects the Nominal Supported Metal Size Effect in Controlling the Reactivity for Low-Temperature CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reforming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02608</link>
      <description>H.Y. Wang, Yaozhong Hu, Yongli Shen, Ewa Chukwu, Wei Xi, Gurong Shen, Jun Wang, Meiqing Shen, Ming Yang, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400297457

                Modulating the metal&#8211;support interfacial structure to achieve coke elimination is highly desired for low-temperature CH4/CO2 reforming. Nonetheless, explicit effects of optimizing the supported metal size and catalyst support properties remain convoluted and sometimes controversial. Herein, we designed different Pt&#8211;CeO2 interfaces by tuning the surface reactive oxygen (SRO) from ceria and the in situ aggregated nanoparticle size developed from single-atom Pt as independent parameters. Intriguingly, the often-emphasized nominal Pt size effect (0.3&#8211;10.5 nm) is secondary due to carbon deposition, while the catalyst with a high SRO concentration exhibits outstanding reactivity. We demonstrated that the SRO from ceria corrects the nominal supported metal size effect in controlling the low-temperature CH4/CO2 reforming reactivity. Specifically, in the Pt&#8211;Ox&#8211;Ce interfacial microstructure, SRO oxidizes the deposited carbon as an oxygen reservoir, making interfacial Pt atoms remain active from coke, and therefore determines the reactivity rather than the nominal Pt species size. In situ characterizations and theoretical studies explained the reaction mechanism of SRO and carbon elimination. This work provides new insights for coke-resistant catalyst design and the coke elimination mechanism.</description>
      <author>H.Y. Wang, Yaozhong Hu, Yongli Shen, Ewa Chukwu, Wei Xi, Gurong Shen, Jun Wang, Meiqing Shen, Ming Yang, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02608</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
