<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 01:46:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>C&#8211;H Activation and Sequential Addition to Dienes and Imines: Synthesis of Amines with &#946;-Quaternary Centers and Mechanistic Studies on the Complex Interplay Between the Catalyst and Three Reactants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05866</link>
      <description>Ramsey M. Goodner, Daniel S. Brandes, Gabriel N. Morais, Tao Qin, Joseph P. Tassone, Brandon Q. Mercado, Shuming Chen, Jonathan A. Ellman, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404650722

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ramsey M. Goodner, Daniel S. Brandes, Gabriel N. Morais, Tao Qin, Joseph P. Tassone, Brandon Q. Mercado, Shuming Chen, Jonathan A. Ellman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05866</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halloysite Clay Nanotubes for Catalytic Conversion of Biomass: Synergy between Computational Modeling and Experimental Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05907</link>
      <description>Lorenzo Lisuzzo, Ludovico Guercio, Giuseppe Cavallaro, Dario Duca, Francesco Ferrante, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404678088

                Halloysite clay nanotubes (HNTs) are emerging nanomaterials for numerous environmental applications, including catalysis and biomass valorization. The efficacy of halloysite as a nanoplatform for the catalytic conversion of biomass can be accurately evaluated by combined approaches based on experimental investigations and computational modeling. Recently, many efforts have been made to properly describe the most peculiar features of halloysite by focusing on its structural and interfacial features through computational studies, which are challenging for natural clay nanoparticles yet crucial for the design of novel catalysts to be exploited in biomass conversion. Within this framework, this review critically and extensively discusses recent advancements related to the use of halloysite in different catalytic processes, such as enzymatic reactions, precious- and nonprecious-metal- and alloy-catalyzed reactions, and acid-activated mechanisms. The research gap on the computational modeling of biomass chemical conversion occurring on halloysite surfaces is highlighted throughout this review, together with the latest experimental achievements. To optimize the catalytic efficiency of halloysite-based materials for biomass valorization, future efforts should focus on the implementation of experimental data with calculations provided by proper models in a synergistic approach.</description>
      <author>Lorenzo Lisuzzo, Ludovico Guercio, Giuseppe Cavallaro, Dario Duca, Francesco Ferrante</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of Nickel Siloxycarbene Complexes from Acylsilanes for the Catalytic Synthesis of Silyl Enol Ethers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06272</link>
      <description>Akihisa Matsuura, Yuri Ito, Tetsuya Inagaki, Takuya Kodama, Mamoru Tobisu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404685890

                A catalytic protocol has been developed to access Fischer carbene nickel complexes using acylsilanes as stable and readily available precursors. The as-generated Fischer carbene complexes exhibit versatile reactivity, including cyclopropanation with alkenes, &#945;-C&#8211;H insertion reactions, and two-component C&#8211;H addition to norbornene, which demonstrates the broad utility of the nickel(0)/acylsilane system for the catalytic applications of Fischer carbene complexes.</description>
      <author>Akihisa Matsuura, Yuri Ito, Tetsuya Inagaki, Takuya Kodama, Mamoru Tobisu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Assembly of &lt;i&gt;E&lt;/i&gt;-Selective Trisubstituted Alkenylborons via Nickel-Catalyzed Reductive Dicarbofunctionalization of Ethynylboron</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05549</link>
      <description>Yifan Ping, Jianbo Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404692174

                While alkenylborons have emerged as powerful precursors for the stereospecific construction of substituted alkenes, efficient synthetic methods toward stereodefined trisubstituted alkenylborons remain limited. Herein, we report a modular and practical approach for the stereoselective synthesis of E-trisubstituted alkenylborons through the nickel-catalyzed three-component reductive coupling of two readily available carbon electrophiles with an ethynyl-Bdan reagent. The protocol exhibits a broad substrate scope and good functional group tolerance, providing expedient access to a variety of trisubstituted alkenylborons with exclusive E-selectivity. The work demonstrates the possibility of applying ethynyl-Bdan as a type of boron reagent in organic synthesis.</description>
      <author>Yifan Ping, Jianbo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Robust Ceria-Supported Catalysts for Catalytic NO Reduction and CO/Hydrocarbon Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04433</link>
      <description>Inhak Song, Libor Kovarik, Mark Engelhard, J&#225;nos Szanyi, Yong Wang, Konstantin Khivantsev, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404711520

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Inhak Song, Libor Kovarik, Mark Engelhard, J&#225;nos Szanyi, Yong Wang, Konstantin Khivantsev</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04433</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Unsymmetrical Disulfides via Photocatalytic Hydrodisulfuration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06457</link>
      <description>Qi-Rui Dong, Yisen Wang, Juan Zhang, Honghong Chang, Jun Tian, Wen&#8208;Chao Gao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi-Rui Dong, Yisen Wang, Juan Zhang, Honghong Chang, Jun Tian, Wen&#8208;Chao Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulsed Electrolysis in Membrane Electrode Assembly Architecture for Enhanced Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction Reaction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05225</link>
      <description>Ramireddy Boppella, Maryam Ahmadi, B Arndt, Danielle R. Lustig, Mohammadreza Nazemi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ramireddy Boppella, Maryam Ahmadi, B Arndt, Danielle R. Lustig, Mohammadreza Nazemi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into Roles of Rare-Earth Metals in Heterobimetallic Ni&#8211;Y Bifunctional Catalysis for Alkyne Semihydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05093</link>
      <description>Peifeng Su, Huayu Liang, Yinwu Li, Zhuofeng Ke, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404738907

                Due to the unique properties of rare-earth (RE) metals, RE catalysts demonstrate distinctive catalytic performance in hydrogenation and related transformations. In typical RE catalytic systems, the roles and function modes have been studied and are relevant to ligands. In recent years, heterobimetallic catalytic systems have emerged for efficient hydrogenation and related transformations. Among these systems, heterobimetallic catalysts with transition metal (TM)-RE combinations integrate the characteristics of TM catalysis and RE catalysis, exhibiting a TM-RE bifunctional effect with remarkable activity and selectivity. However, the roles of RE metals in TM-RE bifunctional catalysis remain ambiguous. This theoretical study takes the Ni&#8211;Y system as a study case, aiming to elucidate the significant roles of the RE center in the TM-RE bifunctional effect on catalytic alkyne semihydrogenation. The results suggest that dynamic coordination can occur at the Y center due to its large size and coordination ability, which accepts the binding of phosphine groups of the ligand. The dynamic coordination of phosphine groups to the large-size RE center assists the Ni center in releasing vacant sites for substrate in-cage binding and reduces the steric effect on the Ni center. Meanwhile, the Lewis acidic RE center can stabilize the bridging hydride, which is crucial for H2 activation and hydrogenation. The TM-RE bifunctional effect promotes the reaction. During the H2 activation stage, due to the stabilization of nickel hydrides by yttrium, the fac-pathway is more favored. The Ni&#8211;H&#8211;Y bridging structure is maintained during the initial hydride insertion in the semihydrogenation stage, which is crucial for the reaction. Additionally, the use of the more active terminal hydride makes the terminal hydride pathway a more plausible mechanism. Benefiting from the capability of yttrium to accept the dynamic coordination of phosphine groups, thereby releasing steric hindrance and stabilizing the bridging hydride concurrently, (Z)/(E)-isomerization can proceed to achieve (E)-selectivity through the H2-assisted Ni&#8211;Y bifunctional pathway with a relatively low energy barrier. Owing to the RE-bridging hydride stabilization effect, the thermodynamic properties of intermediates are closely related to the size of the RE metal center, thereby influencing the activity and the (Z)/(E)-selectivity. These results underscore the important roles of the RE center in TM-RE bifunctional catalysis, offering valuable insights into the future design of effective bifunctional TM-RE catalysts.</description>
      <author>Peifeng Su, Huayu Liang, Yinwu Li, Zhuofeng Ke</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Synthesis of 5-Amino-1-pentanol via Selective Hydrogenolysis of Biomass-Derived Furfurylamine on Supported Platinum Catalysts at Ambient Temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05122</link>
      <description>Guoliang Li, Tong Wang, Cheng&#8208;Bin Hong, Haichao Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404740052

                5-Amino-1-pentanol (APO) is an important nitrogen-containing chemical with versatile applications. However, its synthesis is still not efficient. Here, we report the synthesis of APO from biomass-derived furfurylamine (FAM) via the direct cleavage of its &#945;&#8211;C&#8211;O bond neighboring the &#8722;CH2NH2 group at ambient temperature. Pt/TiO2 catalysts exhibited high efficiency and stability in the FAM hydrogenolysis to APO, affording a high yield of 85.4% at 30 &#176;C and 2.0 MPa of H2 in water. The high efficiency of Pt/TiO2 was found to be related to its superior activity for the cleavage of the &#945;&#8211;C&#8211;O bond in FAM, relative to the hydrogenation of the furan ring on the corner and edge sites of the Pt surfaces. This work provides a viable approach for the precise cleavage of the &#945;&#8211;C&#8211;O bond neighboring the &#8722;CH2NH2 group in the furan ring under mild conditions toward the efficient production of APO and its derivatives.</description>
      <author>Guoliang Li, Tong Wang, Cheng&#8208;Bin Hong, Haichao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Catalytic Hydrogen Transfer Cascade Reactions via Tandem Catalyst Design by Coupling Co Single Atoms with Adjacent Co Clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05569</link>
      <description>Zhanwei Chen, Shaowei Yang, Jie Yang, Bo Zhang, Hao Jiang, Runze Gao, Tianshuai Wang, Qiuyu Zhang, Hepeng Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404749349

                The catalytic hydrogen transfer (CHT) cascade reaction coupling alcohols with nitro compounds to synthesize imines is highly significant due to its remarkable efficiency and atom economy. However, the complicated multistep reaction process makes single-site catalysts exhibit unsatisfactory catalytic performance for the CHT cascade reaction. Herein, inspired by the findings of DFT calculations that Co nanocluster (CoNC) and Co single atom (CoSA) can act as the optimal active sites for alcohol oxidation and nitro reduction, respectively, one dual-active site catalyst (CoSA-CoNC/CN), containing CoSA and CoNC sites, was synthesized by a two-step vacuum pyrolysis strategy. Benefiting from the relay-like tandem catalysis of CoNC and CoSA, CoSA-CoNC/CN achieved an impressive 93% nitrobenzene conversion and 99% imine selectivity at 160 &#176;C in 4 h, with a record turnover frequency of 20.9 h&#8211;1. This work provides insights into the functions of single-atom and nanocluster active sites in the CHT cascade reaction and sheds light on the rational preparation of tandem catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhanwei Chen, Shaowei Yang, Jie Yang, Bo Zhang, Hao Jiang, Runze Gao, Tianshuai Wang, Qiuyu Zhang, Hepeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05569</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Mechanism of SARS-CoV-2 3-Chymotrypsin-Like Protease as Determined by Steady-State and Pre-Steady-State Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04695</link>
      <description>Jiyun Zhu, A. Kemp, Balachandra Chenna, Vivek Kumar, Andrew Rademacher, Sangho Yun, Arthur Laganowsky, Thomas D. Meek, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404762047

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiyun Zhu, A. Kemp, Balachandra Chenna, Vivek Kumar, Andrew Rademacher, Sangho Yun, Arthur Laganowsky, Thomas D. Meek</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Corrosive Cl&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;-Induced Rapid Surface Reconstruction of Amorphous NiFeCoP Enables Efficient Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05704</link>
      <description>Yang Yu, Wei Zhou, Xiaohan Zhou, Junshu Yuan, Xuewei Zhang, Sheng Wang, Jingyu Li, Xiaoxiao Meng, Fei Sun, Jihui Gao, Guangbo Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404772438

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Yu, Wei Zhou, Xiaohan Zhou, Junshu Yuan, Xuewei Zhang, Sheng Wang, Jingyu Li, Xiaoxiao Meng, Fei Sun, Jihui Gao, Guangbo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Conversion of Biomass and Nitrate into Glycine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05235</link>
      <description>Peifeng Li, Biaobiao Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404799850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peifeng Li, Biaobiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effectively Regulating Electrooxidation of Formic Acid over Bimetallic PtCo Alloys via the Integration of Theory and Experiment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06198</link>
      <description>Zhikeng Zheng, Bin Liu, Jiaxiang Qiu, Shaojun Xu, Yuchen Wang, Man Zhang, Ke Li, Zhongti Sun, Ziang Li, Yangyang Wan, C. Richard A. Catlow, Kai Yan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404831841

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhikeng Zheng, Bin Liu, Jiaxiang Qiu, Shaojun Xu, Yuchen Wang, Man Zhang, Ke Li, Zhongti Sun, Ziang Li, Yangyang Wan, C. Richard A. Catlow, Kai Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Analysis of Cyclization by the Substrate-Tolerant Lanthipeptide Synthetase ProcM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06216</link>
      <description>Emily K. Desormeaux, Garrett J. Barksdale, Wilfred A. van der Donk, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404834790

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Emily K. Desormeaux, Garrett J. Barksdale, Wilfred A. van der Donk</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Investigations of MUC1 O-Glycosylation Process Reveal Initial Site Preference by the Polypeptide GalNAc Transferases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05719</link>
      <description>Han Zhang, Kaiyuan Song, Yihan Liu, Fang Yang, Congcong Lu, Rumeng Wei, Zhijue Xu, Xia Zou, Liang Lin, Ting Shi, Lin&#8208;Tai Da, Yan Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404843611

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Han Zhang, Kaiyuan Song, Yihan Liu, Fang Yang, Congcong Lu, Rumeng Wei, Zhijue Xu, Xia Zou, Liang Lin, Ting Shi, Lin&#8208;Tai Da, Yan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05719</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Surface and Penetrating Carbon in Fe-Based Catalysts to Balance the Activity and Stability of Fischer&#8211;Tropsch Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06014</link>
      <description>Xiaoxue Han, Shouying Huang, Chongyang Wei, Haoting Liang, Jing Lv, Yue Wang, Mei&#8208;Yan Wang, Yong Wang, Xinbin Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404857137

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoxue Han, Shouying Huang, Chongyang Wei, Haoting Liang, Jing Lv, Yue Wang, Mei&#8208;Yan Wang, Yong Wang, Xinbin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06014</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
