<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:44:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction with Atomically Precise Au&lt;sub&gt;13&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters: Effect of Ligand Shell on Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06114</link>
      <description>Tetyana I. Levchenko, Hong Yi, Mark D. Aloisio, Ngoc Kim Dang, Guofu Gao, Sachil Sharma, Cao-Thang Dinh, Cathleen M. Crudden, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392550903

                Supported gold nanoclusters of the formula [Au13(L)5Cl2]3+ where L = N-heterocyclic carbene (NHC) or phosphine ligands are examined in the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) in a membrane electrode assembly cell configuration. Gold nanoclusters bearing bisNHC ligands are shown to exhibit improved catalytic performance compared with diphosphine-stabilized nanoclusters after activation at the optimum treatment temperatures. The thermal properties of the nanoclusters are shown to have a significant impact on their catalytic activity. Thermogravimetric analysis, UV&#8211;vis absorption spectroscopy, and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy revealed that thermal treatment of [Au13(diphosphine)5Cl2]3+ nanoclusters results in complete loss of diphosphine ligands while [Au13(bisNHC)5Cl2]3+ nanoclusters show stepwise and partial removal of bisNHC ligands. We propose that the partial removal of bisNHC ligands enables efficient activation of [Au13(bisNHC)5Cl2]3+ clusters while conserving the core structure. This leads to the implication that intact clusters retaining at least some ligands in their coordination environment are more active than ligand-free clusters.</description>
      <author>Tetyana I. Levchenko, Hong Yi, Mark D. Aloisio, Ngoc Kim Dang, Guofu Gao, Sachil Sharma, Cao-Thang Dinh, Cathleen M. Crudden</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revving up a Designed Copper Nitrite Reductase Using Noncoded Active Site Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06159</link>
      <description>Winston C Pitts, Aniruddha Deb, James E. Penner&#8208;Hahn, Vincent L. Pecoraro, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392551437

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Winston C Pitts, Aniruddha Deb, James E. Penner&#8208;Hahn, Vincent L. Pecoraro</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfite-Enhanced Aerobic Methane Oxidation to Methanol over Reduced Phosphomolybdate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00234</link>
      <description>Sikai Wang, Hua An, Max J. H&#252;lsey, Geng Sun, Qian He, Ning Yan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392551491

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sikai Wang, Hua An, Max J. H&#252;lsey, Geng Sun, Qian He, Ning Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Dual Activation of Lattice Oxygen and Molecule Oxygen over CoMn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for VOC Oxidation: Promoting the Role of Oxygen Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06237</link>
      <description>Yewei Ren, Caixia Song, Hui Wang, Zhenping Qu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392552229

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yewei Ren, Caixia Song, Hui Wang, Zhenping Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Charge Transfer via Heterogeneous Doping Promotes Hematite Photoelectrodes for Efficient Solar H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06110</link>
      <description>Fang Guo, Jinwei Bai, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Kai Su, Yang Yang, Xianhu Liu, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392564717

                Photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting into hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) and hydrogen (H2) is a promising alternative to energy and environmentally intensive production. Bulk electronic and surface structures affect the charge transport efficiency and catalytic activity of the photoelectrode. Herein, we design and investigate a hematite (Fe2O3) nanorod photoelectrode with hafnium and titanium binary dopants for highly selective H2O2 production. The resultant photoanode shows a H2O2 yield of 0.41 &#956;mol min&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2 at 1.5 VRHE with a Faradaic efficiency of 72.2%. Experimental investigations and theoretical calculations demonstrate the synergistic effect of Hf and gradient Ti doping on the hematite for the promising H2O2 performance. Hf doping effectively improves the crystallinity of Fe2O3, which favors improving the charge transport and reducing the charge recombination. Gradient Ti doping inhibits the collapse of the nanorod structure, increases the specific surface area, and introduces a large number of active sites on the surface. Ti- and Hf-codoped Ti/Hf:Fe2O3 photoanode improves the kinetics of H2O2 generation, leading to the high selectivity for H2O2 production and suppression of O2 production. This work provides the importance of hematite-based photoanodes toward the regulation of competition reactions for H2O2 production.</description>
      <author>Fang Guo, Jinwei Bai, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Kai Su, Yang Yang, Xianhu Liu, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel as Electrocatalyst for CO&lt;sub&gt;(2)&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction: Effect of Temperature, Potential, Partial Pressure, and Electrolyte Composition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00009</link>
      <description>Rafa&#235;l E. Vos, Marc T. M. Koper, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392578646

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rafa&#235;l E. Vos, Marc T. M. Koper</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Conformational Transitions Underpin the Activation Heat Capacity in the Temperature Dependence of Enzyme Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05584</link>
      <description>Emma J. Walker, Carlin J. Hamill, Rory Crean, Michael S. Connolly, Annmaree K. Warrender, Kirsty L. Kraakman, Erica J. Prentice, Alistair Steyn-Ross, Moira L. Steyn-Ross, Christopher R. Pudney, Marc W. van der Kamp, Louis A. Schipper, Adrian J. Mulholland, Vickery L. Arcus, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392597789

                Many enzymes display non-Arrhenius behavior with curved Arrhenius plots in the absence of denaturation. There has been significant debate about the origin of this behavior and recently the role of the activation heat capacity (&#916;CP&#10727;) has been widely discussed. If enzyme-catalyzed reactions occur with appreciable negative values of &#916;CP&#10727; (arising from narrowing of the conformational space along the reaction coordinate), then curved Arrhenius plots are a consequence. To investigate these phenomena in detail, we have collected high precision temperature-rate data over a wide temperature interval for a model glycosidase enzyme MalL, and a series of mutants that change the temperature-dependence of the enzyme-catalyzed rate. We use these data to test a range of models including macromolecular rate theory (MMRT) and an equilibrium model. In addition, we have performed extensive molecular dynamics (MD) simulations to characterize the conformational landscape traversed by MalL in the enzyme&#8211;substrate complex and an enzyme-transition state complex. We have crystallized the enzyme in a transition state-like conformation in the absence of a ligand and determined an X-ray crystal structure at very high resolution (1.10 &#197;). We show (using simulation) that this enzyme-transition state conformation has a more restricted conformational landscape than the wildtype enzyme. We coin the term &#8220;transition state-like conformation (TLC)&#8221; to apply to this state of the enzyme. Together, these results imply a cooperative conformational transition between an enzyme&#8211;substrate conformation (ES) and a transition-state-like conformation (TLC) that precedes the chemical step. We present a two-state model as an extension of MMRT (MMRT-2S) that describes the data along with a convenient approximation with linear temperature dependence of the activation heat capacity (MMRT-1L) that can be used where fewer data points are available. Our model rationalizes disparate behavior seen for MalL and previous results for a thermophilic alcohol dehydrogenase and is consistent with a raft of data for other enzymes. Our model can be used to characterize the conformational changes required for enzyme catalysis and provides insights into the role of cooperative conformational changes in transition state stabilization that are accompanied by changes in heat capacity for the system along the reaction coordinate. TLCs are likely to be of wide importance in understanding the temperature dependence of enzyme activity and other aspects of enzyme catalysis.</description>
      <author>Emma J. Walker, Carlin J. Hamill, Rory Crean, Michael S. Connolly, Annmaree K. Warrender, Kirsty L. Kraakman, Erica J. Prentice, Alistair Steyn-Ross, Moira L. Steyn-Ross, Christopher R. Pudney, Marc W. van der Kamp, Louis A. Schipper, Adrian J. Mulholland, Vickery L. Arcus</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Directed Nickel-Catalyzed Three-Component Reductive Arylalkylation of Alkenes via the Carbometalation/Radical Cross-Coupling Sequence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00477</link>
      <description>Zhan Dong, Changyu Xu, Jianchao Chang, Sitian Zhou, Peipei Sun, Yuqiang Li, Liang&#8208;An Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392600216

                Asymmetric reductive three-component arylalkylation of alkenes via the radical relay method has been well established, while asymmetric arylalkylation via the migratory insertion strategy remains unexplored. We report enantioselective nickel-catalyzed cross-electrophile arylalkylation of alkenes with aryl- and alkyl halides via an integrated Heck carbometalation/radical cross-coupling sequence. This protocol employing a chiral Ni/PHOX catalytic system allows terminal and internal alkenes to successfully engage the arylalkylation with exquisite control of regio-, chemo-, and stereoselectivity. More importantly, this reductive arylalkylation undergoes regio- and enantioselective arylnickelation followed by radical cross-coupling via Csp3&#8211;Csp3 reductive elimination, thus exhibiting reverse regioselectivity to the radical relay method. Mild reaction conditions and exceptional functional group tolerance facilitate this method&#8217;s compatibility with bioactive motifs and the modular synthesis of biologically active compounds. The control experiments and density functional theory calculations provide insights into the mechanism and origin of regio- and stereoselectivity, and the hemilabile nature of the PHOX ligand is critical for achieving this enantioselective arylalkylation.</description>
      <author>Zhan Dong, Changyu Xu, Jianchao Chang, Sitian Zhou, Peipei Sun, Yuqiang Li, Liang&#8208;An Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glycyl Radical Enzymes Catalyzing the Dehydration of Two Isomers of &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Methyl-4-hydroxyproline</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00216</link>
      <description>Li Jiang, Yiqian Yang, Lin Huang, Yan Zhang, Jingkun An, Yu Zheng, Yiwei Chen, Yanhong Liu, Jianhui Huang, Ee Lui Ang, Suwen Zhao, Huimin Zhao, Rong&#8208;Zhen Liao, Yifeng Wei, Yan Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392601584

                The various isomers of hydroxyproline (HP) are widely distributed in nature, serving as key components of structural proteins, while their quaternized betaine derivatives function as osmoprotectants in many organisms. Aerobic bacteria degrade HPs through a variety of well-studied mechanisms. Recent studies show that certain anaerobic bacteria degrade HPs through distinct mechanisms, involving the O2-sensitive glycyl radical enzymes (GREs) t4L-HP dehydratase (HypD) and t4D-HP C&#8211;N lyase (HplG). Here, we report the discovery of two more GREs, N-methyl c4L-HP dehydratase (HpyG) and N-methyl c4D-HP dehydratase (HpzG), which catalyze radical-mediated dehydration of the two N-methyl-c4HP enantiomers, while also displaying significant activities toward their unmethylated substrates. Both GREs are associated with homologues of pyrroline-5-carboxylate reductase, which catalyze reduction of their products N-methyl-pyrroline-5-carboxylate to form N-methyl-proline. Crystal structures of HpyG and HpzG in complex with their substrates revealed active site architectures distinct from that of HypD and provided insights into the mechanism of enantioselective radical-mediated dehydration. Our research further expands the repertoire of diverse chemical mechanisms involved in the bacterial metabolism of highly prevalent HP isomers and derivatives in the anaerobic biosphere.</description>
      <author>Li Jiang, Yiqian Yang, Lin Huang, Yan Zhang, Jingkun An, Yu Zheng, Yiwei Chen, Yanhong Liu, Jianhui Huang, Ee Lui Ang, Suwen Zhao, Huimin Zhao, Rong&#8208;Zhen Liao, Yifeng Wei, Yan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental Insights on the Electrochemical Nitrogen Oxidation over Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05307</link>
      <description>J. V. P. Long, Dong Luan, Xihong Fu, Huan Li, Huijuan Jing, Jianping Xiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392602509

                Electrocatalytic nitrogen oxidation reaction (eN2OR) has emerged as a sustainable strategy for nitrogen fixation. In this work, density functional theory calculations were performed to rationalize the reaction mechanisms, activity, and selectivity of eN2OR on metal dioxides. The anatase (101), anatase (100), and rutile (110) surfaces were investigated to obtain more generalized insights. Based on the reaction phase diagram analysis, the thermochemical mechanisms were identified as most energetically favorable for N2 and *N2O oxidation, and a theoretical activity map was constructed for eN2OR, explaining well the experimental activity trend. Anatase PtO2(100) was screened as the most active catalyst for nitrate production, which could be covered by a monolayer of *OH under the reaction conditions according to the Pourbaix diagram. A method of electric field controlling constant potential was used to calculate the electrochemical barriers on anatase PtO2(100). It was found that the electrochemical barriers of the oxygen evolution reaction will increase with the decrease of potential, while the thermochemical limiting step of the eN2OR is insensitive to potential. Thus, the eN2OR selectivity can be improved by lowering the applied potential. This work unveils fundamental insights into eN2OR and provides a unified understanding to experiments.</description>
      <author>J. V. P. Long, Dong Luan, Xihong Fu, Huan Li, Huijuan Jing, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Decoration of Platinum Catalysts by ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters for Durable Fuel Cell Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05297</link>
      <description>Nagappan Ramaswamy, Zixiao Shi, Barr Zulevi, Geoff McCool, Nathan P. Mellott, Anusorn Kongkanand, Swami Kumaraguru, Michele L. Ostraat, David A. Muller, Nancy N. Kariuki, Deborah J. Myers, A. Jeremy Kropf, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392615762

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nagappan Ramaswamy, Zixiao Shi, Barr Zulevi, Geoff McCool, Nathan P. Mellott, Anusorn Kongkanand, Swami Kumaraguru, Michele L. Ostraat, David A. Muller, Nancy N. Kariuki, Deborah J. Myers, A. Jeremy Kropf</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Oxygen Evolution Reaction Kinetics with Titanium Incorporated Nickel Ferrite for Efficient Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05761</link>
      <description>Ki-Yong Yoon, Kyung&#8208;Bok Lee, Jaehoon Jeong, Myung&#8208;Jun Kwak, Dohyung Kim, Hyunchul Roh, Ji-Hoon Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Hosik Lee, Juchan Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392622761

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ki-Yong Yoon, Kyung&#8208;Bok Lee, Jaehoon Jeong, Myung&#8208;Jun Kwak, Dohyung Kim, Hyunchul Roh, Ji-Hoon Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Hosik Lee, Juchan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Thiophene&#8211;Sulfur Functional Groups in Carbon Catalysts for Highly Selective H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00419</link>
      <description>Rong-Hui Xie, Chuanqi Cheng, Ruguang Wang, Jisi Li, Erling Zhao, Zhao Yang, Yunlong Liu, Jiaxin Guo, Pengfei Yin, Tao Ling, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392645655

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rong-Hui Xie, Chuanqi Cheng, Ruguang Wang, Jisi Li, Erling Zhao, Zhao Yang, Yunlong Liu, Jiaxin Guo, Pengfei Yin, Tao Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt/Fe-TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Catalyzed Selective Carbonyl Hydrogenation: Fe-Promoted Hydrogen Spillover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05478</link>
      <description>Zhenchao Zhao, Xiang Li, Xin Liu, Hongxia Gao, Aiping Jia, Songhai Xie, Xiaojing Song, Xiaoyan Liu, Yang Fa, Qihua Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392649076

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenchao Zhao, Xiang Li, Xin Liu, Hongxia Gao, Aiping Jia, Songhai Xie, Xiaojing Song, Xiaoyan Liu, Yang Fa, Qihua Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Siteselective and Enantiocomplementary C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Oxyfunctionalization for Synthesis of &#945;-Hydroxy Acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00398</link>
      <description>Xin Lian, Yingle Mao, Zunyun Fu, Weijie Zhang, Jia-Yan Chen, Dan Zhuo, Mingyue Zheng, Jiunn&#8208;Tzong Wu, Cangsong Liao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392658327

                Oxyfunctionalization of abundant carboxylic acids represents a direct approach to synthesizing &#945;-hydroxy acids, which are valuable intermediates of various active pharmaceutical ingredients. Although ideal, the transformation is yet to be accomplished. Herein, enantiocomplementary C(sp3)&#8211;H oxyfunctionalization for the synthesis of &#945;-hydroxy acids was realized by a cooperative strategy of substrate engineering, homologue screening and protein engineering of &#945;-ketoglutarate-dependent nonheme iron aryloxyalkanoate dioxygenases. The reaction provided concise synthetic routes toward three types of 67 &#945;-hydroxy acids with high efficiency and selectivity (yield up to 90% and ee up to &gt;99%). The distinctive complementary reactions add to a growing repertoire of biocatalytic oxyfunctionalization reactions.</description>
      <author>Xin Lian, Yingle Mao, Zunyun Fu, Weijie Zhang, Jia-Yan Chen, Dan Zhuo, Mingyue Zheng, Jiunn&#8208;Tzong Wu, Cangsong Liao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expedient Synthesis of Axially and Centrally Chiral Diaryl Ethers via Cobalt-Catalyzed Photoreductive Desymmetrization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00001</link>
      <description>Yishou Wang, Ruijie Mi, Songjie Yu, Xingwei Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392682464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yishou Wang, Ruijie Mi, Songjie Yu, Xingwei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Doping Strategies to Improve Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Performance of Molybdenum Disulfide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05053</link>
      <description>Yuehan Jia, Yuchen Zhang, Huibin Xu, Jia Li, Ming Gao, Xiaotian Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392693992

                The exhaustion of fossil fuels and resultant pollution issues have prompted the world to look to clean, nonpolluting hydrogen energy. The promising approach of the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) presents a solution for addressing energy and environmental challenges. Consequently, creating high-performance and cost-effective electrocatalysts is essential for the efficient decomposition of water. Molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) has emerged as the most promising among potential electrocatalysts to replace platinum. However, only the edge-site of MoS2 is active for HER due to the MoS2 semiconductive nature and large inactive basal planes. Doping various substances, which significantly improves HER activity, can enhance MoS2's physical and chemical properties. Our Review encapsulates the latest strategies and research advancements in choosing heteroatomic-doped MoS2 for hydrogen production. Various doping elements impart unique physical and chemical properties to MoS2. Specifically, doping with noble metals (e.g., Ag, Pt, Ru, Pd, Rh) and transition metals (e.g., Fe, V, Ni, Mn, Co, Zn, W), as well as codoping with multiple metal atoms (e.g., Cu-Pd, Pt-Te, Co-Nb, Ni-Co), can significantly enhance conductivity and introduce new active sites. These dopants are recognized for activating the basal plane of MoS2, thereby enhancing the HER activity. Furthermore, doping with nonmetallic elements (e.g., N, F, P, An, O) and their codoping combinations (e.g., O-P, N-F, Se-O), as well as the codoping of nonmetal and metal atoms (e.g., Co-Se, Co-P, N-Pt, Ru-O), is crucial for inducing phase conversions and improving stability. Each dopant contributes distinctively, either by enhancing the stability of MoS2, serving as a catalytic site, or broadening the pH range for effective HER. In this discussion, we further explore the current challenges and outlook of this promising area. Furthermore, we discuss existing challenges and promising guidelines for future research on the MoS2-based catalyst, offering advice to translation from laboratory research to large-scale industrial hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Yuehan Jia, Yuchen Zhang, Huibin Xu, Jia Li, Ming Gao, Xiaotian Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-Driven Highly Effective Biomass-Derived Alcohols C&#8211;C Coupling Integrated with H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production by CdS Quantum Dots Modified Zn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05826</link>
      <description>Zongyi Huang, Pengfei Sun, Huizhen Zhang, Haikun Zhang, Shuhong Zhang, Zhou Chen, Xiaodong Yi, Shunji Xie, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392697716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongyi Huang, Pengfei Sun, Huizhen Zhang, Haikun Zhang, Shuhong Zhang, Zhou Chen, Xiaodong Yi, Shunji Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confined Trinuclear Ru Sites in Phosphine-Incorporated Porous Organic Polymers for the Direct Synthesis of Alcohols from Reductive Hydroformylation of Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06221</link>
      <description>Yuchuan Zhu, Zhaozhan Wang, Yuanjun Zhao, Xin Zhou, Yan Zhang, Yong Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392697742

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuchuan Zhu, Zhaozhan Wang, Yuanjun Zhao, Xin Zhou, Yan Zhang, Yong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics of Redox Half-Cycles on Bi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for the Selective Catalytic Combustion of Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05585</link>
      <description>Mark Jacob, Huy Ho&#224;ng Nguy&#7877;n, Matthew Neurock, Aditya Bhan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392697744

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mark Jacob, Huy Ho&#224;ng Nguy&#7877;n, Matthew Neurock, Aditya Bhan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Resolution of Activity-Related Solvation Dynamics in the TIM Barrel Enzyme Murine Adenosine Deaminase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02687</link>
      <description>Shuaihua Gao, Xin Wu, Wenju Zhang, Thomas Richardson, Samuel L. Barrow, Christian A. Thompson-Kucera, Anthony T. Iavarone, Judith P. Klinman, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392701608

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuaihua Gao, Xin Wu, Wenju Zhang, Thomas Richardson, Samuel L. Barrow, Christian A. Thompson-Kucera, Anthony T. Iavarone, Judith P. Klinman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02687</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genome Mining for New Enzyme Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06322</link>
      <description>Dinh Thanh Nguyen, Douglas A. Mitchell, Wilfred A. van der Donk, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392701824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dinh Thanh Nguyen, Douglas A. Mitchell, Wilfred A. van der Donk</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Oxygen Vacancy Site Mechanism of a Self-Assembly Hybrid Catalyst for Efficient Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05789</link>
      <description>Xinshui Lei, Jiang Chang, Qingjun Han, Xiao&#8208;Xin Zhang, Kai Zhao, Ning Yan, Haoxu Guo, Bing Tang, Yifan Li, Yi Cui, Shuhui Yu, Jianhui Li, Yanping Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392704093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinshui Lei, Jiang Chang, Qingjun Han, Xiao&#8208;Xin Zhang, Kai Zhao, Ning Yan, Haoxu Guo, Bing Tang, Yifan Li, Yi Cui, Shuhui Yu, Jianhui Li, Yanping Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active and Sulfur-Tolerant Ruthenium Phosphide Catalyst for Efficient Reductive Amination of Carbonyl Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06179</link>
      <description>Hiroya Ishikawa, Sho Yamaguchi, Tomoo Mizugaki, Takato Mitsudome, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392710185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hiroya Ishikawa, Sho Yamaguchi, Tomoo Mizugaki, Takato Mitsudome</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Hydrogenation of Furfural with Improved Activity and Selectivity at the Surface of Structured Copper Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05691</link>
      <description>Cl&#233;ment Spadetto, Cyril Hachemi, Maxime Nouaille-Degorce, Lo&#239;c Pendu, Lou Bossert, Robert H. Temperton, Andrey Shavorskiy, L. Cardenas, Mathieu S. Pr&#233;vot, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392710286

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cl&#233;ment Spadetto, Cyril Hachemi, Maxime Nouaille-Degorce, Lo&#239;c Pendu, Lou Bossert, Robert H. Temperton, Andrey Shavorskiy, L. Cardenas, Mathieu S. Pr&#233;vot</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05691</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
