<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 01:25:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture and Utilization: Selection, Matching, and Interactions between Adsorption and Catalytic Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03861</link>
      <description>Hongman Sun, Shuzhuang Sun, Xiaoteng Liu, Jingbin Zeng, Youhe Wang, Zifeng Yan, Chunfei Wu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403155268

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongman Sun, Shuzhuang Sun, Xiaoteng Liu, Jingbin Zeng, Youhe Wang, Zifeng Yan, Chunfei Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Investigation into Copper(I) Hydride Catalyzed Formic Acid Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05008</link>
      <description>Roel L. M. Bienenmann, Anne Olarte Loyo, Martin Lutz, Dani&#235;l L. J. Broere, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403171995

                Copper(I) hydride complexes are typically known to react with CO2 to form their corresponding copper formate counterparts. However, recently it has been observed that some multinuclear copper hydrides can feature the opposite reactivity and catalyze the dehydrogenation of formic acid. Here we report the use of a multinuclear PNNP copper hydride complex as an active (pre)catalyst for this reaction. Mechanistic investigations provide insights into the catalyst resting state and the rate-determining step and identify an off-cycle species that is responsible for the unexpected substrate inhibition in this reaction.</description>
      <author>Roel L. M. Bienenmann, Anne Olarte Loyo, Martin Lutz, Dani&#235;l L. J. Broere</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Trace Metal in Plastics on Catalyst Activity and Reusability during Polyolefins Upcycling with Polyoxometalates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04719</link>
      <description>Hongda Zhu, Justin T. Douglas, Bala Subramaniam, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403172589

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongda Zhu, Justin T. Douglas, Bala Subramaniam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04719</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of &#946;&lt;i&gt;-&lt;/i&gt;(Hetero)aryl Ketones via Ligand-Enabled Nondirected C&#8211;H Alkylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04319</link>
      <description>Yogesh Bairagi, Sandip Porey, Sai V. C. Vummaleti, Xinglong Zhang, Goutam Kumar Lahiri, Debabrata Maiti, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403184597

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yogesh Bairagi, Sandip Porey, Sai V. C. Vummaleti, Xinglong Zhang, Goutam Kumar Lahiri, Debabrata Maiti</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micelle-Dependent Spontaneous Formation of Gold(I) in Nanodendritic Chloride-Bridged Particles with Catalytic Activity for Cyclization of Alkynylanilines in an Aqueous Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03427</link>
      <description>Gaganpreet Kaur, Gaspard Hedouin, Raki Mandal, Jacek B. Jasi&#324;ski, Xiaoqing He, Min Su, Juejing Liu, Xiaofeng Guo, Justin R. Walensky, Gary A. Baker, Fabrice Gallou, Sachin Handa, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403184781

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gaganpreet Kaur, Gaspard Hedouin, Raki Mandal, Jacek B. Jasi&#324;ski, Xiaoqing He, Min Su, Juejing Liu, Xiaofeng Guo, Justin R. Walensky, Gary A. Baker, Fabrice Gallou, Sachin Handa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice-Disordered Boron Nitride Colloidal Catalyst for Low-Temperature Selective Methane Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03534</link>
      <description>Younhwa Kim, Hyesung Choi, Yong Jin Kim, Sungsu Kang, Chanhee Choi, Jihoon Kim, Chyan Kyung Song, Jae Hyuck Sung, Jeong Woo Han, Jungwon Park, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403190398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Younhwa Kim, Hyesung Choi, Yong Jin Kim, Sungsu Kang, Chanhee Choi, Jihoon Kim, Chyan Kyung Song, Jae Hyuck Sung, Jeong Woo Han, Jungwon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03534</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Link between Zeolite Crystal Size, Br&#248;nsted Acid Site Distribution, and Dual-Cycle Selectivity in Methanol-to-Olefins over Zeolite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05555</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Wang, Yan Wang, Yueying Chu, Yinghao Liu, Min Hu, Feng Deng, Jun Xu, Jihong Yu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403194508

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Wang, Yan Wang, Yueying Chu, Yinghao Liu, Min Hu, Feng Deng, Jun Xu, Jihong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imaging Gas-Phase Methyl Radicals over a Ag/SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst during the Partial Oxidation of Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03741</link>
      <description>Sebastian Pfaff, Erxiong Huang, Jonathan H. Frank, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403199484

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sebastian Pfaff, Erxiong Huang, Jonathan H. Frank</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Species Heterogeneity and Synergy to Boost Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03593</link>
      <description>Jiankang Zhang, Panzhe Qiao, Hao Tan, Lin Cui, Zhan Zhou, Dong Lin, Yongxiao Tuo, Yong Qin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403208208

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiankang Zhang, Panzhe Qiao, Hao Tan, Lin Cui, Zhan Zhou, Dong Lin, Yongxiao Tuo, Yong Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ ORR Dynamics of Non-Precious Transition Metal Electrocatalysts: the Case of Manganese Antimony X-ides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03260</link>
      <description>Gaurav A. Kamat, Melissa E. Kreider, Johanna Schr&#246;der, Roulince Bobby Dukuly, Joseph T. Perryman, Bj&#248;rt Joensen, Jesse E. Matthews, Ashton M. Aleman, Michaela Burke Stevens, Thomas F. Jaramillo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403213342

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gaurav A. Kamat, Melissa E. Kreider, Johanna Schr&#246;der, Roulince Bobby Dukuly, Joseph T. Perryman, Bj&#248;rt Joensen, Jesse E. Matthews, Ashton M. Aleman, Michaela Burke Stevens, Thomas F. Jaramillo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of &#945;-Quaternary Aldehydes via a Dual Ni/Rh-Catalyzed Tandem Isomerization&#8211;Propargylation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05021</link>
      <description>Justin Ching, M. Jaschinski, Eun Seo Choi, Mark Lautens, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403213785

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Justin Ching, M. Jaschinski, Eun Seo Choi, Mark Lautens</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05021</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
