<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 01:03:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Two Pathways for Electrocatalytic Acetonitrile Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00621</link>
      <description>Qi Zhang, Zunjian Ke, Deyan He, Chaoning Huang, Huan Dai, Chaoliang Tang, Boling Liu, Xiangheng Xiao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394908661

                Electrocatalytic hydrogenation (ECH) of organics offers a promising route for producing value-added chemicals. However, a deeper understanding of the reaction mechanism limits the efficient design of the catalysts. Herein, the two mechanisms are essentially identified on the Ni-based catalysts for acetonitrile hydrogenation, with a deeper understanding of their characteristics in view of their different performances. On this basis, an insight into the shift of the mechanism is proposed. Meanwhile, the optimization strategy of ECH is discovered, and the construction of Tafel sites (Ni/NiO interfaces) can greatly accelerate the kinetics, in addition to increasing the reactant coverage on the catalysts by modulating the electronic structures. Understanding the underlying mechanisms helps in manipulating the design of more efficient ECH catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qi Zhang, Zunjian Ke, Deyan He, Chaoning Huang, Huan Dai, Chaoliang Tang, Boling Liu, Xiangheng Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00621</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Catalytic Efficiency of a GH5 Processive Endoglucanase by a Combinatorial Strategy Using Consensus Mutagenesis and Loop Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01083</link>
      <description>Kemin Lv, Xiaozhou Li, Kequan Chen, Bin Wu, Bingfang He, Gerhard Schenk, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394908851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kemin Lv, Xiaozhou Li, Kequan Chen, Bin Wu, Bingfang He, Gerhard Schenk</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interplay between Catalyst Corrosion and Homogeneous Reactive Oxygen Species in Electrochemical Ozone Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01317</link>
      <description>Rayan Alaufey, Lingyan Zhao, Andrew Lindsay, Tana Siboonruang, Qin Wu, John A. Keith, Ezra C. Wood, Maureen H. Tang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394909286

                Electrochemical ozone production (EOP), a six-electron water oxidation reaction, offers promising avenues for creating value-added oxidants and disinfectants. However, progress in this field is slowed by a dearth of understanding of fundamental reaction mechanisms. In this work, we combine experimental electrochemistry, spectroscopic detection of reactive oxygen species (ROS), oxygen-anion chemical ionization mass spectrometry, and computational quantum chemistry calculations to determine a plausible reaction mechanism on nickel- and antimony-doped tin oxide (Ni/Sb&#8211;SnO2, NATO), one of the most selective EOP catalysts. Antimony doping is shown to increase the conductivity of the catalyst, leading to improved electrochemical performance. Spectroscopic analysis and electrochemical experiments combined with quantum chemistry predictions reveal that hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) is a critical reaction intermediate. We propose that leached Ni4+ cations catalyze hydrogen peroxide into solution phase hydroperoxyl radicals (&#8226;OOH); these radicals are subsequently oxidized to ozone. Isotopic product analysis shows that ozone is generated catalytically from water and corrosively from the catalyst oxide lattice without regeneration of lattice oxygens. Further quantum chemistry calculations and thermodynamic analysis suggest that the electrochemical corrosion of tin oxide itself might generate hydrogen peroxide, which is then catalyzed to ozone. The proposed pathways explain both the roles of dopants in NATO and its lack of stability. Our study interrogates the possibility that instability and electrochemical activity are intrinsically linked through the formation of ROS. In doing so, we provide the first mechanism for EOP that is consistent with computational and experimental results and highlight the central challenge of instability as a target for future research efforts.</description>
      <author>Rayan Alaufey, Lingyan Zhao, Andrew Lindsay, Tana Siboonruang, Qin Wu, John A. Keith, Ezra C. Wood, Maureen H. Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce&lt;sup&gt;4+&lt;/sup&gt;/Ce&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; Redox-Promoted Electron Transfer for Efficient Neutral H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrosynthesis from Two-Electron Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00625</link>
      <description>Sohee Kim, Young Jin, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394913837

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sohee Kim, Young Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00625</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping of the Reaction Trajectory Catalyzed by Class I Ketol-Acid Reductoisomerase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00958</link>
      <description>Xin Lin, Thierry Lonhienne, You Lv, Julia L. Kurz, Ross P. McGeary, Gerhard Schenk, L.W. Guddat, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394924580

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Lin, Thierry Lonhienne, You Lv, Julia L. Kurz, Ross P. McGeary, Gerhard Schenk, L.W. Guddat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substantial Impact of Spin State Evolution in OER/ORR Catalyzed by Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06122</link>
      <description>Mingyuan Yu, Ang Li, Erjun Kan, Caimao Zhan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394925248

                The Fe-embedded N-doped graphene (Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C) is the most representative single atom catalyst (SAC) that has shown great potentiality in electrocatalysis, such as oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the active moiety of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C is still elusive due to contradictory experimental results. Moreover, early simulations mainly focus on the thermodynamic potential of adsorbates, while the effect of spin multiplicity receives little attention. To explore the role of spin multiplicity in electrocatalysis, we employ the constant-potential density functional theory (DFT) to systematically study the structural evolution of the high-spin (HS) and intermediate-spin (IS) FeN4 site (marked by FeN4HS/IS) in OER and ORR processes. With the consideration of spin multiplicity, our simulation shows spontaneous oxidation from Fe(II)N4IS to Fe(III)N4HS at potential U = 0.4 V versus SHE. Further simulation indicates that the FeN4IS site undergoes a sequential adsorption of *OH and *OOH along with U increase, which leads to the spin state transition from IS to HS. According to the constant-potential free energy analysis, the FeN4HS*OOH is confirmed to be the practical active centers of OER, while the FeN4HS*OH and FeN4IS are assigned to the active center of ORR in low and high overpotentials. The predicted ORR activity of FeN4HS*OH agrees with the in situ X-ray absorption near-edge spectroscopy (XANES) and 57Fe M&#246;ssbauer spectroscopy measurement by Xiao et al. [Microporous Framework Induced Synthesis of Single-Atom Dispersed Fe-NC Acidic ORR Catalyst and its In Situ Reduced Fe-N4 Active Site Identification Revealed by X-Ray Absorption Spectroscopy. ACS Catal. 2018, 8, 2824&#8211;2832]. Based on the geometry and orbital analysis, the bond length of Fe&#8211;N and coordination number of Fe center are found to have a significant impact on the d orbital splitting energy and thus induce the turnover of HS/IS stability in the OER/ORR intermediates. Our study brings comprehensive insights into the evolution of coordination and spin state in Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C, which reveals the significance of spin multiplicity in electrocatalysis and benefits further theoretical design of SACs from the perspective of spin effects.</description>
      <author>Mingyuan Yu, Ang Li, Erjun Kan, Caimao Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atroposelective Synthesis of N&#8211;N Axially Chiral Indoles and Pyrroles via NHC-Catalyzed Diastereoselective (3 + 3) Annulation Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00513</link>
      <description>Sowmya Shree Ranganathappa, Bhabani Sankar Dehury, Girij Pal Singh, Sayan Shee, Akkattu T. Biju, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394933767

                The synthesis of N&#8211;N axially chiral molecules in the enantiopure form has emerged as an interesting research topic primarily due to the significance and intricacy in synthesizing these molecules, especially bearing heterocyclic motifs. Herein, we disclose a method for the introduction of N&#8211;N axial chirality along with a point chiral center via the N-heterocyclic carbene (NHC)-catalyzed atroposelective synthesis of dihydropyridinone-containing indoles and pyrroles. The reaction follows a (3 + 3) annulation approach by the interception of indole/pyrrole-derived enamines with &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes under oxidative NHC catalysis proceeding via the &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated acylazoliums. The N&#8211;N axially chiral indoles/pyrroles were formed under mild conditions in broad scope with high selectivity. In addition, preliminary DFT studies of the N&#8211;N rotational barrier of the axially chiral products were performed.</description>
      <author>Sowmya Shree Ranganathappa, Bhabani Sankar Dehury, Girij Pal Singh, Sayan Shee, Akkattu T. Biju</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic N-Acylation for Access to N&#8211;N Atropisomeric N-Aminoindoles: Choice of Acylation Reagents and Mechanistic Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00720</link>
      <description>Chaoyang Song, Chao Pang, Youlin Deng, Hongneng Cai, Xiuhai Gan, Yonggui Robin, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394934073

                The synthesis of N&#8211;N axial compounds containing aromatic acyl amides using common acylation reagents remains challenging. We describe a highly atropenantioselective synthesis of N-aminoindoles containing N&#8211;N axes. A chiral cyclic isothiourea is used as the sole organic catalyst in the atropenantioselective transformation of the N-acylation reaction. Aroyl chlorides have been used as acylation reagents to construct atropisomeric compounds through N-acylation. The N-aminoindole products, which bear stereogenic N&#8211;N axes, were synthesized with high yields and enantioselectivities. Some of the enantiopure N-aminoindole products exhibited promising antibacterial activities against plant pathogens.</description>
      <author>Chaoyang Song, Chao Pang, Youlin Deng, Hongneng Cai, Xiuhai Gan, Yonggui Robin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00720</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Heteroatom-Doped Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C Single-Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction via Simple Descriptor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01377</link>
      <description>Jin Liu, Jing Zhu, Hanhui Xu, Daojian Cheng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394934259

                The coordination engineering of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C single-atom catalysts (SACs) through introducing heteroatom dopants has attracted widespread attention in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). However, the common regularity for tuning the ORR activity by coordinated and environmental heteroatoms has not been sufficiently studied. Herein, we study the ORR activity on 100 Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C SACs with S, P, and B heteroatoms in diverse coordination shells by density functional theory calculations. Based on the energy level distribution of frontier orbits and molecular orbital theory, it is found that the origin of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C ORR activity is the hybridization of molecular orbitals of Fe 3dz2, 3dyz (3dxz), and O2*/OH* intermediates, where hybrid orbitals are adjusted by coordinated and environmental S, P, and B heteroatoms, and then the protonation process of O2* or OH* intermediate is determined. Moreover, we found that the Fe&#8211;O bond length, the d-orbital gap of spin states, the d-orbital center, and the valence state of the Fe site can be used as structural descriptors to predict the ORR activity governed by the protonation of O2* or OH* intermediate as potential-determining steps. Our structural descriptors rationalize the superior ORR performance of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C with S or B atoms doped in the second coordination shell to those in the first coordination shell, as well as the fact that the P heteroatom is more suitable as a coordinated atom than the environmental atom to enhance the ORR activity of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C, in available experimental references. Thanks to structural descriptors, the codoping synergistic effect between P in the first coordination shell and S in the second coordination shell is predicted and confirmed to greatly enhance the ORR activity. This study provides a unified mechanistic understanding on the ORR activity trend among Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C SACs regulated by coordinated and environmental heteroatoms.</description>
      <author>Jin Liu, Jing Zhu, Hanhui Xu, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the High-Entropy Oxide Composition Space: Insights through Comparing Experimental with Theoretical Models for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05915</link>
      <description>Vladislav A. Mints, Katrine L. Svane, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394934324

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is key for the transition to a hydrogen-based energy economy. The observed activity of the OER catalysts arises from the combined effects of surface area, intrinsic activity, and stability. Therefore, alloys provide an effective platform to search for catalysts that balance these factors. In particular, high-entropy oxides provide a vast material composition space that could contain catalysts with optimal OER performance. In this work, the OER performance of the AuIrOsPdPtReRhRu composition space was modeled using an experimentally obtained dataset of 350 nanoparticles. This machine-learned model based on experimental data found the optimal catalyst to be a mixture of AuIrOsPdRu. However, as a "black-box model", it cannot explain the underlying chemistry. Therefore, density functional theory (DFT) calculations were performed to provide a complementary theoretical model with defined assumptions and, hence, a physical interpretation through comparison with the experimental model. The DFT calculations suggest that the majority of the activity originates from Ru and Ir active sites and that the addition of Pd improves the performance of these sites. However, the DFT calculation did not find the experimentally observed beneficial effects of Au and Os. Therefore, we hypothesize that the Os contributed to the performance of the tested catalysts by roughening the surface, whereas Au fulfilled the role of a structural support. Overall, it is demonstrated how machine learning can help accelerate catalyst discovery, and combining machine-learned models obtained from experimental data with models based on DFT calculations can provide important insights into the complex chemistry of OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Vladislav A. Mints, Katrine L. Svane, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Formaldehyde-Mediated Methanol-to-Aromatics Reactions over Zn-Modified Zeolites by Observing the Oxygenated and Polyunsaturated Intermediates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00020</link>
      <description>Tianci Xiao, Jinsong Luo, Weixiong Huang, Linfeng Lu, Chengyuan Liu, Yang Pan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394945572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianci Xiao, Jinsong Luo, Weixiong Huang, Linfeng Lu, Chengyuan Liu, Yang Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclic(alkyl)(amino)carbene-Stabilized Gold Nanoparticles for Selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05727</link>
      <description>Moushakhi Ghosh, Paramita Saha, Sumit Roy, Sudip Barman, Pramod P. Pillai, Abhishek Dey, Shabana Khan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394947823

                N-heterocyclic carbenes (NHCs) have recently gained significant attention as capping ligands for gold nanoparticles due to their strong &#963;-donation properties. It has already been established that the strong &#963;-donation of NHCs enriches the surface of the gold nanoparticles, which controls the catalytic activity of the metal nanoparticles. Cyclic (alkyl)(amino)carbene (CAAC) is a special class of carbene that offers stronger &#963;-donation than NHCs. This extremely electron-rich nature of CAAC projects it as a better surface capping ligand upon extrapolation on the Au(0) surface. In this work, we have isolated stable CAAC-stabilized AuNPs via a ligand exchange method and studied their catalytic behavior toward electrochemical CO2 reduction. These newly synthesized CAAC-stabilized AuNPs furnish a remarkable faradaic efficiency (FE) of 94% [at pH 6.3 for 2 h of controlled potential electrolysis at &#8722;0.7 V vs NHE (normal hydrogen electrode)] toward selective CO formation. Our work sets the platform for CAAC as a robust main group ligand on the surface of different metal nanoparticles, bridging the gap between main group ligands and surface chemistry.</description>
      <author>Moushakhi Ghosh, Paramita Saha, Sumit Roy, Sudip Barman, Pramod P. Pillai, Abhishek Dey, Shabana Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Bias and Redox-Driven Inactivation of the Group B FeFe Hydrogenase CpIII</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01352</link>
      <description>Andrea Fasano, Aurore Jacq&#8208;Bailly, Jeremy Wozniak, Vincent Fourmond, Christophe L&#233;ger, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394951090

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrea Fasano, Aurore Jacq&#8208;Bailly, Jeremy Wozniak, Vincent Fourmond, Christophe L&#233;ger</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Hydrogen Adsorption via Manipulating the d-Band Center of Ferroferric Oxide for Anion Exchange Membrane-Based Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00267</link>
      <description>Lihui Song, Lili Guo, Jianfeng Mao, Zhipeng Li, Jiawei Zhu, Jianping Lai, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Lei Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394953389

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lihui Song, Lili Guo, Jianfeng Mao, Zhipeng Li, Jiawei Zhu, Jianping Lai, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of 6,6&#8242;-Substituents on Bipyridine-Ligated Ni Catalysts for Cross-Electrophile Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00827</link>
      <description>Hanfeng Huang, Jose L. Alvarez-Hernandez, Nilay Hazari, Brandon Q. Mercado, Mycah R. Uehling, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394953706

                A family of 4,4&#8242;-tBu2-2,2&#8242;-bipyridine (tBubpy) ligands with substituents in either the 6-position, 4,4&#8242;-tBu2-6-Me-bpy (tBubpyMe), or 6 and 6&#8242;-positions, 4,4&#8242;-tBu2-6,6&#8242;-R2-bpy (tBubpyR2; R = Me, iPr, sBu, Ph, or Mes), was synthesized. These ligands were used to prepare Ni complexes in the 0, I, and II oxidation states. We observed that the substituents in the 6 and 6&#8242;-positions of the tBubpy ligand impact the properties of the Ni complexes. For example, bulkier substituents in the 6,6&#8242;-positions of tBubpy better stabilized (tBubpyR2)NiICl species and resulted in a cleaner reduction from (tBubpyR2)NiIICl2. However, bulkier substituents hindered or prevented the coordination of tBubpyR2 ligands to Ni0(cod)2. In addition, by using complexes of the type (tBubpyMe)NiCl2 and (tBubpyR2)NiCl2 as precatalysts for different XEC reactions, we demonstrated that the 6 or 6,6&#8242;-substituents lead to major differences in the catalytic performance. Specifically, while (tBubpyMe)NiIICl2 is one of the most active catalysts reported to date for XEC and can facilitate XEC reactions at room temperature, lower turnover frequencies were observed for catalysts containing tBubpyR2 ligands. A detailed study on the catalytic intermediates (tBubpy)Ni(Ar)I and (tBubpyMe2)Ni(Ar)I revealed several factors that likely contributed to the differences in the catalytic activity. For example, whereas complexes of the type (tBubpy)Ni(Ar)I are low spin and relatively stable, complexes of the type (tBubpyMe2)Ni(Ar)I are high-spin and less stable. Furthermore, (tBubpyMe2)Ni(Ar)I captures primary and benzylic alkyl radicals more slowly than (tBubpy)Ni(Ar)I, consistent with the lower activity of the former in catalysis. Our findings will assist in the design of tailor-made ligands for Ni-catalyzed transformations.</description>
      <author>Hanfeng Huang, Jose L. Alvarez-Hernandez, Nilay Hazari, Brandon Q. Mercado, Mycah R. Uehling</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i008_1792869</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394961569

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i008_1792869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i008_1792868</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394961663

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i008_1792868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christina Li, Serge Ruccolo, and Christo Sevov Selected to Receive the 2024 &lt;i&gt;ACS Catalysis&lt;/i&gt; Lectureship for the Advancement of Catalytic Science</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01956</link>
      <description>Cathleen M. Crudden, ACS catalysis. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394961800

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ISSUEEditorialNEXTChristina Li, Serge Ruccolo, and Christo Sevov Selected to Receive the 2024 ACS Catalysis Lectureship for the Advancement of Catalytic ScienceCathleen CruddenCathleen CruddenMore by Cathleen Cruddenhttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-2154-8107Cite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 8, 5987&#8211;5988Publication Date (Web):April 19, 2024Publication History Received1 April 2024Published online19 April 2024Published inissue 19 April 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01956Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InRedditEmail PDF (818 KB) Get e-AlertscloseSUBJECTS:Catalysis,Catalysts,Copper,Peptides and proteins,Redox reactions Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author>Cathleen M. Crudden</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Acridine Photocatalysis Enables Direct Access to Thiols from Carboxylic Acids and Elemental Sulfur</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01289</link>
      <description>Arka Porey, Seth Fremin, Sachchida Nand, Ramon Trevino, William B. Hughes, Shree Krishna Dhakal, Vi&#7879;t D&#361;ng Nguy&#7877;n, Samuel G. Greco, Hadi D. Arman, Oleg V. Larionov, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394962813

                Development of photocatalytic systems that facilitate mechanistically divergent steps in complex catalytic manifolds by distinct activation modes can enable previously inaccessible synthetic transformations. However, multimodal photocatalytic systems remain understudied, impeding their implementation in catalytic methodology. We report herein a photocatalytic access to thiols that directly merges the structural diversity of carboxylic acids with the ready availability of elemental sulfur without substrate preactivation. The photocatalytic transformation provides a direct radical-mediated segue to one of the most biologically important and synthetically versatile organosulfur functionalities, whose synthetic accessibility remains largely dominated by two-electron-mediated processes based on toxic and uneconomical reagents and precursors. The two-phase radical process is facilitated by a multimodal catalytic reactivity of acridine photocatalysis that enables both singlet excited state PCET-mediated decarboxylative carbon&#8211;sulfur bond formation and previously unknown radical reductive disulfur bond cleavage by a photoinduced hydrogen atom transfer process in the silane&#8211;triplet acridine system. The study points to a significant potential of multimodal photocatalytic systems in providing unexplored directions to previously inaccessible transformations.</description>
      <author>Arka Porey, Seth Fremin, Sachchida Nand, Ramon Trevino, William B. Hughes, Shree Krishna Dhakal, Vi&#7879;t D&#361;ng Nguy&#7877;n, Samuel G. Greco, Hadi D. Arman, Oleg V. Larionov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt&#8211;Pyrrole Complex-Assisted Synthesis of Carbon-Supported Pt Intermetallics for Oxygen Reduction in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05471</link>
      <description>Yuting Jiang, Qing Zhang, Jiajia Qian, Yameng Wang, Yongbiao Mu, Zhiyuan Zhang, Zheng Li, Tianshou Zhao, Bilu Liu, Lin Zeng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394963378

                Nanosized intermetallic Pt-transition metal alloys with high catalytic activity and stability are considered as promising catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). However, the preparation of intermetallic Pt alloy nanoparticles remains a dilemma due to their pronounced tendency for sintering at high synthesizing temperatures. Here, we have synthesized several Pt intermetallics with an average size of 4 nm by employing carbon-supported Pt&#8211;-pyrrole complex and transition metal (TM = Fe, Co, Ni) salts as precursors. Transmission electron microscope (TEM) results indicate that not only the uniform pregrowth of the Pt&#8211;pyrrole complex onto the carbon support but also the subsequently derived N-doped carbon shells (&lt;1 nm) on the nanoparticles during annealing contribute to the formation of the nanosized intermetallics. Additional characterization suggests that the intermetallic alloy structure endows the catalyst (PtCo@Pt/C-6) with a downshifted Pt d-band center, which implies the weakened adsorption of the ORR intermediates on the Pt alloy, thus facilitating the ORR kinetics. The fuel cell with the as-prepared PtCo@Pt/C-6 catalyst displays a rated peak power density of 1.1 W/cm2 at 0.67 V (H2/air) and a mass activity of 0.49 A/mgPt at 0.9 V, exceeding the targets of the US Department of Energy (1.0 W/cm2 and 0.44 A/mgPt, respectively). This method demonstrates great potentials for the scalable synthesis of PtTM/C catalysts with high ORR performance and promoting their applications in PEMFCs.</description>
      <author>Yuting Jiang, Qing Zhang, Jiajia Qian, Yameng Wang, Yongbiao Mu, Zhiyuan Zhang, Zheng Li, Tianshou Zhao, Bilu Liu, Lin Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Enhancement of Flavin-Containing Monooxygenase through Machine Learning Methodology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00826</link>
      <description>Takuma Matsushita, Shinji Kishimoto, Kodai Hara, Hiroshi Hashimoto, Hideki Yamaguchi, Yutaka Sait&#333;, Kenji Watanabe, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394907924

                Directed evolution of enzymes often fails to obtain desirable variants because of the difficulty in exploring a huge sequence space. To obtain active variants from a very limited number of variants available at the laboratory scale, machine learning (ML)-guided engineering of enzymes is becoming an attractive methodology. However, as far as we know, there is no example of an ML-guided functional modification of flavin-containing monooxygenase (FMO). FMOs are known to catalyze a variety of oxidative reactions and are involved in the biosynthesis of many natural products (NPs). Therefore, it is expected that the ML-guided functional enhancement of FMO can contribute to the efficient development of NP derivatives. In this research, we focused on p-hydroxybenzoate hydroxylase (PHBH), a model FMO, and altered only four amino acid residues around the substrate binding site. ML models were trained with a small initial library covering only approximately 0.1% of the whole sequence space, and the ML-predicted second library was enriched with active variants. The variant with the highest activity in the second library was PHBH-MWNL (V47M, W185, L199N, and L210), whose activity was more than 100 times that of the wild-type PHBH. For elucidation of the mechanism of the observed activity enhancement, the crystal structure of PHBH-MWNL in complex with 4-hydroxy-3-methyl benzoic acid was determined. In the PHBH-MWNL crystal structure, the missing water molecule WAT2 was observed due to N199 hydrogen-bonding to WAT2, indicating that the L199N mutation contributed to the observed functional improvement by stabilizing the proton relay network proposed to be important in catalysis.</description>
      <author>Takuma Matsushita, Shinji Kishimoto, Kodai Hara, Hiroshi Hashimoto, Hideki Yamaguchi, Yutaka Sait&#333;, Kenji Watanabe</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Imine Reductase Activity of a Promiscuous Glucose Dehydrogenase for Scalable Manufacturing of a Chiral Neprilysin Inhibitor Precursor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05615</link>
      <description>Yang Xiang, Florian Kleinbeck, Charlene Ching, Lorita Boghospor, Shaiany Sabrina Lopes Gomes, Oscar Alvizo, Thomas Allmendinger, Jason S. Fell, Nandhitha Subramanian, Michelle Li, Ravi Garcia, James N. Riggins, David A. Entwistle, Yvonne Richter, Daniel A. Gschwend, Liam Lauener, T.S. Peat, H&#233;l&#232;ne Lebhar, Thierry Schlama, Thomas Ruch, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394996413

                Imine reductases (IREDs) have been identified as an important class of biocatalysts to synthesize chiral amines with substantial promise for industrial application. Here, we report the promiscuous imine reductase activity of a glucose dehydrogenase (GDH). Starting from enzyme GDH Rd1bb, a commercial glucose dehydrogenase variant typically used for NAD(P)H regeneration, eight rounds of directed evolution were used to convert this enzyme into a highly active IRED for the chemo- and stereoselective manufacture of a chiral neprilysin inhibitor precursor, improved NADH cofactor specificity, and superior thermal stability. The evolved variant GDH Rd6bb achieved high productivity, with 99% conversion over 3 h at 50 g/L keto substrate concentration and 10% enzyme loading with respect to the keto substrate. Early process development studies at multigram scale provided the product in 94% yield with &gt;99% purity as a single stereoisomer with an er of &gt;99.9:0.1 and a dr of &gt;99.9:0.1.</description>
      <author>Yang Xiang, Florian Kleinbeck, Charlene Ching, Lorita Boghospor, Shaiany Sabrina Lopes Gomes, Oscar Alvizo, Thomas Allmendinger, Jason S. Fell, Nandhitha Subramanian, Michelle Li, Ravi Garcia, James N. Riggins, David A. Entwistle, Yvonne Richter, Daniel A. Gschwend, Liam Lauener, T.S. Peat, H&#233;l&#232;ne Lebhar, Thierry Schlama, Thomas Ruch</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05615</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multifunctional Glucose Dehydrogenase Enabled Synthesis of Chiral-Bridged Bicyclic Nitrogen Heterocycles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00825</link>
      <description>Guangde Jiang, J. Lu, Megan Zhou, Wesley Harrison, Huimin Zhao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394997118

                Herein, we report that enzymatic cascade reactions using a glucose dehydrogenase (GDH) and an ene-reductase (ERED) can be utilized for the synthesis of chiral 3-substituted cyclic alcohols and chiral-bridged bicyclic nitrogen heterocycles. The crucial step in these cascade reactions is a kinetic resolution reaction by the multifunctional GDH mutant BsGDH_Q252K. This reaction selectively reduces the R-enantiomers of racemic ketone substrates, yielding enantiopure alcohols with high enantiomeric excess (ee) values of the remaining S-enantiomers. When the reaction is coupled with an ERED-promoted dehydrocyclization reaction, chiral-bridged bicyclic nitrogen heterocycles with a configuration of (1S, 5R) can be conveniently synthesized in one pot. Meanwhile, the chiral alcohol products generated from the kinetic resolution reactions can be further converted to the R-enantiomers of the racemic ketone substrates through the cyclohexanol dehydrogenase activity of BsGDH_Q252K when coupled with an NAD(P)H oxidase. When the oxidase is replaced by an ERED, chiral-bridged bicyclic nitrogen heterocycles with a configuration of (1R, 5S) can also be efficiently synthesized in one pot. Mechanistic studies revealed key amino acid residues in BsGDH_Q252K for the kinetic resolution reaction. Subsequent rational design of BmGDH, a homolog of BsGDH, yielded can also enable a quintuple mutant capable of performing this reaction, while the wild type BmGDH cannot.</description>
      <author>Guangde Jiang, J. Lu, Megan Zhou, Wesley Harrison, Huimin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Pd Catalyst Deactivation in the C&#8211;H Coupling of Tryptophan Residues in Water Using Air as the Oxidant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01699</link>
      <description>Igor Beckers, Christophe Vos, Hendrik Van Dessel, A Lauwers, Wouter Stuyck, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Alina A. Skorynina, Aram L. Bugaev, Dirk De Vos, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394997156

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Igor Beckers, Christophe Vos, Hendrik Van Dessel, A Lauwers, Wouter Stuyck, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Alina A. Skorynina, Aram L. Bugaev, Dirk De Vos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01699</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Water on the Catalytic Oxidation of Ethane on IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(110)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00956</link>
      <description>Jovenal Jamir, Connor Pope, S. Ramasubramanian, Vikram Mehar, Junjie Shi, Jason F. Weaver, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394997366

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jovenal Jamir, Connor Pope, S. Ramasubramanian, Vikram Mehar, Junjie Shi, Jason F. Weaver</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Layered Double Hydroxide-Derived Bimetallic Cu&#8211;Co Alloy Catalysts for the Reverse Water&#8211;Gas Shift Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01249</link>
      <description>Kwang Young Kim, Wonsik Jang, Woo&#8208;Jin Byun, Jun-Young Lee, Miri Kim, Ju Hyeong Lee, Geun Bae Rhim, Myung-Joong Youn, Dong Hyun Chun, Seok Ki Kim, Seungho Cho, Jin Ho Lee, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395003169

                Bimetallic alloy catalysts with finely controlled composition and atomic mixing of the two active metals are vital for maximizing their synergistic effect in enhancing catalytic performances. Herein, we report the design and synthetic strategy of bimetallic Cu&#8211;Co alloy catalysts well dispersed on Al2O3 from a CuCoAl-layered double hydroxide (LDH) for boosting the reverse water&#8211;gas shift (RWGS) performance by controlling the composition and textural properties of Cu&#8211;Co alloy particles. An optimized Cu9Co1/Al2O3 catalyst exhibits a remarkably high CO2 to CO conversion rate (&#8764;0.247 mol h&#8211;1 gcat&#8211;1) with &#8764;99.4% of CO selectivity at a relatively low reaction temperature of 400 &#176;C, which outperforms a monometallic Cu/Al2O3 catalyst and a reference Cu9Co1/Al2O3 catalyst prepared by a conventional impregnation method. A combined experimental and theoretical study reveals that the superior activity of the Cu9Co1/Al2O3 catalyst is attributed to two factors: (i) a modified electronic structure due to the Cu&#8211;Co alloy formation that facilitates CO2 activation and CO desorption and (ii) formation of well-dispersed alloy nanoparticles by using LDHs as the catalyst precursors.</description>
      <author>Kwang Young Kim, Wonsik Jang, Woo&#8208;Jin Byun, Jun-Young Lee, Miri Kim, Ju Hyeong Lee, Geun Bae Rhim, Myung-Joong Youn, Dong Hyun Chun, Seok Ki Kim, Seungho Cho, Jin Ho Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01249</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhenium in Heterogeneous Catalysis: A Rising Star for Hydrogenation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00298</link>
      <description>Jingjie Luo, Changhai Liang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395011012

                Rhenium has a special existence in precious metals. In current catalysis, nanoscale Re(Ox) is appreciated by researchers and used to design effective catalyst systems for a variety of hydrogenation reactions, which are widely applied in the fields of petroleum refining, industrial chemical production, and biomass conversion. Current reports focus on the shining characteristics of Re with changeable chemical valences and high oxophilicity. Re-based catalyst provides an essential electronic environment in bimetallic catalysts or behaves as the main reactive center with efficiency. Regardless, there are still limited research works on rhenium compared to other traditional metal catalysts. Herein, investigations concerning Re catalysis during the past decade are summarized. As a burgeoning star, the essential roles of Re sites as a decorator and even the main centers are interpreted in this Review. The advantages of Re in bimetallic and monometallic catalysts, the available-tuned surface and geometric structure, the factors influencing their catalytic behaviors, and the typical heterogeneous reaction models are expressed thoroughly. This Review may shed light on those researchers who are anxious to find more strategies to conquer a tough task and those who are just stepping into the world of rhenium catalysis.</description>
      <author>Jingjie Luo, Changhai Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Reductive Enzyme Cascades for Valorization of Polyethylene Terephthalate Deconstruction Products&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01671</link>
      <description>Madan R. Gopal, Roman M. Dickey, Neil D. Butler, Michael R. Talley, Daniel T. Nakamura, Ashlesha Mohapatra, Mary P. Watson, Wilfred Chen, Aditya M. Kunjapur, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395011899

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ARTICLES ASAPPREVAddition/CorrectionNEXTORIGINAL ARTICLEThis notice is a correctionCorrection to "Reductive Enzyme Cascades for Valorization of Polyethylene Terephthalate Deconstruction Products"Madan R. GopalMadan R. GopalDepartment of Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesCenter for Plastics Innovation, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesMore by Madan R. Gopal, Roman M. DickeyRoman M. DickeyDepartment of Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesCenter for Plastics Innovation, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesMore by Roman M. Dickey, Neil D. ButlerNeil D. ButlerDepartment of Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesMore by Neil D. Butler, Michael R. TalleyMichael R. TalleyDepartment of Chemistry and Biochemistry, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesCenter for Plastics Innovation, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesMore by Michael R. Talley, Daniel T. NakamuraDaniel T. NakamuraCenter for Plastics Innovation, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesMore by Daniel T. Nakamura, Ashlesha MohapatraAshlesha MohapatraDepartment of Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesMore by Ashlesha Mohapatra, Mary P. WatsonMary P. WatsonDepartment of Chemistry and Biochemistry, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesCenter for Plastics Innovation, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesMore by Mary P. Watsonhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-1879-5257, Wilfred ChenWilfred ChenDepartment of Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesCenter for Plastics Innovation, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesMore by Wilfred Chenhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-6386-6958, and Aditya M. Kunjapur*Aditya M. KunjapurDepartment of Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesCenter for Plastics Innovation, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware 19716, United StatesMore by Aditya M. Kunjapurhttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-6869-9530Cite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, XXX, 7050&#8211;7051Publication Date (Web):April 22, 2024Publication History Received18 March 2024Published online22 April 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01671&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InRedditEmail PDF (1 MB) Get e-Alertsclose Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author>Madan R. Gopal, Roman M. Dickey, Neil D. Butler, Michael R. Talley, Daniel T. Nakamura, Ashlesha Mohapatra, Mary P. Watson, Wilfred Chen, Aditya M. Kunjapur</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01671</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Acid-Metal Synergy in &lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt;-Cresol Hydrodeoxygenation over Bifunctional Pt/Aluminosilicate Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00402</link>
      <description>James A. Hunns, Lee J. Durndell, Xingguang Zhang, Muxina Konarova, Adam Lee, Karen Wilson, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395012109

                Strong synergy between proximate Bro&#823;nsted acid and metal sites over a Pt/amorphous silica&#8211;alumina (ASA) catalyst confers striking activity and selectivity enhancements for m-cresol hydrodeoxygenation to methylcyclohexane, a fuel additive and potential liquid organic hydrogen carrier for storing renewable energy. Molecular shuttling back and forth between cooperative acid and metal sites activates m-cresol for consecutive tautomerization, ring hydrogenation, and dehydration, ensuing eventual hydrogenation to methylcyclohexane with a fourfold yield enhancement compared to a physical mix of solid acid and Pt/SiO2.</description>
      <author>James A. Hunns, Lee J. Durndell, Xingguang Zhang, Muxina Konarova, Adam Lee, Karen Wilson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Interaction between Cu and MgO in Cu/MgO Catalysts for CO Hydrogenation to CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;OH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00077</link>
      <description>Wenqi Liu, Shanshan Dang, Sifan Cheng, Zhenzhou Zhang, Xiao Ding, Yanling Shi, Pengfei Ren, Weifeng Tu, Yi&#8208;Fan Han, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395013096

                In this work, the structure&#8211;performance relationship of Cu/MgO catalysts was established to unravel the role of MgO and the active sites for CO hydrogenation to CH3OH synthesis, by intrinsic kinetics, chemical titration, and a series of in situ (operando) spectroscopic characterizations. The turnover rates of CH3OH formation on Cu/MgO catalysts, especially when the Mg/(Mg + Cu) atomic ratio is 0.67, were significantly higher than that on monometallic Cu particles. We have demonstrated that the rates were insensitive to the particle size of Cu but depended linearly on the quantity of Cu&#8211;MgO interfacial sites. The interaction between Cu and MgO particles improved the dispersion of Cu particles and formed more highly active Cu&#8211;MgO interfacial sites as identified by precise characterization. Moreover, this study has also unraveled that both the HCO* and HCOO* species are predominantly reactive intermediates, and their sequential hydrogenation occurs concurrently for CH3OH formation over Cu/MgO catalysts during the CO&#8211;H2 reaction.</description>
      <author>Wenqi Liu, Shanshan Dang, Sifan Cheng, Zhenzhou Zhang, Xiao Ding, Yanling Shi, Pengfei Ren, Weifeng Tu, Yi&#8208;Fan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Insights into a Surface-Designed Au&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;@Pt&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst in the Base-Free Oxidation of Biomass-Derived Tetrahydrofuran-2,5-dimethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00168</link>
      <description>Enhui Du, Enhui Du, Panpan Hao, Jie Yang, Liyuan Huai, Guoxin Chen, Guoxin Chen, C. T. Chen, C. T. Chen, Jian Zhang, Jian Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395027949

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enhui Du, Enhui Du, Panpan Hao, Jie Yang, Liyuan Huai, Guoxin Chen, Guoxin Chen, C. T. Chen, C. T. Chen, Jian Zhang, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvent-Free Hydroxylation of Unactivated C&#8211;H Bonds in Small Molecules and Macromolecules by a Fe Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00775</link>
      <description>Debasmita Chatterjee, Amritha Sajeevan, Sandipan Jana, Rajkumar S. Birajdar, Samir H. Chikkali, Swaminathan Sivaram, Sayam Sen Gupta, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395030697

                One approach to mitigate the crisis of plastic waste is "chemical upcycling", in which waste plastic is either converted into products with higher economic value or depolymerized to its constituent monomer(s). Toward this goal, several metal-catalyzed postfunctionalizations of polymers have been reported, with variable success, mostly on account of a lack of selectivity, the use of harsh reaction conditions, and the use of environmentally unfriendly solvents. We herein demonstrate the selective hydroxylation of the backbone 3&#176; C&#8211;H bonds in synthetic macromolecules (polyolefin and polystyrene) using the in-house developed (Et4N)2[FeIII-(Ph,Me-bTAML)] (3) complex and solid Na2CO3&#183;1.5H2O2 (SPC; sodium percarbonate) under solvent-free mechanochemical conditions. The reaction only employs simple mechanochemical grinding or ball milling at room temperature. The polar functional group &#8211;OH was successfully incorporated into the polymer backbone without any chain degradation and cross-linking. The same reaction conditions were also employed to selectively hydroxylate small organic molecules including complex natural products. The rate and selectivity of the reaction toward 3&#176; C&#8211;H bonds far exceed that performed under homogeneous conditions. Mechanistic investigation indicates the formation of the well-characterized oxoiron(V) intermediate upon mechanical grinding of 3 and SPC. The high selectivity observed under solvent-free conditions is due to the elimination of the solvent-induced side reaction of this intermediate. This reaction represents an environment-friendly process since it uses environmentally benign reagents (iron complex, "oxygen bleach") and eliminates the use of hazardous solvents. The workup protocol involves simple washing with water, where both the spent catalyst and the oxidant are soluble. Selective mechanochemical oxidation of alkyl and benzylic 3&#176; C&#8211;H bonds often found in commercial polymers, such as polyolefin and polystyrene, may offer a potentially useful method to generate oxyfunctionalized material and also provide routes for the deconstruction of macromolecules with strong C&#8211;C bonds under mild conditions.</description>
      <author>Debasmita Chatterjee, Amritha Sajeevan, Sandipan Jana, Rajkumar S. Birajdar, Samir H. Chikkali, Swaminathan Sivaram, Sayam Sen Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric Fields Are a Key Determinant of Carbapenemase Activity in Class A &#946;-Lactamases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05302</link>
      <description>Hira Jabeen, Michael Beer, Michael Beer, James Spencer, Marc W. van der Kamp, Marc W. van der Kamp, H. Adrian Bunzel, H. Adrian Bunzel, Adrian J. Mulholland, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395030775

                Resistance to antibiotics is a public health crisis. Although carbapenems are less susceptible to resistance than other &#946;-lactam antibiotics, &#946;-lactamases mediating resistance against these drugs are spreading. Here, we dissect the contributions of electric fields to carbapenemase activity in class A &#946;-lactamases. We perform QM/MM molecular dynamics simulations of meropenem acyl-enzyme hydrolysis that correctly discriminate carbapenemases. Electric field analysis shows that active-site fields in the deacylation transition state and tetrahedral intermediate are important determinants of activity. The active-site fields identify several residues, some distal, that distinguish efficient carbapenemases. Our field analysis script (www.github.com/bunzela/FieldTools) may help in understanding and combating antibiotic resistance.</description>
      <author>Hira Jabeen, Michael Beer, Michael Beer, James Spencer, Marc W. van der Kamp, Marc W. van der Kamp, H. Adrian Bunzel, H. Adrian Bunzel, Adrian J. Mulholland</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Activation of H&#8211;H Bonds by Platinum in Dilute Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00886</link>
      <description>Tongxin Han, Yuanyuan Li, Tao Wu, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Shuting Xiang, Yueqiang Cao, Yueqiang Cao, Ilkeun Lee, Xinggui Zhou, De&#8208;en Jiang, Anatoly I. Frenkel, Anatoly I. Frenkel, Francisco Zaera, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395037408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tongxin Han, Yuanyuan Li, Tao Wu, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Shuting Xiang, Yueqiang Cao, Yueqiang Cao, Ilkeun Lee, Xinggui Zhou, De&#8208;en Jiang, Anatoly I. Frenkel, Anatoly I. Frenkel, Francisco Zaera</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00886</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of Hydrogen Spillover on Metal-Doped Carbon Materials: Surface Carboxylic Groups Are Key</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00293</link>
      <description>Javier Navarro&#8208;Ruiz, J&#233;r&#233;my Audevard, M. Vidal, Cristian H. Campos, Iker del Rosal, Philippe Serp, Iann C. Gerber, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395042772

                Hydrogen spillover (H-spillover) is the surface migration of activated hydrogen atoms from a metallic particle on which they are generated onto a support. The phenomenon has been widely studied because of its implication in hydrogen storage and in catalytic reactions involving hydrogen. Its existence on carbon materials is well established, but questions remain regarding its mechanism and the involvement of surface oxygen groups. In this study, we combined experimental work with chemical modeling to study the mechanisms of H-spillover on a representative system, including a carbon material presenting basal and prismatic surfaces: oxidized carbon nanotubes doped with Pd. The experimental results, supported by those of modeling, show that the surface carboxylic acid groups are the key species, allowing the spillover of hydrogen on carbon materials to take place. The carboxylic groups can also work in combination with phenol groups to facilitate H-spillover. If the concentration of these groups is too low, then the H-spillover does not operate, except in the case of the addition of water, which serves as a shuttle for the protons. This study leads to a deeper understanding of the long-debated issue of H-spillover on carbon materials and provides insight into designing systems with enhanced properties.</description>
      <author>Javier Navarro&#8208;Ruiz, J&#233;r&#233;my Audevard, M. Vidal, Cristian H. Campos, Iker del Rosal, Philippe Serp, Iann C. Gerber</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Origin of Ligand Effects on Exhaustive Functionalization During Pd-Catalyzed Cross-Coupling of Dihaloarenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00646</link>
      <description>Nathaniel G. Larson, Jacob P. Norman, Sharon R. Neufeldt, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395042864

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nathaniel G. Larson, Jacob P. Norman, Sharon R. Neufeldt</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Dynamics of Oxygen Vacancy in ZnO&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;/Cu during Robust Methanol Synthesis from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01648</link>
      <description>Fanxing Zhang, Boyang Li, Qianqian Xu, Ke Wang, XU Jia-ye, Tiantian Wu, Zhenglong Li, Zhenglong Li, Yan Mao, Shoujie Liu, Yi He, Yi He, Yao Shi, Yaqiong Su, Pengfei Xie, Pengfei Xie, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395048468

                The extensive investigation regarding the active site of the Cu/ZnO/Al2O3 catalyst gradually recognizes the paramount importance of the oxygen vacancy in the hydrogenation of CO2 to methanol. However, it is challenging to probe the nature of oxygen vacancy during methanol synthesis and understand its role in the enhancement of reactivity at the molecule level. Here, the inversed ZnO1&#8211;x/Cu catalysts with abundant oxygen vacancies are prepared by simple ball milling. The interfacial transformations between ZnO1&#8211;x and Cu during material preparation and reaction are elucidated by the correlations of geometrical and chemical states with mechanical energies. The dynamics of the oxygen vacancy during the reaction are revealed as well. The ZnO1&#8211;x/Cu with more oxygen vacancy exhibits a superior CH3OH productivity of 1.2 gMeOH g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 at 240 &#176;C and a selectivity above 90%. The mechanistic studies reveal that oxygen vacancy promotes the activation of CO2 to formate and significantly reduces the barrier of the hydrogenation from *HCOO to *H2COO intermediates.</description>
      <author>Fanxing Zhang, Boyang Li, Qianqian Xu, Ke Wang, XU Jia-ye, Tiantian Wu, Zhenglong Li, Zhenglong Li, Yan Mao, Shoujie Liu, Yi He, Yi He, Yao Shi, Yaqiong Su, Pengfei Xie, Pengfei Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Heterocyclic Carbene Radical Organocatalysis with Nickel Chemistry: A Rational Mechanistic Study-Based Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01253</link>
      <description>Ludivine Delfau, Ernesto Di Mauro, Jacques P&#233;caut, David Mart&#237;n, Eder Tom&#225;s&#8208;Mendivil, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395049498

                A cooperative NHC/nickel catalytic methodology has been developed for the synthesis of ketones employing aromatic aldehydes and tertiary alkyl iodides. All key steps of the postulated catalytic cycle were validated with comprehensive stoichiometric and electrochemical studies, including reduction of NiII by the deprotonated Breslow intermediate, Ni0 promoted halogen-atom abstraction to generate transient tertiary alkyl radicals, and coupling between the latter with the persistent acyl thiazolium radical intermediate. Such a broadly proposed and accepted, yet elusive, acyl thiazolium radical intermediate has been isolated and studied by a single-crystal X-ray diffraction study.</description>
      <author>Ludivine Delfau, Ernesto Di Mauro, Jacques P&#233;caut, David Mart&#237;n, Eder Tom&#225;s&#8208;Mendivil</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01253</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
