<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 01:14:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-Carbenoid-Mediated Selective Transformation: Experimental and DFT Studies of Ag, Pd, and Rh with Enaminones and Diazoesters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03136</link>
      <description>Xin Zhang, Lijuan Song, Yi Jin, Kaixiu Luo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401877969

                Transition-metal-catalyzed transfer of a carbene group via in situ generated carbenoid intermediates from &#945;-diazocarbonyls is a powerful method for initiating diverse cascade sequences that rapidly lead to the generation of structural complexity. Despite significant advancements in carbenoid-enabled catalytic pathways, such as insertions and cyclopropane formation, there has been limited exploration of the selective control of catalytic processes involving carbenoid chemistry. In this study, we reported a metal-carbenoid-mediated cascade transformation approach that allows for selective control by employing different transition metals, including silver, palladium, and rhodium, assisted by a comprehensive density functional theory (DFT) mechanism investigation. Through detailed mechanistic studies, we demonstrate that silver-carbenoids and rhodium-carbenoids yield distinct tandem cyclization products, while palladium-carbenoids afford quaternary &#945;-imine compounds as the final product through direct proton transfer from the same intermediate. Furthermore, the origin of the catalyst-dependent selectivity is elucidated through DFT calculations.</description>
      <author>Xin Zhang, Lijuan Song, Yi Jin, Kaixiu Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alcohols as Alkyl Synthons Enabled by Photoredox-Catalyzed Deoxygenative Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03560</link>
      <description>Tanumoy Mandal, Samrat Mallick, Malekul Islam, Suman De Sarkar, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401894447

                Alcohols are abundant with versatile structural variety and have ample use as pivotal functional groups in numerous organic processes. Because of their frequent occurrence in enumerable natural products, bioactive molecules, and medicinal components, alcohol functionalities provide a promising scope of research to advance the operational diversity for improving clinical success. Recent years have witnessed the design of modern C&#8211;C and C&#8211;heteroatom bond-forming approaches with easily accessible and commercially available unactivated aliphatic alcohols as native adaptive sp3 handles, hence offering groundbreaking transformative pathways for the functionalization of complex molecular architectures. The judicial application of appropriate activating groups to generate the alkyl radical from the alcohol through sp3 C&#8211;O bond fragmentation and employ it as a potential alkylating agent unfolds unique synthetic strategies, thereby replacing the obvious requirement of alkyl halides. This review elaborately discusses the recent trends regarding using alcohols as the C(sp3)-centered alkylating agent in various chemical transformations by exploiting different activation modes for the disrupter of the C&#8211;O bond under photoredox catalysis. The presentation is organized by the nature of the activation of the alcohol scaffolds, the kind of bond formation, and the progress achieved in this domain since the original discovery by providing illustrative examples with mechanistic details, with a focus on difficulties and future prospects.</description>
      <author>Tanumoy Mandal, Samrat Mallick, Malekul Islam, Suman De Sarkar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Ultrahighly Branched Polyethylene Synthesis via Externally Robust Chain-Walking Polymerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02385</link>
      <description>Huijun Fan, Xiaohui Kang, Shengyu Dai, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401913517

                Recently, late-transition-metal-catalyzed chain-walking polymerization has emerged as a promising method for synthesizing a range of polyethylenes, including linear, branched, and hyperbranched structures, solely from ethylene feedstock. The spatial configuration of the catalyst is a crucial factor in determining the branching patterns observed in the resulting polyethylene. In this study, we designed and employed a series of stereoscopically bulky &#945;-diimine Ni(II) and Pd(II) complexes featuring axial flexible cycloalkyl substituents and an equatorial rigid dibenzobarrelene backbone for ethylene (co)polymerization. These Ni(II) complexes exhibited high catalytic activity, reaching up to 106 g/(mol Ni&#183;h), and yielded very-high-molecular-weight polyethylene with extremely narrow molecular weight distributions (1.00&#8211;1.27) and very high branching densities (105&#8211;153/1000C) in a living ethylene polymerization behavior under various polymerization temperatures. Most interestingly, the branching density of polyethylene from the cyclohexyl-substituted Ni(II) complex is almost independent of the polymerization conditions and ultrahighly branched polyethylene with ultrahigh molecular weight (up to 1097 kg/mol) can be accessed. On the other hand, the corresponding Pd(II) complexes also demonstrated moderate catalytic activity, achieving up to 105 g/(mol Pd&#183;h), and yielded highly branched polyethylene with high molecular weights ranging from 160.8 to 511.9 kg/mol. Moreover, these Pd(II) complexes were capable of generating high-molecular-weight E-MA copolymers with adjustable incorporation ratios (0.85&#8211;2.77 mol %) and high branching densities (106&#8211;117/1000C). Through a comparative analysis of single-crystal structures and DFT calculations, we found that the axial flexible cycloalkyl substituents and equatorial rigid dibenzobarrelene backbone of these complexes create an interesting ligand environment that favors chain walking over chain propagation in the nickel-catalyzed ethylene polymerization system. This finding provides valuable insights into the design of more efficient and controllable catalysts for the synthesis of polyethylenes with tailored properties.</description>
      <author>Huijun Fan, Xiaohui Kang, Shengyu Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversed Charge Transfer Enables Dual Active Sites on Ir/hBN for Synergistic N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O Valorization and Propane Selective Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03697</link>
      <description>Y.M. Wu, Yuxin Sun, Xuanhao Wu, Haiqiang Wang, Zhongbiao Wu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401920318

                Valorization of nitrous oxide (N2O) as a mild oxygen source for light alkanes presents a promising and economical method for mitigating global warming. However, activating N2O and alkane together often leads to overoxidation and poor selectivity of the products. To disentangle the trade-off between activity and selectivity, herein, an Ir-based hexagonal boron nitride (hBN) catalyst was synthesized to obtain a reversed charge transfer (RCT) from the support to metal centers, forming dual active sites on Ir clusters and the separation of redox centers, as determined via operando near-ambient-pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (NAP-XPS) and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Ir/hBN demonstrated a high N2O conversion (99.5%) and syngas yield (95.9 mol of CO kgcat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 and 41.9 mol of H2 kgcat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1) during the selective oxidation of propane (C3H8) at 450 &#176;C. The electron-rich Ir interfacial perimeter sites (Ir&#948;&#8722;) enhance N2O adsorption and N&#8211;O bond dissociation to produce active O*; however, facial metallic Ir0 sites effectively facilitate C3H8 activation, including dehydrogenation and cracking. The separation of H* and O* intermediates, along with the frustrated H*/O* spillover, effectively facilitates the formation of H2. The *CH2 intermediate from C3H8 breakage migrates and reacts with O* bound to Ir interfacial sites, where it is oxidized to CO32&#8211; and subsequently liberates CO. This study provides mechanistic insights into the O element valorization from N2O with synergetic enhancement in selective oxidation of light alkanes.</description>
      <author>Y.M. Wu, Yuxin Sun, Xuanhao Wu, Haiqiang Wang, Zhongbiao Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03697</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Extra-Framework Aluminum Species on the Catalytic Properties of Acidic USY Zeolite in (Hydro)cracking Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03269</link>
      <description>Sohrab Askarli, Ildar Mukhambetov, Sang&#8210;Ho Chung, Mohammad Awwad, Jos&#233; Almeida, Sarah Komaty, Juan Carlos Navarro de Miguel, Teng Li, Javier Ruiz&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401943162

                Extra-framework aluminum (EFAl) species are known to alter the acidic nature of zeolites and therefore their catalytic properties. Although it has been reported that the formation of such species leads to a change in the concentration and strength of acidity, the influence of those on hydrocracking warrants further exploration. To investigate these concepts, faujasite zeolite (ultrastable Y, USY) samples with various SiO2/Al2O3 ratios were steamed at different conditions until they showed similar hydrocracking activity to the reference USY sample. The steaming process results in zeolite samples with similar catalytic activity and selectivity but different levels of EFAl. Hexane cracking tests and pentylamine adsorption followed by two-dimensional 1H&#8211;27Al heteronuclear nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy show that samples with a high number of EFAl sites have a larger number of those species in close proximity to the Br&#248;nsted acid site (BAS). After the extensive characterization, we concluded that the catalytic activity and product selectivity in hydrocracking is unrelated to both Br&#248;nsted acid strength and EFAl species near BAS, leaving the number of BAS as the main activity descriptor.</description>
      <author>Sohrab Askarli, Ildar Mukhambetov, Sang&#8210;Ho Chung, Mohammad Awwad, Jos&#233; Almeida, Sarah Komaty, Juan Carlos Navarro de Miguel, Teng Li, Javier Ruiz&#8208;Mart&#237;nez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge Transfer Drives Hydrogen Adsorption, Spillover, and Hydroxylation at the Pt/&#947;-Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03485</link>
      <description>George Yan, Salman A. Khan, Dionisios G. Vlachos, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401946493

                Metal&#8211;support interactions have garnered much attention due to their impact on the structure and reactivity of supported metal catalysts. Despite the widespread recognition of multifunctional mechanisms in metal/metal oxide systems, much less attention has been paid to how the metal influences its support. Here, we explore metal&#8211;support interactions using hydrogen adsorption on a dehydroxylated &#947;-Al2O3(110) supported Pt10 cluster as a prototype. Through molecular dynamics simulations performed using an actively trained machine-learned force field, we observed reversible hydrogen spillover between the support and the metal. Analysis of the electronic structure and chemical nature of the interface reveals that charge transfer from H to the Pt10 cluster drives the spillover by stabilizing H adsorbed on the support. The same charge transfer concept also explains the stabilization of OH fragments at the Pt10/&#947;-Al2O3(110) interface despite the scarcely impacted or even reduced acidity of interfacial Al sites. These findings demonstrate the rich chemistry of metal&#8211;support interfaces and the importance of "inverse" effects in the fundamental understanding of supported catalysts.</description>
      <author>George Yan, Salman A. Khan, Dionisios G. Vlachos</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of Chiral All-Carbon Quaternary Stereocenters by Photoinduced Cobalt-Catalyzed Enantioselective Radical Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04249</link>
      <description>Yue Jia, Kai Zhang, Liang&#8208;Qiu Lu, Ying Cheng, Wen&#8208;Jing Xiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401952585

                Photoinduced enantioselective strategies provide an efficient way to access chiral all-carbon quaternary stereocenters. Compared with the well-developed metal-catalyzed asymmetric conjugate addition of organometallic reagents to enones, the construction of chiral all-carbon quaternary stereocenters through a radical process still remains challenging, especially for the acyclic enones due to their enhanced conformational mobility. Herein, we disclose a photoinduced cobalt-catalyzed asymmetric radical coupling of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated 2-acyl imidazoles and &#945;-silylamines to give &#946;,&#946;-disubstituted &#947;-amino acid derivatives with acyclic quaternary carbon stereocenters. The facile protocol shows good functional group tolerance and a broad substrate scope. The corresponding chiral products were obtained in generally good yields (up to 96%) with high enantioselectivities (up to 99:1 e.r.).</description>
      <author>Yue Jia, Kai Zhang, Liang&#8208;Qiu Lu, Ying Cheng, Wen&#8208;Jing Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04249</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cationic Bis(&#951;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;6&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;-arene) Cobalt(I) Complexes: Enabling Catalyst Discovery by High-Throughput Experimentation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03843</link>
      <description>Maya J. Lebowitz, Connor S. MacNeil, Lauren N. Mendelsohn, Michael Shevlin, Matthew V. Pecoraro, Gabriele Hierlmeier, Paul J. Chirik, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401976037

                Cationic, 20-electron bis(&#951;6-arene)Co(I) complexes have been synthesized and evaluated as precursors for the generation of bis(phosphine) cobalt(I) &#951;6-arene precatalysts. The arenes and anions in the precursors were varied, with isolated examples, including [Al(pftb)4]&#8722; (pftb = (CF3)3CO), [BArF4]&#8722; (tetrakis[3,5-bis(trifluoromethyl)phenyl]borate), and [SbF6]&#8722;. Treatment of the isolated precursors with a series bis(phosphines) resulted in arene displacement and isolation of well-defined [(bis(phosphine))Co(&#951;6-arene)][X] (X = Al(pftb)4&#8211; and SbF6&#8211;; arene = C6H6, C6H5Me, and C6H5Et) complexes in 84&#8211;99% yield. This ligand substitution enabled unprecedented generation of catalyst libraries using high-throughput experimentation (HTE) for asymmetric alkene hydrogenation, as well as formal [2 + 2] cycloaddition, hydroboration, and C(sp2)&#8211;H functionalization. These versatile precursors simplify increasingly complex chemical transformations by introducing single-component, well-defined precatalysts through general ligand substitution.</description>
      <author>Maya J. Lebowitz, Connor S. MacNeil, Lauren N. Mendelsohn, Michael Shevlin, Matthew V. Pecoraro, Gabriele Hierlmeier, Paul J. Chirik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyper-Cross-Linked Polymer-Based Self-Supported Reusable Ru-NHC Catalyst for Amine-Assisted Hydrogenation of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02513</link>
      <description>Ravi Kumar, Tanmoy Mandal, Arindom Bhattacherya, Madhusudan K. Pandey, Jitendra K. Bera, Joyanta Choudhury, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401981354

                Research on the capture and catalytic conversion of CO2 to valuable chemicals and alternative fuel candidates has multifaceted relevance from the perspective of sustainable development goals (SDGs). Methanol, advocated as an alternative fuel, can be produced via amine-assisted integrated capture of CO2 and the subsequent hydrogenation via a formamide intermediate. Notably, amines not only function as CO2-capturing agents but also assist in crucial H2 activation by a metal catalyst during a series of hydrogenation steps to form methanol. Toward implementation of this cascade strategy of amine-assisted hydrogenation of CO2 to MeOH, herein, we developed an NHC-based pincer ligand-bound homogeneous molecular Ru catalyst (Ru-1), which was then translated into a porous hyper-cross-linked polymer (HCP)-based self-supported single-site heterogeneous catalyst, termed as HCP-Ru-1. Initially, a control mechanistic investigation was performed in order to get insights into the crucial H2 activation step at the Ru center of the catalyst assisted by the amine used in the reaction. Next, the formation of the formamide intermediate by both catalyst candidates Ru-1 and HCP-Ru-1 was probed and confirmed, employing several amines in the presence of pressurized CO2 and H2 at a relatively mild temperature of 120 &#176;C, where the catalysts exhibited turnover numbers (TONs) up to 3520 and 15,750, respectively, indicating their high catalytic efficiency. Finally, for the catalytic CO2-to-MeOH production reaction, a polyamine, namely, pentaethylenehexamine (PEHA), was used due to its high efficiency in CO2 capture as well as ability to act as a suitable organic base for deprotonative H2 activation, and the Ru-1 and HCP-Ru-1 systems displayed single-run TONs of 400 and 1150, respectively. As the most significant advancement in this process, the heterogeneous HCP-Ru-1 catalyst turned out to be highly reusable, and in a 10-cycle reuse demonstration experiment, it achieved a cumulative TON of 10,370 with merely 1.13% loss in activity per cycle.</description>
      <author>Ravi Kumar, Tanmoy Mandal, Arindom Bhattacherya, Madhusudan K. Pandey, Jitendra K. Bera, Joyanta Choudhury</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convergent Active Site Evolution in Platinum Single Atom Catalysts for Acetylene Hydrochlorination and Implications for Toxicity Minimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03533</link>
      <description>Vera Giulimondi, Matteo Vanni, Suyash Damir, Tao Zou, Sharon Mitchell, Frank Krumeich, Andrea Ruiz&#8208;Ferrando, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, J.J. Gata-Cuesta, Gonzalo Guill&#233;n&#8208;Gos&#225;lbez, Joost J. Smit, Peter Johnston, Javier P&#233;rez-Ram&#305;&#769;rez, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401991372

                Platinum single atoms anchored onto activated carbon enable highly stable Hg-free synthesis of vinyl chloride (VCM) via acetylene hydrochlorination. Compared to gold-based alternatives, platinum catalysts are in initial phases of development. Most synthetic approaches rely on chloroplatinic acid, presenting opportunities to explore other precursors and their impact on catalyst structure, reactivity, and toxicity aspects. Here, we synthesize platinum single atom catalysts (Pt SACs, 0.2&#8211;0.8 wt % Pt) employing diverse Pt2+ and Pt4+ complexes with ammine, hydroxyl, nitrate, and chloride ligands, following a scalable impregnation protocol on activated carbon extrudates. X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) reveals that Pt4+ species reduce to Pt2+ upon deposition onto the support. Despite similar oxidation states, the initial activity is precursor dependent, with tetraammine-derived Pt SACs displaying 2-fold higher VCM yield than chlorinated counterparts, linked to superior hydrogen chloride binding abilities by density functional theory (DFT) simulations. Their activity gradually converges due to dynamic active site restructuring, delivering remarkable precursor-independent stability over 150 h. Operando XAS and DFT studies uncover reaction-induced ligand exchange, generating common active and stable Pt&#8211;Clx (x = 2&#8211;3) species. Convergent active site evolution enables flexibility in metal precursor selection and thus toxicity minimization through multiparameter assessment. This study advances safe-by-design catalysts for VCM synthesis, highlighting the importance of toxicity analyses in early-stage catalyst development programs.</description>
      <author>Vera Giulimondi, Matteo Vanni, Suyash Damir, Tao Zou, Sharon Mitchell, Frank Krumeich, Andrea Ruiz&#8208;Ferrando, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, J.J. Gata-Cuesta, Gonzalo Guill&#233;n&#8208;Gos&#225;lbez, Joost J. Smit, Peter Johnston, Javier P&#233;rez-Ram&#305;&#769;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide Origin during High-Yield Partial Oxidation of Methane to Protected Methyl Esters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04105</link>
      <description>Andrea N. Blankenship, Alexandru-Tudor Todera&#351;c, Vladimir Paunovi&#263;, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401991373

                Mn/TiO2 catalysts are highly active for the partial oxidation of methane using dioxygen in acidic media to form oxidation-protected methyl esters. Nonetheless, the formation of carbon dioxide in these systems remains significant. In this study, we used 13C isotope-labeled methane to trace the origin of the carbon dioxide formation. These experiments showed that carbon dioxide primarily stems from acid degradation rather than product overoxidation in this system, confirming the high-yield methane partial oxidation of the esterification approach. Evaluation of activities and selectivities of the catalysts with different initial manganese distributions under different methane partial pressures and reaction temperatures revealed that ester selectivity within the liquid products remains nearly constant, while lower temperatures minimize the parasitic overoxidation of solvent. Using this knowledge, we demonstrated that a Mn/TiO2 catalyst synthesized via coprecipitation can provide 90% ester selectivity at 21% methane conversion within 3 h at 215 &#176;C, representing the best reported heterogeneously catalyzed system for methane partial oxidation with molecular oxygen. This study identifies the road ahead for this chemistry, entailing further optimization of solid catalysts for improved ester productivity and high product yields while curtailing undesired side reactions unrelated to methane conversion.</description>
      <author>Andrea N. Blankenship, Alexandru-Tudor Todera&#351;c, Vladimir Paunovi&#263;, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulse Manipulation on Cu-Based Catalysts for Electrochemical Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03513</link>
      <description>Wanlong Xi, Hongyao Zhou, Peng Yang, Huiting Huang, Jia Tian, Marina Ratova, Dan Wu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402031369

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (CO2RR) over Cu-based catalysts has emerged as a promising strategy for value-added artificial carbon cycling, addressing the current climate and energy challenges. However, the product selectivity and long-term stability of Cu-based catalysts are limited by their instability at constant potential. Recent advancements in pulsed techniques aim to overcome these limitations, enhancing the industrial feasibility of the CO2RR systems. This review critically examines recent research progress in pulsed CO2RR over Cu-based catalysts, offering a comprehensive synthesis of current findings. Key pulse parameters and characterization strategies are explored to uncover the mechanisms behind the enhanced CO2RR performance. The focus is on surface reconstruction, encompassing the regeneration and stabilization of the Cu oxidation states alongside morphological evolution, while also discussing microenvironment changes, including local CO2 concentration, local pH, and ionic arrangement. The intricate modulation mechanisms of pulse mode, potential, and duration on the CO2RR performance are elucidated, highlighting their interconnections. Finally, we identify the prevailing challenges and propose future directions for achieving environmentally friendly and economically viable artificial carbon cycling. By providing insightful perspectives on optimizing pulsed CO2RR, this review paves the way for developing more efficient and robust Cu-based catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Wanlong Xi, Hongyao Zhou, Peng Yang, Huiting Huang, Jia Tian, Marina Ratova, Dan Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effects of Complex Cu Species in Cu&#8211;MgO Catalysts for the Water Gas Shift Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04064</link>
      <description>Mei&#8208;Yao Wu, Shanqing Li, Wei-Wei Wang, Chun&#8208;Jiang Jia, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402031423

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mei&#8208;Yao Wu, Shanqing Li, Wei-Wei Wang, Chun&#8208;Jiang Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-Catalyzed Additive-Free Dehydrogenation of Neat Formic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04109</link>
      <description>Bedraj Pandey, Jeanette A. Krause, Hairong Guan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402079016

                Dehydrogenation of formic acid without using additives and solvents is a challenging research problem in base metal catalysis. In this study, cobalt complexes of the type (iPrPPRP)CoH(PMe3) (iPrPPRP = (o-iPr2PC6H4)2PR; R = H or Me) are shown to catalyze the additive-free dehydrogenation of neat formic acid to carbon dioxide. The iPrPPMeP-ligated cobalt hydride is particularly effective, giving catalytic turnover numbers of up to 7122 with a single load of formic acid and 10,338 with a continuous addition of formic acid. Mechanistic investigation focusing on (iPrPPMeP)CoH(PMe3) reveals that the hydride complex is initially converted to [(iPrPPMeP)CoH2(PMe3)]+ and then to "(iPrPPMeP)Co(OCHO)" as the key intermediates for releasing H2 and CO2, respectively. As the catalytic reaction proceeds, decarbonylation of formic acid produces CO, which transforms the intermediates to [(iPrPPMeP)Co(CO)(PMe3)]+ and (iPrPPMeP)Co(CO)H as the less active forms of the catalyst. Further degradation to [(iPrPPMeP)Co(CO)2]+, protonated phosphine ligands, and cobalt formate ends the catalyst's life. Contrary to many other catalytic systems, the cobalt catalysts described here are more active in neat formic acid than in formic acid solutions, which can be attributed to the removal of PMe3 from the coordination sphere (via phosphine protonation) to generate a more reactive intermediate.</description>
      <author>Bedraj Pandey, Jeanette A. Krause, Hairong Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium Promotes Phase Transformation to Active Oxyhydroxide for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03974</link>
      <description>Yong Wang, Sijia Liu, Yunpu Qin, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Jianfang Liu, Yadong Liu, Aimin Chu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402079069

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for renewable energy technologies like metal&#8211;air batteries and water splitting. However, it suffers from sluggish kinetics, necessitating a high-activity and stable catalyst. In this study, we used Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations to demonstrate that Cr doping favors the phase transition of metal (Fe, Co, Ni) hydroxide to the active phase oxyhydroxide. We synthesized FeCoNiCr hydroxide using an aqueous sol&#8211;gel method, ensuring that the four elements Fe, Co, Ni, and Cr are uniformly distributed at the atomic level. As an OER catalyst, FeCoNiCr hydroxide exhibits a very low overpotential of 224 mV in alkaline media, which is 52 mV lower than that of FeCoNi hydroxide, placing it among the best nonprecious metal catalysts reported so far. Additionally, it demonstrates long-term catalytic stability of 150 h. An assembled Zn-Air battery with FeCoNiCr hydroxides was cycled stably for 160 h with a low discharge/charge voltage difference of 0.70 V. DFT calculations and microkinetic modeling demonstrated that Cr doping significantly optimized the adsorption energies of OER intermediates at the Ni and Co sites, thereby enhancing overall OER activity. Bader charge calculations further revealed that Ni and Co in the catalysts consistently maintained a +3 valence throughout the OER process, which is beneficial for OER catalysis.</description>
      <author>Yong Wang, Sijia Liu, Yunpu Qin, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Jianfang Liu, Yadong Liu, Aimin Chu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystalline Oxygen-Modified Carbon Nitride Photocatalyst with Enhanced Internal Electric Field and Strong Resistance to Ionic Interference for Robust Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03031</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, N. Cao, Xiaoming Liu, Fengting He, Yang&#8208;Ming Lu, Shuling Wang, Chaocheng Zhao, Yongqiang Wang, Jinqiang Zhang, Shaobin Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402079090

                Photocatalytic seawater splitting to produce clean hydrogen from nonpotable water using sunlight is a crucial endeavor. However, the scarcity of high-performance photocatalysts in the promising yet fledgling field presents a formidable challenge. Herein, we successfully synthesized a crystalline oxygen-modified carbon nitride (CCNO) polymeric semiconductor that served as an effective photocatalyst for seawater splitting. Comprehensive characterizations and theoretical calculations revealed that nitrogen vacancies and bridging oxygen in the CCNO lattice acted as potent Lewis acid&#8211;base pairs, creating an enhanced built-in electric field. This advancement significantly accelerated charge dynamics and bolstered resistance to ionic interference in seawater. Consequently, CCNO exhibited a robust photocatalytic H2 evolution activity of 29.51 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 in natural seawater, with an impressive apparent quantum efficiency of 66.86% under 420 nm monochromatic light. Seawater splitting for H2 production reached 16.83 mmol g&#8211;1 under natural light irradiation for 3 h (9&#8211;12 o'clock), showcasing its great potential for practical applications. This work presents strategies for developing a metal-free photocatalyst and elucidates its reaction mechanism in the seawater splitting process, laying the foundation for scalable production of clean hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, N. Cao, Xiaoming Liu, Fengting He, Yang&#8208;Ming Lu, Shuling Wang, Chaocheng Zhao, Yongqiang Wang, Jinqiang Zhang, Shaobin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03031</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
