<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 13:18:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Phosphide: An Atypical Catalytic Site</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05160</link>
      <description>Boyang Liu, Xiaocheng Lan, Qin Zhong, Tiefeng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The studies of metal phosphides (MPs) have flourished in the past decades due to their exceptional catalytic performance in thermo-, electro-, and photocatalysis. In this review, we summarize the synthesis methods of MPs and attribute their unique catalytic properties to electronic, geometric, and synergetic modifications. The multifunctionality of phosphorus doping makes phosphide an atypical catalyst. The phosphorus withdraws electrons from metal sites, isolates metal sites, and provides synergetic sites simultaneously, leading to high catalytic activities in various reactions, such as hydroformylation, hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and photocatalytic H2 production. The variety of MPs enables rational design of catalysts based on the requirements of different reactions and expands the application scenarios of MPs. This review summarizes the structure&#8211;performance relationship of MPs, paving the way for future catalyst design and mechanism studies.</description>
      <author>Boyang Liu, Xiaocheng Lan, Qin Zhong, Tiefeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid-Catalyzed Oxy-aminomethylation of Styrenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05342</link>
      <description>Marian Guill&#233;n, Sensheng Liu, Christian D&#237;az-Oviedo, Martin Klu&#223;mann, Benjamin List, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
We report a strong Br&#248;nsted acid-catalyzed three-component oxy-aminomethylation of styrenes with sym-trioxane and sulfonamides or carbamates. This transformation provides a variety of 1,3-oxazinanes in moderate to good yields under mild reaction conditions. The obtained heterocycles can be readily transformed into the corresponding 1,3-amino alcohols, which are useful building blocks for the synthesis of pharmaceutically relevant molecules. Mechanistic studies suggest the intermediacy of an in situ formed 1,3,5-dioxazinane and a subsequent reaction with the olefin.</description>
      <author>Marian Guill&#233;n, Sensheng Liu, Christian D&#237;az-Oviedo, Martin Klu&#223;mann, Benjamin List</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching the Symmetry of a Trinuclear Copper Cluster Catalyst for Electroreducing CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to an Asymmetric C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Product in an Acidic Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03755</link>
      <description>Rui Wang, Long&#8208;Zhang Dong, Jingwen Shi, Mi Zhang, Shun-Li Li, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan, Jiang Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Achieving CO2 electroreduction in an acidic electrolyte to obtain high-value products is a great challenge, but it has remained elusive so far due to the high requirements for catalyst stability. Herein, we designed and constructed a highly stable (acid- and alkali-resistant) and well-defined crystalline coordination compound catalyst, Inz-Cu3, which can switch the structural symmetry by varying the distance and angle between the adjacent synergistic Cu active sites, thus achieving the selective conversion of CO2 to a high-value C2 product in an acidic electrolyte. At a current density of &#8722;320 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2, it achieved up to 42.20% selectivity for the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to C2 products in an acidic electrolyte, and the highly selective catalytic conversion to C2 products (66.79%, containing 35.27% FEC2H4 and 31.52% FEC2H5OH) can also be achieved in a conventional alkaline electrolyte. Moreover, the density functional theory (DFT) calculation and control experiments revealed that the adjacent asymmetric Cu active sites with close distance can stabilize *CHOHCH3 intermediates, thus improving the selectivity of the asymmetric C2 product. This work demonstrates a strategy for the structural design of asymmetric crystalline coordination catalysts and enables the achievement of electroreduction conversion of CO2 to high-value-added C2 products in an acidic electrolyte.</description>
      <author>Rui Wang, Long&#8208;Zhang Dong, Jingwen Shi, Mi Zhang, Shun-Li Li, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan, Jiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerobic Oxidation of Methyl Glycolate by &#945;-Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for the Eco-Friendly Synthesis of Methyl Glyoxylate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05587</link>
      <description>Hao Wang, Tian Lan, Guofeng Zhao, Guoqing Chen, Yong Lu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Methyl glyoxylate (MGO) is an important reagent for value-added chemical and pharmaceutical synthesis, but it urgently requires an eco-friendly synthesis method. Aerobic oxidation of massively obtainable methyl glycolate (MG) is an ideal nonpetrochemical route for MGO production. Herein, &#945;-Fe2O3 with a hydroxyl-deficient surface obtained by a precipitation method is discovered to be an enabling catalyst with a markedly lowered reaction activation energy (88.6 kJ mol&#8211;1), achieving a high specific activity of 0.26 gMGO mcat&#8211;2 h&#8211;1. The MG conversion of 80&#8211;85% and 90&#8211;92% MGO selectivity are obtained at 220 &#176;C and can maintain stability throughout 100 h test. Isotope-labeling experiments and theoretical calculations confirm that this reaction proceeds over &#945;-Fe2O3 following the MvK mechanism. The hydroxyl-deficient surface provides a warranty for such unprecedented catalytic performance, which in nature offers highly reactive lattice oxygen and abundant accessible Fe sites, thereby benefiting MG adsorption/activation, and is conducive to water desorption due to enhanced hydrophobicity.</description>
      <author>Hao Wang, Tian Lan, Guofeng Zhao, Guoqing Chen, Yong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05587</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into Hydrodeoxygenation of Lignin Derivatives over Ni Single Atoms Supported on Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04555</link>
      <description>Haoquan Guo, Jinlin Long, Yu Chen, Xinyu Lu, Yue Yang, Chenrong Ding, Lizhi Wu, Li Tan, Jinlin Long, Guohui Yang, Yu Tang, Noritatsu Tsubaki, Xiaoli Gu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Lignin derivatives are one class of attractive alternative feedstocks for the production of renewable biofuels. Herein, hydrodeoxygenation (HDO) of lignin derivatives was carried out using a single-atom catalyst (SAC) comprised of Ni1 SAC on &#946;-Mo2C. A number of lignin-derived compounds have been investigated, and nearly 100% yield of biofuel molecules was converted from various lignin derivatives through the HDO reaction, demonstrating that Ni1/&#946;-Mo2C has remarkable potential for the production biofuels through catalytic hydrodeoxygenation of lignin derivatives. The reaction mechanism of DHE over single-atom catalyst Ni1/&#946;-Mo2C was confirmed based on comprehensive characterizations of catalysts and DFT calculations. Interestingly, the Ni single-atom active sites alter the reaction pathway by shifting the geometry of the adsorbed intermediate from a vertical to horizontal conformation, which lowered the reaction energy barrier and improved the selectivity to biofuel molecules, resulting in extraordinary catalytic activity. This study suggests an avenue for single-atom catalysis in chemical transformations of lignin derivatives into biofuels.</description>
      <author>Haoquan Guo, Jinlin Long, Yu Chen, Xinyu Lu, Yue Yang, Chenrong Ding, Lizhi Wu, Li Tan, Jinlin Long, Guohui Yang, Yu Tang, Noritatsu Tsubaki, Xiaoli Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Bifunctional Photo/Electrocatalytic Activity of In Situ Grown CdSe QDs on g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheet Z-Scheme Heterostructures for Efficient Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03632</link>
      <description>Amir Mehtab, Tokeer Ahmad, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The successive ionic layer adsorption and reaction (SILAR) method was used to deposit several CdSe quantum dots (QDs) on the surface of g-C3N4 nanosheets. In comparison to the single moiety of g-C3N4, as-prepared heterostructures displayed an improved bifunctional photo- and electrocatalytic activity for oxygen (OER) and hydrogen evolution reactions (HER). Significantly, the 30 SILAR cycles optimized CdSe QDs/g-C3N4 heterostructure exhibited high performances and stabilities for the OER and HER reaction in alkaline conditions. The as-prepared heterostructure catalyst also exhibited an efficient photocatalytic activity toward the H2 evolution reaction and produced 4306 &#956;mol of H2 gas with 23.8% of apparent quantum yield in the presence of triethanolamine as a sacrificial agent. Photoluminescence spectroscopy, electron paramagnetic resonance, and impedance spectroscopy suggest that the synergy between g-C3N4 nanosheets and CdSe QDs leads to higher catalytic activities, as indicated by the low overpotentials of 147 and 218 mV to obtain a 10 mA cm&#8211;2 current density for the HER and OER reactions, respectively. Furthermore, in situ Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy, liquid chromatography&#8211;mass spectroscopy, and high-performance liquid chromatography were conducted to determine the photochemical intermediate products to confirm the successful oxidation of TEOA by capturing holes. The outcome is in accordance with the fact that the photogenerated electrons are transferred from the conduction band (CB) of g-C3N4 nanosheets to the valence band (VB) of CdSe QDs in a Z-scheme manner.</description>
      <author>Amir Mehtab, Tokeer Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factors Affecting the Generation and Catalytic Activity of Extra-Framework Aluminum Lewis Acid Sites in Aluminum-Exchanged Zeolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04195</link>
      <description>Syeda R. Batool, Vitaly L. Sushkevich, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Aluminum ion exchange was employed to introduce Lewis acidity into zeolites BEA, mordenite (MOR), MFI, and FAU (Si/Al = 11&#8211;15) and thereby evaluate what factors affect the generation and activity of extra-framework Lewis acid sites (LAS) in zeolites. After the treatment, all zeolites retain their framework structure and porosity characteristics, as evidenced by diffraction and nitrogen physisorption. The increase in the total aluminum content in BEA and FAU was appreciable, whereas MOR and MFI showed very little uptake of aluminum. The increase in total aluminum content quantitatively follows the increase in total LAS content determined by Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy of adsorbed pyridine after dehydration and increases the concentration of octahedrally coordinated extra-framework aluminum after hydration, determined by 27Al magic-angle spinning (MAS) and multiple-quantum magic-angle spinning (MQMAS) NMR spectroscopy. Likewise, the catalytic activity for Meerwein&#8211;Ponndorf&#8211;Verley reduction of 4-tert-butylcyclohexanone changed accordingly with no significant change in MOR and MFI and significant and maximum increase in BEA and FAU. The selectivity of zeolites toward cis respectively trans 4-tert-butylcyclohexanols was affected by the pore size and framework type of the zeolite and not by the number or structure (extra-framework/framework-associated aluminum) of LAS they contain. While the number of LAS in BEA and FAU significantly increased, their total Br&#248;nsted acid site (BAS) content remained constant, suggesting that the incorporated LAS are neutral moieties. The incorporation of extra-framework LAS by aluminum ion exchange and their catalytic activity depend on the zeolite framework type, pore size, and possibly on the aluminum location within the zeolite framework.</description>
      <author>Syeda R. Batool, Vitaly L. Sushkevich, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Heterocyclic Carbene Moiety in Highly Porous Organic Hollow Nanofibers for Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversions: A Comparative Experimental and Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05576</link>
      <description>Sudip Bhattacharjee, Anjana Tripathi, Rupak Chatterjee, Ranjit Thapa, Tobias M&#252;ller, Asim Bhaumik, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Global warming and climate change are two severe environmental dangers brought on by the steady rise in the carbon dioxide (CO2) concentration in the atmosphere. Thus, in order to reduce this problem, it is essential to find an efficient material for high CO2 capture that can simultaneously exhibit good catalytic activity for CO2 utilization into useful chemicals. Herein, we report the synthesis of N-heterocyclic carbene-based porous organic polymers (NHC-01 and NHC-02) using the Friedel&#8211;Crafts reaction with the imidazolium salt and bi-phenyl. Among the two porous polymers, NHC-01 exhibited outstanding stability, high flexibility, and high BET surface area (1298 m2 g&#8211;1). NHC-01 material displayed a high CO2 uptake capacity of 2.85 mmol g&#8211;1 under 1.0 bar pressure at 273 K. NHC-01/02 has been utilized as a metal-free organocatalyst for the CO2 conversion reaction due to its high surface area, high CO2 absorption capacity, and as it bears the NHC moiety in the organic network. NHC-01 selectively reduced CO2 to methanol via hydrosilylation with complete conversion of silane under atmospheric CO2 pressure. Furthermore, the catalyst also shows good catalytic activity toward N-formylation and reductive cyclization reactions, which showed good yields up to at least four catalytic cycles. The reaction mechanisms are also studied by theoretical simulation using density functional theory (DFT), which shows that intermediates have the appropriate free energy level for the catalyst to promote the reaction with a low energy barrier.</description>
      <author>Sudip Bhattacharjee, Anjana Tripathi, Rupak Chatterjee, Ranjit Thapa, Tobias M&#252;ller, Asim Bhaumik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Insights into a Side Chain Cross-Linking Biarylitide P450 from RiPP Biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05417</link>
      <description>Mathias Henning Hansen, Angus B. Keto, Maxine Treisman, Vishnu Mini Sasi, Laura Coe, Yongwei Zhao, Leo Padva, Caroline He&#223;, Victor Leichthammer, Daniel L. Machell, Ralf B. Schittenhelm, Colin J. Jackson, Julien Tailhades, Max Cr&#252;semann, James J. De Voss, Elizabeth H. Krenske, Max J. Cryle, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Peptide side chain cross-linking is an important feature of many natural products, with an increasing number of examples catalyzed by cytochrome P450s being reported from ribosomal biosynthesis pathways in addition to well-known examples from nonribosomal peptide antibiotics. Despite the dramatic recent increase in the number of enzymes and reactions catalyzed, substrate bound structures of such P450s have proven elusive to date. Here, we report the structural characterization of the biarylitide cross-linking enzyme P450Blt in complex with its pentapeptide substrate MRYLH. This structure, in combination with computational and biochemical experiments, shows the importance of key I-helix residues in this P450 in coordinating to the histidine residue of the substrate and further that this appears to be central to the specificity of this enzyme for generating a C&#8211;N link between the tyrosine and histidine residues in the MRYLH substrate. The structure of the P450Blt-MRYLH complex provides the first insight into how peptide substrates can be accommodated within P450s and offers insights into how other examples of related P450s can accept the varied substrates that have recently been identified using bioinformatic methods.</description>
      <author>Mathias Henning Hansen, Angus B. Keto, Maxine Treisman, Vishnu Mini Sasi, Laura Coe, Yongwei Zhao, Leo Padva, Caroline He&#223;, Victor Leichthammer, Daniel L. Machell, Ralf B. Schittenhelm, Colin J. Jackson, Julien Tailhades, Max Cr&#252;semann, James J. De Voss, Elizabeth H. Krenske, Max J. Cryle</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Modified S&#9552;O Microenvironment Boosts Catalyzed Oxidation of Alcohol &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; Hydrogen Bond Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04779</link>
      <description>Feng Xiao, Song Shi, Guozhi Zhu, Yinwei Wang, Jieqi Cao, Jie Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Enzymes have unique structures, with various amino acid residues encapsulating metal active sites. Their high performance is mainly achieved via weak interactions between the functional groups and the substrate. Inspired by the enzyme structure, we designed an encapsulated catalyst (E-S&#9552;O) wherein AuPd nanoparticles were encapsulated by porous organic frameworks (POFs) modified with S&#9552;O groups. The alcohol reaction rate of E-S&#9552;O increased 2-fold compared with the control catalyst without S&#9552;O groups. The hydrogen bond was formed between alcohol and S&#9552;O groups, which was confirmed via 1H NMR and inverse-phase gas chromatography (IGC) tests. Further insight including adsorption isotherm, in situ diffuse reflective infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS), and the kinetics data confirmed the hydrogen bond could account for the rate enhancement. The proposed catalyst preparation strategy through precise microenvironment control via hydrogen bonds with substrates paves a new way for high-performance catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Feng Xiao, Song Shi, Guozhi Zhu, Yinwei Wang, Jieqi Cao, Jie Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Investigation on C&#8211;C Bond Cleavage of Anthraquinone Catalyzed by an Atypical Nonheme Iron-Dependent Dioxygenase BTG13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04053</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Deng, Hao Su, Xiaodong Hou, Huibin Xu, Zhenbo Yuan, Xiang Sheng, Yijian Rao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
An atypical nonheme iron-dependent dioxygenase BTG13 with a rare iron coordination of four histidine residues and a carboxylated-lysine (Kcx) was recently reported to catalyze the C4a&#8211;C10 bond cleavage of anthraquinone. However, the reaction mechanism of BTG13 remains elusive. Herein, the detailed mechanism of BTG13 is studied using molecular dynamics simulations and density functional theory calculations. The comprehensive mechanistic study shows that the most favorable pathway for the C&#8211;C bond cleavage of anthraquinone involves two unusual steps: (1) a hydrogen atom abstraction (HAA) from an sp3-hybridized carbon of the substrate by FeIII&#8211;O2&#8226;&#8211; and (2) an oxygen rebound to the substrate radical via homolytic O&#8211;O bond cleavage, which activates FeIII&#8211;OOH to form FeIV&#9552;O species. Furthermore, our results reveal that Kcx could increase the electron-donating ability of the ferrous iron, thereby boosting the activation of dioxygen to form FeIII&#8211;O2&#8226;&#8211; species and facilitating the following HAA and O&#8211;O bond cleavage processes. This study advances the current knowledge of reactions catalyzed by iron-dependent oxygenases.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Deng, Hao Su, Xiaodong Hou, Huibin Xu, Zhenbo Yuan, Xiang Sheng, Yijian Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulsing the Applied Potential in Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Enhances the C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activity by Modulating the Dynamic Competitive Binding of *CO and *H</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04224</link>
      <description>Rileigh Casebolt DiDomenico, Kelsey Levine, Colin R. Bundschu, Laila Reimanis, Tom&#225;s Arias, Tobias Hanrath, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
We explore dynamic electrocatalysis by pulsing the applied potential to modulate the temporal microenvironment during the electrochemical reduction of CO2. We focus on copper electrodes by virtue of their unique ability to bind *CO intermediates and enable C&#8211;C coupling to form high-value C2 products, such as ethylene or ethanol. We examine the well-known competition between *CO and *H for active sites, as their relative coverage is crucial for enhancing the formation of C2 products. We found that pulsing the applied potential can significantly enhance the electrocatalytic activity of C&#8211;C coupling, increasing the turnover frequency of C2 products by up to 33-fold compared to potentiostatic electrolysis. We interpret this improvement in the context of oscillating surface coverage and the transient dynamics of the *CO/*H coverage during the cathodic pulse. Through a combination of experimental and computational methods, we investigate how pulse frequency influences the turnover frequency of CO2 to C2 products on Cu. Our study not only validates recent theoretical predictions about the potential of dynamic (electro)catalysis to surpass the limitations imposed by the Sabatier limit but also uncovers scientific and mechanistic insights into dynamic processes within the electrical double layer. These insights are instrumental in formulating design principles for pulsed CO2 electrolysis with enhanced C2 activity. The outcomes of this study lay a foundational framework for future advances in programmable CO2 electrolysis with improved activity, selectivity, and durability.</description>
      <author>Rileigh Casebolt DiDomenico, Kelsey Levine, Colin R. Bundschu, Laila Reimanis, Tom&#225;s Arias, Tobias Hanrath</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of Single-Atom Fe&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; and Ce&#8211;O&lt;sub&gt;v&lt;/sub&gt; Sites on Mesoporous CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Efficient Selective Catalytic Reduction of NO with CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04682</link>
      <description>Y. Bai, Xupeng Zong, Jin Chen, Shu-Dong Wang, Sheng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Nonprecious transition-metal oxides, especially Fe-, Cu-, Co-, and Mn-containing mixed oxides, have been regarded as promising alternatives for noble metal catalysts for the abatement of NOx contamination. However, the identification of the real catalytically active sites for these mixed oxides remains unclear in most cases, which limits our in-depth understanding of the intrinsic mechanism. Here, we comprehensively investigated an iron&#8211;cerium&#8211;aluminum oxide (Fe1/CeO2&#8211;Al2O3) prepared with a co-precipitation method. Structural identification confirmed that Fe sites are atomically dispersed, bonding with four O atoms in the first coordination shell and with two Ce atoms in the second shell on average. Highly efficient removal of NO with 100% selectivity toward N2 has been achieved over these sites at a temperature as low as 250 &#176;C. In situ characterizations and computational studies revealed that the high activity and N2 selectivity of Fe1/CeO2&#8211;Al2O3 can be attributed to the synergetic effect of the single-atomic Fe1 site and surrounding Ce&#8211;Ov, which intensively promotes the adsorption of NO molecules and N2O intermediates. Subsequently, Ce&#8211;Ov facilitates the N&#8211;O dissociation toward N2 and then is regenerated with CO, forming CO2 as a product. The present results provide valuable insights into the mechanism of transition-metal oxide catalysts for the NO&#8211;CO reaction and offer useful guidance for designing catalysts with high activity and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Y. Bai, Xupeng Zong, Jin Chen, Shu-Dong Wang, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate-Specific Evolution of Amine Dehydrogenases for Accessing Structurally Diverse Enantiopure (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;)-&#946;-Amino Alcohols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04995</link>
      <description>Xinjian Yin, Wenzhong Gong, Yuping Zeng, Hulin Qiu, Lan Liu, Frank Hollmann, Bi&#8208;Shuang Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The biocatalytic oxidative deamination of &#946;-amino alcohols holds significant practical potential in kinetic resolution and/or deracemization process to access (R)-&#946;-amino alcohols. This study exemplifies a notable instance of acquisition and utilization of this valuable oxidative deamination activity. Initially, the mutation N261M (M0) was identified to endow a native valine dehydrogenase with oxidative deamination activity toward a few (S)-&#946;-amino alcohols. Subsequently, a phylogenetic analysis-guided, double-code saturation mutagenesis strategy was proposed to engineer M0's side-chain binding site. This strategy facilitated the substrate-specific evolution of M0, resulting in the creation of a panel of mutants (M1&#8211;M4) with noteworthy oxidative deamination activity toward structurally diverse (S)-&#946;-amino alcohols. Using these engineered amine dehydrogenases, termed as &#946;-amino alcohol dehydrogenases (&#946;-AADHs), the complete kinetic resolution and even deracemization of a range of &#946;-amino alcohols have been achieved. This work reports distinct biocatalysts and a synthetic strategy for the synthesis of enantiopure (R)-&#946;-amino alcohols and offers an innovative approach for substrate-specificity engineering of enzymes.</description>
      <author>Xinjian Yin, Wenzhong Gong, Yuping Zeng, Hulin Qiu, Lan Liu, Frank Hollmann, Bi&#8208;Shuang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anode Engineering for Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05162</link>
      <description>Chao Qiu, Zikai Xu, Feng-Yang Chen, Haotian Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Sustainable hydrogen (H2) production via water electrolysis is one of the most critical pathways to decarbonize the chemical industry. Among various electrolyzer technologies, proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolyzer (PEMWE) is widely regarded as having a great advantage and promise for large-scale H2 production given its high efficiency, reliable stability, and high output pressure. Though state-of-the-art iridium-based catalysts exhibit satisfying activity and stability for oxygen evolution reaction at the anode, their high loadings, as well as the precious metal coating and titanium bulk of porous transport layer (PTL) and bipolar plates, significantly add to the capital cost of the PEMWE stack. The respective optimization and integration of PTL, catalyst layer (CL) and PEM is critical for enhancing charge transfer, mass transport, and catalyst utilization to lower the operation and capital cost, yet it has not received adequate attention. In this review, anode engineering strategies to rationally design PTL, PTL/CL interface and PEM/CL interface for performance improvement and cost reduction are summarized. Current understandings on PTL material, structure, and two-phase transport properties are first gathered, followed by the discussion of anode interface engineering methods and catalyst coating techniques. Given the raising attention to large-scale water electrolyzers operating at high current densities, this review provides a practical and comprehensive direction for next-generation PEMWE anode design by addressing the integration of key components related to the cost, efficiency and stability issues in PEMWE.</description>
      <author>Chao Qiu, Zikai Xu, Feng-Yang Chen, Haotian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Potency of a Phenalenyl-Based Photocatalyst under the Photoelectrochemical Condition for Intramolecular C&#8211;S Bond Formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05500</link>
      <description>Parimal C. Sen, N. K. SAHA, Sudipta Raha Roy, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Implementation of an organic molecular photocatalyst for photoelectrochemical (PEC) transformations has been a highly demanding aspect that has not yet been mapped out extensively. Herein, we have unveiled the efficacy of a phenalenyl-based organic photocatalyst toward photoelectrochemical intramolecular C&#8211;S bond construction reactions under mild conditions. This phenalenyl core, which contains a vacant NBMO, acts as an electron reservoir, thereby facilitating the formation of a contact ion pair with electron-rich organic systems through intramolecular electron transfer under photoexcitation and aiding in catalytic regeneration by anodic oxidation in a single pot. Detailed mechanistic investigation by using UV&#8211;visible spectral analysis, cyclic voltammetry experiments, and computational calculations revealed that the prior formation of an EDA complex between the phenalenyl-based photocatalyst and substrate triggers this PEC process. This unified strategy was successfully implemented in six different intramolecular C&#8211;S bond formation reactions to synthesize different heterocycles and make this protocol appealing for the synthesis of C&#8211;S bonds.</description>
      <author>Parimal C. Sen, N. K. SAHA, Sudipta Raha Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First-Principles Approach to Modeling Surface Site Stabilities on Multimetallic Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04337</link>
      <description>Shikha Saini, Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Shyam Deo, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The study of multimetallic alloys and the multitude of possible surface compositions have sparked a tremendous interest in engineering low-cost materials with high activity and selectivity in heterogeneous catalysis. Multimetallic systems provide complementary functionalities and an unprecedented tunability when designing catalyst formulations. However, due to their immense structural and compositional complexity, the investigation and identification of an optimal catalyst is a tedious and time-consuming process, both experimentally and theoretically. Therefore, theoretical design principles are highly desirable to accelerate the screening of catalyst structures across the vast compositional space. In this paper, we introduce a simple and general model for predicting the site stability of multimetallic surfaces and nanoparticles, which is based on physical principles. The model requires only a small set of density functional theory (DFT) calculations of metal atom binding energies on monometallic and dilute alloy surface slabs to optimize the parameters in the simple model. The resulting model allows for the quantification of the stability of any particular atom site in any conceivable chemical environment across a wide range of morphologies, sizes, and arrangements by interpolating the derived parameters from a monometallic system to a completely diluted alloyed system. Herein, we demonstrate the robustness of the model across an extensive data set of transition metal alloy surfaces and 147-atoms cuboctahedral nanoparticles (NPs) composed of IrRhRu and PtPdRu. Our approach yields mean absolute errors of &#8776;0.15 (IrRhRu), 0.20 (PtPdRu), 0.19 (IrRhRu NP), and 0.26 (PtPdRu NP) eV relative to site binding energies calculated using DFT.</description>
      <author>Shikha Saini, Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Shyam Deo, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of the Phase Transformation of Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Enhanced Water Oxidation under a Magnetic Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05032</link>
      <description>Guangjian Song, Wei Mao, Jing Zhou, Liuhua Mu, Sanzhao Song, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Ferromagnetic catalysts in the presence of an external magnetic field can promote the reaction kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by enhancing spin-selective electron transfer as intermediates and products confer spin-dependent behavior. It has been found that &#947;-Fe2O3 with ferromagnetism exhibits an enhanced performance for the OER activity, but its preparation is limited. Herein, we report an adsorption-pyrolysis process in air in which the transformation of &#945;-Fe2O3 into &#947;-Fe2O3 is precisely regulated by controlling the content of Co ions. Interestingly, a small, constant external magnetic field (&#8764;200 mT) was applied at the anode, resulting in a significant impact on the OER performance of the obtained series of catalysts with different contents of &#947;-Fe2O3 under alkaline conditions. Theoretical results reveal that the same spin configuration of Fe and O atoms in &#947;-Fe2O3 provides a spin conduction channel, which enhances the ability to selectively remove spin-oriented electrons from the reactants and accelerates the accumulation of triplet oxygen molecules during the OER process, thereby promoting the OER. These findings provide a strategy toward the controllable phase transformation of Fe2O3 and deep insights for understanding the OER behavior of Fe-based electrocatalysts under magnetic fields.</description>
      <author>Guangjian Song, Wei Mao, Jing Zhou, Liuhua Mu, Sanzhao Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-Unsaturated Aldehydes to Unsaturated Alcohols over Defective MOF-808 with Constructed Frustrated Lewis Pairs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03624</link>
      <description>Linhao Zhong, Xiaoqing Liao, Haishuai Cui, He&#8217;an Luo, Yang Lv, Pingle Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Solid frustrated Lewis pair (FLP) catalysts have received much attention. In this work, MOF-808 with rich defects was constructed using a facile monocarboxylic acid modulator-induced defect strategy and applied in the transfer hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes to unsaturated alcohol using cyclohexanol as the hydrogen source. MOF-808 was prepared from different zirconium precursors, and it was found that MOF-808-ZT obtained from ZrCl4 and H3BTC forms abundant surface hydroxyl groups (Zr&#8211;OH, base sites). Moreover, MOF-808-PA with missing linker defects was constructed by introducing monocarboxylic acid to preoccupy the coordination sites of MOF-808-ZT, leading to abundant Zr&#8211;OH2. The coordinated water molecules are removed by the dehydration of MOF-808-PA at 180 &#176;C, and the underlying coordinatively unsaturated Zr4+ (Zr-CUS) is exposed and acts as a Lewis acid site. Characterizations and DFT calculations show that the Zr-CUS/Zr&#8211;OH FLPs sites can efficiently activate the C&#9552;O of aldehydes and &#8722;OH of cyclohexanol and reduce their activation energy barrier, thus exhibiting good catalytic performance. Moreover, these FLP sites can easily easily dissociate the H&#8211;H bond with a lower activation energy of 0.15 eV, thereby achieving a better catalytic reactivity in the direct hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes to unsaturated alcohols. A possible reaction mechanism was proposed based on in situ DRIFT, vacuum FTIR, and DFT calculations.</description>
      <author>Linhao Zhong, Xiaoqing Liao, Haishuai Cui, He&#8217;an Luo, Yang Lv, Pingle Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03624</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Particle Size Dependent Selectivity Control for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation Using Co/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05139</link>
      <description>Rena Oh, Xiaoyang Huang, James Hayward, Yanping Zheng, Mingshu Chen, Gyeong-Su Park, Graham J. Hutchings, Seong Keun Kim, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The particle size of CeO2 was controlled to study the selectivity toward CO production in CO2 hydrogenation over Co/CeO2 catalysts using ambient-pressure conditions. CeO2 was selected as a typical catalyst support, and it was pretreated by calcination at 450, 750, 900, and 1000 &#176;C, which increases the CeO2 particle size prior to impregnation to prepare a series of 5 wt % Co/CeO2. As a result of catalytic testing, it was found that the CO selectivity can be promoted from 24 &#177; 2% to 49 &#177; 1% when the CeO2 is calcined at 1000 &#176;C. We propose that the CeO2 calcination at high temperatures improved its reducibility, strengthened CO adsorption, and weakened H adsorption over the surface of the impregnated Co nanoparticles. Our proposed explanation toward the increased CO selectivity was supported using in situ techniques, i.e., in situ CO DRIFTS and in situ XPS and TEM characterization. This work provides distinctive insight into the relationship between metal&#8211;support interaction and the controlled product selectivity in CO2 hydrogenation.</description>
      <author>Rena Oh, Xiaoyang Huang, James Hayward, Yanping Zheng, Mingshu Chen, Gyeong-Su Park, Graham J. Hutchings, Seong Keun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activation over Anatase TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Supported Metal Adatoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04201</link>
      <description>Qiang Li, George Yan, Dionisios G. Vlachos, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
H2 activation is fundamental in catalysis. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) can be highly selective hydrogenation catalysts due to their tunable geometric and electronic properties. In this work, H2 activation (adsorption, splitting, and diffusion) on the anatase TiO2-supported SAC has been modeled in detail. The stable configurations of 14 transition metals from 3d to 5d (Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ag, Cd, Os, Ir, Pt, and Au) and Sn have been screened. We compared H and H2 adsorption and H2 heterolytic and homolytic splitting on SA/TiO2. H on the SAC in neutral, hydridic, and proton forms and the preferred H2 dissociation paths are revealed. We found that the metal adatoms strengthen the Br&#248;nsted acids via forming the SA-O bonds and promote the H adsorption on Ti sites via forming the Ti3+ sites. The electronic descriptor using the energy level of the frontier d orbital, referenced to vacuum, can predict the single H and H2 dissociative adsorption energies on the metal site. As the SA-H&#948;- interaction is stronger than Ti-H&#948;-, the activation barriers for heterolytic paths over SA-O sites are lower than over Ti-O sites. H2 adsorption is activated on Au, Ru, Rh, Pd, and Ir in a dihydrogen complex structure with an elongated H-H bond. Homolytic splitting over SA sites is favored thermodynamically and kinetically on Rh, Pd, Os, Ir, and Pt. In contrast, for the remaining SA/TiO2, H-H splitting at the SA-O is kinetically favored compared to the Ti-O sites, but the products are less thermodynamically favored.</description>
      <author>Qiang Li, George Yan, Dionisios G. Vlachos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-Mediated Catalytic Polarization Transfer from &lt;i&gt;para&lt;/i&gt; Hydrogen to 3,5-Dihalogenated Pyridines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05378</link>
      <description>Ben. J. Tickner, Marcus Dennington, Brian A. Collins, Callum A. Gater, Theo Tanner, Adrian C. Whitwood, Peter J. Rayner, D. P. Watts, Simon B. Duckett, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The neutral catalysts [IrCl(H)2(NHC)(substrate)2] or [IrCl(H)2(NHC)(substrate)(sulfoxide)] are used to transfer polarization from para hydrogen (pH2) to 3,5-dichloropyridine and 3,5-dibromopyridine substrates. This is achieved in a rapid, reversible, and low-cost process that relies on ligand exchange within the active catalyst. Notably, the sulfoxide-containing catalyst systems produced NMR signal enhancements between 1 and 2 orders of magnitude larger than its unmodified counterpart. Consequently, this signal amplification by reversible exchange hyperpolarization method can boost the 1H, 13C, and 15N nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) signal intensities by factors up to 4350, 1550, and 46,600, respectively (14.0, 1.3, and 15.4% polarization). In this paper, NMR and X-ray crystallography are used to map the evolution of catalytically important species and provide mechanistic rational for catalytic efficiency. Furthermore, applications in spontaneous radiofrequency amplification by stimulated emission and NMR reaction monitoring are also shown.</description>
      <author>Ben. J. Tickner, Marcus Dennington, Brian A. Collins, Callum A. Gater, Theo Tanner, Adrian C. Whitwood, Peter J. Rayner, D. P. Watts, Simon B. Duckett</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organocatalytic Asymmetric Synthesis of Si-Stereogenic Siloxanols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03932</link>
      <description>J. Dalton, Adolfo S&#225;nchez, Austin T. Kelly, James C. Fettinger, Annaliese K. Franz, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
We report the organocatalytic synthesis of Si-stereogenic compounds via desymmetrization of a prochiral silanediol with a chiral imidazole-containing catalyst. This metal-free silylation method affords high yields with enantioselectivity up to 98:2 for various silanediol and silyl chloride substrate combinations (including secondary alkyl, vinyl, and H groups), accessing products with potential for further elaboration. NMR and X-ray studies reveal insight into the H-bonding interactions between the imidazole organocatalyst and the silanediol and the dual activating role of the Lewis basic imidazole to account for the high enantioselectivity.</description>
      <author>J. Dalton, Adolfo S&#225;nchez, Austin T. Kelly, James C. Fettinger, Annaliese K. Franz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03932</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756349</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(1)] 2024.
ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ISSUEPREVArticleNEXTIssue Editorial MastheadCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 1, XXX-XXXPublication Date (Web):January 5, 2024Publication History Published online5 January 2024Published inissue 5 January 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756349Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyRequest reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InReddit PDF (198 KB) Get e-Alertsclose Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756348</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(1)] 2024.
ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ISSUEPREVArticleIssue Publication InformationCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 1, XXX-XXXPublication Date (Web):January 5, 2024Publication History Published online5 January 2024Published inissue 5 January 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756348Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyRequest reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InReddit PDF (153 KB) Get e-Alertsclose Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Phosphide: An Atypical Catalytic Site</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05160</link>
      <description>Boyang Liu, Xiaocheng Lan, Qin Zhong, Tiefeng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The studies of metal phosphides (MPs) have flourished in the past decades due to their exceptional catalytic performance in thermo-, electro-, and photocatalysis. In this review, we summarize the synthesis methods of MPs and attribute their unique catalytic properties to electronic, geometric, and synergetic modifications. The multifunctionality of phosphorus doping makes phosphide an atypical catalyst. The phosphorus withdraws electrons from metal sites, isolates metal sites, and provides synergetic sites simultaneously, leading to high catalytic activities in various reactions, such as hydroformylation, hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and photocatalytic H2 production. The variety of MPs enables rational design of catalysts based on the requirements of different reactions and expands the application scenarios of MPs. This review summarizes the structure&#8211;performance relationship of MPs, paving the way for future catalyst design and mechanism studies.</description>
      <author>Boyang Liu, Xiaocheng Lan, Qin Zhong, Tiefeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid-Catalyzed Oxy-aminomethylation of Styrenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05342</link>
      <description>Marian Guill&#233;n, Sensheng Liu, Christian D&#237;az-Oviedo, Martin Klu&#223;mann, Benjamin List, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
We report a strong Br&#248;nsted acid-catalyzed three-component oxy-aminomethylation of styrenes with sym-trioxane and sulfonamides or carbamates. This transformation provides a variety of 1,3-oxazinanes in moderate to good yields under mild reaction conditions. The obtained heterocycles can be readily transformed into the corresponding 1,3-amino alcohols, which are useful building blocks for the synthesis of pharmaceutically relevant molecules. Mechanistic studies suggest the intermediacy of an in situ formed 1,3,5-dioxazinane and a subsequent reaction with the olefin.</description>
      <author>Marian Guill&#233;n, Sensheng Liu, Christian D&#237;az-Oviedo, Martin Klu&#223;mann, Benjamin List</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching the Symmetry of a Trinuclear Copper Cluster Catalyst for Electroreducing CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to an Asymmetric C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Product in an Acidic Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03755</link>
      <description>Rui Wang, Long&#8208;Zhang Dong, Jingwen Shi, Mi Zhang, Shun-Li Li, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan, Jiang Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Achieving CO2 electroreduction in an acidic electrolyte to obtain high-value products is a great challenge, but it has remained elusive so far due to the high requirements for catalyst stability. Herein, we designed and constructed a highly stable (acid- and alkali-resistant) and well-defined crystalline coordination compound catalyst, Inz-Cu3, which can switch the structural symmetry by varying the distance and angle between the adjacent synergistic Cu active sites, thus achieving the selective conversion of CO2 to a high-value C2 product in an acidic electrolyte. At a current density of &#8722;320 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2, it achieved up to 42.20% selectivity for the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to C2 products in an acidic electrolyte, and the highly selective catalytic conversion to C2 products (66.79%, containing 35.27% FEC2H4 and 31.52% FEC2H5OH) can also be achieved in a conventional alkaline electrolyte. Moreover, the density functional theory (DFT) calculation and control experiments revealed that the adjacent asymmetric Cu active sites with close distance can stabilize *CHOHCH3 intermediates, thus improving the selectivity of the asymmetric C2 product. This work demonstrates a strategy for the structural design of asymmetric crystalline coordination catalysts and enables the achievement of electroreduction conversion of CO2 to high-value-added C2 products in an acidic electrolyte.</description>
      <author>Rui Wang, Long&#8208;Zhang Dong, Jingwen Shi, Mi Zhang, Shun-Li Li, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan, Jiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerobic Oxidation of Methyl Glycolate by &#945;-Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for the Eco-Friendly Synthesis of Methyl Glyoxylate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05587</link>
      <description>Hao Wang, Tian Lan, Guofeng Zhao, Guoqing Chen, Yong Lu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Methyl glyoxylate (MGO) is an important reagent for value-added chemical and pharmaceutical synthesis, but it urgently requires an eco-friendly synthesis method. Aerobic oxidation of massively obtainable methyl glycolate (MG) is an ideal nonpetrochemical route for MGO production. Herein, &#945;-Fe2O3 with a hydroxyl-deficient surface obtained by a precipitation method is discovered to be an enabling catalyst with a markedly lowered reaction activation energy (88.6 kJ mol&#8211;1), achieving a high specific activity of 0.26 gMGO mcat&#8211;2 h&#8211;1. The MG conversion of 80&#8211;85% and 90&#8211;92% MGO selectivity are obtained at 220 &#176;C and can maintain stability throughout 100 h test. Isotope-labeling experiments and theoretical calculations confirm that this reaction proceeds over &#945;-Fe2O3 following the MvK mechanism. The hydroxyl-deficient surface provides a warranty for such unprecedented catalytic performance, which in nature offers highly reactive lattice oxygen and abundant accessible Fe sites, thereby benefiting MG adsorption/activation, and is conducive to water desorption due to enhanced hydrophobicity.</description>
      <author>Hao Wang, Tian Lan, Guofeng Zhao, Guoqing Chen, Yong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05587</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into Hydrodeoxygenation of Lignin Derivatives over Ni Single Atoms Supported on Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04555</link>
      <description>Haoquan Guo, Jinlin Long, Yu Chen, Xinyu Lu, Yue Yang, Chenrong Ding, Lizhi Wu, Li Tan, Jinlin Long, Guohui Yang, Yu Tang, Noritatsu Tsubaki, Xiaoli Gu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Lignin derivatives are one class of attractive alternative feedstocks for the production of renewable biofuels. Herein, hydrodeoxygenation (HDO) of lignin derivatives was carried out using a single-atom catalyst (SAC) comprised of Ni1 SAC on &#946;-Mo2C. A number of lignin-derived compounds have been investigated, and nearly 100% yield of biofuel molecules was converted from various lignin derivatives through the HDO reaction, demonstrating that Ni1/&#946;-Mo2C has remarkable potential for the production biofuels through catalytic hydrodeoxygenation of lignin derivatives. The reaction mechanism of DHE over single-atom catalyst Ni1/&#946;-Mo2C was confirmed based on comprehensive characterizations of catalysts and DFT calculations. Interestingly, the Ni single-atom active sites alter the reaction pathway by shifting the geometry of the adsorbed intermediate from a vertical to horizontal conformation, which lowered the reaction energy barrier and improved the selectivity to biofuel molecules, resulting in extraordinary catalytic activity. This study suggests an avenue for single-atom catalysis in chemical transformations of lignin derivatives into biofuels.</description>
      <author>Haoquan Guo, Jinlin Long, Yu Chen, Xinyu Lu, Yue Yang, Chenrong Ding, Lizhi Wu, Li Tan, Jinlin Long, Guohui Yang, Yu Tang, Noritatsu Tsubaki, Xiaoli Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Bifunctional Photo/Electrocatalytic Activity of In Situ Grown CdSe QDs on g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheet Z-Scheme Heterostructures for Efficient Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03632</link>
      <description>Amir Mehtab, Tokeer Ahmad, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The successive ionic layer adsorption and reaction (SILAR) method was used to deposit several CdSe quantum dots (QDs) on the surface of g-C3N4 nanosheets. In comparison to the single moiety of g-C3N4, as-prepared heterostructures displayed an improved bifunctional photo- and electrocatalytic activity for oxygen (OER) and hydrogen evolution reactions (HER). Significantly, the 30 SILAR cycles optimized CdSe QDs/g-C3N4 heterostructure exhibited high performances and stabilities for the OER and HER reaction in alkaline conditions. The as-prepared heterostructure catalyst also exhibited an efficient photocatalytic activity toward the H2 evolution reaction and produced 4306 &#956;mol of H2 gas with 23.8% of apparent quantum yield in the presence of triethanolamine as a sacrificial agent. Photoluminescence spectroscopy, electron paramagnetic resonance, and impedance spectroscopy suggest that the synergy between g-C3N4 nanosheets and CdSe QDs leads to higher catalytic activities, as indicated by the low overpotentials of 147 and 218 mV to obtain a 10 mA cm&#8211;2 current density for the HER and OER reactions, respectively. Furthermore, in situ Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy, liquid chromatography&#8211;mass spectroscopy, and high-performance liquid chromatography were conducted to determine the photochemical intermediate products to confirm the successful oxidation of TEOA by capturing holes. The outcome is in accordance with the fact that the photogenerated electrons are transferred from the conduction band (CB) of g-C3N4 nanosheets to the valence band (VB) of CdSe QDs in a Z-scheme manner.</description>
      <author>Amir Mehtab, Tokeer Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factors Affecting the Generation and Catalytic Activity of Extra-Framework Aluminum Lewis Acid Sites in Aluminum-Exchanged Zeolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04195</link>
      <description>Syeda R. Batool, Vitaly L. Sushkevich, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Aluminum ion exchange was employed to introduce Lewis acidity into zeolites BEA, mordenite (MOR), MFI, and FAU (Si/Al = 11&#8211;15) and thereby evaluate what factors affect the generation and activity of extra-framework Lewis acid sites (LAS) in zeolites. After the treatment, all zeolites retain their framework structure and porosity characteristics, as evidenced by diffraction and nitrogen physisorption. The increase in the total aluminum content in BEA and FAU was appreciable, whereas MOR and MFI showed very little uptake of aluminum. The increase in total aluminum content quantitatively follows the increase in total LAS content determined by Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy of adsorbed pyridine after dehydration and increases the concentration of octahedrally coordinated extra-framework aluminum after hydration, determined by 27Al magic-angle spinning (MAS) and multiple-quantum magic-angle spinning (MQMAS) NMR spectroscopy. Likewise, the catalytic activity for Meerwein&#8211;Ponndorf&#8211;Verley reduction of 4-tert-butylcyclohexanone changed accordingly with no significant change in MOR and MFI and significant and maximum increase in BEA and FAU. The selectivity of zeolites toward cis respectively trans 4-tert-butylcyclohexanols was affected by the pore size and framework type of the zeolite and not by the number or structure (extra-framework/framework-associated aluminum) of LAS they contain. While the number of LAS in BEA and FAU significantly increased, their total Br&#248;nsted acid site (BAS) content remained constant, suggesting that the incorporated LAS are neutral moieties. The incorporation of extra-framework LAS by aluminum ion exchange and their catalytic activity depend on the zeolite framework type, pore size, and possibly on the aluminum location within the zeolite framework.</description>
      <author>Syeda R. Batool, Vitaly L. Sushkevich, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Heterocyclic Carbene Moiety in Highly Porous Organic Hollow Nanofibers for Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversions: A Comparative Experimental and Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05576</link>
      <description>Sudip Bhattacharjee, Anjana Tripathi, Rupak Chatterjee, Ranjit Thapa, Tobias M&#252;ller, Asim Bhaumik, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Global warming and climate change are two severe environmental dangers brought on by the steady rise in the carbon dioxide (CO2) concentration in the atmosphere. Thus, in order to reduce this problem, it is essential to find an efficient material for high CO2 capture that can simultaneously exhibit good catalytic activity for CO2 utilization into useful chemicals. Herein, we report the synthesis of N-heterocyclic carbene-based porous organic polymers (NHC-01 and NHC-02) using the Friedel&#8211;Crafts reaction with the imidazolium salt and bi-phenyl. Among the two porous polymers, NHC-01 exhibited outstanding stability, high flexibility, and high BET surface area (1298 m2 g&#8211;1). NHC-01 material displayed a high CO2 uptake capacity of 2.85 mmol g&#8211;1 under 1.0 bar pressure at 273 K. NHC-01/02 has been utilized as a metal-free organocatalyst for the CO2 conversion reaction due to its high surface area, high CO2 absorption capacity, and as it bears the NHC moiety in the organic network. NHC-01 selectively reduced CO2 to methanol via hydrosilylation with complete conversion of silane under atmospheric CO2 pressure. Furthermore, the catalyst also shows good catalytic activity toward N-formylation and reductive cyclization reactions, which showed good yields up to at least four catalytic cycles. The reaction mechanisms are also studied by theoretical simulation using density functional theory (DFT), which shows that intermediates have the appropriate free energy level for the catalyst to promote the reaction with a low energy barrier.</description>
      <author>Sudip Bhattacharjee, Anjana Tripathi, Rupak Chatterjee, Ranjit Thapa, Tobias M&#252;ller, Asim Bhaumik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Insights into a Side Chain Cross-Linking Biarylitide P450 from RiPP Biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05417</link>
      <description>Mathias Henning Hansen, Angus B. Keto, Maxine Treisman, Vishnu Mini Sasi, Laura Coe, Yongwei Zhao, Leo Padva, Caroline He&#223;, Victor Leichthammer, Daniel L. Machell, Ralf B. Schittenhelm, Colin J. Jackson, Julien Tailhades, Max Cr&#252;semann, James J. De Voss, Elizabeth H. Krenske, Max J. Cryle, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Peptide side chain cross-linking is an important feature of many natural products, with an increasing number of examples catalyzed by cytochrome P450s being reported from ribosomal biosynthesis pathways in addition to well-known examples from nonribosomal peptide antibiotics. Despite the dramatic recent increase in the number of enzymes and reactions catalyzed, substrate bound structures of such P450s have proven elusive to date. Here, we report the structural characterization of the biarylitide cross-linking enzyme P450Blt in complex with its pentapeptide substrate MRYLH. This structure, in combination with computational and biochemical experiments, shows the importance of key I-helix residues in this P450 in coordinating to the histidine residue of the substrate and further that this appears to be central to the specificity of this enzyme for generating a C&#8211;N link between the tyrosine and histidine residues in the MRYLH substrate. The structure of the P450Blt-MRYLH complex provides the first insight into how peptide substrates can be accommodated within P450s and offers insights into how other examples of related P450s can accept the varied substrates that have recently been identified using bioinformatic methods.</description>
      <author>Mathias Henning Hansen, Angus B. Keto, Maxine Treisman, Vishnu Mini Sasi, Laura Coe, Yongwei Zhao, Leo Padva, Caroline He&#223;, Victor Leichthammer, Daniel L. Machell, Ralf B. Schittenhelm, Colin J. Jackson, Julien Tailhades, Max Cr&#252;semann, James J. De Voss, Elizabeth H. Krenske, Max J. Cryle</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Modified S&#9552;O Microenvironment Boosts Catalyzed Oxidation of Alcohol &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; Hydrogen Bond Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04779</link>
      <description>Feng Xiao, Song Shi, Guozhi Zhu, Yinwei Wang, Jieqi Cao, Jie Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Enzymes have unique structures, with various amino acid residues encapsulating metal active sites. Their high performance is mainly achieved via weak interactions between the functional groups and the substrate. Inspired by the enzyme structure, we designed an encapsulated catalyst (E-S&#9552;O) wherein AuPd nanoparticles were encapsulated by porous organic frameworks (POFs) modified with S&#9552;O groups. The alcohol reaction rate of E-S&#9552;O increased 2-fold compared with the control catalyst without S&#9552;O groups. The hydrogen bond was formed between alcohol and S&#9552;O groups, which was confirmed via 1H NMR and inverse-phase gas chromatography (IGC) tests. Further insight including adsorption isotherm, in situ diffuse reflective infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS), and the kinetics data confirmed the hydrogen bond could account for the rate enhancement. The proposed catalyst preparation strategy through precise microenvironment control via hydrogen bonds with substrates paves a new way for high-performance catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Feng Xiao, Song Shi, Guozhi Zhu, Yinwei Wang, Jieqi Cao, Jie Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Investigation on C&#8211;C Bond Cleavage of Anthraquinone Catalyzed by an Atypical Nonheme Iron-Dependent Dioxygenase BTG13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04053</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Deng, Hao Su, Xiaodong Hou, Huibin Xu, Zhenbo Yuan, Xiang Sheng, Yijian Rao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
An atypical nonheme iron-dependent dioxygenase BTG13 with a rare iron coordination of four histidine residues and a carboxylated-lysine (Kcx) was recently reported to catalyze the C4a&#8211;C10 bond cleavage of anthraquinone. However, the reaction mechanism of BTG13 remains elusive. Herein, the detailed mechanism of BTG13 is studied using molecular dynamics simulations and density functional theory calculations. The comprehensive mechanistic study shows that the most favorable pathway for the C&#8211;C bond cleavage of anthraquinone involves two unusual steps: (1) a hydrogen atom abstraction (HAA) from an sp3-hybridized carbon of the substrate by FeIII&#8211;O2&#8226;&#8211; and (2) an oxygen rebound to the substrate radical via homolytic O&#8211;O bond cleavage, which activates FeIII&#8211;OOH to form FeIV&#9552;O species. Furthermore, our results reveal that Kcx could increase the electron-donating ability of the ferrous iron, thereby boosting the activation of dioxygen to form FeIII&#8211;O2&#8226;&#8211; species and facilitating the following HAA and O&#8211;O bond cleavage processes. This study advances the current knowledge of reactions catalyzed by iron-dependent oxygenases.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Deng, Hao Su, Xiaodong Hou, Huibin Xu, Zhenbo Yuan, Xiang Sheng, Yijian Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulsing the Applied Potential in Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Enhances the C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activity by Modulating the Dynamic Competitive Binding of *CO and *H</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04224</link>
      <description>Rileigh Casebolt DiDomenico, Kelsey Levine, Colin R. Bundschu, Laila Reimanis, Tom&#225;s Arias, Tobias Hanrath, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
We explore dynamic electrocatalysis by pulsing the applied potential to modulate the temporal microenvironment during the electrochemical reduction of CO2. We focus on copper electrodes by virtue of their unique ability to bind *CO intermediates and enable C&#8211;C coupling to form high-value C2 products, such as ethylene or ethanol. We examine the well-known competition between *CO and *H for active sites, as their relative coverage is crucial for enhancing the formation of C2 products. We found that pulsing the applied potential can significantly enhance the electrocatalytic activity of C&#8211;C coupling, increasing the turnover frequency of C2 products by up to 33-fold compared to potentiostatic electrolysis. We interpret this improvement in the context of oscillating surface coverage and the transient dynamics of the *CO/*H coverage during the cathodic pulse. Through a combination of experimental and computational methods, we investigate how pulse frequency influences the turnover frequency of CO2 to C2 products on Cu. Our study not only validates recent theoretical predictions about the potential of dynamic (electro)catalysis to surpass the limitations imposed by the Sabatier limit but also uncovers scientific and mechanistic insights into dynamic processes within the electrical double layer. These insights are instrumental in formulating design principles for pulsed CO2 electrolysis with enhanced C2 activity. The outcomes of this study lay a foundational framework for future advances in programmable CO2 electrolysis with improved activity, selectivity, and durability.</description>
      <author>Rileigh Casebolt DiDomenico, Kelsey Levine, Colin R. Bundschu, Laila Reimanis, Tom&#225;s Arias, Tobias Hanrath</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of Single-Atom Fe&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; and Ce&#8211;O&lt;sub&gt;v&lt;/sub&gt; Sites on Mesoporous CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Efficient Selective Catalytic Reduction of NO with CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04682</link>
      <description>Y. Bai, Xupeng Zong, Jin Chen, Shu-Dong Wang, Sheng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Nonprecious transition-metal oxides, especially Fe-, Cu-, Co-, and Mn-containing mixed oxides, have been regarded as promising alternatives for noble metal catalysts for the abatement of NOx contamination. However, the identification of the real catalytically active sites for these mixed oxides remains unclear in most cases, which limits our in-depth understanding of the intrinsic mechanism. Here, we comprehensively investigated an iron&#8211;cerium&#8211;aluminum oxide (Fe1/CeO2&#8211;Al2O3) prepared with a co-precipitation method. Structural identification confirmed that Fe sites are atomically dispersed, bonding with four O atoms in the first coordination shell and with two Ce atoms in the second shell on average. Highly efficient removal of NO with 100% selectivity toward N2 has been achieved over these sites at a temperature as low as 250 &#176;C. In situ characterizations and computational studies revealed that the high activity and N2 selectivity of Fe1/CeO2&#8211;Al2O3 can be attributed to the synergetic effect of the single-atomic Fe1 site and surrounding Ce&#8211;Ov, which intensively promotes the adsorption of NO molecules and N2O intermediates. Subsequently, Ce&#8211;Ov facilitates the N&#8211;O dissociation toward N2 and then is regenerated with CO, forming CO2 as a product. The present results provide valuable insights into the mechanism of transition-metal oxide catalysts for the NO&#8211;CO reaction and offer useful guidance for designing catalysts with high activity and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Y. Bai, Xupeng Zong, Jin Chen, Shu-Dong Wang, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate-Specific Evolution of Amine Dehydrogenases for Accessing Structurally Diverse Enantiopure (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;)-&#946;-Amino Alcohols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04995</link>
      <description>Xinjian Yin, Wenzhong Gong, Yuping Zeng, Hulin Qiu, Lan Liu, Frank Hollmann, Bi&#8208;Shuang Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The biocatalytic oxidative deamination of &#946;-amino alcohols holds significant practical potential in kinetic resolution and/or deracemization process to access (R)-&#946;-amino alcohols. This study exemplifies a notable instance of acquisition and utilization of this valuable oxidative deamination activity. Initially, the mutation N261M (M0) was identified to endow a native valine dehydrogenase with oxidative deamination activity toward a few (S)-&#946;-amino alcohols. Subsequently, a phylogenetic analysis-guided, double-code saturation mutagenesis strategy was proposed to engineer M0's side-chain binding site. This strategy facilitated the substrate-specific evolution of M0, resulting in the creation of a panel of mutants (M1&#8211;M4) with noteworthy oxidative deamination activity toward structurally diverse (S)-&#946;-amino alcohols. Using these engineered amine dehydrogenases, termed as &#946;-amino alcohol dehydrogenases (&#946;-AADHs), the complete kinetic resolution and even deracemization of a range of &#946;-amino alcohols have been achieved. This work reports distinct biocatalysts and a synthetic strategy for the synthesis of enantiopure (R)-&#946;-amino alcohols and offers an innovative approach for substrate-specificity engineering of enzymes.</description>
      <author>Xinjian Yin, Wenzhong Gong, Yuping Zeng, Hulin Qiu, Lan Liu, Frank Hollmann, Bi&#8208;Shuang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anode Engineering for Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05162</link>
      <description>Chao Qiu, Zikai Xu, Feng-Yang Chen, Haotian Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Sustainable hydrogen (H2) production via water electrolysis is one of the most critical pathways to decarbonize the chemical industry. Among various electrolyzer technologies, proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolyzer (PEMWE) is widely regarded as having a great advantage and promise for large-scale H2 production given its high efficiency, reliable stability, and high output pressure. Though state-of-the-art iridium-based catalysts exhibit satisfying activity and stability for oxygen evolution reaction at the anode, their high loadings, as well as the precious metal coating and titanium bulk of porous transport layer (PTL) and bipolar plates, significantly add to the capital cost of the PEMWE stack. The respective optimization and integration of PTL, catalyst layer (CL) and PEM is critical for enhancing charge transfer, mass transport, and catalyst utilization to lower the operation and capital cost, yet it has not received adequate attention. In this review, anode engineering strategies to rationally design PTL, PTL/CL interface and PEM/CL interface for performance improvement and cost reduction are summarized. Current understandings on PTL material, structure, and two-phase transport properties are first gathered, followed by the discussion of anode interface engineering methods and catalyst coating techniques. Given the raising attention to large-scale water electrolyzers operating at high current densities, this review provides a practical and comprehensive direction for next-generation PEMWE anode design by addressing the integration of key components related to the cost, efficiency and stability issues in PEMWE.</description>
      <author>Chao Qiu, Zikai Xu, Feng-Yang Chen, Haotian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Potency of a Phenalenyl-Based Photocatalyst under the Photoelectrochemical Condition for Intramolecular C&#8211;S Bond Formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05500</link>
      <description>Parimal C. Sen, N. K. SAHA, Sudipta Raha Roy, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Implementation of an organic molecular photocatalyst for photoelectrochemical (PEC) transformations has been a highly demanding aspect that has not yet been mapped out extensively. Herein, we have unveiled the efficacy of a phenalenyl-based organic photocatalyst toward photoelectrochemical intramolecular C&#8211;S bond construction reactions under mild conditions. This phenalenyl core, which contains a vacant NBMO, acts as an electron reservoir, thereby facilitating the formation of a contact ion pair with electron-rich organic systems through intramolecular electron transfer under photoexcitation and aiding in catalytic regeneration by anodic oxidation in a single pot. Detailed mechanistic investigation by using UV&#8211;visible spectral analysis, cyclic voltammetry experiments, and computational calculations revealed that the prior formation of an EDA complex between the phenalenyl-based photocatalyst and substrate triggers this PEC process. This unified strategy was successfully implemented in six different intramolecular C&#8211;S bond formation reactions to synthesize different heterocycles and make this protocol appealing for the synthesis of C&#8211;S bonds.</description>
      <author>Parimal C. Sen, N. K. SAHA, Sudipta Raha Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First-Principles Approach to Modeling Surface Site Stabilities on Multimetallic Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04337</link>
      <description>Shikha Saini, Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Shyam Deo, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The study of multimetallic alloys and the multitude of possible surface compositions have sparked a tremendous interest in engineering low-cost materials with high activity and selectivity in heterogeneous catalysis. Multimetallic systems provide complementary functionalities and an unprecedented tunability when designing catalyst formulations. However, due to their immense structural and compositional complexity, the investigation and identification of an optimal catalyst is a tedious and time-consuming process, both experimentally and theoretically. Therefore, theoretical design principles are highly desirable to accelerate the screening of catalyst structures across the vast compositional space. In this paper, we introduce a simple and general model for predicting the site stability of multimetallic surfaces and nanoparticles, which is based on physical principles. The model requires only a small set of density functional theory (DFT) calculations of metal atom binding energies on monometallic and dilute alloy surface slabs to optimize the parameters in the simple model. The resulting model allows for the quantification of the stability of any particular atom site in any conceivable chemical environment across a wide range of morphologies, sizes, and arrangements by interpolating the derived parameters from a monometallic system to a completely diluted alloyed system. Herein, we demonstrate the robustness of the model across an extensive data set of transition metal alloy surfaces and 147-atoms cuboctahedral nanoparticles (NPs) composed of IrRhRu and PtPdRu. Our approach yields mean absolute errors of &#8776;0.15 (IrRhRu), 0.20 (PtPdRu), 0.19 (IrRhRu NP), and 0.26 (PtPdRu NP) eV relative to site binding energies calculated using DFT.</description>
      <author>Shikha Saini, Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Shyam Deo, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of the Phase Transformation of Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Enhanced Water Oxidation under a Magnetic Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05032</link>
      <description>Guangjian Song, Wei Mao, Jing Zhou, Liuhua Mu, Sanzhao Song, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Ferromagnetic catalysts in the presence of an external magnetic field can promote the reaction kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by enhancing spin-selective electron transfer as intermediates and products confer spin-dependent behavior. It has been found that &#947;-Fe2O3 with ferromagnetism exhibits an enhanced performance for the OER activity, but its preparation is limited. Herein, we report an adsorption-pyrolysis process in air in which the transformation of &#945;-Fe2O3 into &#947;-Fe2O3 is precisely regulated by controlling the content of Co ions. Interestingly, a small, constant external magnetic field (&#8764;200 mT) was applied at the anode, resulting in a significant impact on the OER performance of the obtained series of catalysts with different contents of &#947;-Fe2O3 under alkaline conditions. Theoretical results reveal that the same spin configuration of Fe and O atoms in &#947;-Fe2O3 provides a spin conduction channel, which enhances the ability to selectively remove spin-oriented electrons from the reactants and accelerates the accumulation of triplet oxygen molecules during the OER process, thereby promoting the OER. These findings provide a strategy toward the controllable phase transformation of Fe2O3 and deep insights for understanding the OER behavior of Fe-based electrocatalysts under magnetic fields.</description>
      <author>Guangjian Song, Wei Mao, Jing Zhou, Liuhua Mu, Sanzhao Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-Unsaturated Aldehydes to Unsaturated Alcohols over Defective MOF-808 with Constructed Frustrated Lewis Pairs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03624</link>
      <description>Linhao Zhong, Xiaoqing Liao, Haishuai Cui, He&#8217;an Luo, Yang Lv, Pingle Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
Solid frustrated Lewis pair (FLP) catalysts have received much attention. In this work, MOF-808 with rich defects was constructed using a facile monocarboxylic acid modulator-induced defect strategy and applied in the transfer hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes to unsaturated alcohol using cyclohexanol as the hydrogen source. MOF-808 was prepared from different zirconium precursors, and it was found that MOF-808-ZT obtained from ZrCl4 and H3BTC forms abundant surface hydroxyl groups (Zr&#8211;OH, base sites). Moreover, MOF-808-PA with missing linker defects was constructed by introducing monocarboxylic acid to preoccupy the coordination sites of MOF-808-ZT, leading to abundant Zr&#8211;OH2. The coordinated water molecules are removed by the dehydration of MOF-808-PA at 180 &#176;C, and the underlying coordinatively unsaturated Zr4+ (Zr-CUS) is exposed and acts as a Lewis acid site. Characterizations and DFT calculations show that the Zr-CUS/Zr&#8211;OH FLPs sites can efficiently activate the C&#9552;O of aldehydes and &#8722;OH of cyclohexanol and reduce their activation energy barrier, thus exhibiting good catalytic performance. Moreover, these FLP sites can easily easily dissociate the H&#8211;H bond with a lower activation energy of 0.15 eV, thereby achieving a better catalytic reactivity in the direct hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes to unsaturated alcohols. A possible reaction mechanism was proposed based on in situ DRIFT, vacuum FTIR, and DFT calculations.</description>
      <author>Linhao Zhong, Xiaoqing Liao, Haishuai Cui, He&#8217;an Luo, Yang Lv, Pingle Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03624</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Particle Size Dependent Selectivity Control for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation Using Co/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05139</link>
      <description>Rena Oh, Xiaoyang Huang, James Hayward, Yanping Zheng, Mingshu Chen, Gyeong-Su Park, Graham J. Hutchings, Seong Keun Kim, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The particle size of CeO2 was controlled to study the selectivity toward CO production in CO2 hydrogenation over Co/CeO2 catalysts using ambient-pressure conditions. CeO2 was selected as a typical catalyst support, and it was pretreated by calcination at 450, 750, 900, and 1000 &#176;C, which increases the CeO2 particle size prior to impregnation to prepare a series of 5 wt % Co/CeO2. As a result of catalytic testing, it was found that the CO selectivity can be promoted from 24 &#177; 2% to 49 &#177; 1% when the CeO2 is calcined at 1000 &#176;C. We propose that the CeO2 calcination at high temperatures improved its reducibility, strengthened CO adsorption, and weakened H adsorption over the surface of the impregnated Co nanoparticles. Our proposed explanation toward the increased CO selectivity was supported using in situ techniques, i.e., in situ CO DRIFTS and in situ XPS and TEM characterization. This work provides distinctive insight into the relationship between metal&#8211;support interaction and the controlled product selectivity in CO2 hydrogenation.</description>
      <author>Rena Oh, Xiaoyang Huang, James Hayward, Yanping Zheng, Mingshu Chen, Gyeong-Su Park, Graham J. Hutchings, Seong Keun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activation over Anatase TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Supported Metal Adatoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04201</link>
      <description>Qiang Li, George Yan, Dionisios G. Vlachos, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
H2 activation is fundamental in catalysis. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) can be highly selective hydrogenation catalysts due to their tunable geometric and electronic properties. In this work, H2 activation (adsorption, splitting, and diffusion) on the anatase TiO2-supported SAC has been modeled in detail. The stable configurations of 14 transition metals from 3d to 5d (Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ag, Cd, Os, Ir, Pt, and Au) and Sn have been screened. We compared H and H2 adsorption and H2 heterolytic and homolytic splitting on SA/TiO2. H on the SAC in neutral, hydridic, and proton forms and the preferred H2 dissociation paths are revealed. We found that the metal adatoms strengthen the Br&#248;nsted acids via forming the SA-O bonds and promote the H adsorption on Ti sites via forming the Ti3+ sites. The electronic descriptor using the energy level of the frontier d orbital, referenced to vacuum, can predict the single H and H2 dissociative adsorption energies on the metal site. As the SA-H&#948;- interaction is stronger than Ti-H&#948;-, the activation barriers for heterolytic paths over SA-O sites are lower than over Ti-O sites. H2 adsorption is activated on Au, Ru, Rh, Pd, and Ir in a dihydrogen complex structure with an elongated H-H bond. Homolytic splitting over SA sites is favored thermodynamically and kinetically on Rh, Pd, Os, Ir, and Pt. In contrast, for the remaining SA/TiO2, H-H splitting at the SA-O is kinetically favored compared to the Ti-O sites, but the products are less thermodynamically favored.</description>
      <author>Qiang Li, George Yan, Dionisios G. Vlachos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-Mediated Catalytic Polarization Transfer from &lt;i&gt;para&lt;/i&gt; Hydrogen to 3,5-Dihalogenated Pyridines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05378</link>
      <description>Ben. J. Tickner, Marcus Dennington, Brian A. Collins, Callum A. Gater, Theo Tanner, Adrian C. Whitwood, Peter J. Rayner, D. P. Watts, Simon B. Duckett, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
The neutral catalysts [IrCl(H)2(NHC)(substrate)2] or [IrCl(H)2(NHC)(substrate)(sulfoxide)] are used to transfer polarization from para hydrogen (pH2) to 3,5-dichloropyridine and 3,5-dibromopyridine substrates. This is achieved in a rapid, reversible, and low-cost process that relies on ligand exchange within the active catalyst. Notably, the sulfoxide-containing catalyst systems produced NMR signal enhancements between 1 and 2 orders of magnitude larger than its unmodified counterpart. Consequently, this signal amplification by reversible exchange hyperpolarization method can boost the 1H, 13C, and 15N nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) signal intensities by factors up to 4350, 1550, and 46,600, respectively (14.0, 1.3, and 15.4% polarization). In this paper, NMR and X-ray crystallography are used to map the evolution of catalytically important species and provide mechanistic rational for catalytic efficiency. Furthermore, applications in spontaneous radiofrequency amplification by stimulated emission and NMR reaction monitoring are also shown.</description>
      <author>Ben. J. Tickner, Marcus Dennington, Brian A. Collins, Callum A. Gater, Theo Tanner, Adrian C. Whitwood, Peter J. Rayner, D. P. Watts, Simon B. Duckett</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organocatalytic Asymmetric Synthesis of Si-Stereogenic Siloxanols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03932</link>
      <description>J. Dalton, Adolfo S&#225;nchez, Austin T. Kelly, James C. Fettinger, Annaliese K. Franz, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024.
We report the organocatalytic synthesis of Si-stereogenic compounds via desymmetrization of a prochiral silanediol with a chiral imidazole-containing catalyst. This metal-free silylation method affords high yields with enantioselectivity up to 98:2 for various silanediol and silyl chloride substrate combinations (including secondary alkyl, vinyl, and H groups), accessing products with potential for further elaboration. NMR and X-ray studies reveal insight into the H-bonding interactions between the imidazole organocatalyst and the silanediol and the dual activating role of the Lewis basic imidazole to account for the high enantioselectivity.</description>
      <author>J. Dalton, Adolfo S&#225;nchez, Austin T. Kelly, James C. Fettinger, Annaliese K. Franz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03932</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756349</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(1)] 2024.
ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ISSUEPREVArticleNEXTIssue Editorial MastheadCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 1, XXX-XXXPublication Date (Web):January 5, 2024Publication History Published online5 January 2024Published inissue 5 January 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756349Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyRequest reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InReddit PDF (198 KB) Get e-Alertsclose Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756348</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(1)] 2024.
ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ISSUEPREVArticleIssue Publication InformationCite this: ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 1, XXX-XXXPublication Date (Web):January 5, 2024Publication History Published online5 January 2024Published inissue 5 January 2024https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756348Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyRequest reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InReddit PDF (153 KB) Get e-Alertsclose Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i001_1756348</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
