<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:46:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Keep the Ligands: Potential Benefits for Fuel Cell Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06298</link>
      <description>Andr&#233;s Molina Villarino, Jonathan L. Rowell, Dasol Yoon, Li Xiao, Yunyi Jia, Zixiao Shi, Joesene Soto, Julia Koldobskiy, David A. Muller, Richard D. Robinson, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393220540

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andr&#233;s Molina Villarino, Jonathan L. Rowell, Dasol Yoon, Li Xiao, Yunyi Jia, Zixiao Shi, Joesene Soto, Julia Koldobskiy, David A. Muller, Richard D. Robinson, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polystyrene Hydrogenolysis to High-Quality Lubricants Using Ni/SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05900</link>
      <description>Brandon C. Vance, Sean Najmi, Dionisios G. Vlachos, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393232044

                Pyrolytic and light-activated oxidation processes are leading technologies for utilizing polystyrene (PS) wastes. These approaches exhibit poor selectivities, use complex reactors, and require solvents. Hydrogenolysis is effective for deconstructing polyolefins, but its application to PS feedstocks has been limited. Herein, we demonstrate Ni/SiO2 catalysts to facilitate PS (Mw &#8776; 97 kDa) hydrogenolysis to produce lubricant base oils possessing group IV properties, achieving maximum yields of 70% within 6 h at 300 &#176;C and 70 bar of H2. Gas, liquid, and oil product yields are stable across reaction conditions, whereas hydrogenation of the PS aromaticity and reduction of the molecular weight benefit from higher temperatures and H2 pressures. Time-dependent experiments underscore the importance of elevated H2 pressure, revealing that PS hydrogenolysis occurs sequentially, with aromatic ring hydrogenation preceding degradation of the C&#8211;C backbone. Kinetic measurements with 1,2-diphenylethane as a probe molecule demonstrate that ring hydrogenation pis 3 orders of magnitude faster than internal C&#8211;C bond cleavage over Ni/SiO2. Ni/SiO2 proves to be effective in the hydrogenolysis of heavier PS polymers and rigid commercial PS products. Conversely, flexibility and foam PS feeds result in Ni/SiO2 deactivation, attributed to performance additives. Unlike polyolefins, the process produces very little methane and other light hydrocarbons. These findings expand the applicability of hydrogenolysis to PS feedstocks, offering a versatile solution and broadening the range of high-value products from PS to include lubricant base oils.</description>
      <author>Brandon C. Vance, Sean Najmi, Dionisios G. Vlachos</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05900</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Hydrogen Evolution Performance: Size and Phase Engineering of Ruthenium Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00368</link>
      <description>Chi-Kai Hung, Antony R. Thiruppathi, Nicholas Burns, Cameron McGuire, Jonathan Quintal, Dazhi Jiang, S. Kycia, Aicheng Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393233907

                Ruthenium-based nanomaterials have seen increased interest as an alternative to platinum electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). In this study, ruthenium nanoparticles supported on a graphene-based composite consisting of expanded graphite and reduced graphene oxide were successfully prepared by using a one-step thermal method. The nanocomposite was optimized for alkaline HER performance by varying the expanded graphite content and annealing temperature, exhibiting an overpotential of 54 mV to achieve 10 mA cm&#8211;2, outperforming the benchmark 20% Pt/C. Through surface characterization of the nanocomposite, the high electrocatalytic activity and stability were found to originate from the interconnected microstructure, optimized porosity, tuned Ru particle size, and homogeneous particle dispersion, revealing the key roles of each component. Using X-ray absorption and X-ray total scattering techniques, the electrochemical performance of the nanocomposite was found to depend on a balance between the size and quality of the ruthenium nanoparticles. The catalyst design principles demonstrated in this work can be applied to streamline and simplify the processes used to develop advanced HER electrocatalysts and other energy storage and conversion materials.</description>
      <author>Chi-Kai Hung, Antony R. Thiruppathi, Nicholas Burns, Cameron McGuire, Jonathan Quintal, Dazhi Jiang, S. Kycia, Aicheng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding pH-Dependent Oxygen Reduction Reaction on Metal Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00461</link>
      <description>Xinnan Mao, Lu Wang, Youyong Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393234212

                Exploring low-cost and high-efficiency catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) kinetics in both acidic and alkaline environments could dramatically improve the efficiency of hydrogen fuel cells and their industrial applications. During the electrochemical process, the effect of pH is a complicating factor and is of great importance in identifying high-efficiency electrocatalysts. In this work, we conducted systematic computations to gain a deep understanding of the pH-dependent ORR activity on Pt, Pd, and their near-surface alloys (NSAs). The effects of pH were calculated by employing the double-reference method, and our calculated pH-dependent current densities are in good agreement with the experimental results. High-throughput calculations identified a series of NSA catalysts with superior ORR performance under acidic or alkaline conditions, and we have developed a pH-corrected theoretical model to efficiently estimate the ORR activity on metal catalysts. This work underscores the importance of considering pH effects when evaluating ORR activity from calculations and provides a strategy for designing superior ORR electrocatalysts in acidic and alkaline solutions.</description>
      <author>Xinnan Mao, Lu Wang, Youyong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale Investigation of the Mechanism and Selectivity of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation over Rh(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05939</link>
      <description>Shijia Sun, Michael Higham, Xingfan Zhang, C. Richard A. Catlow, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393252805

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shijia Sun, Michael Higham, Xingfan Zhang, C. Richard A. Catlow</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05939</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radical 1,2-Nitrogen Migration Cascades of &#946;-Bromo &#945;-Amino Acid Esters to Access &#946;-Amino Acid Motifs Enabled by Cooperative Ni/Diboron Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01034</link>
      <description>Yeonchul Hong, Zi-Cheng Liao, Jiajie Chen, Jian Liu, Yin-Ling Liu, Jin&#8208;Heng Li, Qing Sun, Shi&#8208;Lu Chen, Shuo&#8208;Wen Wang, Shi Tang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393255866

                Amino acid esters serve as crucial intermediates in protein synthesis and as common structural elements in biologically active natural compounds. Herein, we present an efficient radical cascade reaction involving 1,2-nitrogen migration and C(sp2)&#8211;H intramolecular cyclization, enabling access to a diverse array of &#946;-amino acid motifs. Upon cooperative Ni/diboron catalysis, a &#960;-system-independent 1,2-N-shift of &#946;-bromo &#945;-amino acid esters is achieved, which allows the formation of two new bonds, including a C(sp3)&#8211;C(sp2) bond and a C(sp3)&#8211;N bond. The cascade reaction exhibits extensive substrate compatibility and high diastereoselectivity and proceeds without the need for oxidants, toxic radical initiators, and/or elevated temperatures. It has been observed that diboron compounds serve as both an activating reagent for inert C&#8211;N bond cleavage/migration and a reductant for the Ni catalytic cycle. This sheds light on the radical remote migration of N-functionalities without the need for &#960;-systems. The radical cascades involving a 1,2-N-shift followed by intermolecular halogenation or selenation are also demonstrated.</description>
      <author>Yeonchul Hong, Zi-Cheng Liao, Jiajie Chen, Jian Liu, Yin-Ling Liu, Jin&#8208;Heng Li, Qing Sun, Shi&#8208;Lu Chen, Shuo&#8208;Wen Wang, Shi Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Spontaneous Self-Cyclization Enzymes &lt;i&gt;In Vivo&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;In Vitro&lt;/i&gt; with Improved Thermal Tolerance and Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00056</link>
      <description>Bin Wei, Yilin Kang, Yuxuan Zhao, Haichang Xu, Hao Liang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393260657

                Enzymes have selectivity, require mild catalytic conditions, and are important cornerstones in many industrial catalytic processes. Protein self-cyclization has opened up the possibility of preserving fragile enzymes during long-term high-temperature catalysis. However, the mechanism for self-cyclization and improvement of thermal tolerance have not been elucidated, severely limiting their industrial applications. Herein, we provide a strategy for the rational design of fusion proteins based on structural analysis to obtain cyclized enzymes with improved properties. First, we constructed fusion proteins that preferentially translated SpyCatcher (CBT) or SpyTag (TBC), both of which could form stable single self-cyclization with significantly improved thermal tolerance. Especially, the thermal half-life of TBC obtained by modifying the N-terminal SpyTag at 40 &#176;C was 10.83 times that of wild enzymes. Structural analysis revealed that the terminus of the protein, which preferentially translated to SpyCatcher, folded into a conformation that adversely affected stability. In addition, the structure of the catalytic pocket and the orientation of the catalytic residues of CBT were significantly different from those of the wild-type enzymes, which led to a decrease in the catalytic activity. These conclusions were confirmed when another industrial enzyme, sucrose phosphorylase, was cyclized. Finally, the cyclized glucosidase was also superior to the wild-type strain for the preparation of ginsenoside F1 at high titers and as a whole-cell catalyst for extended use. In conclusion, we demonstrated for the first time that conjugated long oligopeptide SpyCatcher significantly affected the catalytic activity and stability of cyclized enzymes. It was necessary to preferentially translate units with less steric hindrance to reduce their impact on the protein structure. The rational design of cyclized enzymes based on structural analysis provides a simple and effective strategy for the modification of industrial enzymes with poor thermal tolerance, providing considerable prospects for biosynthesis in vivo and in vitro.</description>
      <author>Bin Wei, Yilin Kang, Yuxuan Zhao, Haichang Xu, Hao Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the Thermal Activation Network in Human 15-Lipoxygenase-2: Divergence from Plant Orthologs and Its Relationship to Hydrogen Tunneling Activation Barriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00439</link>
      <description>Amanda Ohler, P. E. Taylor, Jasmine A. Bledsoe, Anthony T. Iavarone, Nathaniel C. Gilbert, Adam R. Offenbacher, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393262678

                The oxidation of polyunsaturated fatty acids by lipoxygenases (LOXs) is initiated by a C&#8211;H cleavage step in which the hydrogen atom is transferred quantum mechanically (i.e., via tunneling). In these reactions, protein thermal motions facilitate the conversion of ground-state enzyme&#8211;substrate complexes to tunneling-ready configurations and are thus important for transferring energy from the solvent to the active site for the activation of catalysis. In this report, we employed temperature-dependent hydrogen&#8211;deuterium exchange mass spectrometry (TDHDX-MS) to identify catalytically linked, thermally activated peptides in a representative animal LOX, human epithelial 15-LOX-2. TDHDX-MS of wild-type 15-LOX-2 was compared to two active site mutations that retain structural stability but have increased activation energies (Ea) of catalysis. The Ea value of one variant, V427L, is implicated to arise from suboptimal substrate positioning by increased active-site side chain rotamer dynamics, as determined by X-ray crystallography and ensemble refinement. The resolved thermal network from the comparative Eas of TDHDX-MS between wild-type and V426A is localized along the front face of the 15-LOX-2 catalytic domain. The network contains a clustering of isoleucine, leucine, and valine side chains within the helical peptides. This thermal network of 15-LOX-2 is different in location, area, and backbone structure compared to a model plant lipoxygenase from soybean that exhibits a low Ea value of catalysis compared to the human ortholog. The presented data provide insights into the divergence of thermally activated protein motions in plant and animal LOXs and their relationships to the enthalpic barriers for facilitating hydrogen tunneling.</description>
      <author>Amanda Ohler, P. E. Taylor, Jasmine A. Bledsoe, Anthony T. Iavarone, Nathaniel C. Gilbert, Adam R. Offenbacher</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Contra-Thermodynamic Isomerization&#8211;Asymmetric Hydroboration of Alkenyl Alcohols and Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06194</link>
      <description>Chenchen Li, Kezhuo Zhang, Wanxiang Zhao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277873

                Catalytic isomerization of alkenes is a powerful tool for the construction of complex synthetically valuable molecules due to their redox-neutral, atom- and step-economical nature. However, traditional catalytic asymmetric isomerization of alkenes typically required the use of a heteroatomic group such as OH or NR2 as the thermodynamic driving force (i.e., the C&#9552;C double bond isomerizes along the direction of heteroatomic groups). Here, we present a contra-thermodynamic isomerization/asymmetric hydroboration of alkenyl alcohols and amines, in which the C&#9552;C double bond isomerizes along the opposite direction of OR and NR2. Compared to the traditional thermal isomerizations, this reaction overcomes the unfavorable thermodynamic bias to form a contra-thermodynamic alkene intermediate, followed by an irreversible asymmetric terminal hydroboration to provide highly synthetically valuable chiral 1,n-boryl ethers and amines. This protocol shows a wide substrate scope, including allylic alcohols, homoallylic alcohols, alkenyl alcohols, protected alkenyl alcohols, and various free and protected alkenyl amines. The synthetic utilities and practicability of this method were demonstrated by gram-scale reactions, diverse product transformations, and its applications in the synthesis of bioactive molecules. Preliminary mechanistic studies show that this reaction involves dissociative alkene isomerization and an asymmetric hydroboration of 1,1-disubstituted alkene intermediates.</description>
      <author>Chenchen Li, Kezhuo Zhang, Wanxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalyzed Dual Strain Release of [1.1.1]Propellane with Diazo Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00533</link>
      <description>Jiahao Hu, Xiaobin Yuan, Yufei Li, Xiaoyu Chen, Zaicheng Nie, Mong&#8208;Feng Chiou, Yajun Li, Hongli Bao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393278427

                In recent years, many methods for the synthesis of bicyclo[1.1.1]pentane (BCP) scaffolds have been successfully established owing to their remarkable potent bioactive properties. These BCP scaffolds are typically derived from the single strain release of [1.1.1]propellane. However, approaches for dual strain release of [1.1.1]propellane remain elusive, despite the potential to create innovative opportunities for useful propellane derivatization. In this report, we present herein an efficient method for photocatalyzed dual strain release of [1.1.1]propellane with diazo compounds. Many diazo compounds, including those derived from natural products, such as (+)-borneol, estrone, vitamin E, L-menthol, metronidazole, and geraniol, can be applied to these transformations. Importantly, this method allows the cleavage and formation of multiple C&#8211;C bonds in a photocatalyzed tandem intersystem crossing (ISC)/radical ring-opening/radical&#8211;radical recombination process, and the products can be easily transformed into synthetically challenging spiro compounds, such as spiro [2.3] and spiro [3.4] compounds.</description>
      <author>Jiahao Hu, Xiaobin Yuan, Yufei Li, Xiaoyu Chen, Zaicheng Nie, Mong&#8208;Feng Chiou, Yajun Li, Hongli Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the Synergistic Effect of the Oxide&#8211;Metal Interface on Hot Electron Excitation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00407</link>
      <description>Eunji Lee, Beomjoon Jeon, Hyuk Soon Choi, Jihun Kim, Jong-Seok Kim, Gyuho Han, Kwangjin An, Hyun You Kim, Jeong Young Park, Si Woo Lee, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393280380

                Formulating a quantitative relationship between the extent of electron transfer at metal&#8211;oxide interfaces and catalytic performance aids the rational design of oxide-supported metal catalysts. An effective strategy for monitoring electron transfer at nanoscale interfacial sites is to detect in real time the hot electrons excited when catalytic reactions occur at metal&#8211;oxide perimeter sites. Here, based on our in situ techniques for extracting electron transfer as a current signal using a catalytic nanodiode sensor, we observe hot electron excitation at the CeO2/Pt interface during H2 oxidation. By quantitatively analyzing the hot electrons released during the reaction, we identified the optimal concentration of CeO2/Pt interfaces that maximize the catalytic performance of CeO2/Pt. Through a combinatorial study of experiment and theory, we confirm the decisive role of CeO2/Pt interfacial sites in improving the reactivity and electronic excitation.</description>
      <author>Eunji Lee, Beomjoon Jeon, Hyuk Soon Choi, Jihun Kim, Jong-Seok Kim, Gyuho Han, Kwangjin An, Hyun You Kim, Jeong Young Park, Si Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Engineering of Electrocatalytic Nanomaterials for Hydrogen Evolution: The Impact of Structural and Electronic Modifications of Anchoring Linkers on Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00336</link>
      <description>Andrew J. Bagnall, Matthieu Haake, Sergi Grau, Tatiana Straistari, Matthieu Koepf, Navid Jameei Moghaddam, Carolina Gimbert&#8208;Suri&#241;ach, Jordi Benet&#8208;Buchholz, Antoni Llobet, Murielle Chavarot&#8208;Kerlidou, Bertrand Reuillard, Vincent Artero, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393305578

                The anticipated shortage of an increasing number of critical elements, especially metals, requires a shift toward molecularly defined materials with low metal loadings. More particularly, surface-anchored molecular catalysts are attractive to prospectively enable cost-effective electrochemical hydrogen evolution. However, the design of ligands integrating specific anchoring unit(s) for the immobilization of molecular catalysts can be challenging and has direct consequences for the intrinsic properties of the grafted complex. In this work, two cobalt tetraazamacrocyclic complexes bearing pyrene anchoring groups at different positions on the macrocyclic ligands were synthesized. The pyrene unit allows for simple immobilization and electrochemical characterization of the two complexes on multi-walled carbon nanotube-based electrodes. Thorough electrochemical and electrocatalytic investigation demonstrates important differences between the two closely related catalysts in terms of catalyst loading, catalytic response, and stability over time, with a significantly higher stability observed at pH 7 than at pH 2.</description>
      <author>Andrew J. Bagnall, Matthieu Haake, Sergi Grau, Tatiana Straistari, Matthieu Koepf, Navid Jameei Moghaddam, Carolina Gimbert&#8208;Suri&#241;ach, Jordi Benet&#8208;Buchholz, Antoni Llobet, Murielle Chavarot&#8208;Kerlidou, Bertrand Reuillard, Vincent Artero</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axially Chiral Copper Catalyst for Asymmetric Synthesis of Valuable Diversely Substituted BINOLs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00726</link>
      <description>Jun Gao, P.L. Wang, Ahui Shen, Xueyan Yang, Shouyi Cen, Zhipeng Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393308838

                Optically pure BINOL (1,1&#8242;-bi-2-naphthol) and diversely substituted BINOLs are highly valuable chiral motifs featuring axial chirality widely applied in various fields. Although unsubstituted BINOL is commercially available, the catalytic asymmetric synthesis of optically pure diversely substituted BINOLs is still very challenging. Herein, we report the development of a highly enantioselective dinuclear copper catalyst for oxidative homo- and cross-coupling of a variety of 2-naphthols to provide access to a broad range of highly valuable diversely substituted C2- and C1-symmetric BINOLs in up to 92% yield with high enantioselectivities (up to 99.5:0.5 er).</description>
      <author>Jun Gao, P.L. Wang, Ahui Shen, Xueyan Yang, Shouyi Cen, Zhipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Micropore Topology Influences the Structure and Location of Coke in Zeolite Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00025</link>
      <description>Przemys&#322;aw Rzepka, Denis Sheptyakov, Chao Wang, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, Vladimir Paunovi&#263;, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393309555

                Zeolite catalysts exhibit microporous structures, akin to the pockets in naturally occurring enzyme catalysts, which enable the confinement of reaction intermediates, thus facilitating chemical transformations. Nonetheless, the micropores also influence the formation of coke species, which is the main source of catalytic activity loss. Unveiling the relationships between the micropore topology and the internal structure and location of deactivating coke compounds is of high relevance for comprehending the deactivation mechanisms. In this study, we used an approach exploiting powder neutron diffraction to assess the location of coke and determine the dominating structures in the topologically distinct ZSM-5 (MFI topology), ZSM-35 (FER), and SSZ-13 (CHA) zeolite catalysts deactivated in industrially relevant methanol-to-hydrocarbon (MTH) conversion. In ZSM-5 and ZSM-35 catalysts, coke resides along the straight 10-membered ring (MR) channels and exhibits the highest concentration in their intersecting regions with sinusoidal 10 MR and straight 8 MR pores, respectively. In the SSZ-13 catalyst, coke is not only located in cages but also protrudes through their 8 MR windows, suggesting the interconnectivity of coke molecules between the large cavities. Notably, the coke-associated signals in the ZSM-5 and ZSM-35 catalysts show a strong planar arrangement that can be fitted by polycyclic and monocyclic arene structures, respectively. These averaged coke structures are consistent with the composition of coke assessed by gas chromatography&#8211;mass spectrometry, 13C and two-dimensional 1H double-quantum single-quantum magic-angle spinning nuclear magnetic resonance, and operando diffuse reflectance ultraviolet&#8211;visible spectroscopic analysis. The findings evidence that the pore topology directs the confinement and structure of coke, wherein the largest void zones of the micropore space are the most susceptible to coking.</description>
      <author>Przemys&#322;aw Rzepka, Denis Sheptyakov, Chao Wang, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, Vladimir Paunovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choose Your Own Adventure: A Comprehensive Database of Reactions Catalyzed by Cytochrome P450 BM3 Variants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00086</link>
      <description>Douglas J. Fansher, Jonathan N. Besna, Ali Fendri, Joelle N. Pelletier, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393311212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Douglas J. Fansher, Jonathan N. Besna, Ali Fendri, Joelle N. Pelletier</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Synergistic Power of Ce&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; S-Scheme Heterojunctions for Profound C&#8211;O Bond Cleavage in Lignin Model Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00297</link>
      <description>Hongwu Liao, Yanmin Zhou, Zhuo Chen, Swellam W. Sharshir, Sameh M. Osman, Chong Wang, Meng An, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yusuke Asakura, Zhanhui Yuan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393316547

                In the context of achieving carbon neutrality, converting lignin-derived molecules into high-value products through photocatalytic technology provides an environmentally friendly pathway. Establishing energy-efficient processes for converting lignin derivatives requires the construction of highly active and selective photocatalysts. However, enhancing the efficiency and selectivity of photocatalysts for lignin degradation poses an ongoing challenge due to discrepancies in the redox potential and the rapid recombination of photogenerated carriers. To address these significant obstacles, we devised an innovative strategy by developing a Ce2S3 nanoparticle-anchored TiO2 nanorod (Ce2S3/TiO2). This advanced photocatalyst with the S-scheme heterojunction, enabling simultaneous control of carrier dynamics and band structure, was used to study the photocatalytic degradation of the lignin model compound 2-phenoxy-1-acetophenone. Moreover, the photocatalyst can cleave the C&#946;-O-4 bond selectively to convert the lignin model compound 2-phenoxy-1-acetophenone into phenol and acetophenone under visible-light irradiation. The yields are up to 94 and 80%, respectively, and 94 or 1.4 times greater than those obtained by pure TiO2 or Ce2S3 individually. In addition, our study for the increased activity in Ce2S3/TiO2 based on density functional theory calculations emphasizes the pivotal role of the S-scheme heterojunction generated between Ce2S3 and TiO2. This heterojunction significantly enhances carrier separation efficiency, thereby augmenting the efficacy of the photocatalytic process. The findings furnish valuable insights for developing advanced photocatalytic systems tailored to the efficient depolymerization of C&#946;-O-4 bonds in lignin.</description>
      <author>Hongwu Liao, Yanmin Zhou, Zhuo Chen, Swellam W. Sharshir, Sameh M. Osman, Chong Wang, Meng An, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yusuke Asakura, Zhanhui Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General, Modular Access toward Immobilized Chiral Phosphoric Acid Catalysts and Their Application in Flow Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00985</link>
      <description>Michael Laue, Maximilian Schneider, Markus G. Gebauer, Winfried B&#246;hlmann, Roger Gl&#228;ser, Christoph Schneider, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393316637

                Chiral phosphoric acids (CPAs) are among the most frequently used organocatalysts, with an ever-increasing number of applications. However, these catalysts are only obtained in a multistep synthesis and are poorly recyclable, which significantly deteriorates their environmental and economic performance. We herein report a conceptually different, general strategy for the direct immobilization of CPAs on a broad scope of solid supports including silica, polystyrene, and aluminum oxide. Solid-state catalysts were obtained in high yields and thoroughly characterized with elemental analysis by inductively coupled plasma-optical emission spectrometry (ICP-OES), nitrogen sorption measurements, thermogravimetric analysis, scanning transmission electron microscopy/energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (STEM/EDX) images, and solid-state NMR spectroscopy. Further, the immobilized catalysts were applied to a variety of synthetically valuable, highly stereoselective transformations under batch and flow conditions including transfer hydrogenations, a Friedl&#228;nder condensation/transfer hydrogenation sequence, and Mannich reactions under cryogenic flow conditions. Generally, high yields and stereoselectivities were observed along with robust catalyst stability and reusability. After being used for 10 runs under batch conditions, no loss of selectivity or catalytic activity was observed. Under continuous-flow conditions, the heterogeneous system was in operation for 19 h and the high enantioselectivity remained unchanged throughout the entire process. We expect our approach to extend the applicability of CPAs to a higher level, with a focus on flow chemistry and a more environmentally friendly and resource-efficient use of these powerful catalysts.</description>
      <author>Michael Laue, Maximilian Schneider, Markus G. Gebauer, Winfried B&#246;hlmann, Roger Gl&#228;ser, Christoph Schneider</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00985</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Complex Ligands for High Oxidation State Catalysis: Titanium Hydroamination with Unsymmetrical Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05658</link>
      <description>Zhilin Hou, Rashmi Jena, Tanner J. McDaniel, Brennan S. Billow, Seokjoo Lee, Hannah I. Barr, Aaron L. Odom, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393316892

                A method for modeling high oxidation state catalysts is used on precatalysts with unsymmetrical and symmetrical bidentate ligands to get a more detailed understanding of how changes to ancillary ligands affect the hydroamination of alkynes catalyzed by titanium. To model the electronic donor ability, the ligand donor parameter (LDP) was used, and to model the steric effects, percent buried volume (% Vbur) was employed. For the modeling study, 7 previously unpublished unsymmetrical Ti(XX&#8242;)(NMe2)2 precatalysts were prepared, where XX&#8242; is a chelating ligand with pyrrolyl/indolyl linkages. The rates of these unsymmetrical and 10 previously reported symmetrical precatalysts were used with the model kobs = a + b(LDP)1 + c(LDP)2 + d(% Vbur)1 + e(% Vbur)2, where a&#8211;e were found through least-squares refinement. The model suggests that (1) the two attachment points of the bidentate ligand XX&#8242; are in different environments on the metal (e.g., axial and equatorial in a trigonal bipyramidal or square pyramidal structure), (2) the position of the unsymmetrical ligand on the metal is determined by the electronics of the ligand rather than the sterics, and (3) that one side of the chelating ligand's electronics strongly influences the rate, while the other side's sterics more strongly influences the rate. From these studies, we were able to generate catalysts fitting to this model with rate constants larger than the fastest symmetrical catalyst tested.</description>
      <author>Zhilin Hou, Rashmi Jena, Tanner J. McDaniel, Brennan S. Billow, Seokjoo Lee, Hannah I. Barr, Aaron L. Odom</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benzylic C(sp3)&#8211;H Functionalization via Copper-Catalyzed [3+3] Radical Cycloaddition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00637</link>
      <description>Junsheng Shi, Xiong-Jiang Li, Shu-Yun Jiang, Wei Wu, Hai Ren, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393317410

                The development of benzylic C(sp3)&#8211;H functionalization methods for the assembly of benzylic derivatives has been extensively explored in recent years. However, the engagement of benzylic carbon and its adjacent C=C bond as a C3 synthon in the cycloaddition reaction via direct benzylic C&#8211;H activation is rare. Herein, we report a copper-catalyzed [3+3] radical cycloaddition reaction through benzylic C&#8211;H bond functionalization to construct six-membered cyclohexane-type rings. In this reaction, the 2-benzylic C&#8211;H bond of an indole is selectively activated and the indole serves as a C3 synthon that reacts through highly chemoselective intermolecular self-[3+3] and cross-[3+3] cycloaddition pathways. Multiple symmetric and nonsymmetric polycyclic hexahydrocarbazole scaffolds with hexacyclic 6/5/5/6/5/5/6 and pentacyclic 6/5/5/6/5/6 ring systems are synthesized with high efficiency and chemoselectivity using this strategy. Inspired by the unique radical addition pathway of cross-[3+3] cycloaddition, a highly controllable benzylic C&#8211;H functionalization for the construction of C3a-alkylated pyrroloindolines was also developed.</description>
      <author>Junsheng Shi, Xiong-Jiang Li, Shu-Yun Jiang, Wei Wu, Hai Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare-Earth-Catalyzed Regiodivergent Hydrosilylation of Aryl Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05747</link>
      <description>Wufeng Chen, N. Zhang, Zhengqi Chai, Junnian Wei, Gen Luo, Wen&#8208;Xiong Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393317760

                While transition-metal catalysts have shown the ability to regulate the Markovnikov or anti-Markovnikov regioselective hydrosilylation of aryl alkenes, the selective control of anti-Markovnikov hydrosilylation of aryl alkenes is still a huge challenge in rare-earth catalyst systems. In this study, we report the rare-earth-catalyzed regiodivergent hydrosilylation of aryl alkenes. Specifically, we achieved the highly regioselective anti-Markovnikov hydrosilylation of aryl alkenes with a scandium alkyl complex Cp*AmtBuScCH2SiMe3 (Cp* = pentamethylcyclopentadienyl, AmtBu = tBuNC(Me)NtBu, tBu = t-butyl) as a catalyst. Two key intermediates, e.g., the scandium hydride and scandium phenethyl complex for anti-Markovnikov hydrosilylation, were characterized. Guided by density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we successfully achieved the selective inversion of aryl alkenes in Markovnikov hydrosilylation using a neodymium halide complex [Cp*AmiPrNdCl]2 (AmiPr = iPrNC(Me)NiPr, iPr = isopropyl) with the larger ion radius and reduced steric hindrance in conjunction with LiCH2SiMe3. Interestingly, our study has demonstrated the significant influence of gradually increasing rare-earth ion radii on controlling the increasing Markovnikov selectivity of hydrosilylation reactions, possibly due to the enlargement of the coordination space around rare-earth metal ions. Furthermore, through a comparison of computational and experimental data, we have observed a high level of consistency, reaffirming the potential of using calculations to predict experimental outcomes and providing researchers with valuable insights.</description>
      <author>Wufeng Chen, N. Zhang, Zhengqi Chai, Junnian Wei, Gen Luo, Wen&#8208;Xiong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Catalyst Immediate Environment Enables Acidic Electrochemical Benzyl Alcohol Oxidation to Benzaldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00476</link>
      <description>G. Shiva Shanker, Arnab Ghatak, Shahar Binyamin, Rotem Balilty, Ran Shimoni, Itamar Liberman, Idan Hod, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393319141

                Electrocatalytic alcohol oxidation in acid offers a promising alternative to the kinetically sluggish water oxidation reaction toward low-energy H2 generation. However, electrocatalysts driving active and selective acidic alcohol electrochemical transformation are still scarce. In this work, we demonstrate efficient alcohol-to-aldehyde conversion achieved by reticular chemistry-based modification of the catalyst's immediate environment. Specifically, coating a Bi-based electrocatalyst with a thin layer of metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) substantially improves its performance toward benzyl alcohol electro-oxidation to benzaldehyde in a 0.1 M H2SO4 electrolyte. Detailed analysis reveals that the MOF adlayer influences catalysis by increasing the reactivity of surface hydroxides as well as weakening the catalyst-benzaldehyde binding strength. In turn, low-potential (0.65 V) cathodic H2 evolution was obtained through coupling it with anodic benzyl alcohol electro-oxidation. Consequently, the presented approach could be implemented in a wide range of electrocatalytic oxidation reactions for energy-conversion application.</description>
      <author>G. Shiva Shanker, Arnab Ghatak, Shahar Binyamin, Rotem Balilty, Ran Shimoni, Itamar Liberman, Idan Hod</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enlarging the Three-Phase Boundary to Raise CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Conversions on Exsolved Ni&#8211;Fe Alloy Perovskite Catalysts by Minimal Rh Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00151</link>
      <description>Xueli Yao, Qingpeng Cheng, Xueqin Bai, Bambar Davaasuren, Georgian Melinte, Natalia Morlan&#233;s, Jos&#233; Luis Cerrillo, Vijay Kumar Velisoju, Hend Omar Mohamed, Pewee Datoo Kolubah, Lirong Zheng, Yu Han, Osman M. Bakr, Jorge Gasc&#243;n, Pedro Casta&#241;o, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393319453

                Exsolved Ni&#8211;Fe alloy perovskite catalysts exhibit remarkable coking resistance during C&#8211;H and C&#8211;O activation. However, metallic utilization is typically incomplete, resulting in relatively low catalytic activity. Herein, we investigated minimal doping with Rh to boost the catalytic activity in the dry reforming of methane by promoting exsolution and enlargement of the three-phase boundary between the alloy, support, and reactants. The Rh influences the formation of the Ni&#8211;Fe alloy, as revealed by X-ray diffraction, and promotes the individual and collective CH4 and CO2 conversions, as revealed by packed bed reactor runs, temperature-programmed surface reactions, and in situ infrared spectroscopy. A minimal 0.21 wt % Rh addition enlarges the three-phase boundary while improving oxygen mobility and storage. The oxygen mobility is responsible for promoting CH4 dissociation and dynamic removal of carbon-containing intermediates, such that the catalyst remains stable for over 100 h under both 1 and 14 bar.</description>
      <author>Xueli Yao, Qingpeng Cheng, Xueqin Bai, Bambar Davaasuren, Georgian Melinte, Natalia Morlan&#233;s, Jos&#233; Luis Cerrillo, Vijay Kumar Velisoju, Hend Omar Mohamed, Pewee Datoo Kolubah, Lirong Zheng, Yu Han, Osman M. Bakr, Jorge Gasc&#243;n, Pedro Casta&#241;o</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Strong Metal&#8211;Support Interactions via Synergistic Alloying</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06171</link>
      <description>Yunlong Wang, Xiaobo Chen, Chaoran Li, Yaguang Zhu, Jing Li, Shiyao Shan, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, J. Anibal Boscoboinik, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, Guangwen Zhou, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393345356

                The encapsulation phenomenon associated with a strong metal&#8211;support interactions (SMSI) has been largely restricted to catalyst systems consisting of group VIII metals with high surface energy and reducible transition metal oxide supports with low surface energy. Here, we demonstrate an encapsulation phenomenon that, while sharing morphological similarities with conventional SMSI, follows a distinctive pathway. This is shown by the encapsulation of CuAu nanoparticles (NPs) supported on a highly ordered pyrolytic graphite (HOPG). Through dynamic monitoring of Cu, Au, and Cu50Au50 NPs in an oxidizing atmosphere using ambient-pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, we show that this spontaneous encapsulation is achieved through the synergistic effect of the alloying elements. Specifically, the surface segregation of Cu promotes dissociative O2 adsorption, leading to the formation of atomic O species, while the subsurface enrichment of Au hinders O incorporation of oxygen into the bulk of CuAu NPs. Consequently, O spillover onto the graphite support occurs, resulting in the oxidation of the HOPG surface into graphitic oxide species. The higher affinity of the graphitic oxide species toward the Cu-segregated surface prompts their migration from the HOPG support to encapsulate the CuAu NPs. These results transcend the conventional SMSI and bear practical implications for the design and development of heterogeneous catalysts, particularly in carbon-supported alloy systems.</description>
      <author>Yunlong Wang, Xiaobo Chen, Chaoran Li, Yaguang Zhu, Jing Li, Shiyao Shan, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, J. Anibal Boscoboinik, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, Guangwen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic Equilibrium versus Kinetic Trapping: Thermalization of Cluster Catalyst Ensembles Can Extend Beyond Reaction Time Scales</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06154</link>
      <description>Patricia Poths, Santiago Vargas, Philippe Sautet, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393224125

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Patricia Poths, Santiago Vargas, Philippe Sautet, Anastassia N. Alexandrova</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable Divergent Reactivity of Aziridinium Ylides in the Synthesis of Complex Piperidines and Azetidines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06173</link>
      <description>Mahzad Dehghany, Giuliana Pavaneli, Jacob W. Kailing, Olivia M. Duke, Ilia A. Guzei, Caroline Da Ros Montes D&#8217;Oca, Israel Fern&#225;ndez, Jennifer M. Schomaker, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393372078

                Nitrogenated heterocycles comprise the cores of a number of synthetically useful compounds, including pharmaceuticals, bioactive natural products, agrochemicals, and other drug-like molecules. The widespread interest in methods to increase the fraction of sp3 carbon atoms (Fsp3) of drug-like scaffolds in a stereocontrolled manner, while enabling explorations of unusual amine chemical space, inspired our efforts to tune the reactivity of aziridinium ylides. A sequential nitrene&#8211;carbene transfer of simple allenes leads to divergent product outcomes depending on the nature of the carbene precursor, furnishing products of different ring sizes. In addition, the catalyst control over the ring size via proposed hydrogen-bonding interactions between the catalyst and substrate was explored. Computational studies were employed to gain insight into the major features of substrates and catalysts that influence the tunable reactivity of aziridinium ylide intermediates formed in this chemistry.</description>
      <author>Mahzad Dehghany, Giuliana Pavaneli, Jacob W. Kailing, Olivia M. Duke, Ilia A. Guzei, Caroline Da Ros Montes D&#8217;Oca, Israel Fern&#225;ndez, Jennifer M. Schomaker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06173</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
