<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 15:20:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable Divergent Reactivity of Aziridinium Ylides in the Synthesis of Complex Piperidines and Azetidines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06173</link>
      <description>Mahzad Dehghany, Giuliana Pavaneli, Jacob W. Kailing, Olivia M. Duke, Ilia A. Guzei, Caroline Da Ros Montes D&#8217;Oca, Israel Fern&#225;ndez, Jennifer M. Schomaker, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393372078

                Nitrogenated heterocycles comprise the cores of a number of synthetically useful compounds, including pharmaceuticals, bioactive natural products, agrochemicals, and other drug-like molecules. The widespread interest in methods to increase the fraction of sp3 carbon atoms (Fsp3) of drug-like scaffolds in a stereocontrolled manner, while enabling explorations of unusual amine chemical space, inspired our efforts to tune the reactivity of aziridinium ylides. A sequential nitrene&#8211;carbene transfer of simple allenes leads to divergent product outcomes depending on the nature of the carbene precursor, furnishing products of different ring sizes. In addition, the catalyst control over the ring size via proposed hydrogen-bonding interactions between the catalyst and substrate was explored. Computational studies were employed to gain insight into the major features of substrates and catalysts that influence the tunable reactivity of aziridinium ylide intermediates formed in this chemistry.</description>
      <author>Mahzad Dehghany, Giuliana Pavaneli, Jacob W. Kailing, Olivia M. Duke, Ilia A. Guzei, Caroline Da Ros Montes D&#8217;Oca, Israel Fern&#225;ndez, Jennifer M. Schomaker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Visible-Light-Driven Water Oxidation by a Carbon Nitride Modified with Cobalt Polyoxometalate Molecular Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00627</link>
      <description>Yoshihiko Tomita, Natsuki Taira, Ken Sakai, Hidetoshi Ozawa, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393373284

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yoshihiko Tomita, Natsuki Taira, Ken Sakai, Hidetoshi Ozawa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competing Mechanisms in Palladium-Catalyzed Alkoxycarbonylation of Styrene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00966</link>
      <description>Jaya Mehara, Mariarosa Anania, Pavel Ko&#269;ovsk&#253;, Jana Roithov&#225;, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393375769

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jaya Mehara, Mariarosa Anania, Pavel Ko&#269;ovsk&#253;, Jana Roithov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00966</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Hydrogen-Switchable Dynamic Oxygen Vacancies in MoO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; upon Ru Nanoparticle Decoration for Boosting Photocatalytic Ammonia Synthesis Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05633</link>
      <description>Lulu Zhang, Rui Li, Lijun Guo, Longzhe Cui, Xiaochao Zhang, Yawen Wang, Yunfang Wang, Xuan Jian, Xiaoming Gao, Caimei Fan, Jiancheng Wang, Jianxin Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393376514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lulu Zhang, Rui Li, Lijun Guo, Longzhe Cui, Xiaochao Zhang, Yawen Wang, Yunfang Wang, Xuan Jian, Xiaoming Gao, Caimei Fan, Jiancheng Wang, Jianxin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05633</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Electrocatalytic Semihydrogenation of Alkynols to Alkenols over a Bimetallic CuAu Alloy Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05928</link>
      <description>Qinghui Ren, Leilei Hao, Jiangrong Yang, Mengyu Lv, Hua Zhou, Zhenhua Li, Haohong Duan, Mingfei Shao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393377866

                Electrocatalytic semihydrogenation of alkynols to alkenols under ambient conditions using H2O as a hydrogen source is highly attractive in synthetic chemistry. However, it is still challenging to achieve a high Faradaic efficiency (FE) in a wide potential window. Herein, we reported a bimetallic Cu3Au alloy as an efficient catalyst for electrocatalytic semihydrogenation of alkynols to alkenols. Specifically, during semihydrogenation of 2-butyne-1,4-diol (BYD) to 2-butene-1,4-diol (BED), the Cu3Au catalyst achieves 12.6-fold greater reaction rate and higher FE compared with pure Cu (99 vs 63%). Moreover, the Cu3Au maintains &gt;96% FEs in a wide potential window from &#8722;0.19 to &#8722;0.59 V vs RHE. We demonstrate that the competitive adsorptions of reactive hydrogen (H*) and BYD greatly influence the semihydrogenation processes. The presence of Au in Cu3Au facilitates H* formation and reduces BYD adsorption on Cu, thus enhancing the BYD hydrogenation performance. The Cu3Au catalyst affords a broad substrate scope from alkynols to aromatic alkynes, producing the corresponding alkenes in good selectivities. Finally, we coupled BYD semihydrogenation with glycerol oxidation to replace oxygen evolution reaction in a two-electrode system, showing 40% energy saving at 200 mA for BED production and coproduction of valuable formate at the anode, demonstrating an economical manner.</description>
      <author>Qinghui Ren, Leilei Hao, Jiangrong Yang, Mengyu Lv, Hua Zhou, Zhenhua Li, Haohong Duan, Mingfei Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Carrier Separation on a BiOBr/Bi&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;Br&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Direct Z-Scheme Heterojunction for Superior Photocatalytic Nitrogen Fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06169</link>
      <description>Huiqing Wang, Zhuohua Chen, Yaru Shang, Chade Lv, Xuhan Zhang, Fei Li, Qunzeng Huang, Xiaodi Liu, Wenmin Liu, Liang Zhao, Liqun Ye, Hongmei Xie, Xiaoli Jin, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393381136

                Photocatalytic dinitrogen (N2) fixation is regarded as an achievable technology for ammonia (NH3) production. However, the poor separation efficiency of the photoinduced carriers and ineffective N2 activation remain grand obstacles to high-performance NH3 photosynthesis. Designing advanced heterostructured systems to accelerate charge separation and activate the N2 molecule is a feasible strategy to optimize the photocatalytic N2 fixation activity. Herein, a direct Z-scheme configuration is established between BiOBr and Bi4O5Br2 through a facile one-step solvothermal reaction. This configuration enables effective spatial separation of electron&#8211;hole pairs and preserves the robust redox ability of carriers, concurrently promoting N&#8801;N bond activation and diminishing the energy barrier for the rate-determining step. The formation of direct Z-scheme BiOBr/Bi4O5Br2 heterojunctions is mostly attributed to the similarities in their lattice structures and crystal growth conditions. As a result, the direct Z-scheme BiOBr/Bi4O5Br2 heterojunction exhibits a high NH3 yield of 66.87 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 without using sacrificing reagents, surpassing that of the pristine BiOBr and Bi4O5Br2 by approximately 3.3 and 5.6 times, respectively. This study provides an achievable approach to construct direct Z-scheme heterojunction systems for implementing high-performance N2 fixation under mild conditions.</description>
      <author>Huiqing Wang, Zhuohua Chen, Yaru Shang, Chade Lv, Xuhan Zhang, Fei Li, Qunzeng Huang, Xiaodi Liu, Wenmin Liu, Liang Zhao, Liqun Ye, Hongmei Xie, Xiaoli Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Catalytic Nitrogen&#8211;Nitrogen Bond Formation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00718</link>
      <description>Jianglin Hu, Yichen Wu, Ying Gao, Yinglei Wang, Peng Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393385196

                The lack of effective strategies for direct construction of nitrogen&#8211;nitrogen bonds has hampered developments in the synthesis and application of molecules containing hydrazine or azo motifs. Attracted by their properties both in material science and in medicinal chemistry, more and more attention has been drawn to this area, resulting in fast growth in the design and synthesis of azaheterocycles and substituted hydrazines. This review focuses on efficient catalytic approaches toward the formation of N&#8211;N and N&#9552;N bonds through different strategies, including oxidative dehydrogenation, nitrene-transfer reaction, reductive coupling, and some other recently developed methods.</description>
      <author>Jianglin Hu, Yichen Wu, Ying Gao, Yinglei Wang, Peng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Reaction Network Exploration Scheme Based on Graph Theory Representation and Depth First Search Applied to CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation on Pd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Cu Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00067</link>
      <description>Hui Guo, Hong Zhu, Guan-Zhang Liu, Zhao-Xu Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393385723

                Reaction mechanisms are at the core of understanding reaction systems and designing high-performance catalysts. A complex reaction system often involves various species and elementary reactions, posing a great challenge to determining the reaction mechanism. Here, we proposed a scheme to automatically generate reaction intermediates and elementary reactions to construct a complete reaction network represented by graph theory and employed a depth first search algorithm in the scheme to prune the reaction network to reduce the complexity of the network. With this scheme, microkinetic simulations of CO2 hydrogenation on Pd2Cu using the barriers predicted with the linear thermodynamics&#8211;kinetics relations were performed on the network to determine the mechanism and rate- and selectivity-controlling steps of CO2 hydrogenation to ethanol and methanol. Analysis shows that the simulated selectivity of ethanol and methanol agrees well with the experimental results. CO2 + H &#8594; COOH is the rate-controlling step, and CHOH + H &#8594; CH + H2O, CH2OH + H &#8594; CH2 + H2O, and CH2OH + H &#8594; CH3OH dominate the ethanol selectivity. Both ethanol and methanol are generated via multiple reaction pathway mechanisms. Investigations of the pruned networks show that quantitatively correct results can be obtained from the pruned or pseudocomplete reaction network, as long as the key pathways are embodied in the network. 94% ethanol selectivity of the complete network can be obtained with the pruned network composed of 60 elementary steps, compared to 176 steps of the complete network. The present work articulates graph theory representation, depth first search algorithm, linear thermodynamics&#8211;kinetics relations, and microkinetic simulations to approach complicated heterogeneous reaction systems and exemplifies their comprehensive roles in exploring complex reaction networks.</description>
      <author>Hui Guo, Hong Zhu, Guan-Zhang Liu, Zhao-Xu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin Selectivity Induced by the Interface Effect for Boosted Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00142</link>
      <description>Zhigao Xue, Biao Wu, Zheng Zhang, Ching-Yu Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Qiuju Zhang, Kai Tao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393386676

                Creating highly effective electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) holds paramount importance in advancing carbon-neutral hydrogen production through water electrolysis. Recent research highlights the crucial role of spin effects on the OER, emphasizing that the manipulation of spin polarization is a promising strategy to augment the OER kinetics. Here, we present a core&#8211;shell heterostructure electrocatalyst, which leverages the strong coupling of the interface between antiferromagnetic Co3O4 and NiFe-layered double hydroxide (NiFe-LDH) to trigger a spontaneous magnetic response enhancement, which suggests the strong double exchange interaction at the interface of the core&#8211;shell heterostructure. This electrocatalyst displays a 26-fold increase in intrinsic OER activity compared to pristine NiFe-LDH at an overpotential of 0.25 V. Through experimental and computational analyses, we find that the strong double exchange interaction within the heterostructure creates polarized spin conduction channels at the interface, which enables efficient accumulation of electrons with appropriate spin states, thereby lowering the energy barrier for the generation of triplet O2. Our work presents a promising approach to designing high-performance OER catalysts by introducing spin selectivity in traditional metal oxide electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhigao Xue, Biao Wu, Zheng Zhang, Ching-Yu Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Qiuju Zhang, Kai Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reductive Aminomethylation Using Ammonium Formate and Methanol as N1 and C1 Source: Direct Synthesis of Mono- and Di-Methylated Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00346</link>
      <description>Ishani Borthakur, S. K. Nandi, Yuvraj Bilora, Biswajit Sadhu, Sabuj Kundu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393409196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ishani Borthakur, S. K. Nandi, Yuvraj Bilora, Biswajit Sadhu, Sabuj Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrophobic Surface Modification of Cu-Based Catalysts for Enhanced Semihydrogenation of Acetylene in Excess Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05466</link>
      <description>Ting Liu, Jinqi Xiong, Qian Luo, Shanjun Mao, Yong Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393409197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Liu, Jinqi Xiong, Qian Luo, Shanjun Mao, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Catalyst Self-Adjustment in C&#8211;S Cross-Coupling through Multiscale Liquid-Phase Electron Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06258</link>
      <description>Alexey S. Kashin, D. M. Arkhipova, Liliya T. Sahharova, Julia V. Burykina, Valentine P. Ananikov, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393500093

                Carbon&#8211;carbon and carbon&#8211;heteroatom bond formation mediated by transition metals is a powerful and convenient methodology for organic synthesis. To effectively meet the demands of catalyst design, an in-depth understanding of the reaction mechanisms and pathways of active species evolution is essential. Advances in electron microscopy now offer unprecedented multilevel visualization of liquid-phase chemical systems, providing a powerful tool for mechanistic studies. In this work, we found that the use of either nickel- or copper-based catalyst precursors with preinstalled thiolate groups in combination with pyridinium ionic liquid as the reaction medium leads to a positive synergistic effect, resulting in the formation of transition metal species with high catalytic activity in the C&#8211;S cross-coupling reaction between aryl halides and thiols or disulfides. Through multiscale in situ and operando electron microscopy in the liquid phase, we elucidated the self-adjustment of the catalytic system and revealed the simultaneous emergence of metallic nanoparticles and corresponding thiolate species, leading to the independent activation of the C- and S-substrates and the subsequent elimination of the product via organic group metathesis. The proposed methodology for the catalytic preparation of aromatic organosulfides was used for the design of synthetic routes to pharmacologically important substances.</description>
      <author>Alexey S. Kashin, D. M. Arkhipova, Liliya T. Sahharova, Julia V. Burykina, Valentine P. Ananikov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu&#8211;Sn Bimetallic Activated Carbon&#8211;Carbon Coupling for Efficient Furfural Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06346</link>
      <description>Xiaofeng Liu, Yuhan Sun, Hao Ren, Yuan Lin, Mingbo Wu, Zhong-Tao Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393536047

                Electrochemically driven carbon&#8211;carbon coupling utilizing renewable electricity under ambient conditions has emerged as an innovative approach for synthesizing high-value chemicals, which still faces inherent challenges such as low conversion rates and poor selectivity. While electroreducing furfural to hydrofuroin can produce high-quality biofuel, its efficiency need to be promoted. Herein, Cu&#8211;Sn bimetallic catalyst has been developed with a conversion rate of furfural of &gt;97% and hydrofuroin selectivity of &gt;67% through equilibrium of the interfacial intermediate *H and *fur-CHOH, which exhibits the greatest state-of-the-art overall performance. Characterization and theoretical calculation reveal that Cu serves as the active site for generating *fur-CHOH, whose electron density can be decreased by introducing Sn, and results in a higher *fur-CHOH coverage and a lower energy barrier of dimerization. Moreover, adding Sn also enables sluggish *H formation to balance interfacial *fur-CHOH and *H, leading to reduced hydrogenation byproducts. The as-developed approach provides valuable insights for optimizing other C&#8211;C electrocoupling reactions for the synthesis of high-value chemicals.</description>
      <author>Xiaofeng Liu, Yuhan Sun, Hao Ren, Yuan Lin, Mingbo Wu, Zhong-Tao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Activation of Surface Oxygen for Efficient Oxidative Dehydrogenation Reaction at Elevated Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04731</link>
      <description>Xiang Sun, Heejae Yang, Benchi Chen, Min-Bo Zhou, Yongjian Ye, Xiaobao Li, Hui Zhang, Bo Yu, Yifeng Li, Jeong Woo Han, Yan Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393543441

                Oxidative dehydrogenation (ODH) of alkane with CO2 as the oxidant has attracted worldwide attention as a promising approach for simultaneously producing valuable alkenes and greenhouse gas utilization. The selectivity and yield of the produced alkene, nevertheless, require further enhancement for practical applications. In this work, taking Sr2Ti0.8Co0.6Fe0.6O6-&#948; (STCF) as the electrode material, we demonstrate that a solid oxide electrolysis cell (SOEC) can efficiently catalyze the ODH of ethane to ethylene on the anode and reduce CO2 to CO at the cathode. The optimal yield of ethylene reached 66.3% at 800 &#176;C, which is among the highest values reported in the literature. Such ethane ODH activity is attributed to the activation of surface oxygen on the STCF anode by electrolytic voltage, as revealed experimentally by advanced spectroscopic techniques. The density functional theory calculation further implied that the electrochemically driven formation of active oxygen species on the STCF surface upshifts the O 2p-band center, facilitates electron transfer, and enhances surface adsorption, leading to a strongly promoted dehydrogenation process. The results clarify the critical role of oxygen activity in determining the electrochemical ODH performance and can guide the rational design of catalysts for other electrosynthesis processes.</description>
      <author>Xiang Sun, Heejae Yang, Benchi Chen, Min-Bo Zhou, Yongjian Ye, Xiaobao Li, Hui Zhang, Bo Yu, Yifeng Li, Jeong Woo Han, Yan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04731</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Nitrogen Infiltration into an Ordered Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co Alloy with sp&#8211;d Hybridization to Boost Fuel Cell Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06223</link>
      <description>Mengzhao Zhu, Huijuan Zhang, Yanjun Hu, Fangyao Zhou, Xiaoping Gao, Dayin He, Xuyan Zhao, Chao Zhao, Jing Wang, Wenan Tie, Tian Xia, Bo Wang, Takeshi Yao, Huang Zhou, Zhe Wang, Jin Wang, Wenxin Guo, Yuen Wu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393715758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengzhao Zhu, Huijuan Zhang, Yanjun Hu, Fangyao Zhou, Xiaoping Gao, Dayin He, Xuyan Zhao, Chao Zhao, Jing Wang, Wenan Tie, Tian Xia, Bo Wang, Takeshi Yao, Huang Zhou, Zhe Wang, Jin Wang, Wenxin Guo, Yuen Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Bridging Homogeneous and Heterogeneous Water Oxidation Catalysis by Insolubilized Polyoxometalate Clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00201</link>
      <description>Qiyu Hu, Hongshan Zhou, Yong Ding, Thomas W&#229;gberg, Xiuxiu Han, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393855529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiyu Hu, Hongshan Zhou, Yong Ding, Thomas W&#229;gberg, Xiuxiu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the d-Band Center of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; via Octahedral and Tetrahedral Codoping for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06256</link>
      <description>Xiaotian Wu, Zhiyu Shao, Qian Zhu, Xiangyan Hou, Chao Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Keke Huang, Shouhua Feng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393857012

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaotian Wu, Zhiyu Shao, Qian Zhu, Xiangyan Hou, Chao Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Keke Huang, Shouhua Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Diverse Construction of &lt;i&gt;gem&lt;/i&gt;-Difluoroallylated Bicyclo[1.1.1]pentanes and Cyclobutanes from [1.1.1]Propellane via Copper Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00281</link>
      <description>Xiao-Tian Feng, Qiao&#8208;Qiao Min, Xiangfeng Zeng, Hang Zhao, Xingang Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393858800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao-Tian Feng, Qiao&#8208;Qiao Min, Xiangfeng Zeng, Hang Zhao, Xingang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regeneration of NAD(P)H and its Analogues by Photocatalysis with Ionized Carbon Nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00841</link>
      <description>Zaixiang Xu, Zhongwei Fan, Hanchi Chen, Jianguo Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393859085

                The regeneration of NAD(P)H and its analogues is crucial for biocatalytic processes. However, despite the efficiency of enzymatic catalysis in regenerating NAD(P)H, the sustainability of enzymes is often compromised, particularly under extreme catalytic conditions. Moreover, artificial cofactors may present advantages in certain reactions due to their stability and versatility, yet the substrate specificity of enzymes poses significant challenges to their regeneration through the enzymatic method. Therefore, it is imperative to develop a highly stable regeneration method that can be adapted to both natural and artificial cofactors. In this work, employing potassium-ion-doped carbon nitride (ionCN-0.2) as a catalyst not only achieves high-efficiency photocatalytic regeneration of NAD(P)H, comparable to that of glucose dehydrogenase (GDH), but also a remarkable ability to regenerate nicotinamide analogues. This enhanced performance stems from the tunable negative &#950;-potential, which effectively adsorbs the positively charged [Cp*Rh(bpy)H2O]2+ mediator, resulting in enhanced regeneration kinetics of the nicotinamide moiety. The catalyst demonstrates superior performance compared to the reported systems; the optimal regeneration rate reaches 0.55 mmol L&#8211;1 gcat&#8211;1 min&#8211;1 and approaches enzymatic regeneration efficiency. Expanding the reaction conditions to a wider temperature and pH range also confirms the effectiveness and sufficient stability of this photocatalytic system, offering a promising strategy for stable cofactor regeneration in biocatalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Zaixiang Xu, Zhongwei Fan, Hanchi Chen, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00841</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Electronic Structure Modulation of Interfacial Oxygen Vacancies Promotes the Oxygen Activation Capacity of Pt/Ce&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;M&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06234</link>
      <description>Weiping Yang, Fuyuan Qi, Wei An, Haochen Yu, Shutong Liu, Peipei Ma, Rui Chen, Shuangxi Liu, Lan&#8208;Lan Lou, Kai Yu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393862387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiping Yang, Fuyuan Qi, Wei An, Haochen Yu, Shutong Liu, Peipei Ma, Rui Chen, Shuangxi Liu, Lan&#8208;Lan Lou, Kai Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Pd-Based Alloys for 1,3-Butadiene Selective Hydrogenation via Equilibrium Models of Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01076</link>
      <description>Jin Liu, Yihao Zhang, Jiao Wei, Jing Zhu, Haoxiang Xu, Daojian Cheng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393870438

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jin Liu, Yihao Zhang, Jiao Wei, Jing Zhu, Haoxiang Xu, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZnO Nanowire Arrays Decorated with Cu Nanoparticles for High-Efficiency Nitrate to Ammonia Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04398</link>
      <description>Anlin Feng, Yunxia Hu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Huaijun Lin, Qian Wang, Jie Xu, Anmin Liu, Gang Wu, Qingyang Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393898872

                The electrocatalytic transformation of waste nitrate into useful ammonia is a "one stone, two birds" strategy, which is commendatory from the viewpoint of the environment. In this vein, developing catalysts with high efficiency, selectivity, and stability is desired to make the attractive technology viable. Herein, we synthesized an economical and scalable electrocatalyst of Cu nanoparticles dispersed onto ZnO nanowire arrays (Cu@ZnO NWA) for nitrate reduction reaction (NO3&#8211;RR). This catalyst constructed on the Cu foam achieved a high ammonia yield of &#8764;6.03 mg cm&#8211;2 h&#8211;1, a Faradaic efficiency of &#8764;89.14%, and good stability for the NO3&#8211;RR in the Ar-saturated 0.1 M KOH electrolyte with the presence of 0.05 M KNO3, superior to most Cu-based catalysts reported in the literature. According to electrochemical measurements and density functional theory calculations, ZnO nanowires offer stable support to accomplish uniform dispersion of Cu nanoparticles and provide a synergy to boost electrocatalytic properties of Cu catalysts. This synergistic effect may originate from the electronic localization at the interface of Cu nanoparticles and ZnO nanowires, resulting in the electron deficiency of the Cu@ZnO NWA surface. Therefore, the promotional mechanisms are associated with enhanced adsorption of the electronegative nitrate ions and boosted charge transfer during the NO3&#8211;RR process. Notably, the Cu@ZnO NWA catalyst can be synthesized on most conductor surfaces through a flexible combination of electrodeposition and hydrothermal techniques, showing good commonality and scalability, thus having a vast industrialization potential for practical application.</description>
      <author>Anlin Feng, Yunxia Hu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Huaijun Lin, Qian Wang, Jie Xu, Anmin Liu, Gang Wu, Qingyang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realizing the 4e&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;/2e&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; Pathway Transition of O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Co&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;C Catalysts by Regulating the Chemical Structures beyond the Second Coordination Shells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00781</link>
      <description>Wang Wang, Yunzi Hu, Peng Li, Yucheng Liu, Shengli Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393940834

                The catalytic performance of single-atom catalysts (SACs) is vitally determined by their coordination environments. So far, the catalytic manipulation of SACs has been mainly focused on the first and second nearest coordination structures of the center atoms. We herein demonstrate that the chemical environments beyond the second coordination shells also significantly influence the catalytic behaviors of SACs. Our findings reveal that the presence of graphitic nitrogen can induce a shift of the O2 reduction pathway on CoN4C sites from an energy-conversion favorite 4e&#8211; pathway to a H2O2-production desirable 2e&#8211; pathway. The remote graphitic N tunes the electronic structure of Co from the lower-spin state to the higher-spin state, as proved by the zero-field cooling (ZFC) temperature-dependent magnetic susceptibility, which weakens the adsorption of O2/*OOH, ultimately enhancing the selectivity toward H2O2. It is further revealed that the catalytic influence of graphitic N may be universally present in other SACs such as FeN4C and MnN4C. Impressively, the graphitic N-doped CoN4C exhibits a high H2O2 Faraday efficiency (82%) in a flow cell, with a remarkable H2O2 yield of 0.096 mmol cm&#8211;2 h&#8211;1 for 200 h at 0.358 V (vs RHE), which is sufficient for many applications such as the electro-Fenton-like degradation of the malachite green and demonstrated the feasibility of H2O2 electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Wang Wang, Yunzi Hu, Peng Li, Yucheng Liu, Shengli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i007_1787822</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393982452

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i007_1787822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i007_1787821</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393990563

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i007_1787821</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
