<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 01:14:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Oxygen Vacancy-Promoted Synthesis of Aminoarenes from Nitroarenes Using Waste H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S as a &#8220;Hydrogen Donor&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02478</link>
      <description>Xiaohai Zheng, Bang Li, Rui Huang, Weiping Jiang, Lijuan Shen, Ganchang Lei, Shiping Wang, Shiping Wang, Lilong Jiang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399916695

                The conversion of H2S to high-value-added products is appealing for alleviating environmental pollution and realizing resource utilization. Herein, we report the reduction of nitrobenzene to aniline using waste H2S as a "hydrogen donor" over the catalyst of FeCeO2&#8722;&#948; with abundant oxygen vacancies (Ov), especially an asymmetric oxygen vacancy (ASOv). The electron-rich nature of the ASOv sites facilitates electron transfer to the electron-deficient nitro group, promoting the adsorption and activation of Ph&#8211;NO2 through the elongation and cleavage of the N&#8211;O bond. Benefiting from the formation of abundant ASOv sites, the resulting FeCeO2&#8722;&#948; achieves an impressive 85.6% Ph&#8211;NO2 conversion and 81.9% Ph&#8211;NH2 selectivity at 1.5 MPa and 90 &#176;C, which surpasses that of pure CeO2 with flower and rod morphologies. In situ FT-IR measurements combined with density functional theory calculations have elucidated a plausible reaction mechanism and a rate-limiting step in the hydrogenation of Ph&#8211;NO2 by H2S.</description>
      <author>Xiaohai Zheng, Bang Li, Rui Huang, Weiping Jiang, Lijuan Shen, Ganchang Lei, Shiping Wang, Shiping Wang, Lilong Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Conundrum of &#8220;Pair Sites&#8221; in Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood Reaction Kinetics in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02813</link>
      <description>Daniyal Kiani, Israel E. Wachs, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399916760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniyal Kiani, Israel E. Wachs</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Hydrogenation of Quinizarins to Leuco-quinizarins and Their Direct Derivatization Using Flow-Batch-Separator Unified Reactors under Continuous-Flow Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02955</link>
      <description>Hiroyuki Miyamura, Aditya Sharma, Masasuke Takata, Rokuro Kajiyama, Sh&#363; Kobayashi, Yoshihiro Kon, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399933284

                Anthraquinone derivatives are classes of compounds employed in the production of valuable materials. Leuco-quinizarin, the 2-electron-reduced form of quinizarin (1,4-dihydroxy-anthraquinone), is a highly active and useful reactant for the synthesis of variety of anthraquinone derivatives. However, conventional methods of leuco-quinizarin synthesis require stoichiometric amounts of inorganic reductants and acids or bases. We developed Pt/DMPSi-Al2O3 and Pt-Ni/DMPSi-Al2O3 as highly active and selective heterogeneous catalysts for the hydrogenation of quinizarins to leuco-quinizarins under neutral and continuous-flow conditions. Remarkably, bimetallic effects of Ni and Pt nanoparticle systems were highlighted in the selective hydrogenation of the substituted quinizarin. In addition, the continuous-flow synthesis of leuco-quinizarin and its derivatization reaction were integrated to be a fully continuous process using flow-batch-separator unified reactors.</description>
      <author>Hiroyuki Miyamura, Aditya Sharma, Masasuke Takata, Rokuro Kajiyama, Sh&#363; Kobayashi, Yoshihiro Kon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02955</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hexa-Fe(III) Carboxylate Complexes Facilitate Aerobic Hydrocarbon Oxidative Functionalization: Rh Catalyzed Oxidative Coupling of Benzene and Ethylene to Form Styrene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02355</link>
      <description>Marc T. Bennett, K. Park, Charles B. Musgrave, Jack W. Brubaker, Diane A. Dickie, William A. Goddard, T. Brent Gunnoe, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399938552

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marc T. Bennett, K. Park, Charles B. Musgrave, Jack W. Brubaker, Diane A. Dickie, William A. Goddard, T. Brent Gunnoe</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy between Br&#248;nsted Acid Sites and Carbonaceous Deposits during Skeletal 1-Butene Isomerization over Ferrierite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01898</link>
      <description>Karoline L. Hebisch, Risha Goel, Kinga Go&#322;&#261;&#808;bek, Pawel A. Chmielniak, Carsten Sievers, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399970689

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karoline L. Hebisch, Risha Goel, Kinga Go&#322;&#261;&#808;bek, Pawel A. Chmielniak, Carsten Sievers</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micellar N-Heterocyclic Carbene-like Organic Catalysis from Polymeric Nanoreactors Immobilizing Benzimidazolium Acetate Motifs in Their Core</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00259</link>
      <description>Anne-Laure Wirotius, Romain Lambert, Thomas Dard&#233;, Simon Harrisson, Daniel Taton, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399977853

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anne-Laure Wirotius, Romain Lambert, Thomas Dard&#233;, Simon Harrisson, Daniel Taton</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Electroreduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Alcohols Using Graphitic Frustrated Lewis Pair Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04275</link>
      <description>Hyun-Tak Kim, Jaehyun Park, Jinhong Mun, HyeonOh Shin, Deok&#8208;Ho Roh, Junhyeok Kwon, Sung&#8208;Tae Kim, Sang-Joon Kim, Geunsik Lee, Seok Ju Kang, Tae&#8208;Hyuk Kwon, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399993700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyun-Tak Kim, Jaehyun Park, Jinhong Mun, HyeonOh Shin, Deok&#8208;Ho Roh, Junhyeok Kwon, Sung&#8208;Tae Kim, Sang-Joon Kim, Geunsik Lee, Seok Ju Kang, Tae&#8208;Hyuk Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Stable Production of Long-Chain Hydrocarbons over Hydrophobic Carbon-Encapsulated TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported Ru Catalyst in Fischer&#8211;Tropsch Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02979</link>
      <description>Yunhao Liu, Xincheng Li, Qingpeng Cheng, Ye Tian, Yingtian Zhang, Tao Ding, Song Song, Kepeng Song, Xingang Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400000990

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunhao Liu, Xincheng Li, Qingpeng Cheng, Ye Tian, Yingtian Zhang, Tao Ding, Song Song, Kepeng Song, Xingang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02979</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alleviating Charge Recombination Caused by Unfavorable interaction of P and Sn in Hematite for Photoelectrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01150</link>
      <description>Ji-Hun Kang, Balaji G. Ghule, Seung Gyu Gyeong, Seong&#8208;Ji Ha, Ji&#8208;Hyun Jang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400001152

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ji-Hun Kang, Balaji G. Ghule, Seung Gyu Gyeong, Seong&#8208;Ji Ha, Ji&#8208;Hyun Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Three-Dimensional Azo-Bridged Porous Porphyrin Framework Supported Silver Nanoparticles as the State-of-the-Art Catalyst for the Carboxylative Cyclization of Propargylic Alcohols with CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; under Ambient Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02391</link>
      <description>Yiying Yang, Yingyin Li, Yinghua Lu, Zhiyuan Chen, Rongchang Luo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400002724

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiying Yang, Yingyin Li, Yinghua Lu, Zhiyuan Chen, Rongchang Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02391</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical NADH Regeneration Mediated by Pyridine Amidate Iridium Complexes Interconverting 1,4- and 1,6-NADH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02548</link>
      <description>Caterina Trotta, Gabriel Menendez Rodriguez, Cristiano Zuccaccia, Alceo Macchioni, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400007176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Caterina Trotta, Gabriel Menendez Rodriguez, Cristiano Zuccaccia, Alceo Macchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Performance through Si-Doped CuO: Stabilization of Cu&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;/Cu&lt;sup&gt;0&lt;/sup&gt; Sites and Improved C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Product Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01961</link>
      <description>Long Cheng, Rong Wang, Wenzhe Si, Yanxi Deng, Junhua Li, Yue Peng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400010017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Long Cheng, Rong Wang, Wenzhe Si, Yanxi Deng, Junhua Li, Yue Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass-Transfer Enhancement in the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxidative Dehydrogenation of Propane over GaN Supported on Zeolite Nanosheets with a Short &lt;i&gt;b&lt;/i&gt;-Axis and Hierarchical Pores</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02599</link>
      <description>Zhan&#8208;Jun Zhu, Zhen&#8208;Hong He, Yajie Tian, Sen-Wang Wang, Yongchang Sun, Kuan Wang, Weitao Wang, Zhifang Zhang, Jiajie Liu, Zhao&#8208;Tie Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400019116

                The CO2 oxidative dehydrogenation of propane (CO2&#8211;ODHP) is a highly important reaction for not only producing large amounts of propylene but also consuming the CO2 resource. GaN/zeolite catalysts deliver preferable activity in the reaction. However, similar to Pt- and Cr-based catalysts, there are shortcomings such as poor stability and coke accumulation, especially when operated at temperatures higher than 550 &#176;C. Generally, carbon deposition is one of the main reasons for catalyst deactivation. The limited mass transfer greatly aggravates the deposited carbon formation, since carbon precursors could not be removed in time. In the present work, we modified zeolites with a short b-axis and hierarchical pores, which could offer a shorter diffusion distance and pore-rich structure to enhance the mass transfer. Thanks to this enhancement, the catalyst offers an initial propane conversion of 68.0% with a yield of 39.4% to propylene, surpassing other reported GaN/zeolite catalysts to data. Importantly, the catalyst showed a low loss rate of activity and a low amount of deposited carbon, which was easily regenerated compared with those of other catalysts without a short b-axis or hierarchical pores. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations and in situ diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS) confirmed that the reaction involves a coupling reaction of direct dehydrogenation and CO2 reduction via reverse water&#8211;gas shift reaction, and CO2 participates in the reaction. The present work sheds light on designing an efficient catalyst for CO2&#8211;ODHP via a mass transfer-boosted strategy and, importantly, is expected to provide inspiration in constructing a zeolite with a short b-axis and hierarchical pores.</description>
      <author>Zhan&#8208;Jun Zhu, Zhen&#8208;Hong He, Yajie Tian, Sen-Wang Wang, Yongchang Sun, Kuan Wang, Weitao Wang, Zhifang Zhang, Jiajie Liu, Zhao&#8208;Tie Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate Turnover Dynamics Guide Ketol-Acid Reductoisomerase Redesign for Increased Specific Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01446</link>
      <description>Elijah Karvelis, Carl V. Swanson, Bruce Tidor, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400026423

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elijah Karvelis, Carl V. Swanson, Bruce Tidor</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics and Mechanism of Integrated Catalytic Ammonolysis and Dehydration from Methyl Salicylate over ZnAl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Spinel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01477</link>
      <description>Wei Yu, Zhuo-Ling Xie, Zhen Zeng, Chengcheng Li, J. M. An, Qingqing Hao, Huibin Ge, Huiyong Chen, Xiaoxun Ma, Qun&#8208;Xing Luo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400030614

                A kinetic and mechanistic study of direct catalytic nitrilation from methyl salicylate and ammonia is conducted by using an amphoteric ZnAl2O4 spinel as a model catalyst. This overall process integrates the catalytic ammonolysis of esters with the dehydration of amides, proceeding stepwise over the concerted Lewis acid&#8211;base pairs of Zn&#8211;O&#8211;Al linkages. The chemisorption and activation of C&#8211;O bonds of the ester over Lewis acid&#8211;base pairs facilitate the leaving of the methoxy group, while Lewis basic oxygen (Zn&#8211;O*&#8211;Al) serves as the main hub station for multistep proton transportation, thus leading to the decreased apparent activation energy of nitrilation and ammonolysis. The combined experimental and computational evidence confirms that this direct nitrilation process follows a monomolecular surface adsorption model, i.e., the Eley&#8211;Rideal mechanism, involving eight elementary reaction steps in which chemisorbed surface species of methyl salicylate react with gaseous NH3 molecules via nucleophilic addition&#8211;elimination and multistep proton transfer to generate amides and nitriles in sequence. Microkinetic model discrimination and DFT calculations reveal that the formation of chemisorbed imine (C&#9552;N&#8211;H) via proton transfer from the Lewis basic oxygen atom (Zn&#8211;O*&#8211;Al) to the carbonyl oxygen (C&#9552;O*) is the rate-determining step, thereby providing a potential consideration of protonation and deprotonation ability to rationally design an improved catalyst.</description>
      <author>Wei Yu, Zhuo-Ling Xie, Zhen Zeng, Chengcheng Li, J. M. An, Qingqing Hao, Huibin Ge, Huiyong Chen, Xiaoxun Ma, Qun&#8208;Xing Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Key Loop: Enhancing &lt;scp&gt;l&lt;/scp&gt;-Threonine Transaldolase&#8217;s Catalytic Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02049</link>
      <description>Zhiwen Xi, Jingxin Rao, Xinyi Zhang, Zhiyong Liu, Mingyue Zheng, Lihong Li, Wenchi Zhang, Yan Xu, Rongzhen Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400030623

                l-Threonine transaldolase (LTTA) is an attractive biocatalyst because of its potential diastereoselectivity in the synthesis of &#946;-hydroxy-&#945;-amino acids (&#946;HAAs). However, prospective development of LTTA has been hampered by its low activity. Here, a combination of techniques involving structural comparison, computational analysis, Loop deletion, and alanine scanning was used to identify a key Loop region (Loop 1) regulating the catalytic ability of Chitiniphilus shinanonensis LTTA (CsLTTA). Saturation mutagenesis and iterative saturation mutagenesis at the hot spots in Loop 1 were performed, and the best variant containing an F70T/C57Q/Y69T (TQT) triple mutation was screened. The diastereoisomer excess (de) produced by the TQT variant (95.4%syn) was greater than that produced by the wild-type (WT) enzyme (75.2%syn), and the catalytic efficiency (kcat/Km) of the TQT variant was four times higher than that of the wild-type enzyme. Molecular dynamics simulations, metadynamics simulations, and CAVER analysis revealed the critical role of the Loop 1 structure in regulating the hydrogen bond network and thus reshaping the active-site pocket to control the syn-tunnel direction. Further engineering of Loop 1 in ObiH, an LTTA responsible for obafluorin biosynthesis, resulted in the development of the F70T-C57Q-H69T (ObiH-TQT) variant producing a de of 97%syn. Using the ObiH-TQT variant for kilogram-scale synthesis of l-syn-p-methylsulfonylphenylserine, coupled with acetaldehyde elimination, resulted in space&#8211;time yields of up to 12.7 g L&#8211;1 h&#8211;1. The method achieved 98.3% substrate conversion and 99.2%syn de within 6 h, marking the highest reported levels to date. The above findings will contribute to the industrial production of &#946;-hydroxy-&#945;-amino acids, offer insights into the mechanism of Loop regions regulating the catalytic function of LTTAs, and provide ideas for engineering other enzymes.</description>
      <author>Zhiwen Xi, Jingxin Rao, Xinyi Zhang, Zhiyong Liu, Mingyue Zheng, Lihong Li, Wenchi Zhang, Yan Xu, Rongzhen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Direct Z-Scheme Single-Atom MOC/COF Piezo-Photocatalytic System for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02243</link>
      <description>Zizhan Liang, Xinao Li, Qing Chen, Xiaotian Wang, Peiyang Su, Jianfeng Huang, Yecheng Zhou, Limin Xiao, Jun&#8208;Min Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400031336

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zizhan Liang, Xinao Li, Qing Chen, Xiaotian Wang, Peiyang Su, Jianfeng Huang, Yecheng Zhou, Limin Xiao, Jun&#8208;Min Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia Driven by a Few Nanometer-Confined Built-In Electric Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02317</link>
      <description>Maolin Zhang, Zedong Zhang, Shaolong Zhang, Zechao Zhuang, Kepeng Song, Karthik Paramaiah, Moyu Yi, Hao Huang, Dingsheng Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400037159

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maolin Zhang, Zedong Zhang, Shaolong Zhang, Zechao Zhuang, Kepeng Song, Karthik Paramaiah, Moyu Yi, Hao Huang, Dingsheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergetic Ni&#8211;Ce Active Sites in Mixed Cerium/Zirconium Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Nodes for Selective Methane Oxidation into Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02883</link>
      <description>Wahida Begum, Manav Chauhan, Manav Chauhan, Priyanka Gupta, Naved Akhtar, Neha Antil, Rajashree Newar, Kuntal Manna, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400040958

                The direct oxidation of methane into ethanol with high productivity under mild conditions is a grand challenge. We report the development of mixed cerium/zirconium metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) nodes-supported mononuclear nickel(II)-hydroxyl species [Cex/Zry&#8211;UiO&#8211;Ni(OH)] as efficient heterogeneous catalysts for direct transformation of methane into ethanol. The Ni2+ ion in Cex/Zry&#8211;UiO&#8211;Ni(OH) MOFs coordinates with a &#956;4&#8211;O&#8211;, one hydroxy group, and two neutral carboxylate oxygens, which are directly bonded to the Ce4+ ion at the mixed metal-oxo nodes. The spectroscopic and control experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that the precise composition of the mixed-metal node, the isolation of mono Ni-hydroxyl species at the node, and the cooperative Ni&#8211;Ce active sites confined within the porous UiO-MOFs promote the facile C&#8211;H activation of methane at 80 &#176;C, leading to the formation of &#8226;CH3 radicals and subsequent C&#8211;C coupling within the pores to produce ethanol in an extraordinarily high yield of 6521 mmol gNi&#8211;1 with &gt;93% selectivity, outperforming most of the current reports. Our mechanistic investigation suggests that the direct methane oxidation into ethanol proceeds via a dual catalytic cycle, in which the doping of Ce4+ ion within MOF's node and the proximity between Ce4+ and Ni2+ ions lead to the reversible Ce&#8211;Ocarboxylate bond dissociation and Ni&#8211;(&#956;2&#8211;OH)&#8211;Ce bond formation, which is the key for efficient formation of &#8226;CH3 radical in the turnover limiting step. This work highlights the importance of mixed metal-MOFs in designing well-defined heterobimetallic-supported catalysts for the valorization of methane and light alkanes via cooperative catalysis.</description>
      <author>Wahida Begum, Manav Chauhan, Manav Chauhan, Priyanka Gupta, Naved Akhtar, Neha Antil, Rajashree Newar, Kuntal Manna</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Luminescence Performances of Silicon-Doped Carbon Dots Contribute to Copper-Catalyzed photoATRP?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02203</link>
      <description>Mengjie Zhou, Su Xu, Wenjie Zhang, Ge Shi, Yanjie He, Xiaoguang Qiao, Xinchang Pang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400041360

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengjie Zhou, Su Xu, Wenjie Zhang, Ge Shi, Yanjie He, Xiaoguang Qiao, Xinchang Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;Cine-&lt;/i&gt;Substitution of Enolates: Enolate Dance/Coupling of Cycloalkenyl Pivalates by Nickel Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02707</link>
      <description>Eito Moriya, Kei Muto, Junichiro Yamaguchi, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400047375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eito Moriya, Kei Muto, Junichiro Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture and Electrochemical Reduction of Low-Concentration CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Using a Re(I)-Complex Catalyst in Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01120</link>
      <description>Masahiko Miyaji, Yusuke Tamaki, Kei Kamogawa, Yuto Abiru, Manabu Abe, Osamu Ishitani, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400051414

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Masahiko Miyaji, Yusuke Tamaki, Kei Kamogawa, Yuto Abiru, Manabu Abe, Osamu Ishitani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Aerobic Oxidation of Hydroxyl Compounds Catalyzed by Dimeric &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Salicylidene Oxovanadium Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02766</link>
      <description>Xiaomeng Fan, Jiping Ma, Min Wang, Mingxia Gao, Jie Xu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400078694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaomeng Fan, Jiping Ma, Min Wang, Mingxia Gao, Jie Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Interfacial Hydrogen-Bond Environment by Electrolyte Engineering Promotes Acidic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02916</link>
      <description>Wangxin Ge, Longlong Dong, Chaochen Wang, Yihua Zhu, Zhen Liu, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400092381

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wangxin Ge, Longlong Dong, Chaochen Wang, Yihua Zhu, Zhen Liu, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Catalytic Performance of Metal Hydrides for Reversible Hydrogen Storage in N-ethylcarbazole by Electronic Structure and Hydrogen Chemical Potential Tuning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02947</link>
      <description>Haoming Yu, Zichang Zhang, Xu Jin, Xi Zhang, Kuerbangnisha Kadeer, Y. M. Lin, Zewei Xie, Yushen Huang, T Liu, Kuerbangnisha Kadeer, Qiang Sun, Jianlong Zheng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400093131

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoming Yu, Zichang Zhang, Xu Jin, Xi Zhang, Kuerbangnisha Kadeer, Y. M. Lin, Zewei Xie, Yushen Huang, T Liu, Kuerbangnisha Kadeer, Qiang Sun, Jianlong Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-HCOOH Electroreduction on Graphdiyne-Supported Bimetallic Single-Cluster Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00858</link>
      <description>Bin Chen, Yafei Jiang, Hai Xiao, Jun Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400093530

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Chen, Yafei Jiang, Hai Xiao, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese-Catalyzed Synthesis of Polyketones Using Hydrogen-Borrowing Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03019</link>
      <description>Pavel S. Kulyabin, Oxana V. Magdysyuk, Aaron B. Naden, Daniel M. Dawson, Ketan Pancholi, Matthew Walker, Massimo Vassalli, Amit Kumar, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400111554

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pavel S. Kulyabin, Oxana V. Magdysyuk, Aaron B. Naden, Daniel M. Dawson, Ketan Pancholi, Matthew Walker, Massimo Vassalli, Amit Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Electrochemical Methane Oxidation Mechanism through the In Situ Detection of Reaction Intermediates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00675</link>
      <description>Tareq A. Al&#8208;Attas, Kannimuthu Karthick, Mohd Adnan Khan, Md Golam Kibria, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400111866

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tareq A. Al&#8208;Attas, Kannimuthu Karthick, Mohd Adnan Khan, Md Golam Kibria</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Career in Catalysis: Enrique Iglesia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02557</link>
      <description>David G. Barton, Aditya Bhan, Prashant Deshlahra, Rajamani Gounder, David Hibbitts, Beata A. Kilos, Gina Noh, Justin M. Notestein, Michele L. Sarazen, S. Soled, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400112900

                No abstract</description>
      <author>David G. Barton, Aditya Bhan, Prashant Deshlahra, Rajamani Gounder, David Hibbitts, Beata A. Kilos, Gina Noh, Justin M. Notestein, Michele L. Sarazen, S. Soled</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02557</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient and Selective Nitrogen Reduction Reaction Catalysis of Cluster-Modified MXene Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01369</link>
      <description>Yu Rong, Zhaorui Liu, Dominik Legut, J. Sun, Qianfan Zhang, Joseph S. Francisco, Ruifang Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400119996

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Rong, Zhaorui Liu, Dominik Legut, J. Sun, Qianfan Zhang, Joseph S. Francisco, Ruifang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Photocatalytic Activity of CaTaO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N for Overall Water Splitting through Surface Nitride Ion Enrichment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01590</link>
      <description>Xuecheng Liu, Linjie Yan, Wenpeng Li, Kaihong Chen, Faze Wang, Jiadong Xiao, Takashi Hisatomi, Tsuyoshi Takata, Kazunari Domen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400123390

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuecheng Liu, Linjie Yan, Wenpeng Li, Kaihong Chen, Faze Wang, Jiadong Xiao, Takashi Hisatomi, Tsuyoshi Takata, Kazunari Domen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Radical-Type 1,2-Alkoxy-Sulfenylation of Benzoxazole-2-Thiols to Vinylarenes Catalyzed by Chiral Vanadyl Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02460</link>
      <description>Yueh-Hua Liu, Hon&#8208;Chung Tsui, Pei-Hsuan Chien, Chien&#8208;Tien Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400129690

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yueh-Hua Liu, Hon&#8208;Chung Tsui, Pei-Hsuan Chien, Chien&#8208;Tien Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02460</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
