<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:44:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Pathways to the Formation of C&#8211;N Bonds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04912</link>
      <description>Dimitra Anastasiadou, Marta Costa Figueiredo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392975696

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dimitra Anastasiadou, Marta Costa Figueiredo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Catalyzed Mono- and Dihydrosilylation of Aliphatic Alkynes in Aqueous and Aerobic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00109</link>
      <description>Chanmi Lee, Ji Hwan Jeon, Soochan Lee, Wonyoung Choe, Jaesung Kwak, Sangwon Seo, Sung You Hong, Byunghyuck Jung, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392985422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chanmi Lee, Ji Hwan Jeon, Soochan Lee, Wonyoung Choe, Jaesung Kwak, Sangwon Seo, Sung You Hong, Byunghyuck Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alteration of Hydrodeoxygenation Pathways of Ni/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-A Catalyst through Controlled Regulation of Strong Metal&#8211;Support Interactions and Surface Acidity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00480</link>
      <description>Qi Fang, Hong Du, Xiaoqiang Zhang, Yunjie Ding, Z. Conrad Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392999569

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Fang, Hong Du, Xiaoqiang Zhang, Yunjie Ding, Z. Conrad Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Catalyzed Inter- and Intramolecular Reductive Cross-Coupling Reactions of Arylbenzylammonium Salts through Highly Site-Selective C&#8211;N Bond Cleavage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00504</link>
      <description>Ren-Gui Tian, Longyu Wang, Lei Zheng, Shi&#8208;Kai Tian, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393002326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ren-Gui Tian, Longyu Wang, Lei Zheng, Shi&#8208;Kai Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-Based Principal Component Analysis Followed by Ridge Regression: Application to an Asymmetric Negishi Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06230</link>
      <description>H. Ray Kelly, Sanil Sreekumar, Vidhyadhar Manee, Abbigayle Cuomo, Timothy R. Newhouse, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric G. Buono, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393006540

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Ray Kelly, Sanil Sreekumar, Vidhyadhar Manee, Abbigayle Cuomo, Timothy R. Newhouse, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric G. Buono</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06230</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atroposelective Construction of Carbon&#8211;Boron Axial Chirality through Rh-Catalyzed [2 + 2 + 2] Cycloaddition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00428</link>
      <description>Yu Ping, Xiaofan Shi, Ming Lei, Jianbo Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393026019

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Ping, Xiaofan Shi, Ming Lei, Jianbo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regioselective 1,&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;-Diborylation of Alkylidenecyclopropanes Enabled by Catalysis with a Spirocyclic NHC Ir&lt;sup&gt;III&lt;/sup&gt; Pincer Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00260</link>
      <description>Weifeng Wang, Ka Lu, Peng-Rui Liu, Hui-Hui Zeng, Li&#8211;Miao Yang, Ai&#8208;Jun Ma, Yong&#8208;Qiang Tu, Jin&#8208;Bao Peng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393039483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weifeng Wang, Ka Lu, Peng-Rui Liu, Hui-Hui Zeng, Li&#8211;Miao Yang, Ai&#8208;Jun Ma, Yong&#8208;Qiang Tu, Jin&#8208;Bao Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxide Structure-Dependent OH Promotion Mechanism over a Hydroxylated CoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;/Pt(111) Catalyst toward CO Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01084</link>
      <description>Dongqing Wang, Rongtan Li, Xiangyu Sun, Le Lin, Kun Li, Rankun Zhang, Rentao Mu, Qiang Fu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393040749

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongqing Wang, Rongtan Li, Xiangyu Sun, Le Lin, Kun Li, Rankun Zhang, Rentao Mu, Qiang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Enantioselective Synthesis of Inherently Chiral Macrocycles by Dynamic Kinetic Resolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00598</link>
      <description>Qi L&#252;, Xudong Wang, Shuo Tong, Jieping Zhu, Mei&#8208;Xiang Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393045444

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi L&#252;, Xudong Wang, Shuo Tong, Jieping Zhu, Mei&#8208;Xiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-dependent Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia on Janus Cu@Ni Tandem Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00479</link>
      <description>Yao&#8208;Yin Lou, Qizheng Zheng, Shiyuan Zhou, Jia-Yi Fang, Ouardia Akdim, Xingyu Ding, Rena Oh, Gyeong-Su Park, Xiaoyang Huang, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393054884

                Electrosynthesis of NH3 from nitrate anion (NO3&#8211;) reduction (NO3&#8211;RR) is a cascade reaction, which is considered a great potential alternative to the Haber&#8211;Bosch route to reduce CO2 emissions and alleviate the adverse effects of excessive NO3&#8211; contamination in the environment. Frequently, solid solution alloys (SSAs) with a single-phase active site may struggle to fully utilize their benefits during the entire process of nitrate (NO3&#8211;) reduction, which involves multiple intermediate reactions. In this study, we showed that by separating Cu and Ni in a Janus Cu@Ni catalyst structure, we can achieve high performance in NO3&#8211;RR, yielding a high Faradaic efficiency (92.5%) and a production rate of NH3 (1127 mmol h&#8211;1 g&#8211;1) at &#8722;0.2 V versus RHE, compared to CuNi SSA (82.6%, 264 mmol h&#8211;1 g&#8211;1). Here, we demonstrate that a Janus Cu@Ni catalyst with short-range ordered catalytic sites favors the adsorption of NO through a bridge-bond mode. Simultaneously, a hydrogen spillover process was observed, in which Ni dissociates H2O to generate *H which spontaneously migrates to adjacent catalytic sites to hydrogenate the *NOx intermediates. This facilitates N&#8211;O bond cleavage, resulting in the NH3 production rate nearly 5 times higher than that of CuNi SSA, where NO was linearly bonded on its surface. The study of this catalytic effect, a cooperative tandem enhancement, provides insights into the design of multifunctional heterogeneous catalysts for electrochemical NH3 synthesis.</description>
      <author>Yao&#8208;Yin Lou, Qizheng Zheng, Shiyuan Zhou, Jia-Yi Fang, Ouardia Akdim, Xingyu Ding, Rena Oh, Gyeong-Su Park, Xiaoyang Huang, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible Hydrogenation of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Formamides Using an Atomically Dispersed Ir/C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00751</link>
      <description>Danyang Cheng, Maolin Wang, Shixiang Yu, Mi Peng, Wu Zhou, Wulin Yang, Meng Wang, Ding Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393054890

                The utilization of different energy carriers to efficiently store and release energy plays a vital role in the pursuit of a renewable energy paradigm. In this context, we present an interesting system utilizing morpholine as a dual-functional agent in the reversible hydrogenation of CO2 to formamides employing an atomically dispersed iridium (Ir) catalyst. Morpholine serves as a stabilizer during CO2 hydrogenation and a CO2 capture agent during dehydrogenation, enabling a carbon-neutral cycle for hydrogen storage. Notably, these reversible cycles could be facilitated by the same catalyst and maintained under identical temperature conditions by a simple H2 pressure swing. The robustness of this system is underscored by its consistent performance across multiple charging&#8211;discharging cycles without a noticeable reduction in the storage capacity. Additionally, the Ir catalyst exhibits strong CO tolerance during hydrogenation, making it suitable for purifying crude hydrogen via the reversible process.</description>
      <author>Danyang Cheng, Maolin Wang, Shixiang Yu, Mi Peng, Wu Zhou, Wulin Yang, Meng Wang, Ding Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloroiridium Complexes of Biaryl-Based Diphosphines for Thermal Catalytic Transfer Dehydrogenation of Hindered 1,1-Disubstituted Ethanes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00312</link>
      <description>Yirong Wu, Haofeng Xu, Kuan Wang, Guixia Liu, Lan Gan, Zheng Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393054959

                Thermal catalytic dehydrogenation of congested alkanes, such as the 1,1-disubstituted ethane (1,1-DSE) motif, is still a largely unsolved challenge. Herein, we report the investigation of biaryl-based atropisomeric diphosphines with various electronic and steric properties and their corresponding chloroiridium complexes for catalytic transfer dehydrogenation (CTD) of 1,1-DSEs using tert-butylethene as H-acceptor. The use of diphosphines of the biaryl backbone with a narrow dihedral angle was found to be essential to forming an effective catalytic species, cis-P2ClIr. A systematic investigation of three atropisomeric diphosphine classes, Segphos, MeO-Biphep, and Binap, revealed that the sterically hindered and electron-rich ligands are more efficient than the less hindered and electron-deficient ones. With an understanding of the structure&#8211;activity relationships, we developed two highly encumbered ligands 3,5-TMS,4-MeOMeO-Biphep (M12) and 3-TIPS,5-TMSMeO-Biphep (M13), which afforded &gt;1400 turnovers at 150 &#176;C in the cumene/TBE CTD reaction, representing the most efficient catalyst for thermal catalytic dehydrogenation of 1,1-DSEs. Moreover, these two ligands produced &#8764;420 turnovers in the CTD of 2-(1-adamantyl)propane, demonstrating their ability in dehydrogenation of unactivated hindered dialkyl-substituted ethanes.</description>
      <author>Yirong Wu, Haofeng Xu, Kuan Wang, Guixia Liu, Lan Gan, Zheng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-Driven Ce-MnO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;/Na&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;WO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Composite Catalysts for Low-Temperature Oxidative Coupling of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06301</link>
      <description>Jiaxin Song, Rong Yu, Xin Gao, Xiaoqiang Fan, Baijun Liu, Zhao Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393055019

                Mn/Na2WO4/SiO2 catalyst is widely used in the oxidative coupling of methane (OCM) reactions because of its high catalytic performance and stability. Nevertheless, the complex elemental composition makes the role of each active component in these catalysts still controversial. Herein, we conducted separate studies on Mn/Na2WO4/SiO2 catalyst by separating it into MnOx and Na2WO4/SiO2 (NaWSi). This provided a persuasive strategy to turn manganese oxide from a combustion catalyst into a selective catalyst for the OCM at low temperatures through a synergistic effect between the Ce-MnOx catalyst and Na2WO4/SiO2 catalyst. The introduction of Ce is a key factor in improving the low-temperature OCM activity of the catalyst. The temperature-programmed desorption of oxygen (O2-TPD) and 18O isotope labeling experiments confirm that surface lattice oxygen is the main active oxygen species in the OCM reaction for the Ce-driven catalyst. The presence of Ce strengthens the surface lattice oxygen cycle process on the catalyst, resulting in higher oxygen exchange ability and improved migration of active lattice oxygen. Furthermore, in situ Raman spectroscopy shows that both 3Ce-MnOx and NaWSi catalysts can enhance resistance to carbon deposition in the catalysts. Hence, the 3Ce-MnOx/NaWSi composite catalyst achieved 38.4% conversion of CH4 and a 15.6% yield of C2 at 700 &#176;C and the catalytic activity remained stable for at least 25 h.</description>
      <author>Jiaxin Song, Rong Yu, Xin Gao, Xiaoqiang Fan, Baijun Liu, Zhao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Value-Added Chemicals from Carbohydrates via C&#8211;C Bond Cleavage and Coupling Transformations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05734</link>
      <description>Rui Zhang, Junhua Zhang, Huai Liu, Zhicheng Jiang, Xudong Li, Qianqian Wang, Lincai Peng, Changwei Hu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393055711

                Renewable carbohydrates are nearly inexhaustible libraries of chemical building blocks, and significant research efforts have been devoted to their valorization to valuable chemicals in the past decades. The commonly recognized main transformation routes include dehydration and C&#8211;C bond cleavage pathways, which lead to the production of conventional platform chemicals such as 5-hydroxymethylfurfural/furfural, lactic acid/lactates, and so on. With the huge availability of carbohydrates on earth, the production of other fine chemicals is very attractive but remains sparse. This Review therefore emphasizes the utilization strategies of carbohydrates based on in situ C&#8211;C bond cleavage to lower carbon fragments, such as glycolaldehyde and erythrose, and their subsequent transformations, e.g. hydrogenation, hydrogenolysis, oxidation, nucleophilic addition, and amination. The isolation of reactive intermediates is avoided, leading to the formation of a variety of "unconventional" useful scaffolds, such as ethylene glycol, ethanol, keto-alcohols, glycolic acid, formic acid, C4 skeleton &#945;-hydroxy esters, N-containing compounds, etc. Inspired by the transformation of active intermediates, the direct conversion of monosugars with similar structures through C&#8211;C coupling to furan-based chemicals is also briefly reviewed. The primary focus of this Review is to show the spectacular range of fine chemicals that can be accessed from carbohydrates via C&#8211;C bond cleavage and coupling approaches. A summary of the reviewed works and some opportunities and challenges within this attractive field are underlined for future research in sugar chemistry.</description>
      <author>Rui Zhang, Junhua Zhang, Huai Liu, Zhicheng Jiang, Xudong Li, Qianqian Wang, Lincai Peng, Changwei Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Metal Catalysts for Catalytic Chemical Conversion of Biomass to Chemicals and Fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00208</link>
      <description>Jiayue Chen, Yao Xiao, Fen Guo, Keming Li, Yao&#8208;Bing Huang, Qiang L&#252;, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393055728

                Among all renewable energy sources (e.g., solar energy, wind, and biomass), biomass is the only organic carbon resource which has great potential to partly replace nonrenewable fossil resources to produce high value-added chemicals and biofuels. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have shown compelling prospects and arguably become one of the most active research fields in biomass chemical catalysis due to their fascinating strengths in maximum atomic utilization, highly efficient catalytic reactivity, high selectivity, and good stability. Numerous achievements about the SACs have recently been amassed, including advanced synthesis methods, characterization techniques, and theoretical calculation, allowing us to forecast their working mechanisms and the catalytic roles of metals and coordination sites in the catalytic process. Based on the relevant literatures on SACs over the past few years, this review summarizes the preparation methods of SACs and their catalysis applications for biomass conversions with a special focus on the structure&#8211;activity relationship and catalytic reaction mechanism as well as prospects for the future developments of SACs. This review provides fundamental information for the development of the SACs in biomass valorization, clearly stimulating the development in this emerging research field.</description>
      <author>Jiayue Chen, Yao Xiao, Fen Guo, Keming Li, Yao&#8208;Bing Huang, Qiang L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Lattice Oxygen in Ceria by Plasma Exsolution of MoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; with Atomic Dispersion for NO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Abatement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00069</link>
      <description>Yong Yin, Bing Luo, Sun Yu, Pengfei Xie, Haifeng Xiong, Tianle Zhu, Xiang Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393084436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Yin, Bing Luo, Sun Yu, Pengfei Xie, Haifeng Xiong, Tianle Zhu, Xiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Electron-Transfer-Generated Aryl Sulfonyl Ammonium Salt: Metal-Free Photoredox-Catalyzed Modular Construction of Sulfonamides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00816</link>
      <description>Fang Yan, Qing Li, Songzhe Fu, Yadong Yang, Dehong Yang, Shuang Yao, Man Ki Song, Hong Deng, Xianwei Sui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393093155

                Sulfonamides are prominently featured in organic synthesis and medicinal chemistry. Yet, a general synthetic platform for the modular construction of aryl sulfonamides remains elusive. Herein, a metal-free photoredox-catalyzed three-component construction of aryl sulfonamides via an aryl sulfonyl ammonium salt intermediate, which was generated in situ via a SET event, has been established. A variety of structurally diverse primary, secondary, and tertiary aryl sulfonamides were synthesized rapidly from abundant amines or sodium azide under mild conditions. Notably, the primary aliphatic amine, which remains challenging in the Cu-catalyzed protocols, worked well in this approach. Moreover, aryl sulfonyl fluoride can be accessed smoothly as well, using potassium hydrogen fluoride as the nucleophile. The potential utility of this conversion is demonstrated in the facile construction of three bioactive drug compounds. Preliminary mechanistic studies have revealed that the aryl sulfonyl radical and aryl sulfonyl ammonium salt are the key intermediates in this mechanistically innovative methodology.</description>
      <author>Fang Yan, Qing Li, Songzhe Fu, Yadong Yang, Dehong Yang, Shuang Yao, Man Ki Song, Hong Deng, Xianwei Sui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Splitting Integrated with Self-Transfer Hydrogenolysis for Efficient Demethoxylation of Guaiacols to Phenols over the Ni/MgO Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00038</link>
      <description>Xiaohong Ren, Qiang Qian, Zhuohua Sun, Ting Wei, Xiaoqiang Yu, Zeming Rong, Changzhi Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393097258

                This work demonstrates the upgrading of lignin-derived monomers through a cascade demethoxylation, aqueous-phase reforming reaction, eliminating the need for external hydrogen supply. The core of this research lies in the use of neat water as both reaction medium and the hydrogen donor over a multifunctional Ni/MgO catalyst, which is responsible for water splitting, aqueous-phase reforming of in situ generated methanol, and selective cleavage of the C&#8211;O bond, finally establishing an efficient one-pot approach achieving a high yield of phenols. Reaction mechanism studies proved that the initial H* source came from water by its splitting on the surface of the Ni/MgO catalyst, which triggered the fracture of the aromatic ether bond to afford phenols and CH3O*. The subsequent aqueous-phase reforming of CH3O* and OH* generated more hydrogen and further accelerated the hydrodeoxygenation (HDO) process. A high conversion of 87.8% with a selectivity of 88.9% for phenol could be achieved at 190 &#176;C from guaiacol. Thanks to the interesting water-splitting mechanisms and strong metal&#8211;support interaction (SMSI), Ni/MgO exhibited significantly enhanced stability compared to the previously reported nanoporous Ni catalysts. Further, with real lignin as the substrate, 16.3 wt % combined yield of phenol and 4-methylphenol could be acquired under optimized conditions. Overall, this "H2-free" approach offers a promising alternative to conventional biorefinery processes, addressing the challenges of hydrogen sourcing and economic feasibility.</description>
      <author>Xiaohong Ren, Qiang Qian, Zhuohua Sun, Ting Wei, Xiaoqiang Yu, Zeming Rong, Changzhi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switchable Synthesis of Ethylene/Acrylate Copolymers by a Dinickel Catalyst: Evidence for Chain Growth on Both Nickel Centers and Concepts of Cation Exchange Polymerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00156</link>
      <description>Shuoyan Xiong, Heather A. Spinney, Brad C. Bailey, Briana S. Henderson, Adjeoda A. Tekpor, Matthew R. Espinosa, Paramita Saha, Theodor Agapie, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393157067

                A dinickel complex, X-Ni2, was developed and demonstrated to have a high performance in ethylene/acrylate copolymerization. Further mechanistic studies revealed that X-Ni2 performs acrylate insertion at both Ni centers at distinct rates. Addition of NaBArF24 to X-Ni2 leads to 1:1 binding and serves as a switch for tuning catalytic activity, copolymer MW and acrylate incorporation. NMR studies of cation binding, when present in substoichiometric amounts, suggest a dynamic process involving cation exchange. This phenomenon provides an alternative strategy for controlling chain growth in polar polyolefin synthesis and was probed herein.</description>
      <author>Shuoyan Xiong, Heather A. Spinney, Brad C. Bailey, Briana S. Henderson, Adjeoda A. Tekpor, Matthew R. Espinosa, Paramita Saha, Theodor Agapie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ketyl Radical Generation by Photoexcited Palladium and Development of Organopalladium-Type Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00510</link>
      <description>Kosaku Tanaka, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393162411

                Enabling reactions of traditional substrates that are inert to Pd catalysts has the potential for further advancements in the field of Pd chemistry. In this study, we developed a method for generating ketyl radicals through the reaction of a photoexcited Pd species with ketones. Upon subsequent reaction with olefins, the ketyl radicals generated through this method yielded Pd-specific reductive and Heck-type coupling products. Mechanistic studies indicated that the proposed radical generation method exhibits characteristics distinct from those of traditional methods such as SmI2 reduction and photoredox-catalyzed reactions.</description>
      <author>Kosaku Tanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Photocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Methanation by the Construction of Cooperative Copper Dual-Active Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00060</link>
      <description>Minghui Zhang, Yuyin Mao, Xiaolei Bao, Peng Wang, Yuanyuan Liu, Zhaoke Zheng, Hefeng Cheng, Ying Dai, Zeyan Wang, Baibiao Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393164230

                Selective photocatalytic CO2 methanation provides an attractive avenue to address energy and environmental issues. However, impediments such as the sluggish adsorption and activation of CO2 and H2O molecules, along with unexpected intermediate desorption, greatly restrict the activity and selectivity of photocatalytic CO2 methanation. To address these issues, we devised a dual-active site catalyst comprising Cu single atoms (SAs) and nanoclusters (NCs) supported on defective TiO2 (Cu1+NCs/BT). As a result, a remarkable CH4 selectivity of 98% with a yield of 19.63 &#956;mol gcat.&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 can be obtained over the as-prepared Cu1+NCs/BT in pure water. Mechanistic studies reveal the enhanced performance could be ascribed to the synergistic effect of the Cu dual-active sites, where Cu SAs adsorb and activate CO2, while Cu NCs boost H2O adsorption and dissociation for *H coverage. Additionally, the adjacent Cu dual-active site could jointly stabilize the *CO intermediate and reduce the energy barrier for *CO protonation, promoting the multielectron transfer process.</description>
      <author>Minghui Zhang, Yuyin Mao, Xiaolei Bao, Peng Wang, Yuanyuan Liu, Zhaoke Zheng, Hefeng Cheng, Ying Dai, Zeyan Wang, Baibiao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00060</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
