<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 01:36:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Heptazine-Based Graphitic Carbon Nitride Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting by Effectively Assembling Double-Unit Polymers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05801</link>
      <description>Ruilin Guan, Anqi Shi, Xiuyun Zhang, Bing Wang, Yongtao Li, Xianghong Niu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405039581

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruilin Guan, Anqi Shi, Xiuyun Zhang, Bing Wang, Yongtao Li, Xianghong Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Influence of Carbon Support on the Pyrolysis of Cobalt Phthalocyanine for the Efficient Electroreduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07096</link>
      <description>Johan Hamonnet, Michael S. Bennington, Bernt Johannessen, Jessica L. Hamilton, Paula A. Brooksby, Sally Brooker, Vladimir B. Golovko, Aaron T. Marshall, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405054009

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Johan Hamonnet, Michael S. Bennington, Bernt Johannessen, Jessica L. Hamilton, Paula A. Brooksby, Sally Brooker, Vladimir B. Golovko, Aaron T. Marshall</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07096</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Exploration of Heterogeneous Catalysis with a Gas&#8211;Solid Nanoreactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06026</link>
      <description>Jiawei Bai, Xingchen Liu, Tingyu Lei, Yuwei Zhou, Wenping Guo, Dennis R. Salahub, Xiaodong Wen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405055249

                We present an automated method, gas&#8211;solid nanoreactor molecular dynamics (GS-NMD), designed to explore reaction space and construct reaction networks for complex gas&#8211;solid heterogeneous catalysis systems by integrating multiple acceleration techniques. Periodic pulses were used to drive gas-phase molecules toward the catalyst surface, accelerating adsorption and Eley&#8211;Rideal reactions. Adsorbed species were then subjected to metadynamics to overcome reaction barriers associated with migration, Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood-type reactions, and desorption, using the root-mean-square deviations in Cartesian space as collective variables. We demonstrate the efficiency of GS-NMD with the case of N2 dissociation on Fe surfaces, showing its ability to effectively screen for low-barrier reactions within a vast reaction space and distinct catalysts of different performances. Additionally, we illustrate the method's utility in constructing effective reaction networks for heterogeneous catalysis, exemplified by ammonia synthesis, which comprises only low-barrier elementary steps. These results suggest that GS-NMD is a promising and efficient tool for the automated exploration of heterogeneous catalysis, enabling the identification of the most favorable mechanisms and active sites for gas&#8211;solid reactions.</description>
      <author>Jiawei Bai, Xingchen Liu, Tingyu Lei, Yuwei Zhou, Wenping Guo, Dennis R. Salahub, Xiaodong Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do Variants of Residues in the First Coordination Sphere, Second Coordination Sphere, and Remote Areas Influence the Catalytic Mechanism of Non-Heme Fe(II)/2-Oxoglutarate Dependent Ethylene-Forming Enzyme?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04010</link>
      <description>Midhun George Thomas, Simahudeen Bathir Jaber Sathik Rifayee, Christo Christov, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405057265

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Midhun George Thomas, Simahudeen Bathir Jaber Sathik Rifayee, Christo Christov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Photocatalytic Divergent Decarbonylative Silylation with Cinnamaldehyde via a [Ru(dcbpy)(bpy)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;]&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;-Incorporated UiO-67 Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05535</link>
      <description>Huahui Wang, Bing-Bing Qin, Jiali Cai, Yun Wu, Cong Zhao, Xiao&#8208;Yan Bai, Lu Chen, Yan&#8208;Zhong Fan, Min Zhang, Jiewei Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405075494

                We herein develop an innovative approach for the decarbonylative silylation using a molecular [Ru(dcbpy)(bpy)2]2+ (dcbpy = 2,2&#8242;-bipyridyl-5,5&#8242;-dicarboxylic acid; bpy = 2,2&#8242;-bipyridine) incorporated UiO-67 metal&#8211;organic framework (MOFs) (denoted as UiO-67-Ru) as a powerful heterogeneous catalyst, which is then applied in the reaction of abundantly available cinnamaldehydes with silanes under photothermal condition. Mechanistic studies reveal that the silane can be absorbed and activated within the cavities of the framework, leading to the generation of a silyl radical. The silyl radical plays a key role in the decarbonylative silylation process and further goes through oxidative silylation with cinnamaldehydes to generate the corresponding alkenyl silanes. This work not only develops a strategy for the preparation of alkenyl silane from highly abundant cinnamaldehyde and silanes but also affords useful inspiration on the rational design of MOFs materials for the decarbonylative silylation.</description>
      <author>Huahui Wang, Bing-Bing Qin, Jiali Cai, Yun Wu, Cong Zhao, Xiao&#8208;Yan Bai, Lu Chen, Yan&#8208;Zhong Fan, Min Zhang, Jiewei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shallow Rate-Redox Potential Scaling in Aqueous Molecular Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysis Across a Family of Iron Macrocycles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06561</link>
      <description>Travis Marshall-Roth, Liang Liu, Vennela Mannava, Deiaa M. Harraz, Brian J. Cook, R. Morris Bullock, Yogesh Surendranath, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405089233

                Rate-overpotential scaling relationships have been employed widely to understand trends in oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalysis by dissolved metal macrocycles in organic electrolytes. Similar scaling relationships remain unknown for surface-adsorbed ORR electrocatalysts in the acidic aqueous environments germane to proton-exchange membrane (PEM) fuel cells. Herein, we examine ORR catalysis in aqueous perchloric acid media for a structurally diverse array of iron macrocycle complexes adsorbed on Vulcan carbon black. The macrocycles encompass Fe&#8211;N4, Fe&#8211;N2N&#8242;2 and Fe&#8211;NxC4&#8211;x motifs bearing pyrrolic, pyridinic, and N-heterocyclic carbene (NHC) moieties in the primary ligation sphere, giving rise to a 670 mV range in Fe(III/II) redox potentials, EFe(III/II). Experimental Tafel data in the micropolarization regime were extrapolated to the EFe(III/II) to furnish estimated per-site-normalized current density (jper-site) values that span &#8764;4.6 orders of magnitude across the family of compounds. Despite the structural diversity of this family of compounds, extrapolated jper-site values correlate with the Fe(III/II) redox potentials in a roughly log-linear fashion with a shallow scaling factor of approximately 145 mV/decade. These findings highlight the phenomenology that negative shifts in EFe(III/II) track with diminishing returns in catalytic rate promotion, regardless of the exact ORR mechanism, and suggest that changes to the primary ligating environment in a macrocycle are insufficient to break fundamental rate-potential scaling relationships in aqueous ORR catalysis. Together these studies motivate the further development of higher-potential iron complexes that employ motifs beyond the equatorial ligation plane to enhance ORR catalysis.</description>
      <author>Travis Marshall-Roth, Liang Liu, Vennela Mannava, Deiaa M. Harraz, Brian J. Cook, R. Morris Bullock, Yogesh Surendranath</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Catalyst Restructuring during Catalytic Reforming of CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; by CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05703</link>
      <description>Yu Tang, Xupeng Zong, Luan Nguyen, Franklin Tao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405093687

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Tang, Xupeng Zong, Luan Nguyen, Franklin Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag-Regulated Interfacial Electron Transfer between TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and MoS&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; for Enhanced H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05674</link>
      <description>Xidong Zhang, Jiachao Xu, Haoyu Long, Jiaguo Yu, Huogen Yu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405104681

                The electronic configuration mismatch between the TiO2 support and the MoSx cocatalyst induces spontaneous free-electron transfer in an unfavorable direction, resulting in stronger O2 adsorption on Mo active sites and causing limited H2O2 production. Herein, we propose a strategy for directional free-electron transfer to produce electron-enriched Mo(4 &#8211; &#948;)+ sites via introducing an Ag mediator into the TiO2/MoSx photocatalyst, which aims to weaken O2 adsorption for improving H2O2 production activity. To achieve this, a core&#8211;shell Ag@MoSx cocatalyst was ingeniously constructed on the TiO2 surface to synthesize the TiO2/Ag@MoSx photocatalyst. The resultant TiO2/Ag@MoSx achieves a significantly enhanced H2O2 production rate of 16.13 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 with an AQY value of 8.79%, surpassing TiO2/Ag and TiO2/MoSx by 10.0 and 237.2 times, respectively. Theoretical calculations and experimental results reveal that the incorporation of the Ag mediator into the TiO2/Ag@MoSx system can facilitate directional free-electron transfer to the MoSx cocatalyst. This causes the creation of electron-enriched Mo(4 &#8211; &#948;)+ sites and an increase in the antibonding-orbital occupancy of Mo&#8211;Oads, ultimately weakening the Mo&#8211;Oads bond and enabling high activity in H2O2 production. This study provides valuable insights into optimizing reactant adsorption for efficient artificial photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Xidong Zhang, Jiachao Xu, Haoyu Long, Jiaguo Yu, Huogen Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05674</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stereospecific and Stereodivergent Allyl&#8211;Allyl Coupling: Construction of Vicinal Tertiary and All-Carbon Quaternary Stereocenters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06203</link>
      <description>Yongsuk Jung, Jieun Kim, G.N. Kim, Jeong Wan Ko, Sungwoo Hong, Seung Hwan Cho, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405106290

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongsuk Jung, Jieun Kim, G.N. Kim, Jeong Wan Ko, Sungwoo Hong, Seung Hwan Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Photocatalysts Display Proximity-Enhanced Catalytic Activity in Metallaphotoredox C&#8211;O Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05893</link>
      <description>Luigi Dolcini, Andrea Solida, Daniele Lavelli, Andr&#233;s Mauricio Hidalgo-N&#250;&#241;ez, Tommaso Gandini, Matthieu Fornara, Alessandro Colella, Alberto Bossi, Marta Penconi, Daniele Fiorito, Cesare Gennari, Alberto Dal Corso, Luca Pignataro, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405107662

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luigi Dolcini, Andrea Solida, Daniele Lavelli, Andr&#233;s Mauricio Hidalgo-N&#250;&#241;ez, Tommaso Gandini, Matthieu Fornara, Alessandro Colella, Alberto Bossi, Marta Penconi, Daniele Fiorito, Cesare Gennari, Alberto Dal Corso, Luca Pignataro</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05893</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analogy in the Mechanism of Heterolytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Dissociation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05629</link>
      <description>Ping Jin, Nengchao Luo, Feng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405109345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ping Jin, Nengchao Luo, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Multicomponent Carboxylation of Olefins and Sulfinate Salts with &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06335</link>
      <description>Julien R. Lyonnet, &#193;lvaro Velasco&#8208;Rubio, Roman Abrams, Duc-Ha Phan-Vu, Kim S. M&#252;hlfenzl, Xuemeng Chen, Alessandro Cerveri, Jos&#233; Tiago Menezes Correia, M&#225;rcio W. Paix&#227;o, Charles S. Elmore, Rub&#233;n Mart&#305;&#769;n, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405109917

                Herein, we describe a photoinduced multicomponent catalytic carboxylation protocol that streamlines the access to 13C-labeled carboxylic acids from simple olefin precursors, sulfinate salts and 13CO2. Site selectivity is dictated by the radical philicity of the starting precursors and reaction intermediates, resulting in either a four-component or a five-component endeavor. The method is characterized by its simplicity and flexibility across a wide number of coupling counterparts</description>
      <author>Julien R. Lyonnet, &#193;lvaro Velasco&#8208;Rubio, Roman Abrams, Duc-Ha Phan-Vu, Kim S. M&#252;hlfenzl, Xuemeng Chen, Alessandro Cerveri, Jos&#233; Tiago Menezes Correia, M&#225;rcio W. Paix&#227;o, Charles S. Elmore, Rub&#233;n Mart&#305;&#769;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocrystalline High-Dimensional Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; for Efficient Electroreductive Dicarboxylation of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with Cycloalkane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06490</link>
      <description>Yuanming Xie, Xuelin Wang, Junjun Mao, Chenchen Zhang, Qingqing Song, Toru Murayama, M. C. Lin, Jiawei Zhang, Yang Lou, Chengsi Pan, Ying Zhang, Yongfa Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405110494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanming Xie, Xuelin Wang, Junjun Mao, Chenchen Zhang, Qingqing Song, Toru Murayama, M. C. Lin, Jiawei Zhang, Yang Lou, Chengsi Pan, Ying Zhang, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06490</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvement of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Photocatalysis of a Ru(II)&#8211;Re(I) Complex and Carbon Nitride Hybrid by Coadsorption of an Os(II) Complex Photosensitizer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06134</link>
      <description>Toshiya Tanaka, Mitsuhiko Shizuno, Yusuke Tamaki, Kazuhiko Maeda, Osamu Ishitani, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405112143

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Toshiya Tanaka, Mitsuhiko Shizuno, Yusuke Tamaki, Kazuhiko Maeda, Osamu Ishitani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light-Driven Hybrid Nanoreactor Harnessing the Synergy of Carboxysomes and Organic Frameworks for Efficient Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03672</link>
      <description>Jing Yang, Qiuyao Jiang, Yu Chen, Quan Wen, Xingwu Ge, Qiang Zhu, Wei Zhao, Oluwatobi Samuel Adegbite, Haofan Yang, Liang Luo, Hang Qu, Veronica Del-Angel-Hernandez, Rob Clowes, Jun Gao, Marc A. Little, Andrew I. Cooper, Lu&#8208;Ning Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405113641

                Synthetic photobiocatalysts are promising catalysts for valuable chemical transformations by harnessing solar energy inspired by natural photosynthesis. However, the synergistic integration of all of the components for efficient light harvesting, cascade electron transfer, and efficient biocatalytic reactions presents a formidable challenge. In particular, replicating intricate multiscale hierarchical assembly and functional segregation involved in natural photosystems, such as photosystems I and II, remains particularly demanding within artificial structures. Here, we report the bottom-up construction of a visible-light-driven chemical&#8211;biological hybrid nanoreactor with augmented photocatalytic efficiency by anchoring an &#945;-carboxysome shell encasing [FeFe]-hydrogenases (H&#8211;S) on the surface of a hydrogen-bonded organic molecular crystal, a microporous &#945;-polymorph of 1,3,6,8-tetra(4&#8242;-carboxyphenyl)pyrene (TBAP-&#945;). The self-association of this chemical&#8211;biological hybrid system is facilitated by hydrogen bonds, as revealed by molecular dynamics simulations. Within this hybrid photobiocatalyst, TBAP-&#945; functions as an antenna for visible-light absorption and exciton generation, supplying electrons for sacrificial hydrogen production by H&#8211;S in aqueous solutions. This coordination allows the hybrid nanoreactor, H&#8211;S|TBAP-&#945;, to execute hydrogen evolution exclusively driven by light irradiation with a rate comparable to that of photocatalyst-loaded precious cocatalyst. The established approach to constructing new light-driven biocatalysts combines the synergistic power of biological nanotechnology with the multilength-scale structure and functional control offered by supramolecular organic semiconductors. It opens up innovative opportunities for the fabrication of biomimetic nanoreactors for sustainable fuel production and enzymatic reactions.</description>
      <author>Jing Yang, Qiuyao Jiang, Yu Chen, Quan Wen, Xingwu Ge, Qiang Zhu, Wei Zhao, Oluwatobi Samuel Adegbite, Haofan Yang, Liang Luo, Hang Qu, Veronica Del-Angel-Hernandez, Rob Clowes, Jun Gao, Marc A. Little, Andrew I. Cooper, Lu&#8208;Ning Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i023_1874629</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405120090

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i023_1874629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i023_1874630</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405121157

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i023_1874630</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Nanosteps Modulate the Local Environment of Co Single Atoms to Boost the Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05624</link>
      <description>Sheng Qian, Tengfei Jiang, Junhua Wang, Wenzhi Yuan, Dailing Jia, Ningyan Cheng, Huaiguo Xue, Zhongfei Xu, Romain Gautier, Jingqi Tian, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405136849

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sheng Qian, Tengfei Jiang, Junhua Wang, Wenzhi Yuan, Dailing Jia, Ningyan Cheng, Huaiguo Xue, Zhongfei Xu, Romain Gautier, Jingqi Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05624</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of Catalysis by the [Ga&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;L&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;]&lt;sup&gt;12&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; Metallocage on the Prins Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04696</link>
      <description>Iker Zapirain-Gysling, Gantulga Norjmaa, Jean&#8208;Didier Mar&#233;chal, Gregori Ujaque, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405181903

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Iker Zapirain-Gysling, Gantulga Norjmaa, Jean&#8208;Didier Mar&#233;chal, Gregori Ujaque</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Chemistry and Machine Learning-Assisted Screening of Supported Amorphous Metal Oxide Nanoclusters for Methane Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04021</link>
      <description>Xijun Wang, Kaihang Shi, Anyang Peng, Randall Q. Snurr, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405197131

                Activating the C&#8211;H bond in methane represents a cornerstone challenge in catalytic research. While several supported metal oxide nanoclusters (MeO-NCs) have shown promise for this reaction, their optimal composition remains underexplored primarily due to the large number of possible compositions and their amorphous nature. This study addresses these challenges using computational approaches. Leveraging density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we began with a previously studied supported tetra-copper oxide nanocluster and systematically substituted its Cu sites with first-row transition metals (Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, and Zn). This process allowed us to examine the catalytic activity of 162 MeO-NCs with a variety of geometric and electronic structures, leading to 12 new compositions that outperformed the base nanocluster. Exploring the structure&#8211;activity relationships with machine learning, our analysis uncovered correlations between the intrinsic electronic and structural properties of the nanoclusters and the free energy barriers for methane activation despite the challenges posed by the structural flexibility of these amorphous nanoclusters. The results offer insights into the optimization of MeO-NCs for methane activation. Additionally, we developed a clustering model capable of distinguishing high-performing nanoclusters from less effective ones with strong tolerance to the interference from the structural flexibility of these amorphous nanoclusters. These findings help narrow down the material design space for more time-consuming high-level quantum chemical calculations, offering a promising pathway toward advancing eco-friendly methane conversion.</description>
      <author>Xijun Wang, Kaihang Shi, Anyang Peng, Randall Q. Snurr</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diastereodivergent Parallel Kinetic Resolution of Racemic 2-Substituted Pyrrolidines via Iridium-Catalyzed C(&lt;i&gt;sp&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Borylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06245</link>
      <description>Maosheng He, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Lili Chen, Senmiao Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405197232

                Chiral 2,5-disubstituted pyrrolidines are ubiquitous subunits in natural products, bioactive compounds, pharmaceuticals, and chiral catalysts. However, their asymmetric synthesis still presents a formidable challenge. We herein report a rare example of diastereodivergent parallel kinetic resolution of racemic 2-substituted pyrrolidines via C(sp3)&#8211;H borylation. A vast array of enantioenriched cis- and trans-2,5-disubstituted pyrrolidines were obtained with high enantioselectivities. The synthetic utility was demonstrated by downstream transformations, including the synthesis of optically active pyrrolidine 197B and cis-pyrrolidine 225H.</description>
      <author>Maosheng He, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Lili Chen, Senmiao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Hydrodeoxygenation of Lignin via Aryl Ether C&#8211;O Bond Cleavage: Cs-Mediated Cu Surface Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05146</link>
      <description>Xiaofei Wang, Mei&#8208;Yan Wang, Maoshuai Li, Yue Wang, Xuliang Lin, Yanlin Qin, Xinbin Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405222542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaofei Wang, Mei&#8208;Yan Wang, Maoshuai Li, Yue Wang, Xuliang Lin, Yanlin Qin, Xinbin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of &lt;i&gt;E&lt;/i&gt;-3-Alkenyl 2&lt;i&gt;H&lt;/i&gt;-Indazoles via Pd/Cu-Catalyzed Cross-coupling/Cyclization of 2-Iodoazoarenes with Terminal Allylenes and Visible-Light-Promoted Isomerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06448</link>
      <description>Kalin Mei, Rui Huang, Haiyang Huang, Hongli Bao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405226277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kalin Mei, Rui Huang, Haiyang Huang, Hongli Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium-Catalyzed Formal Asymmetric Reductive Isomerization of &#945;-Hydroxyenones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05378</link>
      <description>Wennan Dong, Caiyi Ren, Lixuan Zhu, Peng Luo, Zhifei Zhao, Shouang Lan, Jinggong Liu, Shuang Yang, Qi Zhang, Xinqiang Fang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405236100

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wennan Dong, Caiyi Ren, Lixuan Zhu, Peng Luo, Zhifei Zhao, Shouang Lan, Jinggong Liu, Shuang Yang, Qi Zhang, Xinqiang Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Oxide-Oriented Ethanol Synthesis via Dimethyl Oxalate Hydrogenation from Syngas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06219</link>
      <description>Yannan Sun, Ke Fu, Jian Wei, Qingjie Ge, Qingxiang Ma, Guofeng Wang, Jian Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405240108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yannan Sun, Ke Fu, Jian Wei, Qingjie Ge, Qingxiang Ma, Guofeng Wang, Jian Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Catalyzed Asymmetric Synthesis of &#946;- or &#946;,&#947;-Substituted GABA Derivatives Enabled by Photoactive Ternary Electron Donor&#8211;Acceptor Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06549</link>
      <description>Ying Xie, Zemin Lai, Albert S. C. Chan, Jing Guo, Gui Lu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405246639

                Enantiopure &#947;-amino butyric acids (GABA) and derivatives have important applications in medicinal chemistry, especially for the treatment of central nervous system diseases. Many marketed drugs feature this moiety. In this context, we have developed a highly enantioselective catalytic strategy for rapidly forging &#946;- or &#946;,&#947;-substituted GABA derivatives by exploiting an unexplored ternary electron donor&#8211;acceptor (EDA) complex simultaneously driven by visible light and chiral Ni catalyst. With this cooperative catalytic system, a range of structurally diverse &#946;- or &#946;,&#947;-substituted GABA derivatives have been achieved in high yields with good enantio- and diastereoselectivities (up to 88% yield, &gt;99% ee, &gt;19:1 dr). Mechanistic studies indicate that the key to success is the dual role of the chiral Ni catalyst, which not only promotes the formation of ternary EDA complexes generated from redox-active esters, Hantzsch esters, and chiral Ni catalyst but can also precisely provide asymmetric induction. The synthetic benefits of this method were proved by enabling easy synthetic access to pharmaceuticals or related bioactive molecules such as pregabalin, baclofen, rolipram, and phenibut.</description>
      <author>Ying Xie, Zemin Lai, Albert S. C. Chan, Jing Guo, Gui Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of Chiral Acyclic Nitriles Containing &#945;-All-Carbon Quaternary Stereocenters via Synergistic Palladium and Phase-Transfer Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06364</link>
      <description>Cheng Guo, Yunpeng Dong, Yi Wang, Xiaona Du, Runxia Ma, Choon&#8208;Hong Tan, Xinjun Luan, Jingyun Ren, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405265174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Guo, Yunpeng Dong, Yi Wang, Xiaona Du, Runxia Ma, Choon&#8208;Hong Tan, Xinjun Luan, Jingyun Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06364</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
