<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 01:23:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Pivotal Role of Acid-Catalyzed Hydration in Electrochemical Carbon Corrosion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05547</link>
      <description>Seunghoon Lee, Haesol Kim, Minho M. Kim, Tae Kyung Ko, Hyung Min, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404172151

                Carbon, with its high electrical conductivity and large surface area, enables the efficient dispersion and utilization of catalytic entities, contributing to the cost-effective development of electrochemical systems for a future energy economy. However, the longevity of these systems is often compromised by carbon corrosion, the fundamental details of which unfortunately remain largely unknown. Here, we elucidate that carbon corrosion is initiated by a covalent addition reaction that chemically breaks the sp2 carbon network, prior to electrochemical oxidation steps. Online differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy and post-mortem X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy unveil the pseudozeroth- and first-order reaction kinetics in the proton concentration and oxygen coverage on the carbon surface, respectively, allowing us to suggest acid-catalyzed hydration with carbocation formation as the initial step in carbon corrosion. The proposed mechanism is further evidenced by the decreased carbon corrosion rate in the presence of the carbocation scavenger, methanol, and by the evolution of the C18O16O product during the corrosion of carbon, pretreated in acid solution prepared with the 18O-isotope of water. Based on these findings, previous empirical understandings, pH-dependent and site-specific (defect, edge, etc.) carbon corrosion characteristics, can be successfully explained, bringing potential avenues for developing rational strategies to mitigate carbon corrosion.</description>
      <author>Seunghoon Lee, Haesol Kim, Minho M. Kim, Tae Kyung Ko, Hyung Min, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Csp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&#8211;Csp&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Coupling of Isonitriles and (Hetero)arenes through a Photoredox-Catalyzed Double Decyanation Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06269</link>
      <description>Mar&#237;a Mart&#237;n, R. Mart&#237;n Romero, Chiara Portolani, Mariola Tortosa, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404181274

                Herein, we demonstrate the ability of isonitriles to be used as alkyl radical precursors in a photoredox-catalyzed transformation involving selective C&#8211;N cleavage and Csp3&#8211;Csp2 bond formation. This protocol allows for the preparation of functionalized heteroarenes from readily available isonitriles through a decyanation process. The reaction is general for primary, secondary, and tertiary substrates, including amino acid derivatives and druglike molecules.</description>
      <author>Mar&#237;a Mart&#237;n, R. Mart&#237;n Romero, Chiara Portolani, Mariola Tortosa</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Enzyme Catalyzed Stereoselective Synthesis of Chiral Aromatic Polysubstituted &#947;-Butyrolactones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04498</link>
      <description>Liliang Chu, Xiaoyan Zhang, Daidi Fan, Yunpeng Bai, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404182439

                Chiral polysubstituted aromatic &#947;-butyrolactones are core structural units of many natural products and high value-added chemicals in the pharmaceutical and food industries. Currently, the precise construction of multiple chiral centers on the five-membered heterocycle substituted by bulky phenyl groups faces big challenges, such as low stereoselectivity, expensive noble metal catalysts, harsh reaction conditions and low atom economy. Herein, we report a one-pot, two-enzyme catalytic strategy for the synthesis of 18 bulky di/trisubstituted aromatic &#947;-butyrolactones on the &#945;-, &#946;- and &#947;-carbons with good enantioselectivities (up to &gt;99% ee) and diastereoselectivities (up to &gt;99:1 dr). This cascade process includes sequential two-step asymmetric reduction of &#945;-/&#946;-unsaturated &#947;-ketoesters by four ene reductases and a carbonyl reductase without intermediate isolation and catalyst removal. In particular, the large sterically hindered substrates (1p&#8211;1s) were converted to the corresponding trisubstituted &#947;-butyrolactones (4p&#8211;4s) with 98&#8211;99% ee and &gt;99:1 dr. This enzymatic cascade process represents a simple, atom-economic and enantioselective method to deliver a broad of bulky polysubstituted &#947;-butyrolactones in a cheap and efficient manner compared to conventional methods.</description>
      <author>Liliang Chu, Xiaoyan Zhang, Daidi Fan, Yunpeng Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Pathway on RuP&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; through Ab Initio Grand Canonical Monte Carlo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04913</link>
      <description>Shihan Qin, Sayan Banerjee, Mehmet G&#246;khan &#350;ensoy, Andrew M. Rappe, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404185926

                In this study, the high catalytic reactivity of ruthenium phosphide (RuP2) has been identified by first-principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations for the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Complex surface reconstructions are considered by applying the ab initio grand canonical Monte Carlo (ai-GCMC) algorithm, efficiently providing a sufficient phase-space exploration of possible surfaces. Combined with surface-phase Pourbaix diagrams, we are able to identify the actual surfaces that obtained under specific experimental environments, thus leading to a more accurate understanding of the nature of the active sites and the binding strength of adsorbates. Specifically, through hundreds of surface reconstructions and hydrogenation states generated with ai-GCMC, we identify the most favorable surface phases of RuP2 under aqueous acidic conditions. We discover that the HER activity is determined by multiple surfaces with different stoichiometries within a narrow electrode potential window. Low HER overpotential (&#951;) has been found for each of the identified surfaces, as low as 0.04 V. High H-coverage reconstructed surfaces have been discovered under acidic conditions, and the surface Ru sites introduced by additional Ru adatoms or exposed by P-vacancies serve as the active sites for HER based on their nearly reversible H binding. This work provides atomistic insights into the origin of high HER activity on RuP2 by exploring the dynamic surface phases of electrocatalysts and features a generalizable method to explore the reconstructed/hydrogenated surface space as a function of experimental conditions.</description>
      <author>Shihan Qin, Sayan Banerjee, Mehmet G&#246;khan &#350;ensoy, Andrew M. Rappe</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Evolving Cobalt&#8211;Protic-NHC Catalysts: Kinetic Zone Diagram Analysis and Mechanistic Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05104</link>
      <description>Sanajit Kumar Mandal, Aayatti Mallick Gupta, Joyanta Choudhury, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404185932

                A series of systematically designed cobalt&#8211;protic-NHC complexes containing pendant proton-shuttle groups was synthesized. The proton-shuttle motifs enabled these complexes to act as efficient electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) from various acids as proton sources. The effect of acid strength on the mechanism of HER was investigated by varying the proton source ( CH3COOH, pKaCH3CN = 23.51), triethylammonium tetrafluoroborate (Et3NHBF4, pKaCH3CN = 18.57), and trifluoroacetic acid (CF3COOH, pKaCH3CN = 12.70). Additionally, by changing experimental parameters such as substrate/catalyst concentration and scan rate, the single-electron EC&#8242; zone diagram could be extended to the present multielectron reaction system where all of the zones were accessed with little deviation in some of the waveforms from the original. From the kinetic zone diagram analysis, some of the performance parameters such as the observed rate constant (kobs), turnover frequency (TOF), and the rate constant of the first chemical step (k1) were determined. Also, the zone diagram provided insight into the mechanistic cycle and the nature of the rate-limiting step. The investigation suggested that the protic proton of the proton-shuttle functionality triggered a hydrogen evolution reaction via intramolecular proton-hydride coupling from the Co(II)&#8211;H intermediate. This intramolecular dihydrogen elimination step, which was independent of the acid concentration, acted as the rate-limiting step and the turnover frequency of HER was fully controlled by this step.</description>
      <author>Sanajit Kumar Mandal, Aayatti Mallick Gupta, Joyanta Choudhury</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Catalyst Performance for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction under a Chiral Bias</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04477</link>
      <description>Aravind Vadakkayil, Wiley A. Dunlap-Shohl, Meera Joy, Brian P. Bloom, David H. Waldeck, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404220015

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aravind Vadakkayil, Wiley A. Dunlap-Shohl, Meera Joy, Brian P. Bloom, David H. Waldeck</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Csp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&#8211;Csp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Bond Formation via Ni-Catalyzed Regio- and Enantioselective Hydroalkylation of Linear 1,3-Diene through Carbonyl Umpolung</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05759</link>
      <description>Ruofei Cheng, Kangbao Zhong, Xue&#8208;Qiang Chu, Yu Lan, Chao&#8208;Jun Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404225574

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruofei Cheng, Kangbao Zhong, Xue&#8208;Qiang Chu, Yu Lan, Chao&#8208;Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trend and Progress in Catalysis for Ethylene Production from Bioethanol Using ZSM-5</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04162</link>
      <description>L. Ouayloul, Iker Agirrezabal-Teller&#237;a, S&#233;bastien Paul, M. El Doukkali, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404234962

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L. Ouayloul, Iker Agirrezabal-Teller&#237;a, S&#233;bastien Paul, M. El Doukkali</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Doped Ni-Based Catalysts Surpass Ir-Baselines for Oxygen Evolution Due to Optimal Charge-Transfer Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</link>
      <description>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404237251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoreforming of Lignocellulose into CO and Lactic Acid over a Single-Atom Fe-Dispersed Order/Disorder Polymeric Carbon Nitride Homojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05510</link>
      <description>Yanglin Chen, Mei Zheng, Jiajun Sun, Jianzhong Xu, Chao Wu, Jiyuan Liu, Limo He, Shibo Xi, Shuzhou Li, Can Xue, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404243653

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanglin Chen, Mei Zheng, Jiajun Sun, Jianzhong Xu, Chao Wu, Jiyuan Liu, Limo He, Shibo Xi, Shuzhou Li, Can Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Asymmetric C&#8211;H Activation/Cyclization of Sulfoximines with Sulfoxonium Ylides by a Chiral &#951;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;-Benzene Ruthenium(II) Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04798</link>
      <description>Huan Liu, Ji&#8208;Jun Jiang, Jun Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404254369

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Liu, Ji&#8208;Jun Jiang, Jun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhodium-Catalyzed (Asymmetric) Annulation of Silacyclobutanes with Bicyclic Olefins via C&#8211;Si Bond Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05675</link>
      <description>Shengbo Xu, Fen Wang, Xingwei Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404257850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengbo Xu, Fen Wang, Xingwei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of Ferrocene 1,3-Derivatives via Palladium/Norbornene Cooperative Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06231</link>
      <description>Princi Gupta, Prakash C. Tiwari, Suchithra Madhavan, Manmohan Kapur, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404258078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Princi Gupta, Prakash C. Tiwari, Suchithra Madhavan, Manmohan Kapur</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Long-Chain Linear &#945;-Olefins Synthesis from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation over K&#8211;FeMn Catalyst via Stabilizing Active Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04325</link>
      <description>Kangzhou Wang, Ziqin Li, Lei Zhu, Weizhe Gao, Yang Tang, Kuan&#8208;Guan Liu, Xinhua Gao, Qingxiang Ma, Jianli Zhang, Tiansheng Zhao, Noritatsu Tsubaki, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404258399

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kangzhou Wang, Ziqin Li, Lei Zhu, Weizhe Gao, Yang Tang, Kuan&#8208;Guan Liu, Xinhua Gao, Qingxiang Ma, Jianli Zhang, Tiansheng Zhao, Noritatsu Tsubaki</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roles of Acidic Proton for Fe-Containing Zeolite in Direct Oxidation of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04875</link>
      <description>Peipei Xiao, Hiroto Toyoda, Yong Wang, K. Nakamura, Samya Bekhti, Ryota Osuga, Maiko Nishibori, Hermann Gies, Toshiyuki Yokoi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404271393

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peipei Xiao, Hiroto Toyoda, Yong Wang, K. Nakamura, Samya Bekhti, Ryota Osuga, Maiko Nishibori, Hermann Gies, Toshiyuki Yokoi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 + 1 &amp;gt; 3: Trimetallic Sites on the Zn-IrP&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/FeP Electrode Trigger Synergistic Effect to Activate Industrial-Grade Performance for Hydrazine-Assisted Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05825</link>
      <description>Xiaoli Sun, Jie Liu, Yunmei Du, Yanru Liu, Wenna Wang, Dehong Chen, Ruiyong Zhang, Lei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404273867

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoli Sun, Jie Liu, Yunmei Du, Yanru Liu, Wenna Wang, Dehong Chen, Ruiyong Zhang, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Chemoenzymatic Cascade for the Formal Enantioselective Hydroxylation and Amination of Benzylic C&#8211;H Bonds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03161</link>
      <description>Shouxin Zhang, Chen Huang, Weixi Kong, Liya Zhou, Jing Wang, Frank Hollmann, Yunting Liu, Yanjun Jiang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404276047

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shouxin Zhang, Chen Huang, Weixi Kong, Liya Zhou, Jing Wang, Frank Hollmann, Yunting Liu, Yanjun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Site Density Engineering of ZnO/Cu Cube Inverse Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06447</link>
      <description>Jialin Li, Dongdong Wang, Wei Xiong, Jieqiong Ding, Weixin Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404276392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jialin Li, Dongdong Wang, Wei Xiong, Jieqiong Ding, Weixin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversing the Enantioselectivity of Enzymatic Dynamic Kinetic Asymmetric Transformations in the Synthesis of Fused Lactones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05196</link>
      <description>Ming-Liang Shi, Yao Yao, Xinyue Fan, Kun Li, Xiao&#8208;Qi Yu, Yan Liu, Zhong&#8208;Liu Wu, Na Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404284677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming-Liang Shi, Yao Yao, Xinyue Fan, Kun Li, Xiao&#8208;Qi Yu, Yan Liu, Zhong&#8208;Liu Wu, Na Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Conversion Propane Dehydrogenation by Photocatalysis under Ambient Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06192</link>
      <description>Yucheng Yuan, Yuhan Zhang, Jan Paul Menzel, John Santoro, Madeline Dolack, Hongyan Wang, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Dunwei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404297788

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yucheng Yuan, Yuhan Zhang, Jan Paul Menzel, John Santoro, Madeline Dolack, Hongyan Wang, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Dunwei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Construction of &#946;-Arylethylamines via Selective C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)-H Arylation of Aliphatic Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04805</link>
      <description>Tu Hua, Xi Deng, Hongyi Li, Yunpeng Xu, Jing Chen, Xiaofeng Zhang, Weiping Su, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404315898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tu Hua, Xi Deng, Hongyi Li, Yunpeng Xu, Jing Chen, Xiaofeng Zhang, Weiping Su</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Electrochemical Furfural Hydrogenation on Pt via Bimetallic Colocalization of Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05428</link>
      <description>Sanghwi Han, Jeongyun Kim, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Won Bo Lee, Jaeyune Ryu, Jeyong Yoon, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404316297

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sanghwi Han, Jeongyun Kim, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Won Bo Lee, Jaeyune Ryu, Jeyong Yoon</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Production of Biomass-Derived Plastic Monomer 2,5-Furandicarboxylic Acid at Industrial-Level Concentration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05864</link>
      <description>Weizhen Xie, Yining Zhang, Hang Zheng, Pengbo Lyu, Xixian Ke, Tianyuan Li, Huayu Fang, Yong Sun, Jin&#8208;Chao Dong, Lin Lu, Changlong Wang, Xing Tang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404317848

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weizhen Xie, Yining Zhang, Hang Zheng, Pengbo Lyu, Xixian Ke, Tianyuan Li, Huayu Fang, Yong Sun, Jin&#8208;Chao Dong, Lin Lu, Changlong Wang, Xing Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Photoredox and Palladium-Catalyzed 1,3-Acyloxyallylation of Aryl Cyclopropanes with Allyl Esters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05180</link>
      <description>Lixu Ren, Jun Wei, Yingfeng Yu, Liya Huang, Lin Yang, Jun Wang, Na Hao, Qiang Fu, Dong Yi, Siping Wei, Ji Lu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404318842

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lixu Ren, Jun Wei, Yingfeng Yu, Liya Huang, Lin Yang, Jun Wang, Na Hao, Qiang Fu, Dong Yi, Siping Wei, Ji Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling the Pitfalls of Rotating Disk Electrode-Based OER Stability Assessment: Bubble Blockage or Substrate Passivation?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05447</link>
      <description>Aline Bornet, Pavel Moreno&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Abhijit Dutta, Ying Kong, Mike Liechti, Soma Vesztergom, Matthias Arenz, Peter Broekmann, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404325018

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aline Bornet, Pavel Moreno&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Abhijit Dutta, Ying Kong, Mike Liechti, Soma Vesztergom, Matthias Arenz, Peter Broekmann</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Ruthenium Catalysts for &lt;i&gt;endo&lt;/i&gt;-Selective Cycloisomerization of Nucleophile-Functionalized Terminal Alkynes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05245</link>
      <description>Hector A. Garcia Mayerstein, Datong Song, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404327114

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hector A. Garcia Mayerstein, Datong Song</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Isopentenol Utilization Pathway-Based &#8220;Deuterium-Scanning&#8221; Method for Mechanistic Investigations of Terpene Cyclases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05811</link>
      <description>Shouqi Zhang, Kaibiao Wang, Yuanning Liu, Tao Wang, Yao Kong, Pengcheng Zhang, Bing Zhang, Min Yin, Guohui Pan, Zhengren Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404348434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shouqi Zhang, Kaibiao Wang, Yuanning Liu, Tao Wang, Yao Kong, Pengcheng Zhang, Bing Zhang, Min Yin, Guohui Pan, Zhengren Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Reconstructed, Mesoporous In&lt;sub&gt;1.8&lt;/sub&gt;Bi&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocubes as Electrocatalysts for Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05431</link>
      <description>Yueqi Feng, Jin Xiao, Yiyi Qiu, Jianlin Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404357930

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yueqi Feng, Jin Xiao, Yiyi Qiu, Jianlin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Investigations on Cp*Co&lt;sup&gt;III&lt;/sup&gt;-Catalyzed Quinoline Transfer Hydrogenation with Formic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05271</link>
      <description>Nidhi Garg, Pardeep Dahiya, Sonia Mallet&#8208;Ladeira, Rinaldo Poli, Basker Sundararaju, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404359527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nidhi Garg, Pardeep Dahiya, Sonia Mallet&#8208;Ladeira, Rinaldo Poli, Basker Sundararaju</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05271</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
