<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 01:02:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Bridging Homogeneous and Heterogeneous Water Oxidation Catalysis by Insolubilized Polyoxometalate Clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00201</link>
      <description>Qiyu Hu, Hongshan Zhou, Yong Ding, Thomas W&#229;gberg, Xiuxiu Han, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393855529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiyu Hu, Hongshan Zhou, Yong Ding, Thomas W&#229;gberg, Xiuxiu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the d-Band Center of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; via Octahedral and Tetrahedral Codoping for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06256</link>
      <description>Xiaotian Wu, Zhiyu Shao, Qian Zhu, Xiangyan Hou, Chao Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Keke Huang, Shouhua Feng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393857012

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaotian Wu, Zhiyu Shao, Qian Zhu, Xiangyan Hou, Chao Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Keke Huang, Shouhua Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Diverse Construction of &lt;i&gt;gem&lt;/i&gt;-Difluoroallylated Bicyclo[1.1.1]pentanes and Cyclobutanes from [1.1.1]Propellane via Copper Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00281</link>
      <description>Xiao-Tian Feng, Qiao&#8208;Qiao Min, Xiangfeng Zeng, Hang Zhao, Xingang Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393858800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao-Tian Feng, Qiao&#8208;Qiao Min, Xiangfeng Zeng, Hang Zhao, Xingang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regeneration of NAD(P)H and its Analogues by Photocatalysis with Ionized Carbon Nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00841</link>
      <description>Zaixiang Xu, Zhongwei Fan, Hanchi Chen, Jianguo Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393859085

                The regeneration of NAD(P)H and its analogues is crucial for biocatalytic processes. However, despite the efficiency of enzymatic catalysis in regenerating NAD(P)H, the sustainability of enzymes is often compromised, particularly under extreme catalytic conditions. Moreover, artificial cofactors may present advantages in certain reactions due to their stability and versatility, yet the substrate specificity of enzymes poses significant challenges to their regeneration through the enzymatic method. Therefore, it is imperative to develop a highly stable regeneration method that can be adapted to both natural and artificial cofactors. In this work, employing potassium-ion-doped carbon nitride (ionCN-0.2) as a catalyst not only achieves high-efficiency photocatalytic regeneration of NAD(P)H, comparable to that of glucose dehydrogenase (GDH), but also a remarkable ability to regenerate nicotinamide analogues. This enhanced performance stems from the tunable negative &#950;-potential, which effectively adsorbs the positively charged [Cp*Rh(bpy)H2O]2+ mediator, resulting in enhanced regeneration kinetics of the nicotinamide moiety. The catalyst demonstrates superior performance compared to the reported systems; the optimal regeneration rate reaches 0.55 mmol L&#8211;1 gcat&#8211;1 min&#8211;1 and approaches enzymatic regeneration efficiency. Expanding the reaction conditions to a wider temperature and pH range also confirms the effectiveness and sufficient stability of this photocatalytic system, offering a promising strategy for stable cofactor regeneration in biocatalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Zaixiang Xu, Zhongwei Fan, Hanchi Chen, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00841</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Electronic Structure Modulation of Interfacial Oxygen Vacancies Promotes the Oxygen Activation Capacity of Pt/Ce&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;M&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06234</link>
      <description>Weiping Yang, Fuyuan Qi, Wei An, Haochen Yu, Shutong Liu, Peipei Ma, Rui Chen, Shuangxi Liu, Lan&#8208;Lan Lou, Kai Yu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393862387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiping Yang, Fuyuan Qi, Wei An, Haochen Yu, Shutong Liu, Peipei Ma, Rui Chen, Shuangxi Liu, Lan&#8208;Lan Lou, Kai Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Pd-Based Alloys for 1,3-Butadiene Selective Hydrogenation via Equilibrium Models of Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01076</link>
      <description>Jin Liu, Yihao Zhang, Jiao Wei, Jing Zhu, Haoxiang Xu, Daojian Cheng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393870438

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jin Liu, Yihao Zhang, Jiao Wei, Jing Zhu, Haoxiang Xu, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZnO Nanowire Arrays Decorated with Cu Nanoparticles for High-Efficiency Nitrate to Ammonia Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04398</link>
      <description>Anlin Feng, Yunxia Hu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Huaijun Lin, Qian Wang, Jie Xu, Anmin Liu, Gang Wu, Qingyang Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393898872

                The electrocatalytic transformation of waste nitrate into useful ammonia is a "one stone, two birds" strategy, which is commendatory from the viewpoint of the environment. In this vein, developing catalysts with high efficiency, selectivity, and stability is desired to make the attractive technology viable. Herein, we synthesized an economical and scalable electrocatalyst of Cu nanoparticles dispersed onto ZnO nanowire arrays (Cu@ZnO NWA) for nitrate reduction reaction (NO3&#8211;RR). This catalyst constructed on the Cu foam achieved a high ammonia yield of &#8764;6.03 mg cm&#8211;2 h&#8211;1, a Faradaic efficiency of &#8764;89.14%, and good stability for the NO3&#8211;RR in the Ar-saturated 0.1 M KOH electrolyte with the presence of 0.05 M KNO3, superior to most Cu-based catalysts reported in the literature. According to electrochemical measurements and density functional theory calculations, ZnO nanowires offer stable support to accomplish uniform dispersion of Cu nanoparticles and provide a synergy to boost electrocatalytic properties of Cu catalysts. This synergistic effect may originate from the electronic localization at the interface of Cu nanoparticles and ZnO nanowires, resulting in the electron deficiency of the Cu@ZnO NWA surface. Therefore, the promotional mechanisms are associated with enhanced adsorption of the electronegative nitrate ions and boosted charge transfer during the NO3&#8211;RR process. Notably, the Cu@ZnO NWA catalyst can be synthesized on most conductor surfaces through a flexible combination of electrodeposition and hydrothermal techniques, showing good commonality and scalability, thus having a vast industrialization potential for practical application.</description>
      <author>Anlin Feng, Yunxia Hu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Huaijun Lin, Qian Wang, Jie Xu, Anmin Liu, Gang Wu, Qingyang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realizing the 4e&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;/2e&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; Pathway Transition of O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Co&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;C Catalysts by Regulating the Chemical Structures beyond the Second Coordination Shells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00781</link>
      <description>Wang Wang, Yunzi Hu, Peng Li, Yucheng Liu, Shengli Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393940834

                The catalytic performance of single-atom catalysts (SACs) is vitally determined by their coordination environments. So far, the catalytic manipulation of SACs has been mainly focused on the first and second nearest coordination structures of the center atoms. We herein demonstrate that the chemical environments beyond the second coordination shells also significantly influence the catalytic behaviors of SACs. Our findings reveal that the presence of graphitic nitrogen can induce a shift of the O2 reduction pathway on CoN4C sites from an energy-conversion favorite 4e&#8211; pathway to a H2O2-production desirable 2e&#8211; pathway. The remote graphitic N tunes the electronic structure of Co from the lower-spin state to the higher-spin state, as proved by the zero-field cooling (ZFC) temperature-dependent magnetic susceptibility, which weakens the adsorption of O2/*OOH, ultimately enhancing the selectivity toward H2O2. It is further revealed that the catalytic influence of graphitic N may be universally present in other SACs such as FeN4C and MnN4C. Impressively, the graphitic N-doped CoN4C exhibits a high H2O2 Faraday efficiency (82%) in a flow cell, with a remarkable H2O2 yield of 0.096 mmol cm&#8211;2 h&#8211;1 for 200 h at 0.358 V (vs RHE), which is sufficient for many applications such as the electro-Fenton-like degradation of the malachite green and demonstrated the feasibility of H2O2 electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Wang Wang, Yunzi Hu, Peng Li, Yucheng Liu, Shengli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i007_1787822</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393982452

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i007_1787822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i007_1787821</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393990563

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i007_1787821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of the Reaction Location of Skeletal 1-Butene Isomerization over Ferrierite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00786</link>
      <description>Pawel A. Chmielniak, Karoline L. Hebisch, Urim Pearl Kim, Jeffrey Kenvin, Carsten Sievers, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566285

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pawel A. Chmielniak, Karoline L. Hebisch, Urim Pearl Kim, Jeffrey Kenvin, Carsten Sievers</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative Redispersion-Derived Single-Site Ru/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts with Mobile Ru Complexes Trapped by Surface Hydroxyls Instead of Oxygen Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01230</link>
      <description>Peng Fei Liu, Zheng Chen, Wei Liu, Xiaodong Wu, Shuang Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566556

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Fei Liu, Zheng Chen, Wei Liu, Xiaodong Wu, Shuang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01230</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorinated Biphenyl Phosphine Ligands for Accelerated [Au(I)]-Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00593</link>
      <description>Riccardo Pedrazzani, Sofia Kiriakidi, Magda Monari, Irene Lazzarini, Giulio Bertuzzi, Carlos Silva L&#243;pez, Marco Bandini, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394567969

                Fluorinated JohnPhos-type ligands are proposed as accelerating tools in homogeneous gold(I) catalysis, with PedroPhosAuCl (Cat1) as the most efficient one. The ligands as well as the corresponding gold complexes were synthesized in high yields and fully characterized also via single-crystal X-ray diffraction. A secondary interaction between the distal phenyl ring of the phosphane ligand and the metal center is identified as key for the fine-tuning of the overall catalytic performance of the complexes. In particular, kinetic as well as computational analysis revealed that by accommodating F atoms on the biphenyl pendant of the ligand, more reactive organo-gold intermediates are realized toward subsequent nucleophilic condensations. The gold-catalyzed indole-hydroarylation of 1,6-enynes and the intramolecular hydroindolynation of alkynes have been adopted as benchmark reactions to exemplify these accelerating effects.</description>
      <author>Riccardo Pedrazzani, Sofia Kiriakidi, Magda Monari, Irene Lazzarini, Giulio Bertuzzi, Carlos Silva L&#243;pez, Marco Bandini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrifying Energy and Chemical Transformations with Single-Atom Alloy Nanoparticle Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00365</link>
      <description>Qiang Gao, Xue Han, Yuanqi Liu, Huiyuan Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394576674

                Single-atom alloys (SAAs) have attracted considerable attention as promising electrocatalysts in reactions central to energy conversion and chemical transformation. In contrast to monometallic nanocrystals and metal alloys, SAAs possess unique and intriguing physicochemical properties, positioning them as ideal model systems for studying structure&#8211;property relationships. However, the field is still in its early stages. In this Perspective, we first review and summarize rational synthesis methods and advanced characterization techniques for SAA nanoparticle catalysts. We then emphasize the extensive applications of SAAs in a range of electrocatalytic reactions, including fuel cell reactions, water splitting, and carbon dioxide and nitrate reductions. Finally, we provide insights into existing challenges and prospects associated with the controlled synthesis, characterization, and design of SAA catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qiang Gao, Xue Han, Yuanqi Liu, Huiyuan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Progress on Preparation of Metal Oxide Catalysts with Porous Structure and Their Catalytic Purification of Diesel Engine Exhausts Gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00323</link>
      <description>Shian Zhou, Lanyi Wang, Siyu Gao, Xinyu Chen, Chunlei Zhang, Di Yu, Xiaoqiang Fan, Xin Yu, Zhao Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394578929

                Because of their special physicochemical properties, pore-structured metal oxide catalysts are widely used in environmental catalysis, energy chemicals, fuel cells, medicine, and other related fields. In recent years, these oxides have also been increasingly studied in the catalytic purification of diesel engine exhaust gases. In this paper, the research progresses of preparation methods of porous metal oxide catalysts and their application in the catalytic purification of diesel engine exhaust were reviewed. The advantages and disadvantages of different methods for the synthesis of porous metal oxide catalysts were elaborated, as well as the mechanism comparison of different types of porous metal oxide catalysts in catalytic purification of diesel engine exhaust pollutants. Finally, the current issues on the preparation of porous metal oxide catalysts and their development trends in application of diesel engine exhaust purification were summarized and discussed. The pore-structured metal oxide catalysts are beneficial for improving the contact efficiency between catalysts and pollutants, which can enhance the catalytic purification efficiency of catalysts. Meanwhile, the intrinsic activity is the most fundamental factor for determining their catalytic activity except for porous structure effects. In addition, this paper can help researchers to deeply understand the important effect of porous metal oxide catalysts in the treatment of diesel engine exhaust pollutants and provide theoretical guidance for the design and development of high-efficiency catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shian Zhou, Lanyi Wang, Siyu Gao, Xinyu Chen, Chunlei Zhang, Di Yu, Xiaoqiang Fan, Xin Yu, Zhao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Overview on Dynamic Phase Transformation and Surface Reconstruction of Iron Catalysts for Catalytic Hydrogenation of CO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; for Hydrocarbons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05854</link>
      <description>Xiaoxu Ding, Minghui Zhu, Bo Sun, Zixu Yang, Yi&#8208;Fan Han, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394579619

                Catalytic hydrogenation of COx (CO and CO2) with renewable H2 represents a feasible practice for carbon capture and utilization and synthesis of chemical commodities, such as olefins, aromatics, and higher alcohols as well as liquid fuels. Direct synthesis via Fischer&#8211;Tropsch Synthesis (FTS) is considered as one of the most promising processes. Iron-based catalysts have been recognized as efficient candidates for catalytic hydrogenation of both CO and CO2 to value-added hydrocarbons due to their superior activities for C&#8211;O bond dissociative activation, reverse/water gas shift reaction, and C&#8211;C chain growth. The structural complexity and dynamic evolution of iron-based catalysts under COx-FTS conditions impose challenges on the understanding of the reaction mechanisms, the dynamic structure of active sites and further improvements of the catalytic performance. In this Review, we discussed the recent developments in characterization techniques for identifying the structural evolution of iron-based catalysts under reaction conditions. We also summarized feasible strategies to manipulate the process of the structural change via promoter interfacing, catalyst pretreating protocols, and application of external physical fields. Finally, we concluded the review by identifying current challenges and opportunities for the next generation of COx catalytic hydrogenation process with an emphasis on the combinatorial contributions from in situ/operando characterizations, chemometrics and machine learning.</description>
      <author>Xiaoxu Ding, Minghui Zhu, Bo Sun, Zixu Yang, Yi&#8208;Fan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Evolution of Oxide-Derived Nanostructured Silver Electrocatalysts during CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00217</link>
      <description>Mengying Yang, Jingjing Wu, Yue Li, Haitao Pan, Hongbo Cui, Xianglong Lu, Xiaohong Tang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394579662

                Oxide-derived (OD) metals have been demonstrated as a kind of promising catalyst with superior catalytic activity for carbon dioxide electroreduction. Here we fabricate OD nanoporous silver by a simple, cost-effective electrochemical oxidation&#8211;reduction treatment, which enables reducing carbon dioxide to carbon monoxide with a Faradaic efficiency of 87% at &#8722;0.8 V vs RHE, significantly higher than that of untreated silver foil under the same conditions. Electron backscattered diffraction analysis reveals that there is a distinct grain refining during the initial CO2 electrochemical reduction from Ag oxide to OD-Ag. Experiment results indicated that the catalytic activity and selectivity are closely linked to the grain boundary and nanoporous structure on the surface, which has also been proven by theoretical calculation. However, after a long catalysis time (12 h), it was found that the surface grain coarsened and the thickness of the nanostructured layer reduced, resulting in the deactivation of the OD-Ag electrode. A dissolution&#8211;redeposition mechanism was proposed to govern the degradation of OD-Ag. The catalytic activity can be regenerated again by applying electrochemical oxidation&#8211;reduction treatment, which can increase the thickness of the porous layer and electrochemical active surface area significantly.</description>
      <author>Mengying Yang, Jingjing Wu, Yue Li, Haitao Pan, Hongbo Cui, Xianglong Lu, Xiaohong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00217</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biocatalytic Enantioselective Reduction of Cyclopropenyl Esters and Ketones Using Ene-Reductases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00899</link>
      <description>Tomohiro Yasukawa, Pierre Gilles, Juliette Martin, Julien Boutet, Janine Cossy, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394581090

                Enantioselective reduction of cyclopropenyl esters and ketones to optically active cyclopropanes has been achieved by using whole-cell-overexpressing ene-reductases (EREDs). By using these enzymes, trans-cyclopropanes were isolated in good yield and high enantiomeric excess. A wide range of optically active cyclopropane esters and ketones were obtained, and a variety of substituent patterns on the cyclopropenes were tolerated.</description>
      <author>Tomohiro Yasukawa, Pierre Gilles, Juliette Martin, Julien Boutet, Janine Cossy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ene-Reductase-Catalyzed Enantioselective Desymmetrization of Cyclohexadienones: Straightforward Access to All-Carbon Quaternary Stereocenters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00239</link>
      <description>Xiaofan Wu, Lin Yang, Zhigang Liu, Ke Zhang, Zedu Huang, Fen&#8208;Er Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394581211

                An unprecedented enzyme-catalyzed enantioselective desymmetrization of achiral 2,5-cyclohexadienones has been reported. Using ene-reductases as the biocatalysts, a variety of &#947;,&#947;-disubstituted cyclohexadienones were reduced to the respective chiral cyclohexenones bearing an all-carbon quaternary stereocenter in high yields (up to 96%) along with low levels of over-reduction (less than 4% cyclohexanones in most cases) and good enantioselectivities (mostly 99% ee), which are superior to the enantioselectivities obtained with the chemocatalysis. A mutagenesis study indicated residue Q232 was likely important for NCR in providing cyclohexenones selectively over cyclohexanones, and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations were performed to rationalize the good enantioselectivity and low level of over-reduction observed for this enzyme. The deuterium-labeling experiment suggested the hydrogen at the N5 atom of the reduced flavin cofactor added to the face of the substrate 1a that has the bulkier phenyl group facing toward it. The current work expands the substrate scope of ene-reductases, providing an efficient, stereoselective access to valuable chiral &#947;,&#947;-disubstituted cyclohexenones, and will stimulate the development of other classes of enzyme-catalyzed enantioselective desymmetrization of cyclohexadienones.</description>
      <author>Xiaofan Wu, Lin Yang, Zhigang Liu, Ke Zhang, Zedu Huang, Fen&#8208;Er Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00239</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
