<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:42:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Lattice Oxygen in Ceria by Plasma Exsolution of MoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; with Atomic Dispersion for NO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Abatement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00069</link>
      <description>Yong Yin, Bing Luo, Sun Yu, Pengfei Xie, Haifeng Xiong, Tianle Zhu, Xiang Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393084436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Yin, Bing Luo, Sun Yu, Pengfei Xie, Haifeng Xiong, Tianle Zhu, Xiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Electron-Transfer-Generated Aryl Sulfonyl Ammonium Salt: Metal-Free Photoredox-Catalyzed Modular Construction of Sulfonamides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00816</link>
      <description>Fang Yan, Qing Li, Songzhe Fu, Yadong Yang, Dehong Yang, Shuang Yao, Man Ki Song, Hong Deng, Xianwei Sui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393093155

                Sulfonamides are prominently featured in organic synthesis and medicinal chemistry. Yet, a general synthetic platform for the modular construction of aryl sulfonamides remains elusive. Herein, a metal-free photoredox-catalyzed three-component construction of aryl sulfonamides via an aryl sulfonyl ammonium salt intermediate, which was generated in situ via a SET event, has been established. A variety of structurally diverse primary, secondary, and tertiary aryl sulfonamides were synthesized rapidly from abundant amines or sodium azide under mild conditions. Notably, the primary aliphatic amine, which remains challenging in the Cu-catalyzed protocols, worked well in this approach. Moreover, aryl sulfonyl fluoride can be accessed smoothly as well, using potassium hydrogen fluoride as the nucleophile. The potential utility of this conversion is demonstrated in the facile construction of three bioactive drug compounds. Preliminary mechanistic studies have revealed that the aryl sulfonyl radical and aryl sulfonyl ammonium salt are the key intermediates in this mechanistically innovative methodology.</description>
      <author>Fang Yan, Qing Li, Songzhe Fu, Yadong Yang, Dehong Yang, Shuang Yao, Man Ki Song, Hong Deng, Xianwei Sui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Splitting Integrated with Self-Transfer Hydrogenolysis for Efficient Demethoxylation of Guaiacols to Phenols over the Ni/MgO Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00038</link>
      <description>Xiaohong Ren, Qiang Qian, Zhuohua Sun, Ting Wei, Xiaoqiang Yu, Zeming Rong, Changzhi Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393097258

                This work demonstrates the upgrading of lignin-derived monomers through a cascade demethoxylation, aqueous-phase reforming reaction, eliminating the need for external hydrogen supply. The core of this research lies in the use of neat water as both reaction medium and the hydrogen donor over a multifunctional Ni/MgO catalyst, which is responsible for water splitting, aqueous-phase reforming of in situ generated methanol, and selective cleavage of the C&#8211;O bond, finally establishing an efficient one-pot approach achieving a high yield of phenols. Reaction mechanism studies proved that the initial H* source came from water by its splitting on the surface of the Ni/MgO catalyst, which triggered the fracture of the aromatic ether bond to afford phenols and CH3O*. The subsequent aqueous-phase reforming of CH3O* and OH* generated more hydrogen and further accelerated the hydrodeoxygenation (HDO) process. A high conversion of 87.8% with a selectivity of 88.9% for phenol could be achieved at 190 &#176;C from guaiacol. Thanks to the interesting water-splitting mechanisms and strong metal&#8211;support interaction (SMSI), Ni/MgO exhibited significantly enhanced stability compared to the previously reported nanoporous Ni catalysts. Further, with real lignin as the substrate, 16.3 wt % combined yield of phenol and 4-methylphenol could be acquired under optimized conditions. Overall, this "H2-free" approach offers a promising alternative to conventional biorefinery processes, addressing the challenges of hydrogen sourcing and economic feasibility.</description>
      <author>Xiaohong Ren, Qiang Qian, Zhuohua Sun, Ting Wei, Xiaoqiang Yu, Zeming Rong, Changzhi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switchable Synthesis of Ethylene/Acrylate Copolymers by a Dinickel Catalyst: Evidence for Chain Growth on Both Nickel Centers and Concepts of Cation Exchange Polymerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00156</link>
      <description>Shuoyan Xiong, Heather A. Spinney, Brad C. Bailey, Briana S. Henderson, Adjeoda A. Tekpor, Matthew R. Espinosa, Paramita Saha, Theodor Agapie, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393157067

                A dinickel complex, X-Ni2, was developed and demonstrated to have a high performance in ethylene/acrylate copolymerization. Further mechanistic studies revealed that X-Ni2 performs acrylate insertion at both Ni centers at distinct rates. Addition of NaBArF24 to X-Ni2 leads to 1:1 binding and serves as a switch for tuning catalytic activity, copolymer MW and acrylate incorporation. NMR studies of cation binding, when present in substoichiometric amounts, suggest a dynamic process involving cation exchange. This phenomenon provides an alternative strategy for controlling chain growth in polar polyolefin synthesis and was probed herein.</description>
      <author>Shuoyan Xiong, Heather A. Spinney, Brad C. Bailey, Briana S. Henderson, Adjeoda A. Tekpor, Matthew R. Espinosa, Paramita Saha, Theodor Agapie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ketyl Radical Generation by Photoexcited Palladium and Development of Organopalladium-Type Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00510</link>
      <description>Kosaku Tanaka, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393162411

                Enabling reactions of traditional substrates that are inert to Pd catalysts has the potential for further advancements in the field of Pd chemistry. In this study, we developed a method for generating ketyl radicals through the reaction of a photoexcited Pd species with ketones. Upon subsequent reaction with olefins, the ketyl radicals generated through this method yielded Pd-specific reductive and Heck-type coupling products. Mechanistic studies indicated that the proposed radical generation method exhibits characteristics distinct from those of traditional methods such as SmI2 reduction and photoredox-catalyzed reactions.</description>
      <author>Kosaku Tanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Photocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Methanation by the Construction of Cooperative Copper Dual-Active Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00060</link>
      <description>Minghui Zhang, Yuyin Mao, Xiaolei Bao, Peng Wang, Yuanyuan Liu, Zhaoke Zheng, Hefeng Cheng, Ying Dai, Zeyan Wang, Baibiao Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393164230

                Selective photocatalytic CO2 methanation provides an attractive avenue to address energy and environmental issues. However, impediments such as the sluggish adsorption and activation of CO2 and H2O molecules, along with unexpected intermediate desorption, greatly restrict the activity and selectivity of photocatalytic CO2 methanation. To address these issues, we devised a dual-active site catalyst comprising Cu single atoms (SAs) and nanoclusters (NCs) supported on defective TiO2 (Cu1+NCs/BT). As a result, a remarkable CH4 selectivity of 98% with a yield of 19.63 &#956;mol gcat.&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 can be obtained over the as-prepared Cu1+NCs/BT in pure water. Mechanistic studies reveal the enhanced performance could be ascribed to the synergistic effect of the Cu dual-active sites, where Cu SAs adsorb and activate CO2, while Cu NCs boost H2O adsorption and dissociation for *H coverage. Additionally, the adjacent Cu dual-active site could jointly stabilize the *CO intermediate and reduce the energy barrier for *CO protonation, promoting the multielectron transfer process.</description>
      <author>Minghui Zhang, Yuyin Mao, Xiaolei Bao, Peng Wang, Yuanyuan Liu, Zhaoke Zheng, Hefeng Cheng, Ying Dai, Zeyan Wang, Baibiao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00060</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
