<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 01:08:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Exploration of the Origin of Alkaline Dependence in the Oxidation of 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural Catalyzed by NiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00940</link>
      <description>Si Wang, Haisong Feng, Tianyong Liu, Yuan Deng, Meng Zhang, Sylvia Zhao, Juan Han, Xin Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399760359

                Alkaline dependence is a common phenomenon in the electrochemical oxidation of biomass, and investigating the influence of alkalinity on the oxidation mechanisms is crucial for enhancing both the activity and the selectivity of biomass oxidation. Herein, we constructed five NiO2Hx catalysts under different alkaline environments (pH &#8776; 9&#8211;13) and employed density functional theory methods to investigate the reaction mechanisms of the selective oxidation of the biomass platform molecule 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF). The origin of alkaline dependence in HMF electrochemical oxidation was analyzed, and the results indicate that the catalyst alkalinity determines the oxidation pathway of HMF to 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid: under weak alkalinity (pH &#8776; 9&#8211;11), the adsorption and activation of the alcohol group in HMF are more favorable, resulting in preferential oxidation of the alcohol group; under strong alkalinity (pH &#8776; 11&#8211;13), the aldehyde group of HMF is more prone to adsorb and activate on the catalyst surface, resulting in a predominant aldehyde oxidation. With the increase in the alkalinity of NiO2Hx, there is a decrease of H atom coverage and an increase in the valence state of Ni, resulting in a transformation in the preferential oxidation pathway of HMF from the alcohol group to the aldehyde group as well as a transition in the oxidation mechanism from direct oxidation to indirect oxidation. NiOOH under moderately alkaline environment effectively reduces the Gibbs free energy change for C&#8211;H/O&#8211;H bonds cleavage, lowering the reaction energy. It significantly enhances the oxidation ability of alcohol and aldehyde groups, exhibiting the highest catalytic performance in the conversion of HMF to FDCA. The study not only provide a comprehensive explanation for the alkaline dependence of HMF oxidation but also offer guidance on how to rationally design catalysts for improving oxidative performance through alkalinity adjustments.</description>
      <author>Si Wang, Haisong Feng, Tianyong Liu, Yuan Deng, Meng Zhang, Sylvia Zhao, Juan Han, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Ni Inverse Catalyst as a Highly Active and Stable Ru-free Catalyst for Ammonia Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02313</link>
      <description>Hongwang Liu, Rongrong Zhang, Sibao Liu, Guozhu Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399766265

                Catalytic ammonia decomposition is an efficient way to produce clean hydrogen, but the design of ammonia decomposition catalysts is limited by the high cost of noble metals and the low activity. Herein, we report a CeO2/Ni inverse catalyst prepared by the coprecipitation method, exhibiting a high hydrogen production rate of 79.6 mmol gcat&#8211;1 min&#8211;1 at 500 &#176;C, which is better than traditional supported Ni-based catalysts and even many of the Ru-based catalysts reported in the literature. In addition, this inverse catalyst showed catalytic stability for 100 h continuous reaction at 600 &#176;C. Systematic catalyst characterizations revealed that the inverse CeO2/Ni catalyst exhibits small cerium oxide nanoparticle islands supported on the Ni nanoparticles. The inverse structure confers enhanced metal&#8211;support interaction and abundant Ni-CeO2 interface sites, which facilitate the generation of highly concentrated oxygen vacancies and abundant electron-rich Ni atoms at the interface under reduction conditions. These features endow the CeO2/Ni inverse configuration possessing increased number of adsorption sites for NH3 molecules, enhancing N&#8211;H bond breaking, and facilitating the recombination desorption of N and H adatoms, thereby accelerating the reaction rate. This work highlights the significance of constructing a rational configuration between the active metal nanoparticles and oxides to enhance the catalytic efficiency for NH3 decomposition.</description>
      <author>Hongwang Liu, Rongrong Zhang, Sibao Liu, Guozhu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Electronic and Vibrational Spectroscopy of Electrochemical Transformations on a Metal-Oxide Surface during Oxygen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05931</link>
      <description>Tanja Cuk, Michael Paolino, Suryansh Singh, James J. P. Stewart, Xihan Chen, Ilya Vinogradov, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399767385

                Oxygen evolution catalysis fuels the planet through photosynthesis and is a primary means for hydrogen storage in energy technologies. Yet the detection of intermediates of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) central to the catalytic mechanism has been an ongoing challenge. This tutorial and minireview covers the relevance of ultrafast electronic and vibrational spectroscopy of the electrochemical transformations of a metal-oxide surface undergoing OER. Here, we highlight the ultrafast trigger and probes of the electron-doped SrTiO3/electrolyte as the primary example in which light probes across the electromagnetic spectrum have detected intermediate forms. We compare the results to other early transition-metal-oxide surfaces when they exist for select probes and longer timescales. The first part covers how the catalytic reaction is triggered by ultrafast light pulses, describing the semiconducting depletion and electrolyte Helmholtz layers. The second part covers the detection of the intermediates that occur upon electron and proton transfer from an adsorbed water species by transient spectroscopy. Their detection by a broadband visible probe, a mid-infrared evanescent wave, and a coherent acoustic wave respectively targets electronic states, vibrational levels, and lattice strain respectively. One of the aims is a tutorial on how these measurements are made and to what extent they allow for the interpretation of experimental spectra by intermediate configurations predicted by theory. Another aim is to describe what these experiments directly recommend in terms of future efforts to visualize the OER intermediates and their dynamics.</description>
      <author>Tanja Cuk, Michael Paolino, Suryansh Singh, James J. P. Stewart, Xihan Chen, Ilya Vinogradov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Control of Oxygen Vacancy Density in In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; to Boost Methanol Synthesis from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01929</link>
      <description>Wenhang Wang, Keke Huo, Yang Wang, Jinghao Xie, Xu Sun, Yingluo He, Meng Li, Jie Liang, Xinhua Gao, Guohui Yang, Si&#8208;Min Lin, Fuyang Cao, Jian Hu, Mingbo Wu, Noritatsu Tsubaki, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399771091

                Oxygen vacancies (Ov) in reducible metal oxides are the vital active sites for methanol synthesis via a CO2 hydrogenation technology. However, the relationship between the density of Ov and the methanol synthesis performance is still ambiguous, and it still shows a lack of a versatile strategy to precisely tailor the number of Ov. In this study, with In2O3 as a representatively catalytic component, the density functional theory computation confirms that the Ov property, especially Ov density, is pivotal to enhancing methanol selectivity of CO2 hydrogenation by suppressing the undesirable reverse water&#8211;gas shift reaction for CO formation, which is attributed to the unique electronic density of In atoms around Ov. To verify the theoretical results, we report a protocol to optimize the concentration of Ov on In2O3 by sequential carbonization and oxidation (SCO) treatments of In-based metal&#8211;organic frameworks, during which the consumption of carbon species and the structural reconstruction of the In2O3 crystal regulated the particle size and Ov concentration of In2O3 by varying the oxidation temperature. The In2O3-5 catalyst carbonized and oxidized at 500 &#176;C exhibits good methanol selectivity (72.3%) at a CO2 conversion of 9.9% under 330 &#176;C, 3 MPa, and high space velocity of 12,000 L&#8211;1 kgcat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1. Multiple in situ characterizations clarify that the proposed Ov property regulating the SCO strategy is convenient to boost methanol synthesis by altering the CO2 hydrogenation process to the HCOO* intermediate-dominated pathway. Our work provides the catalyst design strategy and will shed light on the rational design of reducible metal oxide-based catalysts with a controllable Ov density.</description>
      <author>Wenhang Wang, Keke Huo, Yang Wang, Jinghao Xie, Xu Sun, Yingluo He, Meng Li, Jie Liang, Xinhua Gao, Guohui Yang, Si&#8208;Min Lin, Fuyang Cao, Jian Hu, Mingbo Wu, Noritatsu Tsubaki</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Step Hydrothermal Synthesis of Sn-Doped Sb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Solar Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01762</link>
      <description>Zhenbin Wang, Sanghyun Bae, Milo&#353; Baljozovi&#263;, Pardis Adams, David Yong, Erin Service, Thomas Moehl, Wenzhe Niu, S. David Tilley, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399771389

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenbin Wang, Sanghyun Bae, Milo&#353; Baljozovi&#263;, Pardis Adams, David Yong, Erin Service, Thomas Moehl, Wenzhe Niu, S. David Tilley</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01762</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QM/MM MD Study on the Reaction Mechanism of Thymidine Phosphorylation Catalyzed by the Enzyme &lt;i&gt;Thermotoga maritima&lt;/i&gt; Thymidine Kinase 1</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01867</link>
      <description>Samanta Makurat, Rui P. P. Neves, Maria J. Ramos, Janusz Rak, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399783848

                Here, we report mechanistic studies on type II thymidine kinase, Thermotoga maritima TmTK, aiming to predict barriers for the enzyme-catalyzed reaction. Extensive umbrella sampling QM/MM MD simulations (PBE/GPW/DZVP-GTH-PBE:AMBER) resulted in a free energy barrier for the phosphorylation reaction's rate-limiting step of 16.6 kcal&#183;mol&#8211;1, which is in an excellent agreement with the experimentally reported value. An atomistic picture provided by our simulations reveals that the reaction follows a concerted, dissociative SN2 reaction mechanism in which the 5&#8242;-oxygen of the ribose moiety in thymidine is phosphorylated by the &#947;-phosphate of ATP, while assisted by an asynchronous deprotonation of the 5&#8242;-hydroxyl by a GLU84 base. The reaction was calculated to be endergonic, with a reaction free energy of 10.8 kcal&#183;mol&#8211;1, and it can be followed by low-barrier processes that promote the unbinding of the phosphorylated thymidine product, namely, the deprotonation of the GLU84 by the thymidine-phosphate that is accompanied by a weaker binding of the product to the Mg2+ ion.</description>
      <author>Samanta Makurat, Rui P. P. Neves, Maria J. Ramos, Janusz Rak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01867</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bottom-Up Synthesis of Platinum Dual-Atom Catalysts on Cerium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01840</link>
      <description>Martijn J. Mekkering, Petrus C. M. Laan, Alessandro Troglia, Roland Bliem, Ali Can K&#305;z&#305;lkaya, Gadi Rothenberg, Ning Yan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399783895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Martijn J. Mekkering, Petrus C. M. Laan, Alessandro Troglia, Roland Bliem, Ali Can K&#305;z&#305;lkaya, Gadi Rothenberg, Ning Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of (Rh&#8211;Fe)&#8211;FeO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Complex Sites Enables Methanol Synthesis from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00339</link>
      <description>Yifeng Zhu, Ran Luo, Honghong Shi, Katherine Koh, Libor Kova&#345;&#237;k, John L. Fulton, Johannes A. Lercher, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong, Oliver Y. Guti&#233;rrez, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399803165

                We addressed the challenges of designing catalysts for selective CO2 hydrogenation by incorporating Fe oxide species onto Rh nanoparticles. Nanoscopic FeOx domains created a "reverse catalyst" structure (i.e., a metal oxide supported on a metal) that increased the density of interfacial sites compared to traditional supported catalysts. The contact between the metal nanoparticle and the oxide overlayer induced the formation of a surface Rh&#8211;Fe alloy that stabilized methoxy groups while suppressing hydrogenolysis to methane. Sites at FeOx&#8211;metal interfaces interact with CO2 much stronger than sites on metal surfaces, show larger energy barriers to cleave the C&#8211;O bonds, and offer a barrierless pathway for the hydrogenation of methoxy species to methanol. Consequently, the multifunctional sites over FeOx/Rh&#8211;Fe catalysts highlight and meet the requirements of a selective methanol catalyst: strong interaction with CO2 to ensure a high density of transition states, metal sites to activate and make hydrogen available to surface intermediates, and high energy barriers for C&#8211;O bond cleavage to form carbides. These synthetic and catalytic chemistries, demonstrated for Rh&#8211;Fe&#8211;FeOx interfaces, enable us to overcome the limitations to the design of methanol production catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yifeng Zhu, Ran Luo, Honghong Shi, Katherine Koh, Libor Kova&#345;&#237;k, John L. Fulton, Johannes A. Lercher, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong, Oliver Y. Guti&#233;rrez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crucial Effect of Subsurface Hydrogen on Low-Barrier Hydrogenation and Keto&#8211;Enol Tautomerization of Carbonyl Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01441</link>
      <description>Philipp A. Haugg, Jan Smyczek, P. Hubert, Carsten Schr&#246;der, Swetlana Schauermann, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399804824

                Hydrogenation of a normally highly stable carbonyl group is an important step in many technological applications, including emerging molecular systems for reversible hydrogen storage. In this report, we present a mechanistic study of low-temperature hydrogenation of carbonyl compounds over Pd, proceeding via keto&#8211;enol tautomerization in the first step. The specific focus of this study is on the role of subsurface hydrogen absorbed in the nearest region below the Pd surface. Employing a combination of real space microscopic and operando spectroscopic surface sensitive techniques, as well as molecular beams, we show that subsurface H plays a crucial role in both keto&#8211;enol tautomerization and hydrogenation of the carbonyl compound acetylpyridine on the Pd(111) model catalyst. We demonstrate that a growing amount of subsurface H results in an enhanced abundance of enol species followed by hydrogenation already at cryogenic temperatures. In contrast, if only H adsorbed on the surface is present, no hydrogenation occurs, and substantially smaller amounts of enol species are formed. The population of subsurface H is also accompanied by a change in the mechanism of enol stabilization via hydrogen bonding: while in the presence of subsurface H specific enol-containing dimers are predominately formed, which strongly interact via the enol-acetyl or enol&#8211;enol groups, in the absence of subsurface H, a weaker interaction between the adsorbates occurs, which is realized mainly via the enol group of one molecule with a H atom belonging to the pyridine ring of the neighboring adsorbate. The observed strongly correlated behavior between the growing concentration of subsurface H, enhanced abundance of the enol form of acetylpyridine, and the onset of hydrogenation prove the crucial role of subsurface H species in the low-barrier hydrogenation pathway of carbonyl compounds. The obtained atomistic-level insights offer a prospect of controllable low-temperature hydrogenation of carbonyl compounds by tuning the abundance of subsurface H, which has not been available so far.</description>
      <author>Philipp A. Haugg, Jan Smyczek, P. Hubert, Carsten Schr&#246;der, Swetlana Schauermann</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt(II) Nanoclusters Incorporated in Ordered Mesoporous Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Stable and Coke-Resistant Propane Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02067</link>
      <description>Fabian Ebert, Piyush Ingale, Sarah Vogl, Sebastian Praetz, Christopher Schlesiger, Nils Pfister, Raoul Naumann d&#8217;Alnoncourt, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Arne Thomas, Esteban Gioria, Frank Rosowski, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399806935

                Due to their availability, low cost, and activity, cobalt-based catalysts are a promising alternative to platinum for the industrial propane dehydrogenation processes. However, their low stability due to sintering, phase transformation, and coke deposition leads to severe deactivation. In this work, the synthesis of amorphous, ordered mesoporous alumina with stabilized Co2+ nanoclusters (Co-m-Al2O3) via an evaporation-induced self-assembly synthesis route is presented. The ordered mesoporous alumina is characterized for containing a large amount of defective pentacoordinate Al3+ sites and a small amount of strong acid sites. The incorporation of Co2+ clusters within the m-Al2O3 structure enhances the dispersion and stability and preserves their reduction even after prolonged time on stream. This leads to a highly selective and steady catalytic performance in the propane dehydrogenation reaction under industrial-relevant conditions. A significantly low deactivation rate of 0.53 d&#8211;1 with stable propylene selectivity of 95% is observed after 23 h, resulting in a 117% higher space&#8211;time yield toward propylene compared to the state-of-the-art impregnated Co/&#947;-Al2O3 catalyst. Furthermore, Co-m-Al2O3 leads to 4.6 times less coke formation, measured in situ for the first time. The detailed study of the nature of the cobalt sites, together with the acidic properties of the alumina supports, provides a deeper understanding of cobalt-based catalysts for dehydrogenation reactions.</description>
      <author>Fabian Ebert, Piyush Ingale, Sarah Vogl, Sebastian Praetz, Christopher Schlesiger, Nils Pfister, Raoul Naumann d&#8217;Alnoncourt, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Arne Thomas, Esteban Gioria, Frank Rosowski</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Electron Bias in Hydroarylation of Phenylpropiolic Acid Derivatives To Enable Highly Reversed Regio- and Stereoselectivity via Steric and Transient Post Addition Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01944</link>
      <description>Hui Li, Xu Tian, Qin-Qin Dang, Jing Zhang, Zhen&#8208;Kang Wen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399812225

                The regio- and stereoselective hydroarylation of internal alkynes via transition-metal catalysis offers a direct approach for designing highly stereodefined multifunctionalized olefins. Through recognition of electronic bias, &#946;-syn-hydroarylation of electronic poor alkynes with arylboronic acids has been well studied. However, from the same starting materials, achieving the opposite &#945;-selective and highly anti-stereoselective hydroarylation remains a significant challenge due to these inherent biases. Therefore, an alternative synthetic pathway to trisubstituted alkenes with reversed positioning and configuration of substituents is highly desirable. Based on steric repulsion-induced regioselectivity and transient post-addition coordination-directed stereoselectivity, we report herein an &#945;-hydroarylation method for phenylpropiolic esters using a nickel catalyst that promotes a formal anti-addition pathway. A broad range of organoboronic acids and phenylpropiolic acid derivatives are compatible with this hydroarylation protocol, offering an alternative selectivity to traditional &#946;-syn-hydroarylation reactions. The distinct advantages of our method include precise control over selectivity, reduced catalyst loading, and broad tolerance toward functional groups. These features highlight the potential of our approach in the synthesis of multifunctionalized alkenes and in the late-stage modification of alkyne-based drug intermediates, showcasing its versatility and applicability in organic synthesis.</description>
      <author>Hui Li, Xu Tian, Qin-Qin Dang, Jing Zhang, Zhen&#8208;Kang Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01944</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Durable Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers through Suppressed Electrochemical Corrosion of a NiFe&#8211;Graphitic Carbon Shell Anode Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02696</link>
      <description>Young Sang Park, Gwan Hyun Choi, Jiyoon Jung, Cheol&#8208;Hee Ahn, Seung Sang Hwang, Myeong Gyun Nam, Pil J. Yoo, Albert S. Lee, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399812294

                Anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) shows potential for hydrogen production using cost-effective nonplatinum group metal (non-PGM) catalysts, achieving high current density performance. However, challenges remain in developing materials, including stable membranes and ionomers under alkaline conditions and non-PGM catalysts that are both high-performing and durable for the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This study presents an approach for synthesizing highly crystalline carbon-encapsulated metal nanoparticle networks using a polyphenolic tannic acid precursor and non-PGM NiFe metal cores, creating a durable OER catalyst. The simplified synthetic process introduces graphitic carbon layers (GCLs) to encompass the NiFe catalytic nanoparticles. Rigorous testing over 1100 h of continuous current operation demonstrates the stability of the catalysts, which is attributed to the robust interaction between the catalyst and the carbon support. The enhanced durability is further confirmed through theoretical calculations, showing greater resistance to corrosion in graphitic carbon compared to defective carbon. This study highlights the importance of highly crystalline carbon structures for achieving both high performance and durability in OER catalysts, which are vital for cost-effective AEMWE technologies. The findings contribute significantly to understanding the role of regulating carbon crystalline properties in developing efficient and durable non-PGM OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Young Sang Park, Gwan Hyun Choi, Jiyoon Jung, Cheol&#8208;Hee Ahn, Seung Sang Hwang, Myeong Gyun Nam, Pil J. Yoo, Albert S. Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast Photocatalytic Hydrogen Peroxide Generation by Singlet Oxygen-Engaged Sequential Excitation Energy and Electron-Transfer Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01591</link>
      <description>Xiangkang Zeng, Tianyi Wang, Zhuyuan Wang, Mike Tebyetekerwa, Yue Liu, Zhuoyue Liu, Gen Wang, Ary Anggara Wibowo, Gregory K. Pierens, Qinfen Gu, Xiwang Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399812367

                Sequential excitation energy and electron transfer (ET) are ubiquitous pathways for converting solar energy to chemical energy in photosynthesis. Mimicking this unique process for chemical synthesis is promising yet still a big challenge. Herein, taking photosynthesis as an inspiration, we demonstrate an interesting pathway for oxygen reduction to hydrogen peroxide (H2O2), an important and valuable commodity chemical. The proposed route was verified on a biomimetic photocatalyst, i.e., an aluminum porphyrin metal&#8211;organic framework nanosheet (Al&#8211;TCPP). Experimental investigations and theoretical calculations reveal that the dioxygen molecule is first converted to a highly active singlet oxygen intermediate through an excitation energy transfer (EET) and then reduced to H2O2 via the photogenerated electrons with a reduced barrier over Al&#8211;TCPP. Consequently, Al&#8211;TCPP shows a 32 times higher H2O2 evolution rate than that of the pristine TCPP counterpart, wherein excitation energy transfer mainly exists. This study presents a paradigm to mimic the photosynthetic sequential excitation energy and electron-transfer process for improved synthesis of valuable commodity chemicals.</description>
      <author>Xiangkang Zeng, Tianyi Wang, Zhuyuan Wang, Mike Tebyetekerwa, Yue Liu, Zhuoyue Liu, Gen Wang, Ary Anggara Wibowo, Gregory K. Pierens, Qinfen Gu, Xiwang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Induced Interfacial Lanthanum Hydride and Hydroxide Bifunctional Sites for Selective Hydrogenolysis of Furanic Compounds to Alkyl Diols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01266</link>
      <description>Yongsheng Zhang, Hongxia Xue, Mengqing Cheng, Xiaomeng Yang, Zhen Zhang, Xinbao Zhao, Armin Rezayan, Dandan Han, Dan Wu, Chunbao Xu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399830090

                Selective hydrogenolysis of C&#8211;O bonds in biomass-derived oxygenated molecules is of great significance for the conversion of biomass to chemicals and fuels, especially for the inert C&#8211;O&#8211;C bonds in tetrahydrofuran rings. However, the lack of precise active sites results in the low activity of this reaction. In this work, the metal&#8211;support interfacial structure of the Ni&#8211;La2O3 catalyst was well-controlled by reducing LaNiO3 perovskite at different temperatures. During the reduction, the exsolution and segregation of Ni in the LaNiO3 perovskite led to the formation of metallic Ni nanoparticles and interfacial oxygen-vacant Ni2+-Ov-La3+ sites. Hydrogen spillover from Ni nanoparticles to the interface promoted the in situ generation of La&#8211;OH species under reaction conditions. At the same time, the oxygen vacancies at the interfacial Ni2+-Ov-La3+ sites can accommodate the spilled H, inducing the formation of the La&#8211;H species. The hydroxyl group in tetrahydrofurfuryl alcohol (THFA) interacted with La&#8211;OH through a metal alkoxide intermediate, which was subsequently hydrogenolyzed by the La&#8211;H to produce 1,5-pentanediol (1,5-PeD). The intimate La&#8211;H and La&#8211;OH bifunctional sites on the metal&#8211;support interface have a strong synergistic effect, endowing the Ni&#8211;La2O3 catalyst with a high THFA hydrogenolysis activity. The proposed interfacial La&#8211;H assisted C&#8211;O bond hydrogenolysis provides an idea for the design of efficient hydrodeoxygenation catalysts for biomass upgrading.</description>
      <author>Yongsheng Zhang, Hongxia Xue, Mengqing Cheng, Xiaomeng Yang, Zhen Zhang, Xinbao Zhao, Armin Rezayan, Dandan Han, Dan Wu, Chunbao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Highly Active GaN:ZnO Photocatalysts Applicable to Z-Scheme Overall Water Splitting Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02172</link>
      <description>Kaiwei Liu, Boyang Zhang, Jiaming Zhang, Yao Xu, Jifang Zhang, Zihao Zhang, Shaoyong Ke, Ningning Wang, Shanshan Chen, Guijun Ma, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399848526

                The Z-scheme system, integrating an oxygen evolution photocatalyst (OEP) with a hydrogen evolution photocatalyst (HEP), is an ideal strategy for photocatalytic overall water splitting (OWS), in which the development of an efficient OEP remains a challenge. Herein, the GaN:ZnO photocatalyst was synthesized by an ammonium halide-based process to perform a recorded apparent quantum yield of 30% at 420 nm for oxygen evolution from water. It made the GaN:ZnO a remarkable OEP for the construction of three distinct Z-scheme OWS systems, including an unbiased-photoelectrochemical sheet, direct collision, and redox-ion-mediated electron shuttle. The features and parameters of each Z-scheme system were discussed in relation to water splitting, and the most efficient one was established by employing [Fe(CN)6]3&#8211;/[Fe(CN)6]4&#8211; as an electron shuttle and SrTiO3:Rh as an HEP. This work not only provides a methodology for synthesizing an efficient GaN:ZnO photocatalyst but also highlights its great potential as an OEP applicable to constructing various Z-scheme OWS systems.</description>
      <author>Kaiwei Liu, Boyang Zhang, Jiaming Zhang, Yao Xu, Jifang Zhang, Zihao Zhang, Shaoyong Ke, Ningning Wang, Shanshan Chen, Guijun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Accelerated First-Principles Study of the Hydrodeoxygenation of Propanoic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01419</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Bin Yang, Kareem Abdelfatah, Shrishnu Kumar Kundu, Biplab Rajbanshi, Gabriel Terejanu, Andreas Heyden, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399848574

                The complex reaction network of catalytic biomass conversions often involves hundreds of surface intermediates and thousands of reaction steps, greatly hindering the rational design of metal catalysts for these conversions. Here, we present a framework of machine learning (ML)-accelerated first-principles studies for the hydrodeoxygenation (HDO) of propanoic acid over transition metal surfaces. The microkinetic model (MKM) is initially parametrized by ML-predicted energies and iteratively improved by identifying the rate-determining species and steps (RDS), computing their energies by density functional theory (DFT), and reparameterizing the MKM until all the RDS are computed by DFT. The Gaussian process (GP) model performs significantly better than the linear ridge regression model for predicting both the adsorption free energies and transition state free energies. Parameterized with energies from the GP model, only 5&#8211;20% of the full reaction network has to be computed by DFT for the MKM to possess DFT-level accuracy for the TOF and dominant reaction pathway. While the linear ridge regression model performs worse than the GP model, its performance is greatly improved when only transition states are predicted by the regression model and adsorption energies are computed by DFT. Overall, we find that a high accuracy in adsorption free energies is more important for a reliable MKM than a high accuracy in TS free energies. Finally, based on the GP model with GOH and GCHCHCO as catalyst descriptors, we build two-dimensional volcano plots in activity and selectivity that can help design promising alloy catalysts for HDO reactions of organic acids.</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Bin Yang, Kareem Abdelfatah, Shrishnu Kumar Kundu, Biplab Rajbanshi, Gabriel Terejanu, Andreas Heyden</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into the Electrochemical Oxidation of 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural on a Thin-Film Ni Anode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01448</link>
      <description>Aditya Prajapati, Nitish Govindarajan, Wenyu Sun, Jiayi Huang, Hossein Bemana, Jeremy T. Feaster, Sneha A. Akhade, Nikolay Kornienko, Christopher Hahn, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399853867

                The electrochemical oxidation of alcohols is being explored as a favorable substitute for the oxygen evolution reaction owing to its capability to generate high-value products and lower overpotentials. Herein, we present a systematic investigation into the electrochemical oxidation of 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF), a model biomass platform chemical, on a thin-film nickel catalyst, aiming to investigate the underlying reaction mechanism and shed light on the role of the catalyst's microenvironment and phase on activity and product selectivity. Utilizing a combined experimental and computational approach, we demonstrate that NiOOH is the active phase for HMF oxidation. Additionally, we find a substantial impact of the electrochemical environment, particularly the electrolyte pH, on the reaction. Under highly alkaline conditions (pH = 13), higher activity for HMF oxidation is observed, accompanied by an increased selectivity toward 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) production. Conversely, a less alkaline environment (pH = 11) results in diminished HMF oxidation activity and a higher preference for the partial oxidation product 2,5-diformylfuran (DFF). Mechanistic insights from DFT studies reveal that geminal diols that are present under highly alkaline conditions undergo hydride transfer via HMFCA, while a shift to an alkoxide route occurs at a lower pH, favoring the DFF pathway. Hydride transfer energetics are also strongly affected by the surface Ni oxidation state. This integrated approach, bridging experimental and computational insights, provides a general framework for investigating the electrochemical oxidation of aldehydes and alcohols, thereby advancing rational design strategies in electrocatalysts for alcohol electro-oxidation reactions.</description>
      <author>Aditya Prajapati, Nitish Govindarajan, Wenyu Sun, Jiayi Huang, Hossein Bemana, Jeremy T. Feaster, Sneha A. Akhade, Nikolay Kornienko, Christopher Hahn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Semihydrogenation of Cinnamaldehyde by Water over a Au/&#945;-MoC Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02448</link>
      <description>Y. P. Lu, Qiao Chen, Yunlong Zhang, Wei Yan, Xiaohui Hou, Rui Huang, Dehui Deng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399854204

                Replacing H2 with H2O as the hydrogen source for the water-involved selective hydrogenation of cinnamaldehyde to cinnamyl alcohol (WSHCC) is very attractive yet is underdeveloped by a much lower H2O conversion rate than H2. Here, we report the realization of a high-efficiency WSHCC process by a synergy of CO adsorption and H2O dissociation over a Au/&#945;-MoC1&#8211;x boundary. It shows a specific molar rate of 60.86 mol molAu&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 to cinnamyl alcohol at 96 &#176;C, which is nearly 12-fold that reported earlier, and maintains a high conversion of over 99% and a high selectivity of 77%. Mechanistic studies indicate that the Au/&#945;-MoC1&#8211;x boundary accommodates atomically dispersed Au&#948;+ sites for adsorbing CO, vacating oxygen-covered &#945;-MoC1&#8211;x and thereby creating isolated Mo sites for the preferred adsorption and hydrogenation of C&#9552;O bonds over that of C&#9552;C bonds. This provides a catalyst design strategy for high-efficiency C&#9552;O hydrogenation by water.</description>
      <author>Y. P. Lu, Qiao Chen, Yunlong Zhang, Wei Yan, Xiaohui Hou, Rui Huang, Dehui Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOR-Type Titanosilicate with Specific Ti Location in Defective T3 Sites for Efficient Cyclohexanone Ammoximation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01914</link>
      <description>Zhipeng Wan, Jing-Yi Tan, Wei Chen, Longkang Zhang, Xianchen Gong, Chengwei Zhai, Hengyong Xu, Anming Zheng, Peng Wu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399855782

                Controlling the location and microenvironment of active centers in the zeolite framework is critical for understanding the in-depth structure&#8211;performance relationships of catalytic systems and constructing highly efficient catalysts. Herein, we have developed an MOR-type titanosilicate (denoted as 6M-Ti-M360) with an extremely low framework Ti content (Si/Ti = 300), exhibiting not only ultrahigh catalyst weight-based conversion (81%) but also a record-breaking turnover number (TON = 5845) per Ti site in batchwise ammoximation of cyclohexanone. Its highly isolated and active Ti species took the specific position of defective T3 sites within the eight-member ring side pockets of the MOR topology, evidenced by molecular dimension-dependent shape-selective experiments and theoretical evaluation of the catalytic activation ability of the different crystallographic Ti sites at the molecular level. Despite an extremely low Ti content but with the most active Ti on the defective T3 sites, the 6M-Ti-M360 catalyst maintained the cyclohexanone conversion and cyclohexanone oxime selectivity both as high as 99% for a long lifetime (314 h) in a continuous slurry bed reactor, capable of producing 1100 kg of oxime per gram of Ti. The clarification of the location and local microenvironment of Ti active sites may provide new insights into the exploration and construction of highly active sites in zeolitic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhipeng Wan, Jing-Yi Tan, Wei Chen, Longkang Zhang, Xianchen Gong, Chengwei Zhai, Hengyong Xu, Anming Zheng, Peng Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Chemical Step: The Role of Substrate Access in Acyltransferase from &lt;i&gt;Mycobacterium smegmatis&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00812</link>
      <description>Henrique F. Carvalho, Luuk Mestrom, Ulf Hanefeld, J&#252;rgen Pleiss, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399860420

                Acyltransferase from Mycobacterium smegmatis is a versatile enzyme, which catalyzes the transesterification of esters in aqueous media due to a kinetic preference of the synthesis reaction over the thermodynamically favored hydrolysis reaction. In the active octamer, the active site is deeply buried and connected to the protein surface by long and hydrophobic substrate access channels. The role of the access channel in controlling catalytic activity and substrate specificity was investigated by molecular dynamics simulations and Markov-state models, and the thermodynamics and kinetics of binding of acyl donors, acceptors, and water were compared. Despite the hydrophobic nature of the substrate access channel, water is present in the channel and competes with the acyl acceptors for access to the active site. The binding free energy profiles in the access channel and the flux of butyl and benzyl alcohol and vinyl acetate were analyzed in the concentration range between 10 and 500 mM and compared to water. The flux showed a maximum at an alcohol concentration of 50&#8211;100 mM, in agreement with experimental observations. At the maximum, the flux of alcohol approaches 50% of the flux of water, which explains the high transesterification rate as compared to hydrolysis. The molecular origin of this effect is due to the accumulation of alcohol molecules along the access channel. Extensive molecular dynamics simulations and analysis of trajectories by a Markov-state model provided insights into the role of the access channel in activity and specificity by controlling access and binding of competing substrates.</description>
      <author>Henrique F. Carvalho, Luuk Mestrom, Ulf Hanefeld, J&#252;rgen Pleiss</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Selectivity of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation via Support Composition Modification Adjusted the Activity Reduction of H Species over Ce&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Pr&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported Metal (Ru, Rh) Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01201</link>
      <description>De&#8208;Jiu Wang, Xiaochen Sun, Hai&#8208;Jing Yin, Hao Dong, Haichao Liu, Yawen Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399871818

                Selectivity control of supported metal catalysts, which are most widely utilized in the field of heterogeneous catalysis, is of great scientific significance to obtaining the desired chemical product in a multipath reaction but has remained a grand challenging issue. In this work, we demonstrate that the selectivity of CO2 hydrogenation from CH4 to CO can be tuned by a robust and unique support doping strategy by changing the reduction activity of H species over M/Ce1&#8211;xPrxO2&#8722;&#948; (M = Ru, Rh) in which metal (M) nanoclusters showed the same existence form on differently doped ceria nanorod supports. The CH4 selectivity of the catalyst decreased with an increase in the Pr content in the support. The selectivity of CH4 on Ru/CeO2 was higher than 90%, while on Ru/Ce0.2Pr0.8O2&#8722;&#948;, the selectivity of CO reached 80%. A variety of techniques, including steady-state isotope transient kinetic analysis (SSITKA) type in situ diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS)&#8211;mass spectrum (MS), temperature-programmed desorption (TPD) and temperature-programmed surface reaction (TPSR), had been applied in this work to analyze the structure&#8211;activity relationship between the doping of Pr and the selectivity of the CO2 hydrogenation reaction. Ru sites were not directly involved in the hydrogenation of carbon-containing intermediate species (including bicarbonate and formate) during the CO2 hydrogenation reaction. The active H species on the support sites, which are incorporated in RE3+&#8211;OH, directly contacted and reacted with the carbon-containing intermediate species. The introduction of Pr in the support weakened the reducing ability of the support, thus decreasing the reducing ability of H species on the surface of the catalyst, which further hindered the conversion of formate into CH4, resulting in the declined CH4 selectivity. Our study clearly revealed the important role of support in the CO2 hydrogenation reaction and proposed a strategy to modulate the reaction selectivity via support doping. By changing the redox performance of the support, the activity of H species on the support can be adjusted. Thus, the conversion of important reaction intermediates (such as formate) can be affected, so as to achieve precise regulation of the reaction products. We have provided a broader perspective for the selective catalyst design of heterogeneous catalysis and the reaction mechanism study of supported metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>De&#8208;Jiu Wang, Xiaochen Sun, Hai&#8208;Jing Yin, Hao Dong, Haichao Liu, Yawen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photochemical Reductive Carboxylation of &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Benzoyl Imines with Oxalate Accelerated by Formation of EDA Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02007</link>
      <description>Wen Liu, Pei Xu, H. Jiang, Menglei Li, Tian-Zi Hao, Yiqin Liu, Shaolin Zhu, Kun-Xiao Zhang, Xu Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399871819

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen Liu, Pei Xu, H. Jiang, Menglei Li, Tian-Zi Hao, Yiqin Liu, Shaolin Zhu, Kun-Xiao Zhang, Xu Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Catalyzed Dearomative &lt;i&gt;trans&lt;/i&gt;-1,2-Carboamination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02656</link>
      <description>Charles W. Davis, Yanrong Li, Yu Zhang, Zohaib Siddiqi, Peng Liu, David &#352;arlah, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399872712

                We have achieved the arenophile-mediated, copper-catalyzed dearomative trans-1,2-carboamination of nonactivated arenes with alkyl organometallic nucleophiles. This simple and practical procedure was used to prepare diverse, stereochemically rich alkylated cyclohexadienes from readily available arenes. Synthetic utility was demonstrated through the rapid preparation of complex small molecules difficult to access by conventional routes. Finally, we conducted DFT studies to explore the catalytic process, including a study of the reaction pathway and an examination of the divergent regioselectivity observed with substituted arenes.</description>
      <author>Charles W. Davis, Yanrong Li, Yu Zhang, Zohaib Siddiqi, Peng Liu, David &#352;arlah</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Enzyme Catalyzing the Oxidative Maturation of Reduced Prenylated-FMN to Form the Active Coenzyme</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02747</link>
      <description>Daniel A. DiRocco, Pronay Roy, Anushree Mondal, Prathamesh M. Datar, E. Neil G. Marsh, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399879371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel A. DiRocco, Pronay Roy, Anushree Mondal, Prathamesh M. Datar, E. Neil G. Marsh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formal Decarbonylation of 1,2-Diketones Enabled by Synergistic Catalysis of Lewis Acid&#8211;Base Pairs and Redox Properties in CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02493</link>
      <description>Takehiro Matsuyama, Takafumi Yatabe, Kazuya Yamaguchi, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399885909

                Various decarbonylation reactions via oxidative addition of carbonyl compounds to metal catalysts can be applied to late-stage modification and have been actively studied to date; however, several inherent problems derived from the oxidative addition are difficult to solve, such as toxic CO production, deactivation of catalysts by CO adsorption, intolerance of some functional groups, or air-sensitivity of catalysts. In this context, formal decarbonylation, which eliminates CO as other compounds without involving oxidative addition, is attractive but hardly reported, especially using heterogeneous catalysts. Herein, formal decarbonylation of diaryl 1,2-diketones to afford monoketones using CeO2 as a reusable heterogeneous catalyst and O2 in the air as the terminal oxidant was developed, generating CO2 as the only byproduct. The results revealed that the reaction was enabled by the synergistic catalytic effect of the Lewis acid&#8211;base pairs and redox properties in CeO2.</description>
      <author>Takehiro Matsuyama, Takafumi Yatabe, Kazuya Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production from Biomass-Based HCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H by Cooperation of Quantum Dots Photocatalysts with Weak HCHO Adsorption and In Situ Generated Ni&lt;sup&gt;0&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01708</link>
      <description>Wenxin Niu, Wanghui Zhao, Kaiwen Feng, Fu-Jia Tang, Tao Wang, Kaixuan Wang, Shaohua Shen, Yang Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399896204

                Efficient hydrogen (H2) production from renewable resources, such as biomass, one of the largest renewable resources on the earth, instead of fossil resources, is highly desirable. Making it via HCO2H as an intermediate for H2 production from biomass both facilitates efficient H2 production and can avoid the issues of H2 storage. Herein, we report efficient H2 production from raw biomass-based formic acid (HCO2H) by a noble-metal-free catalysis system under mild conditions, enabled by cooperation of CdS/ZnS-S2&#8211; quantum dots photocatalysts with weak formaldehyde (HCHO) adsorption and in situ generated Ni0, resulting in H2 with a 94% yield in 3.5 h, with a 99.7% selectivity and a 537 &#177; 14 mol mg&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 average rate at 50 &#176;C under visible-light irradiation. This study should promote the exploration of catalytic systems for streamlined H2 production from renewable biomass for practical application.</description>
      <author>Wenxin Niu, Wanghui Zhao, Kaiwen Feng, Fu-Jia Tang, Tao Wang, Kaixuan Wang, Shaohua Shen, Yang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01708</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amino Acid Synthesis through C&#8211;N Coupling between &#945;-Ketoacids and Hydroxylamine from Nitrate Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01793</link>
      <description>Yiyang Zhou, Ruizhi Duan, Qinge Huang, Chunmei Ding, Can Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399896383

                The artificial synthesis of amino acids is an important yet challenging subject. Electrocatalytic C&#8211;N coupling from organic acids and nitrogen sources provides an opportunity for this target but with the difficulty of C&#8211;N bond formation toward the production of amino acids. Herein, we report the synthesis of amino acids (alanine, glutamic acid, glycine, leucine, valine) from nitrate and &#945;-ketoacids with a hybrid catalyst, cobalt phthalocyanine immobilized on carbon nanotubes (CoPc/CNT). The Faradaic efficiency for alanine production with CoPc/CNT is as high as 61%. The CoPc catalyst integrated with CNTs can catalyze nitrate reduction to hydroxylamine, which is switched from a thermodynamically uphill to a downhill process. The hydroxylamine intermediate attacks the &#945;-carbon of an &#945;-ketoacid to form an oxime. Amino acids are produced by the reduction of oximes catalyzed by CNTs. The bifunctionality of CoPc/CNT steers the tandem catalytic reaction toward the efficient production of amino acids in one pot. This work identifies that enhancing the reduction of nitrate to hydroxylamine is the key to C&#8211;N bond formation in amino acid synthesis.</description>
      <author>Yiyang Zhou, Ruizhi Duan, Qinge Huang, Chunmei Ding, Can Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanopatches Positioned at Lewis Acidic Sites of TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Propylene Epoxidation Using Molecular Oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01749</link>
      <description>Zun-Ren Lv, Leilei Kang, Xiaoli Pan, Yang Su, Hua Wang, Lin Li, Xiao Yan Liu, Aiqin Wang, Tao Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399896664

                Controlling the precise placement of active metals on supports is highly desirable yet challenging, which governs both the reaction pathway and the ultimate outcomes of catalytic reactions. Herein, the Cu species are positioned to the Lewis acidic sites created by the ultrahigh-temperature calcination of TiO2, where the atomic structures of the Lewis acids are identified as five-coordinated Ti4+ cations bound to three-coordinated O2&#8211; anions (L&#946; sites) by in situ characterizations. Owing to the robust chemical affinity, CuOx manifests itself as a nanopatch. The Cu/TiO2 catalyst without any modifications exhibits a propylene oxide (PO) formation rate of 44 mmol gCu&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 for direct epoxidation of propylene using molecular oxygen (DEP). The PO yield on Cu/TiO2 can be efficiently correlated with the quantity of the decreased Lewis acids, which demonstrates that the intimated interaction between the Cu species and Lewis acids should be responsible for PO production. Furthermore, density functional theory calculations suggest that Cu+ in the Ti&#8211;O&#8211;Cu interface formed at the L&#946; sites is the active site of the DEP reaction, with the aid of the adjacent Cu atom. This study provides a Cu-based catalyst for the DEP reaction.</description>
      <author>Zun-Ren Lv, Leilei Kang, Xiaoli Pan, Yang Su, Hua Wang, Lin Li, Xiao Yan Liu, Aiqin Wang, Tao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing Amino Tethering and Carbon Shell Confinement Enables Confinement Synthesis of PtCo Intermetallic Catalysts for Highly Durable Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01202</link>
      <description>Kechuang Wan, Chuanqi Luo, Jue Wang, Haitao Chen, Jingjing Zhang, Bing Li, Maorong Chai, Pingwen Ming, Cunman Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399896671

                Intermetallic compounds possess superior catalytic performance over their disordered alloy counterparts, while their synthesis usually requires high-temperature treatment, which causes the sintering of catalysts. This work demonstrates the high-temperature confinement synthesis (HTCS) of PtCo intermetallic compounds for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) by integrating ultrathin nitrogen-doped carbon shell (NCS) confined PtCo alloy into &#8722;NH2 functionalized black pearls 2000 carbon architectures (PtCo@NCS/BP-NH2). Benefiting from amino tethering and carbon shell confinement, high-temperature sintering behavior is effectively inhibited. PtCo@NCS/BP-NH2 possesses outstanding ORR performance, and the assembled single cell exhibits a small peak power density loss rate of 4% after the accelerated durability test (ADT), outperforming PtCo/BP (12.5%) and commercial Pt/C (18.9%). Theoretical calculations along with experiments reveal that PtCo and NCS synergically optimize the electronic structure, weaken the Pt&#8211;O dipole effect, and lower the reaction barrier for ORR. The study provides insight into the HTCS of catalysts and unveils intrinsic electronic interaction for ORR.</description>
      <author>Kechuang Wan, Chuanqi Luo, Jue Wang, Haitao Chen, Jingjing Zhang, Bing Li, Maorong Chai, Pingwen Ming, Cunman Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i012_1814477</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399897740

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i012_1814477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i012_1814478</link>
      <description>, ACS catalysis. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399897753

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i012_1814478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and Reactivity of Active Oxygen Species on Silver Surfaces for Ethylene Epoxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01566</link>
      <description>Minjie Guo, Nanchen Dongfang, Marcella Iannuzzi, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, Luca Artiglia, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399908109

                The epoxidation of ethylene stands as one of the most important industrial catalytic reactions, and silver-based catalysts show superior activity and selectivity. Oxygen is activated on the surface of silver during the reaction and exerts a substantial impact on product selectivity. Notably, the oxygen species residing in the topmost atomic layers profoundly influence the reactivity of a catalyst. However, their characterization under in situ reaction conditions remains a huge challenge, and specific structures have not been identified yet. In this study, we employ in situ X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and density functional theory calculations to determine the oxygen species formed at the topmost atomic layers of a silver foil and to assign them a structure. Three different groups of oxygen species activated on silver are identified: (i) surface lattice oxygen and two oxygen species originating from associatively adsorbed dioxygen and (ii) top and (iii) subsurface oxygen. Transient in situ photoelectron spectroscopy experiments are carried out to reveal the dynamic evolution and thus reactivity of the different oxygen species under ethylene epoxidation reaction environments. The top oxygen atom from the adsorbed associated dioxygen is the most active. Meanwhile, a frequency-selective data analysis method, developed to process time-resolved data, provides insights into the evolving trends of peak intensities for different oxygen species. The versatility of this method suggests its potential application in future time-resolved characterization studies.</description>
      <author>Minjie Guo, Nanchen Dongfang, Marcella Iannuzzi, Jeroen A. van Bokhoven, Luca Artiglia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Oxygen Vacancy-Promoted Synthesis of Aminoarenes from Nitroarenes Using Waste H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S as a &#8220;Hydrogen Donor&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02478</link>
      <description>Xiaohai Zheng, Bang Li, Rui Huang, Weiping Jiang, Lijuan Shen, Ganchang Lei, Shiping Wang, Shiping Wang, Lilong Jiang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399916695

                The conversion of H2S to high-value-added products is appealing for alleviating environmental pollution and realizing resource utilization. Herein, we report the reduction of nitrobenzene to aniline using waste H2S as a "hydrogen donor" over the catalyst of FeCeO2&#8722;&#948; with abundant oxygen vacancies (Ov), especially an asymmetric oxygen vacancy (ASOv). The electron-rich nature of the ASOv sites facilitates electron transfer to the electron-deficient nitro group, promoting the adsorption and activation of Ph&#8211;NO2 through the elongation and cleavage of the N&#8211;O bond. Benefiting from the formation of abundant ASOv sites, the resulting FeCeO2&#8722;&#948; achieves an impressive 85.6% Ph&#8211;NO2 conversion and 81.9% Ph&#8211;NH2 selectivity at 1.5 MPa and 90 &#176;C, which surpasses that of pure CeO2 with flower and rod morphologies. In situ FT-IR measurements combined with density functional theory calculations have elucidated a plausible reaction mechanism and a rate-limiting step in the hydrogenation of Ph&#8211;NO2 by H2S.</description>
      <author>Xiaohai Zheng, Bang Li, Rui Huang, Weiping Jiang, Lijuan Shen, Ganchang Lei, Shiping Wang, Shiping Wang, Lilong Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Conundrum of &#8220;Pair Sites&#8221; in Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood Reaction Kinetics in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02813</link>
      <description>Daniyal Kiani, Israel E. Wachs, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399916760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniyal Kiani, Israel E. Wachs</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Adsorbed CO on the Conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Ethylene on 4,5-Dicyanoimidazole Coordinated Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02042</link>
      <description>Yuhang Jiang, Yating Wang, Wei Chen, Rongzhen Chen, Yu Hang Li, Chunzhong Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399773474

                Upgrading carbon dioxide (CO2) into multicarbon products by using renewable electricity provides a pathway to producing fuel and chemicals. In fact, input CO2 in alkaline and neutral reactors forms carbonates with hydroxide, resulting in lower carbon efficiency, so acidic electrolytes are considered as a strategy to solve this problem. However, hydrogen evolution reaction competition and lower Faradaic efficiency (FE) of the target product limit the development of acidic electrolytes. Here, we report an accessible composite catalyst of a commercial copper (Cu) powder modified by a small molecule 4,5-dicyanoimidazole (DCI) that can maintain a high FE for ethylene (C2H4) even in strong acids with pH &#8804; 1. We achieve CO2 electroreduction on the DCI&#8211;Cu catalyst with an FE of 57% toward C2H4 at a current density of 200 mA cm&#8211;2 at pH 1. By in situ attenuated total reflectance surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy measurements, compressed bonding of the *CO intermediate has been observed, which leads to more C&#8211;C bonding. The density functional theory calculation results further prove that the adsorbed *CO intermediates on the DCI&#8211;Cu catalyst are closer to the reaction sites. Unfortunately, this catalyst still requires improvement in terms of long-term operation. However, we anticipate that this may be generalized to enable molecular strategies to complement metal-based catalysts designed for strong acidic conditions by stabilizing intermediates.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Jiang, Yating Wang, Wei Chen, Rongzhen Chen, Yu Hang Li, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palladium-Catalyzed Allylic Alkylation Reactions of Nucleophilic Allenones: Asymmetric Allylic Alkylation, &lt;i&gt;Z/E&lt;/i&gt; Divergent Allylic Alkylation, and [5 + 2] Annulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01460</link>
      <description>Wang Wang, Yimin Hu, Kuan Li, Jiajia Xu, Cheng Zhang, Leijie Zhou, Lihan Zhu, Wangyu Shi, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399812307

                Metal-catalyzed allenylic substitution reactions where allenes serve as electrophilic precursors have been recognized as a rapid way for novel allene construction. On the contrary, the chemistry in which allenes act as nucleophiles has been far less investigated, especially in a powerful platform such as metal-catalyzed allylic alkylation reactions. We herein describe two unprecedented palladium-catalyzed allylic alkylation reactions of an allene nucleophile. In the first reaction, using vinyloxazolidinones as the allyl precursor, the palladium-catalyzed asymmetric allylation of trisubstituted allenones worked well to prepare an array of axially chiral tetrasubstituted allenes. Mechanistic studies and density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicated that weak hydrogen-bonding interaction between the acidic C(sp2)&#8211;H of allenone and the nitrogen anion of chiral &#960;-azaallyl-Pd species is key to the success of stereocontrol. This reaction revealed the intriguing reactivity of nucleophilic allenones in a metal-catalyzed asymmetric allylation reaction for the first time. In the second reaction, with the use of allenylethylene carbonates as &#960;-oxyallyl-Pd precursors, the palladium-catalyzed allylic alkylation reaction of allenone presented unique reactivity under different reaction conditions to provide divergent synthetic access to (E)- and (Z)-allenyl diene products. Interestingly, the subsequent sequential intramolecular cyclization/isomerization reaction of the (Z)-product delivered dihydrooxepine derivatives as [5 + 2] annulation products.</description>
      <author>Wang Wang, Yimin Hu, Kuan Li, Jiajia Xu, Cheng Zhang, Leijie Zhou, Lihan Zhu, Wangyu Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Aspects of MoS&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Prepared by Atomic Layer Deposition for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01445</link>
      <description>Miika Mattinen, Wei Chen, Rebecca A. Dawley, Marcel A. Verheijen, Emiel J. M. Hensen, W. M. M. Kessels, Ageeth A. Bol, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399858629

                Molybdenum sulfides (MoSx) in both crystalline and amorphous forms are promising earth-abundant electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in acid. Plasma-enhanced atomic layer deposition was used to prepare thin films of both amorphous MoSx with adjustable S/Mo ratio (2.8&#8211;4.7) and crystalline MoS2 with tailored crystallinity, morphology, and electrical properties. All the amorphous MoSx films transform into highly HER-active amorphous MoS2 (overpotential 210&#8211;250 mV at 10 mA/cm2 in 0.5 M H2SO4) after electrochemical activation at approximately &#8722;0.3 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode. However, the initial film stoichiometry affects the structure and consequently the HER activity and stability. The material changes occurring during activation are studied using ex situ and quasi in situ X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. Possible structures of as-deposited and activated catalysts are proposed. In contrast to amorphous MoSx, no changes in the structure of crystalline MoS2 catalysts are observed. The overpotentials of the crystalline films range from 300 to 520 mV at 10 mA/cm2, being the lowest for the most defective catalysts. This work provides a practical method for deposition of tailored MoSx HER electrocatalysts as well as new insights into their activity and structure.</description>
      <author>Miika Mattinen, Wei Chen, Rebecca A. Dawley, Marcel A. Verheijen, Emiel J. M. Hensen, W. M. M. Kessels, Ageeth A. Bol</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electroreductive C&#8211;C Coupling of Furfural to Jet Fuel Precursors in Neutral Media via Synergistic Catalysis of the Polyoxotungstate and Cu Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02524</link>
      <description>Weijie Geng, Di Zhang, Ni Zhen, Jianshi Du, Jing Dong, Chengpeng Liu, Shi&#8208;Lu Chen, Yingnan Chi, Changwen Hu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399864928

                The electrochemical coupling of biomass platform molecules to biofuels provides a promising method for addressing energy crises and environmental issues. However, achieving high yields of C&#8211;C coupling products under ambient conditions remains a challenge. Herein, we present a highly efficient electrocatalyst, [Cu(pz)]3[PW12O40] (Cu-PW12), fabricated by combining a Cu-pz complex (pz = pyrazine), a redox catalytic center, with Keggin-type PW12O40, and an electron sponge. Cu-PW12 exhibits remarkable catalytic activity for the electroreductive C&#8211;C coupling of furfural (FF), a bulk and low-cost biomass platform chemical, to produce a jet fuel precursor, hydrofuroin (HDF). Under neutral and ambient conditions, over 99% of FF is converted and the selectivity of HDF reaches 91.2%. Furthermore, experimental and theoretical studies, including control experiments, kinetic isotope studies, electrochemical and spectral analyses, and DFT calculations, reveal a synergistic catalysis effect between Cu center and PW12. The introduction of PW12 not only facilitates electron transfer, improving FF conversion, but also changes the rate-determining step, favoring the formation of HDF. Under turnover conditions, the Cu-PW12 catalyst is initially reduced and then FF is reduced by the Cu center to ketyl radical after protonation on the electrode surface. Finally, the self-coupling of two ketyl radicals in solution leads to the generation of HDF.</description>
      <author>Weijie Geng, Di Zhang, Ni Zhen, Jianshi Du, Jing Dong, Chengpeng Liu, Shi&#8208;Lu Chen, Yingnan Chi, Changwen Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photochemical Tuning of Tricoordinated Nitrogen Deficiency in Carbon Nitride to Create Delocalized &#960; Electron Clouds for Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01636</link>
      <description>Lei Li, Huanhuan Lu, Cungui Cheng, Xinyan Dai, Fang Chen, Jiqiang Ning, Wentao Wang, Yong Hu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399891463

                Precisely engineering point defects holds promise for the development of state-of-the-art photocatalysts for CO2 conversion. This study demonstrates the controllable creation of nitrogen vacancies (VNs) in the centers of heptazine rings of graphitic carbon nitrides (g-C3N4) via a photochemical-assisted nitrogen etching strategy. Spectroscopic analyses and theoretical simulations elucidate the photochemical process to hydrogenate the nitrogen situated at the center of the g-C3N4 heptazine ring and then release an ammonia molecule, accompanied by the photooxidation of the sacrificial agents. The catalyst with an optimal VNs concentration achieves a CO generation rate of 35.2 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 with nearly 100% selectivity, comparable to the performance of the reported g-C3N4 materials. The remarkably improved photoactivity is due to the adjustments of the electronic structures and the midgap states of g-C3N4 by the delocalized &#960; electron cloud created in the 12-membered ring surrounding the VN, which maximizes the light-harvesting efficiencies and suppresses the recombination of photogenerated electrons and holes. The VNs also activates the neighboring catalytic carbon centers to reduce the energy barrier for CO2 reduction. This work provides a good design concept to regulate catalytic activity by engineering point defects.</description>
      <author>Lei Li, Huanhuan Lu, Cungui Cheng, Xinyan Dai, Fang Chen, Jiqiang Ning, Wentao Wang, Yong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Hydrogenation of Quinizarins to Leuco-quinizarins and Their Direct Derivatization Using Flow-Batch-Separator Unified Reactors under Continuous-Flow Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02955</link>
      <description>Hiroyuki Miyamura, Aditya Sharma, Masasuke Takata, Rokuro Kajiyama, Sh&#363; Kobayashi, Yoshihiro Kon, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399933284

                Anthraquinone derivatives are classes of compounds employed in the production of valuable materials. Leuco-quinizarin, the 2-electron-reduced form of quinizarin (1,4-dihydroxy-anthraquinone), is a highly active and useful reactant for the synthesis of variety of anthraquinone derivatives. However, conventional methods of leuco-quinizarin synthesis require stoichiometric amounts of inorganic reductants and acids or bases. We developed Pt/DMPSi-Al2O3 and Pt-Ni/DMPSi-Al2O3 as highly active and selective heterogeneous catalysts for the hydrogenation of quinizarins to leuco-quinizarins under neutral and continuous-flow conditions. Remarkably, bimetallic effects of Ni and Pt nanoparticle systems were highlighted in the selective hydrogenation of the substituted quinizarin. In addition, the continuous-flow synthesis of leuco-quinizarin and its derivatization reaction were integrated to be a fully continuous process using flow-batch-separator unified reactors.</description>
      <author>Hiroyuki Miyamura, Aditya Sharma, Masasuke Takata, Rokuro Kajiyama, Sh&#363; Kobayashi, Yoshihiro Kon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02955</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hexa-Fe(III) Carboxylate Complexes Facilitate Aerobic Hydrocarbon Oxidative Functionalization: Rh Catalyzed Oxidative Coupling of Benzene and Ethylene to Form Styrene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02355</link>
      <description>Marc T. Bennett, K. Park, Charles B. Musgrave, Jack W. Brubaker, Diane A. Dickie, William A. Goddard, T. Brent Gunnoe, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399938552

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marc T. Bennett, K. Park, Charles B. Musgrave, Jack W. Brubaker, Diane A. Dickie, William A. Goddard, T. Brent Gunnoe</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy between Br&#248;nsted Acid Sites and Carbonaceous Deposits during Skeletal 1-Butene Isomerization over Ferrierite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01898</link>
      <description>Karoline L. Hebisch, Risha Goel, Kinga Go&#322;&#261;&#808;bek, Pawel A. Chmielniak, Carsten Sievers, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399970689

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karoline L. Hebisch, Risha Goel, Kinga Go&#322;&#261;&#808;bek, Pawel A. Chmielniak, Carsten Sievers</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micellar N-Heterocyclic Carbene-like Organic Catalysis from Polymeric Nanoreactors Immobilizing Benzimidazolium Acetate Motifs in Their Core</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00259</link>
      <description>Anne-Laure Wirotius, Romain Lambert, Thomas Dard&#233;, Simon Harrisson, Daniel Taton, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399977853

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anne-Laure Wirotius, Romain Lambert, Thomas Dard&#233;, Simon Harrisson, Daniel Taton</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00259</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
