<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:43:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Chemoselective Aerobic Oxidation of Alcohols Utilizing a Vanadium(V) Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05638</link>
      <description>Mitchell J Kitt, Emily Amir, Eleanor R. Sloane, Douglas G. Fraser, John E. Cerritelli, Caroline S. M. Sabanos, James McNeely, John K. Snyder, Linda H. Doerrer, Aaron B. Beeler, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392793212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mitchell J Kitt, Emily Amir, Eleanor R. Sloane, Douglas G. Fraser, John E. Cerritelli, Caroline S. M. Sabanos, James McNeely, John K. Snyder, Linda H. Doerrer, Aaron B. Beeler</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Alkyne Semihydrogenation Catalysis Enabled by Synergistic Chemical and Thermal Modifications of a PdIn MOF</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00310</link>
      <description>Jordan Santiago Martinez, Jaime Mazar&#237;o, Christian Wittee Lopes, Susana Trasobares, Jos&#233; J. Calvino, Giovanni Agostini, Pascual O&#241;a&#8208;Burgos, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392805147

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jordan Santiago Martinez, Jaime Mazar&#237;o, Christian Wittee Lopes, Susana Trasobares, Jos&#233; J. Calvino, Giovanni Agostini, Pascual O&#241;a&#8208;Burgos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple and Directed Immobilization of a Multicopper Oxidase on Flat Bare Gold Electrodes Provides High Catalytic Currents for O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00516</link>
      <description>F. Rizzo, V&#226;nia Brissos, S. Villain, L&#305;&#769;gia O. Martins, Felipe Conzuelo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392805894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>F. Rizzo, V&#226;nia Brissos, S. Villain, L&#305;&#769;gia O. Martins, Felipe Conzuelo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Co Species in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Assisted Ethane Dehydrogenation: Competing Cleavage of C&#8211;H and C&#8211;C Bonds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00324</link>
      <description>Yingbin Zheng, Junjie Li, Xinbao Zhang, Shaoguo Li, Jie An, Fucun Chen, Xiujie Li, Xiangxue Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392812312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingbin Zheng, Junjie Li, Xinbao Zhang, Shaoguo Li, Jie An, Fucun Chen, Xiujie Li, Xiangxue Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lewis Acid Sites in (110) Facet-Exposed BiOBr Promote C&#8211;H Activation and Selective Photocatalytic Toluene Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00877</link>
      <description>Zhou Guang-hong, Ben Lei, Fan Dong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392818266

                Solar photocatalytic technology has exhibited significant potential for upgrading the value-added chemicals industry through efficient C&#8211;H bond activation, such as selective photocatalytic toluene oxidation. However, improvement in the C&#8211;H bond activation of toluene is still a challenge. Herein, (110) facet-exposed BiOBr (EC-BiOBr) synthesized via a facile crystal facet control strategy exhibited an increasing exposure of Lewis acid sites, as confirmed by in situ Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR) using ammonia as a probe molecule. In situ FT-IR results substantiated the improved absorption capacity of EC-BiOBr for toluene. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicated that the Lewis acid&#8211;base pairs formed by Bi sites and O sites can adsorb toluene directionally, precisely matching the orbit spaces of the conduction band (Bi 6p state) and valence band (O 2p and Br 4p states). Benefiting from the oriented adsorption of toluene, the electron in the C&#8211;H bond could transfer to a photogenerated hole precisely, thus achieving C&#8211;H bond activation. Compared to (001) facet-exposed BiOBr (H&#8211;BiOBr), an 11-fold improvement in the toluene conversion rate (from 233 to 2460 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1) was observed in the EC-BiOBr group, and the benzaldehyde formation rate increased from 233 to 1623 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1. Active species identification and DFT calculations revealed that the superoxide radicals were involved as the primary reactive species in the subsequent oxidation of benzyl radicals generated from the C&#8211;H bond activation of toluene. This work highlights the importance of the surface acid sites regulated by the crystal facet control strategy, which is conducive to the rational design of photocatalysts with high performance in C&#8211;H bond activation.</description>
      <author>Zhou Guang-hong, Ben Lei, Fan Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lewis and Br&#248;nsted Acid Synergistic Catalysis for Efficient Synthesis of Hydroxylamine over Heteroatom Zeolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00179</link>
      <description>Nan Fang, Kai Huo, Yucheng Jin, Dongxu Li, Henry C. Lin, Haoyue Wu, Xuguang Liu, Yueming Liu, Min He, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392818365

                Environmental and efficient synthesis of NH2OH is challenging. Herein, we have provided a route for efficient NH2OH formation by NH3 oxidation via the synergistic catalysis of Lewis acid sites of the framework Ti (Ti LAS) and Br&#248;nsted acid sites of the framework Al (Al BAS) in Ti&#8211;Al-MOR zeolites. Ti LAS was the active center for formation of transition-state NH2OH, while Al BAS could provide the proton H to convert transition-state NH2OH absorbed on Ti LAS to a [NH3OH]+ species. Protonation effect would not only promote the catalytic cycle process resulting from accelerating the desorption of transition-state NH2OH, but also improve the stability of NH2OH, being less prone to oxidative decomposition. In this work, we presented the synergistic catalysis between LAS and BAS over Ti-containing heteroatom zeolites to accelerate the catalytic cycle, which provided an environmental and efficient method for NH2OH formation.</description>
      <author>Nan Fang, Kai Huo, Yucheng Jin, Dongxu Li, Henry C. Lin, Haoyue Wu, Xuguang Liu, Yueming Liu, Min He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Codecoration of Phosphate and Iron for Improving Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Layered Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/NiOOH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00229</link>
      <description>Yuexiang Li, Junliang Liu, Shuqi Li, Shaoqin Peng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392858728

                Hydrogen production through electrochemical water splitting (EWS) presents a viable solution for addressing the fossil energy crisis. However, the commercial viability of this approach is impeded by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). It is urgently needed to develop efficient, stable, and cost-effective OER electrocatalysts. Herein, we comprehensively design and investigate a phosphate ion and Fe3+ codecorating Ni(OH)2/NiOOH electrocatalyst (Pi-Fe:NiOH) for OER. This codecoration induces multiple synergistic effects, which include an increase in the interlayer water content for the internal OER, altering the OER mechanism, facilitating proton transport across the layers, and improving the stability of Pi-Fe:NiOH. Consequently, Pi-Fe:NiOH exhibits a high OER activity with overpotentials of 118 &#177; 1 and 222 &#177; 4 mV at current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8211;2, respectively. More impressively, it maintains stable operation at a high current density of around 300 mA cm&#8211;2 for at least 500 h, much better than the Ni(OH)2/NiOOH electrocatalyst (NiOH) for less than 6 h at a current density below 200 mA cm&#8211;2. These findings offer insights for the design of anion&#8211;cation codoped hydroxide eletrocatalysts, paving a way for the development of efficient and stable OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuexiang Li, Junliang Liu, Shuqi Li, Shaoqin Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Temperature &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Allylation of Allylic Alcohols via Synergistic Pd/Cu Catalysis: A Silica-Supported Dual-Metal-Complex Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00638</link>
      <description>Shun-ichi Sakai, Shingo Hasegawa, Siming Ding, Ryota Osuga, Kiyotaka Nakajima, Shinji Tanaka, Wang&#8208;Jae Chun, Ken Motokura, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392862288

                N-allylation is an important method for constructing C&#8211;N bonds in fine chemical synthesis. Accumulation of catalytically active species on the same support surface is a promising approach for achieving high catalytic efficiency. In this study, we developed a catalyst comprising Pd and Cu complexes immobilized on a silica surface. The dual-metal-complex catalyst catalyzed the N-allylation of aniline using allyl alcohol at the low temperature of 30 &#176;C with tunable selectivity toward mono- and disubstituted products. The coimmobilization of a Cu complex increased the turnover number of the Pd complex 5.3 times, which was much higher than those of reported heterogeneous catalysts used at reaction temperatures higher than 100 &#176;C. A wide substrate scope, recyclability, and suppression of aggregation and leaching were also confirmed. Whereas synergy was scarcely observed for the simple mixture of homogeneous Pd and Cu complexes, the dual-complex catalyst exhibited significant synergy, indicating concerted catalysis on the solid surface. Spectroscopic analysis, including XAFS, in situ IR, and DNP-enhanced 15N NMR, and density functional theory calculations indicated that an aniline molecule is activated by the Cu complex, resulting in the efficient nucleophilic attack to a &#960;-allylpalladium intermediate.</description>
      <author>Shun-ichi Sakai, Shingo Hasegawa, Siming Ding, Ryota Osuga, Kiyotaka Nakajima, Shinji Tanaka, Wang&#8208;Jae Chun, Ken Motokura</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Editorial Masthead</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i006_1781035</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392863198

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i006_1781035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Publication Information</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i006_1781034</link>
      <description>, ACS Catalysis. 14(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392863485

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/csv014i006_1781034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Stable Self-Cleaning Paints Based on Waste-Valorized PNC-Doped TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06203</link>
      <description>Qaisar Maqbool, O. Favoni, Thomas Wicht, Niusha Lasemi, Simona Sabbatini, Michael St&#246;ger&#8208;Pollach, Maria Letizia Ruello, Francesca Tittarelli, G&#252;nther Rupprechter, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392864297

                Adding photocatalytically active TiO2 nanoparticles (NPs) to polymeric paints is a feasible route toward self-cleaning coatings. While paint modification by TiO2-NPs may improve photoactivity, it may also cause polymer degradation and release of toxic volatile organic compounds. To counterbalance adverse effects, a synthesis method for nonmetal (P, N, and C)-doped TiO2-NPs is introduced, based purely on waste valorization. PNC-doped TiO2-NP characterization by vibrational and photoelectron spectroscopy, electron microscopy, diffraction, and thermal analysis suggests that TiO2-NPs were modified with phosphate (P&#9552;O), imine species (R&#9552;N-R), and carbon, which also hindered the anatase/rutile phase transformation, even upon 700 &#176;C calcination. When added to water-based paints, PNC-doped TiO2-NPs achieved 96% removal of surface-adsorbed pollutants under natural sunlight or UV, paralleled by stability of the paint formulation, as confirmed by micro-Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) surface analysis. The origin of the photoinduced self-cleaning properties was rationalized by three-dimensional (3D) and synchronous photoluminescence spectroscopy, indicating that the dopants led to 7.3 times stronger inhibition of photoinduced e&#8211;/h+ recombination when compared to a benchmark P25 photocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Qaisar Maqbool, O. Favoni, Thomas Wicht, Niusha Lasemi, Simona Sabbatini, Michael St&#246;ger&#8208;Pollach, Maria Letizia Ruello, Francesca Tittarelli, G&#252;nther Rupprechter</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Photocatalyzed Divergent Access to Organic Thio- and Isothiocyanates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00565</link>
      <description>Youssef Abderrazak, Oliver Reiser, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392878350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youssef Abderrazak, Oliver Reiser</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atroposelective Synthesis of Diarylamines via Organocatalyzed Electrophilic Amination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00414</link>
      <description>Zidan Ye, Wansen Xie, Donglei Wang, Hua Lee, Xiaoyu Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392900769

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zidan Ye, Wansen Xie, Donglei Wang, Hua Lee, Xiaoyu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Poisoning Is Avoided in a Step of Relevance to the Haber&#8211;Bosch Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06201</link>
      <description>S. K. Tripathi, Luigi Bonati, Simone Perego, Michele Parrinello, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392906279

                For a catalyst to be efficient and durable, it is crucial that the reaction products do not poison the catalyst. In the case of the Haber&#8211;Bosch process, the rate-limiting step is believed to be the decomposition of nitrogen molecules on the Fe(111) surface. This step leads to the production on the surface of atomic nitrogen (N*), which, unless hydrogenated and eventually released as ammonia, remains adsorbed and occupies the active sites. Thus, it is important to ascertain how a high N* coverage affects the nitrogen dissociative chemisorption. To answer this question, we study the properties of the Fe(111) surface at different N* coverage both at room and operando temperature. In the latter regime, we have already found that Fe surface atoms exhibit a high mobility, promoting the formation of adatoms and vacancies, and causing the catalytic centers to acquire a finite lifetime [Bonati et al. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 2023, 120 (50), e2313023120]. We discover that the N* coverage reduces but does not eliminate the iron mobility. Remarkably, the N* atoms stabilize triangular surface structures associated with the formation of vacancies, which are a sign of a frustrated drive toward a more stable Fe4N phase. As a consequence, nitrogen atoms tend to cluster, reducing their poisoning effect. At the same time, the reduction in the number of catalytic centers is counteracted by an increase in their lifetime. The combined effect is that the dissociation barrier is not significantly altered in the range of coverages studied. These results bring to light the complex role that dynamics plays in catalytic reactivity under operando conditions.</description>
      <author>S. K. Tripathi, Luigi Bonati, Simone Perego, Michele Parrinello</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the Synergetic Effects of NTP-La&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ag&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;MnO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; on Soot Oxidation at Low Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06029</link>
      <description>He Sun, Feiyang Zhang, Shixin Liu, Yangyang Liu, Bin Zhu, Xin Yu, Zean Xie, Zhao Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392911304

                No abstract</description>
      <author>He Sun, Feiyang Zhang, Shixin Liu, Yangyang Liu, Bin Zhu, Xin Yu, Zean Xie, Zhao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rh-Catalyzed Enantioselective Hydroalkenylative Cyclization of 1,6-Enynes Constructing All-Carbon Quaternary Stereocenters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00572</link>
      <description>Shunsuke Emi, Shintaro Hamada, Yukichi Kishida, Yu Sato, Futo Morita, Yuki Nagashima, Hidehiro Uekusa, Ken Tanaka, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392912960

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shunsuke Emi, Shintaro Hamada, Yukichi Kishida, Yu Sato, Futo Morita, Yuki Nagashima, Hidehiro Uekusa, Ken Tanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcycling of Plastic Waste Using Photo-, Electro-, and Photoelectrocatalytic Approaches: A Way toward Circular Economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00290</link>
      <description>Devanshu Sajwan, Ankit Sharma, Manisha Sharma, Venkata Krishnan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392918226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Devanshu Sajwan, Ankit Sharma, Manisha Sharma, Venkata Krishnan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B(C&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;F&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Catalyzed Dehydrogenation of Pyrrolidines to Form Pyrroles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05444</link>
      <description>Ana Alvarez-Montoya, Joseph P. Gillions, Laura Winfrey, Rebecca R. Hawker, Kuldip Singh, Fabrizio Ortu, Yukang Fu, L. S. Liebeskind, Alexander P. Pulis, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392921788

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ana Alvarez-Montoya, Joseph P. Gillions, Laura Winfrey, Rebecca R. Hawker, Kuldip Singh, Fabrizio Ortu, Yukang Fu, L. S. Liebeskind, Alexander P. Pulis</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light-Promoted Efficient Generation of Fe(I) to Initiate Amination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00788</link>
      <description>Geyang Song, Qi Li, Jiuzhou Song, Ding-Zhan Nong, Jianyang Dong, Gang Li, Juan Fan, Chao Wang, Xue Duan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392928780

                Iron-catalyzed cross-coupling reactions are difficult to achieve because they usually require a highly reactive, low-valent iron catalyst to undergo the oxidative addition process. Here, we report a method for light-promoted iron-catalyzed C&#8211;N coupling reactions between aryl bromides and amines in the presence of a catalytic amount of a bipyridine ligand under irradiation at 390&#8211;395 nm. This method, which does not require external photosensitizers, features a broad substrate scope (70 examples) and good functional group tolerance, providing a platform for the development of iron-catalyzed coupling reactions in organic synthesis. Mechanistic studies indicate that an organic base and light are crucial for the generation of an Fe(I) species and that the reaction involves an Fe(I)/Fe(III) catalytic cycle.</description>
      <author>Geyang Song, Qi Li, Jiuzhou Song, Ding-Zhan Nong, Jianyang Dong, Gang Li, Juan Fan, Chao Wang, Xue Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Mo Single Atoms and Clusters in Enhancing Pt Catalyst for Benzene Hydrogenation: Distinguishing Between Benzene Spillover and Electronic Effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06026</link>
      <description>Zhuo Li, Fanchun Meng, Xinchun Yang, Yuntao Qi, Yong Qin, Bin Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392936989

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhuo Li, Fanchun Meng, Xinchun Yang, Yuntao Qi, Yong Qin, Bin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Orbital Engineering of Mixed-Addenda Polyoxometalates Boosts Light-Driven Hydrogen Evolution Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00295</link>
      <description>Manzhou Chi, Ying Zeng, Zhongling Lang, Huijie Li, Xing Xin, Yuanyuan Dong, Fangyu Fu, Guo&#8208;Yu Yang, Hongjin Lv, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392948266

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manzhou Chi, Ying Zeng, Zhongling Lang, Huijie Li, Xing Xin, Yuanyuan Dong, Fangyu Fu, Guo&#8208;Yu Yang, Hongjin Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible Intrapore Redox Cycling of Platinum in Platinum-Ion-Exchanged HZSM-5 Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06325</link>
      <description>Kaan Yal&#231;&#305;n, Ram Kumar, Erik Zuidema, Ambarish Kulkarni, Jim Ciston, Karen C. Bustillo, Peter Ercius, Alexander Katz, Bruce C. Gates, Coleman X. Kronawitter, Ron C. Runnebaum, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392948602

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaan Yal&#231;&#305;n, Ram Kumar, Erik Zuidema, Ambarish Kulkarni, Jim Ciston, Karen C. Bustillo, Peter Ercius, Alexander Katz, Bruce C. Gates, Coleman X. Kronawitter, Ron C. Runnebaum</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms of Light Alkene Oligomerization on Metal-Modified Zeolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00552</link>
      <description>Zoya N. Lashchinskaya, Anton A. Gabrienko, Alexander G. Stepanov, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392949694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zoya N. Lashchinskaya, Anton A. Gabrienko, Alexander G. Stepanov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variation in Biosynthesis and Metal-Binding Properties of Isonitrile-Containing Peptides Produced by Mycobacteria versus Streptomyces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00645</link>
      <description>Tzu&#8208;Yu Chen, Jinfeng Chen, Mark W. Ruszczycky, Dalton Hilovsky, Terry L. Hostetler, Xiaojing Liu, Jiahai Zhou, Wei&#8208;chen Chang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392956930

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tzu&#8208;Yu Chen, Jinfeng Chen, Mark W. Ruszczycky, Dalton Hilovsky, Terry L. Hostetler, Xiaojing Liu, Jiahai Zhou, Wei&#8208;chen Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Pathways to the Formation of C&#8211;N Bonds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04912</link>
      <description>Dimitra Anastasiadou, Marta Costa Figueiredo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392975696

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dimitra Anastasiadou, Marta Costa Figueiredo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04912</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
