<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:44:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism and Kinetics of Propane and &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;-Butane Dehydrogenation over Isolated and Nested &#8801;SiOZn&#8211;OH Sites Grafted onto Silanol Nests of Dealuminated Beta Zeolite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05605</link>
      <description>Y. Zhang, Liang Qi, Danna Nozik, Chaochao Dun, Jeffrey J. Urban, Alexis T. Bell, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391593970

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y. Zhang, Liang Qi, Danna Nozik, Chaochao Dun, Jeffrey J. Urban, Alexis T. Bell</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study on Bismuth(III) Catalysts for Synthesis of Phenylsulfonyl Fluoride: Reasons of Their Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04874</link>
      <description>Yu Tian, Shigeyoshi Sakaki, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391594799

                Bismuth(III) complex with diarylsulfone ligand (diAr-SO2) is a non-transition metal catalyst reported recently for the synthesis of arylsulfonyl fluorides. We investigated this catalytic reaction using DFT and SCS-MP2 calculations for geometries and energies, respectively. This catalytic reaction occurs through transmetalation between (BF4)Bi(diAr-SO2) and phenylboronic acid (PhB(OH)2), SO2 insertion into the Bi&#8211;Ph bond of (Ph)Bi(diAr-SO2), and fluorination of the PhOSO group of (PhOSO)Bi(diAr-SO2) by Selectfluor. The rate-determining step is the transmetalation for diAr-SO2 with (CH3, CH3) and (CF3, CF3) but either the transmetalation or fluorination for diAr-SO2 with (CH3, CF3), where (R1, R2) means diAr-SO2 has R1 and R2 substituents on its aryl groups. The activation energy (&#916;G&#176;&#8225;) of the rate-determining step increases in the order (CH3, CF3) &lt; (CH3, CH3) &lt; (CF3, CF3). This increasing order is consistent with the experimentally observed substituent effects on catalytic activity. The transmetalation is difficult to occur in the absence of potassium phosphate (K3PO4) but occurs with moderate activation energy in the presence of K3PO4 because K3PO4 activates the B&#8211;Ph &#963;-bond of phenylboronic acid and stabilizes the dissociating B(OH)2 moiety through electrostatic interaction. The substituents on diAr-SO2 play an important role in the transmetalation; when diAr-SO2 has (CF3, CF3), K3PO4 strongly interacts with the Bi(diAr-SO2) species to form an overly stable adduct to enlarge considerably the &#916;G&#176;&#8225; value. When diAr-SO2 has either (CH3, CF3) or (CH3, CH3), the stabilization energy of the adduct is similar to each other, but the energy destabilization occurs more largely upon going to the asymmetric transition state from the adduct in the (CH3, CH3) case than in the (CH3, CF3) case. Thus, the use of diAr-SO2 with (CH3, CF3) is favorable for the transmetalation. The SO2 insertion into the Bi&#8211;Ph bond of (Ph)Bi(diAr-SO2) occurs with a moderate &#916;G&#176;&#8225; value, whereas the SO2 insertion is difficult to occur when the sulfone (SO2) group of diAr-SO2 is replaced with a CH2 group. The SO2 insertion occurs via a nucleophilic attack of the Ph group to SO2. However, (Ph)Bi(diAr-SO2) with (CH3, CH3) is not the most reactive because not only the HOMO energy of (Ph)Bi(diAr-SO2) but also factors such as the Bi&#948;+&#8211;(C6H3R)&#948;&#8722; (R = CH3 or CF3) bond dipole moment and the Bi&#8211;C6H3R bond strength participate in determining the reactivity of (Ph)Bi(diAr-SO2) for the SO2 insertion where C6H3R is the aryl part of diArSO2. The fluorination occurs with a moderate &#916;G&#176;&#8225; value and an extremely negative &#916;G&#176; value. Its &#916;G&#176;&#8225; value hardly depends on the substituents of diAr-SO2. The presence of K3PO4 and the use of diAr-SO2 ligand with (CH3, CF3) are key for the catalytic activity of the bismuth catalyst.</description>
      <author>Yu Tian, Shigeyoshi Sakaki</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visible-Light Photocatalytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production Boosted by Frustrated Lewis Pairs in Defected Polymeric Carbon Nitride Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05360</link>
      <description>Lixia Ma, Yaping Gao, Baoqiang Wei, Luo Huang, Nan Zhang, Qiang Weng, Lu Zhang, Shengzhong Liu, Ruibin Jiang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391594826

                Frustrated Lewis pairs (FLPs) with a unique &#8220;push&#8211;pull&#8221; effect can effectively activate many types of molecules to obtain unanticipated catalytic activity. Herein, FLPs are introduced into polymeric carbon nitride (CN), and their functions in the photocatalytic synthesis of H2O2 are studied. The FLPs in B-doped CN (BCN) are constituted by electron-deficient boron as Lewis acid sites and nitrogen neighbored with cyano groups as Lewis base sites. The formation of FLPs can improve the light absorption ability and the separation of photogenerated carriers. The FLPs afford strong adsorption of O2, but cannot produce H2O2 directly because the strong activation of oxygen bonds leads to oxygen bond scission during reduction. The FLPs enhance H2O2 production through the effective activation of ethanol (ETOH) by the &#8220;push&#8211;pull&#8221; effect of FLPs. The reduction of O2 to H2O2 is found through &#8226;O2&#8211; and 1O2 species. The photocatalytic H2O2 production rate on BCN can reach 51,008 &#956;M g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1, which is over 12 times that of pristine CN (4113 &#956;M g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1). This study not only provides an effective approach for enhancing photocatalytic H2O2 production but also deepens the understanding of the role of FLPs in molecule activation.</description>
      <author>Lixia Ma, Yaping Gao, Baoqiang Wei, Luo Huang, Nan Zhang, Qiang Weng, Lu Zhang, Shengzhong Liu, Ruibin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Methanol on Cu/ZnO/Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Industrial Catalyst. What Do We Know about the Active Phase and the Reaction Mechanism?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05669</link>
      <description>Gianfranco Pacchioni, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391600545

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion Effect of Pd in the Ru/C-Catalyzed Hydrogenation of Benzofurans</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05429</link>
      <description>Miao Guo, Huicong Dai, Qihua Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391602174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miao Guo, Huicong Dai, Qihua Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAIR Data and Software: Improving Efficiency and Quality of Biocatalytic Science</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06337</link>
      <description>J&#252;rgen Pleiss, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391603087

                Biocatalysis is entering a promising era as a data-driven science. High-throughput experimentation generates a rapidly increasing stream of biocatalytic data, which is the raw material for mechanistic and data-driven modeling to design improved biocatalysts and bioprocesses. However, our laboratory routines and our scientific practice of communicating scientific results are insufficient to ensure the reproducibility and scalability of experiments, and data management has become a bottleneck to progress in biocatalysis. In order to take full advantage of rapid progress in experimental and computational technologies, biocatalytic data should be findable, accessible, interoperable, and reusable (FAIR). FAIRification of data and software is achieved by developing standardized data exchange formats and ontologies, by electronic lab notebooks for data acquisition and documentation of experimentation, collaborative platforms for developing software and analyzing data, and repositories for publishing results together with raw data. The EnzymeML platform provides reusable and extensible tools and formats for FAIR and scalable data management in biocatalysis. FAIRification of data and software and the digitalization of biocatalysis are expected to improve the efficiency of research by automation and to guarantee the quality of biocatalytic science by reproducibility. Most of all, they foster reasoning and creating hypotheses by enabling the reanalysis of previously published data, and thus promote disruptive research and innovation.</description>
      <author>J&#252;rgen Pleiss</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shield Machine-like Substrate Walking Strategy-Based Pocket Engineering of F-Amine Dehydrogenase for Accessing Structurally Diverse Fused-Ring and Linked-Ring Aryl Ketones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00068</link>
      <description>Tao Wu, Yan Xu, Yao Nie, Xiaoqing Mu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391612989

                Although amine dehydrogenases (AmDHs) are emerging as attractive biocatalysts for chiral amine synthesis, their synthetic application in structurally diverse arylamines remains challenging, given the limited substrate acceptance. Substrate walking is an effective coevolution strategy to confer targeted substrate acceptance to an enzyme through a stepwise mutagenesis landscape adaptation. Here, based on the conventional substrate walking strategy, we report a shield machine-like substrate walking strategy to quickly evolve F-BbAmDH from Bacillus badius for accessing the difficult-to-aminate fused-ring and linked-ring aryl ketones. A set of monoring aryl ketone homologues with the benzene ring located at the end of the side-chain and regularly extended carbon skeletons was rationally selected as the transition substrates. A superior mutant library with expanded target fused-ring and linked-ring aryl ketone acceptance was identified based on the activity and specificity enhancement of the transition substrates, enabling the synthesis of pharmaceuticals and bioactive compound-related arylamines with up to 94% yield and 99% ee (R) or 99:1 cis/trans. Structure-based computational results provided molecular insights into the source of the expanded substrate acceptance. Our work demonstrates a concise engineering workflow for the collective acceptance evolution of enzymes for structurally diverse substrate panels and has promising prospects in enzyme engineering.</description>
      <author>Tao Wu, Yan Xu, Yao Nie, Xiaoqing Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles-Based Kinetic Monte Carlo Model of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction under Realistic Conditions: Solvent, Hydrogen Coverage and Electric Field Effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04588</link>
      <description>Yuhong Luo, Yani Guan, Guihua Liu, Yanji Wang, Jingde Li, Luis Ricardez&#8208;Sandoval, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391614041

                The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) plays an important role in electrocatalytic water splitting. Despite the progress on the development of HER catalysts, the dynamic evolution of HER reaction under realistic electrochemical conditions considering the electric field, solvent, and hydrogen coverage effects is still unclear. In this study, a first-principles-based H surface coverage and potential-dependent kinetic Monte Carlo (KMC) HER model on the Pt (111)/Pt (100) surface is presented. The reaction kinetics and electronic structure analysis of HER on Pt surfaces in the presence of dihydrated proton (H5O2+) and H surface coverage is investigated using density functional theory (DFT). The HER KMC model was developed based on the DFT-calculated energetics. The KMC simulation results showed that consideration of H5O2+ species and dynamic evolution of H coverage is essential for accurate description of HER reaction on the Pt catalyst, which fits well with HER polarization data. Moreover, sensitivity analysis shows that HER on Pt (111) is mainly affected by the Tafel step. On the Pt(100) surface, HER is primarily governed by the Heyrovsky pathway. Surface species evolution analysis demonstrates that the high working potential accelerated the formation of [Pt-2H] species, leading to increased H coverage and accelerating the HER process. The predicted weakened H binding strength and increased H coverage at high HER working potential was verified by in situ attenuated total reflection Fourier transformed infrared spectroscopy analysis. Overall, the proposed DFT-KMC model represents the state-of-art dynamic simulation of catalytic HER reaction, providing important insights into the evolution of HER under realistic operation conditions.</description>
      <author>Yuhong Luo, Yani Guan, Guihua Liu, Yanji Wang, Jingde Li, Luis Ricardez&#8208;Sandoval</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Catalyzed Asymmetric Yne-Allylic Substitution Using Electron-Rich Arenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06146</link>
      <description>Defu Luo, Shengtong Niu, Fan Gong, Chao Xu, Shouang Lan, Jinggong Liu, Shuang Yang, Xinqiang Fang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391616495

                Remote stereocontrol in transition-metal catalysis is a challenging but interesting research topic. In this work, we achieved copper-catalyzed asymmetric yne-allylic substitution using electron-rich arenes and acyclic carbonates through remote enantioselectivity control. The reaction delivers a variety of enantioenriched products that contain a diverse set of valuable moieties, such as conjugated enynes, indoles, indolizines, allenes, and dihydrofurans, which are widely used in organic synthesis and act as key units in bioactive molecules and natural products. The synthetic value of this protocol has been demonstrated in a series of further transformations, and mechanistic studies have been conducted to gain more insight into the reaction.</description>
      <author>Defu Luo, Shengtong Niu, Fan Gong, Chao Xu, Shouang Lan, Jinggong Liu, Shuang Yang, Xinqiang Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selecting between Ammonia and Water Oxidation: Electrochemical Oxidation of Ammonia in Water Using an Organometallic&#8211;Inorganic Hybrid Anode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05899</link>
      <description>Han-Yu Liu, Josephine A. Jayworth, Robert H. Crabtree, Gary W. Brudvig, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391637546

                Electrocatalytic ammonia oxidation (AO) under ambient conditions in an aqueous solvent enables an ecofriendly production of nitrite and nitrate. Conventional formation of nitrite and nitrate by AO on noble metals often yields undesired dinitrogen and leads to detrimental nitride surface poisoning. We now find that our previously reported &#8220;Blue Layer&#8221; (BL), an organometallic&#8211;inorganic hybrid anode based on [IrO2]x nanoclusters (x &#8764; 5), is active for selective AO in aqueous solution. Through adjustment of both pH and applied potential (Eapp), we identified optimal operating conditions (pH 8.0, 1.00 V) for AO, where BL achieves optimum selectivity toward nitrate (90.5%), effectively minimizing competitive water oxidation while maintaining activity against ammonia-induced degradation of the electrode.</description>
      <author>Han-Yu Liu, Josephine A. Jayworth, Robert H. Crabtree, Gary W. Brudvig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Structure&#8211;Property Relationship of MgO-Supported Ni Ammonia Decomposition Catalysts from Bulk to Atomic Structure by In Situ/Operando Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05629</link>
      <description>T. H. Ulucan, Jihao Wang, E Onur, Shilong Chen, Malte Behrens, Claudia Weidenthaler, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391642373

                Ammonia is currently being studied intensively as a hydrogen carrier in the context of the energy transition. The endothermic decomposition reaction requires the use of suitable catalysts. In this study, transition metal Ni on MgO as a support is investigated with respect to its catalytic properties. The synthesis method and the type of activation process contribute significantly to the catalytic properties. Both methods, coprecipitation (CP) and wet impregnation (WI), lead to the formation of Mg1&#8211;xNixO solid solutions as catalyst precursors. X-ray absorption studies reveal that CP leads to a more homogeneous distribution of Ni2+ cations in the solid solution, which is advantageous for a homogeneous distribution of active Ni catalysts on the MgO support. Activation in hydrogen at 900 &#176;C reduces nickel, which migrates to the support surface and forms metal nanoparticles between 6 nm (CP) and 9 nm (WI), as shown by ex situ STEM. Due to the homogeneously distributed Ni2+ cations in the solid solution structure, CP samples are more difficult to activate and require harsher conditions to reduce the Ni. The combination of in situ X-ray diffraction (XRD) and operando total scattering experiments allows a structure&#8211;property investigation of the bulk down to the atomic level during the catalytic reaction. Activation in H2 at 900 &#176;C for 2 h leads to the formation of large Ni particles (20&#8211;30 nm) for the samples synthesized by the WI method, whereas Ni stays significantly smaller for the CP samples (10&#8211;20 nm). Sintering has a negative influence on the catalytic conversion of the WI samples, which is significantly lower compared to the conversion observed for the CP samples. Interestingly, metallic Ni redisperses during cooling and becomes invisible for conventional XRD but can still be detected by total scattering methods. The conditions of activation in NH3 at 650 &#176;C are not suitable to form enough reduced Ni nanoparticles from the solid solution and are, therefore, not a suitable activation procedure. The activity steadily increases in the samples activated at 650 &#176;C in NH3 (Group 1) compared to the samples activated at 650 &#176;C in H2 and then reaches the best activity in the samples activated at 900 &#176;C in H2. Only the combination of complementary in situ and ex situ characterization methods provides enough information to identify important structure&#8211;property relationships among these promising ammonia decomposition catalysts.</description>
      <author>T. H. Ulucan, Jihao Wang, E Onur, Shilong Chen, Malte Behrens, Claudia Weidenthaler</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stereoselective &lt;i&gt;gem&lt;/i&gt;-Difunctionalization of Diazo Compounds with Vinyl Sulfoxonium Ylides and Thiols via Metalloradical Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06098</link>
      <description>Srashti Bhardwaj, Dinesh Kumar Gopalakrishnan, Shalu Deshwal, Raju Sen, Vikas Tiwari, Tarak Karmakar, Janakiram Vaitla, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391653535

                Multicomponent reactions that involve carbenes with nucleophiles and electrophiles have demonstrated broad applications in synthetic chemistry. However, because of the high reactivity of transient carbenes, reactions involving two carbene precursors with the nucleophile in the presence of a metal catalyst remain unexplored. Herein, a three-component stereoselective gem-difunctionalization of diazo compounds with thiols and vinyl sulfoxonium ylide is disclosed via Co(II)-based metalloradical catalysis. The key aspect of the present strategy is to exploit the intrinsic difference in the reactivity of vinyl sulfoxonium ylides and diazo compounds with thiol and metal catalysts. The present Doyle&#8211;Kirmse rearrangement of a sulfonium ylide involves a convergent assembly of two in situ-generated intermediates, such as allyl sulfide and &#945;- metalloalkyl radical complex, to provide expeditious access to tertiary sulfide scaffolds. Combined experimental and quantum chemical calculations unveil the intricate mechanism of this three-component reaction. Furthermore, theoretical studies on noncovalent interactions of selectivity-determining transition states explain the origin of the experimentally obtained diastereoselectivity.</description>
      <author>Srashti Bhardwaj, Dinesh Kumar Gopalakrishnan, Shalu Deshwal, Raju Sen, Vikas Tiwari, Tarak Karmakar, Janakiram Vaitla</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous Cu&#8211;W Alloys as Stable and Efficient Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05820</link>
      <description>Xiying Jian, Wenbiao Zhang, Yaxiong Yang, Zhenglong Li, Hongge Pan, Qingsheng Gao, Huaijun Lin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391656368

                Cu and W are completely immiscible in equilibrium conditions, and neither of them is a good catalytic element for the electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to their hydrogen adsorption Gibbs free energy (&#916;GH) being too positive or negative, respectively. However, the combination of Cu with W could potentially result in a moderate &#916;GH. In this study, a series of binary amorphous Cu&#8211;W alloys are fabricated via a magnetron sputtering method. The optimal HER catalytic performance is demonstrated when the nominal component is Cu50W50, showing an overpotential of only 65 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1 M KOH. Accordingly, density functional theory calculations show that the amorphous Cu50W50 alloy has a close-to-zero &#916;GH compared to the pure Cu and W metals, accounting for its HER activity. In addition, the amorphous Cu50W50 alloy shows no obvious degradation at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 for 200 h, highlighting its long-term durability. This work provides a versatile strategy for the preparation of amorphous alloys with completely immiscible components and insights into the compositional design of nonprecious metal electrocatalysts for widespread applications.</description>
      <author>Xiying Jian, Wenbiao Zhang, Yaxiong Yang, Zhenglong Li, Hongge Pan, Qingsheng Gao, Huaijun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05820</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward High CO Selectivity and Oxidation Resistance Solid Oxide Electrolysis Cell with High-Entropy Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05972</link>
      <description>Jun Tang, Na Ni, Baowen Zhou, Chen Yang, Kolan Madhav Reddy, Heng Tu, Yu-Si Liu, Zhe Tan, Longkai Xiang, Haozhen Li, Xing Zhang, Yunyi Zhang, Yixin Li, Hanchao Zhang, Lei Zhu, Zhen Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391679800

                Ni-based cermet materials still persist as pronounced challenges for electrocatalysts in solid oxide electrolysis cells (SOECs), due to their insufficient CO2 catalytic efficiency and inferior resistance to oxidation. In this paper, a (Fe,Co,Ni,Cu,Mo) quinary high-entropy alloy is explored as an alternative cathode material, offering enhanced performance in the co-electrolysis of H2O and CO2 for renewable syngas production. In comparison to traditional nickel-based cathodes, an assembled SOEC employing the as-designed quinary high-entropy alloy exhibits a remarkable increase in CO2 conversion capacity and significantly enhanced oxidation resistance. In addition, the electrolysis current density increases by 18%, and a stability test for more than 110 h reveals no degradation. Moreover, the stability can be maintained for up to 40 h even without any protective gas. Morphological and spectroscopic analyses, coupled with density functional theory (DFT) calculations, elucidate that the high-entropy effect facilitates surface electron redistribution, which in turn contributes to the measurable activity by reducing the energy barrier of CO2 activation. Notably, the superior resistance to oxidation primarily originates from the in situ-formed spinel phase under oxidation conditions. This study demonstrates the satisfying performance of high-entropy alloys as cathode materials in SOEC, validating their high application potential in this field.</description>
      <author>Jun Tang, Na Ni, Baowen Zhou, Chen Yang, Kolan Madhav Reddy, Heng Tu, Yu-Si Liu, Zhe Tan, Longkai Xiang, Haozhen Li, Xing Zhang, Yunyi Zhang, Yixin Li, Hanchao Zhang, Lei Zhu, Zhen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dehydrogenation and Transfer Hydrogenation of Alkenones to Phenols and Ketones on Carbon-Supported Noble Metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04849</link>
      <description>Katja Li, H. Ray Kelly, Jos&#233; Armando L. da Silva, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Eszter Bar&#225;th, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391681918

                The catalytic dehydrogenation of substituted alkenones on noble metal catalysts supported on carbon (Pt/C, Pd/C, Rh/C, and Ru/C) was investigated in an organic phase under inert conditions. The dehydrogenation and semihydrogenation of the enone starting materials resulted in aromatic compounds (primary products), saturated cyclic ketones (secondary products), and cyclic alcohols (minor products). Pd/C exhibits the highest catalytic activity, followed by Pt/C and Rh/C. Aromatic compounds remain the primary products, even in the presence of hydrogen donors. Joint experimental and theoretical analyses showed that the four catalytic materials stabilize a common dienol intermediate on the metal surfaces, formed by keto&#8211;enol tautomerization. This intermediate subsequently forms aromatic products upon dehydrogenation. The binding orientation of the enone reactants on the catalytic surface is strongly metal-dependent, as the M&#8211;O bond distance changes substantially according to the metal. The longer M&#8211;O bonds (Pt: 2.84 &#197; &gt; Pd: 2.23 &#197; &gt; Rh: 2.17 &#197; &gt; Ru: 2.07 &#197;) correlate with faster reaction rates and more favorable keto&#8211;enol tautomerization, as shorter distances correspond to a more stabilized starting material. Tautomerization is shown to occur via a stepwise surface-assisted pathway. Overall, each of the studied metals exhibits a distinct balance of enthalpy and entropy of activation (&#916;H&#176;&#8225;, &#916;S&#176;&#8225;), offering unique possibilities in the realm of enone dehydrogenation reactions that can be achieved by suitable selection of catalytic materials.</description>
      <author>Katja Li, H. Ray Kelly, Jos&#233; Armando L. da Silva, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Eszter Bar&#225;th</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Dynamic Evolution of Single-Atom Co Sites in Covalent Triazine Frameworks for Enhanced H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04439</link>
      <description>Chao Zhu, Yanchi Yao, Qile Fang, Lingxiangyu Li, Baoliang Chen, Yi Shen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391685024

                Unraveling the structural evolution and mechanism of active sites in single-atom catalysts (SACs) during H2O2 production under operational conditions remains challenging due to the transient and elusive nature of the underlying reaction processes. Herein, we employ operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations to unveil the dynamic reconstruction behavior of the Co single atom-loaded covalent triazine framework (CoSA/Py-CTF) during photocatalytic H2O2 production. The unique Py-CTF substrate provides reasonable structural flexibility to the single atom Co site. Under light irradiation and O2 adsorption, single Co atoms are dynamically released from the Py-CTF substrate and then form transient atom-pairs with neighboring Co atoms, serving as the authentic active site. The dynamic shuttling of Co subnanometer domains between single-atoms and atom-pairs facilitates the transition of the O2 adsorption configurations from Pauling type to Yeager type, resulting in a record photocatalytic H2O2 yield (2898.3 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1&#183;g&#8211;1). These findings provide insightful observations into the dynamic photochemical behavior of SACs and present an fresh paradigm for the design of intelligent &#8220;adaptive catalysts&#8221;.</description>
      <author>Chao Zhu, Yanchi Yao, Qile Fang, Lingxiangyu Li, Baoliang Chen, Yi Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium-Catalyzed Tandem Dehydrogenation/Hydroarylation Approach to Synthetically Versatile C2-Alkenyl N&#8211;H Indoles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05841</link>
      <description>Carlos L&#225;zaro&#8208;Milla, Jos&#233; L. Mascare&#241;as, Fernando Fern&#225;ndez L&#243;pez, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391691736

                Readily available N-carbamoyl indolines can be converted into highly valuable 2-alkenyl and 2-alkyl indoles in a one-pot reaction, through an autotandem catalytic cascade promoted by an iridium complex. The process entails a dehydrogenation reaction initiated by an iridium-promoted C(sp3)&#8211;H activation, the addition of the resulting indole to an alkyne -or alkene-partner, and a spontaneous loss of the carbamoyl directing group. Interestingly, the resulting C2-alkenyl indoles can participate in a variety of metal-catalyzed annulations initiated by C&#8211;H activation, including formal [4 + 1] and [4 + 2] cycloadditions, as well as cross-dehydrogenative cyclizations, thus enabling a divergent access to a collection of functionally rich nitrogen-containing heterocycles.</description>
      <author>Carlos L&#225;zaro&#8208;Milla, Jos&#233; L. Mascare&#241;as, Fernando Fern&#225;ndez L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05841</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size-Dependent Structural Features of Subnanometer PtSn Catalysts Encapsulated in Zeolite for Alkane Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00314</link>
      <description>Xiao-Meng Dou, Wenying Li, Kun Zhang, Haiyun Hou, Zhe He, Chaofeng Zhu, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Miguel L&#243;pez&#8208;Haro, Zhaoming Xia, Peng He, Hai Xiao, Lichen Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391692005

                Identification of the most efficient configuration of subnanometer bimetallic clusters is of great importance for the rational design of bimetallic catalysts but remains challenging due to the difficulty to construct the appropriate model systems. Here, we have accommodated subnanometer Pt/Sn sites, spanning from metal single atoms to bimetallic clusters in the 10MR sinusoidal channels of pure-silica MFI-type zeolite, which are employed as model catalysts to identify the optimal configuration of subnanometer PtSn sites for catalyzing an alkane dehydrogenation reaction. According to the electron microscopy and spectroscopy characterization results, the structural configuration of the bimetallic PtSn species in MFI zeolite varies with the Pt loading, which influences their catalytic performances for the propane dehydrogenation reaction. Furthermore, theoretical calculations are performed to understand the structural features of various PtSn species and their catalytic behavior for propane dehydrogenation, providing insights into the structure&#8211;reactivity relationships of subnanometer PtSn catalysts confined in zeolite structures.</description>
      <author>Xiao-Meng Dou, Wenying Li, Kun Zhang, Haiyun Hou, Zhe He, Chaofeng Zhu, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Miguel L&#243;pez&#8208;Haro, Zhaoming Xia, Peng He, Hai Xiao, Lichen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Remarkable Influence of La(III)/&lt;i&gt;N,N&lt;/i&gt;&#8242;-Dioxide Structure on Asymmetric Formal Substitution of 3-Bromo-3-substituted Oxindoles with TMSCN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06130</link>
      <description>Zi Zeng, Longqing Yang, Xiao Zhang, Long Chen, Ziwei Zhong, Fei Wang, Xiaohua Liu, Shujuan Dong, Xiaoming Feng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391719372

                The structural elucidation of chiral rare-earth-based catalysts in asymmetric reactions holds significant importance as it is crucial for comprehending their operational mechanisms and for broadening their applications in the realm of asymmetric synthesis. Herein, a LaIII/(L3-RaMe3)2 complex was identified to be more active and enantioselective than LaIII/L3-RaMe3 in the asymmetric formal substitution of racemic 3-bromo-3-substituted oxindoles with TMSCN. The experimental studies and theoretical calculations disclosed that the partial dissociation of the chiral N,N&#8242;-dioxide ligand was involved in the catalytic process with LaIII/(L3-RaMe3)2. These insights provided a rationale for the remarkable effect of catalyst structures on the results and nonlinear effect observed in the current reaction system. This protocol offers a straightforward and efficient pathway to synthesize various chiral 3-cyano-3-substituted oxindoles (53 examples, up to 99% yield, 98% ee). In addition, the synthesis of a bioactive compound CRTH2 receptor antagonist and obvious inhibitory effect of several products on the viability of cancer cells demonstrate the potential utility of this methodology.</description>
      <author>Zi Zeng, Longqing Yang, Xiao Zhang, Long Chen, Ziwei Zhong, Fei Wang, Xiaohua Liu, Shujuan Dong, Xiaoming Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Strain Effect on Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction of Pt-Based Intermetallics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06291</link>
      <description>Z.Y. Zhong, Yuanhua Tu, Longhai Zhang, Ke Jiang, Chengzhi Zhong, Wei Tan, Lingyu Wang, Jiaxi Zhang, Hui&#8208;Hua Song, Li Du, Zhiming Cui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391738668

                Elucidating the relationship between electrocatalytic activity and surface strain is pivotal for designing highly efficient electrocatalysts for the acidic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, a general correlation is currently absent due to the lack of ideal catalytic materials platforms with well-defined structures and components. Herein, we select L10 and L12 Pt-based intermetallic compounds as model materials to construct a series of core&#8211;shell catalysts with strained Pt skins (IMC@Pt) and establish the correlation between surface strain and HER performance. Density functional theory calculations were performed to determine the surface strain degree, d-band center, and key descriptor &#916;GH* of the catalysts for HER. By combining theoretical and experimental data, we propose a volcano-type trend between surface strain and the HER activity of IMC@Pt with an apex at 4% compressive strain. In addition, we demonstrate a class of highly active and durable IMC@Pt catalysts for acidic HER. Among them, the Pt3V@Pt catalyst exhibits the highest intrinsic HER activity with a specific activity of 4.24 mA cmPt&#8211;2 at an overpotential of 20 mV, which is 4 times higher than that of Pt. This work provides a solid understanding of the essential nature of PtM alloy catalysts and can guide the design of high-performance HER catalysts for water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Z.Y. Zhong, Yuanhua Tu, Longhai Zhang, Ke Jiang, Chengzhi Zhong, Wei Tan, Lingyu Wang, Jiaxi Zhang, Hui&#8208;Hua Song, Li Du, Zhiming Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Functional Plasticity of Two Diterpene Synthases (IrTPS2/IrKSL3a) to Enzyme Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05918</link>
      <description>Baolong Jin, Kangwei Xu, Juan Guo, Ying Ma, Jian Yang, Nianhang Chen, Tao Zeng, Jian Wang, Jianing Liu, Ming Tian, Qing Ma, Haiyan Zhang, Reuben J. Peters, Guanghong Cui, Ruibo Wu, Luqi Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391745873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baolong Jin, Kangwei Xu, Juan Guo, Ying Ma, Jian Yang, Nianhang Chen, Tao Zeng, Jian Wang, Jianing Liu, Ming Tian, Qing Ma, Haiyan Zhang, Reuben J. Peters, Guanghong Cui, Ruibo Wu, Luqi Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tandem Chemical Depolymerization and Photoreforming of Waste PET Plastic to High-Value-Added Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05535</link>
      <description>Mei Li, Shengbo Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391745876

                Photoreforming of poly(ethylene terephthalate) (PET) wastes to high-value-added chemicals is an emerging and promising approach. Nonetheless, a major obstacle is the harsh alkaline pretreatment (COH&#8211; = 5&#8211;10 M) to depolymerize PET, resulting in a surge in processing costs and also posing great challenges to subsequent photocatalytic devices, catalysts, and photocatalytic efficiency. Herein, we introduce a tandem process of chemical depolymerization and photoreforming of waste PET plastics. Depolymerization of PET to monomers is achieved through an intramolecular hydrolysis mechanism on a binuclear zinc catalyst under mild conditions (COH&#8211; &#8804; 0.1 M and T &#8804; 60 &#176;C). Compared with the traditional harsh alkali pretreatment, the depolymerization rate can be increased by nearly an order of magnitude due to the proximity effect of the bimetallic sites. Technoeconomic analysis shows that processing 50,000 tons of plastic annually can save 15.2 million USD. The photoreforming of PET to formic acid and H2 with an impressive production rate of 2000 &#956;mol gcat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 was achieved on an ultrasmall carbon nitride nanosphere photocatalyst, which is nearly 5-fold higher than the corresponding strong alkali pretreatment system. Mechanism research reveals high photocatalytic activity thanks to the mild PET pretreatment and the efficient electron&#8211;hole separation caused by the ultrasmall carbon nitride nanosphere size structure and the electron capture effect of metal Pt. We also demonstrate a gram-scale integrated process for real-world PET plastic wastes including water bottles, clothing fibers, towels, carpets, and mixed plastics containing PET. Our study establishes a new concept of tandem catalysis to reduce the harsh pretreatment of PET by using a synthetic catalyst in polyester plastic photoreforming technology.</description>
      <author>Mei Li, Shengbo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Dynamics in Lean Propylene Catalytic Combustion over CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Pr&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;11&lt;/sub&gt;: Roles and Interplay between Lattice and Adsorbed Oxygen Species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05556</link>
      <description>Xiwei Gao, L. Li, Yuquan Liu, Zheng Chen, Wei Liu, Min Li, Xiaodong Wu, Shuang Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391748560

                In 1954, Mars and van Krevelen proposed the famous &#8220;redox&#8221; mechanism to rationalize the oxidation of hydrocarbons (HCs) over vanadium oxide catalysts. According to this mechanism, the reduction of oxide catalysts (hydrogen abstraction, dehydroxylation, and metal&#8211;oxygen bond cleavage) are kinetically relevant in most cases, and oxides with high reducibility can be made into catalysts with high activity for HC (deep) oxidation. Such a framework, however, cannot explain the fact that Pr6O11 with the most liable lattice oxygen among lanthanide oxides is a worse low-temperature propylene oxidizer than CeO2. In this article, by comparing the kinetic/isotopic performance and the reduction/reoxidation behavior of rod-like CeO2 and Pr6O11 counterparts during lean propylene catalytic combustion, it was suggested that both these lanthanide oxides ignited propylene via a classical redox mechanism, while the reactive oxygen species involved in their following reactions were quite different. Specifically, the reactions over Pr6O11 were limited by the replenishment of lattice oxygen&#9472;the consistent workhorse reactive phase of this catalyst, and could be effectively accelerated at elevated temperature with a drastic dropping in the apparent activation energy (Eaapp, from 75.9 to 60.1 kJ/mol). In contrast, due to the relatively low electrochemical reduction potential of Ce4+/Ce3+ (1.74 eV) than that of Pr4+/Pr3+ (3.2 eV), the propylene-induced defective sites (e.g., Ce3+&#8211;VO) on CeO2&#8211;x readily donated Ce3+ 4f1 electrons to adsorbed O2 during the reoxidation steps in the redox cycles, giving rise to adsorbed oxygen species like O22&#8211; and O&#8211;. These electrophilic Oxn&#8211; species played active roles in the following reduction steps. Benefited from the &#8220;shallow&#8221; reactive region and therefore multiplied redox cycles of CeO2, such an &#8220;Oxn&#8211;-assisted&#8221; Mars&#8211;van Krevelen mechanism led to low Eaapp (&#8764;43 kJ/mol) values close to those obtained on platinum catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiwei Gao, L. Li, Yuquan Liu, Zheng Chen, Wei Liu, Min Li, Xiaodong Wu, Shuang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Combination of Inorganic and Organic Promoters on Palladium Catalysts for Effective Acetylene Partial Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05474</link>
      <description>Kyunglim Hyun, Seongho Yun, Minkee Choi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391754932

                Selective acetylene partial hydrogenation in an ethylene-rich stream plays a crucial industrial role in removing acetylene impurities from ethylene produced through hydrocarbon cracking. In this study, we investigated the distinct promotional effects of Ag and amorphous polyphenylene sulfide (Am-PPS) on Pd catalysts. The addition of Ag increased the electron density of Pd and reduced the size of the Pd ensemble, effectively inhibiting undesired side reactions, such as the overhydrogenation of ethylene to ethane and the hydro-oligomerization of acetylene into C4 and heavier paraffins (green oil). However, alloying with inactive Ag resulted in a reduced number of surface-exposed active Pd atoms, leading to a significant decrease in catalytic activity. On the other hand, surface modification of Pd with Am-PPS was very effective in suppressing ethylene overhydrogenation without compromising acetylene hydrogenation activity. Furthermore, it facilitated the removal of green oil from the catalyst surface before its transformation into coke, significantly retarding the catalyst deactivation. This can be attributed to the rapid cleaning of ethylene and green oil from the Pd surface through the competitive adsorption of the Am-PPS polymer chains. The advantages of each promoter can be synergistically combined through dual promotion. The resulting catalyst exhibited moderate activity, along with exceptionally high ethylene selectivity, and suppressed formation of carbonaceous deposits (both green oil and coke). These findings demonstrate the unique potential to design advanced selective hydrogenation catalysts by leveraging the advantages of both inorganic and organic promoters.</description>
      <author>Kyunglim Hyun, Seongho Yun, Minkee Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Rigidified Superexchange Couplings in Organic Donor&#8211;Acceptor Polymers for Boosting the Photocatalytic Reduction of Nitrate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05937</link>
      <description>Haiyan Peng, Yuhui Liu, Yi Wang, Meiyang Song, Henghui Song, Peng Chen, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391755214

                Regulating the spatial twist angle of flexible geometry is an effective strategy to enhance the spatial overlap in organic semiconductors and provide transfer channels for electron transfer. However, the internal migration rates of macromolecular polymers with flexible geometries and complex compositions are severely restricted, making them elusive and easily overlooked. Here, different configurations of donor&#8211;acceptor (D&#8211;A)-based perylene diimide (PDI) polymers have been elaborately designed and prepared. In fact, the high crystallinity and molecular polarity of coplanar semiconductors lead to a differentiated charge distribution and carrier transfer site, which opens the prelude for charge transfer and exciton dissociation. More importantly, the unique &#960;-conjugated D&#8211;A configuration not only provides a smooth carrier transfer channel for promoting intermolecular electron transfer rates but is also conducive to the adsorption, diffusion, and charge exchange and activation of nitric acid as well as reduces the hydrogenation energy barrier. Ultimately, the coplanar configuration of PDI-connected 3,3-diaminobenzidine polymers (D-PDI) exhibited efficient photocatalytic nitrate reduction activity without the use of a cocatalyst and sacrificial agent. Our work provides fresh insights into molecular structure regulation to develop efficient photocatalysts for solving environmental problems.</description>
      <author>Haiyan Peng, Yuhui Liu, Yi Wang, Meiyang Song, Henghui Song, Peng Chen, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05937</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
