<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 01:02:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Double Catalytic Activity Unveiled: Synthesis, Characterization, and Catalytic Applications of Iridium Complexes in Transfer Hydrogenation and Photomediated Transformations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00673</link>
      <description>Laura Blanco, Andrea Uroz, Kevin Guti&#233;rrez, Silvia Cabrera, Alba Collado, Jos&#233; V. Alem&#225;n, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394714242

                Iridium complexes have been demonstrated to be highly active catalysts for a wide variety of transformations. Their unique photophysical and photochemical properties render them as one of the most established photocatalysts. Moreover, iridium complexes are widely acknowledged for their efficiency in transfer hydrogenation reactions. However, the development of iridium complexes able to promote both traditional organometallic catalysis and photocatalysis is scarce. Thus, the design of iridium-based catalysts is still an active area of research. In this context, we targeted the synthesis of a family of Ir-Cp* systems to explore their (photo)catalytic applications. Here, we describe the synthesis, structural characterization, and photophysical properties of iridium complexes of formula [IrCp*Cl(N^O)]. These complexes have been applied with a double catalytic function, in transfer hydrogenation for carbonyl reduction and in different photomediated transformations.</description>
      <author>Laura Blanco, Andrea Uroz, Kevin Guti&#233;rrez, Silvia Cabrera, Alba Collado, Jos&#233; V. Alem&#225;n</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00673</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhodium(II)-Catalyzed Asymmetric Cyclopropanation and Desymmetrization of [2.2]Paracyclophanes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01292</link>
      <description>Duc Ly, John Bacsa, Huw M. L. Davies, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394714316

                Chiral [2.2]paracyclophane derivatives are of considerable interest because of their potential in asymmetric catalysis and the development of chiral materials. This study describes the scope of rhodium-catalyzed reactions of aryldiazoacetates with [2.2]paracyclophanes. The reaction with the parent [2.2]paracyclophane resulted in cyclopropanation at two positions, the ratio of which is catalyst-controlled. Because of the strain in the system, one of the cyclopropanes exists primarily as the norcaradiene structure, whereas the other preferentially exists as the cycloheptatriene conformer. In contrast, the reaction with [3.3]paracyclophane results in benzylic C&#8211;H functionalization. The reactions with substituted [2.2]paracyclophanes using chiral catalysts can result in either kinetic resolution or desymmetrization. The Rh2(S-p-PhTPCP)]4-catalyzed reaction of monosubstituted paracyclophanes results in kinetic resolution with a selectivity (s) factor of up to 20, whereas reactions on C2v-symmetric disubstituted [2.2]paracyclophanes with Rh2(S-TPPTTL)4 [TPPTTL = 2-(1,3-dioxo-4,5,6,7-tetraphenylisoindolin-2-yl)-3,3-dimethylbutanoate] results in effective desymmetrization to form cycloheptatriene-incorporated paracyclophanes in 78&#8211;98% ee.</description>
      <author>Duc Ly, John Bacsa, Huw M. L. Davies</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New and Revised Aspects of the Electrochemical Synthesis of Hydrogen Peroxide: From Model Electrocatalytic Systems to Scalable Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01011</link>
      <description>Marco Mazzucato, Alessandro Facchin, Mattia Parnigotto, Christian Durante, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394716632

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marco Mazzucato, Alessandro Facchin, Mattia Parnigotto, Christian Durante</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enzymatic Stereodivergent Access to Fluorinated &#946;-Lactam Pharmacophores via Triple-Parameter Engineered Ketoreductases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00945</link>
      <description>Zelong Mei, Congcong Li, Xu Han, Ye Tian, Shuo-Han Li, Weidong Liu, Ge Qu, Manfred T. Reetz, Zhoutong Sun, Jun&#8208;An Ma, Fa&#8208;Guang Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394720109

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zelong Mei, Congcong Li, Xu Han, Ye Tian, Shuo-Han Li, Weidong Liu, Ge Qu, Manfred T. Reetz, Zhoutong Sun, Jun&#8208;An Ma, Fa&#8208;Guang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Based Catalysts for the Selective Monoarylation of Dichloropyridines: Ligand Effects and Mechanistic Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00648</link>
      <description>Geraldo Duran-Camacho, Douglas C. Bland, Fangzheng Li, Sharon R. Neufeldt, Melanie S. Sanford, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394728071

                This report describes a detailed study of Ni phosphine catalysts for the Suzuki&#8211;Miyaura coupling of dichloropyridines with halogen-containing (hetero)aryl boronic acids. With most phosphine ligands, these transformations afford mixtures of mono- and diarylated cross-coupling products as well as competing oligomerization of the boronic acid. However, a ligand screen revealed that PPh2Me and PPh3 afford high yield and selectivity for monoarylation over diarylation as well as minimal competing oligomerization of the boronic acid. Several key observations were made regarding the selectivity of these reactions, including: (1) phosphine ligands that afford high selectivity for monoarylation fall within a narrow range of Tolman cone angles (between 136 and 157&#176;); (2) more electron-rich trialkylphosphines afford predominantly diarylated products, while less electron-rich di- and triarylphosphines favor monoarylation; (3) diarylation proceeds via intramolecular oxidative addition; and (4) the solvent (MeCN) plays a crucial role in achieving high monoarylation selectivity. Experimental and density functional theory studies suggest that all of these data can be explained based on the reactivity of a key intermediate: a Ni0&#8211;&#960; complex of the monoarylated product. With larger, more electron-rich trialkylphosphine ligands, this &#960; complex undergoes intramolecular oxidative addition faster than ligand substitution by the MeCN solvent, leading to selective diarylation. In contrast, with relatively small di- and triarylphosphine ligands, associative ligand substitution by MeCN is competitive with oxidative addition, resulting in the selective formation of monoarylated products. The generality of this method is demonstrated with a variety of dichloropyridines and chloro-substituted aryl boronic acids. Furthermore, the optimal ligand (PPh2Me) and solvent (MeCN) are leveraged to achieve Ni-catalyzed monoarylation of a broader set of dichloroarene substrates.</description>
      <author>Geraldo Duran-Camacho, Douglas C. Bland, Fangzheng Li, Sharon R. Neufeldt, Melanie S. Sanford</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supported Catalytically Active Liquid Metal Solutions: Liquid Metal Catalysis with Ternary Alloys, Enhancing Activity in Propane Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01282</link>
      <description>Michael J. Moritz, Sven Maisel, Narayanan Raman, Haiko Wittk&#228;mper, Christoph Wichmann, Mathias Grabau, Deniz Kahraman, Julien Steffen, Nicola Taccardi, Andreas G&#246;rling, Marco Haumann, Peter Wasserscheid, Hans&#8208;Peter Steinr&#252;ck, Christian Papp, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394728272

                The research and optimization of catalysts are instrumental in revolutionizing chemical processes and making them viable in terms of energy and resources. Supported catalytically active liquid metal solutions (SCALMS) are highly active and stable in the harsh environment of the dehydrogenation reaction of alkanes. This is attributed to their liquid and dynamic nature and their isolated catalytically active single-atom sites. SCALMS consists of a liquid metal matrix (gallium) in which a catalytically active transition metal (platinum, rhodium, palladium, or nickel) is dissolved. Binary SCALMS systems are the subject of extensive research, aiming at a better understanding for achieving optimal performance. This work uses a combined multidisciplinary approach to examine ternary systems of the active transition metal platinum with mixtures of gallium with either tin or indium. Reaction engineering and surface chemical analysis by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy are combined with density functional theory (DFT) and machine learning force field (ML-FF) simulations. Introducing a third metal into the mixture alters the reactivity, surface composition, and concentration gradient in the liquid metal catalyst. We demonstrate that changes in catalytic reactivity correlate with changes in the surface concentration of the active transition metal platinum and of the position of the d-band center. These findings hold great promise for future research directions as they offer potential starting points for developing SCALMS systems.</description>
      <author>Michael J. Moritz, Sven Maisel, Narayanan Raman, Haiko Wittk&#228;mper, Christoph Wichmann, Mathias Grabau, Deniz Kahraman, Julien Steffen, Nicola Taccardi, Andreas G&#246;rling, Marco Haumann, Peter Wasserscheid, Hans&#8208;Peter Steinr&#252;ck, Christian Papp</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CN&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; Vacancies Enhance Ammonia Synthesis over Air-Durable Alkaline Earth Metal Cyanamide-Supported Cobalt Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00830</link>
      <description>Yihao Jiang, Masayoshi Miyazaki, Kiichi Miyashita, Masato Sasase, Kazuhisa Kishida, Hideo Hosono, Masaaki Kitano, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394720578

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yihao Jiang, Masayoshi Miyazaki, Kiichi Miyashita, Masato Sasase, Kazuhisa Kishida, Hideo Hosono, Masaaki Kitano</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into the Reaction Mechanism of Direct Hydrogenation of Maleic Anhydride to Produce 1,4-Butanediol on the Cu&#8211;ZnO Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00745</link>
      <description>Xinyue Guan, Yingzhe Yu, Minhua Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394742732

                1,4-Butanediol is a crucial monomer for the production of biodegradable plastics such as polybutylene succinate (PBS) and polybutyleneadipate-co-terephthalate (PBAT). It is also utilized in the synthesis of derivatives such as &#947;-butyrolactone and tetrahydrofuran. The technology of direct hydrogenation of maleic anhydride to produce 1,4-butanediol on Cu-based catalysts has gained significant attention due to its short process, mild reaction conditions, cost-effective catalysts, and the ability to cogenerate various products. This makes it a promising avenue for the production of 1,4-butanediol. At present, the reaction mechanism for the direct hydrogenation of maleic anhydride to produce 1,4-butanediol on Cu&#8211;ZnO is not well understood, and the types and pathways of byproducts remain unclear. This lack of clarity hinders the modification and application of catalysts for the direct hydrogenation of maleic anhydride to produce 1,4-butanediol. This study systematically investigates the reaction mechanism of direct hydrogenation of maleic anhydride to produce 1,4-butanediol on Cu&#8211;ZnO using spin-polarized density functional theory. The adsorption properties of surface species were studied, revealing that key species succinic anhydride, &#947;-butyrolactone, 1,4-butanediol, tetrahydrofuran, and n-butanol exhibit more stability in adsorption at the Cu211&#8211;ZnO interface compared to noninterface regions. The optimal pathway for the main reaction of direct hydrogenation of maleic anhydride on the Cu211 surface is clarified as MA &#8594; C4H3O3 &#8594; SA &#8594; C4H5O3 &#8594; C4H4O2 &#8594; C4H5O2 &#8594; GBL. At the Cu211&#8211;ZnO interface, the optimal pathway for the main reaction of direct hydrogenation involves MA &#8594; C4H3O3 &#8594; SA &#8594; C4H4O3 &#8594; C4H5O3 &#8594; C4H4O2 &#8594; C4H5O2 &#8594; GBL &#8594; C4H6O2 &#8594; C4H7O2 &#8594; C4H8O2 &#8594; C4H9O2 &#8594; BDO. The study indicates that the Cu211&#8211;ZnO interface is more favorable for the main reaction of direct hydrogenation of maleic anhydride. The most probable pathway for the formation of byproduct butyric acid during the direct hydrogenation on Cu211&#8211;ZnO involves MA &#8594; C4H2O3 &#8594; C4H3O3 &#8594; C4H4O3 &#8594; C4H5O3 &#8594; C4H6O3 &#8594; C4H5O2 &#8594; C4H6O2 &#8594; C4H7O2 &#8594; C4H8O2. The optimal path for the production of butanol involves the process starting with butyric acid, i.e., C4H8O2 &#8594; C4H9O2 &#8594; C4H8O &#8594; C4H9O &#8594; BuOH. Propionic acid is most likely formed through MA, i.e., MA &#8594; C4H2O3 &#8594; C4H3O2 &#8594; C3H4O2 &#8594; C3H5O2 &#8594; C3H6O2. Propionic acid and propionaldehyde are more likely byproducts in the system, with propyl alcohol being difficult to generate due to its higher energy barrier. The most probable pathway for CO production involves SA &#8594; C4H4O3 &#8594; C3H4O2 + CO. In the presence of water, the rate-controlling step for the generation of maleic acid from MA is C4H2O3 + H &#8594; C4H3O3. SA is more inclined to generate succinic acid, succinaldehyde, and GBL, rather than &#947;-hydroxybutyric acid and BDO, with the rate-controlling step being C4H7O2 &#8594; C4H6O2 + H. Water is more likely to form through the combination of two OH groups. During the catalyst construction and modification processes, it is advisable to construct as many Cu211&#8211;ZnO interfaces as possible within a reasonable range to enhance the production of 1,4-butanediol. Suppressing the open-loop reaction of maleic anhydride can effectively inhibit the generation of byproducts such as butyric acid, butyraldehyde, butanol, propionic acid, propionaldehyde, and maleic acid. Timely removal of water generated in the system is essential to prevent the transformation of maleic anhydride into maleic acid and the conversion of succinic anhydride into succinic acid and succinaldehyde. This helps minimize raw material consumption and reduce the formation of byproducts. The elucidation of the reaction mechanism of direct hydrogenation of maleic anhydride on Cu&#8211;ZnO provides valuable insights and guidance for the construction and modification of catalysts, enhancement of 1,4-butanediol yield and purity, and optimization and improvement of the production process. It is hoped that this research can offer some suggestions and assistance for the improvement of the 1,4-butanediol and biodegradable plastics industry.</description>
      <author>Xinyue Guan, Yingzhe Yu, Minhua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Catalyzed Deoxygenative Disulfuration of Alcohols to Access Unsymmetrical Disulfides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00814</link>
      <description>X. Chen, Wang Shao, Guo&#8208;Jun Deng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394761010

                Given the abundance of alcohol feedstocks and the significance of disulfides, we herein report a nickel-catalyzed direct deoxygenative disulfuration of alcohols with trisulfide dioxides to access a wide range of disulfide molecules without the cumbersome decoration of coupling partners. The use of readily available dicyclohexylcarbodiimide to form transient isoureas provides the activation of the high bond dissociation energy of the C&#8211;O bond, which facilitates the straightforward conversion of nonderivatized alcohols to forge a C&#8211;SS bond. Notably, this method obviates a preactivation multistep procedure and provides a catalytic turnover under exogenous ligand and base-free conditions, featuring a broad substrate scope and functional group compatibility. It thus offers a robust alternative to existing methods for the precise construction of versatile disulfide compounds from more abundant and commercially available substrates. The synthetic utility of the method was further showcased by successful gram-scale experiments and disulfuration of structurally complex pharmaceuticals.</description>
      <author>X. Chen, Wang Shao, Guo&#8208;Jun Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Machine Learning-Assisted Design Protocol for Protein Engineering: Transaminase Engineering for the Conversion of Bulky Substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00987</link>
      <description>Marian J. Menke, Yu&#8208;Fei Ao, Uwe T. Bornscheuer, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394766668

                Protein engineering is essential for improving the catalytic performance of enzymes for applications in biocatalysis, in which machine learning provides an emerging approach for variant design. Transaminases are powerful biocatalysts for the stereoselective synthesis of chiral amines but one major challenge is their limited substrate scope. We present a general and practical variant design protocol for protein engineering to combine the advantages of three strategies, including directed evolution, rational design, and machine learning, and demonstrate the application of the protocol in the protein engineering of transaminases with higher activity toward bulky substrates. A high-quality data set was obtained by rational design of selected key positions, which was then applied to create a machine learning model for transaminase activity. This model was applied for the data-assisted design of optimized variants, which showed improved activity (up to 3-fold over parent) for three bulky substrates, maintaining enantioselectivity of the starting enzyme scaffold as well as improving the enantiomeric excess (up to &gt;99%ee).</description>
      <author>Marian J. Menke, Yu&#8208;Fei Ao, Uwe T. Bornscheuer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00987</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Gas-Phase CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation by Multifunctional UiO-66 Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00266</link>
      <description>Celia M. Rueda-Navarro, Zahraa Abou Khalil, Arianna Melillo, Bel&#233;n Ferrer, Ra&#250;l Montero, Asier Longarte, Marco Daturi, Ignacio Vay&#225;, Mohamad El&#8208;Roz, Virginia Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Herme G. Baldov&#237;, Sergio Naval&#243;n, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394769808

                Solar-assisted CO2 conversion into fuels and chemical products involves a range of technologies aimed at driving industrial decarbonization methods. In this work, we report on the development of a series of multifunctional metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) based on nitro- or amino-functionalized UiO-66(M) (M: Zr or Zr/Ti) supported RuOx NPs as photocatalysts, having different energy band level diagrams, for CO2 hydrogenation under simulated concentrated sunlight irradiation. RuOx(1 wt %; 2.2 &#177; 0.9 nm)@UiO-66(Zr/Ti)-NO2 was found to be a reusable photocatalyst, to be selective for CO2 methanation (5.03 mmol g&#8211;1 after 22 h;, apparent quantum yield at 350, 400, and 600 nm of 1.67, 0.25, and 0.01%, respectively), and to show about 3&#8211;6 times activity compared with previous investigations. The photocatalysts were characterized by advanced spectroscopic techniques like femto- and nanosecond transient absorption, spin electron resonance, and photoluminescence spectroscopies together with (photo)electrochemical measurements. The photocatalytic CO2 methanation mechanism was assessed by operando FTIR spectroscopy. The results indicate that the most active photocatalyst operates under a dual photochemical and photothermal mechanism. This investigation shows the potential of multifunctional MOFs as photocatalysts for solar-driven CO2 recycling.</description>
      <author>Celia M. Rueda-Navarro, Zahraa Abou Khalil, Arianna Melillo, Bel&#233;n Ferrer, Ra&#250;l Montero, Asier Longarte, Marco Daturi, Ignacio Vay&#225;, Mohamad El&#8208;Roz, Virginia Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Herme G. Baldov&#237;, Sergio Naval&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of Sulfamoyl Radical for the Modular Synthesis of Sulfonamides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01560</link>
      <description>Haiping Lv, Xinzhou Chen, Xuemei Zhang, Steven L. Kramer, Zhong Lian, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394783336

                Efficient synthesis of sulfonamides has long been pursued by chemists due to their frequent occurrence in pharmaceuticals, especially in anti-inflammatory medicines. The traditional assembly from sulfonyl chlorides and amines, as well as the recently developed one-step synthesis of sulfonamides involving sulfur dioxide, still faces challenges such as poor substrate compatibility and/or stringent reaction conditions. Herein, we present a strategy for the in situ generation of sulfamoyl radicals for the one-step modular synthesis of both alkenyl and alkyl sulfonamides with wide substrate applicability (&gt;100 examples), mild reaction conditions, and easily accessible starting materials. This method is successfully applied to the late-stage modification of drug molecules (23 examples), the one-step synthesis of the drug molecule naratriptan, and the 15N-labeling of sulfonamides.</description>
      <author>Haiping Lv, Xinzhou Chen, Xuemei Zhang, Steven L. Kramer, Zhong Lian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Operation of Paired CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction/Glycerol Oxidation at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05952</link>
      <description>Attila Korm&#225;nyos, Adrienn Szirmai, Bal&#225;zs Endr&#337;di, Csaba Jan&#225;ky, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394786891

                Despite the considerable efforts made by the community, the high operation cell voltage of CO2 electrolyzers is still to be decreased to move toward commercialization. This is mostly due to the high energy need of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is the most often used anodic pair for CO2 reduction. In this study, OER was replaced by the electrocatalytic oxidation of glycerol using carbon-supported Pt nanoparticles as an anode catalyst. In parallel, the reduction of CO2 to CO was performed at the Ag cathode catalyst using a membraneless microfluidic flow electrolyzer cell. Several parameters were optimized, starting from the catalyst layer composition (ionomer quality and quantity), through operating conditions (glycerol concentration, applied electrolyte flow rate, etc.), to the applied electrochemical protocol. By identifying the optimal conditions, a 75&#8211;85% Faradaic efficiency (FE) toward glycerol oxidation products (oxalate, glycerate, tartronate, lactate, glycolate, and formate) was achieved at 200 mA cm&#8211;2 total current density while the cathodic CO formation proceeded with close to 100% FE. With static protocols (potentio- or galvanostatic), a rapid loss of glycerol oxidation activity was observed during the long-term measurements. The anode catalyst was reactivated by applying a dynamic potential step protocol. This allowed the periodic reduction, hence, refreshing of Pt, ensuring stable, continuous operation for 5 h.</description>
      <author>Attila Korm&#225;nyos, Adrienn Szirmai, Bal&#225;zs Endr&#337;di, Csaba Jan&#225;ky</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Peroxide as an Ideal Electron Donor for Long-Lasting Fenton Chemistry: Strong Enhancement of Fe(III) Activity by Heteroatom-Doped Nanocarbons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00048</link>
      <description>Yiming Sun, Peng Zhou, Minglu Sun, Yuchen Zhang, Xiao Wang, Chenying Zhou, Yang Liu, Chuan-Shu He, Bo Lai, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394797401

                Heteroatom doping has been demonstrated to be an effective strategy to improve the catalytic activity of carbon materials. Herein, heteroatom-doped nanocarbons were found to be environmental protection cocatalysts for promoting Fenton oxidation. Nitrogen-doped reduced graphene oxide (N-rGO) exhibited better catalytic activity than sulfur-, boron-, and phosphorus-doped rGO for enhancing Fenton oxidation. Unlike classical electron sacrificial agents, H2O2 was employed as an electron donor to enhance Fenton oxidation during the catalysis of N-rGO. Electrochemical analysis and nitrogen molecular model tests indicated the oxidation potential of Fe(III) increased with improvement in the N atom content (R2 = 0.97), revealing that the Fe atoms of FeOH2+ on the N-rGO surface are more likely to abstract electrons from H2O2. In addition, the delocalized &#960; electron is one of the active sites in N-rGO-boosted Fenton oxidation, and N-rGO could facilitate electron transfer from H2O2 to Fe(III) along the C&#8211;C/C&#9552;C structures due to the improvement of the conductivity ability and the oxidation potential of Fe(III). Moreover, density functional theory (DFT) calculations suggest that the pyrrole N species of N-rGO is the best catalytic activity site, resulting from the pyrrole N species with higher adsorption energy stretching the Fe&#8211;O bond of FeOH2+ to increase the activity of Fe(III) species. Therefore, the study findings provide insight into designing stable and efficient metal-free catalysts to enhance Fe(III) reactivity in overcoming the inherent drawbacks of the Fenton system.</description>
      <author>Yiming Sun, Peng Zhou, Minglu Sun, Yuchen Zhang, Xiao Wang, Chenying Zhou, Yang Liu, Chuan-Shu He, Bo Lai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Functional Analysis of Heparosan Synthase 2 from &lt;i&gt;Pasteurella multocida&lt;/i&gt; to Improve the Synthesis of Heparin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00677</link>
      <description>Eduardo Stancanelli, J.M. Krahn, Elizabeth Viverette, Robert Dutcher, Vijayakanth Pagadala, Mario J. Borgnia, Jian Liu, Lars C. Pedersen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394800995

                Heparin is a widely used drug to treat thrombotic disorders in hospitals. Heparosan synthase 2 from Pasteurella multocida (PmHS2) is a key enzyme used for the chemoenzymatic synthesis of heparin oligosaccharides. It has both activities: glucosaminyl transferase activity and glucuronyl transferase activity; however, the mechanism to carry out the glyco-oligomerization is unknown. Here, we report crystal structures of PmHS2 constructs with bound uridine diphosphate (UDP) and a cryo-EM structure of PmHS2 in complex with UDP and a heptasaccharide (NS 7-mer) substrate. Using a liquid chromatography&#8211;mass spectrometry analytical method, we discovered that the enzyme displays both a two-step concerted oligomerization mode and a distributive oligomerization mode depending on the nonreducing end of the starting oligosaccharide primer. Removal of seven amino acid residues from the C-terminus results in an enzymatically active monomer instead of a dimer and loses the concerted oligomerization mode of activity. In addition, the monomer construct can transfer N-acetyl glucosamine at a substrate concentration that is &#8764;7-fold higher than a wildtype enzyme. It was also determined that an F529A mutant can transfer an N-sulfoglucosamine (GlcNS) saccharide from a previously inactive UDP-GlcNS donor. Performing the glyco-transfer reaction at a high substrate concentration and the capability of using unnatural donors are desirable to simplifying the chemoenzymatic synthesis to prepare heparin-based therapeutics.</description>
      <author>Eduardo Stancanelli, J.M. Krahn, Elizabeth Viverette, Robert Dutcher, Vijayakanth Pagadala, Mario J. Borgnia, Jian Liu, Lars C. Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Dinitrogen Reduction to Silylamines by Molybdenum Nitride Complexes Bearing a Diphenolate N-Heterocyclic Carbene Ligand</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00307</link>
      <description>Zhaoxin Li, Chenrui Liu, Jing An, Xi Wu, Shaowei Hu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394804794

                Despite substantial strides in the catalytic silylation of N2 employing phosphine-ligated transition metal complexes, further development has been impeded by the low reaction yields (based on reducing or silylating reagents). Here we present a series of Mo(VI) nitride complexes featuring a robust tridentate diphenolate N-heterocyclic carbene (OCO) ligand that serves as efficient catalysts for the reduction of N2 to silylamines, producing 57.3 equiv of tris(trimethylsilyl)amine with a yield of as high as 86%. Reductive silylation of Mo nitride complexes resulted in the isolation of a molybdenum silylimide intermediate. Our findings showed that the enhanced efficiency of the system could be ascribed to the high activity of catalysts and the suppression of side reactions, indicating that the OCO ligand plays a crucial role in stabilizing the Mo center across in high- and low-oxidation states in catalysis.</description>
      <author>Zhaoxin Li, Chenrui Liu, Jing An, Xi Wu, Shaowei Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palladium-Catalyzed Annulations via Sequential C&#8211;H Activations of C(sp&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H/C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H or C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H/C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Bonds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01243</link>
      <description>Wan&#8208;Xu Wei, Mateusz Czajkowski, Yangjin Kuang, Tu-Anh V. Nguyen, Bo Qin, Martin Tomanik, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394809512

                Palladium-catalyzed C&#8211;H annulation reactions represent a compelling strategy to construct complex ring systems with high step economy. While there are many approaches to annulate structures by activation of a single C&#8211;H bond, transformations that proceed by activation of multiple C&#8211;H bonds are less explored. This is especially true for examples where one of the reacting C&#8211;H bonds is located at an sp3 center. However, exciting developments in palladium-catalyzed C&#8211;H activation continue to expand the scope of these transformations and provide innovative strategies to construct challenging carbon&#8211;carbon bonds. From these discoveries, sequential C&#8211;H activations have emerged as a powerful tool to access complex ring systems through the activation of C(sp2)&#8211;H/C(sp3)&#8211;H or C(sp3)&#8211;H/C(sp3)&#8211;H bonds. In this Perspective, we showcase recent examples that use this strategy in order to highlight the synthetic potential of C&#8211;H activation-enabled annulations and inspire future use of these disconnections for diverse scaffold synthesis.</description>
      <author>Wan&#8208;Xu Wei, Mateusz Czajkowski, Yangjin Kuang, Tu-Anh V. Nguyen, Bo Qin, Martin Tomanik</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-Selective Bimetallic Heterogeneous Nanostructures for Plasmon-Enhanced Photocatalysis of Nitrobenzene Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00024</link>
      <description>Yaqin Wang, Jinjin Zheng, Qi Liu, Yuqiang Shi, Huijie Liu, Zheng Huang, Jun Yi, Ye Yang, Qin Kuang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394821192

                Nitrobenzene hydrogenation, a critical pathway for synthesizing aniline, typically requires a high temperature and pressurized hydrogen for effective and selective reduction. It is of great significance to find a catalyst with a favorable reaction rate toward the selective hydrogenation of nitroaromatics. Herein, anisotropic Au&#8211;Pd tipped NPs were specially synthesized and found to exhibit efficient plasmon-enhanced hydrogenation of nitrobenzene to aniline. Under light, Au&#8211;Pd tipped NPs exhibited a TOF of 166 h&#8211;1 with high selectivity (&gt;92%). Simulation results demonstrated that site-selective bimetallic heterogeneous nanostructures maintain a strong electromagnetic field, which further promotes the generation and transfer of energetic hot electrons for photocatalysis. Meanwhile, in situ X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and quasi-in situ electron paramagnetic resonance revealed that the movement of hot electrons facilitates the enhanced participation of hot holes in the oxidation of the hydrogen donor. Our findings underscore that the rational design of bimetallic structures not only exposes rich active sites for incoming reactants but also prolongs the lifetime of hot carriers for efficient transfer and injection.</description>
      <author>Yaqin Wang, Jinjin Zheng, Qi Liu, Yuqiang Shi, Huijie Liu, Zheng Huang, Jun Yi, Ye Yang, Qin Kuang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen, Sulfur Co-doped Hollow Carbon-Encapsulated Cu/Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P for Selective Oxidation Esterification of Furfurals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01035</link>
      <description>Yuanji Dong, Xianhai Zeng, Xiongxiong Zuo, Jiaran Li, Yu Jia, Ge Zhang, Junhua Kuang, I&#351;&#305;l Akp&#305;nar, Peng Li, Xing Tang, Jin&#8208;Chao Dong, Lin Liu, Pengbo Lyu, Shuliang Yang, Jian&#8208;Feng Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394822901

                With the remarkable capability of encapsulating multifunctional active sites inside, carbon-based materials play vital roles in multifarious chemical transformations such as hydrogenation reactions, oxidation reactions, esterification reactions, etc. Herein, we propose an efficient and facile approach to construct a Cu/Co2P@C-NS catalyst, which consists of nitrogen&#8211;sulfur co-doped carbon (C-NS) encapsulated cobalt phosphide (Co2P) and copper double active sites. This approach focuses on the design and preparation of core&#8211;shell materials, that is, the ZIF-67 core is coated with an adhesive poly(cyclotriphosphazene-co-4,4&#8242;-sulfonyldiphenol) (PZS) polymer shell. The ZIF-67 core possesses a highly porous structure, coexistence of carbon and nitrogen elements, and uniform dispersion of Co species, making it an ideal template. The heteroatomic PZS polymer with decent coating ability makes it a promising coating material for creating core&#8211;shell structures. Additionally, nitrogen species in the PZS polymer could coordinate with Cu2+ to introduce extra Cu sites into the system. The Cu/Co2P@C-NS catalyst prepared from the pyrolysis of the precursor redistributes the surface charge of Co2P by additionally incorporating Cu, which effectively enhances substrate adsorption. As a result, the Cu/Co2P@C-NS catalyst demonstrates good catalytic performance in the oxidative esterification of furfuryl aldehydes. This study presents a reliable and straightforward method for preparing a non-noble-metal catalyst that exhibits high efficiency and activity in the one-pot oxidation and esterification of furfurals to methyl furoates.</description>
      <author>Yuanji Dong, Xianhai Zeng, Xiongxiong Zuo, Jiaran Li, Yu Jia, Ge Zhang, Junhua Kuang, I&#351;&#305;l Akp&#305;nar, Peng Li, Xing Tang, Jin&#8208;Chao Dong, Lin Liu, Pengbo Lyu, Shuliang Yang, Jian&#8208;Feng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arginine Kinase Activates Arginine for Phosphorylation by Pyramidalization and Polarization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00380</link>
      <description>Fabio Falcioni, Robert W. Molt, Yi Jin, Jonathan P. Waltho, Sam Hay, Nigel G. J. Richards, G. Michael Blackburn, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394834991

                Arginine phosphorylation plays numerous roles throughout biology. Arginine kinase (AK) catalyzes the delivery of an anionic phosphoryl group (PO3&#8211;) from ATP to a planar, trigonal nitrogen in a guanidinium cation. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations have yielded a model of the transition state (TS) for the AK-catalyzed reaction. They reveal a network of over 50 hydrogen bonds that delivers unprecedented pyramidalization and out-of-plane polarization of the arginine guanidinium nitrogen (N&#951;2) and aligns the electron density on N&#951;2 with the scissile P&#8211;O bond, leading to in-line phosphoryl transfer via an associative mechanism. In the reverse reaction, the hydrogen-bonding network enforces the conformational distortion of a bound phosphoarginine substrate to increase the basicity of N&#951;2. This enables N&#951;2 protonation, which triggers PO3&#8211; migration to generate ATP. This polarization&#8211;pyramidalization of nitrogen in the arginine side chain is likely a general phenomenon that is exploited by many classes of enzymes mediating the post-translational modification of arginine.</description>
      <author>Fabio Falcioni, Robert W. Molt, Yi Jin, Jonathan P. Waltho, Sam Hay, Nigel G. J. Richards, G. Michael Blackburn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Diazo Compounds via Catalytic [3 + 2] Annulation of Vinyldiazoacetates and Their Synthetic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01291</link>
      <description>Ming Bao, Diana Victoria Navarrete Carriola, Daniel J. Wherritt, Michael P. Doyle, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394835029

                Highly selective formal [3 + 2]-cycloaddition of vinyldiazoacetates with quinone ketals and quinoneimine ketals has been accomplished at room temperature with catalytic amounts of the Br&#248;nsted acid triflimide, leading to highly functionalized diazoacetates in good yields. The vinyldiazonium ion generated by electrophilic addition to the vinylogous position of the reactant vinyldiazo compound is the key intermediate in this selective transformation. Both oximidovinyldiazoacetates and those with other vinyl substituents undergo cycloaddition reactions with quinone ketals whose products, after extended reaction times, undergo substrate-dependent 1,2-migration; catalysis by Rh2(OAc)4, HNTf2, and Sc(OTf)3 effects these 1,2-migrations to the same products. However, the products from HNTf2-catalyzed reactions between quinoneimine and oximidovinyldiazoacetates undergo Rh2(OAc)4-catalyzed 1,3-C&#8211;H insertion. 1,3-Difunctionalization products are obtained for electrophilic reactions of Eschenmoser's salt with selected vinyldiazoacetates, but with &#945;-dibenzylaminomethyl ether, 1,6-hydride transfer reactions are observed with oximidovinyldiazoacetates.</description>
      <author>Ming Bao, Diana Victoria Navarrete Carriola, Daniel J. Wherritt, Michael P. Doyle</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steric Effects on the Oxygen Reduction Reaction with Cobalt Porphyrin Atropisomers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01295</link>
      <description>Chang-Jiu Li, Haonan Qin, Yiping Xu, Xinyang Peng, Wei Zhang, Rui Cao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394835036

                The steric effects on the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) have been rarely studied because O2 is small in size and ORR catalysts with the only difference in steric hindrance are difficult to be designed and synthesized. Herein, we report on homogeneous ORR catalyzed by four Co porphyrin atropisomers in tetrahydrofuran with decamethylferrocene and HClO4 at 298 K. All four atropisomers are active and selective for the 2H+/2e&#8211; ORR with an activity order &#945;&#945;&#945;&#945; &gt; &#945;&#945;&#945;&#946; &gt; &#945;&#945;&#946;&#946; &gt; &#945;&#946;&#945;&#946;. Kinetic studies revealed that the four atropisomers have the same ORR mechanism with proton-coupled O2 binding as the rate-determining step.</description>
      <author>Chang-Jiu Li, Haonan Qin, Yiping Xu, Xinyang Peng, Wei Zhang, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CsPbBr&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Perovskite Polyhedral Nanocrystal Photocatalysts for Decarboxylative Alkylation via C&lt;sub&gt;sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;H Bond Activation of Unactivated Ethers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01643</link>
      <description>Soumya Mondal, Souvik Banerjee, Suman Bera, Subal Mondal, Siba P. Midya, Rajkumar Jana, Rakesh Kumar Behera, Ayan Datta, Narayan Pradhan, Pradyut Ghosh, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394835419

                Halide perovskite nanocrystals have recently emerged as high-performance light-harvesting materials. They are also extensively studied for the fabrication of both light-emitting and photovoltaic devices. In comparison, their implementation as photocatalysts to trigger different organic reactions is limited. To add more diversity in catalysis, herein, different shapes and heterostructures of CsPbBr3 perovskite polyhedral nanocrystals are explored for visible-light-mediated room temperature photocatalytic Csp3&#8211;H bond-activated alkylation of cyclic ether using feedstock &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated acids as the keto-alkyl source. It started with the decarboxylative coupling of cinnamic acid at the &#945;-position of tetrahydrofuran (THF) and extended to several derivatives. The facets of nanocrystals matter, and hence, differently shaped nanocrystals showed variable rates of catalytic activities. With density functional theory calculation, the surface-adsorption-induced charge carrier transfer mechanism to facilitate such reactions is established. Different semiconductors and noble metal heterostructures that quenched the emission are also compared, and their inactiveness in catalysis was also correlated to the proposed mechanism. Combining all these observations, the roles of light, catalytic surfaces, oxygen, the nature of hosts, and coupling with other material heterostructures are analyzed in detail and reported. Such reactions with Csp3&#8211;H bond activation can lead to complex chemical scaffolds, unveiling an underexplored domain of heterogeneous photocatalytic organic reactions for Csp3&#8211;Csp3 cross-coupling.</description>
      <author>Soumya Mondal, Souvik Banerjee, Suman Bera, Subal Mondal, Siba P. Midya, Rajkumar Jana, Rakesh Kumar Behera, Ayan Datta, Narayan Pradhan, Pradyut Ghosh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of Axially Chiral Diaryl Ethers through Chiral Phosphoric Acid-Catalyzed Desymmetric Acylation with Azlactones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01489</link>
      <description>Jiawei Xu, Wei Lin, Hanliang Zheng, Xin Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394836288

                C&#8211;O axially chiral diaryl ethers play important roles in natural products and bioactive molecules, but because of the low rotational barrier and strict steric hindrance requirements, the catalytic asymmetric construction of axially chiral diaryl ethers still remains a challenge. Herein, we devised a strategy employing achiral azlactone for the desymmetrization of prochiral diamines under the catalysis of chiral phosphoric acid. The targeted C&#8211;O axially chiral diaryl ethers were obtained in very good yields (up to 98%) and high enantioselectivities (up to &gt;99.5:0.5 er). The synthetic utility was demonstrated through large-scale reaction and transformations of the products. Moreover, DFT calculations were conducted to probe the origins of enantioselectivity.</description>
      <author>Jiawei Xu, Wei Lin, Hanliang Zheng, Xin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Consequences of Protons in Methanol Oxidative Dehydrogenation on Molybdenum-Based Polyoxometalate Clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00440</link>
      <description>Gui&#8208;Xin Cai, Ya-Huei Cathy Chin, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394837492

                This study unravels the catalytic effects of adjacent protons in redox catalysis of bifunctional Keggin-type phosphomolybdic acid clusters (H3PMo12O40). Isolated redox sites (O*) and Br&#248;nsted acid-redox site pairs (OH/O*) catalyze methanol oxidative dehydrogenation (ODH), a redox reaction, via the identical elementary steps and the formation of the kinetically relevant [HOCH2&#183;&#183;&#183;H&#183;&#183;&#183;O*]&#8225; and [OH&#183;&#183;&#183;HOCH2&#183;&#183;&#183;H&#183;&#183;&#183;O*]&#8225; transition states, but with different kinetic requirements, established from selective site inactivation, product tracking, dynamic pyridine/2,6-di-tert-butylpyridine titrations, and kinetic assessments. The presence of adjacent protons interacts with and stabilizes the methanol precursor in the OH&#183;&#183;&#183;HOCH2&#8211;H&#183;&#183;&#183;O* adsorbed state through additional H-bonding interactions by 57 kJ mol&#8211;1 in adsorption enthalpy and by 144 J mol&#8211;1 K&#8211;1 in adsorption entropy. These additional interactions, stabilizing the [OH&#183;&#183;&#183;HOCH2&#183;&#183;&#183;H&#183;&#183;&#183;O*]&#8225; transition state, lead to a decrease in apparent methanol activation enthalpy of 50 kJ mol&#8211;1 and in activation entropy of 97 J mol&#8211;1 K&#8211;1, resulting in an overall increase in methanol ODH turnovers. The kinetic consequences of protons established here enable the rationalization of the redox reactivity on bifunctional POM clusters and display a nontraditional confinement effect to stabilize transition state energies.</description>
      <author>Gui&#8208;Xin Cai, Ya-Huei Cathy Chin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Regeneration of Reactive Cofactors with InP Quantum Dots for the Continuous Chemical Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00817</link>
      <description>I. N. Chakraborty, Vanshika Jain, Pradyut Roy, Pawan Kumar, C. P. Vinod, Pramod P. Pillai, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394839944

                The shuttling of redox-active nicotinamide cofactors between the light and dark cycles is the key to the continuous production of biomass in photosynthesis. The replication of such processes in artificial photosynthetic systems demands fast photoregeneration as well as simultaneous integration of these nicotinamide cofactors into the dark cycle. Here, we report the design of an artificial photosynthetic system for the continuous production of butanol via the constant photoregeneration and consumption of nicotinamide cofactors, powered by an indium phosphide quantum dot (InP QD) photocatalyst and alcohol dehydrogenase (ADH) enzyme, respectively. A strong electrostatic attraction between the oppositely charged InP QDs and electron mediators significantly enhanced the charge extraction and utilization processes, enabling a fast (&#8764;30 min, with a turn over frequency of &#8764;1333 h&#8211;1), quantitative (&gt;99%), and selective photoregeneration of enzymatically active nicotinamide cofactors in the light cycle. These photoregenerated nicotinamide cofactors were further coupled in the dark cycle to trigger the ADH oxidoreductase enzyme for the production of butanol, via sequential as well as simultaneous light&#8211;dark cycles. The amount of butanol produced under simultaneous light&#8211;dark cycles was higher than the stoichiometric limit, proving the constant regeneration and consumption of nicotinamide cofactors in light and dark cycles, respectively. Thus, a proper design and integration of the InP QD-based photocatalytic cycle with the enzymatic cycle led to the effective electron shuttling between light and dark cycles, as seen in photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>I. N. Chakraborty, Vanshika Jain, Pradyut Roy, Pawan Kumar, C. P. Vinod, Pramod P. Pillai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00817</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Organoboron/Palladium Cocatalyzed Dehydrative Couplings of Azoles with Allylic Alcohols: A Combined Experimental and Computational Mechanistic Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01010</link>
      <description>Matthew T. Zambri, Teh Ren Hou, Sofia Jdanova, Mark S. Taylor, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394840719

                In the presence of Pd(Xantphos) and an electron-deficient arylboronic acid cocatalyst, azoles such as pyrazoles, triazoles, tetrazoles, and purines undergo regioselective, dehydrative allylations with allylic alcohols. The boronic acid has a significant effect on both the rate and the regioselectivity of these reactions. Herein, a combined experimental and computational mechanistic study of the synergistic organoboron- and palladium-catalyzed allylation of azoles is described. Kinetic analysis and an evaluation of the effects of arylboronic acid substitution on the reaction rate point toward turnover-limiting ionization of the allylic alcohol, with Lewis acid activation by the boronic acid. Computational modeling of the reaction pathway with density functional theory indicates that allylic alcohol ionization is also the regioselectivity-determining step and that the resulting ion pair undergoes C&#8211;N bond formation through an outer-sphere mechanism. An unexpected observation of autocatalysis that emerged from the kinetic analysis motivated a study of the effects of additives, leading to the development of an improved protocol.</description>
      <author>Matthew T. Zambri, Teh Ren Hou, Sofia Jdanova, Mark S. Taylor</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoenzymatic Redox-Neutral Radical Hydrosulfonylation Initiated by FMN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00350</link>
      <description>Linye Jiang, Dannan Zheng, Xiaoyang Chen, Dong Cui, Xinyu Duan, Zhiguo Wang, Jingyan Ge, Jian Xu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394840950

                The photoinduced unnatural reactions catalyzed by flavin-dependent enzymes usually proceed through reduction pathways, which required the use of electron-sacrificial reagents. Herein, we developed a photoenzymatic redox-neutral radical hydrosulfonylation induced by oxidated flavin (FMN) with sulfinates or sulfonyl hydrazines as radical precursors. The reaction involved the excited FMN acquiring an electron from the substrate, and the resulting sulfuryl radical was captured by an alkene. It is then stereoselectively quenched by flavin semiquinone (FMNsq) through hydrogen atom transfer. This study circumvents the need for NADPH recycling systems and expands the potential reaction patterns in photobiocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Linye Jiang, Dannan Zheng, Xiaoyang Chen, Dong Cui, Xinyu Duan, Zhiguo Wang, Jingyan Ge, Jian Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Photoenolization/Diels&#8211;Alder Reaction of 2-Methylbenzaldehydes and 2-Alkylbenzophenones with Chromones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01264</link>
      <description>Yuhao Mo, Lichao Ning, Zhe Liu, Liangkun Yang, Ting Shi, Shujuan Dong, Qi&#8208;Lin Zhou, Xiaoming Feng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394843038

                The asymmetric photoenolization/Diels&#8211;Alder reaction provides a straightforward and atom-economical route to complex chiral polycyclic rings. In comparison with well-developed transformations of 2-alkylbenzophenones, the enantioselective photoenolization/Diels&#8211;Alder reaction of 2-methylbenzaldehydes was challenging due to the shorter-lived and unstable photoenol intermediates. Herein, we present a highly enantioselective photoenolization/Diels&#8211;Alder reaction of 2-methylbenzaldehydes with chromones. Chiral N,N&#8242;-dioxide/ScIII and YbIII complexes were found to interact with both photoenol intermediates and chromones simultaneously, accelerating the Diels&#8211;Alder reaction in an efficient and stereoselective manner. Experimental studies and DFT calculations were carried out to understand the reaction mechanism and the origin of stereoselectivity. In addition, 2-alkylbenzophenones were suitable substrates. A series of chiral fused polycyclic rings with vicinal multisubstituted stereocenters were afforded in good yields and high diastereo- and enantioselectivities.</description>
      <author>Yuhao Mo, Lichao Ning, Zhe Liu, Liangkun Yang, Ting Shi, Shujuan Dong, Qi&#8208;Lin Zhou, Xiaoming Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensitized and Self-Sensitized Photocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to HCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; and CO under Visible Light with Ni(II) CNC-Pincer Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03787</link>
      <description>Sonya Y. Manafe, Nghia Le, Ethan C. Lambert, Christine Curiac, Dinesh Nugegoda, Sanjit Das, Leigh Anna Hunt, Fengrui Qu, Logan M. Whitt, Igor Fedin, Nathan I. Hammer, Charles Edwin Webster, Jared H. Delcamp, Elizabeth T. Papish, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394843717

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sonya Y. Manafe, Nghia Le, Ethan C. Lambert, Christine Curiac, Dinesh Nugegoda, Sanjit Das, Leigh Anna Hunt, Fengrui Qu, Logan M. Whitt, Igor Fedin, Nathan I. Hammer, Charles Edwin Webster, Jared H. Delcamp, Elizabeth T. Papish</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Cu&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Species and Zr Single Atoms for Synergetic Catalytic Transfer Hydrodeoxygenation of 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00763</link>
      <description>Lincai Peng, Yi Yu, Shenghan Gao, Miaomiao Wang, Junhua Zhang, Rui Zhang, Wenlong Jia, Yong Sun, Huai Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394854514

                The formation and stabilization of Cu+ species are important to develop efficient Cu-based catalysts for the catalytic transfer hydrodeoxygenation (CTHDO) of renewable biomass to value-added products but challenging. Herein, we demonstrate that the introduction of atomically dispersed Zr species into a CuOx matrix (Cu10Zr0.39Ox) greatly promoted its catalytic activity and stability for the CTHDO of 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) into 2,5-dimethylfuran (DMF). In particular, almost quantitative DMF yield could be implemented over Cu10Zr0.39Ox accompanied by an impressive DMF formation rate of 8.1 mmolDMF&#183;gcat&#8211;1&#183;h&#8211;1, which outperforms the existing works for the CTHDO of HMF to DMF. Experimental and theoretical observations revealed that the electronic interactions between the doped Zr atom species and CuOx enabled the generation of ample and stable Cu+ species. The single-atom Zr species also promoted the adsorption and activation of the substrates and worked synergistically with Cu+ species to boost the CTHDO of HMF by reducing the reaction energy barriers.</description>
      <author>Lincai Peng, Yi Yu, Shenghan Gao, Miaomiao Wang, Junhua Zhang, Rui Zhang, Wenlong Jia, Yong Sun, Huai Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halide Perovskites for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction: Challenges and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06040</link>
      <description>Krzysztof Bie&#324;kowski, Renata Solarska, Linh Trinh, Justyna Widera-Kalinowska, Basheer Al&#8208;Anesi, Maning Liu, G. Krishnamurthy Grandhi, Paola Vivo, Burcu Oral, Beyza Y&#305;lmaz, Ramazan Y&#305;ld&#305;r&#305;m, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394854758

                Photoelectrochemical water splitting and CO2 reduction provide an attractive route to produce solar fuels while reducing the level of CO2 emissions. Metal halide perovskites (MHPs) have been extensively studied for this purpose in recent years due to their suitable optoelectronic properties. In this review, we survey the recent achievements in the field. After a brief introduction to photoelectrochemical (PEC) processes, we discussed the properties, synthesis, and application of MHPs in this context. We also survey the state-of-the-art findings regarding significant achievements in performance, and developments in addressing the major challenges of toxicity and instability toward water. Efforts have been made to replace the toxic Pb with less toxic materials like Sn, Ge, Sb, and Bi. The stability toward water has been also improved by using various methods such as compositional engineering, 2D/3D perovskite structures, surface passivation, the use of protective layers, and encapsulation. In the last part, considering the experience gained in photovoltaic applications, we provided our perspective for the future challenges and opportunities. We place special emphasis on the improvement of stability as the major challenge and the potential contribution of machine learning to identify the most suitable formulation for halide perovskites with desired properties.</description>
      <author>Krzysztof Bie&#324;kowski, Renata Solarska, Linh Trinh, Justyna Widera-Kalinowska, Basheer Al&#8208;Anesi, Maning Liu, G. Krishnamurthy Grandhi, Paola Vivo, Burcu Oral, Beyza Y&#305;lmaz, Ramazan Y&#305;ld&#305;r&#305;m</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Waste Plastic Upgrading and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoreduction to High-Value Chemicals by a Binuclear Re&#8211;Ru Heterogeneous Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00444</link>
      <description>Mei Li, Shengbo Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394857095

                Photocatalytically converting waste plastic to high-value chemicals is an energy-efficient and promising approach. Nonetheless, the limited photocatalytic efficiency due to the extremely low water solubility of the plastic and the excessive release of CO2 caused by overoxidation during the reaction seriously restricts its practical application. Herein, we propose a tandem process of waste Poly(ethylene terephthalate) (PET) plastic degradation and CO2 photoreduction on a chelating-ligand-anchored binuclear Re&#8211;Ru molecular heterogeneous catalyst. Specifically, waste PET plastics are depolymerized and photo-oxidized to monomers and formic acid on the molecular Ru sites, while the CO2 gas externally purged and generated in situ is photoreduced to CO with an impressive TON of 115 on the molecular Re sites. Compared with the corresponding homogeneous catalyst, the product selectivity is significantly improved from 65 to 95% in water-containing systems, and the TON is also greatly increased by nearly 19 times. Experiments and density functional theory calculations reveal that the high photocatalytic performance is attributed to the significantly enhanced light-capture capability, efficient photogenerated electron transfer between bimetallic Re&#8211;Ru sites, and substantially enhanced CO2-trapping capacity by finely regulating the chelating-ligand-based organosilica nanotube framework structure. The real-world application in nature seawater indicates that this work will provide a practical and feasible technical route for the disposal of waste plastics and mitigating carbon emissions under environmental conditions.</description>
      <author>Mei Li, Shengbo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Role of CO Coverage for Chain Growth in Co-Based Fischer&#8211;Tropsch Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04844</link>
      <description>Konstantijn Tom Rommens, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Mark Saeys, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394857187

                Fischer&#8211;Tropsch synthesis converts CO and H2 to long-chain hydrocarbons. The reaction mechanism, a combination of C&#8211;O scission, C&#8211;C coupling, and hydrogenation steps, and the nature of the active sites remain intensely debated. In this work, we report a comprehensive, dual-site microkinetic model including more than 600 reversible reactions. Our model explicitly accounts for the high CO surface coverage under the reaction conditions by including a CO saturation coverage in the underlying DFT calculations. The model predictions match experimental kinetic observations with a methane selectivity of 18%, a chain growth probability of 0.83, a turnover frequency of 0.084 s&#8211;1, and an activation energy of 107 kJ/mol. A degree of rate control analysis identifies 12 rate-controlling steps, highlighting the challenges in building compact kinetic models based on one or two rate controlling steps. In the dominant reaction mechanism, CO is activated both at B5 step sites and at the terrace sites via H- and hydroxyl-assisted pathways. Chain growth occurs on the crowded terraces predominantly via CH coupling to alkylidine chains. While B5 step sites facilitate CO activation, a small concentration of 5% is sufficient to establish a quasi-equilibrium CH coverage on the terraces and higher concentrations do not notably change the model predictions.</description>
      <author>Konstantijn Tom Rommens, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Mark Saeys</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma Catalysis for Hydrogen Production: A Bright Future for Decarbonization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05434</link>
      <description>Ni Wang, Hope O. Otor, Gerardo Rivera-Castro, Jason C. Hicks, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394857812

                Thermal approaches have played a dominant role in driving chemical reactions within the chemicals and fuels industries, benefiting from ongoing enhancements in efficiency via heat integration, catalyst development, and process intensification. Nevertheless, these traditional thermal approaches remain heavily reliant on fossil fuels, and there exists an urgent demand for the implementation of renewable energy technologies to synthesize fuels, commodity chemicals, and specialty chemicals. Nonthermal plasmas have gained considerable attention in recent years as a promising solution, and the prospects of combining plasmas with suitable catalysts have become even more appealing. Moreover, the evolution of nonthermal plasma catalysis approaches for the generation of clean hydrogen could be transformative in reducing greenhouse gas emissions. This comprehensive review highlights the influential contributions in plasma catalysis for hydrogen production, discusses recent advancements, and provides future prospects for researchers aiming to advance the production of clean hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Ni Wang, Hope O. Otor, Gerardo Rivera-Castro, Jason C. Hicks</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05434</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water-Mediated Photocatalytic Coproduction of Diesel Fuel Additives and Hydrogen from Dimethyl Ether</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01132</link>
      <description>Shiyang Liu, Yike Huang, Nengchao Luo, Jian Zhang, Botao Qiao, Feng Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394869098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiyang Liu, Yike Huang, Nengchao Luo, Jian Zhang, Botao Qiao, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differentiating Plasmon-Enhanced Chemical Reactions on AgPd Hollow Nanoplates through Surface-Enhanced Raman Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06253</link>
      <description>Sulin Jiao, Kun Dai, Lucas V. Besteiro, Gao H, Chuang Xuan, Weichao Wang, Yuan Zhang, Chuntai Liu, Ignacio P&#233;rez&#8208;Juste, Jorge P&#233;rez&#8208;Juste, Isabel Pastoriza&#8208;Santos, Guangchao Zheng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394890917

                Plasmonic photocatalysis demonstrates great potential for efficiently harnessing light energy. However, the underlying mechanisms remain enigmatic due to the transient nature of the reaction processes. Typically, plasmonic photocatalysis relies on the excitation of surface plasmon resonance (SPR) in plasmonic materials, such as metal nanoparticles, leading to the generation of high-energy or "hot electrons", albeit accompanied by photothermal heating or Joule effect. The ability of hot electrons to participate in chemical reactions is one of the key mechanisms, underlying the enhanced photocatalytic activity observed in plasmonic photocatalysis. Interestingly, surface-enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) spectroscopy allows the analysis of chemical reactions driven by hot electrons, as both SERS and hot electrons stem from the decay of SPR and occur at the hot spots. Herein, we propose a highly efficient SERS substrate based on cellulose paper loaded with either Ag nanoplates (Ag NPs) or AgPd hollow nanoplates (AgPd HNPs) for the in situ monitoring of C&#8211;C homocoupling reactions. The data analysis allowed us to disentangle the impact of hot electrons and the Joule effect on plasmon-enhanced photocatalysis. Computational simulations revealed an increase in the rate of excitation of hot carriers from single/isolated AgPd HNPs to an in-plane with a vertical stacking assembly, suggesting its promise as a photocatalyst under broadband light. In addition, the results suggest that the incorporation of Pd into an alloy with plasmonic properties may enhance its catalytic performance under light irradiation due to the collection of plasmon-excitation-induced hot electrons. This work has demonstrated the performance-oriented synthesis of hybrid nanostructures, providing a unique route to uncover the mechanism of plasmon-enhanced photocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Sulin Jiao, Kun Dai, Lucas V. Besteiro, Gao H, Chuang Xuan, Weichao Wang, Yuan Zhang, Chuntai Liu, Ignacio P&#233;rez&#8208;Juste, Jorge P&#233;rez&#8208;Juste, Isabel Pastoriza&#8208;Santos, Guangchao Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06253</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
