<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:18:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the Adjacent Microenvironment of Atomically Dispersed FeN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Sites via Cross-Link-Induced 3D Carbon Nest for Efficient Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06546</link>
      <description>Tonghui Zhao, Guangjin Wang, Dongdong Xiao, Min Young Song, Yanmin Hu, Tingting Chao, Yapeng Li, Zedong Zhang, Yun Lu, Mingxing Gong, Tao Shen, Deli Wang, Huile Jin, Dingsheng Wang, Wei Chen, Yadong Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210421

                Electronic perturbation induced by the microenvironment regulation adjacent to the FeN4 sites anchored on metal&#8211;N&#8211;C materials will accelerate its oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) kinetics. Herein, we report a fine-tuning in the charge configuration of FeN4 sites through a defect-rich N/S-doped carbon nest derived from the chemically cross-linked pyrrole/thiophene copolymer (CCPPT) with a sp3-hybridized cross-linker. Compared with the pyrrole/thiophene copolymer (PPT) without the cross-linker, CCPPT with a knitted three-dimensional (3D) network delivers higher defect density and &#8764;2-fold sulfur retention after pyrolysis. The structural characterizations combined with theoretical calculations suggest that adjacent vacancy defects (Cvd) and FeN4/S2 moiety together induce the charge redistribution of the FeN4 sites on the resultant CC-Fe1/NSC from CCPPT, reducing the adsorption strength of the oxygen-containing intermediates and the energy barrier of ORR. As expected, CC-Fe1/NSC shows an impressive half-wave potential of &#8764;0.91 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE), surpassing both the PPT-derived Fe1/NSC (0.88 V) and the commercial Pt/C (0.86 V). This work provides a distinctive path to manipulate the adjacent microenvironment of the single-atom catalysts toward ORR or even beyond.</description>
      <author>Tonghui Zhao, Guangjin Wang, Dongdong Xiao, Min Young Song, Yanmin Hu, Tingting Chao, Yapeng Li, Zedong Zhang, Yun Lu, Mingxing Gong, Tao Shen, Deli Wang, Huile Jin, Dingsheng Wang, Wei Chen, Yadong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06546</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Catalytic Asymmetric Ketone Allylations and Their Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07194</link>
      <description>Lie Wang, Ruoshi Jin, Yiyuan Peng, Qiuping Ding, Xing&#8208;Ping Zeng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210431

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lie Wang, Ruoshi Jin, Yiyuan Peng, Qiuping Ding, Xing&#8208;Ping Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Br&#248;nsted Acid-Facilitated Thioetherification Cross-Coupling Reactions with Nickel and Visible Light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06734</link>
      <description>Maksim Nikitin, S&#225;ndor B. &#214;tv&#246;s, Indrajit Ghosh, Maximilian Philipp, Ruth M. Gschwind, C. Oliver Kappe, Burkhard Koenig, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210452

                Transition metal-catalyzed cross-coupling reactions are essential in modern organic synthesis, facilitating the rapid creation of complex molecular structures. Traditionally, these reactions rely heavily on conventional bases, with only a few exceptions reported. Recently, we developed adaptive dynamic homogeneous catalysis (AD-HoC), a method that enables C(sp2)&#8211;S cross-couplings without needing traditional ligands, bases, or additives. Given the growing demand for protocols compatible with acidic conditions in metal-catalyzed cross-couplings, we revisited AD-HoC to pioneer acid-facilitated transition metal-catalyzed thioetherification. Our method enables the swift synthesis of thioethers using nickel and visible light, with a substoichiometric amount of Br&#248;nsted acid acting as an enabler. NMR kinetic studies indicate that in the absence of acid, the system displays an induction period characteristic of autocatalysis. Introducing the acid as a simple additive eliminates this induction period and significantly accelerates the reaction. Moreover, the protocol has been successfully scaled to gram-level synthesis using continuous flow technology, achieving productivities of over 100 g per hour in a commercially available lab-scale photoreactor. This highlights the method's robustness and scalability, making it a powerful tool for large-scale applications.</description>
      <author>Maksim Nikitin, S&#225;ndor B. &#214;tv&#246;s, Indrajit Ghosh, Maximilian Philipp, Ruth M. Gschwind, C. Oliver Kappe, Burkhard Koenig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exceptionally Low-Coordinated Bismuth&#8211;Oxygen Vacancy Defect Clusters for Generating Black In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Photocatalysts with Superb CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03491</link>
      <description>Farzin Nekouei, Christopher J. Pollock, Tianyi Wang, Zhong Zheng, Yanzhao Zhang, Zelio Fusco, Huanyu Jin, Thrinathreddy Ramireddy, Ary Anggara Wibowo, Teng L&#252;, Shahram Nekouei, Farzaneh Keshtpour, Julien Langley, Elwy H. Abdelkader, Nicholas J. Cox, Zongyou Yin, Hieu T. Nguyen, Alexey M. Glushenkov, Siva Krishna Karuturi, Zongwen Liu, Wei Li, Hao Li, Yun Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406217331

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Farzin Nekouei, Christopher J. Pollock, Tianyi Wang, Zhong Zheng, Yanzhao Zhang, Zelio Fusco, Huanyu Jin, Thrinathreddy Ramireddy, Ary Anggara Wibowo, Teng L&#252;, Shahram Nekouei, Farzaneh Keshtpour, Julien Langley, Elwy H. Abdelkader, Nicholas J. Cox, Zongyou Yin, Hieu T. Nguyen, Alexey M. Glushenkov, Siva Krishna Karuturi, Zongwen Liu, Wei Li, Hao Li, Yun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Enantioselective Tandem C&#8211;H Indolization toward Biindolyl Atropisomers: Reaction Development and Mechanistic Insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06594</link>
      <description>Zhi&#8208;Huan Peng, Ping Huang, Ao-Long Li, Mingkai Yang, Zhikang Li, Yuanyuan Li, Qin Shi, Jiating Cai, Shengdong Wang, Zhi Zhou, Wei Yi, Hui Gao, Zhongyi Zeng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406218794

                The electrochemical methods for asymmetric indolization are still elusive and pose a significant challenge. Taking advantage of 2-alkynylanilines as electrochemically compatible indolyl equivalents, we herein represent a mild and highly enantioselective electrocatalytic process for tandem C&#8211;H indolization to form 2,3&#8242;-biindolyl atropisomers along with hydrogen evolution reaction. Integrated experimental and computational mechanistic studies revealed that a sequential C&#8211;H metalation/nucleophilic cyclization/reductive elimination/anodic oxidation sequence involving a RhIII&#8211;RhI&#8211;RhIII catalytic cycle accounts for the established transformation.</description>
      <author>Zhi&#8208;Huan Peng, Ping Huang, Ao-Long Li, Mingkai Yang, Zhikang Li, Yuanyuan Li, Qin Shi, Jiating Cai, Shengdong Wang, Zhi Zhou, Wei Yi, Hui Gao, Zhongyi Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled Growth of Silver Nanoparticles by Metal&#8211;Support Interaction for Enhanced Tandem Catalytic Oxidation of HCHO at Low Temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05879</link>
      <description>Yue Ding, Hui Wang, Bin Huang, Yuchun Chang, Hua Yang, Zhenping Qu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406219352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue Ding, Hui Wang, Bin Huang, Yuchun Chang, Hua Yang, Zhenping Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lowering the Kinetic Barrier via the Synergistic Catalysis of N-CNTs Supported RhP Subnanoclusters and Confined Co Nanoparticles for Olefins Hydroformylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06822</link>
      <description>Jiamei Wei, Peng Gao, Shen Wang, Yue Ma, Dong Cao, Daojian Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406219626

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiamei Wei, Peng Gao, Shen Wang, Yue Ma, Dong Cao, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Methanol on Pt(111) Modified with a Pd Monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05442</link>
      <description>Aleksandra Wawrzyniak, Marc T. M. Koper, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406259351

                Electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO2) conversion to value-added, highly reduced chemicals such as methanol (CH3OH) is a promising possibility for producing renewable fuel and simultaneous CO2 recycling. However, this process remains a challenge, with only a few selective electrocatalysts known. Here, we present a study of a palladium monolayer on a platinum (111) single crystal (PdML/Pt(111)) as an electrocatalyst for CO2 conversion to CH3OH. A custom-made setup was employed in order to detect and quantify gaseous and liquid CO2 reduction products in sufficient concentrations despite the limitations of working with a single-crystalline electrode. Under ambient reaction conditions, a Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 1.5% at &#8722;0.9 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) was obtained while using CO2 as the reactant. Other reaction intermediates, carbon monoxide (CO) and formaldehyde (HCHO) were subsequently used as reactants, leading to FEs of 1.8 and 2.5%, respectively, whereas formic acid is not reduced. The corresponding mechanism concluded from our work is compared to the literature. The electrocatalyst introduced here, with a highly well-defined structure for CO2 conversion to CH3OH, opens up possibilities for further catalytic explorations.</description>
      <author>Aleksandra Wawrzyniak, Marc T. M. Koper</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access to Axially Chiral Biaryl Benzylamines via Ancestral Enzyme-Enabled Reductive Amination Desymmetrization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06881</link>
      <description>W. Jim Zheng, Xinxin Zhu, Zheng Zhu, Teng Yang, Lian Zheng, Rui Pan, Shenlin Wang, Lixin Zhang, Qi Chen, Jian-He Xu, Yongtao Xie, Gao&#8208;Wei Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406275770

                Axially chiral biaryl benzylamines are present in numerous natural products, pharmaceuticals, chiral ligands, and catalysts. However, the direct catalytic synthesis of these functional molecules using a robust strategy remains a formidable challenge. Reductive amination desymmetrization of biaryl dialdehydes offers a powerful approach for the construction of axially chiral biaryl benzylamines but suffers from extensive undesirable side reactions. Herein, we engineered ancestral imine reductases to enable reductive amination desymmetrization of biaryl dialdehydes, allowing the construction of a wide range of axially chiral biaryl benzylamines with up to 99% conversion and 99% enantiomeric excess (ee). The ratio of the product to byproducts was up to 97:3 and over 90:10 in most cases. This work presents an alternative strategy for accessing axially chiral biaryl benzylamines and will stimulate the development of associated bioactive molecules and catalysts/ligands.</description>
      <author>W. Jim Zheng, Xinxin Zhu, Zheng Zhu, Teng Yang, Lian Zheng, Rui Pan, Shenlin Wang, Lixin Zhang, Qi Chen, Jian-He Xu, Yongtao Xie, Gao&#8208;Wei Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd-Catalyzed Dehydrogenation Enhanced by Charge Transfer from MoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Promoter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04684</link>
      <description>Byung Gwan Park, Jihyeon Lee, Yoojin Lee, Hyeongeon Lee, Jueun Kim, Eonu Nam, Jong&#8208;Seong Bae, Jeong Woo Han, Kwangjin An, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406317251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Byung Gwan Park, Jihyeon Lee, Yoojin Lee, Hyeongeon Lee, Jueun Kim, Eonu Nam, Jong&#8208;Seong Bae, Jeong Woo Han, Kwangjin An</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water-Controlled Coking Dynamics during High-Pressure Methanol-to-Olefins Reaction over SAPO-34</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06239</link>
      <description>Chengwei Zhang, Xinqiang Wu, Yanan Zhang, Li Wang, Yan Jin, Mingbin Gao, Mao Ye, Yingxu Wei, Zhongmin Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406321093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chengwei Zhang, Xinqiang Wu, Yanan Zhang, Li Wang, Yan Jin, Mingbin Gao, Mao Ye, Yingxu Wei, Zhongmin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate Promiscuity Engineering of ScALDO Enables a Versatile Minimized Enzyme Cascade for Efficient Utilization of Various Sugars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07497</link>
      <description>Shiming Tang, Z Y Zhang, Daocheng Liao, Ying Lin, Yuan&#8208;Yuan Huang, Suiping Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406327422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiming Tang, Z Y Zhang, Daocheng Liao, Ying Lin, Yuan&#8208;Yuan Huang, Suiping Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07497</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Specialization of a Promiscuous Designer Enzyme</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06409</link>
      <description>Reuben B. Leveson&#8208;Gower, Laura Tiessler&#8208;Sala, H.J. Rozeboom, A.M.W.H. Thunnissen, Jean&#8208;Didier Mar&#233;chal, G&#233;rard Roelfes, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406328950

                The evolution of a promiscuous enzyme for its various activities often results in catalytically specialized variants. This is an important natural mechanism to ensure the proper functioning of natural metabolic networks. It also acts as both a curse and blessing for enzyme engineers, where enzymes that have undergone directed evolution may exhibit exquisite selectivity at the expense of a diminished overall catalytic repertoire. We previously performed two independent directed evolution campaigns on a promiscuous designer enzyme that leverages the unique properties of a noncanonical amino acid (ncAA) para-aminophenylalanine (pAF) as catalytic residue, resulting in two evolved variants which are both catalytically specialized. Here, we combine mutagenesis, crystallography, and computation to reveal the molecular basis of the specialization phenomenon. In one evolved variant, an unexpected change in quaternary structure biases substrate dynamics to promote enantioselective catalysis, while the other demonstrates synergistic cooperation between natural side chains and the pAF residue to form semisynthetic catalytic machinery.</description>
      <author>Reuben B. Leveson&#8208;Gower, Laura Tiessler&#8208;Sala, H.J. Rozeboom, A.M.W.H. Thunnissen, Jean&#8208;Didier Mar&#233;chal, G&#233;rard Roelfes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-Catalyzed Chemoselective &#960;&#8211;&#963;&#8211;&#960;-Type Tandem Reductive Coupling to Access Isoquinolines via Carbocobaltation of Nitriles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07667</link>
      <description>Ling Tang, Xueyu Liu, Xintong Wang, Xianmao Liu, Xinmiao Huang, Ni Qian, Chen He, Gen Luo, Yuanhong Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406362720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Tang, Xueyu Liu, Xintong Wang, Xianmao Liu, Xinmiao Huang, Ni Qian, Chen He, Gen Luo, Yuanhong Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helix Zipper Regulating Formolase Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07452</link>
      <description>Zijian Tan, Zijing Tang, Hongli Wei, R.&#8208;H. Zhang, Ling Sun, Weidong Liu, Haifeng Liu, Leilei Zhu, Yanhe Ma, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406362725

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zijian Tan, Zijing Tang, Hongli Wei, R.&#8208;H. Zhang, Ling Sun, Weidong Liu, Haifeng Liu, Leilei Zhu, Yanhe Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Ethylene Production through Enhanced Monomolecular &#946;-Scission in Confined Catalytic Cracking of Olefin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05323</link>
      <description>Yanfen Zuo, Lei Ye, Wenjie Yang, Bo Peng, Jing Zhang, Xingtian Shu, Youhao Xu, Jichang Liu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406369344

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanfen Zuo, Lei Ye, Wenjie Yang, Bo Peng, Jing Zhang, Xingtian Shu, Youhao Xu, Jichang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05323</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
