<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ACS Catalysis</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/ACS-Catalysis.xml</link>
    <description>Articles from ACS Catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:25:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective Synthesis of Chiral Acyclic Nitriles Containing &#945;-All-Carbon Quaternary Stereocenters via Synergistic Palladium and Phase-Transfer Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06364</link>
      <description>Cheng Guo, Yunpeng Dong, Yi Wang, Xiaona Du, Runxia Ma, Choon&#8208;Hong Tan, Xinjun Luan, Jingyun Ren, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405265174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Guo, Yunpeng Dong, Yi Wang, Xiaona Du, Runxia Ma, Choon&#8208;Hong Tan, Xinjun Luan, Jingyun Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zwitterionic &#960;-Allyl-Pd Species Enabled [2&#963;+2&#960;] Cycloaddition Reactions of Vinylbicyclo[1.1.0]butanes (VBCBs) with Alkenes, Carbonyls, and Imines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06660</link>
      <description>Tianxiang Li, Sheng Wang, Jing Wang, Haosong Ren, Zhongren Lin, Zhenyue Li, Jun Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405273729

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianxiang Li, Sheng Wang, Jing Wang, Haosong Ren, Zhongren Lin, Zhenyue Li, Jun Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Gas Nanovessel Promotes Hydrogen Peroxide Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05357</link>
      <description>Junsheng He, Xiaoshan Zheng, Qunxing Huang, Zhenhua Pan, Chiheng Chu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405273771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junsheng He, Xiaoshan Zheng, Qunxing Huang, Zhenhua Pan, Chiheng Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of VldE (Spr1875), a Pneumococcal Two-State &lt;scp&gt;l&lt;/scp&gt;,&lt;scp&gt;d&lt;/scp&gt;-Endopeptidase with a Four-Zinc Cluster in the Active Site</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05090</link>
      <description>Vega Miguel-Ruano, Iv&#225;n Acebr&#243;n, Mijoon Lee, Antonio J. Mart&#237;n-Galiano, C&#233;line Freton, Ux&#237;a P. de Jos&#233;, Balajee Ramachandran, Federico Gago, Morten Kjos, Du&#353;an Hesek, Christophe Grangeasse, Leiv Sigve H&#229;varstein, Daniel Straume, Shahriar Mobashery, J.A. Hermoso, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274852

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vega Miguel-Ruano, Iv&#225;n Acebr&#243;n, Mijoon Lee, Antonio J. Mart&#237;n-Galiano, C&#233;line Freton, Ux&#237;a P. de Jos&#233;, Balajee Ramachandran, Federico Gago, Morten Kjos, Du&#353;an Hesek, Christophe Grangeasse, Leiv Sigve H&#229;varstein, Daniel Straume, Shahriar Mobashery, J.A. Hermoso</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd-Catalyzed C&#8211;H Activation vs &#946;-H Elimination: An Experimental and Computational Insight into the Reactivity of Tertiary Alkylamines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06160</link>
      <description>Jesus Rodrigalvarez, Matthew J. Gaunt, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jesus Rodrigalvarez, Matthew J. Gaunt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional and Structural Analyses of a Highly Multifunctional Enzyme TM1270 from the Hyperthermophile &lt;i&gt;Thermotoga maritima&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05275</link>
      <description>Tetsuya Miyamoto, S. Nitta, Hiroshi Homma, Shinya Fushinobu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405276133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tetsuya Miyamoto, S. Nitta, Hiroshi Homma, Shinya Fushinobu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Photothermal Tandem Catalysis for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Boosted by Zr&#8211;O&#8211;W Interfacial H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O Dissociation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06218</link>
      <description>Ruoxuan Peng, Yuqi Ren, Yitao Si, Kai Huang, Jiancheng Zhou, Lunbo Duan, Naixu Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405302796

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruoxuan Peng, Yuqi Ren, Yitao Si, Kai Huang, Jiancheng Zhou, Lunbo Duan, Naixu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Aromatic Cope Rearrangement with Gold(I) Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06662</link>
      <description>Pierre Locquet, R. Akilan, Raquel Pereira, Fabienne Grellepois, Jean&#8208;Marc Weibel, &#201;ric H&#233;non, Emmanuel Riguet, Aur&#233;lien Blanc, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405304851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pierre Locquet, R. Akilan, Raquel Pereira, Fabienne Grellepois, Jean&#8208;Marc Weibel, &#201;ric H&#233;non, Emmanuel Riguet, Aur&#233;lien Blanc</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06662</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Catalyzed Markovnikov-Selective Radical Hydrochalcogenation of Unactivated Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06770</link>
      <description>Jiayi Li, Lei Zhu, Zhaohui Liu, H. Liu, Si-Chen Tao, S. H. Zhu, Yan&#8208;Long Zheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405312226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayi Li, Lei Zhu, Zhaohui Liu, H. Liu, Si-Chen Tao, S. H. Zhu, Yan&#8208;Long Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation and Stabilization of Engineered Amine Dehydrogenase by Fatty Acids for Bioprocess Intensification of Asymmetric Reductive Amination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05904</link>
      <description>Weixi Kong, Jiawang Zhang, Liya Zhou, Guanhua Liu, Ying He, Li Ma, Frank Hollmann, Sheng Wang, Yunting Liu, Yanjun Jiang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405312334

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weixi Kong, Jiawang Zhang, Liya Zhou, Guanhua Liu, Ying He, Li Ma, Frank Hollmann, Sheng Wang, Yunting Liu, Yanjun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05904</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Indium&#8211;Palladium Intermetallic Catalysts for Selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04670</link>
      <description>Jiabao Lv, Hongman Sun, Guanying Liu, Tong Liu, Guofeng Zhao, Youhe Wang, Xin Tu, Zifeng Yan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405312574

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiabao Lv, Hongman Sun, Guanying Liu, Tong Liu, Guofeng Zhao, Youhe Wang, Xin Tu, Zifeng Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-Photoredox-Catalyzed Divergent Strategy for the Site-Selective Arylation and Alkylation of Glycines and Peptides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06254</link>
      <description>Prahallad Meher, M. Siva Prasad, Karan Ramdas Thombare, Sandip Murarka, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405319097

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Prahallad Meher, M. Siva Prasad, Karan Ramdas Thombare, Sandip Murarka</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Step Construction of Atropisomers Bearing 1,5-Central and Axial Chirality via Catalytic Diastereo- and Atroposelective Remote Desymmetrizing Alkynylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06332</link>
      <description>Shan Wang, Long Li, Ming Jiang, Kaixin Zhao, Daming He, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang, Yingcheng Wang, Fangzhi Peng, Zhihui Shao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405333449

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shan Wang, Long Li, Ming Jiang, Kaixin Zhao, Daming He, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang, Yingcheng Wang, Fangzhi Peng, Zhihui Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous Tandem Catalysis Strategy for Additive-Free CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation into Formic Acid in Water: Crystal Plane Effect of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Cocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05484</link>
      <description>Kohsuke Mori, Jun Shinogi, Yuki Shimada, Hiromi Yamashita, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405333957

                The transformation of carbon dioxide (CO2) into formic acid (FA; HCOOH) in an aqueous phase is a promising method of realizing an environmentally friendly FA/CO2-mediated chemical hydrogen storage/supply cycle. Despite progress in the design of catalysts that operate under basic conditions, the development of efficient catalysts that operate under additive-free conditions lags behind owing to the difficulty in activating CO2 and the low solubility of CO2 in pure water. In the present study, we present a heterogeneous tandem catalysis strategy in which Co3O4 is used as a CO2 hydration cocatalyst to produce a HCO3&#8211; intermediate, in combination with our previously reported PdAg/TiO2 as a catalyst for the hydrogenation of HCO3&#8211; to afford FA. The turnover number based on Pd improved by a factor of more than 8 in the presence of the Co3O4 cocatalyst with a cubic particle morphology enclosed by (100) facets. A series of morphology-controlled Co3O4 cocatalysts was investigated to elucidate the effect of the exposed crystal facets (i.e., (100), (111), or (112)) on their physicochemical properties and catalytic activity in FA synthesis. A systematic comparison based on experimental and density functional theory calculations demonstrated that the substantial enhancement effect of the Co3O4 cubes is attributable to the in situ generation of the largest amount of surface Co&#8211;OH groups with strong basicity originating from the exposed (100) facets. In addition, the present tandem catalytic system displayed high recyclability without exhibiting a structural change or a significant loss of activity. These findings will allow the rational design of an environmentally benign catalytic system for the hydrogenation of CO2 to FA.</description>
      <author>Kohsuke Mori, Jun Shinogi, Yuki Shimada, Hiromi Yamashita</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ordered Adsorption of Oxygen via High-Density Low-Coordinated Ru Sites for Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03294</link>
      <description>Yu Zhang, Junguo Ma, Zewen Zhuang, Aijian Huang, Shuting Zhang, Wenbo Zhai, Yi Yu, Qing Peng, Hai Xiao, Caiyun Nan, Chen Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405333965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Zhang, Junguo Ma, Zewen Zhuang, Aijian Huang, Shuting Zhang, Wenbo Zhai, Yi Yu, Qing Peng, Hai Xiao, Caiyun Nan, Chen Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multisite CuNi/Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst Enabling High-Efficiency Reductive Amination of Biomass-Derived Levulinic Acid (Esters) to Pyrrolidones under Mild Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06035</link>
      <description>Xixi Liu, Peng Zhou, Zhihua Zhu, Yimeng Guo, Hang Lv, Zehui Zhang, Liangfang Zhu, Changwei Hu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405364003

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xixi Liu, Peng Zhou, Zhihua Zhu, Yimeng Guo, Hang Lv, Zehui Zhang, Liangfang Zhu, Changwei Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biocatalytic Formal Asymmetric &lt;i&gt;para&lt;/i&gt;-Aminoethylation of Unprotected Phenols to Chiral Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06475</link>
      <description>Jingqi Zhang, Xuan Deng, Xue Han, Shuangping Huang, Honghong Chang, Lili Gao, Jiandong Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405364941

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingqi Zhang, Xuan Deng, Xue Han, Shuangping Huang, Honghong Chang, Lili Gao, Jiandong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid/Base-Tuned Asymmetric Reductive Heck and Denitrogenative Heck Reactions of In Situ-Formed &#945;,&#946;-Unsaturated Hydrazone</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05561</link>
      <description>Shuling Yu, Xiaoyu Zhou, Xiaofeng Tong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405366807

                Despite significant progress in the catalytic asymmetric 1,4-additions between various Michael donors and acceptors, the exploration of organohalide donors remains elusive. Herein, we report the Pd(0)-catalyzed asymmetric intramolecular 1,4-additions of vinyl/aryl iodides to &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated hydrazones, featuring in situ-formed hydrazone and acid/base-tuned reaction pathways. Due to its strong coordination ability, the hydrazone is capable of steering the C&#8211;C bond formation to follow the 1,4-addition mechanism instead of the conventional alkene insertion, thus enabling the generation of vinylhydrazinyl&#8211;Pd2+ species via the Zimmerman&#8211;Traxler chairlike transition state. Notably, this species preferentially undergoes protonation under acidic conditions, furnishing a reductive Heck reaction with the aid of a native hydrazine reductant, while it is susceptible to &#946;-HN elimination under basic conditions to achieve a denitrogenative Heck reaction. The catalytic protocol affords highly enantioselective access to diverse heterocycles, with alkene and hydrazone groups poised for further chemical manipulations.</description>
      <author>Shuling Yu, Xiaoyu Zhou, Xiaofeng Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atroposelective Three-Component (Fluoro)methylative Alkylation of Terminal Alkynes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06100</link>
      <description>Yaheng Zhao, Liping Huo, Xiaoyu Zhao, Lingling Chu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405376697

                The development of synthetic methods for the selective installation of methyl and fluoromethyl groups is highly desired due to their critical role in drug development. While significant advances have been made in the methylation and difluoromethylation of aromatic compounds, the catalytic atroposelective (fluoro)methylative functionalization of alkynes to forge axially chiral alkenes remains underexploited. Herein, we report an enantioselective cross-electrophile strategy for the efficient 1,2-carbo-(fluoro)methylation of alkynes with two different alkyl halides via nickel catalysis. By integrating a one-electron radical process with a two-electron organometallic process, this protocol employs a simple chiral nickel catalyst to effectively discriminate between secondary and tertiary alkyl groups and (fluoro)methyl groups for alkyne difunctionalization. This protocol demonstrates good compatibility of activated secondary/tertiary alkyl bromides, terminal alkynes, and (fluoro)methyl halides, permitting the straightforward synthesis of a broad range of synthetically valuable axially chiral (fluoro)methyl-substituted alkenes with high chemo-, regio-, trans-, and atropo-selectivity. Preliminary mechanistic studies provide insight into the potential reaction pathway.</description>
      <author>Yaheng Zhao, Liping Huo, Xiaoyu Zhao, Lingling Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Interface-Dependent Active Sites Induced by Strong Metal&#8211;Support Interactions on Au/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in 2,5-Bis(hydroxymethyl)furan Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05341</link>
      <description>Enhui Du, Jie Yang, Liyuan Huai, Panpan Hao, Mingxin Lv, Zhilin Chen, Yuxiang Chen, Jian Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405378410

                Strong metal&#8211;support interactions (SMSI) typically induce the migration of a coverage layer to the metal surface accompanied by electron transfer, forming a unique metal&#8211;support interface. This dual modification in geometric and electronic structures reconstructs the active surface, adjusting the activity and stability of the catalyst. However, identifying and quantifying such newly formed interfacial sites remains a challenge. Herein, by varying the reduction temperature to control the TiO2&#8211;x coverage on Au nanoparticles, the catalytic activity of Au/TiO2 in 2,5-bis(hydroxymethyl)furan (BHMF) oxidation shows a volcano-shaped trend. Combined thiol titration and poisoning kinetics analysis to quantify the ratio of interfacial to surface sites and normalize it to intrinsic activity, revealing that Au-TiO2&#8211;x interfacial sites positively contribute to catalytic performance. This study offers valuable insights into the active sites in heterogeneous catalytic systems with SMSI effects.</description>
      <author>Enhui Du, Jie Yang, Liyuan Huai, Panpan Hao, Mingxin Lv, Zhilin Chen, Yuxiang Chen, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anionic Oxidation Activity/Stability Regulated by Transition Metals in Multimetallic (Oxy)hydroxides for Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03718</link>
      <description>Shuhao Wang, Kamran Dastafkan, Sicheng Wu, Qian Sun, Chengli Rong, Dazhi Yao, Chuan Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405378470

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuhao Wang, Kamran Dastafkan, Sicheng Wu, Qian Sun, Chengli Rong, Dazhi Yao, Chuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovery and Synthetic Applications of a NAD(P)H-Dependent Reductive Aminase from &lt;i&gt;Rhodococcus erythropolis&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04935</link>
      <description>Ewald P. J. Jongkind, J. Domenech, Arthur Govers, Marcel van den Broek, Jean&#8208;Marc Daran, Gideon Grogan, Caroline E. Paul, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405431243

                Reductive amination is one of the most synthetically direct routes to access chiral amines. Several Imine Reductases (IREDs) have been discovered to catalyze reductive amination (Reductive Aminases or RedAms), yet they are dependent on the expensive phosphorylated nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide cofactor NADPH and usually more active at basic pH. Here, we describe the discovery and synthetic potential of an IRED from Rhodococcus erythropolis (RytRedAm) that catalyzes reductive amination between a series of medium to large carbonyl and amine compounds with conversions of up to &gt;99% and 99% enantiomeric excess at neutral pH. RytRedAm catalyzes the formation of a substituted &#947;-lactam and N-methyl-1-phenylethanamine with stereochemistry opposite to that of fungal RedAms, giving the (S)-enantiomer. This enzyme remarkably uses both NADPH and NADH cofactors with KM values of 15 and 247 &#956;M and turnover numbers kcat of 3.6 and 9.0 s&#8211;1, respectively, for the reductive amination of hexanal with allylamine. The crystal structure obtained provides insights into the flexibility to also accept NADH, with residues R35 and I69 diverging from that of other IREDs/RedAms in the otherwise conserved Rossmann fold. RytRedAm thus represents a subfamily of enzymes that enable synthetic applications using NADH-dependent reductive amination to access complementary chiral amine products.</description>
      <author>Ewald P. J. Jongkind, J. Domenech, Arthur Govers, Marcel van den Broek, Jean&#8208;Marc Daran, Gideon Grogan, Caroline E. Paul</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Chiral C2-Quaternary Indolines via Palladium-Catalyzed Decarboxylative Asymmetric Amination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05763</link>
      <description>Mingjun Lv, Xinhui Yu, Jitian Liu, Xiaoxun Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405431372

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingjun Lv, Xinhui Yu, Jitian Liu, Xiaoxun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemically Bonded Schottky Junction for Efficient N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photofixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04443</link>
      <description>Yin Bi, Yuan Fang, Ling Yuan, Jiaxin Li, Chaoqi Zhang, Pengyue Shan, Xinchan Zhang, Chao Liu, Chengzhong Yu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405431397

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yin Bi, Yuan Fang, Ling Yuan, Jiaxin Li, Chaoqi Zhang, Pengyue Shan, Xinchan Zhang, Chao Liu, Chengzhong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Activity and Stability through Compositional Engineering of Ternary PtNi&#8211;Au Alloy ORR Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05269</link>
      <description>Xianxian Xie, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Pere Alemany, Athira Lekshmi Mohandas Sandhya, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Milan Dopita, Michael Vorochta, Albert Bruix, Serhiy Cherevko, Konstantin M. Neyman, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Ivan Khalakhan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405439103

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianxian Xie, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Pere Alemany, Athira Lekshmi Mohandas Sandhya, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Milan Dopita, Michael Vorochta, Albert Bruix, Serhiy Cherevko, Konstantin M. Neyman, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Ivan Khalakhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biocatalytic Cleavage of &lt;i&gt;para&lt;/i&gt;-Acetoxy Benzyl Ethers: Application to Protecting Group Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04257</link>
      <description>Ben Ashley, Chiara Demingo, H.J. Rozeboom, Niccol&#243; Bianciardi, Tom&#225;s Dunleavy, Jacob&#8208;Jan Haaksma, Yiming Guo, Marco W. Fraaije, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443211

                Aryl ethers are ubiquitous protecting groups of alcohols and amines in organic chemistry. This is owed to the simplicity of their appendage to molecules and the robust protection afforded. However, aryl ethers and amines can be challenging to cleave, often requiring harsh and unselective reductive conditions. We report the structure-based engineering of a promiscuous, ether-cleaving vanillyl alcohol oxidase-type biocatalyst for activity on a wide range of para-hydroxy benzyl ethers. Two superior quadruple mutants are identified with improved kinetics and substrate scope. One evolved variant and two predecessors are crystallized, and their structures resolved to 2.8&#8211;1.5 &#197;, revealing a significant increase in the volume and flexibility of the active site cavity. To illustrate the potential usefulness of the engineered biocatalysts, one is later coupled with another biocatalyst in a cascade reaction to catalyze the selective cleavage of an uncommon aryl ether protecting group, para-acyloxy benzyl ethers, in good yield and under mild conditions.</description>
      <author>Ben Ashley, Chiara Demingo, H.J. Rozeboom, Niccol&#243; Bianciardi, Tom&#225;s Dunleavy, Jacob&#8208;Jan Haaksma, Yiming Guo, Marco W. Fraaije</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT-Assisted Atroposelective Construction of Indole-Fused &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Heteroaromatic Frameworks through Palladium-Catalyzed C&#8211;H Imidoylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06720</link>
      <description>Xilong Wang, Jiali Xu, Yu Luo, Yuanyu Wang, Jun Huang, Qiang Zhu, Shuang Luo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xilong Wang, Jiali Xu, Yu Luo, Yuanyu Wang, Jun Huang, Qiang Zhu, Shuang Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06720</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Modulated by B-Doped Cu Promotes Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction for Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05954</link>
      <description>Jia-Jia Wang, Zhuodong Ou, Chenglin Dong, Mengying Su, Amjad Ali, Artem V. Kuklin, Hans &#197;gren, Glib Baryshnikov, Yang Liu, Xue Zhao, Haibo Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443274

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia-Jia Wang, Zhuodong Ou, Chenglin Dong, Mengying Su, Amjad Ali, Artem V. Kuklin, Hans &#197;gren, Glib Baryshnikov, Yang Liu, Xue Zhao, Haibo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05954</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning the Active Phases of CoFe Alloy Carbides for Boosting Olefin Synthesis from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06112</link>
      <description>Na Liu, Qixiang Fan, Jian Wei, Guanghui Zhang, Jian Sun, Wenhui Li, Chunshan Song, Xinwen Guo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443281

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Na Liu, Qixiang Fan, Jian Wei, Guanghui Zhang, Jian Sun, Wenhui Li, Chunshan Song, Xinwen Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Metal Cations Microenvironment for Highly Selective Electrochemical Water Oxidation to Hydrogen Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06189</link>
      <description>Lanke Luo, Mingxuan Li, Haohai Dong, Haomin Jiang, Huatian Chen, Jiongjun Wu, Peiyuan Su, Xinyue Zhang, Lin Chen, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443310

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lanke Luo, Mingxuan Li, Haohai Dong, Haomin Jiang, Huatian Chen, Jiongjun Wu, Peiyuan Su, Xinyue Zhang, Lin Chen, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag/Co-Bimetallic Cooperation in the C&#8211;H Functionalization of Aliphatic Amides with Propiolic Acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05918</link>
      <description>Andr&#233;s Garc&#237;a&#8208;Viada, Emma Duro, Celia S&#225;nchez&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, In&#233;s Alonso, Nuria Rodr&#237;guez, Javier Adrio, Juan C. Carretero, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443360

                We herein describe the high-valent cobalt-catalyzed C(sp3)&#8211;H functionalization of amide derivatives with silver acetylides generated in situ. The reaction proceeds under kinetic control at 60 &#176;C, with a catalyst loading of 5 mol %. These extraordinarily mild conditions for Co-catalysis enable the synthesis of 5-(Z)-ethylidene pyrrolidin-2-one derivatives in good yield and selectivity. Density functional theory calculations have revealed a unique mechanism involving Co&#8211;Ag bimetallic species, rationalizing the nature of the catalytically active species and the role of each additive.</description>
      <author>Andr&#233;s Garc&#237;a&#8208;Viada, Emma Duro, Celia S&#225;nchez&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, In&#233;s Alonso, Nuria Rodr&#237;guez, Javier Adrio, Juan C. Carretero</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Synergy of Ni Single Atom/Clusters and MXene Enabling Semiconductor Quantum Dots Based Superior Photoredox Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05842</link>
      <description>Ming&#8211;Yu Qi, Wei-Yun Xiao, Marco Conte, Zi&#8208;Rong Tang, Yi&#8208;Jun Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443444

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming&#8211;Yu Qi, Wei-Yun Xiao, Marco Conte, Zi&#8208;Rong Tang, Yi&#8208;Jun Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Impact of Niobia Promotion on Pt/Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for Enhanced Catalytic Performance in Benzyltoluene Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03543</link>
      <description>Jun Ki Yoo, Seok-Ho Lee, Tae In Park, Jeong Yong Lee, Kwan&#8208;Young Lee, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443456

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Ki Yoo, Seok-Ho Lee, Tae In Park, Jeong Yong Lee, Kwan&#8208;Young Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Unique Selectivity of Cobalt Phthalocyanine in Multielectron Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05744</link>
      <description>Hengyu Li, Yangfan Shao, Zhichao Zhang, Muhammad N. Tahir, Tingzheng Hou, Lin Gan, Feng Ding, Jia Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443459

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hengyu Li, Yangfan Shao, Zhichao Zhang, Muhammad N. Tahir, Tingzheng Hou, Lin Gan, Feng Ding, Jia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-Controlled Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;M Alloys as Enhanced Catalysts for Ammonia Oxidation Reaction: A Combined Theoretical and Experimental Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05857</link>
      <description>Jaeyoung Yoo, Jungwoo Choi, Su-Yeon Choi, Changsoo Lee, Hyuck Mo Lee, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jaeyoung Yoo, Jungwoo Choi, Su-Yeon Choi, Changsoo Lee, Hyuck Mo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photothermal-Enhanced H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Generation and Lignin Upgrading to Jet Fuel Precursor over Lignin&#8211;Carbon-Bridged Pt/Ni&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;P</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04888</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Jiawen Liao, Xueqing Qiu, Xuliang Lin, Yanlin Qin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405457504

                Merging efficient H2 generation with high-value utilization of biomass via a solar-driven catalytic redox technology presents a promising strategy for overall biorefinery. As the most abundant aromatic polymer in nature, lignin is considered an ideal sacrificial agent to enhance the reductive H2 evolution, coproducing high-value aromatic chemicals/fuels instead of waste carbon oxides. However, the development of an energy-efficient and productive photocatalysis system remains challenging. Herein, a photothermal cocatalytic technology was developed for synergistic enhancement on the redox activities. A feasible synthesis method was proposed to precisely construct a light-sensitive heterojunction between active Pt and NixP, bridged by technical lignin&#8211;carbon. Benefiting from the advanced modulation effect of lignin&#8211;carbon, accelerated electron transfer and active structural rearrangement were realized on the defective catalyst surface. Combining an optimized band gap structure, H2 evolution efficiency was boosted under photothermal cocatalysis and showed a splendid H2 evolution rate of 10.7 mmol&#183;gcat&#8211;1&#183;h&#8211;1 based on a lignin-derived monomer (vanillyl alcohol), 15-fold higher than either photocatalysis or thermocatalysis alone. The H2 evolution obtained from technical lignin (2.9 mmol&#183;gcat&#8211;1&#183;h&#8211;1) surpassed the existing level of biomass. Meanwhile, the controllable coupling of lignin or its derived monomers was enhanced simultaneously, yielding C13&#8211;C16 dimers (43.8% yield) from the lignin-derived monomer via C&#945; node, which act as ideal precursors for jet fuel. This work advances lignin upgrading for hydrogen energy and biofuels.</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Jiawen Liao, Xueqing Qiu, Xuliang Lin, Yanlin Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Reduction Reaction on Pyridinic Nitrogen-Functionalized Carbon: Active Site Quantification and Effects of Lewis Basicity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05289</link>
      <description>Zhongyao Zhang, Feiting Zhang, Zhongxin Song, Lei Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405464001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongyao Zhang, Feiting Zhang, Zhongxin Song, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production from Lignocellulosic Biomass over MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Modified Sulfur Vacancy Enriched ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Photocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05707</link>
      <description>Jiping Tang, Yan Chen, Ziyi Wang, Yun-Hui Hu, Jiahao Wang, Liang Bao, Zong&#8208;Yan Zhao, Yong&#8208;Jun Yuan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405474939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiping Tang, Yan Chen, Ziyi Wang, Yun-Hui Hu, Jiahao Wang, Liang Bao, Zong&#8208;Yan Zhao, Yong&#8208;Jun Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05707</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
