<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 01:20:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>How could emerging nanomedicine-based tuberculosis treatments outperform conventional approaches?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/17435889.2025.2458447</link>
      <description>Jiwon Kim, Khongorzul Enkhtaivan, Jangmi Yang, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Jonghoon Choi, Nanomedicine. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406932408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiwon Kim, Khongorzul Enkhtaivan, Jangmi Yang, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Jonghoon Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/17435889.2025.2458447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lipid Nanoparticle Delivery System for Normalization of Tumor Microenvironment and Tumor Vascular Structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34133/bmr.0144</link>
      <description>Hee-Jin Ha, Yonghyun Choi, Na-Hyeon Kim, Jiwon Kim, Jaehee Jang, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Masayoshi Tanaka, Heeyoung Lee, Jonghoon Choi, Biomaterials Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407034921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hee-Jin Ha, Yonghyun Choi, Na-Hyeon Kim, Jiwon Kim, Jaehee Jang, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Masayoshi Tanaka, Heeyoung Lee, Jonghoon Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34133/bmr.0144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated &lt;i&gt;Systems-to-Atoms&lt;/i&gt; (S2A) Framework for Designing Resilient and Efficient Hydrogen Infrastructure Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05903</link>
      <description>Mengyao Yuan, Giovanna Bucci, Tanusree Chatterjee, Shyam Deo, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird, Wenqin Li, Thomas Moore, Corey Myers, Wenyu Sun, Ethan M. Sunshine, Bo-Xun Wang, Matthew J. McNenly, Sneha A. Akhade, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407089073

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyao Yuan, Giovanna Bucci, Tanusree Chatterjee, Shyam Deo, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird, Wenqin Li, Thomas Moore, Corey Myers, Wenyu Sun, Ethan M. Sunshine, Bo-Xun Wang, Matthew J. McNenly, Sneha A. Akhade</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibrationally Assisted Tunneling through the Bread of a Proton Sandwich&#9472;Connections to Dynamic Matching</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16135</link>
      <description>Yusef Ahmed, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Dean J. Tantillo, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407123053

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yusef Ahmed, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Dean J. Tantillo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16135</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
