<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 01:02:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Strategy for mRNA Encapsulation and Gene Delivery with Metal-Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mlcss</link>
      <description>Harrison Lawson, Huy Nguyen, Ayesha Tupe, Mariah L. Arral, K. Y. Lee, Min L&#252;, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Siyang Zheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394757946

                Over the last two decades, the utility of metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) has expanded from catalysis and gas storage to biomedical applications such as drug delivery. At first, MOF-based delivery platforms focused on delivering small molecules, with current work focusing on nucleic acids, such as DNA, short guide RNA (sgRNA), and short interfering RNA (siRNA). No studies to this date have specifically shown the encapsulation and delivery of mRNA with MOFs, possibly due to the fragile nature of messenger RNA (mRNA). This study explores and identifies suitable synthetic conditions for encapsulating and delivering mRNA with zeolitic imidazole framework-8 (ZIF-8). Initial ZIF-8 encapsulation attempts, although capable of mRNA loading, could not retain mRNA longer than 1 hour in biological media. To address this issue, we added polyethyleneimine (PEI) to the matrix, enabling the retention of mRNA with 4 hours of stability. Polyethyleneimine incorporation resolves the leakage of mRNA from ZIF-8, enabling delivery and resultant protein expression in multiple cell lines comparable to commercial lipid transfection reagents. Furthermore, we report the first application exploring thermally stable mRNA storage with ZIF-8 with successful protein expression achieved after 3 months of room temperature storage. Together, this work expands the catalog of therapeutics MOFs can deliver.</description>
      <author>Harrison Lawson, Huy Nguyen, Ayesha Tupe, Mariah L. Arral, K. Y. Lee, Min L&#252;, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Siyang Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mlcss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Mixed-Integer Linear Programming Formulation for Continuous-Time Inventory Routing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4793503</link>
      <description>Akang Wang, X. Li, Jeffrey E. Arbogast, Zachary Wilson, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394788163

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Akang Wang, X. Li, Jeffrey E. Arbogast, Zachary Wilson, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4793503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon nanomaterials&#8208;based electrically conductive scaffolds for tissue engineering applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/mba2.76</link>
      <description>Genevieve Abd, Raquel Sanchez Diaz, Anju Gupta, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Kunal Mondal, Seeram Ramakrishna, Ashutosh Sharma, Andr&#233;s D&#237;az Lantada, Monsur Islam, MedComm - Biomaterials and applications. 3(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394927677

                Abstract In tissue engineering, the pivotal role of scaffolds is underscored, serving as key elements to emulate the native extracellular matrix. These scaffolds must provide structural integrity and support and supply electrical, mechanical, and chemical cues for cell and tissue growth. Notably, electrical conductivity plays a crucial role when dealing with tissues like bone, spinal, neural, and cardiac tissues. However, the typical materials used as tissue engineering scaffolds are predominantly polymers, which generally characteristically feature poor electrical conductivity. Therefore, it is often necessary to incorporate conductive materials into the polymeric matrix to yield electrically conductive scaffolds and further enable electrical stimulation. Among different conductive materials, carbon nanomaterials have attracted significant attention in developing conductive tissue engineering scaffolds, demonstrating excellent biocompatibility and bioactivity in both in vitro and in vivo settings. This article aims to comprehensively review the current landscape of carbon&#8208;based conductive scaffolds, with a specific focus on their role in advancing tissue engineering for the regeneration and maturation of functional tissues, emphasizing the application of electrical stimulation. This review highlights the versatility of carbon&#8208;based conductive scaffolds and addresses existing challenges and prospects, shedding light on the trajectory of innovative conductive scaffold development in tissue engineering.</description>
      <author>Genevieve Abd, Raquel Sanchez Diaz, Anju Gupta, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Kunal Mondal, Seeram Ramakrishna, Ashutosh Sharma, Andr&#233;s D&#237;az Lantada, Monsur Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/mba2.76</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
