<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 01:24:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale optimization of formic acid dehydrogenation process via linear model decision tree surrogates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108921</link>
      <description>Ethan M. Sunshine, Giovanna Bucci, Tanusree Chatterjee, Shyam Deo, Victoria M. Ehlinger, Wenqin Li, Thomas Moore, Corey Myers, Wenyu Sun, Bo-Xun Wang, Mengyao Yuan, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird, Matthew J. McNenly, Sneha A. Akhade, Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404630758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ethan M. Sunshine, Giovanna Bucci, Tanusree Chatterjee, Shyam Deo, Victoria M. Ehlinger, Wenqin Li, Thomas Moore, Corey Myers, Wenyu Sun, Bo-Xun Wang, Mengyao Yuan, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird, Matthew J. McNenly, Sneha A. Akhade</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108921</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Operationally Flexible Diafiltration Membrane Systems for Critical Mineral Separations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2477929</link>
      <description>Jason Yao, Molly Dougher, Andrew Lee, Alexander W. Dowling, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404652142

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jason Yao, Molly Dougher, Andrew Lee, Alexander W. Dowling, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2477929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decomposition and Algorithmic Approaches for Solving Large-Scale Process Family Design Problems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2477797</link>
      <description>Georgia Stinchfield, Michael Bynum, Jean&#8208;Paul Watson, Carl D. Laird, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404679267

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Georgia Stinchfield, Michael Bynum, Jean&#8208;Paul Watson, Carl D. Laird</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2477797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Period Optimization of Multi-Timescale Energy Systems: Application to Solid-Oxide Electrolysis Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2478222</link>
      <description>Nishant Giridhar, Douglas Allan, Steve Zitney, Eric Liese, Lorenz T. Biegler, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404730544

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nishant Giridhar, Douglas Allan, Steve Zitney, Eric Liese, Lorenz T. Biegler, Debangsu Bhattacharyya</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2478222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-stage Stochastic Generalized Disjunctive Programming (GDP) Model for Proactive Planning and Reactive Operations of Resilient Power Systems under Disruptions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2478216</link>
      <description>Seolhee Cho, Ignacio E. Grossmann, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404730850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seolhee Cho, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2478216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization Model and Algorithm for Capacity Planning and Operation of Reliable and Carbon-neutral Power Systems with High Penetration of Renewable Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2478221</link>
      <description>Seolhee Cho, Javier Tovar-Facio, Benjamin Omell, Radhakrishna Gooty, Christopher McLean, Anthony P. Burgard, John Daniel Siirola, Kyle Skolfield, John Shinn, Ignacio E. Grossmann, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404730865

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seolhee Cho, Javier Tovar-Facio, Benjamin Omell, Radhakrishna Gooty, Christopher McLean, Anthony P. Burgard, John Daniel Siirola, Kyle Skolfield, John Shinn, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2478221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Computational Framework for Evaluating and Optimizing Critical Mineral Recovery Opportunities in Produced Water Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2478224</link>
      <description>Arsh Bhatia, Georgia Stinchfield, Daniel Ovalle Varela, Miguel Zamarripa, Markus Drouven, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Carl D. Laird, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404731511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arsh Bhatia, Georgia Stinchfield, Daniel Ovalle Varela, Miguel Zamarripa, Markus Drouven, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Carl D. Laird</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2478224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Process Systems Engineering for Sustainable Chemical Processes- A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogsc.2024.100982</link>
      <description>Ana I. Torres, Jimena Ferreira, Mart&#237;n Pedemonte, Current Opinion in Green and Sustainable Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404733139

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ana I. Torres, Jimena Ferreira, Mart&#237;n Pedemonte</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogsc.2024.100982</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Uncertainty Estimation of Graph Neural Network Potentials Using Engineered Latent Space Distances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04972</link>
      <description>Joseph Musielewicz, Janice Lan, Matt Uyttendaele, John R. Kitchin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404762044

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joseph Musielewicz, Janice Lan, Matt Uyttendaele, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonconvex Robust Optimization for the Design and Operation of Advanced Energy Systems Using PyROS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2478510</link>
      <description>Jason Sherman, John Daniel Siirola, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404773257

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jason Sherman, John Daniel Siirola, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2478510</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
