<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 18:28:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental and Theoretical Evaluation of Feed Flow Collar Design for Shell Fed Hollow Fiber Membrane Modules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2348930</link>
      <description>Thien Tran, Maya Schuchert, Victor A. Kusuma, Lili Sun, Comfort Oluleke, Nathan Diemler, Lingxiang Zhu, Grigorios Panagakos, G. Glenn Lipscomb, David Hui&#8208;Kang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396974300

                An experimental and theoretical study of module collar design is presented here. Hollow fiber membranes are prepared by dip coating a poly(vinylidene) (PVDF) support with a polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS) gutter layer and a Pebax 2533 selective layer. Fiber bundles with a well-defined fiber packing are prepared using a 3D printed module. A parallel fiber bundle consisting of 4-9 uniformly spaced fibers is created with printed tabs that align the fibers and create a tubesheet. The tabs are sealed within a printed case that possesses a series of external ports for gas introduction and removal. Uniquely, both port location and the use of a collar to assist fluid distribution in the shell can be varied for the same fiber bundle. Experimental measurements are compared to computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations. The experimental module design allows high-fidelity representation of the fiber bundle and module case in the simulations. Comparisons between experiment and simulation are in good agreement over a broad range of experimental conditions. The detrimental effect of having ports located too close, leading to stagnation regions, is captured as well as the beneficial effects of using a collar for shell-side fluid distribution around the fiber bundle. Such results help validate the use of CFD to develop high-performance module designs.</description>
      <author>Thien Tran, Maya Schuchert, Victor A. Kusuma, Lili Sun, Comfort Oluleke, Nathan Diemler, Lingxiang Zhu, Grigorios Panagakos, G. Glenn Lipscomb, David Hui&#8208;Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2348930</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization strategies for produced water networks with integrated desalination facilities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108738</link>
      <description>Sakshi Naik, Miguel Zamarripa, Markus Drouven, Lorenz T. Biegler, Computers &amp; chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396978966

                Optimal management and desalination of produced water is a major challenge for U.S. oil and gas development. Integrating rigorous desalination models into multi-period produced water network optimization problems presents several hurdles, which need to be tackled using advanced optimization strategies. In this work, a novel multi-period produced water network formulation with separate solid and liquid flows is introduced to avoid singularities at zero flows. Rigorous steady state desalination models based on mechanical vapor recompression are embedded at the desalination sites in the network model. An integrated optimization formulation is developed to co-optimize the design of desalination units along with the operation of the network. Furthermore, a more robust approach based on the trust region filter method is developed to efficiently integrate complex desalination models into the multi-period planning problem. Both optimization approaches are demonstrated on a produced water network from the PARETO library (Drouven et al., 2022) using thermal desalination units. Our results show that while the TRF and integrated approaches have comparable solve times, the TRF approach has better performance reliability in terms of solver convergence. Furthermore, the optimal solution obtained by embedding rigorous models into the network is significantly different than when desalination costs are approximated using simple cost models, which motivates further research in this field.</description>
      <author>Sakshi Naik, Miguel Zamarripa, Markus Drouven, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-organized Patterns in Predator-Prey Droplet Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-15zsd</link>
      <description>Yutong Liu, R. Kailasham, Pepijn G. Moerman, Aditya S. Khair, Lauren D. Zarzar, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397010234

                Non-equilibrium patterns are widespread in nature and often arise from the self-organization of constituents through nonreciprocal chemotactic interactions. In this study, we demonstrate how active oil-in-water droplet mixtures with predator-prey interactions can result in a variety of self-organized patterns. By manipulating physical parameters, the droplet diameter ratio and number ratio, we identify distinct classes of patterns within a binary droplet system, rationalize the pattern formation, and quantify motilities. Experimental results are recapitulated in numerical simulations using a minimal computational model that solely incorporates chemotactic interactions and steric repulsion among the constituents. The time evolution of the patterns is investigated and chemically explained. We also investigate how patterns vary with differing interaction strength by altering surfactant composition. Leveraging insights from the binary droplet system, the framework is extended to a ternary droplet mixture composed of multiple chasing droplet pairs to create chemically directed hierarchical organization. Our findings demonstrate how rationalizable, self-organized patterns can be programmed in a chemically minimal system and provide the basis for exploration of emergent organization and higher order complexity in active colloids.</description>
      <author>Yutong Liu, R. Kailasham, Pepijn G. Moerman, Aditya S. Khair, Lauren D. Zarzar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-15zsd</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Permeable Rubbery Thin Film Composite Membranes for CO2 Capture from Steel Mills</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2349470</link>
      <description>Lingxiang Zhu, Thien Tran, Fangming Xiang, Victor A. Kusuma, Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Grigorios Panagakos, Neil Pergar, Brenda Petrilena, David Hopkinson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397020614

                This presentation will report the rational design and fabrication of NETL's highly permeable non-aging thin film composite (TFC) membranes for CO2 capture from various industrial point sources. This talk will also cover the design, computational fluid dynamic simulation, 3D printing, and permeation testing of plate-and-frame membrane modules for an upcoming field demonstration at U. S. Steel's Edgar Thomson Plant in Braddock, PA. The field test will demonstrate membrane-based CO2 capture from a blast furnace for decarbonization of steel manufacturing for the first time in the U.S. A mobile gas permeation test unit is currently under design and construction for the field test, which is scheduled to take place in 2025.</description>
      <author>Lingxiang Zhu, Thien Tran, Fangming Xiang, Victor A. Kusuma, Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Grigorios Panagakos, Neil Pergar, Brenda Petrilena, David Hopkinson</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2349470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1015545: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/cc132rjg</link>
      <description>Kamalkishore Pati, Gabriel Gomes, Trevor Harris, Audrey Hughes, Hoa Phan, Tanmay Banerjee, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin, No host. None(None)] 2015. https://openalex.org/W4397063541

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Kamalkishore Pati, Gabriel Gomes, Trevor Harris, Audrey Hughes, Hoa Phan, Tanmay Banerjee, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/cc132rjg</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1013214: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/cc130bbs</link>
      <description>Kamalkishore Pati, Gabriel Gomes, Trevor Harris, Audrey Hughes, Hoa Phan, Tanmay Banerjee, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin, No host. None(None)] 2015. https://openalex.org/W4397105919

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Kamalkishore Pati, Gabriel Gomes, Trevor Harris, Audrey Hughes, Hoa Phan, Tanmay Banerjee, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/cc130bbs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1013212: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/cc130b8q</link>
      <description>Kamalkishore Pati, Gabriel Gomes, Trevor Harris, Audrey Hughes, Hoa Phan, Tanmay Banerjee, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin, No host. None(None)] 2015. https://openalex.org/W4397108799

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Kamalkishore Pati, Gabriel Gomes, Trevor Harris, Audrey Hughes, Hoa Phan, Tanmay Banerjee, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/cc130b8q</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1059113: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/cc14k2yq</link>
      <description>Kamalkishore Pati, Christopher Michas, David Allenger, Ilya Piskun, Peter S. Coutros, Gabriel Gomes, Igor V. Alabugin, No host. None(None)] 2015. https://openalex.org/W4397182666

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Kamalkishore Pati, Christopher Michas, David Allenger, Ilya Piskun, Peter S. Coutros, Gabriel Gomes, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/cc14k2yq</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1013215: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/cc130bct</link>
      <description>Kamalkishore Pati, Gabriel Gomes, Trevor Harris, Audrey Hughes, Hoa Phan, Tanmay Banerjee, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin, No host. None(None)] 2015. https://openalex.org/W4397214700

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Kamalkishore Pati, Gabriel Gomes, Trevor Harris, Audrey Hughes, Hoa Phan, Tanmay Banerjee, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/cc130bct</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1498362: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1m958c</link>
      <description>Ellen E. Berry, Gabriel Gomes, Alex MacLean, Justin R. Martin, Paul A. Wiget, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2016. https://openalex.org/W4397414928

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Ellen E. Berry, Gabriel Gomes, Alex MacLean, Justin R. Martin, Paul A. Wiget</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1m958c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1498591: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1m9dnz</link>
      <description>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Ronald J. Clark, Igor V. Alabugin, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2016. https://openalex.org/W4397438581

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Ronald J. Clark, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1m9dnz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1503346: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1mgc1h</link>
      <description>Satoshi Umezu, Gabriel Gomes, Tatsuro Yoshinaga, Mikei Sakae, Kenji Matsumoto, Takayuki Iwata, Igor V. Alabugin, Mitsuru Shindo, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2017. https://openalex.org/W4397308426

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Satoshi Umezu, Gabriel Gomes, Tatsuro Yoshinaga, Mikei Sakae, Kenji Matsumoto, Takayuki Iwata, Igor V. Alabugin, Mitsuru Shindo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1mgc1h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1561093: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1pdfvc</link>
      <description>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Suliman Ayad, Ronald J. Clark, Vladislav V. Lobodin, Megan Tuscan, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2017. https://openalex.org/W4397334097

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Suliman Ayad, Ronald J. Clark, Vladislav V. Lobodin, Megan Tuscan, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1pdfvc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1499579: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1mbfjx</link>
      <description>Gabriel Gomes, Ivan A. Yaremenko, Peter S. Radulov, &#1056;&#1086;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085; &#1040;. &#1053;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1042;&#1083;&#1072;&#1076;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088; &#1042;. &#1063;&#1077;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1096;&#1077;&#1074;, Alexander A. Korlyukov, G. I. Nikishin, Igor V. Alabugin, Alexander O. Terent&#8217;ev, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2017. https://openalex.org/W4397439923

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Gabriel Gomes, Ivan A. Yaremenko, Peter S. Radulov, &#1056;&#1086;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085; &#1040;. &#1053;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1042;&#1083;&#1072;&#1076;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088; &#1042;. &#1063;&#1077;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1096;&#1077;&#1074;, Alexander A. Korlyukov, G. I. Nikishin, Igor V. Alabugin, Alexander O. Terent&#8217;ev</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1mbfjx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1561092: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1pdftb</link>
      <description>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Suliman Ayad, Ronald J. Clark, Vladislav V. Lobodin, Megan Tuscan, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2017. https://openalex.org/W4397494117

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Suliman Ayad, Ronald J. Clark, Vladislav V. Lobodin, Megan Tuscan, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1pdftb</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1561088: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1pdfp6</link>
      <description>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Suliman Ayad, Ronald J. Clark, Vladislav V. Lobodin, Megan Tuscan, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2017. https://openalex.org/W4397510025

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Suliman Ayad, Ronald J. Clark, Vladislav V. Lobodin, Megan Tuscan, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1pdfp6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1561089: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1pdfq7</link>
      <description>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Suliman Ayad, Ronald J. Clark, Vladislav V. Lobodin, Megan Tuscan, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2017. https://openalex.org/W4397538196

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Trevor Harris, Gabriel Gomes, Suliman Ayad, Ronald J. Clark, Vladislav V. Lobodin, Megan Tuscan, Kenneth Hanson, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1pdfq7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1586928: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1q8b7k</link>
      <description>Vera A. Vil&#8217;, Gabriel Gomes, Oleg V. Bityukov, Konstantin &#1040;. Lyssenko, G. I. Nikishin, Igor V. Alabugin, Alexander O. Terent&#8217;ev, No host. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4397309570

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Vera A. Vil&#8217;, Gabriel Gomes, Oleg V. Bityukov, Konstantin &#1040;. Lyssenko, G. I. Nikishin, Igor V. Alabugin, Alexander O. Terent&#8217;ev</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1q8b7k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1589392: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1qbwqn</link>
      <description>Nikolay P. Tsvetkov, Edgar Gonz&#225;lez-Rodr&#237;guez, Audrey Hughes, Gabriel Gomes, Frankie D. White, Febin Kuriakose, Igor V. Alabugin, No host. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4397328850

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Nikolay P. Tsvetkov, Edgar Gonz&#225;lez-Rodr&#237;guez, Audrey Hughes, Gabriel Gomes, Frankie D. White, Febin Kuriakose, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1qbwqn</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1815296: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1yxyyr</link>
      <description>Ivan A. Yaremenko, Gabriel Gomes, Peter S. Radulov, Yulia Yu. Belyakova, Anatoliy E. Vilikotskiy, Vera A. Vil&#8217;, Alexander A. Korlyukov, G. I. Nikishin, Igor V. Alabugin, Alexander O. Terent&#8217;ev, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4397338147

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Ivan A. Yaremenko, Gabriel Gomes, Peter S. Radulov, Yulia Yu. Belyakova, Anatoliy E. Vilikotskiy, Vera A. Vil&#8217;, Alexander A. Korlyukov, G. I. Nikishin, Igor V. Alabugin, Alexander O. Terent&#8217;ev</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1yxyyr</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1586927: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1q8b6j</link>
      <description>Vera A. Vil&#8217;, Gabriel Gomes, Oleg V. Bityukov, Konstantin &#1040;. Lyssenko, G. I. Nikishin, Igor V. Alabugin, Alexander O. Terent&#8217;ev, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4397478300

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Vera A. Vil&#8217;, Gabriel Gomes, Oleg V. Bityukov, Konstantin &#1040;. Lyssenko, G. I. Nikishin, Igor V. Alabugin, Alexander O. Terent&#8217;ev</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1q8b6j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1589391: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1qbwpm</link>
      <description>Nikolay P. Tsvetkov, Edgar Gonz&#225;lez-Rodr&#237;guez, Audrey Hughes, Gabriel Gomes, Frankie D. White, Febin Kuriakose, Igor V. Alabugin, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4397491972

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Nikolay P. Tsvetkov, Edgar Gonz&#225;lez-Rodr&#237;guez, Audrey Hughes, Gabriel Gomes, Frankie D. White, Febin Kuriakose, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1qbwpm</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1589393: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1qbwrp</link>
      <description>Nikolay P. Tsvetkov, Edgar Gonz&#225;lez-Rodr&#237;guez, Audrey Hughes, Gabriel Gomes, Frankie D. White, Febin Kuriakose, Igor V. Alabugin, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4397526044

                An entry from the Cambridge Structural Database, the world&#8217;s repository for small molecule crystal structures. The entry contains experimental data from a crystal diffraction study. The deposited dataset for this entry is freely available from the CCDC and typically includes 3D coordinates, cell parameters, space group, experimental conditions and quality measures.</description>
      <author>Nikolay P. Tsvetkov, Edgar Gonz&#225;lez-Rodr&#237;guez, Audrey Hughes, Gabriel Gomes, Frankie D. White, Febin Kuriakose, Igor V. Alabugin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc1qbwrp</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCDC 1906780: Experimental Crystal Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc22051b</link>
      <description>Robert E. Lee, Bryan S. Bashrum, Ethan C. Cagle, Jillian Walters, Jake Massey, Monica Zanghi, Carolyn Birchfield, David N. French, Jessica Joy, Gabriel Gomes, Paul A. Wiget, The Cambridge Structural Database. None(None)] 2019. https://openalex.org/W4397827307

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Robert E. Lee, Bryan S. Bashrum, Ethan C. Cagle, Jillian Walters, Jake Massey, Monica Zanghi, Carolyn Birchfield, David N. French, Jessica Joy, Gabriel Gomes, Paul A. Wiget</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5517/ccdc.csd.cc22051b</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
