<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 01:25:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>DDEL-01. ENGINEERING MRNA THERAPIES FOR BRAIN TUMORS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/neuonc/noae165.0468</link>
      <description>Saigopalakrishna S. Yerneni, Juliana H. Azambuja, Daria Strelkova-Petersen, Brendan R. Gallagher, Julie Shin Kim, Namit Chaudhary, Yongxin Zhao, Peter C. Lucas, Linda M. McAllister&#8208;Lucas, Norbert Pardi, Drew Weissman, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Neuro-Oncology. 26(Supplement_8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404237621

                Abstract Safe delivery of mRNA to the brain will revolutionize the treatment of brain tumors. While lipid nanoparticles (LNPs) are clinically most advanced non-viral delivery vehicles for therapeutic mRNA, LNP-mediated mRNA delivery to the brain remains challenging. We hypothesized that rationally designed LNPs based on extracellular vesicle mimicry would enable efficient delivery of RNA therapeutics to brain cells without undue toxicity. We engineered LNPs consisting of four components similar to the formulation used in the mRNA COVID-19 vaccines (Moderna and Pfizer-BioNTech): ionizable lipid, cholesterol, helper lipid and polyethylene glycol (PEG)-lipid. We screened ten classes of helper lipids based on lipids enriched in extracellular vesicles to engineer biomimetic LNPs and tested their GFP mRNA delivery efficacy in SIM-A9 mouse microglia cell line. Several unique LNP formulations with potent delivery efficacy (&amp;gt;90% cells transfected) and stable GFP expression kinetics (5 days) were identified. LNP formulations with high transfection efficacy were then tested in vivo for luciferase mRNA delivery via intrathecal injection in C57BL/6 mice. Luciferase expression in vivo confirmed widespread mRNA delivery in the brain. We then tested Cre recombinase mRNA delivery in Ai9 mouse to identify LNP-targeted cells via flow cytometry and histology. Flow cytometry and expansion microscopy confirmed Cre recombinase mRNA delivery to a variety of brain cells, including microglia (75-90%), neurons (31-40%), neural stem cells (39-62%), oligodendrocytes (70-90%), and astrocytes (44-76%). LNPs were further evaluated for Cas9 mRNA and CD81 sgRNA delivery in C57BL/6 mouse brains to assess brain-targeted gene editing. Sanger sequencing showed that CRISPR-Cas9 editing was successful in ~40% of cells in the mouse brain. In summary, we engineered extracellular vesicle-based LNP library that can deliver RNA therapeutics to a variety of brain cells in vivo. With further development, this technology could potentially enable genetic and epigenetic therapies targeting drivers of brain tumors.</description>
      <author>Saigopalakrishna S. Yerneni, Juliana H. Azambuja, Daria Strelkova-Petersen, Brendan R. Gallagher, Julie Shin Kim, Namit Chaudhary, Yongxin Zhao, Peter C. Lucas, Linda M. McAllister&#8208;Lucas, Norbert Pardi, Drew Weissman, Kathryn A. Whitehead</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/neuonc/noae165.0468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of hollow fiber membrane packing on the performance of modules formed with fiber tows</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/01496395.2024.2424953</link>
      <description>Lili Sun, Grigorios Panagakos, G. Glenn Lipscomb, Separation Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404278345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lili Sun, Grigorios Panagakos, G. Glenn Lipscomb</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/01496395.2024.2424953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techno-Economic Optimization of a Solvent Absorption Process for CO2 Capture with 3D-Printed Intensified Packing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2476529</link>
      <description>Stephen Summits, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404301555

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stephen Summits, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2476529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Algebraic and Topological-Based Structured Packing Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2476526</link>
      <description>Stephen Summits, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404328019

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stephen Summits, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2476526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative study of machine learning techniques for post-combustion carbon capture systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/frai.2024.1441934</link>
      <description>Yeping Hu, Bo Lei, Yash Girish Shah, Jos&#233; Cadena, Amar Saini, Grigorios Panagakos, Phan Nguyen, Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence. 7(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404387131

                Computational analysis of countercurrent flows in packed absorption columns, often used in solvent-based post-combustion carbon capture systems (CCSs), is challenging. Typically, computational fluid dynamics (CFD) approaches are used to simulate the interactions between a solvent, gas, and column's packing geometry while accounting for the thermodynamics, kinetics, heat, and mass transfer effects of the absorption process. These simulations can then be used explain a column's hydrodynamic characteristics and evaluate its CO 2 -capture efficiency. However, these approaches are computationally expensive, making it difficult to evaluate numerous designs and operating conditions to improve efficiency at industrial scales. In this work, we comprehensively explore the application of statistical ML methods, convolutional neural networks (CNNs), and graph neural networks (GNNs) to aid and accelerate the scale-up and design optimization of solvent-based post-combustion CCSs. We apply these methods to CFD datasets of countercurrent flows in absorption columns with structured packings characterized by several geometric parameters. We train models to use these parameters, inlet velocity conditions, and other model-specific representations of the column to estimate key determinants of CO 2 -capture efficiency without having to simulate additional CFD datasets. We also evaluate the impact of different input types on the accuracy and generalizability of each model. We discuss the strengths and limitations of each approach to further elucidate the role of CNNs, GNNs, and other machine learning approaches for CO 2 -capture property prediction and design optimization.</description>
      <author>Yeping Hu, Bo Lei, Yash Girish Shah, Jos&#233; Cadena, Amar Saini, Grigorios Panagakos, Phan Nguyen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/frai.2024.1441934</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The trust region filter strategy: Survey of a rigorous approach for optimization with surrogate models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2024.100197</link>
      <description>Lorenz T. Biegler, Digital Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404387629

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2024.100197</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
