<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 01:27:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>New particle formation from isoprene under upper-tropospheric conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-024-08196-0</link>
      <description>Jiali Shen, Douglas M. Russell, Jenna DeVivo, Felix Kunkler, Rima Baalbaki, Bernhard Mentler, Wiebke Scholz, Wenjuan Yu, Luc&#237;a Caudillo-Plath, Eva Sommer, Emelda Ahongshangbam, Dina Alfaouri, J. Almeida, A. Amorim, Lisa Beck, H. Beckmann, Moritz Berntheusel, Nirvan Bhattacharyya, Manjula R. Canagaratna, Anouck Chassaing, Romulo Cruz-Simbron, Lubna Dada, Jonathan Duplissy, Hamish Gordon, Manuel Granzin, Lena Gro&#223;e Schute, Martin Heinritzi, Siddharth Iyer, Hannah Klebach, Thinus F. Kruger, Andreas K&#252;rten, Markus Lampim&#228;ki, Lu Liu, Brandon Lopez, M&#243;nica Mart&#237;nez, Aleksandra Morawiec, Antti Onnela, Maija Peltola, Pedro Rato, Mago Reza, Sarah Richter, Birte R&#246;rup, Milin Kaniyodical Sebastian, Mario Simon, Mihnea Surdu, Kalju Tamme, Roseline C. Thakur, Ant&#243;nio Tom&#233;, Yandong Tong, Jens Top, Nsikanabasi Silas Umo, Gabriela Rosalino Unfer, Lejish Vettikkat, Jakob Weissbacher, Christos Xenofontos, Boxing Yang, Marcel Zauner-Wieczorek, Jiangyi Zhang, Zhensen Zheng, Urs Baltensperger, T. Christoudias, Richard C. Flagan, Imad El Haddad, Heikki Junninen, Ottmar M&#246;hler, Ilona Riipinen, Urs Rohner, Siegfried Schobesberger, Rainer Volkamer, Paul M. Winkler, Armin Hansel, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Neil M. Donahue, Jos Lelieveld, Hartwig Harder, Markku Kulmala, Douglas R. Worsnop, J. Kirkby, Joachim Curtius, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Nature. 636(8041)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405030774

                Abstract Aircraft observations have revealed ubiquitous new particle formation in the tropical upper troposphere over the Amazon 1,2 and the Atlantic and Pacific oceans 3,4 . Although the vapours involved remain unknown, recent satellite observations have revealed surprisingly high night-time isoprene mixing ratios of up to 1 part per billion by volume (ppbv) in the tropical upper troposphere 5 . Here, in experiments performed with the CERN CLOUD (Cosmics Leaving Outdoor Droplets) chamber, we report new particle formation initiated by the reaction of hydroxyl radicals with isoprene at upper-tropospheric temperatures of &#8722;30 &#176;C and &#8722;50 &#176;C. We find that isoprene-oxygenated organic molecules (IP-OOM) nucleate at concentrations found in the upper troposphere, without requiring any more vapours. Moreover, the nucleation rates are enhanced 100-fold by extremely low concentrations of sulfuric acid or iodine oxoacids above 10 5 cm &#8722;3 , reaching rates around 30 cm &#8722;3 s &#8722;1 at acid concentrations of 10 6 cm &#8722;3 . Our measurements show that nucleation involves sequential addition of IP-OOM, together with zero or one acid molecule in the embryonic molecular clusters. IP-OOM also drive rapid particle growth at 3&#8211;60 nm h &#8722;1 . We find that rapid nucleation and growth rates persist in the presence of NO x at upper-tropospheric concentrations from lightning. Our laboratory measurements show that isoprene emitted by rainforests may drive rapid new particle formation in extensive regions of the tropical upper troposphere 1,2 , resulting in tens of thousands of particles per cubic centimetre.</description>
      <author>Jiali Shen, Douglas M. Russell, Jenna DeVivo, Felix Kunkler, Rima Baalbaki, Bernhard Mentler, Wiebke Scholz, Wenjuan Yu, Luc&#237;a Caudillo-Plath, Eva Sommer, Emelda Ahongshangbam, Dina Alfaouri, J. Almeida, A. Amorim, Lisa Beck, H. Beckmann, Moritz Berntheusel, Nirvan Bhattacharyya, Manjula R. Canagaratna, Anouck Chassaing, Romulo Cruz-Simbron, Lubna Dada, Jonathan Duplissy, Hamish Gordon, Manuel Granzin, Lena Gro&#223;e Schute, Martin Heinritzi, Siddharth Iyer, Hannah Klebach, Thinus F. Kruger, Andreas K&#252;rten, Markus Lampim&#228;ki, Lu Liu, Brandon Lopez, M&#243;nica Mart&#237;nez, Aleksandra Morawiec, Antti Onnela, Maija Peltola, Pedro Rato, Mago Reza, Sarah Richter, Birte R&#246;rup, Milin Kaniyodical Sebastian, Mario Simon, Mihnea Surdu, Kalju Tamme, Roseline C. Thakur, Ant&#243;nio Tom&#233;, Yandong Tong, Jens Top, Nsikanabasi Silas Umo, Gabriela Rosalino Unfer, Lejish Vettikkat, Jakob Weissbacher, Christos Xenofontos, Boxing Yang, Marcel Zauner-Wieczorek, Jiangyi Zhang, Zhensen Zheng, Urs Baltensperger, T. Christoudias, Richard C. Flagan, Imad El Haddad, Heikki Junninen, Ottmar M&#246;hler, Ilona Riipinen, Urs Rohner, Siegfried Schobesberger, Rainer Volkamer, Paul M. Winkler, Armin Hansel, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Neil M. Donahue, Jos Lelieveld, Hartwig Harder, Markku Kulmala, Douglas R. Worsnop, J. Kirkby, Joachim Curtius, Xu&#8208;Cheng He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-024-08196-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parapint</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.11578/dc.20201109.2</link>
      <description>Michael Bynum, Carl D. Laird, Bethany L. Nicholson, Denis Rizdal, OSTI OAI (U.S. Department of Energy Office of Scientific and Technical Information). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4405168317

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Michael Bynum, Carl D. Laird, Bethany L. Nicholson, Denis Rizdal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.11578/dc.20201109.2</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
