<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 01:19:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Supplementary material to "Gas-phase Observations of Accretion Products from Stabilized Criegee Intermediates in Terpene Ozonolysis with Two Dicarboxylic Acids"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3323-supplement</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Luo, Lauri Franzon, Jiangyi Zhang, Nina Sarnela, Neil M. Donahue, Theo Kurt&#233;n, Mikael Ehn, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403841243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Luo, Lauri Franzon, Jiangyi Zhang, Nina Sarnela, Neil M. Donahue, Theo Kurt&#233;n, Mikael Ehn</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3323-supplement</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas-phase Observations of Accretion Products from Stabilized Criegee Intermediates in Terpene Ozonolysis with Two Dicarboxylic Acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3323</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Luo, Lauri Franzon, Jiangyi Zhang, Nina Sarnela, Neil M. Donahue, Theo Kurt&#233;n, Mikael Ehn, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403841337

                Abstract. Criegee intermediates (CIs), forming from the ozonolysis of alkenes, are highly reactive species with diverse reaction pathways, with important roles in atmospheric chemistry. This study focuses on the formation of accretion products through reactions of thermally stabilized CIs (sCIs) from the ozonolysis of three different terpenes (&#945;-pinene, &#946;-pinene, and &#946;-caryophyllene) with malonic and oxalic acids. Our experimental results demonstrate that these reactions efficiently produce the expected accretion products, though with apparent variations in yields depending on the specific terpene and acid involved. To our knowledge, these are the first direct gas-phase observations of expected adducts from terpene-derived sCIs and carboxylic acids, paving the way for a better understanding of the importance and atmospheric implications of these reactions, especially in terms of aerosol-forming capabilities of these large product molecules.</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Luo, Lauri Franzon, Jiangyi Zhang, Nina Sarnela, Neil M. Donahue, Theo Kurt&#233;n, Mikael Ehn</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Analysis of the Effect of Structured Packing Design on Absorption Column Hydrodynamics for Post-Combustion Carbon Capture Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2474815</link>
      <description>Yash Shah, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403902920

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yash Shah, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2474815</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling and Scaling up of Membrane Modules Leveraging Dimensional Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2474814</link>
      <description>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403903104

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2474814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enumeration of surface site nuclearity and shape in a database of intermetallic low-index surface facets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115795</link>
      <description>Unnatti Sharma, A.L. Nguyen, John R. Kitchin, Zachary W. Ulissi, Michael J. Janik, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403909596

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Unnatti Sharma, A.L. Nguyen, John R. Kitchin, Zachary W. Ulissi, Michael J. Janik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distillation Column Optimization: A formal method using stage-to stage computations and distributed streams</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120875</link>
      <description>Tobias Seidel, Lorenz T. Biegler, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403915426

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tobias Seidel, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Numerical Energy Hessians with Graph Neural Network Potentials
  and Their Application in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.01650</link>
      <description>Brook Wander, Joseph Musielewicz, Raffaele Cheula, John R. Kitchin, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403928590

                Access to the potential energy Hessian enables determination of the Gibbs free energy, and certain approaches to transition state search and optimization. Here, we demonstrate that off-the-shelf pretrained Open Catalyst Project (OCP) machine learned potentials (MLPs) determine the Hessian with great success (58 cm$^{-1}$ mean absolute error (MAE)) for intermediates adsorbed to heterogeneous catalyst surfaces. This enables the use of OCP models for the aforementioned applications. The top performing model, with a simple offset correction, gives good estimations of the vibrational entropy contribution to the Gibbs free energy with an MAE of 0.042 eV at 300 K. The ability to leverage models to capture the translational entropy was also explored. It was determined that 94% of randomly sampled systems had a translational entropy greater than 0.1 eV at 300 K. This underscores the need to go beyond the harmonic approximation to consider the entropy introduced by adsorbate translation, which increases with temperature. Lastly, we used MLP determined Hessian information for transition state search and found we were able to reduce the number of unconverged systems by 65% to 93% overall convergence, improving on the baseline established by CatTSunami.</description>
      <author>Brook Wander, Joseph Musielewicz, Raffaele Cheula, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.01650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Permeable Rubbery Thin Film Composite Membranes for CO2 Capture from Steel Mills</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2475058</link>
      <description>Lingxiang Zhu, Thien Tran, Fangming Xiang, Victor A. Kusuma, Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Grigorios Panagakos, Neil Pergar, Brenda Petrilena, David Hopkinson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403930057

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingxiang Zhu, Thien Tran, Fangming Xiang, Victor A. Kusuma, Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Grigorios Panagakos, Neil Pergar, Brenda Petrilena, David Hopkinson</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2475058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CFD modeling of high-flux plate-and-frame membrane modules for industrial carbon capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2475060</link>
      <description>Cheick Dosso, Grigorios Panagakos, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Lorenz T. Biegler, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403930073

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheick Dosso, Grigorios Panagakos, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2475060</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
