<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 01:38:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming the Central Line&#8211;Associated Bloodstream Infection Plateau through Proactive Safety Methodologies: A Quality Improvement Project</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1097/pq9.0000000000000838</link>
      <description>Christine Marigliano, Sharon Goodman, James Schneider, Charlotte Smith, Brianna Concannon, Aidan Doona, Julia Vitucci, Lorry G. Rubin, Lawrence C. Wolfe, Raymond Festa, Elan Itschakov, Robert Koppel, Donna Baranek, L. Jendresky, Anupama Subramony, Pediatric Quality and Safety. 10(S1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413901169

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Christine Marigliano, Sharon Goodman, James Schneider, Charlotte Smith, Brianna Concannon, Aidan Doona, Julia Vitucci, Lorry G. Rubin, Lawrence C. Wolfe, Raymond Festa, Elan Itschakov, Robert Koppel, Donna Baranek, L. Jendresky, Anupama Subramony</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1097/pq9.0000000000000838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain decomposition preconditioners for Schur complement systems arising in structured nonlinear optimization problems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11081-025-10020-1</link>
      <description>Laurens R. Lueg, Michael Bynum, Carl D. Laird, Lorenz T. Biegler, Optimization and Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413932515

                Abstract Large-scale nonlinear, nonconvex optimization problems arise in many relevant engineering applications, such as integrated energy systems, public health, or supply-chain logistics. Their solution is often challenging due to problem scale, significant spatio-temporal interactions, or time constraints (e.g. for real-time operations). This work focuses on decomposition strategies for nonlinear problems with distributed structure, where interactions between problem partitions can be defined over sparse graphs. Parallelization is achieved on the linear algebra level within an interior point algorithm using the Schur complement method, and we propose several distributed algebraic preconditioners for the Schur complement system, based on approaches from the field of domain decomposition. We demonstrate promising strong scaling results on large-scale problem instances for parameter estimation of infectious disease models and PDE-constrained optimal control.</description>
      <author>Laurens R. Lueg, Michael Bynum, Carl D. Laird, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11081-025-10020-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weak influence of anthropogenic emissions on aerosol, cloud, and rain in the wet season of the Amazon rainforest</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-9685-2025</link>
      <description>Xuemei Wang, K. S. Carslaw, Daniel P. Grosvenor, Hamish Gordon, Atmospheric chemistry and physics. 25(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413961345

                Abstract. Anthropogenic emissions have been shown to affect new particle formation, aerosol concentrations, and clouds. Such effects vary with region, environmental conditions, and cloud types. In the wet season of Amazonia, anthropogenic emissions emitted from Manaus, Brazil, can significantly increase the cloud condensation nuclei (CCN) concentrations compared to the background of mainly natural aerosols. However, the regional response of cloud and rain to anthropogenic emissions in Amazonia remains very uncertain. Here, we aim to quantify how aerosol concentration, cloud, and rain respond to changes in anthropogenic emissions through parameterized new particle formation and primary aerosol emission in the Manaus region and to understand the underlying mechanisms. We ran the atmosphere-only configuration of the HadGEM3 climate model with a nested regional domain that covers most of the rainforest region (720 km by 1200 km with 3 km resolution) under scaled regional emissions. The 7 d simulations show that, in the areas that are affected by anthropogenic emissions, when aerosol and precursor gas emissions are doubled from the baseline emission inventories, aerosol number concentrations increase by 13 %. The nucleation rate that involves sulfuric acid and biogenic compounds generally increases with pollution levels. However, nucleation is suppressed very close to the pollution source, resulting in lower nucleation and soluble Aitken mode aerosol number concentrations. We also found that doubling the anthropogenic emission can increase the cloud droplet number concentrations (Nd) by 9 %, but cloud water and rain mass mixing ratios do not change significantly. Even very strong reductions in aerosol number concentrations by a factor of 4, which is an unrealistic condition, cause only a 4 % increase in rain over the domain. If we assume our simulation has a fine enough grid resolution and an accurate representation of the relevant atmospheric processes, the simulated weak and non-linear response of cloud and rain properties to linearly scaled anthropogenic emissions suggests that the interactions among aerosol, cloud, and precipitation in the Amazonian convective environment are buffered by microphysical processes. It also implies that the convective environment is resilient to the changes in Nd that occur in response to localized anthropogenic aerosol perturbations.</description>
      <author>Xuemei Wang, K. S. Carslaw, Daniel P. Grosvenor, Hamish Gordon</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-9685-2025</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
