<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 01:18:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>The influence of active agent motility on SIRS epidemiological dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sm00864b</link>
      <description>R. Kailasham, Aditya S. Khair, Soft Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404040132

                Active Brownian disks moving in two dimensions that exchange information about their internal state stochastically are chosen to model epidemic spread in a self-propelled population of agents under the susceptible-infected-recovered-susceptible...</description>
      <author>R. Kailasham, Aditya S. Khair</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sm00864b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perioperative Considerations in Patients with Rett Syndrome as Compared to Those with Cerebral Palsy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1097/brs.0000000000005210</link>
      <description>Vishal Sarwahi, Effat Rahman, Katherine Eigo, Jesse Galina, Sayyida Hasan, Andrew L. Ko, Yungtai Lo, Terry Amaral, Aleksandra Djukic, Maria Santiago, James Schneider, Spine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404093102

                Study Design. Retrospective cohort study Objective. This study aimed to compare perioperative outcomes of Rett syndrome and Cerebral palsy patients undergoing posterior spinal fusion for neuromuscular scoliosis. Summary of Background Data. Surgical correction in the treatment of scoliosis for patients with Rett syndrome (RS) has been shown to increase survival rate. Cerebral palsy (CP) patients, like RS patients, are often nonverbal, nonambulatory, with frequent surgical complications. Methods. Retrospective review of 36 RS and 80 CP patients undergoing PSF from 2005-2023. Data and x-ray measurements were collected pre- and post-operatively. Sub-analysis was performed comparing non-ambulatory patients (GMFCS IV-V). Wilcoxon-Rank Sum, Fisher&#8217;s Exact, and Chi-square tests were utilized. Results. The primary outcome measure, complication rates, was similar between the groups ( P =0.09). Preoperative Cobb angle, levels fused, fixation points, and LOS were similar ( P &gt;0.05). EBL was significantly higher in CP patients as was rate of transfusion ( P =0.001) and surgical time ( P =0.001). Postoperative Cobb angle ( P =0.002) was significantly higher for CP patients. There was no significant difference between CP and RS patients in both preoperative ( P =0.383) and postoperative ( P =0.051) coronal decompensation. Nonambulatory status was associated with increased odds of having a postoperative complication (OR=6.17, 95% C.I. 1.36 &#8211; 28.04). Sub-analysis of non-ambulatory RS and CP patients revealed significantly higher postoperative Cobb ( P =0.008), EBL ( P =0.019) and surgical time ( P =0.017) in CP patients compared to RS patients. There were no significant differences in preoperative Cobb, levels fused, fixation points, hospital stay, or complication rate ( P &gt;0.05). Conclusion. RS patients are shown to have better outcomes to CP patients in terms of surgical, perioperative, and radiographic variables. Ambulatory status was identified as an independent risk factor for complications.</description>
      <author>Vishal Sarwahi, Effat Rahman, Katherine Eigo, Jesse Galina, Sayyida Hasan, Andrew L. Ko, Yungtai Lo, Terry Amaral, Aleksandra Djukic, Maria Santiago, James Schneider</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1097/brs.0000000000005210</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Forest Planning: Balancing Timber Production and Carbon Sequestration Through a Multi-Objective Disjunctive Formulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5013129</link>
      <description>Frank Piedra-Jim&#233;nez, Diego Broz, Juan M. Novas, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Mar&#237;a Anal&#237;a Rodr&#237;guez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404140095

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Frank Piedra-Jim&#233;nez, Diego Broz, Juan M. Novas, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Mar&#237;a Anal&#237;a Rodr&#237;guez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5013129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MINLP: Outer Approximation Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_385-1</link>
      <description>Ignacio E. Grossmann, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404142930

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_385-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Optimization of Heat Exchanger Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_235-1</link>
      <description>Juan M. Zamora, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404144322

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juan M. Zamora, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_235-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process systems engineering enables efficient and sustainable membrane-based critical material separations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2476222</link>
      <description>Molly Dougher, Jason Yao, Andrew Lee, Laurianne Lair, Jonathan Aubuchon Ouimet, William A. Phillip, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, Alexander W. Dowling, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404169299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Molly Dougher, Jason Yao, Andrew Lee, Laurianne Lair, Jonathan Aubuchon Ouimet, William A. Phillip, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, Alexander W. Dowling</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2476222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel mixed-integer linear programming formulation for continuous-time inventory routing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cor.2024.106883</link>
      <description>Akang Wang, Xiandong Li, Jeffrey E. Arbogast, Zachary Wilson, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, Computers &amp; Operations Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404211800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akang Wang, Xiandong Li, Jeffrey E. Arbogast, Zachary Wilson, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cor.2024.106883</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
