<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 01:46:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>FOLR1-Targeted Oxygen-Delivering Nanosomes Enhance Chemo-Induced Apoptosis in Hypoxic Cancer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2147/ijn.s513688</link>
      <description>Gahyun Lee, Jiwon Kim, J. Yang, Yoon Jung Jang, Jaehee Jang, Masayoshi Tanaka, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Heeyoung Lee, Jonghoon Choi, International Journal of Nanomedicine. Volume 20(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410829045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gahyun Lee, Jiwon Kim, J. Yang, Yoon Jung Jang, Jaehee Jang, Masayoshi Tanaka, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Heeyoung Lee, Jonghoon Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2147/ijn.s513688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Strategies for RTN Model for Supply Logistics of Carbon Dioxide for Carbon Capture and Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.5c00695</link>
      <description>Soumya Shikha, Joelle Guisso, Anna Robert, Nouha Dkhili, Parveen Kumar, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410863166

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soumya Shikha, Joelle Guisso, Anna Robert, Nouha Dkhili, Parveen Kumar, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.5c00695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Level Direct Currents Eradicate Multi-Drug-Resistant Candida Auris Through Physiological Stress and Antifungal Permeation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5271751</link>
      <description>C. Royo, Charles Landis, Michael T. Geraghty, Sricharani Rao Balmuri, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410884177

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C. Royo, Charles Landis, Michael T. Geraghty, Sricharani Rao Balmuri, Tagbo H. R. Niepa</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5271751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Computational Investigation of High-Flux, Plate-and-Frame Membrane Modules for Industrial Carbon Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100246</link>
      <description>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, Digital Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410893830

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovations in chemical process control: challenges and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101148</link>
      <description>Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian, Helen Durand, Joel A. Paulson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Current Opinion in Chemical Engineering. 48(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410907732

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian, Helen Durand, Joel A. Paulson, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101148</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
