<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 01:45:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Long&#8208;Read, High&#8208;Resolution Sanger Sequencing by Micelle&#8208;Tagging Electrophoresis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elps.70047</link>
      <description>R. Gamble, H. Michael Wenz, Bashar Mullah, James Schneider, Electrophoresis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415411534

                ABSTRACT We demonstrate a gel&#8208;free electrophoretic separation of Sanger sequencing fragments up to 782 bases in length using nonionic wormlike micelles as drag&#8208;tags in micelle&#8208;tagging electrophoresis (MTE). This is an increase of 280 bases over previous MTE methods and a nearly three&#8208;fold improvement over end&#8208;labeled free&#8208;solution electrophoresis (ELFSE) methods that use covalently attached drag&#8208;tags. For MTE, C18 alkane groups are attached to primers prior to their enzymatic extension. This alkane group provides a binding site for wormlike micelles composed of CiEj&#8208;type nonionic surfactants in the running buffer. Transient attachment of micelles to the C18 alkane group provides a highly uniform drag, equal to that of an ssDNA fragment 309 bases long. To account for slight mobility differences among the BigDye chain terminators, we developed a two&#8208;parameter time&#8208;shifting procedure to align the electropherograms for each termination chemistry. The increase in read length for this low&#8208;viscosity buffer (2.1 cP) is attributed to the alignment procedure, the large yet uniform drag, and the small degree of adsorption&#8208;based band broadening.</description>
      <author>R. Gamble, H. Michael Wenz, Bashar Mullah, James Schneider</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elps.70047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelica2Pyomo: a tool to translate Modelica models into Pyomo optimization models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3384/ecp218117</link>
      <description>Matteo Luigi De Pascali, Lorenz T. Biegler, Emanuele Martelli, Francesco Casella, Link&#246;ping electronic conference proceedings. 218(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415503485

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matteo Luigi De Pascali, Lorenz T. Biegler, Emanuele Martelli, Francesco Casella</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3384/ecp218117</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
