<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 01:14:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Conflict-Based Model Predictive Control for Scalable Multi-Robot Motion Planning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/icra57147.2024.10611078</link>
      <description>Ardalan Tajbakhsh, Lorenz T. Biegler, Aaron M. Johnson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401415691

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ardalan Tajbakhsh, Lorenz T. Biegler, Aaron M. Johnson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/icra57147.2024.10611078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substantial contribution of transported emissions to organic aerosol in Beijing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01493-3</link>
      <description>Kaspar R. Daellenbach, Jing Cai, Simo Hakala, Lubna Dada, Chao Yan, Wei Du, Lei Yao, Feixue Zheng, Jialiang Ma, Florian Ungeheuer, Alexander L. Vogel, Dominik Stolzenburg, Yufang Hao, Yongchun Liu, Federico Bianchi, Ga&#235;lle Uzu, Jean&#8208;Luc Jaffrezo, Douglas R. Worsnop, Neil M. Donahue, Markku Kulmala, Nature Geoscience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401428022

                Abstract Haze in Beijing is linked to atmospherically formed secondary organic aerosol, which has been shown to be particularly harmful to human health. However, the sources and formation pathways of these secondary aerosols remain largely unknown, hindering effective pollution mitigation. Here we have quantified the sources of organic aerosol via direct near-molecular observations in central Beijing. In winter, organic aerosol pollution arises mainly from fresh solid-fuel emissions and secondary organic aerosols originating from both solid-fuel combustion and aqueous processes, probably involving multiphase chemistry with aromatic compounds. The most severe haze is linked to secondary organic aerosols originating from solid-fuel combustion, transported from the Beijing&#8211;Tianjing&#8211;Hebei Plain and rural mountainous areas west of Beijing. In summer, the increased fraction of secondary organic aerosol is dominated by aromatic emissions from the Xi&#8217;an&#8211;Shanghai&#8211;Beijing region, while the contribution of biogenic emissions remains relatively small. Overall, we identify the main sources of secondary organic aerosol affecting Beijing, which clearly extend beyond the local emissions in Beijing. Our results suggest that targeting key organic precursor emission sectors regionally may be needed to effectively mitigate organic aerosol pollution.</description>
      <author>Kaspar R. Daellenbach, Jing Cai, Simo Hakala, Lubna Dada, Chao Yan, Wei Du, Lei Yao, Feixue Zheng, Jialiang Ma, Florian Ungeheuer, Alexander L. Vogel, Dominik Stolzenburg, Yufang Hao, Yongchun Liu, Federico Bianchi, Ga&#235;lle Uzu, Jean&#8208;Luc Jaffrezo, Douglas R. Worsnop, Neil M. Donahue, Markku Kulmala</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01493-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic Optimization and Impact of Utility Costs on the Optimal Design of Piperazine-Based Carbon Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.147100</link>
      <description>Ilayda Akkor, Shachit S. Iyer, John Dowdle, Sheng Wang, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401442540

                Recent advances in process design for solvent-based, post-combustion capture (PCC) processes, such as the Piperazine/Advanced Flash Stripper (PZ/AFS) process, have led to a reduction in the energy required for capture. Even though PCC processes are progressively improving in Technology Readiness Levels (TRL), with a few commercial installations, incorporating carbon capture adds cost to any operation. Hence, cost reduction will be instrumental for proliferation. The aim of this work is to improve process economics through optimization and to identify the parameters in our economic model that have the greatest impact on total cost to build and operate these systems. To that end, we investigated changes to the optimal solution and the corresponding cost of capture considering changes in the price of utilities and solvent. We found that changes in solvent price had the most effect on the cost of capture. However, re-optimizing the designs in the event of price changes did not lead to significant improvements in the case of piperazine, cooling water and electricity, whereas re-optimizing for changes in steam prices lead to yearly saving of 3.8%. These findings show that the design choices obtained at the nominal optimal solution are insensitive to utility price changes except for the case of steam and that there is a need for altered designs for locations where the steam prices are different.</description>
      <author>Ilayda Akkor, Shachit S. Iyer, John Dowdle, Sheng Wang, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.147100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NMPC for Mode-Switching Operation of Reversible Solid Oxide Cell Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.103553</link>
      <description>Mingrui Li, Douglas A. Allan, San Dinh, Lorenz T. Biegler, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Vibhav Dabadghao, Nishant Giridhar, Stephen E. Zitney, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456080

                Solid oxide cells (SOCs) are a promising dual-mode technology that generates hydrogen through high-temperature water electrolysis and generates power through a fuel cell reaction that consumes hydrogen. Reversible operation of SOCs requires a transition between these two modes for hydrogen production setpoints as the demand and price of electricity fluctuate. Moreover, a well-functioning control system is important to avoid cell degradation during mode-switching operation. In this work, we apply nonlinear model predictive control (NMPC) to an SOC module and supporting equipment and compare NMPC performance to classical proportional integral (PI) control strategies, while ramping between the modes of hydrogen and power production. While both control methods provide similar performance in many metrics, NMPC significantly reduces cell thermal gradients and curvatures (mixed spatial temporal partial derivatives) during mode switching. A dynamic process flowsheet of the reversible SOC system was developed in the open-source, equation-based IDAES modeling framework. Our IDAES dynamic simulation results show that NMPC can ramp the SOC system between hydrogen and power production targets within short mode switching times. Moreover, NMPC can comply with operating limits in the SOC system more effectively than PI, and only NMPC can directly enforce user-specified limits for mixed spatial temporal partial derivatives of temperature. This allows for management of the trade-off between operating efficiency and cell degradation, which is dependent on these temperature curvatures.</description>
      <author>Mingrui Li, Douglas A. Allan, San Dinh, Lorenz T. Biegler, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Vibhav Dabadghao, Nishant Giridhar, Stephen E. Zitney</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.103553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Design of Intensified Towers for CO2 Capture with Internal, Printed Heat Exchangers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.123118</link>
      <description>Stephen Summits, Paul Akula, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456246

                Solvent-based carbon capture processes typically suffer from the temperature rise of the solvent due to the heat of absorption of CO2. This increased temperature is not thermodynamically favorable and results in a significant reduction in performance in the absorber column. As opposed to interstage coolers, which only remove, cool, and return the solvent at discrete locations in the column, internal coolers that are integrated with the packing can cool the process inline, which can result in improved efficiency. This work presents the modeling of these internal coolers within an existing generic, equation-oriented absorber column model that can cool the process while allowing for simultaneous mass transfer. Optimization of this model is also performed, which is capable of optimally choosing the best locations to place these devices, such that heat removal and mass transfer area are balanced. Results of the optimization have shown that optimally placed cooling elements result in a significant increase in the capture efficiency of the process, compared to a similar column with no internal cooling, with a common trend being the cooling of the column in the temperature bulge region. It is observed that by optimally placing an internal cooler, the solvent flow rate can be decreased, and the CO2 lean loading can be increased while still maintaining the same efficiency. These process changes can lead to a substantial reduction in costs due to lower reboiler duty.</description>
      <author>Stephen Summits, Paul Akula, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.123118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of Processes for Recovering Rare Earth Elements from End-of-Life Hard Disk Drives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.123161</link>
      <description>Chris Laliwala, Ana I. Torres, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456327

                As the United States continues efforts to decarbonize the power and transportation sectors, significant challenges associated with the reliance of clean energy technologies on rare earth elements (REEs) will have to be overcome. One potential approach for increasing the supply of these elements is to extract REEs from end-of-life (EOL) hard disk drives (HDDs). HDDs contain neodymium and praseodymium, which are among the most important REEs for the clean energy transition, as they are crucial to producing the permanent magnets needed for wind turbines and electric vehicles. Here, we propose a superstructure-based approach to find the optimal pathway for recovering REEs from EOL HDDs. The superstructure was optimized by maximizing the net present value (NPV) over 15 years. Projected prices for commercial rare earth oxides and the projected amount of EOL HDDs in the U.S. were estimated and used in the model. These projections were used to establish the base case optimal result, assuming that the plant recycles 60% of personal computers EOL HDDs in the U.S. each year. The model was then expanded to consider the recycling of EOL HDDs generated before the beginning of plant production. Next, a sensitivity analysis was conducted to evaluate the impact of different parameters on the venture's profitability and the optimal processing pathway. Combined, these results offer both valuable insights into the economic viability of REE recycling extraction and a method for performing similar analyses in the future.</description>
      <author>Chris Laliwala, Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.123161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating the Design of Desalination Technologies into Produced Water Network Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.195308</link>
      <description>Sakshi Naik, Miguel Zamarripa, Markus Drouven, Lorenz T. Biegler, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456412

                The oil and gas energy sector uses billions of gallons of water for hydraulic fracturing each year to extract oil and gas. The water injected into the ground for fracturing along with naturally occurring formation water from the oil wells surfaces back in the form of produced water. Produced water can contain high concentrations of total dissolved solids and is unfit for reuse outside the oil and gas industry without desalination. In semi-arid shale plays, produced water desalination for beneficial reuse could play a crucial role in alleviating water shortages and addressing extreme drought conditions. In this paper we co-optimize the design and operation of desalination technologies along with operational decisions across produced water networks. A multi-period produced water network model with simplified split-fraction-based desalination nodes is developed. Rigorous steady-state desalination mathematical models based on mechanical vapor recompression are developed and embedded at the desalination sites in the network model. An optimal common design is ensured across all periods using global capacity constraints. The solution approach is demonstrated for multi-period planning problems on networks from the PARETO open-source library. Model formulation and challenges associated with scalability are discussed.</description>
      <author>Sakshi Naik, Miguel Zamarripa, Markus Drouven, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.195308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances of PyROS: A Pyomo Solver for Nonconvex Two-Stage Robust Optimization in Process Systems Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.142058</link>
      <description>Jason Sherman, Natalie M. Isenberg, John Daniel Siirola, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401457140

                In this work, we present recent algorithmic and implementation advances of the nonconvex two-stage robust optimization solver PyROS. Our advances include extensions of the scope of PyROS to models with uncertain variable bounds, improvements to the formulations and/or initializations of the various subproblems used by the underlying cutting set algorithm, and extensions to the pre-implemented uncertainty set interfaces. The effectiveness of PyROS is demonstrated through the results of an original benchmarking study on a library of over 8,500 small-scale instances, with variations in the nonlinearities, degree-of-freedom partitioning, uncertainty sets, and polynomial decision rule approximations. To demonstrate the utility of PyROS for large-scale process models, we present the results of a carbon capture case study. Overall, our results highlight the effectiveness of PyROS for obtaining robust solutions to optimization problems with uncertain equality constraints.</description>
      <author>Jason Sherman, Natalie M. Isenberg, John Daniel Siirola, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.142058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of Circular Economy Networks: A Case Study of Polyethylene Terephthalate (PET)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.154237</link>
      <description>Abdulkarim S. Ahmed, Ana I. Torres, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401458110

                Circular systems design is an emerging approach for promoting sustainable development. Despite its perceived advantages, the characterization of circular systems remains loosely defined and ambiguous. This work proposes a network optimization framework that evaluates three objective functions related to economic and environmental domains and employs a Pareto analysis to illuminate the trade-offs between objectives. The US polyethylene terephthalate (PET) value chain is selected as a case study and represented via a superstructure containing various recycling pathways. The superstructure optimization problems are modeled as a mixed integer linear program (MILP) and linear programs (LPs), implemented in Pyomo, and solved with CPLEX for a one-year assessment horizon. Solutions to the circular economy models are then compared to the corresponding solutions of linear economy models. Preliminary results show that the optimal circular network is advantageous over the optimal linear network for all objectives subject to the current market supply of raw materials and the total cost of production. However, when considering the present chemical processing infrastructure of the US economy and unrestricted biomass feedstock availability, a linear economy is favorable as an outcome of low operating cost and carbon sequestration.</description>
      <author>Abdulkarim S. Ahmed, Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.154237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of surrogate modeling in the formulation of pooling optimization problems for the CO2 point sources</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.193976</link>
      <description>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Miguel Zamarripa, JP Osorio Su&#65533;rez, A Uribe-Rodr&#65533;guez, M. Soledad D&#237;az, Lorenz T. Biegler, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401458740

                Post-combustion carbon capture technologies have the potential to contribute significantly to achieving the environmental goals of reducing CO2 emissions in the short term. However, these technologies are energy and cost-intensive, and the variability of flue gas represents important challenges. The optimal design and optimization of such systems are critical to reaching the net zero and net negative goals, in this context, the use of computer-aided process design can be very effective in overcoming these issues. In this study, we explore the implementation of carbon capture technologies within an industrial complex, by considering the pooling of CO2 streams. We present an optimization formulation to design carbon capture plants with the goal of enhancing efficiency and minimizing the capture costs. Capital and operating costs are represented via surrogate models (SMs) that are trained using rigorous process models in Aspen Plus, each data point is obtained by solving an optimization problem in Aspen Plus equation-oriented approach. Since selecting the functional form of the surrogate model is crucial for the solution performance; we study different SM approaches (i.e., ALAMO, kriging, radial basis function, polynomials, and artificial neural networks) and analyze their impact on solver performance. Numerical results show the computational advantage of using ALAMO while highlighting the increased complexity of using ANN and kriging to formulate optimization problems. Regarding the pooling of CO2 streams, the optimal designs for the network are not trivial, thus showing the importance of addressing the problem systematically.</description>
      <author>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Miguel Zamarripa, JP Osorio Su&#65533;rez, A Uribe-Rodr&#65533;guez, M. Soledad D&#237;az, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.193976</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decarbonization of Oil Refineries through Electrification and Low-Carbon Feedstocks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.119417</link>
      <description>Ana I. Torres, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401458841

                Chemical Process Industries must navigate a series of changes in their operations to comply with increasing sustainability targets. These changes may involve the use of electricity-based operations, the implementation of carbon capture strategies, and the use of biomass or end-of-life carbon-containing waste as feedstocks. De-carbonizing oil refineries is particularly challenging as they possess highly valuable infrastructure. Discarding this infrastructure before the end of its life to build entirely new electric and biomass-based operations does not seem to be an economical or even a sustainable solution. This presentation will cover recent work in my group related to the decarbonization of oil refineries, focusing on proposing solutions that could be integrated with existing plants... (ABSTRACT ABBREVIATED)</description>
      <author>Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.119417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Retrofit Decarbonization in Oil Refineries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.114841</link>
      <description>Somnath Chattopadhyay, Rahul Gandhi, Iris Grossmann, Ana I. Torres, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401459918

                The chemical industry is actively pursuing energy transition and decarbonization through renewables and other decarbonization initiatives. However, navigating this transition is challenging due to uncertainties in capital investments, electricity costs, and carbon taxes. Adapting to decarbonization standards while preserving existing valuable infrastructure presents a dilemma. Early transitions may lead to inefficiencies, while delays increase the carbon footprint. This research proposes a framework to find an optimal retrofit decarbonization strategy for existing oil refineries. We start with a generic process flowsheet representing the refinery's current configuration and operations, and consider various decarbonization alternatives. Through superstructure optimization, we identify the most cost-effective retrofit strategy over the next three decades to achieve decarbonization goals. We develop a Mixed-Integer Linear Programming (MILP) model, integrating simplified process equations and logical constraints to identify the most economical retrofit decarbonization strategy. The paper presents numerical results from the MILP model. Furthermore, the trends exhibited by the outcomes across various scenarios considering distinct electricity costs and carbon tax levels are presented. These results provide valuable insights into the economic feasibility of retrofit electrification strategies for decision-makers in the chemical industry.</description>
      <author>Somnath Chattopadhyay, Rahul Gandhi, Iris Grossmann, Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.114841</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Membrane Cascade Design for Critical Mineral Recovery Through Logic-based Superstructure Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.127917</link>
      <description>Daniel Ovalle, Norman Tran, David L. Woodruff, Ignacio E. Grossmann, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401460026

                Critical minerals and rare earth elements play an important role in our climate change initiatives, particularly in applications related with energy storage. Here, we use discrete optimization approaches to design a process for the recovery of Lithium and Cobalt from battery recycling, through membrane separation. Our contribution involves proposing a Generalized Disjunctive Programming (GDP) model for the optimal design of a multistage diafiltration cascade for Li-Co separation. By solving the resulting nonconvex mixed-integer nonlinear program model to global optimality, we investigated scalability and solution quality variations with changes in the number of stages and elements per stage. Results demonstrate the computational tractability of the nonlinear GDP formulation for design of membrane separation processes while opening the door for decomposition strategies for multicomponent separation cascades. Future work aims to extend the GDP formulation to account for stage installation and explore various decomposition techniques to enhance solution efficiency.</description>
      <author>Daniel Ovalle, Norman Tran, David L. Woodruff, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.127917</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Design Approaches for Cost-Effective Manufacturing and Deployment of Chemical Process Families with Economies of Numbers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.112787</link>
      <description>Georgia Stinchfield, S. Jan, Josh Morgan, Miguel Zamarripa, Carl D. Laird, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401460148

                Developing methods for rapid, large-scale deployment of carbon capture systems is critical for meeting climate change goals. Optimization-based decisions can be employed at the design and manufacturing phases to minimize the costs of deployment and operation. Manufacturing standardization results in significant cost savings due to economies of numbers. Building on previous work, we present a process family design approach to design a set of carbon capture systems while explicitly including economies of numbers savings within the formulation. Our formulation optimizes both the number and characteristics of the common components in the platform and simultaneously designs the resulting set of carbon capture systems. Savings from economies of numbers are explicitly included in the formulation to determine the number of components in the platform. We show and discuss the savings we gain from economies of numbers.</description>
      <author>Georgia Stinchfield, S. Jan, Josh Morgan, Miguel Zamarripa, Carl D. Laird</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.112787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Solid Oxide Electrolysis Cell Systems Accounting for Long-Term Performance and Health Degradation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.177040</link>
      <description>Nishant V. Giridhar, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Douglas A. Allan, Stephen E. Zitney, Mingrui Li, Lorenz T. Biegler, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401460311

                This study focuses on optimizing solid oxide electrolysis cell (SOEC) systems for efficient and durable long-term hydrogen (H2) production. While the elevated operating temperatures of SOECs offer advantages in terms of efficiency, they also lead to chemical degradation, which shortens cell lifespan. To address this challenge, dynamic degradation models are coupled with a steady-state, two-dimensional, non-isothermal SOEC model and steady-state auxiliary balance of plant equipment models, within the IDAES modeling and optimization framework. A quasi-steady state approach is presented to reduce model size and computational complexity. Long-term dynamic simulations at constant H2 production rate illustrate the thermal effects of chemical degradation. Dynamic optimization is used to minimize the lifetime cost of H2 production, accounting for SOEC replacement, operating, and energy expenses. Several optimized operating profiles are compared by calculating the Levelized Cost of Hydrogen (LCOH).</description>
      <author>Nishant V. Giridhar, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Douglas A. Allan, Stephen E. Zitney, Mingrui Li, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.177040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process Flowsheet Optimization with Surrogate and Implicit Formulations of a Gibbs Reactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.148498</link>
      <description>Sergio Bugosen, Carl D. Laird, Robert Parker, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401460400

                Alternative formulations for the optimization of chemical process flowsheets are presented that leverage surrogate models and implicit functions to replace and remove, respectively, the algebraic equations that describe a difficult-to-converge Gibbs reactor unit operation. Convergence reliability, solve time, and solution quality of an optimization problem are compared among full-space, ALAMO surrogate, neural network surrogate, and implicit function formulations. Both surrogate and implicit formulations lead to better convergence reliability, with low sensitivity to process parameters. The surrogate formulations are faster at the cost of minor solution error, while the implicit formulation provides exact solutions with similar solve time. In a parameter sweep on the autothermal reformer flowsheet optimization problem, the full-space formulation solves 33 out of 64 instances, while the implicit function formulation solves 52 out of 64 instances, the ALAMO polynomial formulation solves 64 out of 64 instances, and the neural network formulation solves 48 out of 64 instances. This work demonstrates the trade-off between accuracy and solve time that exists in current methods for improving convergence reliability of chemical process flowsheet optimization problems.</description>
      <author>Sergio Bugosen, Carl D. Laird, Robert Parker</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.148498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enumeration of Surface Site Nuclearity and Shape in a Database of Intermetallic Low-Index Surface Facets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4921171</link>
      <description>Unnatti Sharma, Angela Nguyen, John R. Kitchin, Zachary W. Ulissi, Michael J. Janik, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401476302

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Unnatti Sharma, Angela Nguyen, John R. Kitchin, Zachary W. Ulissi, Michael J. Janik</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4921171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CFD Modeling of High-Flux Plate-and-Frame Membrane Modules for Industrial Carbon Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2427396</link>
      <description>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401496885

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2427396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Membrane-based Carbon Capture using Dimensional Analysis, CFD and Process System Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2427395</link>
      <description>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401496910

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2427395</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NETL Research &amp;amp; Innovation Center - Membrane Capture Media Development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2427262</link>
      <description>Lingxiang Zhu, Thien Tran, Fangming Xiang, Victor A. Kusuma, Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Grigorios Panagakos, Neil Pergar, Brenda Petrilena, David Hopkinson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401497006

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingxiang Zhu, Thien Tran, Fangming Xiang, Victor A. Kusuma, Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Grigorios Panagakos, Neil Pergar, Brenda Petrilena, David Hopkinson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2427262</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
