<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 01:38:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Generative machine learning approaches to optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2025-hk886</link>
      <description>Victor Alves, John R. Kitchin, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409750178

                Solving optimization problems, especially for nonlinear and constrained systems, is a challenge. Decades of specialized algorithms have been developed for general and special cases of root &#64257;nding, minimization (including constraints), for parameter estimation, and mapping connected spaces. These approaches typically require a model, or set of equations, and then analytical, or iterative numerical approaches can be used to &#64257;nd a solution, and in some special cases a globally best solution can be found and proven. In this work we present an alternative approach to solving these problems that is based in generative machine learning models. The idea is these models either estimate a joint probability distribution of input and output variables, or are able to transform a distribution of inputs to a distribution of outputs (or vice versa). Then, by suitable conditioning (specifying desired properties of some variables), the solutions to these problems can be obtained by sampling the distribution, or by transformation of a distribution sample to the solution space. We illustrate the approach with Gaussian mixture models, which approximate the joint probability distribution. We show examples in root &#64257;nding, unconstrained and constrained optimization, parameter estimation and mapping input and output spaces. This work is intended to be pedagogical to show how a generative model can be used to solve problems in optimization. We discuss some limitations of this approach, but conclude the approach has promise and is di&#64256;erent than existing approaches.</description>
      <author>Victor Alves, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2025-hk886</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science acceleration and accessibility with self-driving labs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59231-1</link>
      <description>Richard B. Canty, Jeffrey A. Bennett, Keith A. Brown, Tonio Buonassisi, Sergei V. Kalinin, John R. Kitchin, Benji Maruyama, R. G. Moore, Joshua Schrier, Martin Seifrid, Shijing Sun, Tejs Vegge, Milad Abolhasani, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409768533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Richard B. Canty, Jeffrey A. Bennett, Keith A. Brown, Tonio Buonassisi, Sergei V. Kalinin, John R. Kitchin, Benji Maruyama, R. G. Moore, Joshua Schrier, Martin Seifrid, Shijing Sun, Tejs Vegge, Milad Abolhasani</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59231-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constraining aerosol&#8211;cloud adjustments by uniting surface observations with a perturbed parameter ensemble</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-4547-2025</link>
      <description>August Mikkelsen, Daniel T. McCoy, Trude Eidhammer, Andrew Gettelman, Ci Song, Hamish Gordon, Isabel L. McCoy, Atmospheric chemistry and physics. 25(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409780216

                Abstract. Aerosol&#8211;cloud interactions (ACIs) are the largest source of uncertainty in inferring the magnitude of future warming consistent with the observational record. The effective radiative forcing due to ACI (ERFaci) is dominated by liquid clouds and is composed of two terms: the change in cloud albedo due to redistributing liquid over a larger number of cloud droplets (Nd) and the change in cloud macrophysical properties due to changes in cloud microphysics. These terms are, respectively, referred to as the radiative forcing due to ACI (RFaci) and aerosol&#8211;cloud adjustments. While the magnitude of RFaci is uncertain, its sign is confidently negative and results in a cooling in the historical record. In contrast, the adjustment of cloud liquid water path (LWP) to enhanced Nd and associated radiative forcing is uncertain in sign. Increased LWP in response to increased Nd is consistent with precipitation suppression, while decreased LWP in response to increased Nd is consistent with enhanced evaporation from cloud top. Observational constraints of these processes are poor in part because of causal ambiguity in the relationship between Nd and LWP. To better understand this relationship, precipitation (P), Nd, and LWP surface observations from the Eastern North Atlantic (ENA) atmospheric observatory are combined with the output from a perturbed parameter ensemble (PPE) hosted in the Community Atmosphere Model version 6 (CAM6). This allows for causal interpretation of observed covariability. Observations of precipitation and cloud from ENA constrain the range of possible LWP aerosol&#8211;cloud adjustments relative to the prior from the PPE by 15 %, resulting in a global value that is confidently positive (a historical cooling) ranging from 2.1 to 6.9 g m&#8722;2. It is found that observed covariability between Nd and LWP is dominated by coalescence scavenging and that this observed covariability is not strongly related to aerosol&#8211;cloud adjustments.</description>
      <author>August Mikkelsen, Daniel T. McCoy, Trude Eidhammer, Andrew Gettelman, Ci Song, Hamish Gordon, Isabel L. McCoy</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-4547-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative machine learning approaches to optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2025-hk886-v2</link>
      <description>Victor Alves, John R. Kitchin, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409823420

                Solving optimization problems, especially for nonlinear and constrained systems, is a challenge. Decades of specialized algorithms have been developed for general and special cases of root &#64257;nding, minimization (including constraints), for parameter estimation, and mapping connected spaces. These approaches typically require a model, or set of equations, and then analytical, or iterative numerical approaches can be used to &#64257;nd a solution, and in some special cases a globally best solution can be found and proven. In this work we present an alternative approach to solving these problems that is based in generative machine learning models. The idea is these models either estimate a joint probability distribution of input and output variables, or are able to transform a distribution of inputs to a distribution of outputs (or vice versa). Then, by suitable conditioning (specifying desired properties of some variables), the solutions to these problems can be obtained by sampling the distribution, or by transformation of a distribution sample to the solution space. We illustrate the approach with Gaussian mixture models, which approximate the joint probability distribution. We show examples in root &#64257;nding, unconstrained and constrained optimization, parameter estimation and mapping input and output spaces. This work is intended to be pedagogical to show how a generative model can be used to solve problems in optimization. We discuss some limitations of this approach, but conclude the approach has promise and is di&#64256;erent than existing approaches.</description>
      <author>Victor Alves, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2025-hk886-v2</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
