<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 01:20:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Perioperative Considerations in Patients with Rett Syndrome as Compared to Those with Cerebral Palsy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1097/brs.0000000000005210</link>
      <description>Vishal Sarwahi, Effat Rahman, Katherine Eigo, Jesse Galina, Sayyida Hasan, Andrew L. Ko, Yungtai Lo, Terry Amaral, Aleksandra Djukic, Maria Santiago, James Schneider, Spine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404093102

                Study Design. Retrospective cohort study Objective. This study aimed to compare perioperative outcomes of Rett syndrome and Cerebral palsy patients undergoing posterior spinal fusion for neuromuscular scoliosis. Summary of Background Data. Surgical correction in the treatment of scoliosis for patients with Rett syndrome (RS) has been shown to increase survival rate. Cerebral palsy (CP) patients, like RS patients, are often nonverbal, nonambulatory, with frequent surgical complications. Methods. Retrospective review of 36 RS and 80 CP patients undergoing PSF from 2005-2023. Data and x-ray measurements were collected pre- and post-operatively. Sub-analysis was performed comparing non-ambulatory patients (GMFCS IV-V). Wilcoxon-Rank Sum, Fisher&#8217;s Exact, and Chi-square tests were utilized. Results. The primary outcome measure, complication rates, was similar between the groups ( P =0.09). Preoperative Cobb angle, levels fused, fixation points, and LOS were similar ( P &gt;0.05). EBL was significantly higher in CP patients as was rate of transfusion ( P =0.001) and surgical time ( P =0.001). Postoperative Cobb angle ( P =0.002) was significantly higher for CP patients. There was no significant difference between CP and RS patients in both preoperative ( P =0.383) and postoperative ( P =0.051) coronal decompensation. Nonambulatory status was associated with increased odds of having a postoperative complication (OR=6.17, 95% C.I. 1.36 &#8211; 28.04). Sub-analysis of non-ambulatory RS and CP patients revealed significantly higher postoperative Cobb ( P =0.008), EBL ( P =0.019) and surgical time ( P =0.017) in CP patients compared to RS patients. There were no significant differences in preoperative Cobb, levels fused, fixation points, hospital stay, or complication rate ( P &gt;0.05). Conclusion. RS patients are shown to have better outcomes to CP patients in terms of surgical, perioperative, and radiographic variables. Ambulatory status was identified as an independent risk factor for complications.</description>
      <author>Vishal Sarwahi, Effat Rahman, Katherine Eigo, Jesse Galina, Sayyida Hasan, Andrew L. Ko, Yungtai Lo, Terry Amaral, Aleksandra Djukic, Maria Santiago, James Schneider</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1097/brs.0000000000005210</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Forest Planning: Balancing Timber Production and Carbon Sequestration Through a Multi-Objective Disjunctive Formulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5013129</link>
      <description>Frank Piedra-Jim&#233;nez, Diego Broz, Juan M. Novas, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Mar&#237;a Anal&#237;a Rodr&#237;guez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404140095

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Frank Piedra-Jim&#233;nez, Diego Broz, Juan M. Novas, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Mar&#237;a Anal&#237;a Rodr&#237;guez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5013129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MINLP: Outer Approximation Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_385-1</link>
      <description>Ignacio E. Grossmann, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404142930

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_385-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Optimization of Heat Exchanger Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_235-1</link>
      <description>Juan M. Zamora, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404144322

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juan M. Zamora, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_235-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process systems engineering enables efficient and sustainable membrane-based critical material separations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2476222</link>
      <description>Molly Dougher, Jason Yao, Andrew Lee, Laurianne Lair, Jonathan Aubuchon Ouimet, William A. Phillip, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, Alexander W. Dowling, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404169299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Molly Dougher, Jason Yao, Andrew Lee, Laurianne Lair, Jonathan Aubuchon Ouimet, William A. Phillip, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, Alexander W. Dowling</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2476222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel mixed-integer linear programming formulation for continuous-time inventory routing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cor.2024.106883</link>
      <description>Akang Wang, Xiandong Li, Jeffrey E. Arbogast, Zachary Wilson, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, Computers &amp; Operations Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404211800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akang Wang, Xiandong Li, Jeffrey E. Arbogast, Zachary Wilson, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cor.2024.106883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DDEL-01. ENGINEERING MRNA THERAPIES FOR BRAIN TUMORS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/neuonc/noae165.0468</link>
      <description>Saigopalakrishna S. Yerneni, Juliana H. Azambuja, Daria Strelkova-Petersen, Brendan R. Gallagher, Julie Shin Kim, Namit Chaudhary, Yongxin Zhao, Peter C. Lucas, Linda M. McAllister&#8208;Lucas, Norbert Pardi, Drew Weissman, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Neuro-Oncology. 26(Supplement_8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404237621

                Abstract Safe delivery of mRNA to the brain will revolutionize the treatment of brain tumors. While lipid nanoparticles (LNPs) are clinically most advanced non-viral delivery vehicles for therapeutic mRNA, LNP-mediated mRNA delivery to the brain remains challenging. We hypothesized that rationally designed LNPs based on extracellular vesicle mimicry would enable efficient delivery of RNA therapeutics to brain cells without undue toxicity. We engineered LNPs consisting of four components similar to the formulation used in the mRNA COVID-19 vaccines (Moderna and Pfizer-BioNTech): ionizable lipid, cholesterol, helper lipid and polyethylene glycol (PEG)-lipid. We screened ten classes of helper lipids based on lipids enriched in extracellular vesicles to engineer biomimetic LNPs and tested their GFP mRNA delivery efficacy in SIM-A9 mouse microglia cell line. Several unique LNP formulations with potent delivery efficacy (&amp;gt;90% cells transfected) and stable GFP expression kinetics (5 days) were identified. LNP formulations with high transfection efficacy were then tested in vivo for luciferase mRNA delivery via intrathecal injection in C57BL/6 mice. Luciferase expression in vivo confirmed widespread mRNA delivery in the brain. We then tested Cre recombinase mRNA delivery in Ai9 mouse to identify LNP-targeted cells via flow cytometry and histology. Flow cytometry and expansion microscopy confirmed Cre recombinase mRNA delivery to a variety of brain cells, including microglia (75-90%), neurons (31-40%), neural stem cells (39-62%), oligodendrocytes (70-90%), and astrocytes (44-76%). LNPs were further evaluated for Cas9 mRNA and CD81 sgRNA delivery in C57BL/6 mouse brains to assess brain-targeted gene editing. Sanger sequencing showed that CRISPR-Cas9 editing was successful in ~40% of cells in the mouse brain. In summary, we engineered extracellular vesicle-based LNP library that can deliver RNA therapeutics to a variety of brain cells in vivo. With further development, this technology could potentially enable genetic and epigenetic therapies targeting drivers of brain tumors.</description>
      <author>Saigopalakrishna S. Yerneni, Juliana H. Azambuja, Daria Strelkova-Petersen, Brendan R. Gallagher, Julie Shin Kim, Namit Chaudhary, Yongxin Zhao, Peter C. Lucas, Linda M. McAllister&#8208;Lucas, Norbert Pardi, Drew Weissman, Kathryn A. Whitehead</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/neuonc/noae165.0468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of hollow fiber membrane packing on the performance of modules formed with fiber tows</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/01496395.2024.2424953</link>
      <description>Lili Sun, Grigorios Panagakos, G. Glenn Lipscomb, Separation Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404278345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lili Sun, Grigorios Panagakos, G. Glenn Lipscomb</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/01496395.2024.2424953</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
