<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 01:20:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>RTN Model for Supply Logistics of Carbon Dioxide in the Field Management for Carbon Capture and Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02991</link>
      <description>Joelle Guisso, Soumya Shikha, Alejandro Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Anna Robert, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406624634

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joelle Guisso, Soumya Shikha, Alejandro Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Anna Robert, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02991</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maternal milk cell components are uptaken by infant liver macrophages via extracellular vesicle mediated transport</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1096/fj.202402365r</link>
      <description>Rose Doerfler, Saigopalakrishna S. Yerneni, Samuel T. LoPresti, Namit Chaudhary, Alexandra N. Newby, Jilian R. Melamed, Angela Malaney, Kathryn A. Whitehead, The FASEB Journal. 39(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406674773

                Abstract Milk is a multifaceted biofluid that is essential for infant nutrition and development, yet its cellular and bioactive components, particularly maternal milk cells, remain understudied. Early research on milk cells indicated that they cross the infant's intestinal barrier and accumulate within systemic organs. However, due to the absence of modern analytical techniques, these studies were limited in scope and mechanistic analysis. To overcome this knowledge gap, we have investigated the transintestinal transport of milk cells and components in pups over a 21&#8208;day period. Studies employed a mT / mG foster nursing model in which milk cells express a membrane&#8208;bound fluorophore, tdTomato . Using flow cytometry, we tracked the transport of milk cell&#8208;derived components across local and systemic tissues, including the intestines, blood, thymus, mesenteric lymph nodes, and liver. These experiments identified milk&#8208;derived fluorescent signals in intestinal epithelial and immune cells as well as liver macrophages in 7&#8208;day&#8208;old pups. However, the minute numbers of macrophages in mouse milk suggest that maternal cells are not systemically accumulating in the infant; instead, pup macrophages are consuming milk cell membrane components, such as apoptotic bodies or extracellular vesicles ( EVs ). Ex vivo experiments using primary macrophages support this hypothesis, showing that immune cells preferentially consumed EVs over milk cells. Together, these data suggest a more complex interplay between milk cells and the infant's immune and digestive systems than previously recognized and highlight the need for future research on the role of milk cells in infant health.</description>
      <author>Rose Doerfler, Saigopalakrishna S. Yerneni, Samuel T. LoPresti, Namit Chaudhary, Alexandra N. Newby, Jilian R. Melamed, Angela Malaney, Kathryn A. Whitehead</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1096/fj.202402365r</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the fourth paradigm of modeling in chemical engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-024-00170-x</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird, Nature Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706802

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin, Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-024-00170-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Model Building through Simultaneous Optimization with Spectral Data: A Silanol End-Capping Reaction Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03612</link>
      <description>Thomas Krumpolc, Daniel W. Trahan, Xiaoyun Chen, M. Wang, Lorenz T. Biegler, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406760229

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thomas Krumpolc, Daniel W. Trahan, Xiaoyun Chen, M. Wang, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protein corona formed on lipid nanoparticles compromises delivery efficiency of mRNA cargo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.20.633942</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Voke, Mariah L. Arral, Henry Squire, Teng-Jui Lin, Roxana Coreas, Alison Lui, Anthony T. Iavarone, Rebecca L. Pinals, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Markita P. Landry, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406797180

                Lipid nanoparticles (LNPs) are the most clinically advanced nonviral RNA-delivery vehicles, though challenges remain in fully understanding how LNPs interact with biological systems. In vivo, proteins form an associated corona on LNPs that redefines their physicochemical properties and influences delivery outcomes. Despite its importance, the LNP protein corona is challenging to study owing to the technical difficulty of selectively recovering soft nanoparticles from biological samples. Herein, we developed a quantitative, label-free mass spectrometry-based proteomics approach to characterize the protein corona on LNPs. Critically, this protein corona isolation workflow avoids artifacts introduced by the presence of endogenous nanoparticles in human biofluids. We applied continuous density gradient ultracentrifugation for protein-LNP complex isolation, with mass spectrometry for protein identification normalized to protein composition in the biofluid alone. With this approach, we quantify proteins consistently enriched in the LNP corona including vitronectin, C-reactive protein, and alpha-2-macroglobulin. We explore the impact of these corona proteins on cell uptake and mRNA expression in HepG2 human liver cells, and find that, surprisingly, increased levels of cell uptake do not correlate with increased mRNA expression in part likely due to protein corona-induced lysosomal trafficking of LNPs. Our results underscore the need to consider the protein corona in the design of LNP-based therapeutics.</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Voke, Mariah L. Arral, Henry Squire, Teng-Jui Lin, Roxana Coreas, Alison Lui, Anthony T. Iavarone, Rebecca L. Pinals, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Markita P. Landry</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.20.633942</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
