<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 03:23:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4va90010c</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394609944

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4va90010c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4em90011a</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Processes &amp; impacts. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394610056

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4em90011a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ew90011a</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Water research &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626148

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ew90011a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4en90012j</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626337

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4en90012j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea90013h</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Atmospheres. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626403

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea90013h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Strategy for mRNA Encapsulation and Gene Delivery with Metal-Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mlcss</link>
      <description>Harrison Lawson, Huy Nguyen, Ayesha Tupe, Mariah L. Arral, K. Y. Lee, Min L&#252;, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Siyang Zheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394757946

                Over the last two decades, the utility of metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) has expanded from catalysis and gas storage to biomedical applications such as drug delivery. At first, MOF-based delivery platforms focused on delivering small molecules, with current work focusing on nucleic acids, such as DNA, short guide RNA (sgRNA), and short interfering RNA (siRNA). No studies to this date have specifically shown the encapsulation and delivery of mRNA with MOFs, possibly due to the fragile nature of messenger RNA (mRNA). This study explores and identifies suitable synthetic conditions for encapsulating and delivering mRNA with zeolitic imidazole framework-8 (ZIF-8). Initial ZIF-8 encapsulation attempts, although capable of mRNA loading, could not retain mRNA longer than 1 hour in biological media. To address this issue, we added polyethyleneimine (PEI) to the matrix, enabling the retention of mRNA with 4 hours of stability. Polyethyleneimine incorporation resolves the leakage of mRNA from ZIF-8, enabling delivery and resultant protein expression in multiple cell lines comparable to commercial lipid transfection reagents. Furthermore, we report the first application exploring thermally stable mRNA storage with ZIF-8 with successful protein expression achieved after 3 months of room temperature storage. Together, this work expands the catalog of therapeutics MOFs can deliver.</description>
      <author>Harrison Lawson, Huy Nguyen, Ayesha Tupe, Mariah L. Arral, K. Y. Lee, Min L&#252;, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Siyang Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mlcss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v5</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2014. https://openalex.org/W4394266427

                Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. All images from the work have been included in a zipped folder.</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating ambient particulate organic carbon concentrations and partitioning using thermal optical measurements and the volatility basis set</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.3115603</link>
      <description>Jiesi Ma, Xiang Li, Peishi Gu, Timothy R. Dallmann, Albert A. Presto, Neil M. Donahue, Figshare. None(None)] 2016. https://openalex.org/W4394432920

                We introduce a new method to estimate the mass concentration of particulate organic carbon (POC) collected on quartz filters, demonstrating it using quartz-filter samples collected in greater Pittsburgh. This method combines thermal-optical organic carbon and elemental carbon (OC/EC) analysis and the volatility basis set (VBS) to quantify the mass concentration of semi-volatile POC on the filters. The dataset includes ambient samples collected at a number of sites in both summer and winter as well as samples from a highway tunnel. As a reference we use the two-filter bare-Quartz minus Quartz-Behind-Teflon (Q-QBT) approach to estimate the adsorbed gaseous fraction of organic carbon (OC), finding a substantial fraction in both the gas and particle phases under all conditions. In the new method we use OC fractions measured during different temperature stages of the OC/EC analysis for the single bare-quartz (BQ) filter in combination with partitioning theory to predict the volatility distributions of the measured OC, which we describe with the VBS. The effective volatility bins are consistent for data from both ambient samples and primary organic aerosol (POA)-enriched tunnel samples. Consequently, with the VBS model and total OC fractions measured over different heating stages, particulate OC can be determined by using the BQ filter alone. This method can thus be applied to all quartz filter-based OC/EC analyses to estimate the POC concentration without using backup filters. &#169; 2016 American Association for Aerosol Research</description>
      <author>Jiesi Ma, Xiang Li, Peishi Gu, Timothy R. Dallmann, Albert A. Presto, Neil M. Donahue</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.3115603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v6</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2014. https://openalex.org/W4394440837

                Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. All images from the work have been included in a zipped folder.</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural network predictions of segregation on AuPd(111) surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.4272203.v1</link>
      <description>Jacob R. Boes, John R. Kitchin, Figshare. None(None)] 2016. https://openalex.org/W4394521036

                Supporting information for the manuscript "Neural network predictions of segregation on AuPd(111) surfaces." This includes the supporting information file as submitted for publication along with figures and data discussed in that manuscript.</description>
      <author>Jacob R. Boes, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.4272203.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v4</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2013. https://openalex.org/W4394074877

                Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. All images from the work have been included in a zipped folder.</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v3</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2013. https://openalex.org/W4394281422

                Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. All images from the work have been included in a zipped folder.</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2013. https://openalex.org/W4394383699

                Abstract: ======= Transition metal dioxides (BO2) exhibit a number of polymorphic structures with distinct properties, but the isolation of different polymorphs for a given composition is carried out using trial and error experimentation. We present computational studies of the relative stabilities and equations of state for six polymorphs (anatase, brookite, rutile, columbite, pyrite, and fluorite) of five different BO2 dioxides (B = Ti, V, Ru, Ir, and Sn). These properties were computed in a consistent fashion using several exchange correlation functionals within the density functional theory formalism, and the effects of the different functionals are discussed relative to their impact on predictive synthesis. We compare the computational results to prior observations of high-pressure synthesis and epitaxial film growth and then use this discussion to predict new accessible polymorphs in the context of epitaxial stabilization using isostructural substrates. For example, the relative stabilities of the columbite polymorph for VO2 and RuO2 are similar to those of TiO2 and SnO2, the latter two of which have been previously stabilized as epitaxial films. On Figshare ========== Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. Supporting images are included in a zipped folder. Full Article ======== http://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/am4059149 Documented supporting Info ====================== http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/am4059149/suppl_file/am4059149_si_001.pdf</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting information for "Neural network and ReaxFF comparison for Au properties, Int. J. Quantum Chem., 116(13), 979&#8211;987 (2016)."</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1603022</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, Jacob R. Boes, John A. Keith, Mitchell C. Groenenboom, Figshare. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4394384117

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin, Jacob R. Boes, John A. Keith, Mitchell C. Groenenboom</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1603022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting information for "Modeling Palladium Surfaces with Density Functional Theory, Neural Networks and Molecular Dynamics"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.5849991</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, Tianyu Gao, Figshare. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4394406137

                This data set can be used to reproduce most of the figures and analysis in our paper "Modeling Palladium Surfaces with Density Functional Theory, Neural Networks and Molecular Dynamics". The details for how to use this dataset are in the supporting information file for that paper.Note, the original data was posted here: https://figshare.com/articles/Data_zip/4347956/1This dataset supercedes that one.</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin, Tianyu Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.5849991</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting information for "Neural network and ReaxFF comparison for Au properties, Int. J. Quantum Chem., 116(13), 979&#8211;987 (2016)."</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1603022.v1</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, Jacob R. Boes, John A. Keith, Mitchell C. Groenenboom, Figshare. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4394531894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin, Jacob R. Boes, John A. Keith, Mitchell C. Groenenboom</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1603022.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OR-Gym: A Reinforcement Learning Library for Operations Research Problems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2008.06319</link>
      <description>Christian D. Hubbs, H&#233;ctor D. P&#233;rez, Owais Sarwar, Nikolaos V. Sahinidis, Ignacio E. Grossmann, John M. Wassick, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4394643743

                Reinforcement learning (RL) has been widely applied to game-playing and surpassed the best human-level performance in many domains, yet there are few use-cases in industrial or commercial settings. We introduce OR-Gym, an open-source library for developing reinforcement learning algorithms to address operations research problems. In this paper, we apply reinforcement learning to the knapsack, multi-dimensional bin packing, multi-echelon supply chain, and multi-period asset allocation model problems, as well as benchmark the RL solutions against MILP and heuristic models. These problems are used in logistics, finance, engineering, and are common in many business operation settings. We develop environments based on prototypical models in the literature and implement various optimization and heuristic models in order to benchmark the RL results. By re-framing a series of classic optimization problems as RL tasks, we seek to provide a new tool for the operations research community, while also opening those in the RL community to many of the problems and challenges in the OR field.</description>
      <author>Christian D. Hubbs, H&#233;ctor D. P&#233;rez, Owais Sarwar, Nikolaos V. Sahinidis, Ignacio E. Grossmann, John M. Wassick</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2008.06319</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
