<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 01:20:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>New Library-Based Methods for Nontargeted Compound Identification by GC-EI-MS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jasms.4c00451</link>
      <description>Deborah McGlynn, Lindsay D. Yee, H. Martin Garraffo, Lewis Y. Geer, Tytus D. Mak, Yuri A. Mirokhin, Dmitrii V. Tchekhovskoi, Coty N. Jen, A. H. Goldstein, Anthony J. Kearsley, Stephen E. Stein, Journal of the American Society for Mass Spectrometry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406375656

                While gas chromatography mass spectrometry (GC-MS) has long been used to identify compounds in complex mixtures, this process is often subjective and time-consuming and leaves a large fraction of seemingly good-quality spectra unidentified. In this work, we describe a set of new mass spectral library-based methods to assist compound identification in complex mixtures. These methods employ mass spectral uniqueness and compound ubiquity of library entries alongside noise reduction and automated comparison of retention indices to library compounds. As a test data set, we used a publicly available electron ionization mass spectrometry data set consisting of 4833 spectra of particulate organic compounds emitted by combustion of wildland fuels. In the present work, spectra in this data set were first identified using the NIST 2023 EI-MS Library and associated batch process identification software (NIST MS PepSearch) using retention-index corrected Identity Search scoring. Resulting identifications and related information were then employed to parametrize other factors that correlate with identification. A method for identifying compounds absent from but related to those present in mass spectral libraries using the Hybrid Similarity Search is illustrated. Nevertheless, some 90% of the spectra remain unidentified. Through comparison of unidentified to identified mass spectra in this data set, a new simple measure, namely median relative abundance, was developed for evaluating the likelihood of identification.</description>
      <author>Deborah McGlynn, Lindsay D. Yee, H. Martin Garraffo, Lewis Y. Geer, Tytus D. Mak, Yuri A. Mirokhin, Dmitrii V. Tchekhovskoi, Coty N. Jen, A. H. Goldstein, Anthony J. Kearsley, Stephen E. Stein</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jasms.4c00451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast and sensitive measurements of sub-3 nm particles using Condensation Particle Counters For Atmospheric Rapid Measurements (CPC FARM)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-18-197-2025</link>
      <description>Darren Cheng, Stavros Amanatidis, Gregory S. Lewis, Coty N. Jen, Atmospheric measurement techniques. 18(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406399967

                Abstract. New particle formation (NPF) is the atmospheric process whereby gas molecules react and nucleate to form detectable particles. NPF has a strong impact on Earth's radiative balance as it produces roughly half of global cloud condensation nuclei. However, the time resolution and sensitivity of current instrumentation are inadequate in measuring the size distribution of sub-3 nm particles, the particles critical for understanding NPF. Here we present the Condensation Particle Counters For Atmospheric Rapid Measurements (CPC FARM), a method to measure the concentrations of freshly nucleated particles. The CPC FARM consists of five CPCs operating in parallel, each configured to operate at different detectable particle sizes between 1&#8211;3 nm. This study explores two methods to calculate the size distribution from the differential measurements across the CPC channels. The performance of both inversion methods was tested against the size distribution measured by a pair of stepping particle mobility sizers (SMPSs) during an ambient air sampling study in Pittsburgh, PA. Observational results indicate that the CPC FARM is more accurate with higher time resolution and sensitivity in the sub-3 nm range compared to the SMPS.</description>
      <author>Darren Cheng, Stavros Amanatidis, Gregory S. Lewis, Coty N. Jen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-18-197-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of an integrated modeling framework for visibility and air quality forecasting in Delhi</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/bams-d-24-0194.1</link>
      <description>A. Jayakumar, T. J. Anurose, Shweta Bhati, M. A. Hendry, Garry Hayman, Hamish Gordon, Paul R. Field, Saji Mohandas, Heather Rumbold, Prafull Yadav, Narendra G. Dhangar, Avinash N. Parde, Sandeep Wagh, Sachin D. Ghude, Andrew Ross, Daniel Smith, Stephen Dorling, John P. George, V. Siva Prasad, M. Ravichandran, Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406469103

                Abstract Rapid urbanization has subjected the megacities of developing countries to various environmental stresses. Delhi, a major Indian megacity, faces increasing urban stress leading to reduction in air quality, and visibility. These challenges necessitate an integrated modeling framework to mitigate adverse environmental impacts on public health. Therefore, we have developed an advanced version of the high-resolution Delhi Model with Chemistry and Aerosol framework (DM-Chem) at the National Centre for Medium Range Weather Forecasting (NCMRWF) under the Weather and Climate Science for Service Partnership India (WCSSP India) project. This collaborative initiative between India and the UK aims to provide real-time forecasts of visibility and fine particulate matter (PM 2.5 ) for Delhi and neighbouring regions during the winter season. The DM Chem framework is unique due to its detailed urban canopy scheme and realistic aerosol representation, making it well-suited for city-scale forecasts. It is designed to predict extreme fog and pollution events in the winter season. Here we discuss the major physical parameterization improvements for the model, along with its skill and deficiencies in predicting extreme events. Notably, irrigation effects on surrounding agricultural areas have significantly improved fog and visibility forecasts, but have degraded the wind forecasts. We demonstrate the applicability of this modeling framework to study aerosol-radiation interaction during fog holes and discuss its potential to be applied or adapted to other megacities worldwide.</description>
      <author>A. Jayakumar, T. J. Anurose, Shweta Bhati, M. A. Hendry, Garry Hayman, Hamish Gordon, Paul R. Field, Saji Mohandas, Heather Rumbold, Prafull Yadav, Narendra G. Dhangar, Avinash N. Parde, Sandeep Wagh, Sachin D. Ghude, Andrew Ross, Daniel Smith, Stephen Dorling, John P. George, V. Siva Prasad, M. Ravichandran</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1175/bams-d-24-0194.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logic-Based Discrete-Steepest Descent: A solution method for process synthesis Generalized Disjunctive Programs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108993</link>
      <description>Daniel Ovalle, David A. Li&#241;&#225;n, Albert Lee, Jorge M. G&#243;mez, Luis Ricardez&#8208;Sandoval, Ignacio E. Grossmann, David E. Bernal, Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406519921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel Ovalle, David A. Li&#241;&#225;n, Albert Lee, Jorge M. G&#243;mez, Luis Ricardez&#8208;Sandoval, Ignacio E. Grossmann, David E. Bernal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code and Data Repository for Scalable Parallel Nonlinear Optimization with PyNumero and Parapint</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1287/ijoc.2023.1272.cd</link>
      <description>Jose S. Rodriguez, Robert Parker, Carl D. Laird, Bethany L. Nicholson, John Daniel Siirola, Michael Bynum, INFORMS journal on computing. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4406365235

                PyNumero is a package for developing parallel algorithms for nonlinear programs (NLPs).</description>
      <author>Jose S. Rodriguez, Robert Parker, Carl D. Laird, Bethany L. Nicholson, John Daniel Siirola, Michael Bynum</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1287/ijoc.2023.1272.cd</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
