<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 01:13:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>CFD Modeling of High-Flux Plate-and-Frame Membrane Modules for Industrial Carbon Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2427396</link>
      <description>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401496885

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2427396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Membrane-based Carbon Capture using Dimensional Analysis, CFD and Process System Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2427395</link>
      <description>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401496910

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2427395</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NETL Research &amp;amp; Innovation Center - Membrane Capture Media Development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2427262</link>
      <description>Lingxiang Zhu, Thien Tran, Fangming Xiang, Victor A. Kusuma, Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Grigorios Panagakos, Neil Pergar, Brenda Petrilena, David Hopkinson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401497006

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingxiang Zhu, Thien Tran, Fangming Xiang, Victor A. Kusuma, Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Grigorios Panagakos, Neil Pergar, Brenda Petrilena, David Hopkinson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2427262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-stabilizing economic nonlinear model predictive control applied to modular systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108825</link>
      <description>San Dinh, Kuan&#8208;Han Lin, Fernando V. Lima, Lorenz T. Biegler, Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401503825

                No abstract</description>
      <author>San Dinh, Kuan&#8208;Han Lin, Fernando V. Lima, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand Shell Thickness of PEGylated Gold Nanoparticles Controls Cellular Uptake and Radiation Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c06568</link>
      <description>Paul T. Lawrence, Andrew J. Gellman, Allison J. Tierney, E. Charles H. Sykes, Charles R. Mace, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401534980

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Paul T. Lawrence, Andrew J. Gellman, Allison J. Tierney, E. Charles H. Sykes, Charles R. Mace</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c06568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Sensitive Reaction Kinetics of Chiral Molecules on Intrinsically Chiral Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04224</link>
      <description>Kareem Abdelmaqsoud, Michael Radetic, Carlos Fern&#225;ndez-Cab&#225;n, Michael Widom, John R. Kitchin, Andrew J. Gellman, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401547089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kareem Abdelmaqsoud, Michael Radetic, Carlos Fern&#225;ndez-Cab&#225;n, Michael Widom, John R. Kitchin, Andrew J. Gellman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Error Imbalance of Large-Scale Machine Learning Potentials in Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00615a</link>
      <description>Kareem Abdelmaqsoud, Muhammed Shuaibi, Adeesh Kolluru, Raffaele Cheula, John R. Kitchin, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401579937

                Machine learning potentials (MLPs) have greatly accelerated atomistic simulations for material dis- covery. The Open Catalyst 2020 (OC20) dataset is one of the largest datasets for training MLPs for heterogeneous...</description>
      <author>Kareem Abdelmaqsoud, Muhammed Shuaibi, Adeesh Kolluru, Raffaele Cheula, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00615a</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
