<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:42:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-level optimization strategies for large-scale nonlinear process systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108657</link>
      <description>Lorenz T. Biegler, Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392859961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parafoil System Cooperative Recovery: A Coordinated Distributed NMPC Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/taes.2024.3378193</link>
      <description>Zhixuan Wei, Zhijiang Shao, Lorenz T. Biegler, IEEE Transactions on Aerospace and Electronic Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392908417

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhixuan Wei, Zhijiang Shao, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/taes.2024.3378193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous locomotion of a symmetric squirmer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1017/jfm.2024.149</link>
      <description>Richard Cobos, Aditya S. Khair, Ory Schnitzer, Journal of Fluid Mechanics. 983(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392921640

                The squirmer is a popular model to analyse the fluid mechanics of a self-propelled object, such as a micro-organism. We demonstrate that some fore&#8211;aft symmetric squirmers can spontaneously self-propel above a critical Reynolds number. Specifically, we numerically study the effects of inertia on spherical squirmers characterised by an axially and fore&#8211;aft symmetric &#8216;quadrupolar&#8217; distribution of surface-slip velocity; under creeping-flow conditions, such squirmers generate a pure stresslet flow, the stresslet sign classifying the squirmer as either a &#8216;pusher&#8217; or &#8216;puller&#8217;. Assuming axial symmetry, and over the examined range of the Reynolds number $Re$ (defined based upon the magnitude of the quadrupolar squirming), we find that spontaneous symmetry breaking occurs in the puller case above $Re \approx 14.3$ , with steady swimming emerging from that threshold consistently with a supercritical pitchfork bifurcation and with the swimming speed growing monotonically with $Re$ .</description>
      <author>Richard Cobos, Aditya S. Khair, Ory Schnitzer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1017/jfm.2024.149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature, humidity, and ionisation effect of iodine oxoacid nucleation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00013g</link>
      <description>Birte R&#246;rup, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Jiali Shen, Rima Baalbaki, Lubna Dada, Mikko Sipil&#228;, J. Kirkby, Markku Kulmala, A. Amorim, Andrea Baccarini, David M. Bell, Luc&#237;a Caudillo, Jonathan Duplissy, Henning Finkenzeller, A. Kuerten, Houssni Lamkaddam, Chuan Ping Lee, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Hanna E. Manninen, Guillaume Marie, Ruby Marten, Bernhard Mentler, A. Onnela, Maxim Philippov, Wiebke Scholz, Mario Simon, Dominik Stolzenburg, Yee Jun Tham, Ant&#243;nio Tom&#233;, Andrea C. Wagner, Mingyi Wang, Dongyu Wang, Yonghong Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Marcel Zauner-Wieczorek, Urs Baltensperger, Joachim Curtius, Neil M. Donahue, Imad El Haddad, Richard C. Flagan, Armin Hansel, Ottmar M&#246;hler, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#776;&#228;, Rainer Volkamer, D. R. Worsnop, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Environmental science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393038292

                Iodine oxoacids are recognised for their significant contribution to the formation of new particles in coastal and polar atmospheres. Nevertheless, to incorporate the iodine oxoacid nucleation mechanism into global simulations,...</description>
      <author>Birte R&#246;rup, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Jiali Shen, Rima Baalbaki, Lubna Dada, Mikko Sipil&#228;, J. Kirkby, Markku Kulmala, A. Amorim, Andrea Baccarini, David M. Bell, Luc&#237;a Caudillo, Jonathan Duplissy, Henning Finkenzeller, A. Kuerten, Houssni Lamkaddam, Chuan Ping Lee, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Hanna E. Manninen, Guillaume Marie, Ruby Marten, Bernhard Mentler, A. Onnela, Maxim Philippov, Wiebke Scholz, Mario Simon, Dominik Stolzenburg, Yee Jun Tham, Ant&#243;nio Tom&#233;, Andrea C. Wagner, Mingyi Wang, Dongyu Wang, Yonghong Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Marcel Zauner-Wieczorek, Urs Baltensperger, Joachim Curtius, Neil M. Donahue, Imad El Haddad, Richard C. Flagan, Armin Hansel, Ottmar M&#246;hler, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#776;&#228;, Rainer Volkamer, D. R. Worsnop, Katrianne Lehtipalo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00013g</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
