<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 01:38:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear Model Predictive Control with an Infinite Horizon Approximation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5249681</link>
      <description>Lorenz T. Biegler, San Dinh, Yao Tong, Zhenyu Wei, Owen Gerdes, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410253659

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lorenz T. Biegler, San Dinh, Yao Tong, Zhenyu Wei, Owen Gerdes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5249681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Retrofit of Carbon Capture and Electrification Technologies in Oil Refineries for Reducing Direct CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04995</link>
      <description>S. Chattopadhyay, Kaliaperumal Karthikeyan, Rahul Gandhi, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Ana I. Torres, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410269108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Chattopadhyay, Kaliaperumal Karthikeyan, Rahul Gandhi, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In vitro monitoring of Babesia microti infection dynamics in whole blood microenvironments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.05.07.652765</link>
      <description>Chao Li, Emily G. Bache, Amy L. Apgar, Danielle M. Tufts, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410335725

                Babesiosis &#8212; a globally emerging tick-borne infectious disease primarily caused by the intraerythrocytic piroplasm parasite, Babesia microti &#8212; has traditionally been studied using animal models such as mice. Compared to animal models, microfluidic-based models offer advantages, including direct analysis of human samples (such as patient blood), enhanced assay capacity (including physical/optical access, consistency, and throughput), low costs, and easy adoption. Here, we report an open microfluidic platform named &#956;&#8211;Blood for monitoring B. microti infection dynamics in vitro. Compared to other microfluidic-based models, &#956;&#8211;Blood allows direct examination of infected and uninfected whole blood without preprocessing steps like blood dilution or cell isolation, minimizing observer artifacts and preserving the natural whole blood microenvironment. The system enables extended (days-long) monitoring of infection dynamics, including parasite identification, parasitemia measurement, and parasite-host cell interactions, using label-free phase contrast and fluorescence confocal microscopy. With its open microfluidic configuration, &#956;-Blood provides an in vitro model for studying blood-borne infections while maintaining integrity of the whole blood microenvironment.</description>
      <author>Chao Li, Emily G. Bache, Amy L. Apgar, Danielle M. Tufts, Tagbo H. R. Niepa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.05.07.652765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and optimization of circular economy networks&#8212;A case study of PET</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2025.109164</link>
      <description>Abdulhakeem Ahmed, Anoop N. Nair, Ana I. Torres, Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410348848

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulhakeem Ahmed, Anoop N. Nair, Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2025.109164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic effect of gold-zinc oxide composite nanostructures for the selective and controlled killing of antibiotic-resistant bacteria and the removal of resistant bacterial biofilms from the body</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s40580-025-00488-z</link>
      <description>Jongjun Park, Tae Hui Bae, S. Y. Kim, Seong-Eun Park, Yonghyun Choi, Masayoshi Tanaka, Jiwon Kim, Jaehee Jang, J. Yang, Heeyoung Lee, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Shin Hyuk Kang, Jonghoon Choi, Nano Convergence. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410358349

                Abstract Infections involving antibiotic-resistant bacteria have become a major problem. Pathogenic bacteria use mechanisms such as drug target bypass, target modification, and biofilm formation to evade treatment. To respond to these problems, antibacterial research using metal and metal oxide nanoparticles is currently active. Nanoparticles treat bacterial infections through reactive oxygen species generation or antibacterial ion release. However, their application has faced problems related to human compatibility, as they react non-specifically, targeting both mammalian and bacterial cells. In addition, ZnO nanoparticles show low antibacterial activity against Gram-negative bacteria. Thus, the demand for antibacterial substances with enhanced specificity and improved efficacy is increasing. We bound gold to the surface of ZnO nanoparticles, enabling photocatalytic and photothermal actions through visible light irradiation. To improve bacterial specificity, Concanavalin A (Con A), a lectin that can specifically target bacterial membrane lipopolysaccharides, was conjugated with the nanoparticles. We showed that Con A-conjugated Au/ZnO nanoparticles (Au/ZnO-Con A) exhibit photocatalytic and photothermal effects under white light, enhancing their antibacterial ability, and through enhanced specificity, increased antibacterial and anti-biofilm abilities were confirmed. The developed particles showed the potential to alleviate antibiotic resistance in a bacterial skin infection model, presenting a new platform for treating bacterial infections. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Jongjun Park, Tae Hui Bae, S. Y. Kim, Seong-Eun Park, Yonghyun Choi, Masayoshi Tanaka, Jiwon Kim, Jaehee Jang, J. Yang, Heeyoung Lee, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Shin Hyuk Kang, Jonghoon Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s40580-025-00488-z</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
