<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:52:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Large-Scale Optimization of Nonconvex MINLP Refinery Scheduling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108678</link>
      <description>Robert E. Franzoi, Brenno C. Menezes, Jeffrey D. Kelly, Jorge Andrey Wilhelms Gut, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Computers &amp; chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394000444

                Modeling and optimization of large-scale refinery scheduling problems is challenging because of their complexity and size. Herein, we propose a mathematical model to represent such problems more accurately and realistically, and a state-of-the-art optimization framework for its solution. The framework leverages the use of mathematical optimization and algorithmic methods by combining modeling approaches (process design, model decompositions), solving strategies (rescheduling, heuristics), and machine learning regression (surrogate models). An industrial-size refinery scheduling problem (2 blenders, 4 feed tanks, distillation network with 5 towers, processing network with FCC, hydrotreaters, debutanizers, superfractionator, catalytic reformer) is formulated as a hierarchical nonconvex mixed-integer nonlinear programming (MINLP) model and is successfully optimized, providing higher profitability and more efficient scheduling operations considering 12 feedstocks, 10 products and multiple scenarios for time horizon and step. Results highlight the importance of tuning scheduling parameters and employing an enhanced computer-aided framework to enable the solution of industrial refinery scheduling operations.</description>
      <author>Robert E. Franzoi, Brenno C. Menezes, Jeffrey D. Kelly, Jorge Andrey Wilhelms Gut, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4va90010c</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394609944

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4va90010c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4em90011a</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Processes &amp; impacts. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394610056

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4em90011a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ew90011a</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Water research &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626148

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ew90011a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4en90012j</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626337

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4en90012j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Outstanding Papers published in the &lt;i&gt;Environmental Science&lt;/i&gt; journals of the Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea90013h</link>
      <description>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland, Environmental science. Atmospheres. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626403

                The Editors-in-Chief of the Environmental Science journals introduce the Outstanding Papers of 2023.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Cai, Neil M. Donahue, Graham A. Gagnon, Kevin C. Jones, C&#233;lia M. Manaia, Elsie M. Sunderland, Peter J. Vikesland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea90013h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v5</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2014. https://openalex.org/W4394266427

                Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. All images from the work have been included in a zipped folder.</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating ambient particulate organic carbon concentrations and partitioning using thermal optical measurements and the volatility basis set</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.3115603</link>
      <description>Jiesi Ma, Xiang Li, Peishi Gu, Timothy R. Dallmann, Albert A. Presto, Neil M. Donahue, Figshare. None(None)] 2016. https://openalex.org/W4394432920

                We introduce a new method to estimate the mass concentration of particulate organic carbon (POC) collected on quartz filters, demonstrating it using quartz-filter samples collected in greater Pittsburgh. This method combines thermal-optical organic carbon and elemental carbon (OC/EC) analysis and the volatility basis set (VBS) to quantify the mass concentration of semi-volatile POC on the filters. The dataset includes ambient samples collected at a number of sites in both summer and winter as well as samples from a highway tunnel. As a reference we use the two-filter bare-Quartz minus Quartz-Behind-Teflon (Q-QBT) approach to estimate the adsorbed gaseous fraction of organic carbon (OC), finding a substantial fraction in both the gas and particle phases under all conditions. In the new method we use OC fractions measured during different temperature stages of the OC/EC analysis for the single bare-quartz (BQ) filter in combination with partitioning theory to predict the volatility distributions of the measured OC, which we describe with the VBS. The effective volatility bins are consistent for data from both ambient samples and primary organic aerosol (POA)-enriched tunnel samples. Consequently, with the VBS model and total OC fractions measured over different heating stages, particulate OC can be determined by using the BQ filter alone. This method can thus be applied to all quartz filter-based OC/EC analyses to estimate the POC concentration without using backup filters. &#169; 2016 American Association for Aerosol Research</description>
      <author>Jiesi Ma, Xiang Li, Peishi Gu, Timothy R. Dallmann, Albert A. Presto, Neil M. Donahue</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.3115603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v6</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2014. https://openalex.org/W4394440837

                Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. All images from the work have been included in a zipped folder.</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural network predictions of segregation on AuPd(111) surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.4272203.v1</link>
      <description>Jacob R. Boes, John R. Kitchin, Figshare. None(None)] 2016. https://openalex.org/W4394521036

                Supporting information for the manuscript "Neural network predictions of segregation on AuPd(111) surfaces." This includes the supporting information file as submitted for publication along with figures and data discussed in that manuscript.</description>
      <author>Jacob R. Boes, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.4272203.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v4</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2013. https://openalex.org/W4394074877

                Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. All images from the work have been included in a zipped folder.</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v3</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2013. https://openalex.org/W4394281422

                Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. All images from the work have been included in a zipped folder.</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919.v3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Information - "Identifying Potential BO2 Oxide Polymorphs for Epitaxial Growth Candidates"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919</link>
      <description>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador, Figshare. None(None)] 2013. https://openalex.org/W4394383699

                Abstract: ======= Transition metal dioxides (BO2) exhibit a number of polymorphic structures with distinct properties, but the isolation of different polymorphs for a given composition is carried out using trial and error experimentation. We present computational studies of the relative stabilities and equations of state for six polymorphs (anatase, brookite, rutile, columbite, pyrite, and fluorite) of five different BO2 dioxides (B = Ti, V, Ru, Ir, and Sn). These properties were computed in a consistent fashion using several exchange correlation functionals within the density functional theory formalism, and the effects of the different functionals are discussed relative to their impact on predictive synthesis. We compare the computational results to prior observations of high-pressure synthesis and epitaxial film growth and then use this discussion to predict new accessible polymorphs in the context of epitaxial stabilization using isostructural substrates. For example, the relative stabilities of the columbite polymorph for VO2 and RuO2 are similar to those of TiO2 and SnO2, the latter two of which have been previously stabilized as epitaxial films. On Figshare ========== Data has been stored as a JSON file and contains information about how every calculation was setup, like the planewave cutoff, exchange correlation functional, k-point grid, etc. It also contains relevant output from the calculation, like total energies, volumes, unit cell parameters, atomic positions, forces, etc. Supporting images are included in a zipped folder. Full Article ======== http://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/am4059149 Documented supporting Info ====================== http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/am4059149/suppl_file/am4059149_si_001.pdf</description>
      <author>Prateek Mehta, John R. Kitchin, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.858919</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NUMAC: Description of the Nested Unified Model with Aerosols and Chemistry, and evaluation with KORUS-AQ data: supporting data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7823962</link>
      <description>Hamish Gordon, K. S. Carslaw, Adrian A. Hill, Paul R. Field, N. L. Abraham, A. J. Beyersdorf, Chelsea Corr&#8208;Limoges, Pratapaditya Ghosh, John Hemmings, Anthony C. Jones, Claudio S&#225;nchez, Xuemei Wang, Jonathan Wilkinson, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4394037240

                Simulated data presented in manuscript with title above, generated with the Met Office Unified Model, together with observations from KORUS-AQ and MODIS that are used in the model evaluation. The Terra/MODIS aerosol datasets were acquired from the Level-1 and Atmosphere Archive &amp; Distribution System (LAADS) Distributed Active Archive Center (DAAC), located in the Goddard Space Flight Center in Greenbelt, Maryland https://ladsweb.nascom.nasa.gov/. All surface and aircraft observation data is freely and publicly available at https://www-air.larc.nasa.gov/cgi-bin/ArcView/korusaq, last access 10 June 2022.</description>
      <author>Hamish Gordon, K. S. Carslaw, Adrian A. Hill, Paul R. Field, N. L. Abraham, A. J. Beyersdorf, Chelsea Corr&#8208;Limoges, Pratapaditya Ghosh, John Hemmings, Anthony C. Jones, Claudio S&#225;nchez, Xuemei Wang, Jonathan Wilkinson</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7823962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting information for "Neural network and ReaxFF comparison for Au properties, Int. J. Quantum Chem., 116(13), 979&#8211;987 (2016)."</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1603022</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, Jacob R. Boes, John A. Keith, Mitchell C. Groenenboom, Figshare. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4394384117

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin, Jacob R. Boes, John A. Keith, Mitchell C. Groenenboom</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1603022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting information for "Modeling Palladium Surfaces with Density Functional Theory, Neural Networks and Molecular Dynamics"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.5849991</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, Tianyu Gao, Figshare. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4394406137

                This data set can be used to reproduce most of the figures and analysis in our paper "Modeling Palladium Surfaces with Density Functional Theory, Neural Networks and Molecular Dynamics". The details for how to use this dataset are in the supporting information file for that paper.Note, the original data was posted here: https://figshare.com/articles/Data_zip/4347956/1This dataset supercedes that one.</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin, Tianyu Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.5849991</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting information for "Neural network and ReaxFF comparison for Au properties, Int. J. Quantum Chem., 116(13), 979&#8211;987 (2016)."</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1603022.v1</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, Jacob R. Boes, John A. Keith, Mitchell C. Groenenboom, Figshare. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4394531894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin, Jacob R. Boes, John A. Keith, Mitchell C. Groenenboom</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1603022.v1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
