<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 02:01:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Low-level direct currents eradicate multi-drug-resistant Candidozyma auris through physiological stress and antifungal permeation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166070</link>
      <description>C. Royo, Charles Landis, Michael T. Geraghty, Sricharani Rao Balmuri, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Chemical Engineering Journal. 520(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412688025

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C. Royo, Charles Landis, Michael T. Geraghty, Sricharani Rao Balmuri, Tagbo H. R. Niepa</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50 years of mixed-integer nonlinear and disjunctive programming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejor.2025.07.016</link>
      <description>Jan Kronqvist, David E. Bernal, Ignacio E. Grossmann, European Journal of Operational Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412688049

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jan Kronqvist, David E. Bernal, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejor.2025.07.016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiphase computational fluid dynamics modeling of reacting flows in absorption columns for carbon capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100252</link>
      <description>Yash Girish Shah, Amiee Jackson, Costas Tsouris, Charles Finney, Grigorios Panagakos, Digital Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412702394

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yash Girish Shah, Amiee Jackson, Costas Tsouris, Charles Finney, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100252</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multistage Economic MPC for Systems with a Cyclic Steady State: A Gas Network Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.122276</link>
      <description>Sakshi Naik, Lavinia Marina Paola Ghilardi, Robert Parker, Lorenz T. Biegler, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412714218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sakshi Naik, Lavinia Marina Paola Ghilardi, Robert Parker, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.122276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping uncertainty using differentiable programming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18940</link>
      <description>Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird, Fernando V. Lima, John R. Kitchin, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412788564

                Abstract Uncertainty quantification (UQ) and propagation is a ubiquitous challenge in science, permeating our field in a general fashion, and its importance cannot be overstated. Recently, the commoditization of differentiable programming, motivated by the development of machine learning, has allowed easier access to tools for evaluating derivatives of complex systems, of implicit and nonlinear nature. Motivated by this, we develop a UQ mapping approach based on differentiable programming principles. The approach is novel, faster, and yields equally accurate results when compared against the current state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art approaches for the UQ problem, which is to quantify and map uncertainty using linear methods or expensive Monte Carlo simulations. Three case studies&#8212;namely a continuous stirred tank reactor, a membrane reactor, and a fed&#8208;batch bioreactor&#8212;are assessed and compared against typical uncertainty mapping techniques. Lastly, the method allows the use of a single model implementation to perform forward and inverse uncertainty maps, easily switching mapping directions.</description>
      <author>Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird, Fernando V. Lima, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic modeling of kinetic surface segregation mechanisms in CuAu binary alloys: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113413</link>
      <description>Nadia Ait Labyad, Abdallah El-asri, Moussa Amrani, Andrew J. Gellman, Herv&#233; Mart&#237;nez, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412792535

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nadia Ait Labyad, Abdallah El-asri, Moussa Amrani, Andrew J. Gellman, Herv&#233; Mart&#237;nez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances on MagLITe: deposition and photocollection efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-0221/20/08/c08002</link>
      <description>B. Gelli, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Rosa Sol&#224;, V.C. Palav&#233;ri, Paloma L&#243;pez-Reyes, Juan I. Larruquert, P. Schio, F. C. Marques, E. Kemp, Journal of Instrumentation. 20(08)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412827379

                Abstract MagLITe (Magnesium Fluoride Light collection Improvement Technique) is a novel approach to enhancing light collection efficiency in liquid argon (LAr) particle detectors while addressing critical limitations of traditional wavelength shifters (WLS). This work presents new results on the development, characterization, and performance of MagLITe. Using a protective thin-film coating of magnesium fluoride (MgF 2 ), MagLITe mitigates issues of WLS degradation and reflection losses while increasing photocollection efficiency. A modified Transfer Matrix Method (TMM) was employed to model and optimize the optical stack, and experimental validation was performed using a custom-designed LAr test setup. A first comparative measurements between bare WLS and MagLITe-coated samples demonstrate a 7.3% increase in photocollection efficiency, validating the potential of MagLITe for future large-scale neutrino experiments.</description>
      <author>B. Gelli, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Rosa Sol&#224;, V.C. Palav&#233;ri, Paloma L&#243;pez-Reyes, Juan I. Larruquert, P. Schio, F. C. Marques, E. Kemp</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-0221/20/08/c08002</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
