<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 01:20:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Modifying the Abdul-Razzak &amp;amp; Ghan aerosol activation parameterization (version ARG2000) impacts simulated cloud radiative effects (shown in the UK Met Office Unified Model, version 13.0)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2423</link>
      <description>Pratapaditya Ghosh, Katherine J. Evans, Daniel P. Grosvenor, Hyun&#8208;Gyu Kang, Salil Mahajan, Min Nina Xu, Wei Zhang, Hamish Gordon, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403497021

                Abstract. The representation of aerosol activation is a key source of uncertainty in global composition-climate model simulations of aerosol-cloud interactions. The Abdul-Razzak and Ghan (ARG) activation parameterization is used in several global and regional models that employ modal aerosol microphysics schemes. In this study, we investigate the ability of the ARG parameterization to reproduce simulations with a cloud parcel model, and find its performance is sensitive to the geometric standard deviations (widths) of the lognormal aerosol modes. We recommend adjustments to three constant parameters in the ARG equations, which improve the performance of the parameterization for small mode widths and its ability to simulate activation in polluted conditions. For the accumulation mode width of 1.4 used in the Met Office Unified Model (UM), our modifications decrease the mean bias in the activated fraction of aerosols compared to a cloud parcel model from -6.6 % to +1.2 %. We implemented our improvements in the UM and compared simulated global cloud droplet concentrations with satellite observations. The simulated cloud radiative effect changes by -1.43 Wm-2 and aerosol indirect radiative forcing over the industrial period changes by -0.10 Wm-2.</description>
      <author>Pratapaditya Ghosh, Katherine J. Evans, Daniel P. Grosvenor, Hyun&#8208;Gyu Kang, Salil Mahajan, Min Nina Xu, Wei Zhang, Hamish Gordon</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supplementary material to "Modifying the Abdul-Razzak &amp;amp; Ghan aerosol activation parameterization (version ARG2000) impacts simulated cloud radiative effects (shown in the UK Met Office Unified Model, version 13.0)"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2423-supplement</link>
      <description>Pratapaditya Ghosh, Katherine J. Evans, Daniel P. Grosvenor, Hyun&#8208;Gyu Kang, Salil Mahajan, Min Xu, Wei Zhang, Hamish Gordon, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403497188

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pratapaditya Ghosh, Katherine J. Evans, Daniel P. Grosvenor, Hyun&#8208;Gyu Kang, Salil Mahajan, Min Xu, Wei Zhang, Hamish Gordon</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2423-supplement</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low temperature growth of sub 10-nm particles by ammonium nitrate condensation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00117f</link>
      <description>Neil M. Donahue, Mao Xiao, Ruby Marten, Mingyi Wang, Weimeng Kong, Meredith Schervish, Qing Ye, Victoria Hofbauer, Lubna Dada, Jonathan Duplissy, Henning Finkenzeller, Hamish Gordon, J. Kirkby, Houssni Lamkaddam, Vladimir Makhmutov, Maxim Philippov, Birte R&#246;rup, Rainer Volkamer, Dongyu Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Richard C. Flagan, Dominik Stolzenburg, Imad El Haddad, Environmental Science Atmospheres. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403597421

                Co-condensation of nitric acid and ammonia vapors to form ammonium nitrate transforms from a fully semi-volatile behavior when it is relatively warm (273 K and above, typical of the seasonal...</description>
      <author>Neil M. Donahue, Mao Xiao, Ruby Marten, Mingyi Wang, Weimeng Kong, Meredith Schervish, Qing Ye, Victoria Hofbauer, Lubna Dada, Jonathan Duplissy, Henning Finkenzeller, Hamish Gordon, J. Kirkby, Houssni Lamkaddam, Vladimir Makhmutov, Maxim Philippov, Birte R&#246;rup, Rainer Volkamer, Dongyu Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Richard C. Flagan, Dominik Stolzenburg, Imad El Haddad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00117f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biosensing of Bacterial Secretions via Topological Defects at Smectic Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02698</link>
      <description>Vajra S. Badha, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Mohamed Amine Gharbi, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403609907

                Characterizing the anchoring properties of smectic liquid crystals (LCs) in contact with bacterial solutions is crucial for developing biosensing platforms. In this study, we investigate the anchoring properties of a smectic LC when exposed to Bacillus subtilis and Escherichia coli bacterial suspensions using interfaces with known anchoring properties. By monitoring the optical response of the smectic film, we successfully distinguish different types of bacteria, leveraging the distinct changes in the LC's response. Through a comprehensive analysis of the interactions between bacterial proteins and the smectic interface, we elucidate the potential underlying mechanisms responsible for these optical changes. Additionally, we introduce the utilization of topological defects, the focal conic domains (FCDs), at the smectic interface as an indicative measure of the bacterial concentration. Our findings contribute to the understanding of bacteria&#8211;LC interactions and demonstrate the significant potential of smectic LCs and their defects for biosensing applications, paving the way for advancements in pathogen detection and protein-based sensing.</description>
      <author>Vajra S. Badha, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Mohamed Amine Gharbi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Low temperature growth of sub 10-nm particles by ammonium nitrate condensation"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00117f/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Neil M. Donahue, Mao Xiao, Ruby Marten, Mingyi Wang, Weimeng Kong, Meredith Schervish, Qing Ye, Victoria Hofbauer, Lubna Dada, Jonathan Duplissy, Henning Finkenzeller, Hamish Gordon, J. Kirkby, Houssni Lamkaddam, Vladimir Makhmutov, Maxim Philippov, Birte R&#246;rup, Rainer Volkamer, Dongyu Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Richard C. Flagan, Dominik Stolzenburg, Imad El Haddad, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403630514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Neil M. Donahue, Mao Xiao, Ruby Marten, Mingyi Wang, Weimeng Kong, Meredith Schervish, Qing Ye, Victoria Hofbauer, Lubna Dada, Jonathan Duplissy, Henning Finkenzeller, Hamish Gordon, J. Kirkby, Houssni Lamkaddam, Vladimir Makhmutov, Maxim Philippov, Birte R&#246;rup, Rainer Volkamer, Dongyu Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Richard C. Flagan, Dominik Stolzenburg, Imad El Haddad</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00117f/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving the security constrained unit commitment problem: Three novel approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijepes.2024.110213</link>
      <description>Alessandro Francesco Castelli, Iiro Harjunkoski, Jan Poland, Marco Giuntoli, Emanuele Martelli, Ignacio E. Grossmann, International Journal of Electrical Power &amp; Energy Systems. 162(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403631750

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alessandro Francesco Castelli, Iiro Harjunkoski, Jan Poland, Marco Giuntoli, Emanuele Martelli, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijepes.2024.110213</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
