<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 15:47:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale analysis for the utilization of CO2 towards the production of chemicals at the country level: Case study of Spain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.140551</link>
      <description>Guillermo Gal&#225;n, Mariano Mart&#237;n, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024.
This work evaluates a systematic comparison between the production of methanol and methane using CO2 and renewable hydrogen. CO2 is captured from point and dilute sources using aqueous MEA solutions and a conventional DAC process. Hydrogen is obtained through water electrolysis, powered by PV panels and wind turbines. First, a techno-economic evaluation is developed to detail the characteristics of the production facilities and the renewable energy systems. Finally, a Facility Location Problem (FLP) is developed to determine the centralized and decentralized CO2 use in Spain. This supply network is formulated as a mixed-integer linear programming (MILP) problem, selecting the optimal amount of CO2 to capture, the number and location of the facilities, the distribution of the PV panels for a fixed available area in the territory, and the number of wind turbines across the 47 Spanish peninsular provinces. Methanol is the selected product, with prices between 1000&#8211;2600 &#8364;/tMethanol. MEA solutions are preferred over DAC. Methane production is also considered through decentralized CO2 capture due to abundant CO2 availability and high transportation costs. A sensitivity analysis was performed, obtaining prices from 18.97 to 20.36 &#8364;/MMBTU to 8.90&#8211;9.09 &#8364;/MMBTU in the years 2022 and 2050, covering 5 times the methane production for that period. The implementation of carbon taxes could lower methane prices to around 2&#8211;3 &#8364;/MMBTU by 2050, aligning closely with natural gas prices.</description>
      <author>Guillermo Gal&#225;n, Mariano Mart&#237;n, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.140551</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
