<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:25:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Isoprene chemistry under upper-tropospheric conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-64229-w</link>
      <description>Douglas M. Russell, Felix Kunkler, Jiali Shen, Matthias Kohl, Jenna DeVivo, Nirvan Bhattacharyya, Christos Xenofontos, Hannah Klebach, Luc&#237;a Caudillo-Plath, Mario Simon, Emelda Ahongshangbam, J. Almeida, A. Amorim, H. Beckmann, M. Busato, Manjula R. Canagaratna, Anouck Chassaing, R&#243;mulo Cruz-Simbr&#243;n, Lubna Dada, Philip Holzbeck, Bernhard Judmaier, Milin Kaniyodical Sebastian, Paap Koemets, Thinus F. Kruger, Lu Liu, M&#243;nica Mart&#237;nez, Bernhard Mentler, Aleksandra Morawiec, Antti Onnela, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#228;, Pedro Rato, Mago Reza, Samuel Ruhl, Wiebke Scholz, Eva Sommer, Ant&#243;nio Tom&#233;, Yandong Tong, Jens Top, Nsikanabasi Silas Umo, Gabriela Rosalino Unfer, Ryan X. Ward, Jakob Weissbacher, Boxing Yang, Wenjuan Yu, Marcel Zauner-Wieczorek, Imad Zgheib, Jiangyi Zhang, Zhensen Zheng, Imad El Haddad, Richard C. Flagan, Armin Hansel, Heikki Junninen, Markku Kulmala, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Jos Lelieveld, Ottmar M&#246;hler, Siegfried Schobesberger, Rainer Volkamer, Paul M. Winkler, Douglas R. Worsnop, T. Christoudias, Andrea Pozzer, Neil M. Donahue, Hartwig Harder, J. Kirkby, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Joachim Curtius, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414602749

                Abstract Isoprene (C 5 H 8 ) is the non-methane hydrocarbon with the highest emissions to the atmosphere. It is mainly produced by vegetation, especially broad-leaved trees, and efficiently transported to the upper troposphere in deep convective clouds, where it is mixed with lightning NO x . Isoprene oxidation products drive rapid formation and growth of new particles in the tropical upper troposphere. However, isoprene oxidation pathways at low temperatures are not well understood. Here, in experiments at the CERN CLOUD chamber at 223 K and 243 K, we find that isoprene oxygenated organic molecules (IP-OOM) all involve two successive $${{{\rm{OH}}}}^{\bullet}$$    OH   &#8729;    oxidations. However, depending on the ambient concentrations of the termination radicals ( $${{{{\rm{HO}}}}_{2}}^{\bullet},\,{{{\rm{NO}}}}^{\bullet}$$      HO   2     &#8729;   ,    NO   &#8729;    , and $${{{\rm{NO}}}}_{2}^{\bullet}$$    NO   2   &#8729;    ), vastly-different IP-OOM emerge, comprising compounds with zero, one or two nitrogen atoms. Our findings indicate high IP-OOM production rates for the tropical upper troposphere, mainly resulting in nitrate IP-OOM but with an increasing non-nitrate fraction around midday, in close agreement with aircraft observations.</description>
      <author>Douglas M. Russell, Felix Kunkler, Jiali Shen, Matthias Kohl, Jenna DeVivo, Nirvan Bhattacharyya, Christos Xenofontos, Hannah Klebach, Luc&#237;a Caudillo-Plath, Mario Simon, Emelda Ahongshangbam, J. Almeida, A. Amorim, H. Beckmann, M. Busato, Manjula R. Canagaratna, Anouck Chassaing, R&#243;mulo Cruz-Simbr&#243;n, Lubna Dada, Philip Holzbeck, Bernhard Judmaier, Milin Kaniyodical Sebastian, Paap Koemets, Thinus F. Kruger, Lu Liu, M&#243;nica Mart&#237;nez, Bernhard Mentler, Aleksandra Morawiec, Antti Onnela, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#228;, Pedro Rato, Mago Reza, Samuel Ruhl, Wiebke Scholz, Eva Sommer, Ant&#243;nio Tom&#233;, Yandong Tong, Jens Top, Nsikanabasi Silas Umo, Gabriela Rosalino Unfer, Ryan X. Ward, Jakob Weissbacher, Boxing Yang, Wenjuan Yu, Marcel Zauner-Wieczorek, Imad Zgheib, Jiangyi Zhang, Zhensen Zheng, Imad El Haddad, Richard C. Flagan, Armin Hansel, Heikki Junninen, Markku Kulmala, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Jos Lelieveld, Ottmar M&#246;hler, Siegfried Schobesberger, Rainer Volkamer, Paul M. Winkler, Douglas R. Worsnop, T. Christoudias, Andrea Pozzer, Neil M. Donahue, Hartwig Harder, J. Kirkby, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Joachim Curtius</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-64229-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protein corona formed on lipid nanoparticles compromises delivery efficiency of mRNA cargo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63726-2</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Voke, Mariah L. Arral, Henry Squire, Teng-Jui Lin, Lining Zheng, Roxana Coreas, Alison Lui, Anthony T. Iavarone, Rebecca L. Pinals, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Markita P. Landry, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414650697

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Voke, Mariah L. Arral, Henry Squire, Teng-Jui Lin, Lining Zheng, Roxana Coreas, Alison Lui, Anthony T. Iavarone, Rebecca L. Pinals, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Markita P. Landry</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63726-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectral Manifold Harmonization for Graph Imbalanced Regression</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2507.01132</link>
      <description>Brenda Nogueira, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Meng Jiang, Nitesh V. Chawla, Nuno Moniz, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414688037

                Graph-structured data is ubiquitous in scientific domains, where models often face imbalanced learning settings. In imbalanced regression, domain preferences focus on specific target value ranges that represent the most scientifically valuable cases; however, we observe a significant lack of research regarding this challenge. In this paper, we present Spectral Manifold Harmonization (SMH), a novel approach to address imbalanced regression challenges on graph-structured data by generating synthetic graph samples that preserve topological properties while focusing on the most relevant target distribution regions. Conventional methods fail in this context because they either ignore graph topology in case generation or do not target specific domain ranges, resulting in models biased toward average target values. Experimental results demonstrate the potential of SMH on chemistry and drug discovery benchmark datasets, showing consistent improvements in predictive performance for target domain ranges. Code is available at https://github.com/brendacnogueira/smh-graph-imbalance.git.</description>
      <author>Brenda Nogueira, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Meng Jiang, Nitesh V. Chawla, Nuno Moniz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2507.01132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting chemical and protein sequence space to predict biocatalytic reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-025-09519-5</link>
      <description>Alan Paton, Daniil A. Boiko, Jonathan C. Perkins, Nicholas Cemalovic, Thiago Resch&#252;tzegger, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Alison R. H. Narayan, Nature. 646(8083)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414690409

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alan Paton, Daniil A. Boiko, Jonathan C. Perkins, Nicholas Cemalovic, Thiago Resch&#252;tzegger, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Alison R. H. Narayan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-025-09519-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Electrolyte pH Affects the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c14208</link>
      <description>Jay T. Bender, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Nicolas Bueno Ponce, Angel E. Valles, Alyssa K. Uvodich, Delia J. Milliron, John R. Kitchin, Joaquin Resasco, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414731738

                Electrolyte pH is known to affect catalytic activity and selectivity for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). But a clear understanding of why ORR rates respond more strongly to pH over certain catalysts than others has not been developed. Here, we propose that pH effects on the ORR result from electric field induced changes in the binding energies of intermediates involved in kinetically relevant elementary steps. For strongly binding metals (Pt, Ir, Ru, and Pd), whose rates are limited by the proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) step to form *OOH or remove adsorbed OH (*OH), ORR rates are weakly affected by electrolyte pH. This behavior is observed because the binding energies of the reaction intermediates in these steps are minimally affected by electric field strength. The weak pH dependence is most pronounced for Pt, which shows essentially identical rates in acidic and alkaline electrolytes. For weakly binding metals (Au, Ag), whose rates are limited by non-PCET O2 adsorption, ORR rates increase significantly when moving from acidic to alkaline electrolytes. This strong pH dependence results from the stabilization of adsorbed O2 by the increasingly negative electric field present at the catalyst surface under alkaline conditions. We argue that modifying electrolyte pH does not change the rate-determining elementary step for the ORR, but does decrease the apparent activation barrier for O2 adsorption over weakly binding catalysts. These arguments are substantiated by a combination of experimental kinetic studies and atomistic simulations.</description>
      <author>Jay T. Bender, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Nicolas Bueno Ponce, Angel E. Valles, Alyssa K. Uvodich, Delia J. Milliron, John R. Kitchin, Joaquin Resasco</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c14208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-term measurements of wind and turbulence from a calibrated 1290 MHz radar wind profiler at the Eastern North Atlantic atmospheric observatory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2025-4434</link>
      <description>August Mikkelsen, Virendra P. Ghate, Daniel T. McCoy, Hamish Gordon, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414822723

                Abstract. Turbulence in the marine boundary layer is closely coupled with the physical properties of marine boundary layer clouds. However, these turbulent motions are difficult to observe, resulting in very few observations of turbulence properties over the open oceans. In this work data collected by the 1290 MHz Radar Wind Profiler (RWP) part of the Atmospheric Radiation Measurement (ARM) Eastern North Atlantic (ENA) site are used to characterize winds and boundary layer turbulence. The RWP wind, precipitation long pulse and precipitation short pulse modes were calibrated using the surface laser disdrometer. Over the 10 years of data analyzed here, the RWP wind mode calibration constant, sensitivity, and dynamic range fluctuated between -84 to -44 dB, -15 to 9 dBZ, and 12 to 21 dBZ, respectively. The clear-air RWP echoes were used to derive structure function of the refractive index (Cn2) and dissipation rates of turbulence kinetic energy (&#949;). Both Cn2 and &#949; decreased from surface upwards with higher values in the winter months and lower values in the summer months consistent with previous studies. Despite the marine location, the &#949; was affected by island heating during southerly wind conditions. The results reported herein have implications for RWP operational research and climatological studies at the ARM ENA site.</description>
      <author>August Mikkelsen, Virendra P. Ghate, Daniel T. McCoy, Hamish Gordon</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2025-4434</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
