<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 01:08:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of CO2 capture plants with surrogate model uncertainties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108709</link>
      <description>A. Pedrozo, C. M. Valderrama-R&#237;os, Miguel Zamarripa, Josh Morgan, Juan-Pablo Osorio-Su&#225;rez, Ariel Uribe-Rodr&#237;guez, M. Soledad Diaz, Lorenz T. Biegler, Computers &amp; chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395033023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Pedrozo, C. M. Valderrama-R&#237;os, Miguel Zamarripa, Josh Morgan, Juan-Pablo Osorio-Su&#225;rez, Ariel Uribe-Rodr&#237;guez, M. Soledad Diaz, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: Mechanobiology of biofilms and associated host -pathogen interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fcimb.2024.1416131</link>
      <description>Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Landon W. Locke, Timothy E. Corcoran, Janet Lee, Frontiers in cellular and infection microbiology. 14(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395045737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Landon W. Locke, Timothy E. Corcoran, Janet Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fcimb.2024.1416131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Bayesian parameter estimation with model&#8208;based design of experiments for dynamic processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18418</link>
      <description>Xinyu Cao, Xi Chen, Xi Chen, Lorenz T. Biegler, AIChE journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395087592

                Abstract Integration of Bayesian parameter estimation (BPE) with model&#8208;based design of experiments (MBDoE) aims to estimate process parameters efficiently and systematically. To achieve more efficient use of resources by iteratively selecting informative experiments based on current knowledge about the parameters, an integrated method with BPE and MBDoE is proposed in this article. A built&#8208;in Markov Chain Monte Carlo is also developed to yield not only the distribution profile of the estimated parameters but also aid in the determination of stopping criteria and the estimation of noise. Two applications of dynamic batch reactor systems are presented. Comparative analysis substantiates the superior performance of this approach in terms of parameter accuracy and the efficiency of experimentation.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Cao, Xi Chen, Xi Chen, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tailored decomposition approach for optimization under uncertainty of carbon removal technologies in the EU power system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108691</link>
      <description>Valentina Negri, Daniel V&#225;zquez, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Gonzalo Guill&#233;n&#8208;Gos&#225;lbez, Computers &amp; chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395658791

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Valentina Negri, Daniel V&#225;zquez, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Gonzalo Guill&#233;n&#8208;Gos&#225;lbez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iterative MILP algorithm to find alternate solutions in linear programming models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11081-024-09887-3</link>
      <description>D. Kakkad, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Bianca Springub, Christos Galanopoulos, Leonardo Salsano de Assis, Nga Tran, John M. Wassick, Optimization and engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395671135

                Abstract We address in this paper linear programming (LP) models in which it is desired to find a finite set of alternate optima. An LP may have multiple alternate solutions with the same objective value or with increasing objective values. For many real life applications, it can be interesting to have a pool of solutions to compare what operations should be executed and what is the cost/benefit of doing it. To obtain a specified number of these alternate solutions in the increasing order of objective values, we propose an iterative MILP algorithm in which we successively add integer cuts on inactive constraints. We demonstrate the application and effectiveness of this algorithm on a 2 dimensional LP and on small and large supply chain problems. The proposed iterative MILP algorithm provides an effective approach for finding a specified number of alternate optima in LP models, which provides a useful tool in a variety of applications as for instance in supply chain optimization problems.</description>
      <author>D. Kakkad, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Bianca Springub, Christos Galanopoulos, Leonardo Salsano de Assis, Nga Tran, John M. Wassick</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11081-024-09887-3</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
