<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 01:23:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Variable aggregation for nonlinear optimization problems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2502.13869</link>
      <description>Sakshi Naik, Lorenz T. Biegler, Russell Bent, Robert Parker, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407793209

                Variable aggregation has been largely studied as an important pre-solve algorithm for optimization of linear and mixed-integer programs. Although some nonlinear solvers and algebraic modeling languages implement variable aggregation as a pre-solve, the impact it can have on constrained nonlinear programs is unexplored. In this work, we formalize variable aggregation as a pre-solve algorithm to develop reduced-space formulations of nonlinear programs. A novel approximate maximum variable aggregation strategy is developed to aggregate as many variables as possible. Furthermore, aggregation strategies that preserve the problem structure are compared against approximate maximum aggregation. Our results show that variable aggregation can generally help to improve the convergence reliability of nonlinear programs. It can also help in reducing total solve time. However, Hessian evaluation can become a bottleneck if aggregation significantly increases the number of variables appearing nonlinearly in many constraints.</description>
      <author>Sakshi Naik, Lorenz T. Biegler, Russell Bent, Robert Parker</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2502.13869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Simulations Suggest Biomass Burning Aerosols are Regionally Important Ice Nucleating Particles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.174043088.83664402/v1</link>
      <description>Kanishk Gohil, Ryan C. Sullivan, Paul J. DeMott, Hamish Gordon, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407873079

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kanishk Gohil, Ryan C. Sullivan, Paul J. DeMott, Hamish Gordon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.174043088.83664402/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incomplete mass closure in atmospheric nanoparticle growth</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-025-00893-5</link>
      <description>Dominik Stolzenburg, Nina Sarnela, Federico Bianchi, Jing Cai, Runlong Cai, Yafang Cheng, Lubna Dada, Neil M. Donahue, Hinrich Grothe, Sebastian Holm, Veli&#8208;Matti Kerminen, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#228;, Juha Sulo, Paul M. Winkler, Chao Yan, Juha Kangasluoma, Markku Kulmala, npj Climate and Atmospheric Science. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407927611

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dominik Stolzenburg, Nina Sarnela, Federico Bianchi, Jing Cai, Runlong Cai, Yafang Cheng, Lubna Dada, Neil M. Donahue, Hinrich Grothe, Sebastian Holm, Veli&#8208;Matti Kerminen, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#228;, Juha Sulo, Paul M. Winkler, Chao Yan, Juha Kangasluoma, Markku Kulmala</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-025-00893-5</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
