<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 12:06:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-use capabilities of concern of biological AI models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012975</link>
      <description>Jaspreet Pannu, Doni Bloomfield, Robert MacKnight, Magda&#8208;Viola Hanke, Alex W. Zhu, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Anita Cicero, Thomas V. Inglesby, PLoS Computational Biology. 21(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410204437

                As a result of rapidly accelerating artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities, multiple national governments and multinational bodies have launched efforts to address safety, security and ethics issues related to AI models. One high priority among these efforts is the mitigation of misuse of AI models, such as for the development of chemical, biological, nuclear or radiological (CBRN) threats. Many biologists have for decades sought to reduce the risks of scientific research that could lead, through accident or misuse, to high-consequence disease outbreaks. Scientists have carefully considered what types of life sciences research have the potential for both benefit and risk (dual use), especially as scientific advances have accelerated our ability to engineer organisms. Here we describe how previous experience and study by scientists and policy professionals of dual-use research in the life sciences can inform dual-use capabilities of AI models trained using biological data. Of these dual-use capabilities, we argue that AI model evaluations should prioritize addressing those which enable high-consequence risks (i.e., large-scale harm to the public, such as transmissible disease outbreaks that could develop into pandemics), and that these risks should be evaluated prior to model deployment so as to allow potential biosafety and/or biosecurity measures. While biological research is on balance immensely beneficial, it is well recognized that some biological information or technologies could be intentionally or inadvertently misused to cause consequential harm to the public. AI-enabled life sciences research is no different. Scientists&#8217; historical experience with identifying and mitigating dual-use biological risks can thus help inform new approaches to evaluating biological AI models. Identifying which AI capabilities pose the greatest biosecurity and biosafety concerns is necessary in order to establish targeted AI safety evaluation methods, secure these tools against accident and misuse, and avoid impeding immense potential benefits.</description>
      <author>Jaspreet Pannu, Doni Bloomfield, Robert MacKnight, Magda&#8208;Viola Hanke, Alex W. Zhu, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Anita Cicero, Thomas V. Inglesby</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear Model Predictive Control with an Infinite Horizon Approximation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5249681</link>
      <description>Lorenz T. Biegler, San Dinh, Yao Tong, Zhenyu Wei, Owen Gerdes, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410253659

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lorenz T. Biegler, San Dinh, Yao Tong, Zhenyu Wei, Owen Gerdes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5249681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Retrofit of Carbon Capture and Electrification Technologies in Oil Refineries for Reducing Direct CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04995</link>
      <description>S. Chattopadhyay, Kaliaperumal Karthikeyan, Rahul Gandhi, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Ana I. Torres, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410269108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Chattopadhyay, Kaliaperumal Karthikeyan, Rahul Gandhi, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In vitro monitoring of Babesia microti infection dynamics in whole blood microenvironments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.05.07.652765</link>
      <description>Chao Li, Emily G. Bache, Amy L. Apgar, Danielle M. Tufts, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410335725

                Babesiosis &#8212; a globally emerging tick-borne infectious disease primarily caused by the intraerythrocytic piroplasm parasite, Babesia microti &#8212; has traditionally been studied using animal models such as mice. Compared to animal models, microfluidic-based models offer advantages, including direct analysis of human samples (such as patient blood), enhanced assay capacity (including physical/optical access, consistency, and throughput), low costs, and easy adoption. Here, we report an open microfluidic platform named &#956;&#8211;Blood for monitoring B. microti infection dynamics in vitro. Compared to other microfluidic-based models, &#956;&#8211;Blood allows direct examination of infected and uninfected whole blood without preprocessing steps like blood dilution or cell isolation, minimizing observer artifacts and preserving the natural whole blood microenvironment. The system enables extended (days-long) monitoring of infection dynamics, including parasite identification, parasitemia measurement, and parasite-host cell interactions, using label-free phase contrast and fluorescence confocal microscopy. With its open microfluidic configuration, &#956;-Blood provides an in vitro model for studying blood-borne infections while maintaining integrity of the whole blood microenvironment.</description>
      <author>Chao Li, Emily G. Bache, Amy L. Apgar, Danielle M. Tufts, Tagbo H. R. Niepa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.05.07.652765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and optimization of circular economy networks&#8212;A case study of PET</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2025.109164</link>
      <description>Abdulhakeem Ahmed, Anoop N. Nair, Ana I. Torres, Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410348848

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulhakeem Ahmed, Anoop N. Nair, Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2025.109164</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
