<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 01:48:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering an Electroactive Bacterial Cellulose-Carbon Nanotube Composite Membrane Against Staphylococcus aureus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioflm.2025.100305</link>
      <description>Daniel L. Levin, Camila S. Cu&#233;-Royo, Denis Johnson, Soumalya Gosh, Sricharani Rao Balmuri, Huda Usman, Shakira M. Martinez-Vasquez, David Kumar Yesudoss, Abdoulaye Djire, Mostafa Bedewy, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, Biofilm. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412494346

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel L. Levin, Camila S. Cu&#233;-Royo, Denis Johnson, Soumalya Gosh, Sricharani Rao Balmuri, Huda Usman, Shakira M. Martinez-Vasquez, David Kumar Yesudoss, Abdoulaye Djire, Mostafa Bedewy, Tagbo H. R. Niepa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioflm.2025.100305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A diagonal volatility basis set to assess the condensation of organic vapors onto particles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ea00062a</link>
      <description>Brandon Lopez, Nirvan Bhattacharyya, Jenna DeVivo, Mingyi Wang, Luc&#237;a Caudillo, Mihnea Surdu, Federico Bianchi, Zo&#233; Brasseur, Angela Buchholz, Dexian Chen, Jonathan Duplissy, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Victoria Hofbauer, Naser G. A. Mahfouz, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Ruby Marten, Bernhard Mentler, Maxim Philippov, Meredith Schervish, Dongyu Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Andr&#233; Welti, Imad El Haddad, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Markku Kulmala, Douglas R. Worsnop, J. Kirkby, Roy L. Mauldin, Dominik Stolzenburg, Siegfried Schobesberger, Richard C. Flagan, Neil M. Donahue, Environmental Science Atmospheres. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412539819

                We present a &#8220;diagonal&#8221; Volatility Basis Set (dVBS) comparing gas-phase concentrations of oxygenated organic molecules (OOM) to their condensed-phase mass fractions. This permits closure of vapor concentrations with particle composition...</description>
      <author>Brandon Lopez, Nirvan Bhattacharyya, Jenna DeVivo, Mingyi Wang, Luc&#237;a Caudillo, Mihnea Surdu, Federico Bianchi, Zo&#233; Brasseur, Angela Buchholz, Dexian Chen, Jonathan Duplissy, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Victoria Hofbauer, Naser G. A. Mahfouz, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Ruby Marten, Bernhard Mentler, Maxim Philippov, Meredith Schervish, Dongyu Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Andr&#233; Welti, Imad El Haddad, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Markku Kulmala, Douglas R. Worsnop, J. Kirkby, Roy L. Mauldin, Dominik Stolzenburg, Siegfried Schobesberger, Richard C. Flagan, Neil M. Donahue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ea00062a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "A diagonal volatility basis set to assess the condensation of organic vapors onto particles"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ea00062a/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Brandon Lopez, Nirvan Bhattacharyya, Jenna DeVivo, Mingyi Wang, Luc&#237;a Caudillo, Mihnea Surdu, Federico Bianchi, Zo&#233; Brasseur, Angela Buchholz, Dexian Chen, Jonathan Duplissy, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Victoria Hofbauer, Naser G. A. Mahfouz, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Ruby Marten, Bernhard Mentler, Maxim Philippov, Meredith Schervish, Dongyu Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Andr&#233; Welti, Imad El Haddad, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Markku Kulmala, Douglas R. Worsnop, J. Kirkby, Roy L. Mauldin, Dominik Stolzenburg, Siegfried Schobesberger, Richard C. Flagan, Neil M. Donahue, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412565945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brandon Lopez, Nirvan Bhattacharyya, Jenna DeVivo, Mingyi Wang, Luc&#237;a Caudillo, Mihnea Surdu, Federico Bianchi, Zo&#233; Brasseur, Angela Buchholz, Dexian Chen, Jonathan Duplissy, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Victoria Hofbauer, Naser G. A. Mahfouz, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Ruby Marten, Bernhard Mentler, Maxim Philippov, Meredith Schervish, Dongyu Wang, Stefan K. Weber, Andr&#233; Welti, Imad El Haddad, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Markku Kulmala, Douglas R. Worsnop, J. Kirkby, Roy L. Mauldin, Dominik Stolzenburg, Siegfried Schobesberger, Richard C. Flagan, Neil M. Donahue</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ea00062a/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing forest planning: Balancing timber production and carbon sequestration through a multi-objective disjunctive formulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forpol.2025.103575</link>
      <description>Frank Piedra-Jim&#233;nez, Diego Broz, Juan M. Novas, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Mar&#237;a Anal&#237;a Rodriguez, Forest Policy and Economics. 178(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412589428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Frank Piedra-Jim&#233;nez, Diego Broz, Juan M. Novas, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Mar&#237;a Anal&#237;a Rodriguez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forpol.2025.103575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calibrating Interdependent Photochemistry, Nucleation, and Aerosol Microphysics in Chamber Experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2025-2412</link>
      <description>Neil M. Donahue, Victoria Hofbauer, Henning Finkenzeller, Dominik Stolzenburg, Paulus S. Bauer, Randall Chiu, Lubna Dada, Jonathan Duplissy, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Martin Heinritzi, C. R. Hoyle, Andreas K&#252;rten, &#1040;. &#1053;. &#1050;&#1074;&#1072;&#1096;&#1085;&#1080;&#1085;, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Naser G. A. Mahfouz, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Roy L. Mauldin, Ugo Molteni, Lauriane L. J. Qu&#233;l&#233;ver, Matti Rissanen, Siegfried Schobesberger, Mario Simon, Andrea C. Wagner, Mingyi Wang, Chao Yan, Penglin Ye, Ilona Riipinen, Hamish Gordon, Joachim Curtius, Armin Hansel, Imad El Haddad, Markku Kulmala, Douglas R. Worsnop, Rainer Volkamer, Paul M. Winkler, J. Kirkby, Richard C. Flagan, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412634907

                Abstract. Laboratory experiments addressing complex phenomena such as atmospheric new-particle formation and growth typically involve numerous instruments measuring a range of key coupled variables. In addition to independent calibration, the combined dataset provides not just constraints on the parameters of interest but also on the critical instrument calibrations. Here we find good agreement between production and loss rates of sulfuric acid (H2SO4) in an experiment performed at the CERN CLOUD chamber involving oxidation of sulfur dioxide (SO2) in the presence of ammonia (NH3) at 58 % relative humidity, driving new-particle formation and growth of particles by H2SO4 + NH3 nucleation initiated by O3 photolysis via several light sources. This closure requires consistency across numerous parameters, including: the particle number and size distribution; their condensation sink for H2SO4; the particle growth rates; the concentration of H2SO4; and the nucleation coefficients for both neutral and ion-induced pathways. Our study shows that accurate agreement can be achieved between production and loss of condensable vapors in laboratory chambers under atmospheric conditions, with accuracy ultimately tied to particle number measurement (i.e. a condensation particle counter). This, in turn implies parameters such as the H2SO4 concentration and particle size distributions can be determined to a comparable precision.</description>
      <author>Neil M. Donahue, Victoria Hofbauer, Henning Finkenzeller, Dominik Stolzenburg, Paulus S. Bauer, Randall Chiu, Lubna Dada, Jonathan Duplissy, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, Martin Heinritzi, C. R. Hoyle, Andreas K&#252;rten, &#1040;. &#1053;. &#1050;&#1074;&#1072;&#1096;&#1085;&#1080;&#1085;, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Naser G. A. Mahfouz, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Roy L. Mauldin, Ugo Molteni, Lauriane L. J. Qu&#233;l&#233;ver, Matti Rissanen, Siegfried Schobesberger, Mario Simon, Andrea C. Wagner, Mingyi Wang, Chao Yan, Penglin Ye, Ilona Riipinen, Hamish Gordon, Joachim Curtius, Armin Hansel, Imad El Haddad, Markku Kulmala, Douglas R. Worsnop, Rainer Volkamer, Paul M. Winkler, J. Kirkby, Richard C. Flagan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2025-2412</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
