<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 01:19:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Development of an integrated modeling framework for visibility and air quality forecasting in Delhi</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/bams-d-24-0194.1</link>
      <description>A. Jayakumar, T. J. Anurose, Shweta Bhati, M. A. Hendry, Garry Hayman, Hamish Gordon, Paul R. Field, Saji Mohandas, Heather Rumbold, Prafull Yadav, Narendra G. Dhangar, Avinash N. Parde, Sandeep Wagh, Sachin D. Ghude, Andrew Ross, Daniel Smith, Stephen Dorling, John P. George, V. Siva Prasad, M. Ravichandran, Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406469103

                Abstract Rapid urbanization has subjected the megacities of developing countries to various environmental stresses. Delhi, a major Indian megacity, faces increasing urban stress leading to reduction in air quality, and visibility. These challenges necessitate an integrated modeling framework to mitigate adverse environmental impacts on public health. Therefore, we have developed an advanced version of the high-resolution Delhi Model with Chemistry and Aerosol framework (DM-Chem) at the National Centre for Medium Range Weather Forecasting (NCMRWF) under the Weather and Climate Science for Service Partnership India (WCSSP India) project. This collaborative initiative between India and the UK aims to provide real-time forecasts of visibility and fine particulate matter (PM 2.5 ) for Delhi and neighbouring regions during the winter season. The DM Chem framework is unique due to its detailed urban canopy scheme and realistic aerosol representation, making it well-suited for city-scale forecasts. It is designed to predict extreme fog and pollution events in the winter season. Here we discuss the major physical parameterization improvements for the model, along with its skill and deficiencies in predicting extreme events. Notably, irrigation effects on surrounding agricultural areas have significantly improved fog and visibility forecasts, but have degraded the wind forecasts. We demonstrate the applicability of this modeling framework to study aerosol-radiation interaction during fog holes and discuss its potential to be applied or adapted to other megacities worldwide.</description>
      <author>A. Jayakumar, T. J. Anurose, Shweta Bhati, M. A. Hendry, Garry Hayman, Hamish Gordon, Paul R. Field, Saji Mohandas, Heather Rumbold, Prafull Yadav, Narendra G. Dhangar, Avinash N. Parde, Sandeep Wagh, Sachin D. Ghude, Andrew Ross, Daniel Smith, Stephen Dorling, John P. George, V. Siva Prasad, M. Ravichandran</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1175/bams-d-24-0194.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logic-Based Discrete-Steepest Descent: A solution method for process synthesis Generalized Disjunctive Programs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108993</link>
      <description>Daniel Ovalle, David A. Li&#241;&#225;n, Albert Lee, Jorge M. G&#243;mez, Luis Ricardez&#8208;Sandoval, Ignacio E. Grossmann, David E. Bernal, Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406519921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel Ovalle, David A. Li&#241;&#225;n, Albert Lee, Jorge M. G&#243;mez, Luis Ricardez&#8208;Sandoval, Ignacio E. Grossmann, David E. Bernal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RTN Model for Supply Logistics of Carbon Dioxide in the Field Management for Carbon Capture and Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02991</link>
      <description>Joelle Guisso, Soumya Shikha, Alejandro Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Anna Robert, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406624634

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joelle Guisso, Soumya Shikha, Alejandro Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Anna Robert, Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02991</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
