<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 01:12:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Conflict-Based Model Predictive Control for Scalable Multi-Robot Motion Planning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/icra57147.2024.10611078</link>
      <description>Ardalan Tajbakhsh, Lorenz T. Biegler, Aaron M. Johnson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401415691

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ardalan Tajbakhsh, Lorenz T. Biegler, Aaron M. Johnson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/icra57147.2024.10611078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substantial contribution of transported emissions to organic aerosol in Beijing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01493-3</link>
      <description>Kaspar R. Daellenbach, Jing Cai, Simo Hakala, Lubna Dada, Chao Yan, Wei Du, Lei Yao, Feixue Zheng, Jialiang Ma, Florian Ungeheuer, Alexander L. Vogel, Dominik Stolzenburg, Yufang Hao, Yongchun Liu, Federico Bianchi, Ga&#235;lle Uzu, Jean&#8208;Luc Jaffrezo, Douglas R. Worsnop, Neil M. Donahue, Markku Kulmala, Nature Geoscience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401428022

                Abstract Haze in Beijing is linked to atmospherically formed secondary organic aerosol, which has been shown to be particularly harmful to human health. However, the sources and formation pathways of these secondary aerosols remain largely unknown, hindering effective pollution mitigation. Here we have quantified the sources of organic aerosol via direct near-molecular observations in central Beijing. In winter, organic aerosol pollution arises mainly from fresh solid-fuel emissions and secondary organic aerosols originating from both solid-fuel combustion and aqueous processes, probably involving multiphase chemistry with aromatic compounds. The most severe haze is linked to secondary organic aerosols originating from solid-fuel combustion, transported from the Beijing&#8211;Tianjing&#8211;Hebei Plain and rural mountainous areas west of Beijing. In summer, the increased fraction of secondary organic aerosol is dominated by aromatic emissions from the Xi&#8217;an&#8211;Shanghai&#8211;Beijing region, while the contribution of biogenic emissions remains relatively small. Overall, we identify the main sources of secondary organic aerosol affecting Beijing, which clearly extend beyond the local emissions in Beijing. Our results suggest that targeting key organic precursor emission sectors regionally may be needed to effectively mitigate organic aerosol pollution.</description>
      <author>Kaspar R. Daellenbach, Jing Cai, Simo Hakala, Lubna Dada, Chao Yan, Wei Du, Lei Yao, Feixue Zheng, Jialiang Ma, Florian Ungeheuer, Alexander L. Vogel, Dominik Stolzenburg, Yufang Hao, Yongchun Liu, Federico Bianchi, Ga&#235;lle Uzu, Jean&#8208;Luc Jaffrezo, Douglas R. Worsnop, Neil M. Donahue, Markku Kulmala</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01493-3</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
