<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 01:08:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory mapping of tumor associated macrophage nanoparticle article abstracts using an eLDA topic modeling machine learning approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0304505</link>
      <description>Chloe Brown, Colette Bilynsky, Melanie Gainey, Sarah Young, John R. Kitchin, Elizabeth Wayne, PloS one. 19(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399769525

                The role of macrophages in regulating the tumor microenvironment has spurned the exponential generation of nanoparticle targeting technologies. With the large amount of literature and the speed at which it is generated it is difficult to remain current with the most up-to-date literature. In this study we performed a topic modeling analysis of 854 abstracts of peer-reviewed literature for the most common usages of nanoparticle targeting of tumor associated macrophages (TAMs) in solid tumors. The data spans 20 years of literature, providing a broad perspective of the nanoparticle strategies. Our topic model found 6 distinct topics: Immune and TAMs, Nanoparticles, Imaging, Gene Delivery and Exosomes, Vaccines, and Multi-modal Therapies. We also found distinct nanoparticle usage, tumor types, and therapeutic trends across these topics. Moreover, we established that the topic model could be used to assign new papers into the existing topics, thereby creating a Living Review. This type of &#8220;birds-eye-view&#8221; analysis provides a useful assessment tool for exploring new and emerging themes within a large field.</description>
      <author>Chloe Brown, Colette Bilynsky, Melanie Gainey, Sarah Young, John R. Kitchin, Elizabeth Wayne</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0304505</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branched&#8208;Tail Lipid Nanoparticles for Intravenous mRNA Delivery to Lung Immune, Endothelial, and Alveolar Cells in Mice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adhm.202400225</link>
      <description>Daria M. Strelkova Petersen, Ryan M. Weiss, Khalid A. Hajj, Sai Gopal Krishna Yerneni, Namit Chaudhary, Alexandra N. Newby, Mariah L. Arral, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Advanced healthcare materials/Advanced Healthcare Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399772948

                Abstract Lipid nanoparticles (LNPs) are proven as safe and effective delivery systems on a global scale. However, their efficacy has been limited primarily to liver and immune cells targets. To extend the potential applicability of mRNA drugs, we have synthesized and examined a library of 580 ionizable lipidoids for delivery to extrahepatocellular targets following intravenous administration. Of these lipidoids, over 40 enabled protein expression in mice, with the majority transfecting the liver. Beyond the liver, several LNPs containing new, branched&#8208;tail ionizable lipidoids potently delivered mRNA to the lungs, with cell&#8208;level specificity depending on helper lipid chemistry. Incorporation of the neutral helper lipid DOPE at 16 mol% enabled highly specific delivery to natural killer and dendritic cells within the lung. Although inclusion of the cationic helper lipid, DOTAP, improved lung tropism, it did so at the expense of cell specificity, resulting in equal transfection of endothelial and lymphoid cells. DOTAP formulations were also less favorable than DOPE formulations in that they elevated liver enzyme level and the overall cytokine response. Together, these data identify a new branched&#8208;tailed LNP formulation with a unique ability to selectively transfect lung immune cell populations without the use of toxicity&#8208;prone cationic helper lipids. This novel vehicle may unlock RNA therapies for lung diseases associated with immune cell dysregulation, including cancer, viral infections, and autoimmune disorders. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Daria M. Strelkova Petersen, Ryan M. Weiss, Khalid A. Hajj, Sai Gopal Krishna Yerneni, Namit Chaudhary, Alexandra N. Newby, Mariah L. Arral, Kathryn A. Whitehead</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adhm.202400225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matheuristic Approaches for Multi-Product 3-Dimensional Container Loading Problem</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4871843</link>
      <description>Riddhesh Kumtakar, Nitish Umang, Gary Kocis, Dean Face, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399849795

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Riddhesh Kumtakar, Nitish Umang, Gary Kocis, Dean Face, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4871843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intense formation of secondary ultrafine particles from Amazonian vegetation fires and their invigoration of deep clouds and precipitation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2024.05.015</link>
      <description>Manish Shrivastava, Jiwen Fan, Yuwei Zhang, Quazi Z. Rasool, Bin Zhao, Jianjian Shen, Jeffrey R. Pierce, Shantanu H. Jathar, Ali Akherati, Jie Zhang, Rahul A. Zaveri, Brian Gaudet, Ying Liu, Meinrat O. Andreae, Mira L. P&#246;hlker, Neil M. Donahue, Yuan Wang, John H. Seinfeld, One earth. 7(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399887232

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manish Shrivastava, Jiwen Fan, Yuwei Zhang, Quazi Z. Rasool, Bin Zhao, Jianjian Shen, Jeffrey R. Pierce, Shantanu H. Jathar, Ali Akherati, Jie Zhang, Rahul A. Zaveri, Brian Gaudet, Ying Liu, Meinrat O. Andreae, Mira L. P&#246;hlker, Neil M. Donahue, Yuan Wang, John H. Seinfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2024.05.015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logic-Based Outer Approximation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_348-1</link>
      <description>Ignacio E. Grossmann, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399940117

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_348-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MINLP: Logic-Based Methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_383-1</link>
      <description>Ignacio E. Grossmann, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399940165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_383-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactions of peroxy radicals from monoterpene and isoprene oxidation simulated in the radical Volatility Basis Set</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00056k</link>
      <description>Meredith Schervish, Martin Heinritzi, Dominik Stolzenburg, Lubna Dada, Mingyi Wang, Qing Ye, Victoria Hofbauer, Jenna DeVivo, Federico Bianchi, Sophia Brilke, Jonathan Duplissy, Imad El Haddad, Henning Finkenzeller, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, A. N. Kvashnin, Changhyuk Kim, J. Kirkby, Markku Kulmala, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Brandon Lopez, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Bernhard Mentler, Ugo Molteni, Wei Nie, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#228;, Lauriane L. J. Qu&#233;l&#233;ver, Rainer Volkamer, Andrea C. Wagner, Paul M. Winkler, Chao Yan, Neil M. Donahue, Environmental science. Atmospheres. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399971674

                Isoprene affects new particle formation rates in environments and experiments also containing monoterpenes. For the most part, isoprene reduces particle formation rates, but the reason is debated. It is proposed...</description>
      <author>Meredith Schervish, Martin Heinritzi, Dominik Stolzenburg, Lubna Dada, Mingyi Wang, Qing Ye, Victoria Hofbauer, Jenna DeVivo, Federico Bianchi, Sophia Brilke, Jonathan Duplissy, Imad El Haddad, Henning Finkenzeller, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, A. N. Kvashnin, Changhyuk Kim, J. Kirkby, Markku Kulmala, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Brandon Lopez, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Bernhard Mentler, Ugo Molteni, Wei Nie, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#228;, Lauriane L. J. Qu&#233;l&#233;ver, Rainer Volkamer, Andrea C. Wagner, Paul M. Winkler, Chao Yan, Neil M. Donahue</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00056k</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
