<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 01:11:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A TRIVIALIDADE E O MAU USO DOS ANTIBI&#211;TICOS: DESENVOLVIMENTO DE SUPERBACT&#201;RIAS E OUTRAS REPERCUSS&#213;ES</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56083/rcv4n5-155</link>
      <description>Gabrielle Pereira Damasceno, Ana Carolyne Moribe, Marcos Gontijo da Silva, A. B. Silva, Carmen Santana, Daniela Cintia de Azevedo Dantas Vasconcelos, Evilyn Rachel Teixeira Barreto Dos Anjos, Gabriel Gomes, GICELE SANTOS DA SILVA, Itamar Medeiros Paiva Souza Filho, Jonce de Oliveira, Kallianna Dantas Ara&#250;jo, Leandro Bernardo Guimar&#227;es, L. SILVA, Maria Caroline Alexandre da Silva, Marcos Sobral, Maria S. Santos, Margarida Albuquerque, Ricardo Nascimento Abreu, Yohana de Siqueira Queiroz, Contempor&#226;nea. 4(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398771463

                Bact&#233;rias resistentes a antibi&#243;ticos, tamb&#233;m conhecidas como superbact&#233;rias, representam atualmente uma das principais amea&#231;as &#224; sa&#250;de p&#250;blica mundial. Infec&#231;&#245;es por essas bact&#233;rias est&#227;o se tornando cada vez mais comuns e algumas delas s&#227;o resistentes a praticamente todos os antibi&#243;ticos existentes. O objetivo deste trabalho &#233; discutir a banaliza&#231;&#227;o do uso de antibi&#243;ticos com o surgimento de bact&#233;rias multirresistentes a antibi&#243;ticos. Foi feita uma busca em portais cient&#237;ficos usando o termo de busca &#8220;superbact&#233;rias&#8221; e "bact&#233;rias multirresistentes&#8221;. Os artigos encontrados foram discutidos de forma narrativa. Conclus&#227;o: A velocidade com que os cientistas descobrem novos antibi&#243;ticos vem sendo cada vez mais lenta. Nesse cen&#225;rio, a Organiza&#231;&#227;o Mundial de Sa&#250;de estima que, se nada for feito para controlar essas superbact&#233;rias, a m&#233;dio e longo prazo, estas ser&#227;o respons&#225;veis por milh&#245;es de mortes por ano no mundo, tornando-se mais letais que o c&#226;ncer.</description>
      <author>Gabrielle Pereira Damasceno, Ana Carolyne Moribe, Marcos Gontijo da Silva, A. B. Silva, Carmen Santana, Daniela Cintia de Azevedo Dantas Vasconcelos, Evilyn Rachel Teixeira Barreto Dos Anjos, Gabriel Gomes, GICELE SANTOS DA SILVA, Itamar Medeiros Paiva Souza Filho, Jonce de Oliveira, Kallianna Dantas Ara&#250;jo, Leandro Bernardo Guimar&#227;es, L. SILVA, Maria Caroline Alexandre da Silva, Marcos Sobral, Maria S. Santos, Margarida Albuquerque, Ricardo Nascimento Abreu, Yohana de Siqueira Queiroz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56083/rcv4n5-155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CFD Modeling of High-Flux Plate-and-Frame Membrane modules for industrial carbon capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2352462</link>
      <description>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hui&#8208;Kang, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398774513

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hui&#8208;Kang, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2352462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CFD and systems engineering to minimize membrane-based carbon capture costs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2352466</link>
      <description>H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, Thien Tran, David Hui&#8208;Kang, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398774799

                In this study, we propose a superstructure for membrane-based carbon capture, addressing these challenges through the formulation of an optimization problem. The case study considers a flue gas with a flowrate of 1000 mol/s and a 30 % CO2 (molar basis), which is representative of steel plants. Reduced models, derived from rigorous CFD simulations of membrane modules, are utilized to enhance the efficiency of the optimization process. The reduced model includes specific input variables such as inlet flow rate, retentate and permeate pressures, and inlet CO2 concentration; while the CO2 recovery and purity in the permeate side are considered as output variables. In this way, we exploit the information from the CFD simulations in the superstructure, aiding in the selection of the optimal configuration for the multi-stage membrane process. The results underscore the efficiency of a multi-stage membrane design, showing capture costs around 45 $/t-CO2.</description>
      <author>H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, Thien Tran, David Hui&#8208;Kang, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2352466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Capture through Membranes - Leveraging Multiphysics Modeling, Dimensional Analysis and Machine Learning to Scale up and Optimize Devices and Processes for Decarbonization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2352465</link>
      <description>H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, Thien Tran, David Hui&#8208;Kang, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398780627

                We study the separation performance using membrane modules through dimensional analysis (DA). We formulate the main process equations to identify relevant dimensionless numbers inherent in the physics. In particular, we identify that the critical step in the separation process is mass transfer through the selective layer. Remarkably, the dimensionless feed flow (DFfeed) emerges as a crucial factor in describing this process. Not only does DFfeed directly appear in the governing equations, but it also holds a physical significance associated with the time scales for the mass transfer across the feed side and through the selective layer. Regarding the output performance variables, we consider the recovery, stage cut, productivity and purity. In this context, we profit from experimental data and CFD simulations to evaluate the separation performance of the modules when varying the input flowrate, the scale of the module, and the CO2 permeance. These datasets enable us to establish correlations between performance metrics and the dimensionless feed flow (DFfeed). Using simple power functions of DFfeed, we obtain R2 coefficients exceeding 0.99, indicating the accuracy of the correlations built in the present work. In the future, we wish to use DA to understand key transport mechanisms, predict and control module performance, and challenge the universality of these findings by testing various gas separations across different membrane modules beyond our case study.</description>
      <author>H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, Thien Tran, David Hui&#8208;Kang, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2352465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CFD modeling of high-flux plate-and-frame membrane modules for industrial carbon capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2352463</link>
      <description>Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, Thien Tran, David Hui&#8208;Kang, H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398780693

                In this work, we explore the use of CO2-selective flat sheet membranes for capturing CO2 from point sources. We employ Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) models to design high-flux plate-and-frame membrane modules to achieve uniform flow distribution among membrane elements, minimize dead-end zones, and ease the common concentration polarization issue for gas separation membranes. The goal is to drive membrane technology improvements by providing better module designs for given membrane properties and operating conditions.</description>
      <author>Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, Thien Tran, David Hui&#8208;Kang, H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2352463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative corrosion resistance of a Cr Fe Ni1-- composition spread alloy film (CSAF) in dry air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160391</link>
      <description>Camille Ferris, Nicholas Golio, Herv&#233; Mart&#237;nez, Andrew J. Gellman, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399010088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Camille Ferris, Nicholas Golio, Herv&#233; Mart&#237;nez, Andrew J. Gellman</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160391</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Mechanism of the Holes in the Blanket of Fog Over the Indo&#8208;Gangetic Plains: Are They Driven by Urban Heat Islands or Aerosol?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2023gl107252</link>
      <description>Anurose Theethai Jacob, A. Jayakumar, M. Sandhya, Hamish Gordon, S. Aryasree, Saji Mohandas, Shweta Bhati, V. S. Prasad, Geophysical research letters. 51(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399011192

                Abstract Fog holes were reported over cities of the Indo&#8208;Gangetic plains of India, which were attributed to the urban heat island (UHI) effect. The present study reports the observational evidence of fog holes over rural area using satellite and ground observations. Delayed onset and early dissipation of fog is observed over the holes. Numerical simulations demonstrate that aerosol&#8208;radiation interaction (ARI) leads to fog holes over both urban and rural regions. The anthropogenic aerosols and associated ARI dominate the UHI effect over the urban fog holes, while the aerosol absorption due to ARI mainly controls the rural fog holes. Turning off aerosol absorption causes &#8764; 2 hours delay in the fog dissipation over urban area, whereas it yields persistent fog over rural area under saturated environment. An enhancement of soluble Aitken black carbon over the fog holes indicates the importance of aging process during fog dissipation.</description>
      <author>Anurose Theethai Jacob, A. Jayakumar, M. Sandhya, Hamish Gordon, S. Aryasree, Saji Mohandas, Shweta Bhati, V. S. Prasad</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2023gl107252</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient bounds tightening based on SOCP relaxations for AC optimal power flow</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11081-024-09891-7</link>
      <description>Yuanxun Shao, Dillard Robertson, Michael Bynum, Carl D. Laird, Anya Castillo, Joseph K. Scott, Optimization and engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399016103

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanxun Shao, Dillard Robertson, Michael Bynum, Carl D. Laird, Anya Castillo, Joseph K. Scott</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11081-024-09891-7</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
