<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 01:40:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Control Method for Vehicle Cooperative Rendezvous</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2514/1.g008445</link>
      <description>Zhenyu Wei, Zhijiang Shao, Lorenz T. Biegler, Journal of Guidance Control and Dynamics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410007158

                Cooperative rendezvous/docking is an enabling technology for future autonomous missions. However, it is still a challenge to design a fully distributed, stability-guaranteed control method for cooperative rendezvous. To address this issue, this paper proposes a distributed control method for an unmanned vehicle cooperative rendezvous mission. First, the cooperative rendezvous process is formulated as an optimal control problem. To decentralize the control framework, a rendezvous parameter is introduced, and the rendezvous parameter optimization algorithm is designed to guarantee the terminal rendezvous of autonomous vehicles while improving the system performance. On this basis, a distributed control framework, based on rendezvous parameter optimization, generates the control commands to achieve cooperative rendezvous. Results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed distributed control approach through three simulations.</description>
      <author>Zhenyu Wei, Zhijiang Shao, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2514/1.g008445</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
