<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 01:11:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electrophoretically Snagging Viral Genomes in Wormlike Micelle Networks Using Peptide Nucleic Acid Amphiphiles and dsDNA Oligomers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.biomac.4c00332</link>
      <description>Kwok&#8208;Min Hui, L. Yan, James Schneider, Biomacromolecules. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400731940

                We demonstrate that the attachment of 30-170 bp dsDNA oligomers to ssDNA viral genomes gives a significant additional mobility shift in micelle-tagging electrophoresis (MTE). In MTE, a modified peptide nucleic acid amphiphile is attached to the viral genome to bind drag-inducing micelles present in capillary electrophoresis running buffers. Further attachment of 30-170 bp dsDNA oligomers drastically shifts the mobility of the 5.1 kB ssDNA genome of mouse minute virus (MMV), providing a new mechanism to improve resolution in CE-based analysis of kilobase nucleic acids. A model based on biased-reptation electrophoresis, end-labeled free-solution electrophoresis, and Ferguson gel-filtration theory is presented to describe the observed mobility shifts.</description>
      <author>Kwok&#8208;Min Hui, L. Yan, James Schneider</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.biomac.4c00332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Segregation Across Ternary Alloy Composition Space: Cu X Ag Y Au1- X - Y</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898954</link>
      <description>Andrew J. Gellman, Robert Burnley, Zhitao Guo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400769359

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrew J. Gellman, Robert Burnley, Zhitao Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898954</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Membrane-based carbon capture process optimization using CFD modeling</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4400840524</link>
      <description>H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, OSTI OAI (U.S. Department of Energy Office of Scientific and Technical Information). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400840524

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H&#233;ctor A. Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor A. Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4400840524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Trust Region Filter Modeling Strategies for Computationally Expensive Black-Box Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108816</link>
      <description>Runzhe Liang, Yueheng Han, Haoyang Hu, Bingzhen Chen, Zhihong Yuan, Lorenz T. Biegler, Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400928238

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Runzhe Liang, Yueheng Han, Haoyang Hu, Bingzhen Chen, Zhihong Yuan, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108816</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
