<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:47:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Lipid nanoparticle structure and delivery route during pregnancy dictate mRNA potency, immunogenicity, and maternal and fetal outcomes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2307810121</link>
      <description>Namit Chaudhary, Alexandra N. Newby, Mariah L. Arral, Saigopalakrishna S. Yerneni, Samuel T. LoPresti, Rose Doerfler, Daria M. Strelkova Petersen, Catalina Montoya, Julie S. Kim, Bethany Fox, Tiffany A. Coon, Angela Malaney, Yoel Sadovsky, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392367072

                Treating pregnancy-related disorders is exceptionally challenging because the threat of maternal and/or fetal toxicity discourages the use of existing medications and hinders new drug development. One potential solution is the use of lipid nanoparticle (LNP) RNA therapies, given their proven efficacy, tolerability, and lack of fetal accumulation. Here, we describe LNPs for efficacious mRNA delivery to maternal organs in pregnant mice via several routes of administration. In the placenta, our lead LNP transfected trophoblasts, endothelial cells, and immune cells, with efficacy being structurally dependent on the ionizable lipid polyamine headgroup. Next, we show that LNP-induced maternal inflammatory responses affect mRNA expression in the maternal compartment and hinder neonatal development. Specifically, pro-inflammatory LNP structures and routes of administration curtailed efficacy in maternal lymphoid organs in an IL-1&#946;-dependent manner. Further, immunogenic LNPs provoked the infiltration of adaptive immune cells into the placenta and restricted pup growth after birth. Together, our results provide mechanism-based structural guidance on the design of potent LNPs for safe use during pregnancy.</description>
      <author>Namit Chaudhary, Alexandra N. Newby, Mariah L. Arral, Saigopalakrishna S. Yerneni, Samuel T. LoPresti, Rose Doerfler, Daria M. Strelkova Petersen, Catalina Montoya, Julie S. Kim, Bethany Fox, Tiffany A. Coon, Angela Malaney, Yoel Sadovsky, Kathryn A. Whitehead</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2307810121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decomposition methods for multi-horizon stochastic programming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3258743/v2</link>
      <description>Hongyu Zhang, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Asgeir Tomasg&#229;rd, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392452074

                Abstract Multi-horizon stochastic programming includes short-term and long-term uncertainty in investment planning problems more efficiently than traditional multi-stage stochastic programming. In this paper, we exploit the block separable structure of multi-horizon stochastic linear programming, and establish that it can be decomposed by Benders decomposition and Lagrangean decomposition. In addition, we propose parallel Lagrangean decomposition with primal reduction that, (1) solves the scenario subproblems in parallel, (2) reduces the primal problem by keeping one copy for each scenario group at each stage, and (3) solves the reduced primal problem in parallel. We apply the parallel Lagrangean decomposition with primal reduction, Lagrangean decomposition and Benders decomposition to solve a stochastic energy system investment planning problem. The computational results show that: (a) the Lagrangean type decomposition algorithms have better convergence at the first iterations to Benders decomposition, and (b) parallel Lagrangean decomposition with primal reduction is very efficient for solving multi-horizon stochastic programming problems. Based on the computational results, the choice of algorithms for multi-horizon stochastic programming is discussed.</description>
      <author>Hongyu Zhang, Ignacio E. Grossmann, Asgeir Tomasg&#229;rd</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3258743/v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction: What is a Bear?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/9781787445925-005</link>
      <description>Owen Nevin, Ian Convery, Peter G Davis, John R. Kitchin, Melanie Clapham, Boydell and Brewer eBooks. None(None)] 2019. https://openalex.org/W4392322282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Owen Nevin, Ian Convery, Peter G Davis, John R. Kitchin, Melanie Clapham</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/9781787445925-005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Knowing Individual Bears</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/9781787445925-012</link>
      <description>Owen Nevin, Ian Convery, John R. Kitchin, Boydell and Brewer eBooks. None(None)] 2019. https://openalex.org/W4392322290

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Owen Nevin, Ian Convery, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/9781787445925-012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of sulfured and/or phosphored molecules : evaluation of their additivating properties : correlation structure/properties</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4392432167</link>
      <description>Robert D. Tilton, No host. None(None)] 1994. https://openalex.org/W4392432167

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Robert D. Tilton</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 1994 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4392432167</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
