<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 01:08:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Matheuristic Approaches for Multi-Product 3-Dimensional Container Loading Problem</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4871843</link>
      <description>Riddhesh Kumtakar, Nitish Umang, Gary Kocis, Dean Face, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399849795

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Riddhesh Kumtakar, Nitish Umang, Gary Kocis, Dean Face, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4871843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intense formation of secondary ultrafine particles from Amazonian vegetation fires and their invigoration of deep clouds and precipitation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2024.05.015</link>
      <description>Manish Shrivastava, Jiwen Fan, Yuwei Zhang, Quazi Z. Rasool, Bin Zhao, Jianjian Shen, Jeffrey R. Pierce, Shantanu H. Jathar, Ali Akherati, Jie Zhang, Rahul A. Zaveri, Brian Gaudet, Ying Liu, Meinrat O. Andreae, Mira L. P&#246;hlker, Neil M. Donahue, Yuan Wang, John H. Seinfeld, One earth. 7(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399887232

                New particle formation (NPF) in fire smoke is thought to be unlikely due to large condensation and coagulation sinks that scavenge molecular clusters. We analyze aircraft measurements over the Amazon and find that fires significantly enhance NPF and ultrafine particle (UFP &lt; 50 nm diameter) numbers compared to background conditions, contrary to previous understanding. We identify that the nucleation of dimethylamine with sulfuric acid, which is aided by the formation of extremely low volatility organics in biomass-burning smoke, can overcome the large condensation and coagulation sinks and explain aircraft observations. We show that freshly formed clusters rapidly grow to UFP sizes through biomass-burning secondary organic aerosol formation, leading to a 10-fold increase in UFP number concentrations. We find a contrasting effect of UFPs on deep convective clouds compared to the larger particles from primary emissions for the case investigated here. UFPs intensify the deep convective clouds and precipitation due to increased condensational heating, while larger particles delay and reduce precipitation.</description>
      <author>Manish Shrivastava, Jiwen Fan, Yuwei Zhang, Quazi Z. Rasool, Bin Zhao, Jianjian Shen, Jeffrey R. Pierce, Shantanu H. Jathar, Ali Akherati, Jie Zhang, Rahul A. Zaveri, Brian Gaudet, Ying Liu, Meinrat O. Andreae, Mira L. P&#246;hlker, Neil M. Donahue, Yuan Wang, John H. Seinfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2024.05.015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logic-Based Outer Approximation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_348-1</link>
      <description>Ignacio E. Grossmann, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399940117

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_348-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MINLP: Logic-Based Methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_383-1</link>
      <description>Ignacio E. Grossmann, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399940165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ignacio E. Grossmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54621-2_383-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactions of peroxy radicals from monoterpene and isoprene oxidation simulated in the radical Volatility Basis Set</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00056k</link>
      <description>Meredith Schervish, Martin Heinritzi, Dominik Stolzenburg, Lubna Dada, Mingyi Wang, Qing Ye, Victoria Hofbauer, Jenna DeVivo, Federico Bianchi, Sophia Brilke, Jonathan Duplissy, Imad El Haddad, Henning Finkenzeller, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, A. N. Kvashnin, Changhyuk Kim, J. Kirkby, Markku Kulmala, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Brandon Lopez, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Bernhard Mentler, Ugo Molteni, Wei Nie, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#228;, Lauriane L. J. Qu&#233;l&#233;ver, Rainer Volkamer, Andrea C. Wagner, Paul M. Winkler, Chao Yan, Neil M. Donahue, Environmental science. Atmospheres. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399971674

                Isoprene affects new particle formation rates in environments and experiments also containing monoterpenes. For the most part, isoprene reduces particle formation rates, but the reason is debated. It is proposed...</description>
      <author>Meredith Schervish, Martin Heinritzi, Dominik Stolzenburg, Lubna Dada, Mingyi Wang, Qing Ye, Victoria Hofbauer, Jenna DeVivo, Federico Bianchi, Sophia Brilke, Jonathan Duplissy, Imad El Haddad, Henning Finkenzeller, Xu&#8208;Cheng He, A. N. Kvashnin, Changhyuk Kim, J. Kirkby, Markku Kulmala, Katrianne Lehtipalo, Brandon Lopez, &#1042;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1093;&#1084;&#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Bernhard Mentler, Ugo Molteni, Wei Nie, Tuukka Pet&#228;j&#228;, Lauriane L. J. Qu&#233;l&#233;ver, Rainer Volkamer, Andrea C. Wagner, Paul M. Winkler, Chao Yan, Neil M. Donahue</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ea00056k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycling Rare Earth Elements from End-of-Life Electric and Hybrid Electric Vehicle Motors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-28824-1.50219-2</link>
      <description>Chris Laliwala, Ana I. Torres, Computer-aided chemical engineering/Computer aided chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399991313

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chris Laliwala, Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-28824-1.50219-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prioritizing High-Consequence Biological Capabilities in Evaluations of Artificial Intelligence Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4873106</link>
      <description>Jaspreet Pannu, D. Shaun Bloomfield, Aibin Zhu, Robert MacKnight, Gabriel Gomes, Anita Cicero, Thomas V. Inglesby, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400015840

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jaspreet Pannu, D. Shaun Bloomfield, Aibin Zhu, Robert MacKnight, Gabriel Gomes, Anita Cicero, Thomas V. Inglesby</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4873106</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
