<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 01:44:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetically Responsive Nanocultures for Direct Microbial Assessment in Soil Environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.05.17.654660</link>
      <description>Huda Usman, Mehdi Molaei, Stephen D. House, Martin F. Haase, Cindi L. Dennis, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410477537

                Cultivating microorganisms in native-like conditions is vital for bioprospecting and accessing currently unculturable species. However, there remains a gap in scalable tools that can both mimic native microenvironments and enable targeted recovery of microbes from complex settings. Such approaches are essential to advance our understanding of microbial ecology, predict community functions, and discover novel biotherapeutics. We present magnetic nanocultures, a high-throughput microsystem for isolating and growing environmental microbes under near-native conditions. These nanoliter-scale bioreactors are encapsulated in semi-permeable membranes that form magnetic polymeric microcapsules using iron oxide nanoparticles within polydimethylsiloxane-based shells. This design offers mechanical stability and magnetic actuation, enabling efficient retrieval from soil-like environments. The nanocultures are optimized for optical and biological properties to support microbial encapsulation, growth, and sorting. Our study demonstrates the feasibility of using magnetically responsive microenvironments to cultivate elusive microbes, offering a promising platform for discovering previously uncultured or unknown microbial species.</description>
      <author>Huda Usman, Mehdi Molaei, Stephen D. House, Martin F. Haase, Cindi L. Dennis, Tagbo H. R. Niepa</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.05.17.654660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing aerosol science through early career research</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/02786826.2025.2468594</link>
      <description>Coty N. Jen, James F. Davies, Aerosol Science and Technology. 59(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410485568

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Coty N. Jen, James F. Davies</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/02786826.2025.2468594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Strategy for mRNA Encapsulation and Gene Delivery with Nanoscale Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202504465</link>
      <description>Harrison Lawson, Nguy&#7877;n Huy Ho&#224;ng, Keng&#8208;Jung Lee, Nattarat Wongsuwan, Ayesha Tupe, Mengrou Lu, Mariah L. Arral, Anne Behre, Zihan Ling, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Adam W. Feinberg, Xi Ren, Siyang Zheng, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410507430

                Abstract Metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) have evolved from uses in catalysis and gas storage to exciting applications in biomedicine, particularly in drug delivery. Initially, MOFs are primarily used to deliver small molecules, recent innovations have shifted focus toward more complex nucleic acids like DNA, short guide RNA (sgRNA), and short interfering RNA (siRNA). Remarkably, no studies to date have demonstrated the encapsulation and delivery of messenger RNA (mRNA) via MOFs in vitro and in vivo. This study addresses that gap by identifying synthetic conditions to encapsulate and deliver mRNA using zeolitic imidazole framework&#8208;8 (ZIF&#8208;8). Early attempts show mRNA loading in ZIF&#8208;8 but loss of mRNA in biological media. To overcome this challenge, polyethyleneimine (PEI) is incorporated into the formulation, forming a robust polymer complex core&#8208;MOF shell particle. This system stabilizes mRNA complexes and delays their release, resulting in effective protein expression in multiple cell lines and mice, performing on par with commercial lipid&#8208;based systems. Here, the first investigation into thermally stable mRNA storage using ZIF&#8208;8 demonstrates successful protein expression after three months of room&#8208;temperature storage in vitro and one month in vivo. These findings broaden the scope of MOF&#8208;based therapeutic delivery and open new avenues for long&#8208;term mRNA storage and transport.</description>
      <author>Harrison Lawson, Nguy&#7877;n Huy Ho&#224;ng, Keng&#8208;Jung Lee, Nattarat Wongsuwan, Ayesha Tupe, Mengrou Lu, Mariah L. Arral, Anne Behre, Zihan Ling, Kathryn A. Whitehead, Adam W. Feinberg, Xi Ren, Siyang Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202504465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Framework for Dynamic Modeling of Circular Economy Networks: The Polyethylene Terephthalate (PET) Packaging Supply Chain as a Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.5c00273</link>
      <description>Daniel Pert, Ana I. Torres, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410550070

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel Pert, Ana I. Torres</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.5c00273</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double-layer structure and interfacial tension at an ionic surfactant-laden interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137924</link>
      <description>Emerson M. Uhlig, Aditya S. Khair, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410616356

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Emerson M. Uhlig, Aditya S. Khair</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing molecular machine learning representations with stereoelectronics-infused molecular graphs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s42256-025-01031-9</link>
      <description>Daniil A. Boiko, Thiago Resch&#252;tzegger, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Lengeling, Samuel M. Blau, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes, Nature Machine Intelligence. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410629037

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniil A. Boiko, Thiago Resch&#252;tzegger, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Lengeling, Samuel M. Blau, Gabriel dos Passos Gomes</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s42256-025-01031-9</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
