<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CMU Chemical Engineering</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CMU-Chemical-Engineering.xml</link>
    <description>Papers by people in the Department of Chemical Engineering at CMU</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 01:41:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Level Direct Currents Eradicate Multi-Drug-Resistant Candida Auris Through Physiological Stress and Antifungal Permeation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5271751</link>
      <description>C. Royo, Charles Landis, Michael T. Geraghty, Sricharani Rao Balmuri, Tagbo H. R. Niepa, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410884177

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C. Royo, Charles Landis, Michael T. Geraghty, Sricharani Rao Balmuri, Tagbo H. R. Niepa</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5271751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Computational Investigation of High-Flux, Plate-and-Frame Membrane Modules for Industrial Carbon Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100246</link>
      <description>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, Digital Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410893830

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheick Dosso, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovations in chemical process control: challenges and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101148</link>
      <description>Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian, Helen Durand, Joel A. Paulson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Current Opinion in Chemical Engineering. 48(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410907732

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian, Helen Durand, Joel A. Paulson, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CFD Modeling of Concentration Polarization in High-Performance Flat-Sheet Modules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2568340</link>
      <description>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410951088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Cheick Dosso, Thien Tran, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor Kusuma, David Hopkinson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2568340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Uncertainty in High CO&#8322; Capture rate with MEA Solvent Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2567978</link>
      <description>Lingyan Deng, Katherine Hedrick, Joshua Morgan, Michael Matuszewski, Grigorios Panagakos, Daison Caballero, Miguel Zamarripa, Benjamin Omell, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411023261

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingyan Deng, Katherine Hedrick, Joshua Morgan, Michael Matuszewski, Grigorios Panagakos, Daison Caballero, Miguel Zamarripa, Benjamin Omell</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2567978</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validation of High-Flux Plate-and-Frame Membrane module design for CO2 capture: a CFD Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2568464</link>
      <description>Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor Kusuma, Thien Tran, David Hopkinson, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411041545

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheick Dosso, Lingxiang Zhu, Victor Kusuma, Thien Tran, David Hopkinson, H&#233;ctor Pedrozo, Lorenz T. Biegler, Grigorios Panagakos</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2568464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process Systems Engineering-Informed Design and Scale-Up of Multi-stage Diafiltration Cascades for Lithium and Cobalt Recovery from Spent Lithium-Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2568411</link>
      <description>Molly Dougher, Jason Yao, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, Alexander W. Dowling, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411041678

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Molly Dougher, Jason Yao, Chrysanthos E. Gounaris, Alexander W. Dowling</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2568411</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
