<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 01:08:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured Mnmoo4 as a Trifunctional Electrocatalyst for Overall Water Splitting and Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853666</link>
      <description>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399337243

                Electrochemical water splitting and CO2 reduction are important processes to produce hydrogen and low&#8211;carbon fuels as renewable energy sources. Here, nanostructured MnMoO4, prepared by the reflux precipitation method, was investigated as a trifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions. Using a combination of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results, a direct band gap of 3.05 eV was obtained experimentally for the prepared MnMoO4. An overpotential of 0.36 V at a current density of 5 mA cm-2 and a Tafel slope of 58 mV dec-1 were obtained for the oxygen evolution reaction. At a current density of 3 mA cm-2, overpotentials of 0.39 V and 0.58 V were achieved in the absence and presence of CO2 bubbling into a 0.1 M KOH solution, respectively, emphasizing the poisoning effect of CO2 reduction intermediates for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Based on the obtained results, MnMoO4 could be a promising electrocatalyst for water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions.</description>
      <author>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioinspired bimetallic catalysts for CO2 reduction beyond C1 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101148692</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399349336

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101148692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening of Defective BC3-Supported Single-Atom Catalysts for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01217h</link>
      <description>Renyi Li, Caimu Wang, Yaozhong Liu, C. Suo, Danyang Zhang, Zaibin Jiao, Wei Guo, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399349369

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) driven by renewable electricity offers a green and sustainable technology for synthesizing chemicals and managing global carbon balance. However, developing electrocatalysts with high activity and...</description>
      <author>Renyi Li, Caimu Wang, Yaozhong Liu, C. Suo, Danyang Zhang, Zaibin Jiao, Wei Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01217h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Atoms Immobilization on MXene-Metal-Organic Polyhedra Assemblies for Selective Reduction of CO2 to Formic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101151123</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399350957

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101151123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Carbon Footprint Assessment of Wood Flooring and Potential Pathways of Co2 Emissions Reduction -Six Cases from China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4855622</link>
      <description>Jia Guo, Lin Gao, Zhu Han, Daxin Liang, Zefang Xiao, Yonggui Wang, Haigang Wang, Yanjun Xie, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399451908

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Guo, Lin Gao, Zhu Han, Daxin Liang, Zefang Xiao, Yonggui Wang, Haigang Wang, Yanjun Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4855622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical CO2 Reduction with Surface Immobilized Mn-NHC Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101152972</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4399404585

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101152972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel bipolar Membrane-Electrode Assembly designs for Simultaneous CO2 Capture and Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101153662</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4399412451

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101153662</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycling Electronic Waste to Catalyse H2 Production and CO2 Reduction Using Recovered Metals: A Step towards Circular Economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101152892</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4399406096

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101152892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Technology and a Convert&#1077;r for Neutralizing Greenhouse Gases Emitted from Automobiles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54338/27382656-2024.6-001</link>
      <description>Yeghiazar Vardanyan, V. M. Harutyunyan, Karapet Mosikyan, Vladimir Sahidovich Koichev, Journal of architectural and engineering research. 6(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399325246

                The article touches upon the issues of global warming associated with carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions into the atmosphere from vehicle internal combustion engines (ICE). To neutralize existing greenhouse gases emitted by ICE, in particular CO2, the interaction of the latter with various chemicals has been studied. The dynamics of exhaust gas emissions from ICE cylinders were observed. The experimental research was conducted to develop a greenhouse gas neutralization technology. Carbon dioxide neutralization converter with three neutralization batteries and a homogenization device is presented. This converter can guarantee CO2 neutralization of up to 92%. The formation of CO2 in the cylinders of modern petrol engines is due to the final combustion of the air-petrol fuel mixture. The combustion of the latter in the cylinder can be heterogeneous and diffusive. In addition, CO2 is generated in large quantities during diffusion combustion. The most effective method of diffusive combustion was chosen by the constructors of modern ICE, which is the formation of an artificial turbulent gas-dynamic condition for the fuel mixture due to the increase in the temperature of the air adsorbed in the cylinder, which ensures the engine's thermal energy efficiency coefficient of up to 35%. The CO2 volume in the exhaust gases of such engines reaches up to 16%. Thus, considering the perfection of modern ICE design for providing a high-efficiency reaction for the hydrocarbon oxidation in the fuel mixture in the combustion chamber, it becomes apparent that the presence of about 16% CO2 in the fractional composition of emitted dissolved gases is a serious problem in terms of increasing the volume of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere. Therefore, the goal of this article is to develop a reduction technology.</description>
      <author>Yeghiazar Vardanyan, V. M. Harutyunyan, Karapet Mosikyan, Vladimir Sahidovich Koichev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54338/27382656-2024.6-001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a Highly Stable Methane Reforming Catalyst Via Lattice Metal Ion Reduction Accompanying Support Phase Transition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854274</link>
      <description>Libo Han, Hui Yang, Xiaolei Fu, Ruijue Hu, Haiquan Su, Lili Wan, Yiyi Su, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399338171

                Dry reforming of methane (DRM) is one of the most important technologies for converting carbon dioxide and methane into syngas. ZrO2-supported Ni catalysts have shown promising potential for DRM. However, their catalytic stability remains a challenge due to sintering and coking. In this work, a feasible strategy for the preparation of a highly stable ZrO2-supported Ni catalyst, Ni/ZrO2-Mt, was reported. The key points for the preparation of Ni/ZrO2-Mt were the replacement of Zr4+ in the metastable tetragonal ZrO2 with lattice Ni2+, followed by the reduction of lattice Ni2+ into metallic Ni and the phase transformation of ZrO2 support from the metastable tetragonal phase to the monoclinic phase. Compared with the catalyst Ni/ZrO2-Mn (no phase transition and lattice Ni2+ reduction), Ni/ZrO2-Mt could run stably for 800 h without deactivation, with both CO2 and CH4 conversions maintaining 96%. Corresponding to its high stability, the Ni/ZrO2-Mt displayed excellent resistance to sintering and coking, which was attributed to the enhanced metal-support interaction arising from the reduction of lattice Ni2+ and the transformation of the support phase. The proposed catalyst synthetic strategy provided an optional method for preparing highly stable catalysts.</description>
      <author>Libo Han, Hui Yang, Xiaolei Fu, Ruijue Hu, Haiquan Su, Lili Wan, Yiyi Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capturing carbon dioxide from air with charged-sorbents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-024-07449-2</link>
      <description>Huaiguang Li, Mary E. Zick, Teedhat Trisukhon, Matteo Signorile, Xinyu Liu, Helen Eastmond, Shivani Sharma, Tristan Spreng, Jack A. Taylor, Jamie W. Gittins, Cavan Farrow, Seng Lim, Valentina Crocell&#224;, Phillip J. Milner, Alexander C. Forse, Nature. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399366349

                Abstract Emissions reduction and greenhouse gas removal from the atmosphere are both necessary to achieve net-zero emissions and limit climate change 1 . There is thus a need for improved sorbents for the capture of carbon dioxide from the atmosphere, a process known as direct air capture. In particular, low-cost materials that can be regenerated at low temperatures would overcome the limitations of current technologies. In this work, we introduce a new class of designer sorbent materials known as &#8216;charged-sorbents&#8217;. These materials are prepared through a battery-like charging process that accumulates ions in the pores of low-cost activated carbons, with the inserted ions then serving as sites for carbon dioxide adsorption. We use our charging process to accumulate reactive hydroxide ions in the pores of a carbon electrode, and find that the resulting sorbent material can rapidly capture carbon dioxide from ambient air by means of (bi)carbonate formation. Unlike traditional bulk carbonates, charged-sorbent regeneration can be achieved at low temperatures (90&#8211;100 &#176;C) and the sorbent&#8217;s conductive nature permits direct Joule heating regeneration 2,3 using renewable electricity. Given their highly tailorable pore environments and low cost, we anticipate that charged-sorbents will find numerous potential applications in chemical separations, catalysis and beyond.</description>
      <author>Huaiguang Li, Mary E. Zick, Teedhat Trisukhon, Matteo Signorile, Xinyu Liu, Helen Eastmond, Shivani Sharma, Tristan Spreng, Jack A. Taylor, Jamie W. Gittins, Cavan Farrow, Seng Lim, Valentina Crocell&#224;, Phillip J. Milner, Alexander C. Forse</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-024-07449-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scanning Bubble Electrochemical Microscopy: Mapping of Electrocatalytic Activity with Low-Solubility Reactants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c00917</link>
      <description>J.F. Monteiro, Kim McKelvey, Analytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399359847

                Determining electrocatalytic activity for reactions that involve reactants with limited solubility presents a significant challenge due to the reduced mass-transport to the electrocatalyst surface. This limitation is seen in important reactions such as the oxygen reduction reaction, nitrogen reduction reaction, and carbon dioxide reduction reaction. We introduce a new approach, which we call scanning bubble electrochemical microscopy, to enable the detection and high-resolution mapping of electrocatalytic activity with low-solubility reactants at high mass-transport rates. Using a scanning probe approach, a dual-barreled nanopipette is used to precisely deliver the gas-phase reactant within micrometers of an electrocatalyst surface, which results in high mass-transport rates at the electrocatalyst surface directly under the probe. We demonstrate the scanning bubble electrochemical microscopy approach by mapping the oxygen reduction reaction on model platinum microelectrode surfaces. We anticipate that scanning bubble electrochemical microscopy will provide an effective tool for measuring the electrocatalytic activity of reactants that have limited solubility.</description>
      <author>J.F. Monteiro, Kim McKelvey</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c00917</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The structure of carbon dioxide at the air&#8208;water interface and its chemical implications.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400825</link>
      <description>Marilia T. C. Martins&#8208;Costa, Manuel F. Ruiz&#8208;L&#243;pez, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399360917

                The efficient reduction of CO2 into valuable products is a challenging task in an international context marked by the climate change crisis and the need to move away from fossil fuels. Recently, the use of water microdroplets has emerged as an interesting reaction media where many redox processes which do not occur in conventional solutions take place spontaneously. Indeed, several experimental studies in microdroplets have already been devoted to study the reduction of CO2 with promising results. The increased reactivity in microdroplets is thought to be linked to unique electrostatic solvation effects at the air&#8208;water interface. In the present work, we report a theoretical investigation on this issue for CO2 using first&#8208;principles molecular dynamics simulations. We show that CO2 is stabilized at the interface, where it can accumulate, and that compared to bulk water solution, its electron capture ability is larger. Our results suggests that reduction of CO2 might be easier in interface&#8208;rich systems such as water microdroplets, which is in line with early experimental data and indicate directions for future laboratory studies. The effect of other relevant factors which could play a role in CO2 reduction potential is discussed.</description>
      <author>Marilia T. C. Martins&#8208;Costa, Manuel F. Ruiz&#8208;L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the environmental and downstream human health impacts of decentralizing cancer care.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2024.42.16_suppl.1522</link>
      <description>Andrew Hantel, Colin Cernik, Thomas Walsh, Hajime Uno, Dalia Larios, Jonathan E. Slutzman, Gregory A. Abel, Journal of clinical oncology. 42(16_suppl)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399324775

                1522 Background: Greenhouse gas emissions from healthcare are substantial and harm persons with cancer. Emissions from outpatient cancer care visits are not well described, nor are the downstream reduction in human harms that could be obtained through visit &#8220;decentralization&#8221; (telemedicine and local care when possible). Methods: This life-cycle assessment (LCA)-based study evaluated changes in emissions and downstream health harms associated with (1) telemedicine visits using retrospective observational analysis and (2) fully decentralized visits using counterfactual modeling. The retrospective observational cohort included persons receiving cancer care at Dana-Farber Cancer Institute (DFCI) and 20 affiliated facilities between 5/2015-12/2020. The main outcome was the adjusted per visit-day difference in emissions (in kilograms carbon dioxide equivalents: kgCO 2 e) between two periods: an in-person care period (5/2015-2/2020; &#8220;Pre&#8221;) and a telemedicine period (3/2020-12/2020; &#8220;Post&#8221;). Mixed effects log-linear model assessed emissions changes adjusted for age, sex, race, ethnicity, and cancer type, with random effects on person. The counterfactual model assessed emissions changes between actual in-person visits during the Pre period and a counterfactual with maximal decentralization. Visit-day eligibility for decentralization was obtained by categorizing appointments (e.g., clinician visit, infusion) as DFCI required, local care possible, or telemedicine possible. This cohort was matched to a national population diagnosed with cancer over the same period (Cancer in North America [CiNA] dataset) using mixed-effects linear modeling, through which annual changes in disability-adjusted life-years (DALY) from clinician visit decentralization were estimated using Eckelman&#8217;s mortality cost of carbon conversion. Results: There were123,890 unique patients in the DFCI cohort seen over 1.6 million visit-days (Pre N=110,180, Post N=61,691) at a median of 6 visit-days per patient (IQR 2, 15). An estimated 72,554,006 kgCO 2 e were within scope of the LCA emitted during the study period. In mixed-effects log-linear regression, the adjusted mean absolute reduction in per visit-day emissions between Pre and Post periods was 36.4 kgCO 2 e (95%CI 36.2,36.6), or a reduction of 81.3% (95%CI 80.8,81.7) compared to the baseline model. In the counterfactual decentralized care model of the Pre period, there was a relative emissions reduction of 33.1% (95%CI 32.9,33.3). When demographically matched to 10.3 million persons in the CiNA dataset, decentralized care would have reduced national emissions by 75.3 million kgCO 2 e annually; this corresponds to an estimated annual reduction of 15.0-47.7 DALYs. Conclusions: Employing decentralization through telemedicine and local care can substantially reduce emissions during cancer care delivery; this corresponds to a small reduction in human mortality.</description>
      <author>Andrew Hantel, Colin Cernik, Thomas Walsh, Hajime Uno, Dalia Larios, Jonathan E. Slutzman, Gregory A. Abel</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2024.42.16_suppl.1522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In&#8211;Situ Characterization Techniques for Mechanism Studies of CO2 Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202300511</link>
      <description>Rasmeet Singh, Lizhuo Wang, Jun Huang, ChemPlusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399475691

                The paramount concerns of global warming, fossil fuel depletion, and energy crises have prompted the need of hydrocarbons productions via CO2 conversion. In order to achieve global carbon neutrality, much attention needs to be diverted towards CO2 management. Catalytic hydrogenation of CO2 is an exciting opportunity to curb the increasing CO2 and produce value-added products. However, the comprehensive understanding of CO2 hydrogenation is still a matter of discussion due to its complex reaction mechanism and involvement of various species. This review comprehensively discusses three processes: reverse water gas shift (RWGS) reaction, modified Fischer Tropsch synthesis (MFTS), and methanol-mediated route (MeOH) for CO2 hydrogenation to hydrocarbons. It is also very important to understand the real-time evolvement of catalytic process and reaction intermediates by employing in-situ characterization techniques. Subsequently, in second part of this review, we provided a systematic analysis of advancements in in-situ techniques aimed to monitor the evolution of catalysts during CO2 reduction process. The section also highlights the key components of in-situ cells, their working principles, and applications in identifying reaction mechanisms for CO2 hydrogenation. Finally, by reviewing respective achievements in the field, we identify key gaps and present some future directions for CO2 hydrogenation and in-situ studies.</description>
      <author>Rasmeet Singh, Lizhuo Wang, Jun Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202300511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paris's parking policy for healthier cities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s2542-5196(24)00089-5</link>
      <description>Zaheer Allam, Mark Nieuwenhuijsen, Zarrin Allam, &#152;The &#156;Lancet. Planetary health. 8(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399369837

                Paris's policy adjustment in February, 2024, aimed at curbing the influx of large high-emission vehicles into its urban core by escalating parking fees for non-residents, embodies a sophisticated blend of urban planning, environmental quality efforts, climate action, and public health policy. This move is a nuanced approach to discourage the use of vehicles that disproportionately contribute to urban air pollution and greenhouse gas emissions. The initiative supports sustainable urban mobility, resonating with a wider European endeavour to minimise car dependency within cities.1Nieuwenhuijsen MJ Urban and transport planning pathways to carbon neutral, liveable and healthy cities; a review of the current evidence.Environ Int. 2020; 140105661Crossref PubMed Scopus (220) Google Scholar This policy intervention draws attention to the increasing trend of vehicle upsizing, with sport utility vehicles (SUVs) emerging as a particular concern because of their substantial environmental, climate, and, hence, health footprints. In Paris, transportation accounts for around 30% of greenhouse gas emissions,2Ministry for an Ecological and Solidary TransitionGHG information for transport services: application of article L. 1431-3 of the French transport code.https://www.ecologie.gouv.fr/sites/default/files/Information_GES%20-%202019.pdfDate: 2019Date accessed: February 1, 2024Google Scholar with private vehicles, particularly diesel and petrol-powered SUVs, being major contributors. As vehicles grow in size, their emissions and fuel consumption escalate correspondingly, exacerbating urban pollution and contributing to climate change. Data indicate that the average size of an SUV has expanded, with some models now mirroring the dimensions of small tanks, exacerbating their unsustainability. For instance, the average carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions from new cars registered in 2020 were substantially higher for SUVs, at approximately 134 g/km, which was 13 g higher than the average emissions of other new petrol cars.3European Environment AgencyAverage CO2 emissions from new cars and new vans increased again in 2019.https://www.eea.europa.eu/highlights/average-co2-emissions-from-new-cars-vans-2019Date: 2020Date accessed: February 1, 2024Google Scholar This shift towards larger vehicles is driven by a complex interplay of commercial interests and consumer preferences, with automotive manufacturers reaping higher profit margins from sales of SUVs.4Davis SC Truett LF An analysis of the impact of sport utility vehicles in the United States. Oak Ridge National Lab, Oak Ridge, TN2000Google Scholar This trend is alarming because of the clear evidence linking vehicle emissions to clinically significant health risks, including respiratory and cardiovascular diseases. For instance, SUVs have been associated with greater injury severity than regular sized cars, particularly regarding head injuries, because on collision with a cyclist, the cyclist is more likely to be thrown to the ground and subsequently further injured by other cars.5Monfort SS Mueller BC Bicyclist crashes with cars and SUVs: injury severity and risk factors.Traffic Inj Prev. 2023; 24: 645-651Crossref Scopus (1) Google Scholar Additionally, outdoor air pollution, to which vehicle emissions are a major contributor, is recognised as a leading environmental risk factor, responsible for millions of premature deaths globally.6Kheirbek I Haney J Douglas S Ito K Matte T The contribution of motor vehicle emissions to ambient fine particulate matter public health impacts in New York City: a health burden assessment.Environ Health. 2016; 15: 89Crossref PubMed Scopus (119) Google Scholar By making it more costly for non-residents to park SUVs and similar high-emission vehicles, the city of Paris is aiming to deter their use and promotes a shift towards smaller cars or use of public transport. This approach is informed by a broader vision of sustainable urban mobility that prioritises active transportation modes, such as walking and cycling, aligning with the 15-minute city concept.7Allam Z Nieuwenhuijsen M Chabaud D Moreno C The 15-minute city offers a new framework for sustainability, liveability, and health.Lancet Planet Health. 2022; 6: e181-e183Summary Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (56) Google Scholar This model proposes a reconfiguration of urban spaces to ensure that residents can access essential services within a short walk or bicycle ride from their homes, thereby reducing the need for car travel and its associated environmental burden. The implications of such policies extend beyond environmental sustainability to encompass substantial public health benefits. Studies have shown that reducing vehicle emissions can lead to notable improvements in air quality, with consequential reductions in morbidity and mortality from air pollution-related diseases.8Giles-Corti B Foster S Shilton T Falconer R The co-benefits for health of investing in active transportation.N S W Public Health Bull. 2010; 21: 122-127Crossref PubMed Scopus (151) Google Scholar Furthermore, promoting active transportation contributes to physical health benefits, including reduced obesity rates and improved mental wellbeing, enhancing the overall quality of life for urban residents.8Giles-Corti B Foster S Shilton T Falconer R The co-benefits for health of investing in active transportation.N S W Public Health Bull. 2010; 21: 122-127Crossref PubMed Scopus (151) Google Scholar Paris's initiative also reflects a growing recognition of the need to address the climate crisis through urban policy measures. The role of cities in the climate agenda is well recognised and, for the first time, the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change is producing a dedicated special report on climate change and cities as part of an upcoming assessment report.9Intergovernmental Panel on Climate ChangeIPCC calls for nomination of experts to draft an outline of the Special Report on Climate Change and Cities.https://www.ipcc.ch/2023/10/27/nomination-experts-climate-change-and-cities-scoping-meeting/Date: 2023Date accessed: February 1, 2024Google Scholar The transportation sector is a major source of CO2 emissions and cities are on the frontline of efforts to transition society towards low-carbon mobility solutions. The move to restrict high-emission vehicles from central urban areas is a crucial step in this direction, signalling a shift towards more sustainable, health-promoting urban environments. Moreover, the policy is indicative of a broader trend in urban governance that seeks to reclaim city spaces for people rather than cars, fostering more liveable, vibrant, and healthy urban landscapes. In addition to environmental and health outcomes, the policy adjustment underscores the importance of liveability as a crucial dimension of urban sustainability. By reducing the dominance of cars in the city centre, Paris is enhancing the accessibility and enjoyment of public spaces, contributing to a more pleasant urban experience for both residents and visitors. This transformation supports the development of communities that are not only ecologically sustainable but also socially inclusive and economically vibrant, aligning with compact city principles.10Nieuwenhuijsen MJ Cities at the heart of the climate action and public health agenda.Lancet Public Health. 2024; 9: e8-e9Summary Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (2) Google Scholar The Parisian policy could serve as a model for other cities grappling with similar challenges of pollution, congestion, and unsustainable urban growth. It demonstrates the potential of targeted policy interventions to influence consumer behaviour and automotive industry trends, encouraging a shift towards smaller, more efficient, and possibly electric public and active transportation. As such, it contributes to the broader discourse on sustainable urban development, highlighting the interconnectedness of environmental quality, climate crisis, public health, and urban liveability. We declare no competing interests.</description>
      <author>Zaheer Allam, Mark Nieuwenhuijsen, Zarrin Allam</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s2542-5196(24)00089-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Analyzable Solutions for Left-Turn-Centered Congestion Problems in Urban Grid Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114777</link>
      <description>Taraneh Ardalan, Denis Sarazhinsky, Nemanja Dobrota, Aleksandar Stevanovic, Sustainability. 16(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399321298

                Traffic congestion caused by left-turning vehicles in a coordinated corridor is a multifaceted problem requiring tailored solutions. This study explores the impact of shared left-turn lanes within one-way couplets, particularly during peak hours, where high left-turn volumes, limited side street storage, and the overlapped green time between pedestrians and left-turners contribute to queue spillbacks, coordination interruption, and network congestion. The focus of this paper is on the solutions that can be easily analyzed by practitioners, here called &#8220;analyzable solutions&#8221;. This approach stands in contrast to solutions derived from &#8220;non-transparent&#8221; optimization tools, which do not allow for a clear assessment of the solution&#8217;s adequacy or the ability to predict its impact in real-world applications. This paper investigates the effects of employing two analyzable signal timing strategies: Lagging Pedestrian (LagPed) phasing and Left-Turn Progression (LTP) offsets. Using high-fidelity microsimulation, the authors evaluated different scenarios, assessing pedestrian delays, queue lengths, travel time index, area average travel time index, and environmental impacts such as Fuel Consumption (FC) and CO2 emissions. The effectiveness of the proposed strategies was comprehensively evaluated against the base case scenario, demonstrating considerable improvements in various performance measures, including approximately a 5% reduction in FC and CO2 emissions. Implementation of the LTP strategy alone yields substantial reductions in delays, the number of stops, the queue length for left-turning vehicles, travel times for all road users, and ultimately FC and CO2 emissions. This study offers innovative approach to addressing the complex and multifaceted problem of left-turn-centered congestion in urban grid networks using efficient and down-to-earth analyzable solutions.</description>
      <author>Taraneh Ardalan, Denis Sarazhinsky, Nemanja Dobrota, Aleksandar Stevanovic</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of microstructure evolution and redox behavior of Ni-GDC cermet by cyclic re-oxidation in CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.478</link>
      <description>Yang Sun, Yanan Hou, Xiaofeng Guo, Huiying Qi, Ding Rong Ou, Peng Qiu, Tonghuan Zhang, Di Liu, Shuna Han, Baofeng Tu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399321601

                The microstructure and reactivity of Ni-GDC cermet under cyclic oxidation in CO2 conditions were investigated using temperature-programmed reduction (TPR), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). The XRD results revealed that NiO was formed during the re-oxidation process in CO2. SEM and TPR results demonstrated that nanostructured NiO aggregates were formed on the surface of the sample after being re-oxidized at 400 &#176;C for 1200 min, resulting in an &#945; peak with high reduction activity and a conversion of only 16% from Ni to NiO. In contrast, the samples re-oxidized at 600 &#176;C for 600 min and 800 &#176;C for 240 min were completely oxidized, resulting in reconstructed and sintered NiO with larger particle size, and a &#946; peak with lower reactivity and a conversion of 100%. Redox cycling was further conducted on completely oxidized samples, which showed a decrease in &#946; peak temperature from the first to seventh cycle. The migration and redistribution of sintered NiO towards the exterior were confirmed by comparing SEM images after the first and fourth cycles, which favored an increase in the reactive area. Therefore, this study reveals that lower re-oxidation temperatures (&#8804;400 &#176;C) and an appropriate increase in redox cycles are beneficial for forming surficial nanostructures while hindering the formation of large sintered NiO particles.</description>
      <author>Yang Sun, Yanan Hou, Xiaofeng Guo, Huiying Qi, Ding Rong Ou, Peng Qiu, Tonghuan Zhang, Di Liu, Shuna Han, Baofeng Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering Geometric Reconstruction of Bismuth with Accelerated Dynamics for CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407665</link>
      <description>Xiaowen Wang, Yangyang Zhang, Wei Shao, Yifan Li, Feng Yan, Zhifeng Dai, Yanxu Chen, Xianwei Meng, Jianghai Xia, Genqiang Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399361569

                Bismuth&#8208;based materials have emerged as promising catalysts in the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formate. However, the reasons for the reconstruction of Bi&#8208;based precursors to form bismuth nanosheets are still puzzling, especially the formation of defective bismuth sites. Herein, we prepare bismuth nanosheets with vacancy&#8208;rich defects (V&#8208;Bi NS) by rapidly reconstructing Bi19Cl3S27 under negative potential. Theoretical analysis reveals that the introduction of chlorine induces the generation of intrinsic electric field in the precursor, thereby increasing the electron transfer rate and further promoting the metallization of trivalent bismuth. Meanwhile, in situ Raman and ex situ XRD tests verify that Bi19Cl3S27 has a faster reconstruction rate than Bi2S3. The formed V&#8208;Bi NS exhibits up to 96% HCOO&#8208; Faraday efficiency and 400 mA cm&#8208;2 HCOO&#8208; partial current densities, and its ECSA normalized formate current density and yield are 2.2 times higher than those of intact bismuth nanosheets (I&#8208;Bi NS). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that bismuth vacancies with electron&#8208;rich aggregation reduce the activation energy of CO2 to *CO2&#8208; radicals and stabilize the adsorption of the key intermediate *OCHO, thus facilitating the reaction kinetics of formate production.</description>
      <author>Xiaowen Wang, Yangyang Zhang, Wei Shao, Yifan Li, Feng Yan, Zhifeng Dai, Yanxu Chen, Xianwei Meng, Jianghai Xia, Genqiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Experimental Method to Simulate Reduction Behavior of Burden in Blast Furnace Shaft</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854358</link>
      <description>Wang Guang, Weiwei Xu, Qianyu Yi, Bin-bin Lyu, Qingguo Xue, Jingsong Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399344749

                In order to evaluate the effects of CO and H2 for the gas-solid reaction behavior of the ferrous burden and coke in blast furnace shaft, a near-steady-state simulation test method of the blast furnace shaft was designed. The reduction behavior of the ferrous burden, carbon solution loss reaction under different temperatures and atmospheres, and the effect of hydrogen enrichment on the CO gas utilization ratio were investigated. The results show that above 830&#176;C, the reduction degrees of different ferrous burden structures under H2 atmosphere are higher than that under CO atmosphere. Better reduction degradation behavior could be obtained under the hydrogen-rich atmosphere. The H2O generated under H2 atmosphere could promote the carbon solution loss reaction. The solution loss ratio reaching the maximum at 950&#176;C. Under hydrogen-rich atmosphere, CO gas utilization ratio increased with the increased of H2 concentration due to the effects of the products H2O and CO2.</description>
      <author>Wang Guang, Weiwei Xu, Qianyu Yi, Bin-bin Lyu, Qingguo Xue, Jingsong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Toll Collection (Etc) Deployment on Highways: Global Patterns, Estimated Gains from the Case of Vietnam, and Policy Discussion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853522</link>
      <description>Vu Ming M. Khuong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399337342

                This paper examines the transformative shift towards Electronic Toll Collection (ETC) systems in highway management, focusing on their patterns and realized gains. By analyzing the global landscape of ETC deployment and delving deeply into the case of Vietnam, it provides practical policy insights for developing countries in this strategically urgent transition.A distinctive feature of this paper is its detailed examination of Vietnam's transition from manual toll collection (MTC) to ETC, highlighting substantial gains in emissions reduction, efficiency improvement, and savings in time and costs. In 2023, the first year of Vietnam's full ETC implementation, the estimated gains included a reduction in the consumption of 60,816 tons of gasoline and diesel, 192 tons of CO2-equivalent emissions, and 37.3 million hours in manpower time, with the total monetary equivalent value in cost savings amounting to $442 million. For the next seven years, 2024-2030, as Vietnam continues to rapidly expand highway networks, these respective figures are projected to amount to 597,862 tons of gasoline and diesel, 1,886,106 tons of CO2-equivalent emissions, 917.1 million hours, and $4.352 billion.Through policy discussion, the paper emphasizes the importance of ETC in boosting productivity and sustainable development, reducing pollution, and fostering advancement towards a smart economy and society. It underscores the critical role of government leadership and private sector engagement in successful ETC deployment.Additionally, the estimation results highlight the critical urgency and enormous benefits of making major investments and leveraging digital transformation in toll facilities such as metros, tunnels, and skyways to reduce heavy traffic congestion in megacities and inter-city roads, where millions of people and vehicles could save hours of waiting time in travel.</description>
      <author>Vu Ming M. Khuong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Mitigation Strategies across the Life Cycle of Municipal Solid Waste Incineration Plants in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c02324</link>
      <description>Yan Ma, Pin-Jing He, Fan L&#252;, Hua Zhang, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399370573

                Municipal solid waste incineration (MSWI) has become a major source of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from the waste sector in China. A comprehensive life cycle assessment model was developed for evaluating the regional and seasonal variations of GHG emissions from four MSWI plants with operational data. Subsequently, the scope was expanded nationwide to encompass carbon emission reduction pathways for MSWI plants in China. The results indicated that all plants were sources of GHG emissions, emitting between 187 and 444 kg CO2-eq/t waste, with plastic incineration exerting the most pronounced impact. The direct GHG emissions from MSWI plants exhibit distinct seasonal variations in Jiangsu and Shanghai, with emissions notably higher during the winter season. Considering the physicochemical properties of waste and the energy mix across various provinces in China, a roadmap for GHG emission reduction from MSWI was proposed. Enhanced management of low-value recyclable plastic should be reinforced in regions with higher incineration rates and direct carbon emissions, particularly in the eastern and southern parts of the country. When building or updating MSWI plants, priority should be given to upgrading steam power generation parameters in regions with higher carbon emission factors for electricity generation, such as the northwest, northeast, and southeast. Additionally, a rational design for the peripheral heat supply network of MSWI plants could augment the energy utilization efficiency. The findings are useful for the reduction of carbon emissions from MSWI in China.</description>
      <author>Yan Ma, Pin-Jing He, Fan L&#252;, Hua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c02324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESEARCH PATTERNS AND TRENDS OF CARBON EMISSION FROM INLAND WATERS AT A GLOBAL SCALE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30638/eemj.2024.065</link>
      <description>Yifei Zhao, Jie Yuan, Environmental Engineering and Management Journal. 23(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399350219

                This paper presents a bibliometric analysis of the publications on carbon emission from inland waters (CEW) in the past 10 years (2011)(2012)(2013)(2014)(2015)(2016)(2017)(2018)(2019)(2020).The study in this paper utilizes the Scopus database, which enables the retrieval of 6303 related documents.The findings of the study showed that the amount of CEW research has consistently increased over the years, and is expected to grow rapidly in the future.China and USA are the top publishing sources on CEW worldwide, with the Chinese Academy of Sciences being the top leading institution.The research in this field has focused on the CO2 source identification, the impact of environmental factors on CEW, the reduction of carbon emissions, as well as the energy usage performance and efficiency.This comprehensive study not only enhances the understanding of current CEW research among scholars and managers but also provides a historical reference for future research.</description>
      <author>Yifei Zhao, Jie Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30638/eemj.2024.065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First Emission Map of China's National Parks: Emissions from National Parks Have Significantly Different Patterns and Require Attention</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854205</link>
      <description>Shan Yang, Huan Xu, Zhicong Zhao, Fangyi Wang, Qibo Sun, Jiale Tang, Jia He, Zhong Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399345351

                National parks act as significant carbon reserves and sinks, yet their ability to offset carbon emissions is under threat, underscoring the need for stringent greenhouse gas emission control and reduction measures. Previous research has lacked detailed spatial inventories of greenhouse gas emissions from all national park sources at a national level, impeding the development of precise carbon management strategies. In this study, we conducted a uniform analysis of greenhouse gas emissions across all five national parks in China for the year 2020 at a national scale. It quantitatively assesses the spatial distribution and characteristics of emission sources, revealing that in 2020, China's national parks released a total of 6.79 million tonnes of greenhouse gas, predominantly CO2. The majority of emissions stemmed from residential and animal husbandry activities, with emission levels demonstrating spatial coherence&#8212;areas with high emissions were clustered together, and similarly for low-emission areas. Although the emissions per unit area in most national parks were significantly lower than the national average, emission hotspots in the Three-River-Source National Park were 1.78 times above the national average. The study emphasizes the importance of employing emission maps for devising effective greenhouse gas control and reduction strategies, aiming to enhance the carbon-neutral potential of national parks.</description>
      <author>Shan Yang, Huan Xu, Zhicong Zhao, Fangyi Wang, Qibo Sun, Jiale Tang, Jia He, Zhong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antimicrobial Assay of Metal Ions Using Yeast and Its Relevance to Food Preservation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsfoodscitech.4c00079</link>
      <description>Zhiguo Cao, Muhammad Shahidul Islam, Jared Sisler, Kam Chiu Tam, ACS food science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399320958

                The increasing occurrence of antimicrobial resistance in recent years has spurred research to produce new antimicrobial compounds. However, there is currently a lack of a rapid, simple, and quantitative assay to determine the antimicrobial characteristics of new antimicrobial compounds. In this study, we demonstrated that a simple water displacement apparatus can be used to determine the effects of various metal ions on the cell viability of a model organism Saccharomyces cerevisiae (S. cerevisiae) by monitoring the volume of CO2 (VCO2) released. Analysis on the effect of different metal ions on S. cerevisiae demonstrated a linear relationship between VCO2 and the reduction potentials and a linear&#8211;logarithmic relationship between VCO2 and the metal/ligand binding constant indicating this measurement's accuracy and quantitative nature. Due to its speed, simplicity, and accuracy, this water displacement method has the potential to be used as a pre-screening method to facilitate the rapid quantification and development of more effective antimicrobial agents for various applications including antimicrobial food preservation and packaging.</description>
      <author>Zhiguo Cao, Muhammad Shahidul Islam, Jared Sisler, Kam Chiu Tam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsfoodscitech.4c00079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Reactive Sites for Electrocatalytic Conversion of Nitrate to High Value-Added Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854058</link>
      <description>Yan Yu-feng, Pengfei Guo, Xin Xu, Zhongyan Zhang, Huan Lou, Fanfei Sun, Meiqin Shi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399342907

                CuZn catalysts with various structures were synthesized for electrocatalyzing NO3- and CO2. Among them, CuZn supported on nitrogen-doped carbon exhibited the capability for directly producing urea, while after treated at higher temperature it presents the highest yield of ammonia. XAFS analysis revealed in the optimized sample, Zn existed as the single atom and Cu contained Cu-O(N) and Cu-Cu coordination structures. The Cu-O(N) species promoted the C-N coupling, while the Cu-Cu component played a crucial role in the reduction of nitrate to ammonia. Cu&#948;+ (1&lt;&#948;&lt;2) in the catalyst contributed to the C-N coupling. In addition, in-situ XAFS data indicated that under the optimal potential of -0.89 V, the valence state of Cu&#948;+ decreased slightly but remained within the range of 1&lt;&#948;&lt;2. After 8-hour stability test, the catalyst maintained a stable coordination structure. This study reveals that the Cu coordination environment is a crucial parameter for selectively producing ammonia or urea.</description>
      <author>Yan Yu-feng, Pengfei Guo, Xin Xu, Zhongyan Zhang, Huan Lou, Fanfei Sun, Meiqin Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsically reactive hyperbranched interface governs graphene oxide dispersion and crosslinking in epoxy for enhanced flame retardancy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.005</link>
      <description>Hefeng Li, Cong Liu, Jie Zhu, Xianhua Huan, Kun Xu, Hongbo Geng, Xiaopeng Chen, Tianming Li, Da Deng, Ding Wen-hui, Lei Zu, Ge Liu, Xiaolong Jia, Xiaoping Yang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399393303

                Enhancing the flame retardancy of epoxy (EP) resins typically entailed a trade-off with other physical properties. Herein, hyperbranched poly(amidoamine) (HPAA) and phytic acid (PA) were used to functionalize graphene oxide (GO) via electrostatic self-assembly in water to prepare a phosphorus-nitrogen functionalized graphene oxide nanosheet (PN-GOs), which could be utilized as high efficient flame-retardant additive of epoxy resin without sacrificing other properties. The PN-GOs demonstrated improved dispersion and compatibility within the EP matrix, which resulted in significant concurrent enhancements in both the mechanical performance and flame-retardant properties of the PN-GOs/EP nanocomposites over virgin EP. Notably, the incorporation of just 1.0 wt% PN-GOs yielded a 20.4, 6.4 and 42.7 % increases in flexural strength, flexural modulus and impact strength for the PN-GOs/EP nanocomposites, respectively. Furthermore, simultaneous reductions were achieved in the peak heat release rate (pHRR) by 60.0 %, total smoke production (TSP) by 43.0 %, peak CO production rate (pCOP) by 57.9 %, and peak CO2 production rate (pCO2P) by 63.9 %. This study presented a facile method for the design of GO-based nano flame retardants, expanding their application potential in polymer-matrix composites.</description>
      <author>Hefeng Li, Cong Liu, Jie Zhu, Xianhua Huan, Kun Xu, Hongbo Geng, Xiaopeng Chen, Tianming Li, Da Deng, Ding Wen-hui, Lei Zu, Ge Liu, Xiaolong Jia, Xiaoping Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microplastics increase the microbial functional potential of greenhouse gas emissions and water pollution in a freshwater lake: a metagenomic study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.119250</link>
      <description>Tianyu Zhuo, Kehong Yu, Bo Chai, Qingfeng Tang, Xia Gao, Jiamin Wang, Lei He, Xiaohui Lei, Yang Li, Meng Yuan, Lifeng Wu, Bin Chen, Environmental research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399356879

                Aquatic ecosystems are being increasingly polluted by microplastics (MPs), which calls for an understanding of how MPs affect microbially driven biogenic element cycling in water environments. A 28-day incubation experiment was conducted using freshwater lake water added with three polymer types of MPs (i.e., polyethylene, polypropylene, polystyrene) separately or in combination at a concentration of 1 items/L. The effects of various MPs on microbial communities and functional genes related to carbon, nitrogen, phosphorus, and sulfur cycling were analyzed using metagenomics. Results showed that Sphingomonas and Novosphingobium, which were indicator taxa (genus level) in the polyethylene treatment group, made the largest functional contribution to biogenic element cycling. Following the addition of MPs, the relative abundances of genes related to methane oxidation (e.g., hdrD, frhB, accAB) and denitrification (napABC, nirK, norB) increased. These changes were accompanied by increased relative abundances of genes involved in organic phosphorus mineralization (e.g., phoAD) and sulfate reduction (cysHIJ), as well as decreased relative abundances of genes involved in phosphate transport (phnCDE) and the SOX system. Findings of this study underscore that MPs, especially polyethylene, increase the potential of greenhouse gas emissions (CO2, N2O) and water pollution (PO43&#8211;, H2S) in freshwater lakes at the functional gene level.</description>
      <author>Tianyu Zhuo, Kehong Yu, Bo Chai, Qingfeng Tang, Xia Gao, Jiamin Wang, Lei He, Xiaohui Lei, Yang Li, Meng Yuan, Lifeng Wu, Bin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.119250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indicators of Global Climate Change 2023: annual update of key indicators of the state of the climate system and human influence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-16-2625-2024</link>
      <description>Piers M. Forster, Chris Smith, Tristram Walsh, William F. Lamb, Robin Lamboll, B. D. Hall, Mathias Hauser, Aur&#233;lien Ribes, Debbie Rosen, Nathan P. Gillett, Matthew D. Palmer, Joeri Rogelj, Karina von Schuckmann, Blair Trewin, Myles Allen, Robbie M. Andrew, Richard Betts, Alex Borger, Tim Boyer, Jiddu A. Broersma, Carlo Buontempo, Samantha Burgess, Chiara Cagnazzo, Lijing Cheng, Pierre Friedlingstein, Andrew Gettelman, Johannes G&#252;tschow, Masayoshi Ishii, Stuart Jenkins, Lan X, Colin Morice, Jens M&#252;hle, Christopher Kadow, John Kennedy, Rachel Killick, P. B. Krummel, Jan C. Minx, Gunnar Myhre, Vaishali Na&#239;k, Glen P. Peters, Anna Pirani, Julia Pongratz, Carl&#8208;Friedrich Schleussner, Sonia I. Seneviratne, Sophie Szopa, Peter Thorne, Mahesh Kovilakam, Elisa Majam&#228;ki, Jukka-Pekka Jalkanen, Margreet van Marle, Rachel Hoesly, Robert Rohde, Dominik L. Schumacher, Guido R. van der Werf, Russell S. Vose, Kirsten Zickfeld, Xuebin Zhang, Val&#233;rie Masson&#8208;Delmotte, Panmao Zhai, Earth system science data. 16(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399318659

                Abstract. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) assessments are the trusted source of scientific evidence for climate negotiations taking place under the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). Evidence-based decision-making needs to be informed by up-to-date and timely information on key indicators of the state of the climate system and of the human influence on the global climate system. However, successive IPCC reports are published at intervals of 5&#8211;10 years, creating potential for an information gap between report cycles. We follow methods as close as possible to those used in the IPCC Sixth Assessment Report (AR6) Working Group One (WGI) report. We compile monitoring datasets to produce estimates for key climate indicators related to forcing of the climate system: emissions of greenhouse gases and short-lived climate forcers, greenhouse gas concentrations, radiative forcing, the Earth's energy imbalance, surface temperature changes, warming attributed to human activities, the remaining carbon budget, and estimates of global temperature extremes. The purpose of this effort, grounded in an open-data, open-science approach, is to make annually updated reliable global climate indicators available in the public domain (https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.11388387, Smith et al., 2024a). As they are traceable to IPCC report methods, they can be trusted by all parties involved in UNFCCC negotiations and help convey wider understanding of the latest knowledge of the climate system and its direction of travel. The indicators show that, for the 2014&#8211;2023 decade average, observed warming was 1.19 [1.06 to 1.30] &#176;C, of which 1.19 [1.0 to 1.4] &#176;C was human-induced. For the single-year average, human-induced warming reached 1.31 [1.1 to 1.7] &#176;C in 2023 relative to 1850&#8211;1900. The best estimate is below the 2023-observed warming record of 1.43 [1.32 to 1.53] &#176;C, indicating a substantial contribution of internal variability in the 2023 record. Human-induced warming has been increasing at a rate that is unprecedented in the instrumental record, reaching 0.26 [0.2&#8211;0.4] &#176;C per decade over 2014&#8211;2023. This high rate of warming is caused by a combination of net greenhouse gas emissions being at a persistent high of 53&#177;5.4 Gt CO2e yr&#8722;1 over the last decade, as well as reductions in the strength of aerosol cooling. Despite this, there is evidence that the rate of increase in CO2 emissions over the last decade has slowed compared to the 2000s, and depending on societal choices, a continued series of these annual updates over the critical 2020s decade could track a change of direction for some of the indicators presented here.</description>
      <author>Piers M. Forster, Chris Smith, Tristram Walsh, William F. Lamb, Robin Lamboll, B. D. Hall, Mathias Hauser, Aur&#233;lien Ribes, Debbie Rosen, Nathan P. Gillett, Matthew D. Palmer, Joeri Rogelj, Karina von Schuckmann, Blair Trewin, Myles Allen, Robbie M. Andrew, Richard Betts, Alex Borger, Tim Boyer, Jiddu A. Broersma, Carlo Buontempo, Samantha Burgess, Chiara Cagnazzo, Lijing Cheng, Pierre Friedlingstein, Andrew Gettelman, Johannes G&#252;tschow, Masayoshi Ishii, Stuart Jenkins, Lan X, Colin Morice, Jens M&#252;hle, Christopher Kadow, John Kennedy, Rachel Killick, P. B. Krummel, Jan C. Minx, Gunnar Myhre, Vaishali Na&#239;k, Glen P. Peters, Anna Pirani, Julia Pongratz, Carl&#8208;Friedrich Schleussner, Sonia I. Seneviratne, Sophie Szopa, Peter Thorne, Mahesh Kovilakam, Elisa Majam&#228;ki, Jukka-Pekka Jalkanen, Margreet van Marle, Rachel Hoesly, Robert Rohde, Dominik L. Schumacher, Guido R. van der Werf, Russell S. Vose, Kirsten Zickfeld, Xuebin Zhang, Val&#233;rie Masson&#8208;Delmotte, Panmao Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-16-2625-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interventions for postburn pruritus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.cd013468.pub2</link>
      <description>Sarthak Sinha, Vincent Gabriel, Rohit Arora, Wisoo Shin, J Scott, Shyla K Bharadia, Myriam Verly, Waleed Rahmani, Duncan Nickerson, Frankie O. G. Fraulin, Pallab Chatterjee, Rajeev Ahuja, Jeff Biernaskie, Cochrane library. 2024(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399365486

                Background Postburn pruritus (itch) is a common and distressing symptom experienced on healing or healed burn or donor site wounds. Topical, systemic, and physical treatments are available to control postburn pruritus; however, it remains unclear how effective these are. Objectives To assess the effects of interventions for treating postburn pruritus in any care setting. Search methods In September 2022, we searched the Cochrane Wounds Specialised Register, the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL), Ovid MEDLINE (including In&#8208;Process &amp; Other Non&#8208;Indexed Citations), Ovid Embase, and EBSCO CINAHL Plus. We also searched clinical trials registries and scanned references of relevant publications to identify eligible trials. There were no restrictions with respect to language, publication date, or study setting. Selection criteria Randomised controlled trials (RCTs) that enrolled people with postburn pruritus to compare an intervention for postburn pruritus with any other intervention, placebo or sham intervention, or no intervention. Data collection and analysis We used the standard methodological procedures expected by Cochrane. We used GRADE to assess the certainty of the evidence. Main results We included 25 RCTs assessing 21 interventions with 1166 randomised participants. These 21 interventions can be grouped into six categories: neuromodulatory agents (such as doxepin, gabapentin, pregabalin, ondansetron), topical therapies (such as CQ&#8208;01 hydrogel, silicone gel, enalapril ointment, Provase moisturiser, beeswax and herbal oil cream), physical modalities (such as massage therapy, therapeutic touch, extracorporeal shock wave therapy, enhanced education about silicone gel sheeting), laser scar revision (pulsed dye laser, pulsed high&#8208;intensity laser, fractional CO2 laser), electrical stimulation (transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation, transcranial direct current stimulation), and other therapies (cetirizine/cimetidine combination, lemon balm tea). Most RCTs were conducted at academic hospitals and were at a high risk of performance, attrition, and detection bias. While 24 out of 25 included studies reported change in burn&#8208;related pruritus, secondary outcomes such as cost&#8208;effectiveness, pain, patient perception, wound healing, and participant health&#8208;related quality of life were not reported or were reported incompletely. Neuromodulatory agents versus antihistamines or placebo There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that doxepin cream may reduce burn&#8208;related pruritus compared with oral antihistamine (mean difference (MD) &#8208;2.60 on a 0 to 10 visual analogue scale (VAS), 95% confidence interval (CI) &#8208;3.79 to &#8208;1.42; 2 studies, 49 participants). A change of 2 points represents a minimal clinically important difference (MCID). Due to very low&#8208;certainty evidence, it is uncertain whether doxepin cream impacts the incidence of somnolence as an adverse event compared to oral antihistamine (risk ratio (RR) 0.64, 95% CI 0.32 to 1.25; 1 study, 24 participants). No data were reported on pain in the included study. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that gabapentin may reduce burn&#8208;related pruritus compared with cetirizine (MD &#8208;2.40 VAS, 95% CI &#8208;4.14 to &#8208;0.66; 1 study, 40 participants). A change of 2 points represents a MCID. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that gabapentin reduces the incidence of somnolence compared to cetirizine (RR 0.02, 95% CI 0.00 to 0.38; 1 study, 40 participants). No data were reported on pain in the included study. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that pregabalin may result in a reduction in burn&#8208;related pruritus intensity compared with cetirizine with pheniramine maleate (MD &#8208;0.80 VAS, 95% CI &#8208;1.24 to &#8208;0.36; 1 study, 40 participants). A change of 2 points represents a MCID. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that pregabalin reduces the incidence of somnolence compared to cetirizine (RR 0.04, 95% CI 0.00 to 0.69; 1 study, 40 participants). No data were reported on pain in the included study. There is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence that ondansetron probably results in a reduction in burn&#8208;related pruritus intensity compared with diphenhydramine (MD &#8208;0.76 on a 0 to 10 numeric analogue scale (NAS), 95% CI &#8208;1.50 to &#8208;0.02; 1 study, 38 participants). A change of 2 points represents a MCID. No data were reported on pain and adverse events in the included study. Topical therapies versus relevant comparators There is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence that enalapril ointment probably decreases mean burn&#8208;related pruritus compared with placebo control (MD &#8208;0.70 on a 0 to 4 scoring table for itching, 95% CI &#8208;1.04 to &#8208;0.36; 1 study, 60 participants). No data were reported on pain and adverse events in the included study. Physical modalities versus relevant comparators Compared with standard care, there is low&#8208;certainty evidence that massage may reduce burn&#8208;related pruritus (standardised mean difference (SMD) &#8208;0.86, 95% CI &#8208;1.45 to &#8208;0.27; 2 studies, 166 participants) and pain (SMD &#8208;1.32, 95% CI &#8208;1.66 to &#8208;0.98). These SMDs equate to a 4.60&#8208;point reduction in pruritus and a 3.74&#8208;point reduction in pain on a 10&#8208;point VAS. A change of 2 VAS points in itch represents a MCID. No data were reported on adverse events in the included studies. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that extracorporeal shock wave therapy (ESWT) may reduce burn&#8208;related pruritus compared with sham stimulation (SMD &#8208;1.20, 95% CI &#8208;1.65 to &#8208;0.75; 2 studies, 91 participants). This equates to a 5.93&#8208;point reduction in pruritus on a 22&#8208;point 12&#8208;item Pruritus Severity Scale. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that ESWT may reduce pain compared with sham stimulation (MD 2.96 on a 0 to 25 pressure pain threshold (PPT), 95% CI 1.76 to 4.16; 1 study, 45 participants). No data were reported on adverse events in the included studies. Laser scar revision versus untreated or placebo controls There is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence that pulsed high&#8208;intensity laser probably results in a reduction in burn&#8208;related pruritus intensity compared with placebo laser (MD &#8208;0.51 on a 0 to 1 Itch Severity Scale (ISS), 95% CI &#8208;0.64 to &#8208;0.38; 1 study, 49 participants). There is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence that pulsed high&#8208;intensity laser probably reduces pain compared with placebo laser (MD &#8208;3.23 VAS, 95% CI &#8208;5.41 to &#8208;1.05; 1 study, 49 participants). No data were reported on adverse events in the included studies. Authors' conclusions There is moderate to low&#8208;certainty evidence on the effects of 21 interventions. Most studies were small and at a high risk of bias related to blinding and incomplete outcome data. Where there is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence, practitioners should consider the applicability of the evidence for their patients.</description>
      <author>Sarthak Sinha, Vincent Gabriel, Rohit Arora, Wisoo Shin, J Scott, Shyla K Bharadia, Myriam Verly, Waleed Rahmani, Duncan Nickerson, Frankie O. G. Fraulin, Pallab Chatterjee, Rajeev Ahuja, Jeff Biernaskie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.cd013468.pub2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;One for all, all for one&#8217;: A tale from the formative years of Scandinavian exercise physiology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1113/ep091943</link>
      <description>Ronan M. G. Berg, Experimental physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399353119

                In Scandinavia, we have a proud tradition of exercise physiology. The period from 1910 to 1920, during which August Krogh (1874&#8211;1949) and Johannes Lindhard (1870&#8211;1947) provided measurements on cardiorespiratory function and metabolism during exercise in humans, can certainly be considered its birth, at least from a merely Danish perspective. However, it is in my opinion the decades that followed the establishment of the Rockefeller Institute in Copenhagen in 1928 that comprise the formative years of Scandinavian exercise physiology. This institute, established with funds secured by August Krogh after he became a Nobel laureate, offered advanced research and teaching facilities in areas such as zoophysiology, medical physiology, gymnastics theory, biochemistry and biophysics (Asmussen, 1987). Krogh was instrumental in its design, ensuring the inclusion of facilities for Lindhard's Gymnastics Theory Laboratory on the first floor of the north wing, strategically located above his own Zoophysiological Laboratory to facilitate interaction and collaboration. It was in this environment, and under the guidance of both Lindhard and Krogh, that three scientists emerged as seminal figures in Scandinavian exercise physiology: Erik Hohw&#252; Christensen (1904&#8211;1996), Marius Nielsen (1903&#8211;2000) and Erling Asmussen (1907&#8211;1991), fondly referred to by Krogh as 'The Three Musketeers' (Schmidt-Nielsen, 1995). The tales of these three scientists are many, and their efforts to evolve and promote exercise physiology, scientifically, pedagogically and organisationally, are certainly reminiscent of the noble characters' fight for justice in Alexandre Dumas's novel. I will try to refrain from digressing too much into the swashbuckler genre here, but Dumas's sentiment that 'the merit of all things lies in their difficulty' seems to resonate well with their scientific endeavours, as they repeatedly tackled scientific challenges that appeared insurmountable, either conceptually or methodologically (Asmussen, 1987; &#197;strand, 1991). However, because a comprehensive account of their collective contributions would merit a whole monograph in its own right, I will only recapitulate one important aspect of their work from the formative years of Scandinavian exercise physiology here: the adaptative resetting of homeostasis across organ systems during exercise. Erik Hohw&#252; Christensen, universally known as 'Hohw&#252;', was still an undergraduate student in natural history, chemistry, geography and geology when he joined Lindhard at the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory, shortly after the Rockefeller Institute had been inaugurated in 1928. Under Lindhard's supervision, he engaged in a series of studies that followed up on Krogh and Lindhard's work from the preceding decade that demonstrated extremely rapid cardiovascular and gas exchange kinetics following exercise onset. Initially, his efforts were focused on enhancing the functionality of Krogh's bicycle ergometer (Krogh, 1913) and refining Krogh and Lindhard's nitrous oxide rebreathing technique developed for the measurement of cardiac output (Krogh &amp; Lindhard, 1912). While doing this, Hohw&#252; ensured an unprecedented standardisation of experimental conditions, exercising stringent control over variables such as diet, meal timings and rest periods prior to measurements. As an alternative to the nitrous oxide rebreathing technique, Hohw&#252; adapted the relatively new acetylene rebreathing method for measurements during exercise (Christensen, 1931a, 1932a), and soon Hohw&#252; expanded from mere methodologically based studies to mechanistic studies that focused not only on cardiac output, but also on blood glucose, respiration and thermoregulation (Christensen, 1931b, 1931c, 1931d, 1931e, 1932b). However, while Krogh and Lindhard's studies had mostly focused on exercise at moderate intensity in moderately fit men approaching middle age (themselves), Hohw&#252; continued the longstanding Scandinavian tradition of self-experimentation within physiology, to conduct studies at (near-)maximal intensity in highly fit, young athletes, that is, himself and three fellow students that he knew from his dormitory, including Marius Nielsen. All these experiments were meticulously carried out using Krogh's now-optimised bicycle ergometer, ensuring well-defined workloads. Most critically, and unlike other contemporary studies that typically captured measurements during transitional states&#8212;such as at the onset of exercise, immediately following exertion or during short breaks&#8212;Hohw&#252;'s work was characterised by extended continuous exercise sessions that facilitated the acquisition of steady state measurements, to compare and distinguish the physiological changes that take place during rest, exercise at well-defined intensities, and recovery. Hohw&#252; graduated in 1931, majoring in gymnastic theory, and defended his doctoral thesis based on the abovementioned studies later the same year. Marius Nielsen also graduated in 1931, majoring in natural history, and soon began conducting his experiments at the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory, focusing on the work of breathing during exercise (Nielsen, 1936a). Soon, an opportunity arose that would prove pivotal to their continued work. Since World War I, there had been an extraordinary surge in enthusiasm for sports, fuelled by the belief in athleticism as a crucial factor for health. However, some critics questioned whether these efforts genuinely contributed to improving health, highlighting the lack of clear evidence on whether athletic sports had a positive or negative impact on the body. The ambiguity surrounding the physiological effects of strenuous exercise and the safe limits of such exertion prompted the League of Nations' Health Organization to convene a meeting in Copenhagen in January 1931. Here, it was acknowledged that the specific changes occurring in the body under extreme athletic strain remained largely unexplored. To address this, experts at the meeting recommended that the Health Organization initiate a comprehensive study into various physiological responses to maximum muscular effort. Krogh and Lindhard, who attended the meeting, proposed a 2-year research programme to investigate these phenomena and subsequently received funding to continue Hohw&#252; and Nielsen's research. The preliminary results were presented to the Health Organization in Geneva in 1934, encompassing a comprehensive 32-page report (Christensen et al., 1934), which is also an early account of the oxygen transport cascade, highlighting the convective and diffusive steps for oxygen transport from ambient air to working muscle in relation to exercise performance. The funding from the League of Nations' Health Organization enabled Krogh to hire both Hohw&#252; and Nielsen as research assistants at the Zoophysiological Laboratory. Nielsen utilised this opportunity to also focus on the chemical regulation of ventilation (Nielsen, 1936b). These studies were not particularly focused on exercise as such, but exercise was used along with hypobaric hypoxia and experimentally induced metabolic acidosis (by orally administered ammonium chloride) as a means for uncovering the mechanisms regulating ventilation in humans. Specifically, Nielsen aimed to determine whether CO2 or H+ was the primary chemical stimulus that increased the 'excitability' of the respiratory centre to enhance breathing in these different conditions, a matter of great controversy during those years. During exercise, it was believed that either the increased CO2 or H+ production in the contracting skeletal muscle (and other working tissues) could increase P aC O 2 ${{P}_{{\mathrm{aC}}{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ and/or reduce arterial pH, which would then increase ventilation. Lindhard and Krogh, in particular, had both placed their bets on P aC O 2 ${{P}_{{\mathrm{aC}}{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ , but much to Nielsen's surprise, he found that both P aC O 2 ${{P}_{{\mathrm{aC}}{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ and arterial pH remained relatively constant during the prolonged strenuous exercise sessions to which he subjected Hohw&#252; and his fellow students. When Nielsen presented this to Krogh, admitting that he did not understand how to grasp these findings, Krogh replied, 'No, I don't understand that either! You must find out!' Krogh said this in such a compelling manner that it remained a source of inspiration for Nielsen for much of his future work (Schmidt-Nielsen, 1995). Nielsen defended his doctoral thesis on the regulation of respiration in 1936. While he did not succeed in conclusively determining whether CO&#8322; or H&#8314; was the primary stimulus governing the regulation of ventilation, much pointed towards CO2. However, the stimulus for the increased ventilation during any of the examined conditions was clearly not an increase in P aC O 2 ${{P}_{{\mathrm{aC}}{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ per se, but rather seemed to involve an altered sensitivity of the respiratory centre to CO&#8322; (Nielsen, 1936b). Curiously, Nielsen followed up with a study on thermoregulation during exercise, to challenge a common viewpoint that the increase in core temperature during exercise represents a failure of thermoregulation (Nielsen, 1938). Hohw&#252;'s previous study on core temperature during prolonged strenuous exercise, showing increases in temperature to levels that would be considered life-threatening in a clinical setting, had not done much to resolve this (Christensen, 1931c). In a room that was carefully thermoregulated to maintain consistent air temperature and humidity, the young scientists cycled vigorously at various intensities on Krogh's bicycle ergometer, which was suspended on a scale for the continuous measurement of weight loss due to perspiration, while rectal and skin temperatures were continuously measured (Nielsen, 1936a, 1936b). Rectal temperature increased proportionally with exercise intensity, independently of differences in the conditions for heat loss, while changes in skin temperature remained relatively minor (Nielsen, 1938). In fact, body temperature was kept within much narrower limits at a given exercise intensity than at rest. Nielsen could thus conclude that the rise in body temperature during exercise is a regulatory response and not the result of a failure in thermoregulation (Nielsen, 1938). Together, Nielsen's studies on ventilation and thermoregulation, conducted under carefully controlled conditions and at a well-defined steady state of exercise as established by Hohw&#252;, pointed towards highly regulated exercise adaptations. While all this was going on, Asmussen, who was slightly younger than Hohw&#252; and Nielsen, had started attending lectures at the Rockefeller Institute as a student of natural history. He became acquainted with Hohw&#252; who knew that Lindhard needed an assistant to develop a method for isolating frog skeletal muscle fibres. Asmussen thus joined the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory as an unpaid assistant, and soon he was able to isolate muscle fibres from the frog's semitendinosus muscle, which then allowed him to conduct a series of studies on isometric and isotonic contractions. He continued spending his afternoons and evenings doing this after he majored in gymnastic theory in 1931 while earning his livelihood as a secondary school teacher of natural history and physical education, and in 1933 he defended his doctoral thesis on this work. By 1935, Asmussen had finally landed a position as a full-time research assistant at the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory, this time with an actual salary, so that he could quit his job as a secondary school teacher and focus more wholly on his research. However, in the meantime, Lindhard had invited the renowned German neurophysiologist Fritz Buchtal (1907&#8211;2003) to join the laboratory, in part because of the increasing hostility towards the Jewish community in Germany. Buchtal's expertise naturally drove the focus at the laboratory more in the direction of electrophysiological studies of skeletal muscle, which prompted Asmussen to concentrate on the integrative physiology of the human body in response to exercise instead. Asmussen thus conducted a study on the cardiopulmonary response to static exercise by leg presses against an angle lever with considerable loads. The study showed that oxygen uptake, ventilation and cardiac output showed variable changes during exercise depending on the workload, but they all increased sharply immediately after, which was attributed to the mechanical constraint of blood flow by the actively engaged muscles (Asmussen &amp; Hansen, 1938). The thematic overlap between Hohw&#252; and Nielsen were obvious to anyone, and soon the three started working closely together. Thus, by 1936, the memorable trio had finally been formed! Initially, Hohw&#252;, Nielsen and Asmussen turned their attention towards matters deemed urgent at the time, in particular the mechanisms behind the increase in cardiac output during exercise. A prevalent theory suggested that vasodilatation in working muscle triggered a reduction in arterial blood pressure, which then led to an increase in cardiac output through baroreflex feedback. However, this could not explain the increase in stroke volume previously reported by Hohw&#252; (Christensen, 1931e), and furthermore, the arterial baroreflex feedback loop had not been conclusively demonstrated in humans, neither during postural changes nor during steady state exercise. Moreover, the existing studies often uncritically assumed that heart rate was an accurate reflection of cardiac output, a notion also inconsistent with Hohw&#252;'s earlier studies (Christensen, 1931d, 1931e). In the basement under the north wing of the Rockefeller Institute, the trio devised an experimental set-up allowing for the manipulation of blood volume distribution through pneumatic thigh cuff inflation and deflation and by the use of a tilt table (enabling upright, supine and head-down measurements), reconstructed from a resuscitation table previously designed by Krogh in one of his less successful scientific endeavours (Krogh, 1934). This set-up also permitted the measurement of oxygen uptake, cardiac output (by Hohw&#252;'s modified acetylene rebreathing technique), and blood volume changes through water displacement plethysmography. They mostly used exercise protocols that involved rhythmic arm extensions against an elastic resistance, or by employing Krogh's bicycle ergometer. The routine was such that, after completing their teaching duties around 10 a.m., The Three Musketeers would commence the day's experiments, during which they took turns serving as experimental subjects. Following lunch, they dedicated time to analysing the data obtained. The set-up and measurements were continually refined to achieve reproducible results; even so, one experimental day would generally yield only one measurement point for a given variable (Asmussen, 1987). Therefore, although their papers often report results from relatively few, in this case three subjects, these results are usually based on several months of daily experimentation. When it came to drafting manuscripts based on the the data, they would sit together at a desk in the late afternoons and evenings; Nielsen, having the neatest handwriting, would write with a pencil as they collectively formulated each sentence of the paper, while Hohw&#252;, who came from a Danish-minded family in Southern Jutland&#8212;a region that had not become part of Denmark until the Reunification in 1920&#8212;and had attended a German school, ensured that the paper's language, written in German, was impeccable (Asmussen, 1987). Krogh was a regular visitor, keen to showcase the experimental set-up to scientists from around the world, and in the evenings, he would often stop by to discuss results and ideas, contributing to further optimisation of the experiments (Asmussen, 1987; Schmidt-Nielsen, 1995). In their collaborative experiments conducted from 1936 and approximately 5 years forth, The Three Musketeers demonstrated that thigh cuff deflation in the sitting position and a postural change from supine to upright both result in blood displacement to the lower extremities with a concomitant increase in heart rate, and vice versa when moving from upright to the supine posture (Asmussen et al., 1938, 1939a). Despite a higher heart rate in the upright position, cardiac output was found to be lower due to a lower stroke volume than in the supine position, even though oxygen uptake was similar (Asmussen et al., 1939b). Additionally, superimposing arm exercise during postural changes while restricting venous return by thigh cuff inflation, caused heart rate to vary with posture in relation to differences in stroke volume, but it still increased with exercise in all postures (Asmussen &amp; Christensen, 1939; Asmussen et al., 1939c). The baroreflex feedback loop could thus be effectively demonstrated in humans, and it seemed to remain equally effective for regulating heart rate during exercise compared to rest. Hence, as Nielsen had demonstrated for ventilation and thermoregulation, the changes in cardiovascular function during exercise seemed to reflect highly regulated phenomena. In another study, about half of the working musculature was isolated from the rest of the circulation by thigh cuff inflation during exercise on Krogh's bicycle ergometer. Despite a significant reduction in oxygen uptake, cardiac output and heart rate were barely affected (Asmussen et al., 1940). This indicated that the determinant of the cardiac output increase during exercise was the workload. In a subsequent study, a similar increase in cardiac output was observed, both in the healthy state and in the case of impaired proprioceptive feedback due to posterior fascicle demyelination (neurosyphilis) when muscle contractions were induced by electrical stimulation (Asmussen et al., 1943a). Together these studies showed that during steady state light-to-moderate exercise, it was not vasodilatation in the working muscle nor cortical feed-forward impulses that accounted for the increase in cardiac output. Given that no substances produced in the muscles below the inflated cuffs could enter the main circulation while the nervous connections remained intact, a neural feedback mechanism related to the volume of involved musculature, but unrelated to proprioception, seemed to be at play. Following up on the studies from Nielsen's doctoral thesis, similar observations were made regarding the ventilatory response to exercise. Thus, during light and moderate exercise on Krogh's bicycle ergometer, the reduction in oxygen uptake evoked by thigh cuff inflation did not affect the ventilatory response to exercise (Asmussen, Hohw&#252; Christensen et al., 1943). Furthermore, a similar ventilatory response was observed during electrically induced muscle contractions, both in the healthy state and in the case of posterior fascicle demyelination (Asmussen et al., 1943b). Hence, the steady state ventilatory response to exercise also seemed to be triggered by a non-proprioceptive neural feedback mechanism. By the early 1940s, The Three Musketeers had thus demonstrated that ventilation, thermoregulation and cardiovascular function remain tightly regulated during exercise, involving feedback mechanisms originating within the working skeletal muscle that function to reset this regulation according to the given workload. However, they could not identify the exact stimulus that triggered this feedback mechanism. In 1941, that is, at the peak of The Three Musketeers' collaborative studies, Hohw&#252; decided to depart to Sweden to pursue a professorship at the Royal Gymnastic Central Institute (GCI) in Stockholm, thus marking the end of this formative period of Scandinavian exercise physiology. Apart from a brief leave of absence from GCI in the early 1960s, Hohw&#252; remained there until his retirement in 1970. However, to quote Dumas, 'Friendship is a sacred bond that cannot be broken by distance or time', and the trio remained in touch. Notably, Asmussen and Nielsen, who both became professors at the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory in 1961 and 1965, respectively, continued to investigate the elusive stimulus within working muscle that seemingly functioned to reset homeostatic regulation, initially naming it the 'work stimulus' (Asmussen &amp; Nielsen, 1958), but later using the term 'work factor' (Asmussen, 1965), thus aligning with the contemporary terminology in exercise endocrinology (Goldstein, 1965; Ingle, 1955). Later, Hohw&#252;'s students, notably Bengt Saltin (1935&#8211;2014), followed up on another series of Hohw&#252;'s early studies on skeletal muscle fuel utilization during exercise, thereby integrating glucose homeostasis into this paradigm. However, that is a different story for another time. When reflecting on the collaboration between The Three Musketeers within the context of Alexandre Dumas's 1842 novel, I have often wondered: who is who? One might liken Hohw&#252; to Athos, the noble and naturally leading figure. Nielsen could be compared to Aramis, the quieter and more thoughtful innovator. As for Asmussen, rather than resembling Porthos, the jovial and boisterous member, he might be better represented as D'Artagnan. Hence, during these formative years, the younger Asmussen grew to become Hohw&#252; and Nielsen's equal, and subsequently a driving force for their collaboration that served as the group's visionary (Saltin, 1991). This is well-exemplified by an opening talk of his at a symposium entitled 'Physiology of Muscular Exercise' held in Dallas in 1966, in which he compiled the results of The Three Musketeers to elegantly formulate the concept of adaptive resetting of homeostasis during exercise (Asmussen, 1967): 'For every state of physical exercise, there is a carefully controlled level of pulmonary function, ventilation, cardiac output and deep body temperature. These levels are maintained at least as precisely as the resting level, and the controlling feedback systems are the same in exercise as during rest; only the set-point has been changed.' At the present day, it is evident that this adaptive resetting of homeostasis during exercise should be considered a universal phenomenon involving myriad neural and non-neural mechanisms, encompassed by the evolving concept of interorgan crosstalk (Hargreaves, 2021; Severinsen &amp; Pedersen, 2020). Returning to the questions posed at The League of Nations meeting in 1931, it is thus clear that exercise is not merely a disturbance that organ systems must counteract, eliciting abnormal or extreme responses. Rather, every organ of the healthy body is 'designed' to accommodate to the steady state of exercise, both in its own right and through its interaction with other organs&#8212;'one for all, and all for one!' Sole author. The author has no conflict of interest to declare. None.</description>
      <author>Ronan M. G. Berg</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1113/ep091943</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
