<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:42:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Prospects for the Development of Nanocomposite Catalysts for the Oxidative Conversion of C1-C4 Alkanes with Carbon Dioxide to Produce Hydrogen/Synthesis Gas and Organic Compounds: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11237-024-09790-z</link>
      <description>Sergiy O. Soloviev, Theoretical and Experimental Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393011083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sergiy O. Soloviev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11237-024-09790-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digitalization and net-zero carbon: The role of industrial robots towards carbon dioxide emission reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141820</link>
      <description>Weizhi Yao, Liang Liu, Hidemichi Fujii, Lianshui Li, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393039058

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weizhi Yao, Liang Liu, Hidemichi Fujii, Lianshui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141820</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How informal environmental regulations constrain carbon dioxide emissions under pollution control and carbon reduction: Evidence from China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118732</link>
      <description>Po Kou, Ying Han, Baoling Jin, Tian Li, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392983203

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Po Kou, Ying Han, Baoling Jin, Tian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of organic cations in the electrochemical reduction of CO2 in aprotic solvents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-wl1bg</link>
      <description>James McGregor, Jay T. Bender, Amanda Petersen, Louise M. Ca&#241;ada, Jan Rossmeisl, Joan F. Brennecke, Joaquin Resasco, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392917891

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 is sensitive to the microenvironment surrounding catalytic active sites. Although the impact of changing electrolyte composition on CO2 reduction kinetics in aqueous electrolytes has been studied intensively, less is known about the influence of the electrochemical environment in non-aqueous solvents. Here, we present data demonstrating that organic alkyl ammonium cations influence catalytic performance in non-aqueous media and describe a physical model that rationalizes these observations. Using results from a combination of kinetic, spectroscopic, and computational techniques, we argue that the interfacial electric field present at the catalyst surface is sensitive to the molecular identity of the organic cation in the aprotic electrolyte. This is true irrespective of solvent, electrolyte ionic strength, or the supporting electrolyte counter anion. Our results suggest that changes in the interfacial field can be attributed to differences in the cation-electrode distance. Changes in the electric field strength are consequential to CO2R to CO as they modify the energetics of the kinetically relevant CO2 activation step.</description>
      <author>James McGregor, Jay T. Bender, Amanda Petersen, Louise M. Ca&#241;ada, Jan Rossmeisl, Joan F. Brennecke, Joaquin Resasco</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-wl1bg</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the Electrochemical Reduction of Co2 on Au25(Sr)18- Nanocluster</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4761900</link>
      <description>Dominic Alfonso, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392876479

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dominic Alfonso</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4761900</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction on a copper foam electrode at elevated pressures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150478</link>
      <description>Nandalal Girichandran, Saeed Saedy, Ruud Kortlever, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392878167

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nandalal Girichandran, Saeed Saedy, Ruud Kortlever</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 catalyzed by a Cobalt molecular complex and a bimetallic Ni-Sn electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393024413</link>
      <description>Paul Rayess, No host. None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4393024413

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Paul Rayess</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393024413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Potential of Suspension Electrodes for Enhanced Limiting Currents in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ya00611e</link>
      <description>Nathalie E. G. Ligthart, Gerard Prats Vergel, JT Johan Padding, David A. Vermaas, Energy advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392887580

                CO2 conversion is an important part of the transition towards clean fuels and chemicals. However, low solubility of CO2 in water and its slow diffusion cause mass transfer limitations in...</description>
      <author>Nathalie E. G. Ligthart, Gerard Prats Vergel, JT Johan Padding, David A. Vermaas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ya00611e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient photoelectrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formate via Bi-Doped InOCl nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174220</link>
      <description>Yibo Jia, Huimin Yang, Rui Chen, Yi Zhang, Fanfan Gao, Nan Cheng, Jiaqi Yang, Xuemei Gao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392975989

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yibo Jia, Huimin Yang, Rui Chen, Yi Zhang, Fanfan Gao, Nan Cheng, Jiaqi Yang, Xuemei Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Blood Cell (RBC)-like Ni@N&#8211;C composites for Efficient Electrochemical CO2 Reduction and Zn-CO2 Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta08049h</link>
      <description>Lei Han, Chengwei Wang, Haiping Xu, Ming Yang, Bing Liu, Ming Liu, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392854289

                Developing high-activity and selectivity electrocatalysts for reducing CO2 to value-added products provides an alternative pathway to alleviate the energy crisis and greenhouse effect. Herein, we presented a ligand-assisted supermolecule-derived red...</description>
      <author>Lei Han, Chengwei Wang, Haiping Xu, Ming Yang, Bing Liu, Ming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta08049h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in Membrane Technologies for Enhanced Water Splitting and Co2 Reduction: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52783/jchr.v14.i2.3372</link>
      <description>, Journal of Chemical Health Risks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393005861

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52783/jchr.v14.i2.3372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Tuning of the Selectivity of Cu-Based Interface for Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction by Ligand Modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4760891</link>
      <description>Yonggao Yan, Tongxian Li, Manuel Oliva&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Yuguo Zhao, Shuo Wang, Xin Chen, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392973237

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yonggao Yan, Tongxian Li, Manuel Oliva&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Yuguo Zhao, Shuo Wang, Xin Chen, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4760891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi&#8208;metallic Layered Catalysts for Stable Electrochemical CO2 Reduction to Formate and Formic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301894</link>
      <description>Tu N. Nguyen, Behnam Nourmohammadi Khiarak, Zijun Xu, Amirhossein Farzi, Sharif Md. Sadaf, Ali Seifitokaldani, Cao-Thang Dinh, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392882857

                We report the development of bismuth (Bi) gas diffusion electrodes on a polytetrafluoroethylene&#8208;based electrically conductive silver (Ag) substrate (Ag@Bi), which exhibits high Faradaic efficiency (FE) for formate of over 90% in 1 M KOH and 1 M KHCO3 electrolytes. The catalyst also shows high selectivity of formic acid above 85% in 1 M NaCl catholyte, which has a bulk pH of 2&#8208;3 during ECR, at current densities up to 300 mA cm&#8208;2. In 1 M KHCO3 condition, the Ag@Bi maintains a formate FE above 90% for at least 500 hours at the current density of 100 mA cm&#8208;2. We found that Ag@Bi catalysts degrade over time due to the leaching of Bi in the NaCl catholyte. To overcome this challenge, we deposited a layer of Ag nanoparticles on the surface of Ag@Bi to form a multi&#8208;layer Ag@Bi/Ag catalyst. This designed catalyst exhibits 300 hours of stability with FE for formic acid &#8805; 70% at 100 mA cm&#8208;2. Our work establishes a new strategy for achieving the operational longevity of ECR under wide pH conditions, which is critical for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Tu N. Nguyen, Behnam Nourmohammadi Khiarak, Zijun Xu, Amirhossein Farzi, Sharif Md. Sadaf, Ali Seifitokaldani, Cao-Thang Dinh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transient Pulsed Discharge Preparation of Graphene Aerogel Supported Asymmetric Cu Cluster Catalysts Promote CO2 Reduction to Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3991307/v1</link>
      <description>Wenxing Chen, Kaiyuan Liu, Hao Shen, Zhiyi Sun, Qiang Zhang, Guoqiang Liu, Zhongti Sun, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392922115

                Abstract Precisely designing asymmetrical structure is an efficient strategy to optimize the performance of metallic catalysts for electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reactions. Herein, a transient high-density current induced by pulsed discharge is used to rapidly construct graphene aerogel (GAs) supported asymmetric Cu cluster catalysts. Cu atoms decomposed by CuCl 2 are converged on graphene surfaces in GAs together with oxygen originating from the intense current and instantaneous high temperature. The atomic and electronic structures of Cu nanoclusters exhibit asymmetric distribution due to lattice distortion and O-doping in Cu crystals. Typically, in CO 2 reduction reactions, the selectivity and activity of ethanol are related to the asymmetric structure and strong interfacial interaction of Cu-O/C moieties, exhibiting an ideal Faradaic efficiency (ethanol 75.3% and C 2+ products 90.5%) at -1.1 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). Meanwhile, the benefit of the strong interaction between Cu nanoclusters and GA supports, the catalyst exhibits long-term stability. In situ XAFS reveals that the Cu 4 -Cu/C 2 O 1 interaction displays the effective active sites in CO 2 RR. The pathways of corresponding products and the reaction mechanism on Cu 4 -Cu/C 2 O 1 moieties are revealed through the in situ attenuated total reflectance Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy and the calculation of density functional theory. This work gives a new solution to solve the challenge for balancing the activity and stability of asymmetric-structure catalysts toward energy conversion reactions.</description>
      <author>Wenxing Chen, Kaiyuan Liu, Hao Shen, Zhiyi Sun, Qiang Zhang, Guoqiang Liu, Zhongti Sun, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3991307/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulate the Adsorption of Oxygen-Containing Intermediates to Promote the Reduction of Co2 to Ch4 on Ni-Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4764056</link>
      <description>Hedan Yao, Liuyi Pan, Xi Yao, Wenhong Li, Yi Qin, Dong Li, Yingxia Wang, Wenjie Xue, Qianqian Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392955133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hedan Yao, Liuyi Pan, Xi Yao, Wenhong Li, Yi Qin, Dong Li, Yingxia Wang, Wenjie Xue, Qianqian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4764056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-doped Cu2O with the tunable Cu0 and Cu+sites for selective CO2 electrochemical reduction to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.03.012</link>
      <description>Yao Shen, Ling-Bo Qian, Qing Xu, S. S. Wang, Yong Chen, Hong L&#252;, Yingke Zhou, Jiexu Ye, Jingkai Zhao, Xiang Gao, Shihan Zhang, Journal of Environmental Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392894348

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Shen, Ling-Bo Qian, Qing Xu, S. S. Wang, Yong Chen, Hong L&#252;, Yingke Zhou, Jiexu Ye, Jingkai Zhao, Xiang Gao, Shihan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.03.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable preparation of Cu2O/Cu-CuTCPP MOF heterojunction for enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159937</link>
      <description>Miao Sun, Xiao Xu, Shihao Min, Jie He, Kun Li, Longtian Kang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392907560

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miao Sun, Xiao Xu, Shihao Min, Jie He, Kun Li, Longtian Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gram-scale synthesis of Ni-Zn diatomic sites catalyst for efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114050</link>
      <description>Jinchao Li, Zhipeng Cao, Xinai Zhang, Ling Gao, Xueling Li, Liang Chen, Yaping Zhang, Qingchun Zhang, Ping Zhang, Tianxia Liu, Molecular Catalysis. 558(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392930254

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinchao Li, Zhipeng Cao, Xinai Zhang, Ling Gao, Xueling Li, Liang Chen, Yaping Zhang, Qingchun Zhang, Ping Zhang, Tianxia Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrophilic-hydrophobic Janus polybenzimidazole membrane electrode assemblies regulate hydrogen evolution for high efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.memsci.2024.122665</link>
      <description>Zhi Qiu, Maowei He, Shuyu Liang, Xinyu Li, Zuyu Li, Yanan Jiang, Yun Ye, Lihua Wang, Journal of Membrane Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392932366

                The membrane Electrode Assemblies (MEAs) electrolyzers are the most attractive systems for the electrolytic conversion of CO2 into commodity chemicals and fuels at commercially relevant current densities. Suppressing the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is vital to the highly efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). However, little attention has been paid to the HER. Herein, polybenzimidazole (PBI) Janus membranes with significant hydrophobic/hydrophilic asymmetric surface wettability were constructed for regulating the HER in CO2RR. The HER was modulated by adjusting the microstructure and surface hydrophobicity of the membrane as well as the CO2 feeding method. The p-PBI-HCF MEA showed a significant suppression of HER and a 6-fold improvement in CO selectivity over p-PBI MEA. The p-PBI-HCF exhibited superior CO2RR performance in MEA compared to commercial membranes (FAA-3-50 and Nafion115). At 2.0&#8211;3.0 V, the CO Faraday efficiency (FECO) of the p-PBI-HCF MEA electrolyzer remained above 92%. The optimal energy efficiency range was between 2.0 and 2.4 V when the FECO was close to 100%. The p-PBI-HCF provided 92% FECO and a current density of 225 mA cm&#8722;2 at 3 V. This work provides guidelines for the development of viable PBI membranes and MEAs for CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Zhi Qiu, Maowei He, Shuyu Liang, Xinyu Li, Zuyu Li, Yanan Jiang, Yun Ye, Lihua Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.memsci.2024.122665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Metalated Porphyrin-Based MOFs Coupled with Anatase as Photocatalysts for CO2 Reduction: The Effect of Metalation Proportion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17061483</link>
      <description>Maria Anagnostopoulou, Val&#233;rie Keller, Konstantinos C. Christoforidis, Energies. 17(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393006588

                Converting carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable chemicals such as fossil resources via photocatalysis requires the development of advanced materials. Herein, we coupled zirconium-based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) containing porphyrin and Cu-porphyrin with anatase TiO2. The effect of the porphyrin metalation proportion was also investigated. Notably, while the use of free-base porphyrin as the organic linker resulted in the development of PCN-224, the presence of Cu-porphyrin provided mixed-phase MOF structures containing both PCN-224 and PCN-222. MOF/TiO2 composites bearing partial (50%) metalated porphyrin were proven more active and selective towards the production of CH4, at ambient conditions, in the gas phase and using water vapors without the use of hole scavengers. The optimized composite bearing 15 wt.% of the partial metalated MOF was three times more active than pure TiO2 towards CH4 production. This study provides insights on the effect of precise materials engineering at a molecular level on the development of advanced MOF-based photocatalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Maria Anagnostopoulou, Val&#233;rie Keller, Konstantinos C. Christoforidis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17061483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review: Enhanced performance of recycled cement and CO2 emission reduction effects through thermal activation and nanosilica incorporation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135763</link>
      <description>Ying&#8208;Ying Zheng, Xinyue Xi, Heng Liu, Cheng-Ran Du, Hongbo Lu, Construction and Building Materials. 422(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392873054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying&#8208;Ying Zheng, Xinyue Xi, Heng Liu, Cheng-Ran Du, Hongbo Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Objective Evolutionary Optimization &amp; 4E analysis of a bulky combined cycle power plant by CO2/ CO/ NOx reduction and cost controlling targets</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4392886402</link>
      <description>Soheil Mohtaram, HongGuang Sun, Ji Lin, Wen Chen, Yonghui Sun, RePEc: Research Papers in Economics. None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4392886402

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soheil Mohtaram, HongGuang Sun, Ji Lin, Wen Chen, Yonghui Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4392886402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ exsolved ultrafine Ni nanoparticles from CeZrNiO2 solid solution for efficient photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction by CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmate.2024.100188</link>
      <description>Guanrui Ji, Lanxiang Ji, Shaowen Wu, L. Meng, Ying-Lian Jia, Zhanning Liu, Shihua Dong, Jian Tian, Yuanzhi Li, Advanced Powder Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392852583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanrui Ji, Lanxiang Ji, Shaowen Wu, L. Meng, Ying-Lian Jia, Zhanning Liu, Shihua Dong, Jian Tian, Yuanzhi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmate.2024.100188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Synergistic Effect of Ni Single Atoms and Adjacent 3d metal Doped Ni Nanoparticles in Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00167b</link>
      <description>Yingjie Liu, Zhaohui Wu, Shuting Bai, Tianyang Shen, Qian Li, Guihao Liu, Xiaoliang Sun, Yihang Hu, Ziheng Song, Jinfeng Chu, Yu&#8208;Fei Song, Nanoscale advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392917915

                Herein, we report the successful fabrication of a serious of transition metal doped Ni nanoparticles (NPs) cooperated by Ni single atoms in nitrogen-doped carbon nanotubes (denoted as Ni1+NPsM-NCNTs, M =...</description>
      <author>Yingjie Liu, Zhaohui Wu, Shuting Bai, Tianyang Shen, Qian Li, Guihao Liu, Xiaoliang Sun, Yihang Hu, Ziheng Song, Jinfeng Chu, Yu&#8208;Fei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00167b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inductive effect in amino functionalized ionic liquids modified TS-1 nanosheets for efficiently sunlight-driven CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131504</link>
      <description>Xin Guo, Zhiyuan Wang, Siqi Jiang, Mengwei Li, Jianing Guo, Yu Chen, Xiujuan Wei, Baohui Qi, Qizhong Huang, Yanduo Liu, Hongquan Jiang, Yu&#8208;Feng Hu, Fuel. 367(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392932051

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Guo, Zhiyuan Wang, Siqi Jiang, Mengwei Li, Jianing Guo, Yu Chen, Xiujuan Wei, Baohui Qi, Qizhong Huang, Yanduo Liu, Hongquan Jiang, Yu&#8208;Feng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au@ZnS core&#8211;shell nanoparticles decorated 3D hierarchical porous TiO2 photocatalysts for visible-light-driven CO2 reduction into CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120017</link>
      <description>Yifei Li, Yuechang Wei, Jing Xiong, Zhiling Tang, Yingli Wang, Xiong Wang, Zhao Zhang, Jian Liu, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392845137

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifei Li, Yuechang Wei, Jing Xiong, Zhiling Tang, Yingli Wang, Xiong Wang, Zhao Zhang, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120017</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
