<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:36:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Bi Doped In2O3 Nanofiber for Efficient Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401399</link>
      <description>Yuanxiang Zhao, Xinchun Lv, Zifan Zhu, H. J. Yang, Xintao Ma, Yifei Sun, Abdullah Alodhayb, Xiaodong Yi, Wei Shi, Zhou Chen, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403255205

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) to formic acid (HCOOH) is attracted for superfluous CO2 removal and HCOOH production under ambient conditions. Indium based catalysts has considered as a good candidate material for CO2RR&#8208;to&#8208;HCOOH due to their environmentally friendly features. However, the catalytic efficiency is limited by the poor HCOOH Faradaic efficiency (FE) and high reaction overpotential of electrocatalyst, and the activity and stability of indium based catalysts are unsatisfactory, especially in industrial current density that is critical for commercialization. Herein, a fiber Bi&#8208;doped In2O3 was synthesized through electrospinning method, and it demonstrate a FEHCOOH of 88.2% at &#8208;1.5 V vs. RHE (Reversible Hydrogen Electrode) with partial current density of &#8208;21.8 mA cm&#8208;2 in H type cell. Specially, the Bi&#8208;In electrocatalyst reach the industrial current density standard, which can work at &#8208;400 mA cm&#8208;2 current density with FEHCOOH of 92.7% (yield of HCOOH is 6.9 mmol h&#8208;1) in home&#8208;made Flow cell. Importantly, Bi&#8208;In shows 24 hours long&#8208;term stability test in &#8208;300 mA cm&#8208;2. The improvement catalytic activity of Bi&#8208;In catalyst is ascribed to the optimized electronic structure of In site, and the reduced work function value of Bi&#8208;In is beneficial for reducing the formation energy of the key *OCHO intermediates.</description>
      <author>Yuanxiang Zhao, Xinchun Lv, Zifan Zhu, H. J. Yang, Xintao Ma, Yifei Sun, Abdullah Alodhayb, Xiaodong Yi, Wei Shi, Zhou Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401399</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pitfalls in Photochemical and Photoelectrochemical Reduction of CO2 to Energy Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29194758</link>
      <description>Tomasz Baran, Domenico Caringella, Angela Dibenedetto, Michele Aresta, Molecules. 29(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403218775

                The photochemical and photoelectrochemical reduction of CO2 is a promising approach for converting carbon dioxide into valuable chemicals (materials) and fuels. A key issue is ensuring the accuracy of experimental results in CO2 reduction reactions (CO2RRs) because of potential sources of false positives. This paper reports the results of investigations on various factors that may contribute to erroneous attribution of reduced-carbon species, including degradation of carbon species contained in photocatalysts, residual contaminants from synthetic procedures, laboratory glassware, environmental exposure, and the operator. The importance of rigorous experimental protocols, including the use of labeled 13CO2 and blank tests, to identify true CO2 reduction products (CO2RPs) accurately is highlighted. Our experimental data (eventually complemented with or compared to literature data) underline the possible sources of errors and, whenever possible, quantify the false positives with respect to the effective conversion of CO2 in clean conditions. This paper clarifies that the incidence of false positives is higher in the preliminary phase of photo-material development when CO2RPs are in the range of a few 10s of &#956;g gcat&#8722;1 h&#8722;1, reducing its importance when significant conversions of CO2 are performed reaching 10s of mol gcat&#8722;1 h&#8722;1. This paper suggests procedures for improving the reliability and reproducibility of CO2RR experiments, thus validating such technologies.</description>
      <author>Tomasz Baran, Domenico Caringella, Angela Dibenedetto, Michele Aresta</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29194758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal trajectory of technological growth in Sub-Sahara Africa: new insights for achieving carbon dioxide emissions reduction and environmental sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10668-024-05467-8</link>
      <description>Seidu Abdulai Jamatutu, Kashif Abbass, Huaming Song, Sidique Gawusu, Kyei Emmanuel Yeboah, Environment Development and Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403209063

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seidu Abdulai Jamatutu, Kashif Abbass, Huaming Song, Sidique Gawusu, Kyei Emmanuel Yeboah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10668-024-05467-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling the Polarity of Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks to Promote Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416367</link>
      <description>Xiaolong Zhang, Junnan Chen, Xiaogang Wang, Yingjun Dong, Jiapeng Ji, Linbo Li, Ming Xue, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403335645

                The addition of polar functional groups to porous structures is an effective strategy for increasing the ability of metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) to capture CO2 by enhancing interactions between the dipoles of the polar functional groups and the quadrupoles of CO2. However, the potential of MOFs grafted to polar functional group to activate CO2 has not been investigated in the context of CO2 electrolysis. In this study, we report a mixed&#8208;ligand strategy to incorporate various functional groups in the MOFs. We found that substituents with strong polarity led to increased catalytic performance of electrochemical CO2 reduction for these polarized MOFs. Both experimental and theoretical evidence indicates that the presence of polar functional groups induces a charge redistribution in the micropores of MOFs. We have shown that higher electron densities of sp2&#8208;carbon atoms in benzimidazolate ligands reduces the energy barrier to generate *COOH, which is simultaneously controlled by the mass transfer of CO2. Our research offers an effective method of disrupting local electron neutrality in the pores of electrocatalysts/supports to activate CO2 under electrochemical conditions.</description>
      <author>Xiaolong Zhang, Junnan Chen, Xiaogang Wang, Yingjun Dong, Jiapeng Ji, Linbo Li, Ming Xue, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COmbined suN-Driven Oxidation and CO2 Reduction for renewable energy storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101006839</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4403221851

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101006839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do CuAl catalysts outperform in CO2 electro-reduction to C2H4?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2292-3</link>
      <description>Dongfang Cheng, Gong Zhang, Lulu Li, Xiangcheng Shi, Wenjin Zhu, Xintong Yuan, Lyudmila V. Moskaleva, Peng Zhang, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403209488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongfang Cheng, Gong Zhang, Lulu Li, Xiangcheng Shi, Wenjin Zhu, Xintong Yuan, Lyudmila V. Moskaleva, Peng Zhang, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2292-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial photosynthetic system for diluted CO2 reduction in gas-solid phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53066-y</link>
      <description>Ya Wang, Jianxin Wei, Hong&#8208;Liang Tang, Le Shao, Long&#8722;Zhang Dong, X. Chu, Yanxia Jiang, Guiling Zhang, Fengming Zhang, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403328377

                Rational design of robust photocatalytic systems to direct capture and in-situ convert diluted CO2 from flue gas is a promising but challenging way to achieve carbon neutrality. Here, we report a new type of host-guest photocatalysts by integrating CO2-enriching ionic liquids and photoactive metal-organic frameworks PCN-250-Fe2M (M = Fe, Co, Ni, Zn, Mn) for artificial photosynthetic diluted CO2 reduction in gas-solid phase. As a result, [Emim]BF4(39.3 wt%)@PCN-250-Fe2Co exhibits a record high CO2-to-CO reduction rate of 313.34 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 under pure CO2 atmosphere and 153.42 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 under diluted CO2 (15%) with about 100% selectivity. In scaled-up experiments with 1.0 g catalyst and natural sunlight irradiation, the concentration of pure and diluted CO2 (15%) could be significantly decreased to below 85% and 10%, respectively, indicating its industrial application potential. Further experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that ionic liquids not only benefit CO2 enrichment, but also form synergistic effect with Co2+ sites in PCN-250-Fe2Co, resulting in a significant reduction in Gibbs energy barrier during the rate-determining step of CO2-to-CO conversion. Artificial photosynthetic diluted CO2 reduction from fuel gas is promising but challenging for carbon neutrality. Here, the authors report a host-guest system by integrating CO2-enriching ionic liquids and photoactive metal-organic frameworks, greatly enhancing CO2-to-CO conversion efficiency.</description>
      <author>Ya Wang, Jianxin Wei, Hong&#8208;Liang Tang, Le Shao, Long&#8722;Zhang Dong, X. Chu, Yanxia Jiang, Guiling Zhang, Fengming Zhang, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53066-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403224119

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403223487

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403224103

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403223846

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Jiangnan Li, Xinyi Duan, Chao Wu, Yucheng Cao, Zhiyao Duan, Peng Zhang, Wenjun Fan, Fuxiang Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403224004

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiangnan Li, Xinyi Duan, Chao Wu, Yucheng Cao, Zhiyao Duan, Peng Zhang, Wenjun Fan, Fuxiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403224106

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction into formate: Unleashing the effect of engineered bimetallic oxides supported on activated carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161468</link>
      <description>H. R. Manjunath, Chob Singh, Puneethkumar M. Srinivasappa, Krishnan Ravi, Ankush V. Biradar, Hanimi Reddy Bapatu, Arvind H. Jadhav, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403243822

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. R. Manjunath, Chob Singh, Puneethkumar M. Srinivasappa, Krishnan Ravi, Ankush V. Biradar, Hanimi Reddy Bapatu, Arvind H. Jadhav</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on reaction mechanism of CO2 electro-reduction to CO in organic medium: Revealed by experimental and spectroscopic Investigations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161459</link>
      <description>Fengxia Shen, Shuai Wu, Mario Kurniawan, David Ostheimer, Jin Shi, Tianyou Chen, Andreas Bund, Thomas Hannappel, Jianxiong Liu, Pengchong Zhao, Shipeng Miao, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403242096

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengxia Shen, Shuai Wu, Mario Kurniawan, David Ostheimer, Jin Shi, Tianyou Chen, Andreas Bund, Thomas Hannappel, Jianxiong Liu, Pengchong Zhao, Shipeng Miao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161459</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convenient partial reduction of CO2 to a useful C1 building block: efficient access to 13C&#8208;labelled N&#8208;heterocyclic carbenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401179</link>
      <description>Nicholas A. Phillips, Joshua S. Sapsford, D&#225;niel Cs&#243;k&#225;s, Bianka K&#243;tai, Ines Perez-Tabarnero, Silvia D&#237;ez&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Daniel Scott, Imre P&#225;pai, Andrew E. Ashley, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403214267

                The selective, transition metal&#8208;free hydrosilylation of CO2 to CH2(OSiEt3)2 has been achieved under mild conditions and in high isolated yields (up to 90%) using Et3SiH and the simple, easily prepared borohydride catalyst Li+[HB(C6F5)3]&#8722;. The resulting CO2&#8208;derived bis(silyl)acetal product &#8211; whose mechanism of formation has been interrogated through detailed computational and experimental studies &#8211; can be rapidly valorized through the facile synthesis of N&#8208;heterocyclic carbenes, via their corresponding imidazolium salts. By using relatively inexpensive, isotopically enriched 13CO2 this protocol can be exploited to prepare NHC isotopologues that are selectively 13C labelled at the key, ligating C2 position. This provides an electronically responsive 13C NMR spectroscopic handle with dramatically enhanced sensitivity which can directly benefit reactivity studies in both organo&#8208; and organometallic catalysis, where NHC use is ubiquitous.</description>
      <author>Nicholas A. Phillips, Joshua S. Sapsford, D&#225;niel Cs&#243;k&#225;s, Bianka K&#243;tai, Ines Perez-Tabarnero, Silvia D&#237;ez&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Daniel Scott, Imre P&#225;pai, Andrew E. Ashley</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N, S-coordinated Ni single-atom catalysts for efficient CO2 reduction in a zero-gap membrane electrode assembly electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101706</link>
      <description>Ye Eun Jeon, Jumi Hong, Byeong&#8208;Seon An, Hyun You Kim, Chunjoong Kim, Jinwoo Lee, Han-Koo Lee, Jin-Won Park, You Na Ko, Youngeun Kim, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403287192

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ye Eun Jeon, Jumi Hong, Byeong&#8208;Seon An, Hyun You Kim, Chunjoong Kim, Jinwoo Lee, Han-Koo Lee, Jin-Won Park, You Na Ko, Youngeun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Microbial CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction by the Biocompatible and Electroactive Bimetallic Fe&#8211;Mn Oxide Cathode for Acetate Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06214</link>
      <description>Jin Du, Hebin Liang, Yan&#8211;Rong Zou, Bing Li, Xiaoyan Li, Lin Lin, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403293539

                The electroreduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) to high-value organic chemicals by the microbial electrosynthesis (MES) system relies heavily on the electrochemical properties of the electrode materials. In this work, CO2 reduction for acetate production was greatly boosted by decorating the carbon felt cathode using the Fe&#8211;Mn bimetallic oxides, using an enriched anaerobic mixed culture dominated by the homoacetogen Acetobacterium wieringae. In comparison with the unmodified carbon felt as the cathode in the MES reactor, modification with MnFe2O4 increased the acetate production rate from 28 to 78 g/(m2&#183;d), higher than those with MnO at 59 g/(m2&#183;d) and Fe2O3 at 62 g/(m2&#183;d), and the relative abundance of A. wieringae increased dramatically from 51 to 87% in the biofilm. This was probably due to the mediated electron uptake via the redox cycles of Mn(III)/(II) and Fe(III)/(II), improved specific surface area, and enhanced hydrophilicity of the cathode, benefiting from the synergistic effect of Fe and Mn ions. Overall, this study provides a facile and promising electrode modification strategy for MES with Fe&#8211;Mn bimetallic oxides for efficient CO2 conversion and acetate production, bringing the world closer to achieving carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Jin Du, Hebin Liang, Yan&#8211;Rong Zou, Bing Li, Xiaoyan Li, Lin Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Control of Copper-Based MOF Catalysts for Electroreduction of CO2: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102205</link>
      <description>Hongxin Fu, Hailing Ma, Shuaifei Zhao, Processes. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403296453

                With the excessive use of fossil fuels, atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) concentrations have risen dramatically in recent decades, leading to serious environmental and social issues linked to global climate change. The emergence of renewable energy sources, such as solar, tidal, and wind energy, has created favorable conditions for large-scale electricity production. Recently, significant attention has been drawn to utilizing renewable energy to catalyze the conversion of CO2 into fuels, producing substantial industrial feedstocks. In these CO2 conversion processes, the structure and performance of catalysts are critical. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) and their derivatives have emerged as promising electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction, offering advantages such as high surface area, porosity, exceptional functionality, and high conversion efficiency. This article provides a comprehensive review of structural regulation strategies for copper-based MOFs, highlighting innovative mechanisms like synergistic bimetallic catalysis, targeted doping strategies, and the construction of heterostructures. These novel approaches distinguish this review from previous studies, offering new insights into the electrocatalytic performance of copper-based MOFs and proposing future research directions for improved catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Hongxin Fu, Hailing Ma, Shuaifei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide Capture and Sequestration for Production of Synthetic Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18412/1816-0395-2024-10-4-9</link>
      <description>E.L. Kolychev, Artem Sulimov, &#1050;. &#1040;. &#1054;&#1074;&#1095;&#1080;&#1085;&#1085;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, A. V. Kleimenov, Ecology and Industry of Russia. 28(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403219674

                The processes of carbon dioxide sequestration at obtaining various inorganic carbonate materials, including with the use of biotechnologies, and formation of organic polymers and monomers for them from CO 2 are considered. It is revealed that in the case of inorganic materials the use of slags and sludges containing a large amount of metal oxides from various industries looks the most appropriate, and in the case of materials based on organic polymers the technologies based on polycarbonates, as well as polycarbonate-containing polyols and phosgene-free isocyanates for polyurethanes are preferable. New promising methods under active development but not yet industrially applied, such as electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide and its condensation with butadiene, are analyzed.</description>
      <author>E.L. Kolychev, Artem Sulimov, &#1050;. &#1040;. &#1054;&#1074;&#1095;&#1080;&#1085;&#1085;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, A. V. Kleimenov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18412/1816-0395-2024-10-4-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative analysis of embodied carbon in modular and conventional construction methods in Hong Kong</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-73906-7</link>
      <description>Jiaying Wei, Bin Ge, Ying Zhong, Tik Long Lee, Yi Zhang, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403246062

                Addressing the rise in global temperatures and the associated increase in greenhouse gases, particularly carbon dioxide, is a critical challenge necessitating innovative approaches within the building sector, a significant contributor to worldwide carbon emissions. While previous studies have demonstrated the prefabrication's potential in reducing emissions, comprehensive assessments using actual project data for buildings constructed entirely with modular methods in Hong Kong are lacking. This study bridges this gap by evaluating the modular integrated construction (MiC) method through an embodied carbon assessment of the Kai Tak Community Isolation Facility. Using comprehensive project data from China State Construction (HK) Limited, the research conducts a comparative analysis between the actual emissions of the MiC method and those of a hypothetical conventional construction approach. Quantitative analysis reveals that MiC achieves a 20.7% reduction in embodied carbon, primarily due to shortened construction timelines, decreased waste generation, and optimized material usage. This significant reduction suggests substantial potential for decreasing the construction industry's carbon footprint. The study provides empirical evidence supporting the environmental benefits of MiC in Hong Kong construction industry, promoting its broader adoption of MiC as a strategy for achieving carbon reduction targets. The findings align with Hong Kong's carbon neutrality goals and contribute to the global initiative to mitigate the effects of climate change.</description>
      <author>Jiaying Wei, Bin Ge, Ying Zhong, Tik Long Lee, Yi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-73906-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst Design and Engineering for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;to&#8208;Formic Acid Electrosynthesis for a Low&#8208;Carbon Economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404980</link>
      <description>Karthik Peramaiah, Moyu Yi, Indranil Dutta, Sudipta Chatterjee, Huabin Zhang, Zhiping Lai, Kuo&#8208;Wei Huang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403359797

                Abstract Formic acid (FA) has emerged as a promising candidate for hydrogen energy storage due to its favorable properties such as low toxicity, low flammability, and high volumetric hydrogen storage capacity under ambient conditions. Recent analyses have suggested that FA produced by electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) reduction reaction (eCO 2 RR) using low&#8208;carbon electricity exhibits lower fugitive hydrogen (H 2 ) emissions and global warming potential (GWP) during the H 2 carrier production, storage and transportation processes compared to those of other alternatives like methanol, methylcyclohexane, and ammonia. eCO 2 RR to FA can enable industrially relevant current densities without the need for high pressures, high temperatures, or auxiliary hydrogen sources. However, the widespread implementation of eCO 2 RR to FA is hindered by the requirement for highly stable and selective catalysts. Herein, the aim is to explore and evaluate the potential of catalyst engineering in designing stable and selective nanostructured catalysts that can facilitate economically viable production of FA.</description>
      <author>Karthik Peramaiah, Moyu Yi, Indranil Dutta, Sudipta Chatterjee, Huabin Zhang, Zhiping Lai, Kuo&#8208;Wei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Catalytic Vehicles in the Reduction of Environmental Pollution in Nangrahar City of Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.70436/nuijb.v3i02.293</link>
      <description>Bashir ullah Safi, Fazal Rahman Mukhlis Safi, Abdul Rabi Atif, No host. 03(ICCC(special))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403228494

                Due to the increase in the number of vehicles in the cities, air pollution is one of the serious environmental hazards because it increases the greenhouse gases in the atmosphere and causes climate change. To reduce the bad effects of the gases produced by car engines, the gases are filtered with the help of a catalytic in the silencer of the car (carbon monoxide to carbon dioxide, nitrogen monoxide to nitrogen oxide and hydrocarbons to water vapor) before it leaves the silencer of the car. The catalytic was synthesized in 1895 from various expensive (platinum, rhodium, palladium) materials that work as a result of chemical reactions and have a high price. The purpose of this research is to inform people about the role and value of catalytic in preventing environmental pollution in the eastern zone of Afghanistan. Data was collected through online questionnaire and interviews from 102 participants. The findings of the research show that the catalytic play a vital role in the reduction of environmental pollution in Nangarhar city of Afghanistan. The study revealed that catalytic helps the cars in the prevention of air pollution. The catalytic breaks down dangerous gases into environment friendly gases before they leave the silencer of the car and so has a great role in the reduction of environmental pollution. Similarly, the catalytic is an essential part of the car that has a vital role in the health of the car i.e., the car having the catalytic will be in good condition for a longer period of time, will go with high speed and will use less fuel. Moreover, the use of catalytic is recommended in every car and other fuel consuming machines to avoid environmental pollution.</description>
      <author>Bashir ullah Safi, Fazal Rahman Mukhlis Safi, Abdul Rabi Atif</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.70436/nuijb.v3i02.293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Interactive Effects of Technological Innovation, Transportation Industry Development, and CO2 Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198672</link>
      <description>Kaige An, Li Wang, Zhenning Wang, Zisen He, Yao Zhong, Jia Shen, Xiaohong Ren, Sustainability. 16(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403216540

                This paper aims to clarify the intricate relationships between technological innovation, transportation industry development, and CO2 emissions to facilitate a positive synergy among technology, the economy, and climate, advancing the fulfillment of the &#8216;double carbon&#8217; goal. Utilizing panel data from 30 provinces in China from 2005 to 2020, we employ the panel vector autoregressive model using a generalized method of moments to empirically examine the dynamic interactive effects between these participants. The findings reveal that the transportation industry significantly promoted the inhibitory impact of technological innovation on CO2 emissions. However, such reductions cannot counterbalance the rise in emissions from the transportation industry. Moreover, its effects varied significantly across regions. Specifically, transportation industry development within eastern China contributed to a shift in the local carbon emission effects from positive to negative under the positive influence of technological innovation. In the northeast, the transportation industry enhanced the inhibitory effect of technological innovation on CO2 emissions. In contrast, across the western region, industrial development in transportation intensified the role of technological innovation in promoting CO2 emissions. Furthermore, this work found that CO2 emissions notably diminished the CO2 reduction performance of technological innovation in the eastern part and enhanced this performance in the northeastern region. These findings further revealed the complex interplay between technological innovation, the transportation industry, and CO2 emissions. They offer insights for policymakers to tailor region-specific technologies to bolster the &#8216;dual carbon&#8217; goal and sustainable transportation development strategies, thereby achieving CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Kaige An, Li Wang, Zhenning Wang, Zisen He, Yao Zhong, Jia Shen, Xiaohong Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton-Responsive Ligands Promote CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture and Accelerate Catalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/HCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; Interconversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02092</link>
      <description>Jeffrey M. Barlow, Nikita Gupta, Ksenija D. Glusac, David M. Tiede, David M. Kaphan, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403214359

                The synthesis and investigation of [Rh(DHMPE)2][BF4] (1) are reported. 1 features proton-responsive 1,2-bis[(dihydroxymethyl)phosphino]ethane (DHMPE) ligands, which readily capture CO2 from atmospheric sources upon deprotonation. The protonation state of the DHMPE ligand was observed to have a significant impact on the catalytic reactivity of 1 with CO2. Deprotonation and CO2 binding to 1 result in a &#8764;10-fold rate enhancement in catalytic degenerate CO2 reduction with formate, monitored by 12C/13C isotope exchange between H12CO2&#8211; and 13CO2. Studies performed using a similar complex lacking the hydroxyl ligand functionality ([Rh(DEPE)2][BF4] where DEPE = 1,2-bis(diethylphosphino)ethane) do not show the same rate enhancements when base is added. Based upon the cation-dependent activity of the catalyst, Eyring analysis, and cation sequestration experiments, CO2 binding to 1 is proposed to facilitate preorganization of formate/CO2 in the transition state via ligand-based encapsulation of Na+ or K+ cations to lower the activation energy and increase the observed catalytic rate. Incorporation of proton-responsive DHMPE ligands provides a unique approach to accelerate the kinetics of catalytic CO2 reduction to formate.</description>
      <author>Jeffrey M. Barlow, Nikita Gupta, Ksenija D. Glusac, David M. Tiede, David M. Kaphan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering interfacial molecular interactions on Ag Hollow fibre gas diffusion electrodes for high efficiency in CO2 conversion to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403251</link>
      <description>Yizhu Kuang, Guoliang Chen, Dimuthu Herath Mudiyanselage, Hesamoddin Rabiee, Beibei Ma, Fatereh Dorosti, Ashok Kumar Nanjundan, Zhonghua Zhu, Hao Wang, Lei Ge, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403257796

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) occurs at the nanoscale interface of the electrode&#8208;electrolyte. Therefore, tailoring the interfacial properties in the interface microenvironment provides a powerful strategy to optimise the activity and selectivity of electrocatalysts towards the desired products. Here, the microenvironment at the electrode&#8208;electrolyte interface of the flow&#8208;through Ag&#8208;based hollow fibre gas diffusion electrode (Ag HFGDE) is modulated by introducing surfactant cetyltrimethylammonium bromide (CTAB) as the electrolyte additive. The porous hollow fibre configuration and gas penetration mode facilitate the CO2 mass transfer and the formation of the triple&#8208;phase interface. Through the ordered arrangement of hydrophobic long&#8208;alkyl chains, CTAB molecules at the electrode/electrolyte interface promoted CO2 penetration to active sites and repelled water to reduce the activity of competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). By applying CTAB&#8208;containing catholyte, Ag HFGDE achieved a high CO Faradaic efficiency (FE) of over 95 % in a wide potential range and double the partial current density of CO. The enhancement of CO selectivity and suppression of hydrogen was attributed to the improvement of charge transfer and the CO2/H2O ratio enhancement. These findings highlight the importance of adjusting the local microenvironment to enhance the reaction kinetics and product selectivity in the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Yizhu Kuang, Guoliang Chen, Dimuthu Herath Mudiyanselage, Hesamoddin Rabiee, Beibei Ma, Fatereh Dorosti, Ashok Kumar Nanjundan, Zhonghua Zhu, Hao Wang, Lei Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Selectivity Tandem Photocatalytic Methanation of CO2 by Lacunary Polyoxometalates&#8208;Stabilized *CO Intermediate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413594</link>
      <description>Qian Zhu, Zhaohui Li, Tao Zheng, Xingxing Zheng, Si Liu, Shen Gao, Xionghui Fu, Xiaofang Su, Yi Zhu, Yuanming Zhang, Yongge Wei, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403359942

                Stabilizing specific intermediates to produce CH4 remains a main challenge in solar&#8208;driven CO2 reduction. Herein, g&#8208;C3N4 is modified with saturated and lacunary phosphotungstates (PWx, x = 12, 11, 9) to tailor the CO2 reduction pathway to yield CH4 in high selectivity. Increased lacuna of phosphotungstates leads to higher CH4 yield and selectivity, with a superior CH4 selectivity of 80% and 40.8 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8208;1&#183;h&#8208;1 evolution rate for PW9/g&#8208;C3N4. Conversely, g&#8208;C3N4 and PWx alone show negligible CH4 production. The conversion of CO2 to CH4 follows a tandem catalytic process. CO2 is initially activated on g&#8208;C3N4 to form *CO intermediates, meanwhile photogenerated electrons derived from g&#8208;C3N4 transfer to PWx. Then the reduced PWx captures *CO, which is subsquently hydrogenated to CH4. With the injection of two photogenerated electrons, PW9 is capable of adsorbing and activating *CO. However, the reduced PW12 and PW11 are incapable of adsorbing *CO due to the small energy of occupied molecular orbitals, which is the reason for the poorer activity of PWx/g&#8208;C3N4 (x = 12, 11) compared with that of PW9/g&#8208;C3N4. This work provides new insights to regulate highly selective CO2 photoreduction to CH4 by utilizing lacuna of polyoxometalates to enhance the interaction of metals in polyoxometalates with key intermediates.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhu, Zhaohui Li, Tao Zheng, Xingxing Zheng, Si Liu, Shen Gao, Xionghui Fu, Xiaofang Su, Yi Zhu, Yuanming Zhang, Yongge Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LCCO2 Assessment and Fertilizer Production from Absorbed-CO2 Solid Matter in a Small-Scale DACCU Plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17195011</link>
      <description>Tianjiao Cheng, takeji hirota, Hiroshi Onoda, Andante Hadi Pandyaswargo, Energies. 17(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403250453

                This study investigates a novel method of utilizing Direct Air Capture (DAC) technology for fertilizer production. Unlike traditional Direct Air Carbon Capture and Utilization (DACCU) technologies, Direct Air Carbon Capture for Fertilizers (FDAC) has the potential to produce fertilizers directly. This study aims to assess the feasibility of FDAC-based fertilizer production by examining the current state of traditional DAC technologies, evaluating the CO2 fixation potential of FDAC, and analyzing the decarbonization effect of producing fertilizers using FDAC. Our evaluation results indicate that CO2 emissions from producing 1 ton of conventional chemical fertilizer, FDAC fertilizer (current status), FDAC fertilizer with ingredient adjustment (sodium hydroxide), and FDAC fertilizer with ingredient adjustment (magnesium hydroxide) are 1.69, 1.12, 1.04, and 1.06 tons of CO2, respectively. The FDAC fertilizer (current status) emits 0.57 tons of CO2 per ton less than commercial fertilizers. FDAC fertilizers also have the potential to reduce CO2 emissions further when the fertilizer composition is adjusted, offering a promising solution for lowering the environmental impact of fertilizer production. Significant CO2 reduction can be expected by replacing conventional low-intensity chemical fertilizers with FDAC-produced fertilizers.</description>
      <author>Tianjiao Cheng, takeji hirota, Hiroshi Onoda, Andante Hadi Pandyaswargo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17195011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permeability evolution of sandstone caprock transverse fractures during intermittent CO2 injection in coal-bearing strata</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231372</link>
      <description>Zhaolong Ge, Qisi Huai, Zhe Zhou, Jingwei Zheng, Qinglin Deng, Yunzhong Jia, Chunxiang Liu, Physics of Fluids. 36(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403217154

                The caprock of coal-bearing strata plays a critical role in CO2 geological storage, with the presence of fractures posing a heightened risk of CO2 leakage. The cyclic effects of CO2 injection and in situ stress influence the permeability of caprock fractures. However, the combined impact of CO2 and in situ stress on fracture permeability remains uncertain. This study conducted cyclic seepage experiments under varying amplitude stresses on fractured sandstone samples soaked in ScCO2 for different times (0, 15, 30, and 60 days). The microstructural characteristics of the fractured sandstone surfaces were analyzed using scanning electron microscopy and x-ray diffraction. The experimental results indicated that soaking in ScCO2 reduces sandstone fracture permeability, but the extent of this reduction is nonlinearly related to the soaking time. During the stress cycling process, due to the effect of plastic deformation, the permeability of sandstone fractures decreases with increasing cyclic amplitude and remains relatively constant with decreasing cyclic amplitude. At the same cyclic amplitude, the permeability of sandstone fractures initially increases and then decreases with prolonged soaking time. The impact of ScCO2 and stress cycling on the permeability of sandstone fractures is the result of a series of combined chemical&#8211;mechanical effects. The combined effects of chemical dissolution and mechanical degradation significantly influence the permeability of sandstone fractures, and this impact is notably time-dependent. During short-term soaking, geochemically induced changes in the surface structure of fractures cause fluctuations in permeability, while in long-term soaking, the combined chemical&#8211;mechanical effects promote a reduction in fracture permeability.</description>
      <author>Zhaolong Ge, Qisi Huai, Zhe Zhou, Jingwei Zheng, Qinglin Deng, Yunzhong Jia, Chunxiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoexcitation and One-Electron Reduction Processes of a CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoreduction Dyad Catalyst Having a Zinc(II) Porphyrin Photosensitizer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02271</link>
      <description>Toshio Honda, Takumi Ehara, Ren Sato, Tomohiro Ogawa, Yusuke Kuramochi, Akiharu Satake, Kiyoshi Miyata, Ken Onda, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403257236

                We have explored the photophysical properties and one-electron reduction process in the dyad photocatalyst for CO2 photoreduction, ZnP-phen=Re, in which the catalyst of fac-[Re(1,10-phenanthoroline)(CO)3Br] is directly connected with the photosensitizer of zinc(II) porphyrin (ZnP), using time-resolved infrared spectroscopy, transient absorption spectroscopy, and quantum chemical calculations. We revealed the following photophysical properties: (1) the intersystem crossing occurs with a time constant of &#8764;20 ps, which is much faster than that of a ZnP single unit, and (2) the charge density in the excited singlet and triplet states is mainly localized on ZnP, which means that the excited state is assignable to the &#960;&#8211;&#960;* transition in ZnP. The one-electron reduction by 1,3-dimethyl-2-phenyl-2,3-dihydro-1H-benzo[d]imidazole occurs via the triplet excited state with the time constant of &#8764;100 ns and directly from the ground state with the time constant of &#8764;3 &#956;s. The charge in the one-electron reduction species spans ZnP and the phenanthroline ligand, and the dihedral angle between ZnP and the phenanthroline ligand is rotated by &#8764;24&#176; with respect to that in the ground state, which presumably offers an advantage for proceeding to the next CO2 reduction process. These insights could guide the new design of dyad photocatalysts with porphyrin photosensitizers.</description>
      <author>Toshio Honda, Takumi Ehara, Ren Sato, Tomohiro Ogawa, Yusuke Kuramochi, Akiharu Satake, Kiyoshi Miyata, Ken Onda</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Synergistic Effect of the Carbon Emission Trading Scheme on Pollution and Carbon Reduction in China&#8217;s Power Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198681</link>
      <description>Xiling Zhang, Xiaoqian Liu, Zeyu Zhang, Ruiyi Tang, Ting Zhang, Junqiang Yao, Sustainability. 16(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403217171

                The synergistic effect of pollution and carbon reduction can alleviate the dual pressure of improving environmental quality and reducing greenhouse gas emissions in China. The carbon emission trading scheme (CETS) is a crucial market-based tool for carbon emission reduction, and understanding its synergistic impact on air pollution control is essential. Based on data from 30 provincial panels in China spanning from 2007 to 2021, we employ the difference-in-differences (DID) method to analyze the synergistic effects of the carbon emission trading plan in the power industry and its influence mechanisms are examined. We observe that the CETS significantly enhances both pollution and carbon reduction in China&#8217;s power sector, particularly demonstrating effective synergy in reducing CO2, SO2, and PM2.5 emissions. Furthermore, mechanism analysis reveals that the CETS achieves joint emission reductions by lowering energy consumption, influencing the power industry&#8217;s generation structure, promoting technological innovation among enterprises, and thereby realizing synergistic pollution and carbon reduction effects in China&#8217;s power sector. Heterogeneity analysis shows that regions with limited power facility, low electricity generation, and small economic scale exhibit the most pronounced synergistic benefits from pollution and carbon reduction efforts.</description>
      <author>Xiling Zhang, Xiaoqian Liu, Zeyu Zhang, Ruiyi Tang, Ting Zhang, Junqiang Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historical Trends and Controlling Factors of Isoprene Emissions in CMIP6 Earth System Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2313</link>
      <description>Thi Nhu Ngoc, Kengo Sudo, Akihiko Ito, L. K. Emmons, Vaishali Na&#239;k, Kostas Tsigaridis, &#216;yvind Seland, Gerd Folberth, Douglas I. Kelley, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403250384

                Abstract. Terrestrial isoprene, a biogenic volatile organic compound emitted by many plants, influences atmospheric chemistry and the Earth&#8217;s radiative balance. Elucidating its historical changes is therefore important for predicting climate change and air quality. Isoprene emissions can respond to climate (e.g., temperature, shortwave radiation, precipitation), land use and land cover change (LULCC), and atmospheric CO2 concentrations. However, historical trends of isoprene emissions and the relative influences of the respective drivers of those trends remain highly uncertain. This study addresses uncertainty in historical isoprene emission trends and their influential factors, particularly the roles of climate, LULCC, and atmospheric CO2 (via fertilization and inhibition effects). The findings are expected to reconcile discrepancies among different modelling approaches and to improve predictions of isoprene emissions and their climate change effects. To investigate isoprene emission trends, controlling factors, and discrepancies among models, we analyzed long-term (1850&#8211;2014) global isoprene emissions from online simulations of CMIP6 Earth System Models and offline simulations using the VISIT dynamic vegetation model driven by climate reanalysis data. Mean annual global present-day isoprene emissions agree well among models (434&#8211;510 TgC yr&#8315;&#185;) with a 5 % inter-model spread (24 TgC yr&#8315;&#185;), but regional emissions differ greatly (9&#8211;212 % spread). All models show an increasing trend in global isoprene emissions in recent decades (1980&#8211;2014), but their magnitudes vary (+1.27 &#177; 0.49 TgC yr&#8315;&#178;, 0.28 &#177; 0.11 % yr&#8315;&#185;). Long-term trends of 1850&#8211;2014 show high uncertainty among models (&#8211;0.92 to +0.31 TgC yr&#8315;&#178;). Results of emulated sensitivity experiments indicate meteorological variations as the main factor of year-to-year fluctuations, but the main drivers of long-term isoprene emission trends differ among models. Models without CO2 effects implicate climate change as the driver, but other models with CO2 effects (fertilization only/and inhibition) indicate CO2 and LULCC as the primary drivers. The discrepancies arise from how models account for CO2 and LULCC alongside climate effects on isoprene emissions. Aside from LULCC-induced reductions, differences in CO2 inhibition representation (strength and presence or absence of thresholds) were able to mitigate or reverse increasing trends because of rising temperatures or in combination with CO2 fertilization. Net CO2 effects on global isoprene emissions show the highest inter-model variation (&#963; = 0.43 TgC yr&#8315;&#178;), followed by LULCC effects (&#963; = 0.17 TgC yr&#8315;&#178;), with climate change effects exhibiting more or less variation (&#963; = 0.06 TgC yr&#8315;&#178;). The critical drivers of isoprene emission trends depend on a model&#8217;s emission scheme complexity. This dependence emphasizes the need for models with accurate representation of CO2 and LULCC effects alongside climate change influences for robust long-term predictions. Important uncertainties remain in understanding the interplay between CO2, LULCC, and climate effects on isoprene emissions, mainly for CO2. More long-term observations of isoprene emissions across various biomes are necessary, along with improved models with varied CO2 responses. Moreover, instead of reliance on the current models, additional emission schemes can better capture isoprene emissions complexities and their effects on climate.</description>
      <author>Thi Nhu Ngoc, Kengo Sudo, Akihiko Ito, L. K. Emmons, Vaishali Na&#239;k, Kostas Tsigaridis, &#216;yvind Seland, Gerd Folberth, Douglas I. Kelley</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Straightforward Model for Quantifying Local pH Gradients Governing the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09521</link>
      <description>Samuel S. Veroneau, Alaina C. Hartnett, Jaeyune Ryu, Hyukhun Hong, Cyrille Costentin, Daniel G. Nocera, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403326469

                The production and consumption of protons by an electrocatalyst will, under certain conditions, generate localized microenvironments with properties distinct from those of the bulk solution. These local properties are particularly impactful for reactions involving proton-coupled electron transfer, where the generation of locally basic or acidic environments may significantly influence the energy efficiency and reaction selectivity of the electrocatalyst. Whereas local pH environments have been observed and characterized in reductive half-reactions, including the CO2 reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions, the incompatibility of conventional techniques and materials has limited studies in oxidative half-reactions, including the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which provides the reducing equivalents for solar-to-fuels electrolysis. With the straightforward parameters bulk pH, buffer composition and pKa, and mass transport, we develop a model for describing local pH as a function of current density regardless of the microscopic details of the mechanism. Using an acid-stable PbOx OER catalyst, we observe the formation and dissipation of pH gradients during the OER and validate the model with voltammetric and potentiometric studies. The model predicts how local acidic environments can develop over a narrow OER current density window, thus providing further motivation for the development of OER catalysts that are stable to acid, even when operating in basic aqueous conditions. More generally, the model is not restricted to the OER and is useful for determining the onset of local pH gradients for other electrocatalytic reactions that involve the consumption or generation of protons in energy conversion reactions.</description>
      <author>Samuel S. Veroneau, Alaina C. Hartnett, Jaeyune Ryu, Hyukhun Hong, Cyrille Costentin, Daniel G. Nocera</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09521</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibration reduction of an electric vehicle heat exchanger by controlling the polarization of its ferroelectric ceramics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3397/in_2024_3673</link>
      <description>L. Maurin, Thomas Durand-Texte, S&#233;bastien Goud&#233;, Charlie Bricault, Adrien Pelat, Fran&#231;ois Gautier, NOISE-CON proceedings. 270(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403266565

                The growing requirements in terms of CO2 emissions reduction in transports renders necessary the development of new electric traction technologies. This results in new technical constraints for equipment manufacturers, forcing them to reduce the acoustic emissivity of their new products inside and outside vehicles. Heat exchangers for electric cars are part of this new product category. High voltage supplied by the battery of electrical vehicles requires introduction of a new energy conversion process and technology. To this end, components based on ceramics containing barium titanate (BaTiO3) with high electrocaloric coupling properties are selected to provide the heating function. Baryum titanate is ferroelectric. This category of materials is subjected to piezoelectric and electrostrictive effects. The vibrations induced in the components (rods) containing the BaTiO3 ceramics are transmitted through the system, and cause undesired acoustic radiation. This coupling is a suffered effect and is not taken into account in the integration process during the rods manufacturing. In this study, an experimental characterization is proposed to identify the involved electromechanical coupling coefficients. Numerical simulations of the vibrations induced by BaTiO3 are carried out and used to study the possibility of attenuating them by controlling the polarisation of the ceramics or by geometric modifications.</description>
      <author>L. Maurin, Thomas Durand-Texte, S&#233;bastien Goud&#233;, Charlie Bricault, Adrien Pelat, Fran&#231;ois Gautier</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3397/in_2024_3673</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data mining and machine learning : a study of the CO2 emission trends in South Africa</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51415/10321/5580</link>
      <description>Ghulam Masudh Mohamed, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403247783

                This study addresses the pressing global issue of elevated carbon dioxide emissions (CO2E), with a particular focus on South Africa (SA), which ranks amongst the world's top emitters and largest in Africa. By introducing a novel integration of Change-point Analysis (CPA) and Machine Learning (ML) techniques, this research addresses significant gaps in CO2E trend analysis. Unlike previous studies, this research applies CPA methodologies within the distinct context of SA, employing algorithms like cumulative sum (CUSUM) and Bootstrap analysis to pinpoint crucial change-points in CO2E data specific to the country. The Bootstrap analysis determines the confidence levels associated with each detected change. Additionally, this study sought to validate historical trends and predict future patterns using ML models, with a specific focus on employing the AdaBoost ensemble learning technique. Drawing on insights from a Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and MetaAnalyses (PRISMA)-based systematic review, the research selects input variables based on the factors identified as significant contributors to CO2E, ensuring the models capture the relevant variables effectively. The results of the systematic review highlight energy production and economic growth as key drivers of CO2E, thus validating their selection as input data for constructing the CPA and ML models. To conduct this study, secondary data was obtained from the World Bank's Open Data initiative data repository, a common source for environmental research. This selection was justified by a literature review, which highlighted the reliability and applicability of this data source. The CPA results reveal significant change-points in electricity generation, economic growth, and CO2E, with an average confidence level of 94%, indicating the accuracy of this analytical approach. Moreover, the CPA results emphasise the relationship between economic growth, electricity production, and CO2E in SA. Before forecasting future CO2E trends, the effectiveness of the AdaBoost regressor in enhancing model performance was benchmarked against traditional ML algorithms, including Linear regression, Polynomial regression, Bayesian Linear regression and K-Nearest Neighbors (KNN) regression, to determine the most effective technique for forecasting CO2E. The researcher evaluated model performance using key regression ML performance metrics, including Root Mean Squared Error (RMSE), Mean Absolute Error (MAE), coefficient of determination (R2) score, and an additional accuracy score introduced by the researcher. Notably, the AdaBoost models demonstrated superior performance, with an average RMSE score of 10,143.17 kilotons (kt), MAE score of 9,642.64 kt, R2 of 0.90, and accuracy of 96.74%. The study also revealed that, on average, models that were trained using the AdaBoost algorithm surpassed traditional ML models, in terms of performance. They achieved a reduction in RMSE score by 6,417.29 kt, a decrease in MAE score by 4,358.09 kt, an increase in R2 score by 0.07 and enhanced accuracy by 0.60%. Additionally, a comparative analysis of the repeated holdout methods and cross-validation techniques was conducted, with results revealing that repeated holdout had a more significant impact on model performance. After excluding outliers, the average improvement in crossvalidation results, due to the repeated holdout method, was a decrease of 783.32 kt for RMSE, a reduction of 1,289.39 kt for MAE, and an increase of 0.88% for accuracy. The extent to which the repeated holdout method improved the performance of ML models that were integrated with cross-validation techniques, was correlated with the initial model performance. For ML models with RMSE and MAE scores equal to or exceeding 15,000 kt, the findings indicate that the repeated holdout methods studied should enhance performance by at least 2,000 kt. Similarly, an improvement of nearly 3% or higher in accuracy was noted, when the crossvalidation value for this metric was 94% or lower. The AdaBoost model, integrated with repeated holdout, was selected as the optimal model, as evidenced by the results, for forecasting CO2E in SA from 2021 to 2027. The forecasted CO2E trends validate that energy production and economic growth are indeed the primary drivers of CO2E in SA, as previously highlighted by the CPA model. This underscores the importance of addressing these factors to effectively mitigate carbon emissions in the country. Moreover, the forecasted results indicate that SA is unlikely to meet the global temperature limit of 1.5 degrees Celsius by 2030, given the trajectory showing a shortfall in achieving the target level of 334 million tonnes (Mt) of CO2E, agreed upon in the Paris Agreement. However, the country did meet its CO2E commitments outlined in the 2030 National Development Plan, showing some progress towards environmental sustainability. Nonetheless, the failure to meet these targets at their lower ranges suggests the need for further efforts to reduce carbon emissions, which is crucial for aligning with the Paris Agreement objectives and achieving a zero net emission rate by 2050. This highlights the importance of ongoing initiatives to enhance environmental policies and practices in SA. Future research should focus on integrating load-shedding dynamics into the analysis to examine and confirm its effects on energy production, economic growth, and CO2E in SA. Additionally, future research should focus on forecasting future change-points for the socio-economic indicators or variables utilised in this study. This can help policymakers anticipate fluctuations and devise proactive strategies, to address environmental and economic challenges effectively. It is also recommended that future research consider the output of renewable energy production, when analysing CO2E trends.</description>
      <author>Ghulam Masudh Mohamed</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51415/10321/5580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of future climate and land use changes on runoff in the Min-Tuo River Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2166/wcc.2024.384</link>
      <description>Nan Jiang, Quan Ni, Yu Deng, Mingyan Wu, Ziying Yue, Mengyu Zhu, Huaizhun Ren, Yuxuan Wang, Journal of Water and Climate Change. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403296968

                ABSTRACT In the face of escalating global warming and intensified human activities, it is crucial to quantitatively assess the combined impacts of future climate change (CC) and land use change (LUCC) on runoff. This study employed simulation results of future CC and LUCC in the Min-Tuo River Basin, utilizing the CMIP6 and cellular automata (CA)-Markov models in conjunction with the SWAT model to project runoff changes under various scenarios. The findings indicate an anticipated increase in both precipitation and average temperature in the future. Projected LUCC involves a reduction in arable land and grassland, alongside expansion of other land cover types. Changes in basin runoff are predominantly influenced by precipitation, with a higher likelihood of extreme events as CO2 emissions increase. Across four emission scenarios, the impact of future CC on basin runoff varies from &#8722;5.21 to +6.09%, while future LUCC's contribution ranges from +0.05 to +0.07%. When both factors are considered, the overall trend indicates a decrease in future runoff changes, ranging from &#8722;0.27 to +0.17%. These findings underscore the greater influence of CC on runoff compared with LUCC, thereby providing a scientific foundation for ecological conservation and water resources management in the basin.</description>
      <author>Nan Jiang, Quan Ni, Yu Deng, Mingyan Wu, Ziying Yue, Mengyu Zhu, Huaizhun Ren, Yuxuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2166/wcc.2024.384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning syngas composition using laser surface modified silver electrode for CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2351/7.0001542</link>
      <description>Austin McKee, Wuji Huang, Ninggang Shen, Syed Mubeen, Hongtao Ding, Journal of Laser Applications. 36(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403218032

                Electrochemical reduction of CO2 and H2O to synthesize gas (H2 and CO mixture) is of significant interest due to established industrial pathways to tune the H2 to CO composition to generate an array of valuable products including methanol, synthetic fuel, synthetic natural gas, and hydrogen. However, controlled H2:CO ratios are challenging on CO-active electrocatalysts like silver. We demonstrate that applying laser engineering to adjust the surface wetting state of a silver electrocatalyst with water contact angles &#952;w ranging from 47&#176; and 135&#176;, H2:CO ratios can be tuned from 1 to 4 at modest potentials (&#8722;0.7 V versus RHE, RHE&#8212;reversible hydrogen electrode) with almost total unity Faradaic efficiency. Both hydrophilic (&#952;w = 47&#176;) and more hydrophobic (&#952;w = 135&#176;) samples showed an increasing H2:CO trend with rising potentials (0.7&#8211;1.2 V versus RHE) due to mass transport. Conversely, silver electrocatalyst with &#952;w = 110&#176; exhibited a constant H2:CO ratio of 4. This indicates catalyst wettability potentially affects *H and *HOCO intermediates&#8217; adsorption, impacting H2:CO ratios. Our results show the feasibility of syngas composition control on silver catalysts via surface wettability, providing a simpler alternative to complex multicomponent electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Austin McKee, Wuji Huang, Ninggang Shen, Syed Mubeen, Hongtao Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2351/7.0001542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate impact of alternative organic fertilizers using life cycle assessment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad8589</link>
      <description>Xiaoyi Meng, Marie Trydeman Knudsen, S&#248;ren O. Petersen, Henrik Bjarne M&#248;ller, Fatemeh Hashemi, Environmental Research Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403288892

                Abstract Anaerobic digestion is a common method for managing liquid manure and other biomasses, generating biogas as a renewable energy source. The resulting digestate can be processed into organic fertilizers to enhance nutrient recycling, but its environmental impact warrants investigation. In this study, a life cycle assessment (LCA) was conducted to examine the impact of fertilizers derived from cattle slurry and grass-clover co-digestion on global warming (measured in CO2 equivalent) compared to untreated cattle slurry. The different treatments analyzed include untreated cattle slurry, digestate, liquid fractions from digestate separation, and an enriched liquid nitrogen-sulfur product derived from post-processing of biogas and drying the solid fraction. The functional units of this study were 100 kg of total nitrogen in the final organic fertilizer (FU1) with the cradle-to-processing gate boundary and the harvesting 1 ton of spring barley dry matter (FU2) with the cradle-to-field application boundary. The carbon footprint ranged from 24 to 49% of the baseline scenario for FU1, and from -6 to 177% of the baseline scenario for FU2. The main contributors to the carbon footprint of fertilizers included greenhouse gas emissions from storage and field application. However, biogas production from anaerobic digestion, together with the concurrent mitigation of CH4 emissions during storage, contributed most to a reduction in the overall global warming potential associated with anaerobic digestate and its liquid fraction. This study showed large climate prospects in replacing untreated slurry as organic fertilizer with alternatives resulting from its anaerobic digestion and post-treatment.</description>
      <author>Xiaoyi Meng, Marie Trydeman Knudsen, S&#248;ren O. Petersen, Henrik Bjarne M&#248;ller, Fatemeh Hashemi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad8589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis, Characterization, and Shaping of UiO-67 Metal-Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33540/2439</link>
      <description>Christia Jabbour, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403222099

                This PhD thesis investigates the flexibility of metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) materials, particularly focusing on their adaptable synthesis and shaping techniques. MOFs, known for their dynamic framework structures and flexible linkers, allow researchers to design new and existing porous materials for specific applications, such as catalysis and environmental protection. The research covers a range of topics, including synthesis, characterization, shaping, and catalytic testing, with particular emphasis on the flexible properties of MOFs. Chapter 2 focuses on the application of MOFs in active coatings on surfaces and functionalized fabrics to deactivate biological and chemical toxins, a crucial topic in light of the global health crisis induced by the SARS-CoV-2 outbreak. The chapter discusses advancements in metal- and metal-oxide-based catalysts for inactivating chemical and biological threats. It also explores MOF applications in textiles, which are designed to capture and degrade chemical warfare agents. Despite progress, challenges remain, particularly in translating laboratory results to real-world conditions, such as creating multifunctional protective suits that are durable and capable of detoxifying toxins while remaining comfortable. The chapter highlights the promise of MOFs in addressing these challenges, but also the need for improved manipulation onto fibers and long-term stability. Chapters 3, 4, and 5 delve into the catalytic potential of MOFs and their manipulation for specific applications. In Chapter 3, the focus is on the catalytic activity of platinum nanoparticles (Pt-NPs) embedded within the UiO-67 MOF structure, specifically investigating their role in the CO2 hydrogenation reaction. The study examines the effects of reduction and pyrolysis treatments on Pt-NPs, finding that certain treatment processes improve the selectivity for methanol formation. This chapter emphasizes the importance of understanding the catalytic properties of MOFs and their potential for CO2 conversion. Chapter 4 investigates surface-mounted MOFs (SURMOFs), which offer promising in situ measurement capabilities. The chapter discusses the synthesis and characterization of three different SURMOF materials: UU-1, ZIF-8, and UiO-67. It explores how different anchor molecules, substrates, and synthetic conditions affect the growth and morphology of these SURMOFs. The chapter also addresses the limitations of current analytical techniques and proposes transmission-based characterization on transparent substrates. The findings highlight the importance of spectroscopic characterization in understanding the behavior of SURMOFs during various processes, offering insights for their application in fields like sensing, separation, and catalysis. Finally, Chapter 5 addresses the challenge of shaping MOFs via mechanical pressure by presenting a synthesis procedure that forms MOF beads through entanglement with chitosan (CS). This method eliminates the need for mechanical pressure, which can be detrimental to MOF structures. The study compares two synthesis procedures&#8212;one-pot synthesis (OPS) and post-synthetic functionalization (PSF)&#8212;and finds that OPS leads to better incorporation of MOFs into CS beads, resulting in higher thermal stability. Overall, this thesis demonstrates the versatility of MOFs in catalysis, environmental protection, and material science, while also addressing the challenges associated with shaping and long-term stability.</description>
      <author>Christia Jabbour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33540/2439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04595</link>
      <description>Hongwei Wu, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403213946

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. Energy &amp; FuelsASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse EditorialOctober 8, 20242024 Energy and Fuels Rising StarsClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Hongwei WuHongwei WuDiscipline of Chemical Engineering, Western Australian School of Mines: Minerals, Energy and Chemical Engineering, Curtin University, Kent Street, Bentley, Western Australia 6102, AustraliaMore by Hongwei Wuhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-2816-749XOpen PDFEnergy &amp; FuelsCite this: Energy Fuels 2024, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04595https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04595Published October 8, 2024 Publication History Received 20 September 2024Published online 8 October 2024editorial&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.BatteriesEnergyFossil fuelsFuelsRedox reactionsSince 2021, Energy &amp; Fuels has established annual recognition of Energy and Fuels Rising Stars to honor some early- and midcareer researchers (EMCRs) who have made significant contributions to discovering new knowledge and/or advancing technological development in their respective fields of energy research. The candidates of rising stars were nominated by open call then finalized by our editorial office. At the time of nomination, a rising star candidate must be 12 years or less within the award of PhD degree and in independent research career. Energy &amp; Fuels also publishes annually a Special Issue (SI) to highlight the group of rising stars in each year. (1&#8722;3)It is our great pleasure to announce the following cohort of 2024 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars (alphabetically ordered according to surname):Sili Deng, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, United StatesMichiel Dusselier, KU Leuven, BelgiumMelis Duyar, University of Surrey, United KingdomChiara Ferrara, Universit&#224; degli Studi di Milano-Bicocca, ItalyMatteo Gazzani, Utrecht University, NetherlandsLei Ge, University of Southern Queensland, AustraliaJoshua Heyne, Washington State University and Pacific Northwest National Laboratory, United StatesJungho Jae, Pusan National University, South KoreaMuhammad Shahzad Kamal, King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals, Saudi ArabiaHaegyeom Kim, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, United StatesLong Kong, Northwestern Polytechnical University, ChinaKongzhai Li, Kunming University of Science and Technology, ChinaY. Chris Li, State University of New York at Buffalo, United StatesCheng Lian, East China University of Science and Technology, ChinaXue Feng Lu, Fuzhou University, ChinaJianfeng Mao, The University of Adelaide, AustraliaPeng Tan, University of Science and Technology of China, ChinaJiayu Wan, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, ChinaJian Wang, City University of Hong Kong, ChinaLu Wang, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Shenzhen, ChinaYi Wang, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, ChinaChularat Wattanakit, Vidyasirimedhi Institute of Science and Technology, ThailandXianyong Wu, University of Puerto Rico at R&#237;o Piedras, Puerto RicoQuan Xu, China University of Petroleum-Beijing, ChinaJin Xuan, University of Surrey, United KingdomChang Geun Yoo, State University of New York, United StatesGuanghui Zhang, Dalian University of Technology, ChinaKai Zhang, Nankai University, ChinaKai Zhu, Harbin Engineering University, ChinaEnergy&amp; Fuels is also pleased to present this SI that highlights the invited research articles contributed by our 2024 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars. This SI includes 8 (mini)review papers and 21 original research articles. As shown in Table 1, these papers cover a wide range of research topics within the scope of Energy &amp; Fuels and are expected to generate significant impacts in the field for many years to come. We trust that our readers will find these articles stimulating and interesting.Table 1. Full List of Papers in the SI Contributed by 2024 Energy and Fuels Rising Starsrising startitle (article type)DOIDeng, SiliFast QoI-Oriented Bayesian Experimental Design with Unified Neural Response Surfaces for Kinetic Uncertainty Reduction (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02299Dusselier, MichielThe One Step Methanol-Mediated CO2 Conversion to Gasoline: A Critical Review (Review)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03013Duyar, MelisThe Effect of Na/Ca Adsorbent on NiRu-DFM Performance for Integrated CO2 Capture and Hydrogenation (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02601Ferrara, ChiaraLow Temperature Carbothermic Reduction for Recycling of LiCoO2 and Recovery of Critical Raw Materials (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02714Gazzani, MatteoHow Would Ideal Sorbents Improve the Technical and Economic Performance of Adsorption-Based Direct Air Capture? (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01156Ge, LeiSteering CO Selectivity in CO2 Electroreduction over Silver Microtubular Gas-Diffusion Electrodes via Surface Reconstruction (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01240Heyne, JoshuaProbabilistic Fuel Property Prediction Methods for Design and Qualification of Aviation Fuels: A Review (Review)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02457Jae, JunghoEffect of TiO2-Supported Pt&#8211;ReOx Bimetallic Catalyst on Selective Hydrogenation of Carboxylic Acids to Alcohols by Rhenium Deposition Method (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02475Kamal, Muhammad ShahzadDeep Eutectic Solvents: Comprehensive Review and Future Directions on Synthesis and Oilfield Applications (Review)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01582Kim, HaegyeomInverse Consequences of the SnO2 Protection Layers on Pt/C Catalysts in Proton-Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02232Kong, LongDisassociating Lithium Salts in Deep Eutectic Solvents and Inhibiting Aluminum Corrosion for Low-Temperature Lithium&#8211;Metal Batteries (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02174Li, KongzhaiRed Mud as the Catalyst for Energy and Environmental Catalysis: A Review (Review)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02269Li, Y. ChrisEnhancing Local CO2 Concentration via Covalent Interaction for the Conversion of Carbonate to CO (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00335Lian, ChengUnderstanding the Mechanism of Ammonia Synthesis in Alkali Metal Hydride-Intercalated Graphene Catalysts (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01071Lu, Xue FengA Review on Highly Efficient Ru-Based Electrocatalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction (Review)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02080Mao, JianfengSize-Controllable N-Doped Porous Carbon Derived from Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Enables High-Performance Lithium-Ion/Sodium-Ion Batteries (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02267Tan, PengExtending the Cycling Life of Lithium-Ion Batteries with Silicon/Graphite Composite Anodes by Automatic External Stress Regulation (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00880Wan, JiayuPerspectives on Ultrafast, Precise Synthesis and Regeneration of Advanced Battery Materials (Review)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02209Wang, JianBenchmarking Metal Oxide Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04109Wang, LuShedding Light on Solar Olefin Synthesis: Advances and Perspectives (Review)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01608Wang, YiImportance of Physical/Chemical Interactions between Rice Husk and Polypropylene during Their Copyrolysis (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01943Wattanakit, ChularatPerspectives on Recent Advances in Hierarchical Zeolites for Bioethanol Conversion to Chemicals, Jet Fuels, and Carbon Nanotubes (Review)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02069Wu, XianyongBuilding a High-Potential Silver&#8211;Sulfur Redox Reaction Based on the Hard&#8211;Soft Acid&#8211;Base Theory (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00817Xu, QuanNitrogen-Doped Bismuth Oxide-Modified Carbon Cloth as a Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Iron&#8211;Chromium Redox Flow Batteries (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01739Xuan, JinPotentials of Progressive and Disruptive Innovation-Driven Cost Reductions of Green Hydrogen Production (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01247Yoo, Chang GeunImpacts of Hydrogen Bond Donor Structure in Phenolic Aldehyde Deep Eutectic Solvent on Pretreatment Efficiency (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02301Zhang, GuanghuiHighly Active and Stable Isolated Ir&#948;+ Sites in Iridium Phosphide for Propane Dehydrogenation (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02006Zhang, KaiHighly Reversible Zn Metal Anode Enabled by Interfacial Water Pocket (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02858Zhu, KaiTrace Amount of High Concentration Electrolyte for High-Performance Aqueous Zn Metal Anodes (Article)10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02637We extend our warmest congratulations to this group of 2024 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars!Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorHongwei Wu, Editor-in-Chief, Discipline of Chemical Engineering, Western Australian School of Mines: Minerals, Energy and Chemical Engineering, Curtin University, Kent Street, Bentley, Western Australia 6102, Australia, https://orcid.org/0000-0002-2816-749XNotesViews expressed in this editorial are those of the author and not necessarily the views of the ACS.AcknowledgmentsClick to copy section linkSection link copied!We are grateful to our Editors, Editorial Advisory Board members, past Rising Stars, 2024 Rising Star candidates, reviewers, and the editorial assistance team for the great contributions that have made this 2024 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars initiative and SI possible.ReferencesClick to copy section linkSection link copied! This article references 3 other publications. 1Wu, H. 2021 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars. Energy Fuels 2021, 35, 15247&#8211; 15248, DOI: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.1c03135 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.2Wu, H. 2022 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars. Energy Fuels 2022, 36, 12365&#8211; 12366, DOI: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.2c03140 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.3Wu, H. 2023 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars. Energy Fuels 2023, 37, 15245&#8211; 15247, DOI: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03754 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.Cited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferencesOpen PDF Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsEnergy &amp; FuelsCite this: Energy Fuels 2024, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04595Published October 8, 2024 Publication History Received 20 September 2024Published online 8 October 2024&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsArticle Views83Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesThis publication has no figures.References This article references 3 other publications. 1Wu, H. 2021 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars. Energy Fuels 2021, 35, 15247&#8211; 15248, DOI: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.1c03135 There is no corresponding record for this reference.2Wu, H. 2022 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars. Energy Fuels 2022, 36, 12365&#8211; 12366, DOI: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.2c03140 There is no corresponding record for this reference.3Wu, H. 2023 Energy and Fuels Rising Stars. Energy Fuels 2023, 37, 15245&#8211; 15247, DOI: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03754 There is no corresponding record for this reference.</description>
      <author>Hongwei Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperthermia&#8208;induced changes in blood flow dynamics and their influence on cardiac output</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1113/jp287447</link>
      <description>A. Morgan, The Journal of Physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403297931

                Our understanding of cardiovascular haemodynamics and the factors that govern it is vital for appreciating the workings of a healthy physiological system, as well as elucidating the pathophysiology behind disease and identifying potential treatment options. A recent article in The Journal of Physiology by Watanabe et al. (2024) sought to contribute to this field by exploring the impact of passive hyperthermia on human circulation and the underlying central and peripheral mechanisms. It has traditionally been believed that blood circulation is driven by the pressure created by the heart (Furst &amp; Gonz&#225;lez-Alonso, 2023). In hyperthermia, cardiac output is increased, and the traditional perspective would suggest that this is mainly due to an increased heart rate, supplemented by central mechanisms such as increased left ventricular systolic function. However, studies have shown that an increased heart rate alone is not sufficient to increase cardiac output (Joyce &amp; Wang, 2021). Also, central mechanisms exert their effects with increases in core temperature at rest, which would not explain the increase in cardiac output seen with peripheral hyperthermia that does not affect core temperature. Therefore, it appears that other factors are involved in increasing cardiac output in peripheral hyperthermia, potentially including increased blood velocity or increased systemic vascular conductance. The exact mechanisms and their relationship to central forces are not well elucidated, and this is what Watanabe et al. (2024) set out to understand. The main aim set by Watanabe et al. (2024) was to explore how single-leg, two-leg, and whole-body hyperthermia affect peripheral and systemic circulation, as well as the metabolic and cardiorespiratory responses. They also aimed to investigate the factors affecting central haemodynamic changes in hyperthermia. Their hypothesis was that passive hyperthermia increases cardiac output, not due to central mechanisms like left ventricular contractility, but rather due to peripheral haemodynamic changes. The researchers enrolled eight young healthy males, and each participant was randomly assigned four counterbalanced protocols. These were 3 h of no heating as a control, 3 h of single-leg heating, 3 h of two-leg heating and 2.5 h of whole-body heating. The latter is shorter due to participant discomfort leading to early termination. The heating was provided using a water-perfused garment, and extensive measurements were taken throughout the protocols. To evaluate leg, arm, and head haemodynamics, ultrasound was used to measure blood flow at the common femoral artery, brachial artery, and common and internal carotid arteries. To evaluate cardiac function, echocardiography was used. Participants also underwent blood sampling, as well as respiratory, metabolic, blood pressure, and heart rate measurements. In single-leg heating, the study found that blood flow only increased in the leg. The two-leg and whole-body heating protocols, however, showed increased blood flow to both legs and forearms, with whole-body heating also leading to increased extracranial blood flow. None of the heating trials showed a significant difference in anterior cerebral blood flow. This finding is particularly interesting given the progressive increase in cardiac output across protocols. These results suggest that local mechanisms controlling blood flow differ across body sites, and that increased cardiac output alone does not increase perfusion. Importantly, the authors found that blood velocity increased to a greater extent than vessel diameter size, indicating that velocity predominantly contributed to the observed increase in blood flow. Additionally, there was a progressive increase in systemic vascular conductance across all heating protocols, along with increased blood kinetic energy in both two-leg and whole-body heating. Using correlational analysis, the authors showcased that increased local temperature was associated with increased local blood flow and vascular conductance. Further analysis suggests that increased cardiac output is linked with not only the aforementioned factors but also increased blood velocity and kinetic energy in the limbs and head. This supports the study's hypothesis and highlights that peripheral mechanisms may be more important than previously thought. Evaluating cardiac function revealed some key findings. Left ventricular ejection fraction and heart rate increased in all heating sessions. However, alongside the increase in heart rate was a reduction in left ventricular filling and ejection times. Despite this, stroke volume was increased or maintained in all heating protocols. This finding is likely to be due to an increase in venous return to the heart, with an increase in left ventricular end diastolic volume and a reduction in the end systolic volume. Collectively, these results indicate that hyperthermia not only drives heart rate but crucially increases venous return to enhance cardiac output. This goes against existing literature, which suggests hyperthermia reduces preload (Wilson &amp; Crandall, 2011), possibly due to factors such as the method of assessing preload, environmental conditions, and participant characteristics. Further research would help to confirm this result. A unique finding was that whole-body heating increased left ventricular twist and untwisting rate, an effect not seen with leg-only heating. This suggests that systemic hyperthermia may engage more comprehensive cardiac adjustments, and that peripheral heating increases cardiac output without necessarily relying on central cardiac mechanisms. These findings come together to suggest an alternative model of circulation, contrary to the traditional cardio-centric view. The study found that respiratory and metabolic responses only changed in the whole-body heating protocol. There was an increase in oxygen uptake, carbon dioxide output, pulmonary ventilation, and end-tidal O2 pressure. In contrast, these changes were not observed in leg-only heating, yet cardiac output still increased. This differentiation suggests that metabolic and respiratory factors are not essential for increasing blood flow in peripheral hyperthermia, thereby strengthening the hypothesis of the study. However, it also shows the ongoing role of central mechanisms in certain hyperthermia conditions. This study is thoughtfully planned and provides robust data supporting the hypothesis. However, it should be noted that there are some limitations. One such limitation is the small and specific sample size of young healthy males. Although this is understandable in the context of an initial study exploring physiology in a normal state, it does reduce the generalisability of the results to other populations such as females and older groups with cardiovascular illness. Additionally, many measurements were derived using ultrasound, which tends to have a degree of inter-operator variability. It is unclear whether one or more operators were involved in conducting these measurements. However, the authors provide a thorough explanation of the ultrasound techniques used. Furthermore, the study did not directly measure right heart function or venous flow to the heart, instead inferring venous return data from their left ventricular recordings. Although this may lead to inaccuracies, similar techniques have been previously used and support this method. The authors also acknowledged that they used correlational analysis to evaluate the link between cardiac output and peripheral circulation, appropriately highlighting that this does not establish causation. The authors provide us with new insights into how human circulation is controlled, in a field where specific mechanisms behind heat-related changes are not well understood. With a deeper understanding of peripheral haemodynamics and the relationship with cardiac output, we are better positioned to conduct future research and explore treatment options for cardiovascular disease. For example, one can evaluate these findings in the context of heart failure and the potential use of lower limb heating to improve cardiac output. Although this has been previously studied (Inoue et al., 2012), there is a dearth of literature. Another interesting possibility is the use of the measurements from this study, such as blood kinetic energy, as markers of disease onset and progression, given their suggested importance. This is an important study from Watanabe et al. (2024), employing a well thought out methodology to suggest that peripheral mechanisms in passive hyperthermia are key to controlling blood circulation. They demonstrate that increases in cardiac output are linked with increases in local velocity and kinetic energy of blood flow secondary to heat, rather than central mechanisms. While there are some limitations to the research, the findings provide new insights into the study of human circulation and establish a platform for further research. This should include further physiological research in diverse populations to confirm the results, as well as clinical research to understand changes found in pathology and to identify possible treatment options. Please note: The publisher is not responsible for the content or functionality of any supporting information supplied by the authors. Any queries (other than missing content) should be directed to the corresponding author for the article. No competing interests declared. Sole author. None.</description>
      <author>A. Morgan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1113/jp287447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Items of Interest to Process R&amp;amp;D Chemists and Engineers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.oprd.4c00418</link>
      <description>James A. Schwindeman, Alex Kosanovich, Christopher B. Kelly, Timothy Kwok, Thomas James, Annabel Ansel, James M. MacDougall, Jimmy Lauberteaux, David P. Day, Sylvain Guizzetti, John Knight, Organic Process Research &amp; Development. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403244826

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. Organic Process Research &amp; DevelopmentASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse Highlights from the LiteratureOctober 9, 2024Some Items of Interest to Process R&amp;D Chemists and EngineersClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!James A. SchwindemanJames A. SchwindemanLaxai, Daufuskie Island, South Carolina 29915, United StatesMore by James A. SchwindemanAlex KosanovichAlex KosanovichDow, Texas Operations, 230 Abner Jackson Parkway, ECB/4B137, Lake Jackson, Texas 77566, United StatesMore by Alex KosanovichChristopher B. KellyChristopher B. KellyJanssen Research &amp; Development, 1400 McKean Road, Spring House, Pennsylvania 19477, United StatesMore by Christopher B. Kellyhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-5530-8606Timothy KwokTimothy KwokVertex Pharmaceuticals, 86-88 Jubilee Avenue, Milton Park, Abingdon OX14 4RW, U.K.More by Timothy Kwokhttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-0634-6654Thomas JamesThomas JamesPharmaceutical Technology and Development, AstraZeneca, Macclesfield SK10 2NA, U.K.More by Thomas Jameshttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-9728-9482Annabel Q. AnselAnnabel Q. AnselVividion Therapeutics, 5820 Nancy Ridge Drive, San Diego, California 92121, United StatesMore by Annabel Q. Anselhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-7456-5827James M. MacDougallJames M. MacDougallCambrex, 1205 11th Street, Charles City, Iowa 50616, United StatesMore by James M. MacDougallhttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-0356-6248Jimmy LauberteauxJimmy LauberteauxSanofi Winthrop Industrie, 45 chemin M&#233;teline, 04200 Sisteron, FranceMore by Jimmy LauberteauxDavid Philip DayDavid Philip DaySynthetic Medicinal Chemist, School of Life Sciences, University of Dundee, Dundee DD1 5EH, U.K.More by David Philip DaySylvain GuizzettiSylvain GuizzettiNovAlix, Building A: Chemistry, Bioparc, Bld. S&#233;bastien Brant, BP 30170, F-67405 Illkirch Cedex, FranceMore by Sylvain Guizzettihttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-4656-2431John Knight*John KnightJKonsult Ltd, Meadow View, Cross Keys, Hereford HR1 3NT, U.K.*Email: [email protected]More by John KnightOpen PDFOrganic Process Research &amp; DevelopmentCite this: Org. Process Res. Dev. 2024, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.oprd.4c00418https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.oprd.4c00418Published October 9, 2024 Publication History Received 27 September 2024Published online 9 October 2024editorialPublished 2024 by American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS PublicationsPublished 2024 by American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.AminesAromatic compoundsHydrocarbonsOrganic compoundsPharmaceuticalsElectrophilic C(sp2)&#8211;H Cyanation with Inorganic Cyanate by PIII/PV&#9552;O-Catalyzed Phase Transfer ActivationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Electrophilic cyanation is a scarcely employed methodology to introduce a nitrile functionality that mostly relies on reagents prepared by multistep synthesis or derived from hydrogen cyanide. Radosevich and Hu from MIT succeeded in using sodium cyanate as the cyanide source for electrophilic cyanation through phosphine oxide deoxygenation ( Angew. Chem., Int. Ed., DOI: 10.1002/anie.202409854). The optimized reaction conditions involve a 10 mol % loading of the phosphetane catalyst P4 (see the scheme), 1.5 equiv of diethyl methyl(bromo)malonate as the activator, and diphenylsilane as the reductant to allow catalyst turnover. Moreover, addition of a mild acid (pyridinium bromide) to prevent competition from malonate and insolubility of the cyanate source were found to be crucial to achieve high yields. Single-turnover experiments and computational studies allowed the authors to propose a mechanism involving attack of the nucleophile on N-isocyanatophosphonium followed by dehydration. Several five-membered heterocyclic cores (pyrrole, imidazole, thiophene) as well as electron-rich carbocycles react in good to high yields. Three examples of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated nitrile synthesis are also provided with modest yields.Synthesis of Alcohols: Streamlined C1 to Cn Hydroxyalkylation through Photoredox CatalysisClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Despite significant recent progress in the field, hydroxyalkylation still relies on classical organometallic addition to carbonyl compounds, complex synergistic systems, or use of tailored additives. Luisi and co-workers from the University of Bari and Politecnico di Bari recently tackled this issue by developing a photochemical protocol using unmodified &#945;-hydroxy acids as hydroxyalkyl radical sources ( Chem. Sci., DOI: 10.1039/D4SC02696A). Preliminary computational studies aided the design of the reaction, whose optimization led to the rapid identification of electron-poor alkenes as somophiles, 4CzIPN as the photocatalyst, and potassium phosphate as the base in dimethyl sulfoxide. Under the best conditions, a variety of alkenes conjugated with esters, ketones, electron-poor (hetero)aromatics, phosphate, sulfoxides, and sulfones efficiently react with secondary or tertiary hydroxyalkyl radicals. The methodology was extended to the use of glyoxylic acid for hydroxymethylation and successfully transposed to flow by shifting to potassium tert-butoxide as a homogeneous base and increasing the light intensity.Electrocatalytic Formal C(sp2)&#8211;H Alkylations via Nickel-Catalyzed Cross-Electrophile Coupling with Versatile Arylsulfonium SaltsClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Methodologies to forge C(sp2)&#8211;C(sp3) bonds have triggered major interest across the synthetic community over the last decades, with photo- and electrochemistry assets being exploited to develop milder conditions compared to cross-coupling reactions involving organometallic reactants. Ackermann and co-workers from the University of G&#246;ttingen extended the scope of the cross-coupling reaction of arylsulfonium salts through the implementation of an electrochemical nickel-catalyzed protocol for cross-electrophile coupling ( Angew. Chem., Int. Ed., DOI: 10.1002/anie.202401198). The optimized conditions rely on the use of zinc and nickel electrodes in an undivided cell with tetrabutylammonium iodide as an additive in dimethylacetamide at 60 &#176;C. A number of mono-, di-, and trisubstituted (hetero)aromatic dibenzothiophenium (DBT) salts bearing common functional groups (halogens, esters, N-phthalimide) are alkylated with primary and secondary alkyl iodides in good to high yields. Worthy of note are the facts that selective alkylation can be achieved even with a mixture of positional isomers of the sulfonium salt and that one-pot dibenzothiophenylation/cross-coupling proved viable. Experimental and computational studies support a mechanism involving oxidative addition of the DBT salt and cathodic reduction of the formed Ni complex as first steps, followed by single electron transfer (SET) and radical rebound prior to final reductive elimination from the NiIII complex.Meta-Selective Methylation of Aromatics under Superacidic ConditionsClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Developing synthetic methodologies to selectively insert a methyl group onto aromatic compounds is of great interest, especially in biological programs, where the introduction of this functionality, known as the methyl "magic effect", can boost potency. However, a current perusal of benzenoid rings in small-molecule active pharmaceutical ingredients (APIs) displays a significant heterogeneous distribution of the substitution patterns, highlighting the lack of existing selective methods to access challenging 1,3, 1,3,5, and 1,2,3,4 patterns. In this prospect, Thibaudeau, Michelet and co-workers, in collaboration with ACTIV-H, proposed an elegant meta-selective methylation of aromatic rings under superacidic conditions ( Nat. Commun., DOI: 10.1038/s41467-024-49421-8). The use of this non-nucleophilic highly acidic reaction medium is necessary to (1) activate the methylating agent, (2) generate a long-lived cyclohexadienyl cation which can then rearrange toward the more stable meta regioisomer, and (3) in most instances prevent overalkylation by shielding the methylated aromatic after protonation. The efficiency of this method was demonstrated on more than 50 examples including APIs (more than 10), hence further highlighting the tolerance of many functional groups under these strongly acidic conditions. Deuterium or 13C isotope labeling was also performed on several APIs using these conditions.Iron-Catalyzed C(sp3)&#8211;COOH Decarboxylative Oxygenation with TEMPOClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Creating C(sp3)&#8211;O bonds is a valuable transformation which is well-handled in nature using decarboxylative processes from carboxylic acids. In sharp contrast, to date only limited chemical methodologies have described such transformations using aliphatic carboxylic acids directly with a broad scope and full selectivity. Recently, a solution for the direct utilization of carboxylic acids as alkylating agents has been brought forward using photochemistry, but most of the publications still rely on expensive and rare-earth metals such as iridium or rubidium. In this work, Kirchner, Schiemann, Kielb, Bunescu, and co-workers proposed an iron-catalyzed direct decarboxylative oxygenation method starting from aliphatic carboxylic acids under irradiation with light ( Angew. Chem., Int. Ed., DOI: 10.1002/anie.202403292). Under these experimental conditions, more than 40 substrates, including 12 complex bioactive compounds, were successfully oxygenated, hence highlighting the good substrate compatibility of this method. The utility of the synthesized compounds was also demonstrated across the postsynthetic transformations of the C&#8211;O(TEMPO) bond to diverse valuable functionalities. A thorough mechanistic study revealed the triple role played by TEMPO in the reaction: (1) as the oxygenation reagent, (2) as an oxidant to turn over the iron catalyst, and (3) as an internal mild base for the carboxylic acid deprotonation.Direct Introduction of the 1-Fluorocyclopropyl Group via Stille Cross-Coupling: A Way of Getting around Per- and Polyfluoroalkyl SubstancesClick to copy section linkSection link copied!The tactical introduction of small fluorinated carbocycles proffers many opportunities for those seeking to optimize biochemical engagement and/or physicochemical properties of putative therapeutic agents. More specifically, fluorinated cyclopropanes possess all the benefits associated three-membered carbocycles (e.g., rigidification without loss of three-dimensionality) while also affording improved binding affinity via fluorine's weak non-covalent interactions and beneficial alterations to lipophilicity. Further, these compact units can often serve as bioisosteric replacements for an array of motifs (e.g., CF3-cyclopropanes serving as tert-butyl isosteres). Though well-defined approaches exist for the assembly of certain fluorinated cyclopropane classes, others suffer from limited (and in some cases impractical) methods for their construction. One such group is the 1-fluorocyclopropyl (1-FCp) motif. Common strategies for accessing 1-FCp center on building the ring from fluorinated olefins (which have a tendency to polymerize) or deoxyfluorination of cyclopropanols (wherein ring opening is common). A perhaps more readily deployable strategy, especially from the standpoint of parallel synthesis, would be a bench-stable reagent for 1-FCp cross-coupling. Recently, Leroux and co-workers, in partnership with scientists at Bayer AG, reported the development and implementation of an organostannyl-based 1-FCp reagent that allows for efficient coupling with sp2 electrophiles ( Adv. Synth. Catal., DOI: 10.1002/adsc.202400401). Ultimately, the authors identified a combination of Pd2(dba)3 and JackiePhos with CuCl and KF as additives for successful cross-coupling. Synthesis of the requisite organostannane could be accomplished by a Si-to-Sn swap from commercial (1-fluorovinyl)methyldiphenylsilane followed by iron-catalyzed cyclopropanation. Although the main focus of this report was on 1-FCp installation itself, the process was extended to more complex fluorinated cyclopropanes with stereocontrol.Vinyltriarylbismuthonium Salts: Powerful Vehicles for &#945;-Vinylation of Carbonyl CompoundsClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Among strictly carbon-based functionalities, olefins are perhaps the most versatile in terms of breadth of transforms, acting primarily as nucleophiles in polar reactions or Giese acceptors in odd-electron processes. Further, they can be exploited at all levels of development, be it as a synthetic handle for structure&#8211;activity relationship interrogation or as a key raw material in a commercial process. One of the simplest olefinic building blocks is gaseous ethylene, a C2 feedstock that is utilized in numerous industrial processes, most notably in polymerization. Though able to be used on scale, its use in research laboratories is hampered by its physical properties and tendency to polymerize. Ethylene "equivalents" are employed in its stead, but the vast majority of such species are nucleophilic in nature. Electrophilic ethylene species often have similar or worse properties compared to ethylene itself, thus making broad implementation problematic. In a recent report, Rawal and co-workers identified vinyltriphenylbismuthonium (VTB) salts as bench-stable vinyl cation equivalents for the &#945;-vinylation of carbon nucleophiles ( J. Am. Chem. Soc., DOI: 10.1021/jacs.4c05709). VTB salts can be engaged with lithium enolates to affect vinylation in good to excellent yields with high dr in systems where diastereomers are generated. The process is presumed to proceed through a pentavalent O-bismuth enolate. This hypervalent species can, in one mechanistic postulate, transfer a carbon "ligand" (in this case the vinyl group) to the &#945;-carbon with release of a trivalent bismuthane. Alternatively, an O-to-C rearrangement would yield an &#945;-keto bismuth(V) species, which upon "reductive elimination" would yield the observed vinylated product. The authors were able not only to extend this strategy to other olefins and tandem reactions (i.e., 1,4-addition followed by trapping) but also to showcase the utility of these reagents in natural product assembly. Further, the authors also devised a practical, scalable preparation of VTB salts from readily accessible organobismuth species and showed that the spent Bi(III) could be recovered and presumably recycled. The methodology was extended to more complex (non-vinyl) bismuthonium ions as well.Sulfone Electrophiles in Cross-Electrophile Coupling: Nickel-Catalyzed Difluoromethylation of Aryl BromidesClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Despite its relatively small size and its nearly complete absence in naturally occurring compounds, the influence that fluorine has had on the development of life-changing pharmaceuticals is immense. Introduction of fluorine or, more commonly, fluorinated motifs allows practitioners to surmount challenges relating to metabolism, absorption, and even binding affinity, ultimately translating to longer-lasting therapeutics with higher target fidelity. Because of this proven track record, bioisosteric replacement of certain motifs has become common to the workflow used for triaging targets and identifying metabolic hotspots. One common isosteric "swap" involves replacement of an array of chalcogen-based functionalities with the difluoromethyl (CF2H) group. This fluorinated moiety is a putative C-centered hydrogen-bond donor but generally provides a marked increase in lipophilicity. Although in the past two decades the technology for CF2H incorporation has greatly improved, gaps still remain, especially in a late-stage fashion. The most ideal methods would be those balancing scope with practicality of building blocks; that is, reagents and processes that use commodity and sustainable CF2H feedstocks are likely to have the most industry-wide uptake. Recently, the Weix group at the University of Wisconsin in collaboration with Monfette at Pfizer reported on a practical Ni-based approach for the difluoromethylation of aryl and heteroaryl bromides using difluoromethyl 2-pyridyl sulfone (DFPS) ( ACS Catal., DOI: 10.1021/acscatal.4c01999). The crux of their approach was the SET reduction of DFPS to generate a CF2H radical (whose presence was confirmed by radical cyclization experiments). This radical could then be funneled into a standard Ni cross-electrophile coupling regime. PyBCam was identified as the optimal ligand for this process, and the scope of the transformation proved to be quite wide. Further, the authors were able to define a scalable route to DFPS that is free of ozone-depleting substances (ODSs) using 2-chloro-2,2-difluoroacetophenone to deliver the CF2H unit. Alternative heteroaryl difluoromethyl sulfone reagents were also identified, showing this to be a general paradigm for CF2H radical generation/cross-coupling.Ammonia Borane-Dependent Transfer Hydrogenation of Carboxylic Esters to Primary AlcoholsClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Among the many interesting hydrogenation reactions, the hydrogenation of carboxylic esters to primary alcohols is an essential transformation as well as a very challenging one. Conventionally, the reduction of esters is achieved by the aggressive action of unstable metal hydride-reducing agents (NaBH4 or LiAlH4), enabling the formation of the alcohol product. An additional option for ester reduction is hydrogenation facilitated with heterogeneous catalysts under harsh conditions. Expanding on their previous work on the use of ammonia borane (NH3&#183;BH3, AB) as a source of dihydrogen, Natte and co-workers at the Indian Institute of Technology Hyderabad reported the catalyst-free reduction of esters to alcohols ( J. Org. Chem., DOI: 10.1021/acs.joc.4c00964). Screening experiments revealed that the stoichiometry was critical to obtain high yields. THF was identified as the preferred solvent, and 120 &#176;C was the preferred reaction temperature. Replacement of AB with other amine borane complexes was less effective. A variety of potentially reducible functional groups, such as boronic ester, nitro, fluoroalkyl, and halo, were not impacted by the reaction with AB. Both aliphatic and aromatic esters were reduced to the corresponding primary alcohols with AB in uniformly good to excellent yields. In conclusion, the reduction of a diverse range of carboxylic esters via the hydrogen transfer agent ammonia borane was reported.Multicomponent Synthesis of &#945;-Branched Amines via a Zinc-Mediated Carbonyl Alkylative Amination ReactionClick to copy section linkSection link copied!The ability of &#945;-branched amine motifs to modulate key biological interactions and regulate the physicochemical properties of small molecules has rendered them as ubiquitous structural features among pharmaceutical agents, agrochemicals, and natural products. For many years, carbonyl reductive amination has been the benchmark for the synthesis of complex alkylamines and is particularly effective when there is limited &#945;-branching in the respective amine and carbonyl components. However, poor reactivity is often observed when sterically encumbered ketones are utilized as substrates. Gaunt and co-workers at the University of Cambridge detailed an operationally simple, efficient, and scalable synthesis of complex alkylamines via a multicomponent carbonyl alkylative amination (CAA) reaction ( J. Am. Chem. Soc., DOI: 10.1021/jacs.3c14037). The reaction was performed with a primary or secondary amine or an aniline, an aldehyde, and an alkyl iodide in the presence of a reductant and a Lewis acid. Screening experiments revealed that the optimal reductant, Lewis acid, and solvent were zinc, TMSOTf, and ethyl acetate, respectively. The reaction is sensitive to air, but simple sparging with nitrogen was sufficient. The reaction was insensitive to the particle size of the zinc; 10&#8211;400 &#956;m particles demonstrated equivalent efficacy. The CAA reaction was demonstrated with a variety of primary or secondary amines or anilines, aldehydes, and alkyl iodides; good yields were obtained. Alkyl chlorides and bromides were also viable substrates; the yields were lower than with the corresponding iodides. Ketones were unreactive to the CAA reaction conditions. The alkyl iodides could be successfully replaced with redox-activated esters as the radical precursors under the standard reaction conditions with no deleterious effect on the yields. In conclusion, an economical, robust, and scalable strategy for the synthesis of complex alkylamines under mild conditions via a zinc-mediated carbonyl alkylative amination reaction was detailed.Modular Synthesis of &#945;-Branched Secondary Alkylamines via Visible-Light-Mediated Carbonyl Alkylative AminationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Gaunt and co-workers built on their interests in branched secondary alkylamines using the three-component coupling approach under blue LED irradiation using tris(trimethylsilyl)silane to generate the alkyl radical derived from the alkyl iodide ( Chem. Sci., DOI: 10.1039/d4sc03916e). Key to this approach is the selective addition of an alkyl radical into the electrophilic imine formed in situ from the primary amine and aldehyde. These studies systematically investigated the scope of this transformation through exploring a wide array of individual coupling partners, generating a wide array of secondary amine products (&gt;50 examples). The methodology was further expanded by design of the coupling partners to induce cyclization of the initial products from the three-component coupling step to generate heterocyclic systems in an efficient manner.Synthesis of 2-Pyridones through N-Insertion of CyclopentenonesClick to copy section linkSection link copied!A good illustration of how N-heterocyclic compounds are important scaffolds in the pharmaceutical area is reflected by the fact that more than half of FDA-approved drugs feature this moiety. Despite this encouraging statistic, traditional methods for the synthesis of 2-pyridones are still often lengthy, require prefunctionalized building blocks, employ harsh conditions, or lack generality. In this prospect, Morandi and co-workers found inspiration from the famous Beckmann rearrangement, where pyridine-2-ones would be obtained after an N-insertion, ring-expansion rearrangement from readily available cyclopentenones ( Angew. Chem., Int. Ed., DOI: 10.1002/anie.202408230). This one-pot procedure consists of the formation of a transient silyl enol ether which rearranges through N-insertion using a combination of PIDA and ammonium carbamate. Under these mild conditions, a scope of more than 30 examples was obtained, including natural products such as cis-jasmone. Many functional groups are tolerated (free alcohol, carboxylic acid, alkene, alkyne, etc.), and the methodology is also amenable to 15N-labeling of APIs.Sandmeyer Chlorosulfonylation of (Hetero)aromatic Amines Using DABSO as a SO2 SurrogateClick to copy section linkSection link copied!The importance of modern organosulfur chemistry cannot be overstated, as organosulfur compounds find widespread applications in agrochemicals, materials, fine chemicals, and pharmaceuticals. Of the many different sulfur-containing functional groups, sulfonamides have a special place in modern drug discovery, as they can act as bioisosteres for carboxylic acids, esters, and amides. Despite the ubiquity of sulfonamides, their synthesis relies nearly exclusively on one textbook transformation, the reaction of an amine with a sulfonyl chloride in the presence of a base. Sch&#228;fer at Idorsia Pharmaceuticals, Willis at the University of Oxford, and their co-workers developed a novel Sandmeyer-type sulfonyl chloride synthesis from feedstock anilines and DABCO-bis(sulfur dioxide) (DABSO) as a stable SO2 surrogate ( Org. Lett., DOI: 10.1021/acs.orglett.4c01908). DABSO is a commercially available, inexpensive, bench-stable, easily handled crystalline solid. The diazonium salt was derived from the corresponding aniline by treatment with tert-butyl nitrite and was trapped in situ with DABSO. The resultant sulfonyl chloride could be isolated or treated with an amine to form the sulfonamide directly. RC-1 experiments confirmed the tert-butyl nitrite addition to be fully dose-controlled without any thermal accumulation. The reaction protocol was successful on a variety of electron-neutral and electron-deficient anilines; electron-rich anilines required heating to 75 &#176;C to achieve full conversion. The reaction tolerated a variety of functional groups, including halogen, fluoroalkyl, nitrile, nitro, and ester. Heterocyclic amines were also demonstrated to be suitable substrates. In summary, anilines were converted into the corresponding sulfonyl chlorides by a Sandmeyer-type reaction with DABSO as a SO2 surrogate under mild conditions. The resultant sulfonyl chlorides could be converted in situ into sulfonamides.Palladium(Methylnaphthyl)(tBuBrettPhos) Complexes as Efficient and Selective Catalysts for the Monoarylation of Ammonia and HydrazineClick to copy section linkSection link copied!The transition-metal-catalyzed monoarylation of ammonia is one of the most attractive syntheses of anilines because of its simplicity and atom economy. However, this protocol is challenging since the aniline products are more reactive to a second arylation than ammonia is to the first. For Pd-catalyzed reactions, bulky, electron-rich ligands are essential to achieve selective monoarylation. The selective monoarylation of hydrazine is even harder to achieve. Goo&#223;en and co-workers at Ruhr Universit&#228;t Bochum reported their discovery of [Pd(MeNAP)(tBuBrettPhos)Br] as an efficient one-component catalyst for the arylation of ammonia and hydrazine ( ACS Catal., DOI: 10.1021/acscatal.4c02624). Catalyst screening experiments revealed the enhanced performance of [Pd(1-MeNAP)(tBuBrettPhos)Br] versus other combinations of palladium sources and electron-rich ligands for the desired monoarylation of ammonia with aryl chlorides. Preformation of this catalyst system was not required. Ammonium triflate and hydrazine triflate were utilized as convenient, solid surrogates for ammonia and hydrazine, respectively. A range of aryl chlorides were converted into the corresponding anilines or arylhydrazines with excellent selectivity for monoarylation. Excellent yields were obtained irrespective of the electronic nature of the aryl chloride substrate. The hydrazine products were converted in situ to pyrazoles to simplify their isolation and quantification on small scale. The reaction scope was extended to multiple heterocycles, including pyridine, pyrazine, thiophene, and quinoline. In conclusion, the bench-stable complex [Pd(1-MeNAP)(tBuBrettPhos)Br] was shown to catalyze the monoarylation of ammonia and hydrazine derivatives with a new level of activity and selectivity.Homoleptic Organolanthanum-Catalyzed CarbohalogenationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Lithium&#8211;halogen exchange is a crucial transformation in organic chemistry. The formation of nucleophilic carbanions and generation of organometallic species which can engage in metal-mediated processes enable indispensable synthetic disconnections. Regardless, metal&#8211;halogen exchange is rarely used for cascade transformations due to the reactivity of these species, and catalytic methods, especially those using nonprecious metals, are limited. Chen, Maron, Wei, and co-workers recently reported a catalytic lanthanum&#8211;halogen exchange and carbometalation/halogenation to furnish functionally dense cyclic systems ( J. Am. Chem. Soc., DOI: 10.1021/jacs.4c10445). The authors employed a homoleptic lanthanum catalyst in conjunction with a mild lithium source and catalytic base to achieve a cascade reaction. Allyloxybromo- and -iodoarenes can undergo carbohalogenation in good yields. In addition to dihydrobenzofuran derivatives, indole and indoline motifs can be accessed when N-allyl bromoanilines are employed. Alternatively, when a fluorine is present at the 3-postion, dihalobiphenyl products are achieved in high yields instead via an aryne-based pathway. Following scope exploration, the authors interrogated the mechanism of each reaction and demonstrated the energetically challenging pathway allowed by this unique set of reaction conditions. In particular, the mechanistic divergence from palladium- and nickel-catalyzed systems was noted. The synthetic value of the products as intermediates en route to pharmaceutical agents was demonstrated through the synthesis of TAK-875, an iterative alkyne addition, and a diastereoselective carbohalogenation. The La-catalyzed cascade and aryne transformations offer new synthetic strategies toward densely functionalized motifs and extend the utility of the classical metal&#8211;halogen exchange. More importantly, this method demonstrates the use of highly earth-abundant, nontoxic, and cost-effective lanthanides in the synthesis of complex products and sheds light on the potential to improve current methods or develop novel reactions using more sustainable approaches.CuSO4/N-(9H-Carbazol-9-yl)picolinamide-Catalyzed C&#8211;O Coupling of (Hetero)aryl Chlorides with P</description>
      <author>James A. Schwindeman, Alex Kosanovich, Christopher B. Kelly, Timothy Kwok, Thomas James, Annabel Ansel, James M. MacDougall, Jimmy Lauberteaux, David P. Day, Sylvain Guizzetti, John Knight</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.oprd.4c00418</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
