<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:21:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a red phosphorus-molybdenum dioxide electron-rich interface for efficient photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.244</link>
      <description>Guanghui Luo, Huimin Liu, Ruilin Wang, Chengyu Duan, Mengdi Sun, Yinglong Lu, Zheshun Ou, Zhuofeng Hu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405985650

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanghui Luo, Huimin Liu, Ruilin Wang, Chengyu Duan, Mengdi Sun, Yinglong Lu, Zheshun Ou, Zhuofeng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved performances toward electrochemical carbon dioxide and oxygen reductions by iron-doped stannum nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04843a</link>
      <description>Jiangtao Zhu, Quan Zhang, Caiyun Wang, Yanhong Feng, Gaocan Qi, Yuanyuan Zhang, Kang Lian, Jun Luo, Xijun Liu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405982193

                The CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) show great promise for expanding the use of renewable energy sources and fostering carbon neutrality. Sn-based catalysts show CO2RR activity;...</description>
      <author>Jiangtao Zhu, Quan Zhang, Caiyun Wang, Yanhong Feng, Gaocan Qi, Yuanyuan Zhang, Kang Lian, Jun Luo, Xijun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04843a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chlorine tailored CdOxCly/Al2O3 for syngas formation in electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01426j</link>
      <description>Xin Wang, Zhen&#8208;Hong He, Hui-Hui Cao, Yu-Xuan Ji, Xueyu Fan, Rongqiu Yan, Kuan Wang, Weitao Wang, Lu Li, Zhao&#8208;Tie Liu, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405988951

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (eCO2RR) is widely recognized as one of the most promising approaches to produce valuable chemicals especially syngas and mitigate carbon emissions. Hence, it holds immense significance...</description>
      <author>Xin Wang, Zhen&#8208;Hong He, Hui-Hui Cao, Yu-Xuan Ji, Xueyu Fan, Rongqiu Yan, Kuan Wang, Weitao Wang, Lu Li, Zhao&#8208;Tie Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01426j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag Nanoparticle-Modified Metal Azole Framework for Enhancing the Electrocatalytic Reduction of Carbon Dioxide to Carbon Monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010032</link>
      <description>Xu Han, Haotian Wang, Yijie Zhang, Yuting Tan, Xiaomeng Lv, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406012791

                The electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2RR) into high-value-added products is considered to be a promising way to mitigate carbon emissions. However, it remains a challenge to design an efficient catalyst with an excellent performance. In this work, we synthesized a metal azole framework (MAF) by changing 2-methylimidazole ligands into 5-mercapto-1-methyltetrazole (MMT) for use as organic linkers and mercaptan groups as anchoring sites for the Ag nanoparticles. The Ag NPs@ MAF-MMT material displayed a wide potential window from &#8722;0.6 to &#8722;1.2 V vs. RHE, with a maximum CO Faradaic efficiency (FECO) over 90.5%, and a current density of 18 mA cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;1.1 V vs. RHE for 11 h in an H-cell. This work provides a new option to immobilize Ag nanoparticles in MAFs material for the exploration of carbon dioxide reduction catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xu Han, Haotian Wang, Yijie Zhang, Yuting Tan, Xiaomeng Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Electrochemical Reduction Cell Model of Photosynthesis for Carbon Dioxide Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5083012</link>
      <description>Tamunosaki Graham Douglas, Okpara Obinna Michael, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406063550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tamunosaki Graham Douglas, Okpara Obinna Michael</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5083012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature-dependent pathways in carbon dioxide electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.12.052</link>
      <description>Shiqiang Liu, Yaoyu Yin, Jiahao Yang, Wenling Zhao, Meng Zhou, Huisheng Qin, Jiapeng Jiao, Yiyong Wang, Hengan Wang, Xing Tong, Yi Xu, Xiaofu Sun, Qinggong Zhu, Maohong Fan, Xinchen Kang, Buxing Han, Science Bulletin. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406070539

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiqiang Liu, Yaoyu Yin, Jiahao Yang, Wenling Zhao, Meng Zhou, Huisheng Qin, Jiapeng Jiao, Yiyong Wang, Hengan Wang, Xing Tong, Yi Xu, Xiaofu Sun, Qinggong Zhu, Maohong Fan, Xinchen Kang, Buxing Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.12.052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green synthesis of two-dimensional copper nanomaterials using biomass for the reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61173/zc8fdz27</link>
      <description>Siyan Chen, Science and Technology of Engineering Chemistry and Environmental Protection. 1(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405930003

                The problem of greenhouse gas emissions has become increasingly severe, so energy conservation and emissions reduction have become a critical challenge for our society. In response to the challenge of lowering carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions and transforming them into valuable energy molecules, this work explores the eco-friendly preparation of two-dimensional (2D) nanocopper-based catalysts. In this study, biomass was utilized as both the reductant and the capping reagent to prepare these catalysts. The structure and morphology of the resulting products were analyzed using scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM). Their crystal structures were characterized by X-ray diffraction (XRD). The synthesis process of this type of nanomaterials was also studied. These copper-based catalysts were then evaluated for their efficiency in reducing CO2 into small energy molecules of HCOOH. A significant innovation of this study is using biomass as the reductant and capping agent, which guarantees the green synthesis process and exhibits great potential in converting CO2 into valuable energy molecules. This research is significant for creating new energy sources and protecting the environment.</description>
      <author>Siyan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61173/zc8fdz27</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise Regulation of In Situ Exsolution Components of Nanoparticles for Constructing Active Interfaces toward Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14279</link>
      <description>Luo Yao, Chang Xu, Jietao Wang, Dong Zhang, Lei Fu, Xiang&#8208;Kui Gu, Yao Wang, Tong Liu, Mingyue Ding, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406010230

                Metal nanocatalysts supported on oxide scaffolds have been widely used in energy storage and conversion reactions. So far, the main research is still focused on the growth, density, size, and activity enhancement of exsolved nanoparticles (NPs). However, the lack of precise regulation of the type and composition of NPs elements under reduction conditions has restricted the architectural development of in situ exsolution systems. Herein, we propose a strategy to attain a regulated distribution of exsolved transition metals (Cu, Ni, and Fe) on Sr2Fe1.2Ni0.2Cu0.2Mo0.4O6&#8211;&#948; medium-entropy perovskite oxides by varying the oxygen partial pressure (pO2) gradient in the mixture. At 800 &#176;C, the unitary Cu, binary Cu&#8211;Ni, and ternary Cu&#8211;Ni&#8211;Fe NPs are exsolved as pO2 decreases from high to low. Combining experimental and theoretical simulations, we further corroborate that solid oxide electrolysis cells with ternary alloy clusters at the CNF@SFO interface exhibit superior CO2 electrolytic performance. Our results provide tailored strategies for nanostructures and nanointerfaces for studying metal oxide exsolution systems, including fuel electrode materials.</description>
      <author>Luo Yao, Chang Xu, Jietao Wang, Dong Zhang, Lei Fu, Xiang&#8208;Kui Gu, Yao Wang, Tong Liu, Mingyue Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Volcanic Relationship of Model Molecular Catalysts in CO2 Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03912b</link>
      <description>Jin&#8208;Zhao Wang, Yang Xu, Anqi Wei, Julian Skagfj&#246;rd Reinhold, Wei Li-xin, Lei Shi, Yushuo Zhang, Shaofeng Liu, Chong Wang, Bo Zhang, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405902991

                We have constructed a series of model metal phthalocyanine (MPc) for the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR), constructed a volcano relationship through density functional theory (DFT) and experiments, and obtained...</description>
      <author>Jin&#8208;Zhao Wang, Yang Xu, Anqi Wei, Julian Skagfj&#246;rd Reinhold, Wei Li-xin, Lei Shi, Yushuo Zhang, Shaofeng Liu, Chong Wang, Bo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03912b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction based on advanced Cu-based materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14711/thesis-991013340443503412</link>
      <description>Yinuo Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405916652

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) has exhibited great potential in alleviating the issue of global warming and producing value-added products within industrial production levels. Nevertheless, diversified reaction preferences on the catalyst and tedious reaction pathways for several target products impede the progress towards industrialization. Therefore, it is particularly important to obtain a comprehensive understanding of the relationship between the reaction preference (pathways and intermediates) and the structure of the catalyst and interface reaction, aiming to achieving effective generation of target product with high selectivity, high conversion rate and low overpotential. Cu has been considered as an extremely promising candidate for electrochemical CO2RR owing...[ Read more ]</description>
      <author>Yinuo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14711/thesis-991013340443503412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-modified Nb2O5 photocatalysts for high performance of CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113288</link>
      <description>Junli Chen, Tao Wang, Ziqi Yang, Pan Gao, Materials Research Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405915916

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junli Chen, Tao Wang, Ziqi Yang, Pan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing oil recovery and emissions reduction through co2 injection in mature offshore fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37878/2708-0080/2024-5.13</link>
      <description>B.S. Akhymbayeva, Neft i gaz. 143(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406055596

                The article explores the potential of CO2 injection technology for enhanced oil recovery (EOR) and simultaneous reduction of carbon emissions through storage in oil reservoirs and aquifers. The study focuses on 23 oil fields on the Norwegian Continental Shelf, identified as promising candidates for implementing this technology. The model used in the research assesses the economic and technical feasibility of CO2 injection, along with the integration of EOR and long-term carbon storage. The primary goal is to demonstrate that injecting 70 million tons of CO2 annually over 40 years can result in an additional oil recovery of 5.9%-7.6% of the original oil in place, equivalent to 276-351 million cubic meters. Excess CO2 can be stored in aquifers, further contributing to the reduction of carbon emissions. The article outlines key aspects of the study, including economic and technical parameters, such as costs associated with CO2 transportation, storage, and drilling of new wells, as well as various oil and CO2 price scenarios. The environmental benefits of the project are highlighted, showing that the significant CO2 retained in oil reservoirs and aquifers compensates for emissions from the combustion of recovered oil. The study also discusses the features of the model, including scenarios for continuous CO2 injection and considerations of infrastructure costs. The article emphasizes the importance of developing and implementing such projects in the context of global climate change mitigation efforts and points to the significant potential of CO2 injection technology for the oil industry. The aim of this article is to evaluate the feasibility and potential benefits of large-scale CO2 injection for enhanced oil recovery (EOR) and long-term carbon storage in oil fields and aquifers. The study seeks to demonstrate how CO2 injection can increase oil recovery rates while simultaneously reducing carbon emissions, providing a comprehensive technical-economic assessment of the process. Through the analysis of 23 oil fields on the Norwegian Continental Shelf, the article aims to present the economic, environmental, and operational advantages of integrating CO2 storage with EOR operations.</description>
      <author>B.S. Akhymbayeva</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37878/2708-0080/2024-5.13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in Cu-based electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159210</link>
      <description>R. Q. Xiong, Huimin Xu, Hong-Rui Zhu, Zhijie Zhang, Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069753

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Q. Xiong, Huimin Xu, Hong-Rui Zhu, Zhijie Zhang, Gao&#8208;Ren Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159210</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale X-ray scattering elucidates activation and deactivation of oxide-derived copper electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55742-5</link>
      <description>Jim de Ruiter, Vincent R. M. Benning, Shuang Yang, B. J. den Hartigh, Hui Wang, P. Tim Prins, Joren M. Dorresteijn, Joris C. L. Janssens, Gouranga Manna, Andrei V. Petukhov, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Freddy T. Rabouw, Ward van der Stam, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406023937

                Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) into sustainable fuels and base chemicals requires precise control over and understanding of activity, selectivity and stability descriptors of the electrocatalyst under operation. Identification of the active phase under working conditions, but also deactivation factors after prolonged operation, are of the utmost importance to further improve electrocatalysts for electrochemical CO2 conversion. Here, we present a multiscale in situ investigation of activation and deactivation pathways of oxide-derived copper electrocatalysts under CO2 reduction conditions. Using well-defined Cu2O octahedra and cubes, in situ X-ray scattering experiments track morphological changes at small scattering angles and phase transformations at wide angles, with millisecond to second time resolution and ensemble-scale statistics. We find that undercoordinated active sites promote CO2 reduction products directly after Cu2O to Cu activation, whereas less active planar surface sites evolve over time. These multiscale insights highlight the dynamic and intimate relationship between electrocatalyst structure, surface-adsorbed molecules, and catalytic performance, and our in situ X-ray scattering methodology serves as an additional tool to elucidate the factors that govern electrocatalyst (de)stabilization. The development of robust materials for electrochemical CO2 conversion requires identification of the activation and deactivation phase after prolonged operation. Here, the authors present a multiscale in situ X-ray scattering methodology to probe the life and death of copper oxide electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jim de Ruiter, Vincent R. M. Benning, Shuang Yang, B. J. den Hartigh, Hui Wang, P. Tim Prins, Joren M. Dorresteijn, Joris C. L. Janssens, Gouranga Manna, Andrei V. Petukhov, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Freddy T. Rabouw, Ward van der Stam</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55742-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sc cluster supported on two-dimensional biphenylene for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162298</link>
      <description>Zheng&#8208;Zhe Lin, Meng-Rong Li, Dong Yue, Xi Chen, Applied Surface Science. 687(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406061954

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zheng&#8208;Zhe Lin, Meng-Rong Li, Dong Yue, Xi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Activity and Selectivity of Cupt/C Catalysts for the Electrochemical Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5082628</link>
      <description>Manuel Guti&#233;rrez, David Sebasti&#225;n, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Federica Zammillo, Mario Gallone, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, M.J. L&#225;zaro, S. P&#233;rez-Rodr&#237;guez, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406058296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manuel Guti&#233;rrez, David Sebasti&#225;n, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Federica Zammillo, Mario Gallone, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, M.J. L&#225;zaro, S. P&#233;rez-Rodr&#237;guez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5082628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for dopant selection in Cu catalysts to promote the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction for ethylene production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.030</link>
      <description>Dogyeong Kim, Seohyeon Ka, Man Ho Han, Woong Kim, Seungho Yu, Jae&#8208;Young Choi, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Woong Hee Lee, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405926186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dogyeong Kim, Seohyeon Ka, Man Ho Han, Woong Kim, Seungho Yu, Jae&#8208;Young Choi, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Woong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selecting a synthetic route of copper-modified g-C3N4/TiO2 photocatalysts for efficient CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113863</link>
      <description>Anna Yu. Kurenkova, &#1040;ndrey &#1040;. Saraev, Roman F. Alekseev, Angelina V. Zhurenok, D.D. Mishchenko, E. Yu. Gerasimov, Ekaterina A. Kozlova, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405962043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anna Yu. Kurenkova, &#1040;ndrey &#1040;. Saraev, Roman F. Alekseev, Angelina V. Zhurenok, D.D. Mishchenko, E. Yu. Gerasimov, Ekaterina A. Kozlova</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Effect and Mechanism of Hydrothermal Modification on TiO2 Catalysts for CO2 Photo-Thermal Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04906-5</link>
      <description>Bin Guan, Junyan Chen, Zhongqi Zhuang, Lei Zhu, Zeren Ma, Xuehan Hu, Chenyu Zhu, Sikai Zhao, Kaiyou Shu, Hongtao Dang, Tiankui Zhu, Zhen Huang, Catalysis Letters. 155(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406039202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Guan, Junyan Chen, Zhongqi Zhuang, Lei Zhu, Zeren Ma, Xuehan Hu, Chenyu Zhu, Sikai Zhao, Kaiyou Shu, Hongtao Dang, Tiankui Zhu, Zhen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04906-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing atomically dispersed Ni-Mn catalysts for electrochemical CO2 reduction over the wide potential window</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.245</link>
      <description>Huili Guo, Yihong Liu, Ling Wang, Nana Wang, Xiaojie Jiang, Jingyu Pang, Dong&#8208;Bin Dang, Xiaoyan Ji, Yan Bai, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406011726

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huili Guo, Yihong Liu, Ling Wang, Nana Wang, Xiaojie Jiang, Jingyu Pang, Dong&#8208;Bin Dang, Xiaoyan Ji, Yan Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Reduction Method for Energy Input and CO2 Emissions: Direct Supply of Underground Seawater for Land-Based Aquaculture Systems in South Korea</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010177</link>
      <description>Seungyeop Baek, BH Jeon, Sebong Oh, Wontak Choi, Seunggi Choi, Yonmo Sung, Energies. 18(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406049598

                This study addresses the challenges of and opportunities for achieving the ambitious greenhouse gas emissions reduction target of the fishery sector of the Republic of Korea, set at 96% by 2030. We also focus on the current status of land-based aquaculture and underground seawater resource development, quantitatively compare energy inputs for land-based fish cultivation, and evaluate the potential of underground seawater to reduce CO2 emissions. Since 2010, 762 underground seawater boreholes have been developed, yielding a cumulative daily pumpage of 125,780 m3. Jeollanam-do was found to have the highest daily pumpage, with an annual energy requirement of 131,205,613 Mcal. Despite the fact that the energy demands for underground seawater are higher in some months, it provides a 22.6% reduction in total annual energy consumption compared to surface water. The use of underground seawater for heating or cooling resulted in a 24.1% reduction in the required input energy. However, energy requirements increase due to the relatively high surface water temperature in some regions and seasons. This study also highlights the utilization of underground seawater in heating or cooling surface water via indirect applications using geothermal heat pumps. This innovative research broadens the methods of greenhouse gas mitigation, particularly in the agriculture, livestock, and fisheries industries.</description>
      <author>Seungyeop Baek, BH Jeon, Sebong Oh, Wontak Choi, Seunggi Choi, Yonmo Sung</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palladium (II) pyridylidene sulfonamide (PYSA) catalysts featuring Ortho-Substitution allow for improved electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113838</link>
      <description>Afshan Khurshid, Yasir Altaf, Muhammad Tahir, Ehsan Ullah Mughal, Ryan J. Trovitch, M. Naveed Zafar, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406018578

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Afshan Khurshid, Yasir Altaf, Muhammad Tahir, Ehsan Ullah Mughal, Ryan J. Trovitch, M. Naveed Zafar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bias distribution and regulation for efficient oxygen atom transfer in photoelectrochemical cells coupled with styrene epoxidation and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115941</link>
      <description>Jiaming Wang, Lei Wu, Siqin Liu, Shunan Liu, Hongwei Ji, Chuncheng Chen, Yuchao Zhang, Jincai Zhao, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406057272

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaming Wang, Lei Wu, Siqin Liu, Shunan Liu, Hongwei Ji, Chuncheng Chen, Yuchao Zhang, Jincai Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-layer design and optimization of CO2 emission reduction in the iron and steel industry based on 'BRL' industrial metabolism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2025.134387</link>
      <description>Junwen Chen, Qingshan Gong, Zhanlong Cao, Min Ling Liu, Minchao Xie, Gang Zhao, Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406074473

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junwen Chen, Qingshan Gong, Zhanlong Cao, Min Ling Liu, Minchao Xie, Gang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2025.134387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure-activity relationship of small organic molecule functionalized Bi-based heterogeneous catalysts for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.246</link>
      <description>Kun Liu, Junping Niu, Yijia Bai, Jianlei Qi, Limin Han, Ning Zhu, Ligang Yan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406053501

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kun Liu, Junping Niu, Yijia Bai, Jianlei Qi, Limin Han, Ning Zhu, Ligang Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of applying full oxygen blast furnace on the transformation of energy mix and reduction of CO2 emissions for an integral steel plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2025.134390</link>
      <description>Xinjian Li, Weijian Tian, Hui Li, Kui Quan, Xu Zhang, Xin Lu, Hao Bai, Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406062562

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinjian Li, Weijian Tian, Hui Li, Kui Quan, Xu Zhang, Xin Lu, Hao Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2025.134390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Highly Catalytic Activity and Stability of Visible-Light-Driven CO2 Reduction via CsPbBr3 QDs/Cu-BTC Core-Shell Photocatalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406010374

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Highly Catalytic Activity and Stability of Visible-Light-Driven CO2 Reduction via CsPbBr3 QDs/Cu-BTC Core-Shell Photocatalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406010339

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Highly Catalytic Activity and Stability of Visible-Light-Driven CO2 Reduction via CsPbBr3 QDs/Cu-BTC Core-Shell Photocatalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406010292

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZIF-67-derived NiCo2O4 hollow nanocages coupled with g-C3N4 nanosheets as Z-scheme photocatalysts for enhancing CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.010</link>
      <description>Fanwei Meng, Chao Qu, Lanyang Wang, Decai Yang, Zezhong Zhao, Qingsong Ye, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406065874

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fanwei Meng, Chao Qu, Lanyang Wang, Decai Yang, Zezhong Zhao, Qingsong Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of metal&#8211;organic framework based photocatalysts correlated with specific additives for driving gas&#8211;liquid-solid CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.12.019</link>
      <description>Huijie He, Weikai Zhai, P. Liu, Jingyu Wang, Materials Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huijie He, Weikai Zhai, P. Liu, Jingyu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.12.019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Highly Catalytic Activity and Stability of Visible-Light-Driven CO2 Reduction via CsPbBr3 QDs/Cu-BTC Core-Shell Photocatalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406010403

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Highly Catalytic Activity and Stability of Visible-Light-Driven CO2 Reduction via CsPbBr3 QDs/Cu-BTC Core-Shell Photocatalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Yuanming Hou, Yanqing Zhang, Shilong Jiao, Jingyi Qin, Luoyu Liu, Zhengzheng Xie, Zhongjie Guan, Jianjun Yang, Qiuye Li, Xianwei Fu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406010315

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanming Hou, Yanqing Zhang, Shilong Jiao, Jingyi Qin, Luoyu Liu, Zhengzheng Xie, Zhongjie Guan, Jianjun Yang, Qiuye Li, Xianwei Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Highly Catalytic Activity and Stability of Visible-Light-Driven CO2 Reduction via CsPbBr3 QDs/Cu-BTC Core-Shell Photocatalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406010405

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Catalytic Activity and Stability of Visible-Light-Driven CO2 Reduction via CsPbBr3 QDs/Cu-BTC Core-Shell Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e</link>
      <description>Yuanming Hou, Yanqing Zhang, Shilong Jiao, Jingyi Qin, Luoyu Liu, Zhengzheng Xie, Zhongjie Guan, Jianjun Yang, Qiuye Li, Xianwei Fu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405972199

                Metal halide perovskites show great potential in photocatalysis, while intrinsic instability seriously hinders its application in photocatalytic CO2 reduction. Coincidentally, metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have garnered immense interest due to their...</description>
      <author>Yuanming Hou, Yanqing Zhang, Shilong Jiao, Jingyi Qin, Luoyu Liu, Zhengzheng Xie, Zhongjie Guan, Jianjun Yang, Qiuye Li, Xianwei Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07190e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen powered heavy-duty trucks may contribute CO2 emission increase instead of reduction under current hydrogen production structure in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2025.134379</link>
      <description>Hao Xu, Feng Chen, Jinping Cheng, Yucai Bai, Shuqing Zhao, Yiheng Wu, Yin Lu, Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406074609

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Xu, Feng Chen, Jinping Cheng, Yucai Bai, Shuqing Zhao, Yiheng Wu, Yin Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2025.134379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Approaches To Carbon Sequestration Emerging Technologies And Global Impacts On Climate Change Mitigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51470/er.2024.6.2.15</link>
      <description>Murugesan Mohana Keerthi, Environmental Reports.. 6(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405949953

                Carbon sequestration is emerging as a crucial strategy to mitigate the effects of climate change by reducing atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) concentrations. While natural processes such as forests and oceans contribute to carbon storage, engineered approaches have gained significant attention due to their potential to enhance sequestration on a global scale. This review explores innovative carbon sequestration technologies, including Direct Air Capture (DAC), Bioenergy with Carbon Capture and Storage (BECCS), soil carbon sequestration, ocean fertilization, and carbon mineralization. Each of these technologies offers unique opportunities to capture and store CO2, with varying degrees of feasibility, cost, and environmental impact, their promise, challenges such as high costs, storage capacity concerns, and ecological risks remain. The review also discusses the global implications of these technologies on climate change mitigation, emphasizing the need for integrated policies, international cooperation, and ongoing research to maximize their potential. Ultimately, carbon sequestration, when coupled with emission reduction strategies, can play a pivotal role in achieving long-term climate goals.</description>
      <author>Murugesan Mohana Keerthi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51470/er.2024.6.2.15</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Multi-pollutant Impacts of Sulfur Reduction Strategies in the United States: A Cost-Benefit Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestair.4c00114</link>
      <description>Xinran Wu, Tracey Holloway, P.J. Meier, Morgan R. Edwards, ACS ES&amp;T Air. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405963468

                Electricity generation units (EGUs) emit a mix of health- and climate-relevant air emissions through coal combustion, with the potential to impact multiple emissions. Previous studies have focused on evaluating the cobenefits of climate policies on air quality, studies that consider how air pollution controls affect carbon emissions remain relatively sparse. To evaluate different emission reduction strategies' impacts on multiple air pollutants and carbon dioxide (CO2), here we apply a multi-pollutant analysis framework, focused on sulfur dioxide (SO2) controls on coal-fired EGUs in the United States (U.S.). Eighty-nine EGUs without SO2 controls in the contiguous U.S. as of 2020 are identified and investigated. Results show that add-on pollution controls like flue gas desulfurization (FGD) reduce SO2 emissions from coal combustion, but increase emissions of nitrogen oxides (NOx), fine particulate matter (PM2.5), volatile organic compounds (VOCs), and CO2. A coal-to-natural gas transition reduces all pollutants except VOCs. A coal-to-renewable transition reduces all studied pollutants. We find that add-on SO2 controls could generate a total annual net benefit of $13.4 billion nationwide when considering a multi-pollutant portfolio of emissions, as compared with $32.9 billion total annual net benefits from coal-to-natural gas transition and $40.5 billion from coal-to-renewable transition. Our results highlight the potential of implementing the multi-pollutant analysis framework to evaluate multi-pollutant emission reduction strategies.</description>
      <author>Xinran Wu, Tracey Holloway, P.J. Meier, Morgan R. Edwards</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestair.4c00114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Microbes and Microbiomes in GHG Emissions and Mitigation in Agricultural Ecosystem Restoration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/9789815322347124020007</link>
      <description>Muthusamy Shankar, Sethupathi Nedumaran, Deepasri Mohan, Helen Mary Rose, M Kokila, Selvaraj Keerthana, Ravi Raveena, K. Boomiraj, Sudhakaran Mani, BENTHAM SCIENCE PUBLISHERS eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405963357

                Microbes are crucial for the survival of life on Earth as they affect the major biogeochemical cycles that make our planet congenial for life, providing essential elements like carbon and nitrogen in required forms and quantities. Microbes also play a significant role as either generators or consumers of greenhouse gases, such as carbon dioxide (CO2 ), methane (CH4 ), and nitrous oxide (N2O), through various processes in our environment. The distribution of these chemicals on the Earth and in the atmosphere is severely reliant on the equilibrium of these microbial progressions. The consumption of GHGs by microbes is facilitated through their use as substrates in processes like photo/chemoautotrophy, methanotrophy, and nitrous oxide reduction. The CO2 emitted from the organic matter decomposition and terrestrial respiration is subsequently subjected to photosynthetic fixation partially and is mitigated through carbon sequestration into soil and biomass. The biogenic release of methane through the biological anaerobic decomposition of organic materials by methanogens constitutes an important source of atmospheric CH4, while methanotrophs, through CH4 oxidation, facilitate methane emission mitigation. The microbial nitrification denitrification processes are the significant source of N2O emission, while the N2Oreducing bacteria are responsible for decreasing N2O emissions via nitrous oxide reduction enzymatic processes. The complexity of the interactions between these microbes with neighboring biotic and bacterial variables in order to regulate Earth's greenhouse gas emissions is a factor that affects their activity. Hence, interdisciplinary approaches, including microbial ecology, environmental genomics, soil and plant sciences, etc., should be concentrated on mitigating greenhouse gases.</description>
      <author>Muthusamy Shankar, Sethupathi Nedumaran, Deepasri Mohan, Helen Mary Rose, M Kokila, Selvaraj Keerthana, Ravi Raveena, K. Boomiraj, Sudhakaran Mani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/9789815322347124020007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Analysis of an Ammonia Combustion System for Future Two-Stroke Low-Speed Marine Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse13010039</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Serrano, Ricardo Novella, H&#233;ctor Climent, F.J. Arnau, Alejandro Calvo, Lauge Thorsen, Journal of Marine Science and Engineering. 13(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405934084

                Ammonia, being 17.6% hydrogen by mass, is regarded as a hydrogen carrier and carbon-free fuel as long as its production methods rely on renewable energy sources. The production and combustion of green ammonia do not generate carbon dioxide, offering a promising avenue for substantial reductions in greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from a well-to-wake perspective. This paper presents a comprehensive methodology for the development and validation of a thermodynamic model for a two-stroke low-speed marine engine incorporating a hybrid ammonia-diesel diffusion combustion system. The simulation tools are rigorously validated using experimental data obtained during diesel operation. Subsequently, the study explores various aspects of the novel ammonia-diesel combustion system, addressing combustion and emissions characteristics. The investigation incorporates diverse simulation scenarios involving direct fuel injection through dedicated valves into the cylinder head of a six-cylinder, turbocharged compression-ignition engine. The engine features two diesel injection valves, employed to initiate the combustion process, and two ammonia injection valves. Simulation scenarios include variations in the injection timing of the pilot diesel injector and the relative orientation of diesel and ammonia sprays. Case C emerges as the preferred configuration, demonstrating superior metrics in terms of combustion stability, air-fuel mixing, and emissions profile compared to other cases. The results indicate a reduction of CO2 emissions of approximately 95% in mass compared to the baseline diesel operation. Furthermore, notable reductions in NOx emissions are observed, preliminarily attributed to the lower flame temperature of ammonia. Despite the appearance of N2O emissions as a result of ammonia oxidation, the overall potential reduction in GHG emissions, in CO2-equivalent terms, exceeds 85% at selected operating points. This work contributes valuable insights into the optimization of cleaner propulsion systems for maritime applications, facilitating the industry&#8217;s transition toward more sustainable and environmentally friendly practices.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Serrano, Ricardo Novella, H&#233;ctor Climent, F.J. Arnau, Alejandro Calvo, Lauge Thorsen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse13010039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Career Recommendations for the Equitable Growth of a Marine Carbon Dioxide Removal Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024cn000246</link>
      <description>Gabriella D. Kitch, Patrick J. Duke, Kalina C. Grabb, Susana Marcela Simancas-Giraldo, Falilu Olaiwola Adekunbi, Charles Izuma Addey, Lisandro A. Arbilla, Andr&#233;a da Consola&#231;&#227;o de Oliveira Carvalho, Sophie N. Chu, Ryan A. Green, S. Hamnca, Anirban Ghosh, Amanda Kirkland, Kaitlyn B. Lowder, Melissa Mel&#233;ndez, Marcos Fontela, K&#233;vin Robache, Mallory Ringham, Jakob R&#248;nning, Katelyn M. Schockman, Mary Margaret Stoll, Raquel Ren&#243;, Elizabeth Wright-Fairbanks, Perspectives of Earth and Space Scientists. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406067027

                Abstract In addition to steep carbon emission reductions, all modeled pathways to reach global climate goals require carbon removal. Marine carbon dioxide removal has the potential to play a large role in drawing down legacy anthropogenic emissions due to the scalability and durability of proposed methods. While this field is rapidly expanding, a number of issues remain, including efforts to grow the industry, align projects with equity and justice goals, and ensure development of trusted, unique, durable carbon credits. We, a group of early career ocean professionals (ECOPs), provide an overview of the scale of the field, the aforementioned issues, and then make recommendations to ensure global equity and expand early career capacity in the marine carbon dioxide removal sector. We argue that substantial investment is needed to reduce costs of marine carbon dioxide removal and spur innovation in monitoring, reporting, and verification, but also in the training and development of early career researchers. Careful co&#8208;design of marine removal projects by experienced and emerging collaborators, including local communities, can help mitigate perpetuating existing global inequalities. Given the anticipated growth of the marine carbon dioxide removal workforce, ECOPs can contribute their existing interdisciplinary expertise, if they are supported within traditional structures. Those entering the field can leverage skill sets that intersect engineering, policy, community engagement, and business. We maintain that ECOPs will be key leaders in the field, if appropriately engaged, compensated, and empowered.</description>
      <author>Gabriella D. Kitch, Patrick J. Duke, Kalina C. Grabb, Susana Marcela Simancas-Giraldo, Falilu Olaiwola Adekunbi, Charles Izuma Addey, Lisandro A. Arbilla, Andr&#233;a da Consola&#231;&#227;o de Oliveira Carvalho, Sophie N. Chu, Ryan A. Green, S. Hamnca, Anirban Ghosh, Amanda Kirkland, Kaitlyn B. Lowder, Melissa Mel&#233;ndez, Marcos Fontela, K&#233;vin Robache, Mallory Ringham, Jakob R&#248;nning, Katelyn M. Schockman, Mary Margaret Stoll, Raquel Ren&#243;, Elizabeth Wright-Fairbanks</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024cn000246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pressure regulated CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrolysis on two-dimensional Bi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05357e</link>
      <description>Ruijin Sun, Jiwu Zhao, Hang Liu, Yanrong Xue, Xu Lu, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405971387

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO&#8322;RR) offers potential for sustainable production and greenhouse gas mitigation, particularly with renewable energy integration. However, its widespread application is hindered by expensive catalysts,...</description>
      <author>Ruijin Sun, Jiwu Zhao, Hang Liu, Yanrong Xue, Xu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05357e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Population Aging on Carbon Emissions: Based on the Perspective of Industrial Structure Upgrading and Rationalization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2754-1169/2025.19684</link>
      <description>Xinran Li, Advances in Economics Management and Political Sciences. 159(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406035301

                China's aging population society has entered a high-speed deepening stage, promoting energy saving and emission reduction, realizing low carbon development history is an important strategic task in our country. On the Basis of panel data since 2011 to 2021, using an intermediate effect model, this paper studies the relations among the population aging, industry structure upgrading as well as rationalization and the emission of carbon dioxide. The results indicate that aging exerts a significant positive impact on carbon emissions. The influence of population aging on carbon emissions is inverted U shape. When aging reaches a certain level, the influence on carbon emissions has a nonlinear feature of decreasing marginal effect. The aging can exert a prominent influence on carbon emissions in the regions through upgrading and rationalization of the industrial structure. That influence about population aging on carbon emissions is remarkable in the region. Therefore, promoting the optimization process of industry structure forced by population aging contributes to realizing "reduction effect of carbon emissions" under the background of population aging.</description>
      <author>Xinran Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2754-1169/2025.19684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of carbon footprint management model of electric power enterprises based on artificial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0316537</link>
      <description>Liangzheng Wu, K. Li, Yan Huang, Zhengdong Wan, Jieren Tan, PLoS ONE. 20(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406052380

                This study intends to optimize the carbon footprint management model of power enterprises through artificial intelligence (AI) technology to help the scientific formulation of carbon emission reduction strategies. Firstly, a carbon footprint calculation model based on big data and AI is established, and then machine learning algorithm is used to deeply mine the carbon emission data of power enterprises to identify the main influencing factors and emission reduction opportunities. Finally, the driver-state-response (DSR) model is used to evaluate the carbon audit of the power industry and comprehensively analyze the effect of carbon emission reduction. Taking China Electric Power Resources and Datang International Electric Power Company as examples, this study uses the comprehensive evaluation method of entropy weight- technique for order preference by similarity to ideal solution (TOPSIS). China Electric Power Resources Company has outstanding performance in promoting renewable energy, with its comprehensive evaluation index rising from 0.5458 in 2020 to 0.627 in 2022, while the evaluation index of Datang International Electric Power Company fluctuated and dropped to 0.421 in 2021. The research conclusion reveals the actual achievements and existing problems of power enterprises in energy saving and emission reduction, and provides reliable carbon information for the government, enterprises, and the public. The main innovation of this study lies in: using artificial intelligence technology to build a carbon footprint calculation model, combining with the data of International Energy Agency Carbon Dioxide (IEA CO 2 ) emission database, and using machine learning algorithm to deeply mine the important factors in carbon emission data, thus putting forward a carbon audit evaluation system of power enterprises based on DSR model. This study not only fills the blank of carbon emission management methods in the power industry, but also provides a new perspective and basis for the government and enterprises to formulate carbon emission reduction strategies.</description>
      <author>Liangzheng Wu, K. Li, Yan Huang, Zhengdong Wan, Jieren Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0316537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research for Global Carbon Emissions Influence Factor and Sustainable Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61173/mjvphc97</link>
      <description>Bishan Cheng, Science and Technology of Engineering Chemistry and Environmental Protection. 1(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405946875

                Today, carbon emission pollution is particularly serious. Greenhouse gases are produced all the time in every part of people&#8217;s lives, which directly leads to catastrophic global warming. Controlling carbon emissions is related to the fate of the entire earth, and countries around the world need to study the most effective and lowest-cost emission reduction methods as soon as possible. In this regard, this article comprehensively reviews the factors affecting global carbon emissions and analyzes the rising trend of carbon emissions in recent years. The article focuses on the mechanisms of major sources of carbon emissions such as transportation, urbanization, and industrial production, and their impact on the environment. The study found that the combustion of fossil fuels produces a large amount of carbon dioxide emissions and forest reclamation is the main reason for the increase in greenhouse gas concentrations, which directly leads to climate change. In addition, the article also analyzes the potential impact of urbanization. This article emphasizes the importance of reducing carbon emissions through global cooperation, technological innovation, and policy intervention to promote sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Bishan Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61173/mjvphc97</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microalgae photosynthetic carbon sequestration technology, financing subsidies and carbon trading mechanism: An evolutionary game mechanism modeling study from a biomechanical perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62617/mcb1005</link>
      <description>Bo Zhang, Mingyue Gong, Dong Chen, Molecular &amp; cellular biomechanics. 22(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405981860

                The global consensus to move towards carbon neutrality has been growing amidst turbulence, and the issue of carbon emissions has been an unavoidable topic for achieving the goal of carbon neutrality. The introduction of microalgae photosynthetic carbon sequestration technology optimizes the culture environment of microalgae through hydrodynamics and enhances the efficiency of light and carbon dioxide transfer, thus increasing the rate of photosynthesis and carbon sequestration effect of microalgae. Based on the biomechanical perspective, this study constructed a three-party dynamic evolution game model including agricultural subjects, enterprises and local governments, analyzed the mechanism of photosynthetic carbon sequestration by microalgae, the financing subsidy system and the carbon trading mechanism, and explored the strategic choices and behavioral evolution process of the agricultural subjects and local enterprises in the face of different policy incentives, and verified the conclusions by numerical simulation analysis. The study shows that: (1) the implementation of financial subsidy policies by local governments significantly increases the willingness of agricultural producers and enterprises to apply microalgae photosynthetic carbon sequestration technology, thus accelerating the process of agricultural carbon emission reduction; (2) the integration of energy enterprises and microalgae industry in the carbon trading market is conducive to the generation of renewable energy, and realizes a win-win situation for the government&#8217;s environmental benefits and the enterprise&#8217;s economic benefits; (3) the adoption of microalgae carbon sequestration by agricultural producers (3) The adoption of microalgae carbon sequestration technology by agricultural producers is conducive to the promotion of the virtuous cycle of soil microbial communities and the realization of crop income. This study evaluates the potential impacts of different policy combinations on agricultural carbon emission reduction based on the carbon trading mechanism, which can help promote the application of microalgae carbon sequestration technology and the implementation of agricultural carbon emission reduction.</description>
      <author>Bo Zhang, Mingyue Gong, Dong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62617/mcb1005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Systematic Analysis of Progress in Doping Combustion Characterization of Ammonia-Fueled Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/66z1jh50</link>
      <description>Zicong Wang, Qingjun Zhou, Highlights in Science Engineering and Technology. 120(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405902207

                In the global environment of carbon emission reduction, diesel engine emissions of carbon dioxide, nitrogen oxide and other harmful gases seriously polluting the environment has been boycotted by governments around the world. Ammonia, as a clean, environment-friendly, easy-to-transport green energy, has broad application prospects. However, due to its poor combustion performance and high calorific value, there are some limitations in its application. In this paper, the mechanism, combustion characteristics and emission characteristics of an engine fueled with ammonia-hydrogen fuel and ammonia-carbon-based fuel are reviewed. Hydrogen fuel and diesel fuel with low ignition energy and fast laminar flame spread characteristics, can make up the shortage of pure ammonia fuel, reduce nitrogen oxide emissions. Among them, hydrogen ammonia fuel has become the mainstream and the most promising fuel, compared with pure ammonia fuel and ammonia diesel fuel has the advantages of clean, low transport costs, fast combustion and so on, will become the future engine main application fuel.</description>
      <author>Zicong Wang, Qingjun Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/66z1jh50</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulation and Pathway Selection for China&#8217;s Carbon Peak: A Multi-Objective Nonlinear Dynamic Optimization Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010154</link>
      <description>Liang Shen, Qiheng Yuan, Qi He, Peng Jiang, H. Ji, Junyi Shi, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405920264

                This study innovatively develops a multi-objective Markal-Macro model, which simultaneously considers three objectives: minimizing carbon emissions from energy consumption, minimizing carbon emissions from production processes, and maximizing societal welfare. Based on the Cobb&#8211;Douglas production function, we construct a production function of carbon emission and use it as a coupling equation of the Markal-Macro model (Markal is the abbreviation of market allocation, and Macro is the abbreviation of macroeconomy). This enables the coupling of the endogenous variables of carbon emissions and those related to maximizing societal welfare. By collecting relevant data on energy consumption, production outputs, and key economic indicators, five different scenarios are established. To enhance the computational efficiency of the simulation, we introduce a Firefly Algorithm into the penalty function method. The objective of our simulation is to explore the optimal carbon peak pathway for China. The results indicate that under the baseline scenario, China can achieve its carbon peak by 2029, with the peak value reaching approximately 12.5 billion tons of carbon dioxide. Finally, based on the simulation results, this study provides specific policy recommendations for China&#8217;s carbon peak pathway, addressing aspects such as industrial structure, energy consumption structure, the share of clean energy, economic growth targets, and the growth of emission reduction expenditures, while considering regional five-year plans and regional carbon peak strategies. From the aspect of the practical contributions, this article not only provides a set of methods for policymakers to make the Carbon Peak Implementation Plan but also offers an optimal path to improve the sustainable development for China.</description>
      <author>Liang Shen, Qiheng Yuan, Qi He, Peng Jiang, H. Ji, Junyi Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid CIGS&#8208;Cobalt Quaterpyridine Photocathode with Backside Illumination: a New Paradigm for Solar Fuel Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423727</link>
      <description>Marc Robert, Hichem Ichou, L&#233;o Choubrac, Garen Suna, Debashrita Sarkar, Paulo Jorge Marques Cordeiro, St&#233;phane Diring, Fabien Pineau, Julien Bonin, Nicolas Barreau, Fabrice Odobel, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405927295

                Chalcogenide&#8208;based thin&#8208;film solar cell optimized for rear illumination and used for CO2 reduction is presented. Central to this innovation is a thinner, Cu(In,Ga)S2 chalcopyrite absorber coated with a robust metallic top layer, which potentially surpasses the performance of conventional front&#8208;illuminated designs. Using cobalt quaterpyridine molecular catalyst, photocurrent densities for CO2 reduction exceeding 10 mA/cm2 at 0.0 V vs. RHE under 1 Sun illumination, and ca. 16 mA/cm2 at &#8208;0.25 V vs. RHE were achieved in voltammetry experiments. Controlled potential electrolysis showed catalytic activity over 20 h with selectivity for CO ranging from &gt; 92% (first 4 hours) to 86% at the end of the experiment. This approach opens limitless possibilities for employing various reduction catalysts, extending far beyond CO2 reduction. It imposes minimal constraints on absorption properties, immobilization methods, and catalyst nature, setting the stage for high&#8208;performance, adaptable PEC devices.</description>
      <author>Marc Robert, Hichem Ichou, L&#233;o Choubrac, Garen Suna, Debashrita Sarkar, Paulo Jorge Marques Cordeiro, St&#233;phane Diring, Fabien Pineau, Julien Bonin, Nicolas Barreau, Fabrice Odobel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;OH Catalyzed by an Iron Porphyrinoid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08922</link>
      <description>Paramita Saha, Sk Amanullah, Sudip Barman, Abhishek Dey, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406066116

                Designing catalysts for the selective reduction of CO2, resulting in products having commercial value, is an important area of contemporary research. Several molecular catalysts have been reported to facilitate the reduction of CO2 (both electrochemical and photochemical) to yield 2e&#8211;/2H+ electron-reduced products, CO and HCOOH, and selective reduction of CO2 beyond 2e&#8211;/2H+ is rare. This is partly because the factors that control the selectivity of CO2 reduction beyond 2e&#8211; are not yet understood. An iron chlorin complex with a pendent amine functionality in its second sphere, known to selectively catalyze CO2RR to HCOOH with a very low overpotential from its formal Fe(I) state, can catalyze CO2RR from its formal Fe(0) state by 6e&#8211;/6H+, forming CH3OH as a major product with a Faradaic yield of &#8764;50%. Mechanistic investigations using in situ spectro-electrochemistry indicate that the reactivity of a low-spin d7 FeI&#8211;COOH intermediate species generated during CO2RR is crucial in determining the product selectivity of this reaction. In weakly acidic conditions, C-protonation of this FeI&#8211;COOH species, which is also chemically prepared and spectroscopically characterized, leads to HCOOH. The O-protonation, leading to C&#8211;OH bond cleavage and eventually to CH3OH, is &#8764;3 kcal/mol higher in energy and can be achieved in more acidic solutions. Hydrogen bonding to the pendent amine in the catalyst stabilizes reactive intermediates formed in the CO2RR and enables 6e&#8211;/6H+ reduction of CO2 to CH3OH.</description>
      <author>Paramita Saha, Sk Amanullah, Sudip Barman, Abhishek Dey</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid CIGS&#8208;Cobalt Quaterpyridine Photocathode with Backside Illumination: a New Paradigm for Solar Fuel Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423727</link>
      <description>Marc Robert, Houssam Ichou, L&#233;o Choubrac, Garen Suna, Debashrita Sarkar, Paulo Jorge Marques Cordeiro, St&#233;phane Diring, Fabien Pineau, Julien Bonin, Nicolas Barreau, Fabrice Odobel, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405927296

                Chalcogenide-based thin-film solar cell optimized for rear illumination and used for CO2 reduction is presented. Central to this innovation is a thinner, Cu(In,Ga)S2 chalcopyrite absorber coated with a robust metallic top layer, which potentially surpasses the performance of conventional front-illuminated designs. Using cobalt quaterpyridine molecular catalyst, photocurrent densities for CO2 reduction exceeding 10 mA/cm2 at 0.0 V vs. RHE under 1 Sun illumination, and ca. 16 mA/cm2 at -0.25 V vs. RHE were achieved in voltammetry experiments. Controlled potential electrolysis showed catalytic activity over 20 h with selectivity for CO ranging from &gt; 92% (first 4 hours) to 86% at the end of the experiment. This approach opens limitless possibilities for employing various reduction catalysts, extending far beyond CO2 reduction. It imposes minimal constraints on absorption properties, immobilization methods, and catalyst nature, setting the stage for high-performance, adaptable PEC devices.</description>
      <author>Marc Robert, Houssam Ichou, L&#233;o Choubrac, Garen Suna, Debashrita Sarkar, Paulo Jorge Marques Cordeiro, St&#233;phane Diring, Fabien Pineau, Julien Bonin, Nicolas Barreau, Fabrice Odobel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulation of direct dimethyl ether (DME) synthesis using existing methanol production infrastructure in Arzew, Algeria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18668/ng.2024.12.06</link>
      <description>Ilhem Sidi-Yacoub, Ahmed Feddag, Ikram Khelifa, Nafta-Gaz. 80(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406038649

                This study investigates the direct synthesis of dimethyl ether (DME) from syngas using the existing methanol production infrastructure at the Methanol and Synthetic Resins complex in Arzew, Algeria. The primary objective is to assess the feasibility of repurposing the adiabatic multiphase fixed-bed methanol production reactor for DME production while maintaining the original reactor dimensions, flow conditions, syngas composition, as well as temperature and pressure parameters used in methanol production. The research introduced a significant modification by replacing the initial copper oxide-based catalyst with a hybrid catalyst composed of &#947;-alumina and CuO/ZnO/Al2O3. This catalyst enables the direct production of DME from syngas, which is a mixture of carbon dioxide, carbon monoxide, and hydrogen. The study employed simulation models using Aspen-HYSYS V11 to predict DME productivity, manage the high temperatures resulting from exothermic reactions in each catalyst bed, and determine the required quench gas injection for temperature reduction. The simulation results indicated an overall DME yield of 2.81%, which is comparable to the methanol production rate of 3%. Further simulations with recycling stages increased the crude DME mass to 4.11%. These findings highlight the potential of using the current infrastructure to improve profitability and time efficiency in producing this alternative fuel.</description>
      <author>Ilhem Sidi-Yacoub, Ahmed Feddag, Ikram Khelifa</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18668/ng.2024.12.06</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life cycle GHG emissions reduction of an integrated CCUS system for combined heat and power plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4491/eer.2024.446</link>
      <description>Sora Yi, Junbeum Kim, Environmental Engineering Research. 30(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405913875

                The carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS) technologies have shown promise for directly reducing the amount of CO2 released into the atmosphere from significant point sources. This study aims to evaluate an integrated CCUS system in South Korea using three technologies: microalgae photocultivation, CO2 membrane separation, and carbon mineralization. LCAs showed the total GHG emissions, excluding carbon offset effects, were 358 kg CO2 eq/ton, with 95.8% from CO2 membrane separation. Microalgae and mineralization emitted 14.6 kg CO2 eq/ton (4.1%) and 0.371 kg CO2 eq/ton (0.1%), respectively. Including carbon offsets from CaCO3 production and CO2 utilization, the system's net emissions were -745 kg CO2 eq/ton. Further economic studies are needed, but the study confirmed the system's high GHG reduction efficiency through LCA, enhancing the potential use of CCUS technologies in urban CHP plants.</description>
      <author>Sora Yi, Junbeum Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4491/eer.2024.446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving factors of CO2 emissions in southeast China: Comparative study of long-term trends, short-term fluctuations, and spatial variations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1525/elementa.2023.00028</link>
      <description>Yimin Huang, Wei-Sheng Lin, Yuan Wang, Haiping Luo, Zhu Lin, Yanmin He, Feng Wang, Wen-ting Lai, Rui Shi, Elementa Science of the Anthropocene. 12(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405935317

                This study explores the factors driving CO2 emissions related to energy use in Fujian Province from 2000 to 2019, with an emphasis on long-term trends, short-term fluctuations, and spatial disparities. Utilizing annual data on CO2 emissions and various influencing factors from multiple cities within Fujian Province, we examine the factors driving long-term changes in CO2 emissions. To analyze short-term emission trajectories, we employ a temporal decomposition model, while spatial decomposition techniques are used to assess the variability in emission drivers across 9 prefecture-level cities over different years. Our findings reveal an inverted U-shaped relationship between CO2 emissions and urbanization over the 20-year study period. Furthermore, short-term fluctuations indicate a gradual reduction in the impact of urbanization on the increase in CO2 emissions within the industrial, transportation, and household sectors in Fujian Province. Additionally, economic development, measured as per capita gross domestic product, is shown to significantly influence CO2 emissions. Efforts to reduce energy intensity, which refers to the amount of energy consumed per unit of economic output, in both the industrial and household sectors are identified as potential strategies for emission reduction. The variability in CO2 emissions among cities is primarily attributed to differences in energy intensity and population sizes. These insights are critical for formulating policies aimed at promoting low-carbon development, reducing carbon emissions, and enhancing sustainability throughout Fujian Province.</description>
      <author>Yimin Huang, Wei-Sheng Lin, Yuan Wang, Haiping Luo, Zhu Lin, Yanmin He, Feng Wang, Wen-ting Lai, Rui Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1525/elementa.2023.00028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Country-Specific Modeling of Methane Production and Emission Reduction Utilizing Pig Manure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010095</link>
      <description>Ilho Bae, Seokbo Park, Juhee Shin, Jin Mi Triolo, Seung Gu Shin, Energies. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406018687

                The purpose of this study is to effectively support the operation of biogas plants that utilize anaerobic digestion of pig manure. An analysis was conducted on the characteristics of manure collected from 17 pig farms. Following this, the methane potential of the manure was evaluated, and a comparison of microbial communities was made at the end of the biochemical methane potential test. Based on these analyses, methane production during anaerobic digestion was modeled under various scenarios, allowing for the calculation of expected electricity generation and carbon dioxide reduction. The experimental results were categorized according to manure management type and the types of pigs raised. In this study, at a temperature of 37 &#176;C and a hydraulic retention time of 30 days, the scraper method demonstrated the highest methane production rates, achieving 0.85 and 1.03 m3/m3/day for both mono-anaerobic digestion of manure and co-digestion with food wastewater. However, establishing definitive characteristics of manure management types requires the collection of more comprehensive data from a broader range of farms, which will be critical for conducting further in-depth research.</description>
      <author>Ilho Bae, Seokbo Park, Juhee Shin, Jin Mi Triolo, Seung Gu Shin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CalTrans: Implementation of advanced technology and materials recycling techniques for the use of alternative materials in concrete as plain or reinforced materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5399/osu/1179</link>
      <description>Fengyin Du, Julien Hubert, Keshav Bharadwaj, Krishna Siva Teja Chopperla, Gopakumar Kaladaram, Jason H. Ideker, O. Burkan Isgor, W. Jason Weiss, Larry Sutter, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405909913

                The manufacture of ordinary portland cement (OPC) is responsible for approximately 4-8% of the total global Greenhouse Gases (GHG) emissions. Recent CalTrans research resulted in changes to specifications to reduce the clinker content of OPC by using ground limestone creating a Portland Limestone Cement (PLC) that is compliant with ASTM C595-IL as one method to reduce the carbon footprint (approximately a 10% CO2 reduction) [1]. Supplementary Cementitious Materials (SCMs) may be able to be used to further reduce the clinker content in concrete, providing an additional 20 to 40% CO2 reduction depending on the volume of cement replaced and the SCM used. This project focused on reducing the carbon content using alternative SCMs.</description>
      <author>Fengyin Du, Julien Hubert, Keshav Bharadwaj, Krishna Siva Teja Chopperla, Gopakumar Kaladaram, Jason H. Ideker, O. Burkan Isgor, W. Jason Weiss, Larry Sutter</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5399/osu/1179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current Status of Methane Emissions in China and Its Impact on Climate Change: Policy and Countermeasure Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2754-1169/2025.19636</link>
      <description>Shuo Li, Advances in Economics Management and Political Sciences. 133(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406035969

                Sources of methane emissions include agriculture, such as rice fields and livestock farming, energy production, such as natural gas and oil extraction, and waste disposal, such as landfills. As a potent greenhouse gas, methane has a more substantial short-term warming effect than carbon dioxide, so controlling methane emissions has become an essential goal of global climate action. Countries are reducing methane emissions through policies, regulations, and technical means. Research has found that methane emissions have significantly impacted China's climate system, leading to frequent extreme weather events and posing threats to ecosystems. The Chinese government has adopted emission reduction policies but faces challenges in policy implementation and technology application. This article uses a literature review to analyze the current status of methane emissions in China, analyze its impact on climate change, evaluate the effectiveness of current policies, and propose improvements. The technological obstacles to reducing methane emissions and the challenges in implementing policies are examined in this essay, which combines policy analysis with technical application discussions. This provides a new perspective for climate policy research, enriches the research content in greenhouse gas emission reduction, and offers solid theoretical support for the comprehensive governance framework for climate change response.</description>
      <author>Shuo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2754-1169/2025.19636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring pyrolysis and reduction behaviour of high-sulphur petroleum coke for disposal of Zn-containing dust</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233241307376</link>
      <description>Haiming Cheng, Weitong Du, Yao Tingfeng, Pu Guangqiang, Ju Dianchun, Zhuo Chen, Ironmaking &amp; Steelmaking Processes Products and Applications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406042534

                High-sulphur petroleum coke (HSPC), a significant byproduct of petroleum refining, has limited applications except as fuel for combustion. This study aims to expand its utility by investigating its efficacy as a reductant for disposing of Zn-containing dust, thereby substituting traditional coal-based reductants. The pyrolysis results showed that the gases generated from the pyrolysis of HSPC primarily comprised hydrogen gas (H 2 ), carbon monoxide (CO), methane and carbon dioxide. The reductant gases H 2 and CO accounted for above 90% of the total pyrolysis gas at 1200 &#176;C. The reduction reaction mechanism was elucidated by thermodynamic calculations and carbothermal experiments. At 800 &#176;C, ZnFe 2 O 4 is gradually decomposed into Fe 3 O 4 , FeO and ZnO, and Fe 2 O 3 is completely reduced to Fe 3 O 4 . At 900&#8211;1000 &#176;C, iron oxides are basically reduced to Fe, and ZnO is also reduced to Zn. Above 1100 &#176;C, CaMgSiO 4 as a slag phase is generated due to the combination of CaO, MgO and SiO 2 . At 1200 &#176;C, the roasting product with a metallic material is obtained, and the sulphur removal rate reaches 58%. This study provides valuable insights into the clean and efficient recovery and reuse of petroleum coke&#8211;coal, offering a promising avenue for sustainable resource management.</description>
      <author>Haiming Cheng, Weitong Du, Yao Tingfeng, Pu Guangqiang, Ju Dianchun, Zhuo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233241307376</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2&#8208;driven Oxygen Vacancy Diffusion and Healing on TiO2(110) at Ambient Pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420449</link>
      <description>Young Jae Kim, Hyuk Choi, Daeho Kim, Yongman Kim, Ki-Jeong Kim, Jeongjin Kim, G. Thornton, Hyun You Kim, Jeong Young Park, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069041

                Understanding how TiO2 interacts with CO2 at the molecular level is crucial in the CO2 reduction toward value&#8208;added energy sources. Here, we report in&#8208;situ observations of the CO2 activation process on the reduced TiO2(110) surface at room temperature using ambient pressure scanning tunneling microscopy. We found that oxygen vacancies (Vo) diffuse dynamically along the bridging oxygen (Obr) rows of the TiO2(110) surface under ambient CO2(g) environments. This physical phenomenon exclusively occurs when the oxygen abstracted upon CO2 dissociation instantly occupies the Vo sites of Obr rows on the TiO2(110), whereas the TiO2(110) surface without the Vo only allows CO2 physisorption on five&#8208;fold&#8208;coordinated Ti4+ sites. Synchrotron&#8208;based ambient pressure X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy also identifies the changes in surface oxidation states of TiO2(110) by the healing of Vo sites or the CO2 physisorption under ambient CO2(g) conditions. Density functional theory calculations propose a mechanism of the CO2&#8208;driven Vo diffusion and the physisorbed CO2 configurations. Our combined results unravel the critical role of defect sites on TiO2 in determining the elementary step of CO2 activation during chemical reactions.</description>
      <author>Young Jae Kim, Hyuk Choi, Daeho Kim, Yongman Kim, Ki-Jeong Kim, Jeongjin Kim, G. Thornton, Hyun You Kim, Jeong Young Park</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2&#8208;driven Oxygen Vacancy Diffusion and Healing on TiO2(110) at Ambient Pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420449</link>
      <description>Young Jae Kim, Hyuk Choi, Daeho Kim, Yongman Kim, Ki-Jeong Kim, Jeongjin Kim, G. Thornton, Hyun You Kim, Jeong Young Park, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069057

                Understanding how TiO2 interacts with CO2 at the molecular level is crucial in the CO2 reduction toward value&#8208;added energy sources. Here, we report in&#8208;situ observations of the CO2 activation process on the reduced TiO2(110) surface at room temperature using ambient pressure scanning tunneling microscopy. We found that oxygen vacancies (Vo) diffuse dynamically along the bridging oxygen (Obr) rows of the TiO2(110) surface under ambient CO2(g) environments. This physical phenomenon exclusively occurs when the oxygen abstracted upon CO2 dissociation instantly occupies the Vo sites of Obr rows on the TiO2(110), whereas the TiO2(110) surface without the Vo only allows CO2 physisorption on five&#8208;fold&#8208;coordinated Ti4+ sites. Synchrotron&#8208;based ambient pressure X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy also identifies the changes in surface oxidation states of TiO2(110) by the healing of Vo sites or the CO2 physisorption under ambient CO2(g) conditions. Density functional theory calculations propose a mechanism of the CO2&#8208;driven Vo diffusion and the physisorbed CO2 configurations. Our combined results unravel the critical role of defect sites on TiO2 in determining the elementary step of CO2 activation during chemical reactions.</description>
      <author>Young Jae Kim, Hyuk Choi, Daeho Kim, Yongman Kim, Ki-Jeong Kim, Jeongjin Kim, G. Thornton, Hyun You Kim, Jeong Young Park</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 mineralization in the production of sustainable concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7764/ric.00134.21</link>
      <description>Igor De la Varga, Yogiraj Sargam, Daniel Martins Alexio, Revista Ingenier&#237;a de Construcci&#243;n. 39(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406018863

                As the concrete industry continues to grapple with the challenge of reducing its carbon footprint, CO2 mineralization technologies offer a practical and scalable solution. These technologies enable the integration of CO2 as a valuable raw material, transforming waste emissions into durable mineral compounds during the concrete production process. This study investigates the implementation of CO2 mineralization in fresh concrete, analyzing its effects on key material properties such as strength and durability. Experimental results reveal that the process not only ensures equivalent compressive strength of concrete with a reduced cement content, but also contributes to reductions in embodied carbon compared to traditional methods. Furthermore, the study underscores the role of this approach in supporting the industry's decarbonization efforts, aligning with global sustainability goals. The findings highlight CO2 mineralization as a pivotal step toward the creation of more sustainable construction materials, offering both environmental and economic benefits. These conclusions demonstrate the transformative potential of this technology in advancing the sustainability of concrete production while addressing the pressing demand for eco-friendly construction practices.</description>
      <author>Igor De la Varga, Yogiraj Sargam, Daniel Martins Alexio</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7764/ric.00134.21</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Reaction Mechanism and Deactivation of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Assisted Propane Oxidative Dehydrogenation over VO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts: A Multiple Operando Spectroscopic Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04900</link>
      <description>Leon Schumacher, Kathrin Hofmann, Christian He&#223;, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405944424

                The CO2-assisted oxidative dehydrogenation (ODH) of propane is of great technical importance and enables the use (and thus removal from the atmosphere) of CO2, a greenhouse gas, in a value-adding process. Supported vanadium oxide (VOx) catalysts are a promising alternative to more active but toxic chromium oxide catalysts. Despite its common use, TiO2 has not been investigated as a support material for VOx in the CO2&#8211;ODH of propane. In this study, we elucidate the interaction between titania (P25) and vanadia in the reaction mechanism by analyzing the reaction network and investigating the catalyst using X-ray diffraction (XRD), multiwavelength Raman, UV&#8211;vis and diffuse reflectance IR Fourier transform (DRIFT) spectroscopy. Besides direct and indirect ODH reaction pathways, propane dry reforming (PDR) is identified as a side reaction, which is more prominent on bare titania. The presence of VOx enhances the stability and the selectivity toward propylene by participating in the redox cycle, activating CO2 and leading to a higher rate of regeneration. Additionally, VOx catalyzes the conversion of anatase to rutile, which facilitates CO2 activation, thereby leading to an encapsulation of vanadium. At higher loadings, reducible VOx oligomers are present on the surface, facilitating some PDR, but less than on bare P25. As the main deactivation mechanisms of the catalyst system, we propose the reduction of the titania lattice and the consumption of vanadium, while carbon formation appears to be less relevant. Our results highlight the importance of analyzing the CO2&#8211;ODH reaction network and applying a multispectroscopic approach to obtain a detailed mechanistic understanding of CO2-assisted propane ODH over supported VOx catalysts.</description>
      <author>Leon Schumacher, Kathrin Hofmann, Christian He&#223;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04900</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impacts of reduced ice sheets, vegetation, and elevated CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on future Arctic climates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/15230430.2024.2433860</link>
      <description>Katherine Power, Qiong Zhang, Arctic Antarctic and Alpine Research. 56(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406027986

                This study investigates the climatic response of the Arctic to key factors that could shape future climate scenarios: significantly reduced ice sheets, changes in vegetation, and elevated CO2 levels. Using the EC-Earth3.3 Earth system model (ESM), we explore the effects of these forcings under conditions reminiscent of the mid-Pliocene, a key reference for potential future warm climates. Our results reveal that the Arctic climate response varies significantly with different CO2 levels, primarily due to feedbacks involving sea ice and surface albedo. The effects of the reduced ice sheet are, in a pre-industrial CO2 environment (280 ppm), an Arctic warming of 2.4&#176;C. This is driven by substantial sea ice loss in the Barents Sea, which reduces surface albedo. Surprisingly, at 400 ppm CO2, Arctic warming incurred from the ice sheet reduction is lower than expected, at 1.9&#176;C, because sea ice loss is less pronounced compared to pre-industrial conditions, leading to smaller albedo changes. At 560 ppm, the warming is more substantial (2.9&#176;C) but still less than expected, largely due to the already reduced sea-ice extent at this high CO2 level. Vegetation changes further modulate Arctic climate dynamics. At 400 ppm CO2, the expansion of needleleaf evergreen trees decreases surface albedo, adding an additional 0.5&#176;C of warming. However, at 560 ppm CO2, the warming effect of vegetation growth was muted (0.3&#176;C) due to the development of a more diverse canopy with brighter deciduous species, which mitigates the albedo-driven warming. Our findings underscore the complex interplay between CO2 levels, sea ice, and vegetation in determining in Arctic climate dynamics. They highlight that the importance of maintaining CO2 levels at or below 400 ppm to moderate Arctic warming effectively. This study emphasizes the value of integrating paleoclimate insights into future climate projections and underscores the need for a more detailed examination of feedback mechanisms to enhance the robustness of climate models.</description>
      <author>Katherine Power, Qiong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/15230430.2024.2433860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate and performance-driven architectural floorplan optimization using deep graph networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1108/ecam-08-2024-1107</link>
      <description>Yang Yang, Huimin Luo, Mohammad Anvar Adibhesami, Engineering Construction &amp; Architectural Management. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405951886

                Purpose This study introduces a novel approach to generating and optimizing energy-efficient and climate-responsive architectural floorplans. Design/methodology/approach The DGraph-cGAN model utilizes advanced deep-learning techniques to produce diverse, realistic layouts that meet specific design constraints and functional requirements. Findings The results show significant energy savings (32.1% overall) across different building types and climate conditions, with reductions in energy use intensity, CO2 emissions and annual energy costs. Case studies demonstrate notable improvements in energy savings, CO2 emission reduction, daylight autonomy, thermal comfort and cost savings. Practical implications The DGraph-cGAN model has great potential for advancing architectural design optimization, with opportunities for further refinement and application in various contexts. Originality/value This study contributes to developing a novel approach to optimizing architectural floorplans using deep learning techniques. It provides a valuable tool for architects and designers to create energy-efficient, climate-responsive buildings.</description>
      <author>Yang Yang, Huimin Luo, Mohammad Anvar Adibhesami</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1108/ecam-08-2024-1107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive effects of salinity, redox, and colloids on greenhouse gas production and carbon mobility in coastal wetland soils</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0316341</link>
      <description>Nicholas Ward, Madison Bowe, Katherine A. Muller, Xingyuan Chen, Qian Zhao, Rosalie Chu, Zezhen Cheng, Thomas Wietsma, Ravi Kukkadapu, PLoS ONE. 19(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405910050

                Coastal wetlands, including freshwater systems near large lakes, rapidly bury carbon, but less is known about how they transport carbon either to marine and lake environments or to the atmosphere as greenhouse gases (GHGs) such as carbon dioxide and methane. This study examines how GHG production and organic matter (OM) mobility in coastal wetland soils vary with the availability of oxygen and other terminal electron acceptors. We also evaluated how OM and redox-sensitive species varied across different size fractions: particulates (0.45&#8211;1&#956;m), fine colloids (0.1&#8211;0.45&#956;m), and nano particulates plus truly soluble (&lt;0.1&#956;m; NP+S) during 21-day aerobic and anaerobic slurry incubations. Soils were collected from the center of a freshwater coastal wetland (FW-C) in Lake Erie, the upland-wetland edge of the same wetland (FW-E), and the center of a saline coastal wetland (SW-C) in the Pacific Northwest, USA. Anaerobic methane production for FW-E soils were 47 and 27,537 times greater than FW-C and SW-C soils, respectively. High Fe 2+ and dissolved sulfate concentrations in FW-C and SW-C soils suggest that iron and/or sulfate reduction inhibited methanogenesis. Aerobic CO 2 production was highest for both freshwater soils, which had a higher proportion of OM in the NP+S fraction (64&#177;28% and 70&#177;10% for FW-C and FW-E, respectively) and organic C:N ratios reflective of microbial detritus (5.3&#177;5.3 and 5.3&#177;7.0 for FW-E and FW-C, respectively) compared to SW-C, which had a higher fraction of particulate (58&#177;9%) and fine colloidal (19&#177;7%) OM and organic C:N ratios reflective of vegetation detritus (11.4 &#177; 1.7). The variability in GHG production and shifts in OM size fractionation and composition observed across freshwater and saline soils collected within individual and across different sites reinforce the high spatial variability in the processes controlling OM stability, mobility, and bioavailability in coastal wetland soils.</description>
      <author>Nicholas Ward, Madison Bowe, Katherine A. Muller, Xingyuan Chen, Qian Zhao, Rosalie Chu, Zezhen Cheng, Thomas Wietsma, Ravi Kukkadapu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0316341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Spatial Allocation of Pediatric Medical Facilities for Reduced Travel-Related CO2 Emissions: A Case Study in Tianjin, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/land14010071</link>
      <description>Haohao Dong, Haifeng Zhang, Rui Wang, Yutong Zhang, Yuxue Zhang, Lisha Zhang, Land. 14(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405989268

                Due to the limited availability of medical facilities and the urgency and irreplaceability of medical-seeking behaviors, the transportation processes used to access these resources inherently result in high carbon emissions. Unfortunately, pediatric medical facilities are among the least substitutable destinations, making it challenging to reduce travel-related CO2 emissions by traditional means such as decreasing travel frequency or optimizing transportation means. This study proposes enhancing the spatial allocation of pediatric medical facilities to effectively reduce travel-related CO2 emissions. This study selects 27 hospitals with pediatric departments in Tianjin as the research subject. It introduces a model for measuring travel-related CO2 emissions for pediatric medical-seeking, STIRPAT, and ridge regression models as well as conducts simulations under various scenarios to test the hypotheses. Therefore, methods for enhancing the spatial allocation of pediatric medical facilities are proposed. The results show that (1) travel-related CO2 emissions for pediatric medical-seeking are the highest in the city center, outpatient-related CO2 emissions surpass inpatient ones, and children&#8217;s hospital-related CO2 emissions are higher than those related to comprehensive hospitals, from which potential carbon reduction points can be explored; (2) children&#8217;s hospitals with multibranch and composite functional allocations can significantly reduce CO2 emissions; (3) comprehensive hospitals can further alleviate CO2 emissions from children&#8217;s hospitals by enhancing the medical level, transportation infrastructure, population distribution, and other spatial environmental factors; (4) from the perspective of low-carbon travel and equity, a spatial allocation strategy should be adopted for children&#8217;s hospitals that includes multiple branches and composite functions, while comprehensive hospitals should focus on service capacity, parity, supply&#8211;demand ratio, and the population density of children.</description>
      <author>Haohao Dong, Haifeng Zhang, Rui Wang, Yutong Zhang, Yuxue Zhang, Lisha Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/land14010071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilization of a mixture of tuff and dune sand for use in road construction in arid areas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46932/sfjdv5n12-073</link>
      <description>Akacem Mustapha, Bouragaa Kheira, Bennacer Lyacine, South Florida Journal of Development. 5(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406053347

                The materials constituting the pavement bodies, until today, have been limited to certain so-called noble materials (rolled sands, aggregates, etc.), but these are in the process of being exhausted under the effect of intensive exploitation and the scarcity of quality quarries. With the objective of preserving the deposits of aggregates in the process of exhaustion for future generations and of exploiting the aeolian sands in abundance in the regions of southern Algeria, we aim to enhance the latter in the body of the roadway mixed with the tuffs, this would imply a reduction in construction costs (use of local aggregates of lower quality available in large quantities, reduction in transport costs). From an environmental point of view, this would limit the impacts with a reduction in CO2 emissions linked to transport.</description>
      <author>Akacem Mustapha, Bouragaa Kheira, Bennacer Lyacine</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46932/sfjdv5n12-073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nonlinear Dynamics of CO2 Emissions in Pakistan: A Comprehensive Analysis of Transportation, Electricity Consumption, and Foreign Direct Investment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010189</link>
      <description>Muhammad Adeel, Biao Wang, Ji Ke, Israel Muaka Mvitu, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405945366

                CO2 emissions are major drivers of climate change, causing global warming, extreme weather, and biodiversity loss. They disrupt ecosystems, deplete resources, and threaten public health and economic stability. Reducing CO2 emissions is essential for climate stability and sustainability. This study explores the complex relationships between CO2 emissions and factors such as the transportation sector, electricity consumption, foreign direct investment (FDI), international trade, and gross domestic product (GDP). The focus is on small- and medium-sized enterprises (SME) in Pakistan. Using time series data from 2000 to 2022. This study applies advanced econometric techniques, including nonlinear autoregressive distributed lag (NARDL), dynamic ordinary least squares (DOLS), and fully modified ordinary least squares (FMOLS). The findings highlight that increased electricity consumption, international trade, transportation activities, and FDI contribute to higher CO2 emissions. However, FDI can also help reduce emissions, particularly through investments in green technologies. This study emphasizes the importance of transitioning to renewable energy and adopting sustainable practices across sectors such as electricity, trade, and transportation. Specifically, transportation and electricity consumption were found to significantly impact CO2 emissions, with a 10% increase in transportation activities resulting in a 5% rise in emissions. Conversely, FDI can reduce emissions by approximately 3% per unit of investment, largely due to green technology adoption. Additionally, integrating renewable energy and energy-efficient technologies in transportation can lead to a 20% reduction in emissions. Policymakers and experts must prioritize strategies that promote renewable energy adoption and integrate sustainable practices to reduce CO2 emissions and ensure long-term environmental sustainability. This research is innovative in its analysis of the interconnected effects of electricity consumption, trade, transportation, and FDI on CO2 emissions. By applying sophisticated econometric methods, it highlights the potential of FDI, particularly green investments, to mitigate environmental damage. This study, focusing on Pakistan, offers insights into how economic growth can be balanced with environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Adeel, Biao Wang, Ji Ke, Israel Muaka Mvitu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE ROLE OF EDUCATION IN REDUCING ENVIRONMENTAL POLLUTION: A REVIEW</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35631/ijmoe.622022</link>
      <description>Noor Zahirah Mohd Sidek, International Journal of Modern Education. 6(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405949340

                Environmental pollution is a major global challenge that can adversely affect ecosystems and human health. In developing countries, the lack of awareness and inadequate sustainable practices exacerbate pollution levels, making it imperative to identify long-term solutions. Here, education plays a crucial role in addressing this issue by raising environmental awareness, encouraging sustainable practices, and shaping policy reforms. Despite the importance of education in driving environmental change, the precise impact of education levels and expenditures on reducing pollution remains underexplored, especially in the ASEAN region. This paper addresses this issue by examining how education mitigates environmental pollution, focusing on both the level of education and expenditure on education. Using data from ten ASEAN countries covering the period from 1980 to 2022, this study employs three statistical methods&#8212;quantile regression (0.5), FMOLS, and Robust OLS&#8212;to analyze the relationship between education and CO2 emissions. The results consistently show a negative relationship between CO2 emissions and education, as measured by educational expenditure in primary, secondary, and tertiary education. These findings suggest that investing in education, regardless of the level, has a significant and direct impact on reducing CO2 emissions. By fostering a well-educated and environmentally aware population, ASEAN countries can achieve substantial reductions in CO2 emissions, contributing to global efforts to reduce environmental pollution.</description>
      <author>Noor Zahirah Mohd Sidek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35631/ijmoe.622022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for an extensive &#8710;&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; flask sample monitoring campaign over Europe to constrain fossil CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3013</link>
      <description>Carlos G&#243;mez-Ortiz, Guillaume Monteil, Ute Karstens, Marko Scholze, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405983454

                Abstract. During 2024, an intensive &#916;14CO2 flask sampling campaign is being conducted at 12 stations across Europe as part of the CO2MVS Research on Supplementary Observations (CORSO) project. These &#916;14CO2 samples, combined with CO2 atmospheric measurements, aim to improve fossil CO2 emission estimates across Europe through inverse modeling. In this study, we perform a series of Observing System Simulation Experiments (OSSEs) to assess the added value of this intensive campaign and explore different sampling strategies for optimizing fossil fuel emission estimates. The strategies focus on selecting samples for inversions based on their fossil CO2 and nuclear 14C composition. We evaluate three sampling approaches: (1) a base scenario using uniform sampling without specific selection criteria, comparing current methods with the addition of flask samples; (2) a strategy that selects samples with high fossil CO2 content; and (3) a combined approach that accounts for nuclear 14C contamination to reduce potential biases from nuclear facilities. Our results suggest that higher sampling density improves the accuracy of fossil CO2 estimates, especially during low-emission periods, such as summer. Increasing the number of samples reduces uncertainty, enhancing the robustness of inverse modeling outcomes. Selecting samples based on fossil CO2 contamination further refines the estimates, but the most significant uncertainty reduction occurs when nuclear contamination is also considered. This combined strategy effectively mitigates biases in regions with high nuclear activity, like France and the UK. These findings highlight the importance of increasing sampling frequency and strategically selecting samples to improve fossil fuel emission estimates across Europe.</description>
      <author>Carlos G&#243;mez-Ortiz, Guillaume Monteil, Ute Karstens, Marko Scholze</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GREEN ECONOMY: ECONOMETRIC ANALYSIS OF THE IMPLEMENTATION OF ECO-INNOVATIONS IN UKRAINE AND THE EU</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33111/sedu.2024.55.128.141</link>
      <description>Vladyslav Yaremenko, Strategy of Economic Development of Ukraine. None(55)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405917404

                In the article, the state and dynamics of eco-innovation development in Ukraine and the European Union (EU) countries are examined, focusing on comparing the two regions. In the context of growing environmental challenges, such as climate change, eco-innovations are essential for achieving sustainable development, reducing CO2 emissions, and enhancing economic efficiency. The EU demonstrates a high level of research and development (R&amp;D) investment and a transition to renewable energy sources. In Ukraine, there is a positive trend, although the pace of development is slower. The study conducts a regression analysis to determine the impact of R&amp;D expenditures, the share of renewable energy, and CO2 emission levels on the eco-innovation index, confirming the significance of emission reduction as a key factor in stimulating ecological innovations. The results highlight the need to improve Ukraine&#8217;s state policy in the field of ecoinnovations, taking into account the European experience.</description>
      <author>Vladyslav Yaremenko</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33111/sedu.2024.55.128.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techno-Economic Analysis of Heat Integrated Stripper Application in Chemical Absorption Process for Co2 Capture: Insights from Pilot Plant Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5079077</link>
      <description>Adam Tatarczuk, Marcin Szega, Tomasz Billig, L. Wi&#281;c&#322;aw&#8208;Solny, Janusz Zdeb, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405972458

                This paper presents a comprehensive techno-economic analysis of heat-integrated stripper (HIS) application in chemical absorption processes for CO2 capture, drawing insights from pilot plant studies and simulation analyses. Escalating concerns over carbon emissions prompts a growing interest in amine-based chemical absorption, a proven and promising technology not only for the power industry but also for sectors with hard-to-abate emissions, such as cement, metallurgy, refining, and fertilizer production. Additionally, it supports the capture of CO2 from biogenic carbon sources (BECCS).The HIS, integrating heat exchangers within the stripper offers a potential solution to alleviate energy demands. Pilot tests at TAURON Power Plants, using a mobile plant with a 1 TPD CO2 capture capacity, validated a 7% reduction in reboiler heat duty with HIS. Simulation analyses corroborated experimental findings, providing insights into gas-liquid phase behavior and desorption efficiency across the stripper.The economic evaluation revealed a 1.3% increase in initial capital costs, offset by 3.2% operational savings, suggesting a payback period of less than two years. By enhancing CO2 capture efficiency and reducing energy demand, HIS integration offers a practical pathway toward improving the sustainability and economic viability of carbon capture technologies, supporting the global transition to a net-zero energy future.</description>
      <author>Adam Tatarczuk, Marcin Szega, Tomasz Billig, L. Wi&#281;c&#322;aw&#8208;Solny, Janusz Zdeb</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5079077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the working process of a gas-diesel engine running on ammonia with the addition of hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17816/0321-4443-635228</link>
      <description>Yu. V. Galyshev, Luo Xinyao, Oleg Abyzov, Alexey Zaitsev, Tractors and Agricultural Machinery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405945700

                BACKGROUND: Ammonia, as a carbon-free fuel, has attracted much attention from researchers in different countries and is considered one of the promising alternative fuels that reduce greenhouse gas emissions. Despite the fact that the properties of ammonia have been widely studied, the practical application of this type of fuel remains difficult. Additional research is needed to overcome problems, including low combustion rate, high emissions of nitrogen oxides and unburned ammonia. To stimulate the combustion process in the cylinder, it is possible to use hydrogen additive as an activator of the combustion of the ammonia-air mixture. This article is aimed at a computational study of the effect of replacing diesel fuel with ammonia on the characteristics and harmful emissions of an internal combustion engine. AIM: Computational study of the working process and harmful emissions from exhaust gases of a motor-tractor dual-fuel engine when operating on ammonia with the addition of hydrogen. METHODS: The object of the study was a modern automobile and tractor diesel engine YaMZ-53415. The calculations were carried out for the nominal operating mode of the engine. For three-dimensional modeling of the working process of a gas-diesel engine running on ammonia with the addition of hydrogen, the Ansys Forte software package was used, which was developed based on modern theoretical concepts of the physics of three-dimensional gas and liquid flows, fuel spray dynamics and combustion processes. RESULTS: Calculation of the working process of a dual-fuel engine running on ammonia with different ignition doses of diesel fuel showed that when the dose of diesel fuel is reduced from 100% to 5%, the engine power and efficiency are maintained, the maximum pressure in the cylinder is reduced by 26%, nitrogen oxide emissions and the amount of unburned ammonia increase. Calculation of the working process of a dual-fuel engine running on ammonia with hydrogen additive allowed us to determine the minimum hydrogen additive that ensures complete combustion of ammonia. CONCLUSIONS: Running a dual-fuel engine on ammonia results in a significant reduction in carbon dioxide emissions, more than an order of magnitude, i.e. ammonia can become an alternative to hydrocarbon fuel to achieve carbon neutrality. The use of a small hydrogen additive &#8212; 0.4% allows to significantly increase the combustion rate of the ammonia-air mixture and ensures almost complete combustion of ammonia. Nitrogen oxide emissions when replacing diesel fuel with ammonia increase more than twice. To reduce them, it is necessary to use known methods - exhaust gas recirculation, SCR-neutralizer.</description>
      <author>Yu. V. Galyshev, Luo Xinyao, Oleg Abyzov, Alexey Zaitsev</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17816/0321-4443-635228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Correlations Between Various Drivers of Energy Demand in Post-Combustion Carbon Capture Retrofitted Power Plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering9010003</link>
      <description>Dalal Alalaiwat, Ezzat Khan, ChemEngineering. 9(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405992158

                Power plants are one of the main sources emitting the CO2 that is responsible for climate change consequences. Post-combustion carbon capture (PCC), particularly using an aqueous solution, is highly recommended to be used as a mitigation solution to reduce the emissions of CO2 from power plants. Although PCC is a promising solution, the process still needs further development to reduce the energy demand for solvent regeneration. This paper reviews the challenges related to the post-combustion processes and finds the correlations between selected variables addressed by several researchers. Moreover, this study provides valuable insights into the factors influencing the reduction in energy demand and efficiency penalties. The research findings highlight the importance of considering two key drivers during the design of the PCC process. These are the absorber temperature and the type and amount of the selected solvent. Indeed, statistical analyses show that there is a correlation between the identified drivers&#8217; values and the energy demand of solvent regeneration.</description>
      <author>Dalal Alalaiwat, Ezzat Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering9010003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle CO2 Emissions and Techno-Economic Analysis of Wood Pellet Production and CHP with Different Plant Scales and Sawdust Drying Processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010140</link>
      <description>Kenji Koido, Daichi Konno, Michio Sato, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405920559

                This study presents a life cycle assessment (LCA) and economic analysis of wood pellet production and utilisation in gasification combined heat and power (CHP) systems, focusing on optimising the drying process and evaluating the impacts of varying plant scales. In line with Japan&#8217;s target of achieving net-zero emissions by 2050, the research examines primary energy demand (PED), CO2 emissions, and financial viability across the wood pellet production (gate-to-gate) and CHP energy generation (gate-to-grave) stages. The results reveal that the drying process accounts for 35&#8211;39% of the total energy consumption in wood pellet production, with the heat source significantly influencing PED and CO2 emissions. Systems employing wood-fired boilers and wood pellet CHP for drying achieve reductions in PED by 12&#8211;26% and CO2 emissions by 14&#8211;31% compared to the conventional grid-supplied drying process. Economic analysis reveals that scaling up production enhances financial performance, with net income increasing by up to 20% and payback periods reducing to approximately 10 years in facilities producing 2.5 tons of wood pellets per hour. These findings highlight the critical role of optimised drying processes, plant scalability, and efficient supply chains in advancing sustainable wood pellet-based bioenergy systems that support Japan&#8217;s renewable energy targets.</description>
      <author>Kenji Koido, Daichi Konno, Michio Sato</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROSPECTS FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF HYDROGEN ENERGY: INNOVATIVE TECHNOLOGIES AS THE KEY TO REDUCING THE PRICE OF &#8220;GREEN&#8221; HYDROGEN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37128/2520-6168-2024-4-5</link>
      <description>S. Kravets, ENGINEERING ENERGY TRANSPORT AIC. None(4 (127))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405988033

                The article considers the prospects for the development of hydrogen energy, in particular, the application of hydrogen production technology based on water splitting using the latest electrolysis technologies. Particular attention is paid to the innovative methodology proposed by the Israeli company H2Pro, which promises a significant reduction in the cost of "green" hydrogen by 2030 to the level of less than $1 per kilogram. This reduction in hydrogen prices by 60-80% will make it more competitive in the energy market, which can lead to widespread adoption of hydrogen technologies in various sectors of the economy. The technology developed by H2Pro uses the E-TAC (Electrochemical Thermally Activated Chemical Water Splitting) method, which consists of a two-step process for the production of hydrogen and oxygen. The first stage involves cold electrochemical splitting of water, which generates hydrogen and oxidizes the anode, while the second stage, thermally activated, regenerates the anode by releasing oxygen, without the need for additional electricity consumption. This technology makes it possible to reduce energy costs and increase the efficiency of the process, reaching an efficiency of 95%, which is a significant achievement in the field of hydrogen energy. The author of the article also draws attention to the importance of this achievement for the global transition to renewable energy sources. In particular, reducing the cost of hydrogen production with the help of such technologies can provide cheaper energy production than traditional energy carriers such as gasoline and diesel, and also become a key factor in the implementation of ambitious environmental initiatives aimed at reducing carbon dioxide emissions. In addition to technological innovation, the article also discusses the need for infrastructure development for the storage, transportation and use of hydrogen, which remains one of the main barriers to its large-scale use. However, thanks to the efforts of companies such as H2Pro, which are actively working on improving production processes and reducing costs, hydrogen energy has a great chance of becoming an integral part of the energy system of the future. Thus, the development of hydrogen energy technologies, such as E-TAC, is an important step on the way to ensuring a clean and sustainable energy supply, which will contribute to reducing the environmental impact and ensuring the sustainable development of the world economy in the face of global climate change.</description>
      <author>S. Kravets</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37128/2520-6168-2024-4-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the value of CO2 shipping transport flexibility in international batchwise transportation carbon capture and storage networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5070419</link>
      <description>Denis Fraga, Anna Korre, Zhenggang Nie, &#350;evket Durucan, SSRN Electronic Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406028171

                The benefits of CO&#8322; shipping transport within international Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS) networks have been growing in importance as it offers flexibility and allows to postpone investment in capital-intensive infrastructure until enough CCS projects are launched. This work explores this value through a comparative cost assessment of 15 what-if scenarios devised for standalone and integrated CCS networks, designed around the Northern Lights project and the UK's Teesside cluster. The analysis is performed by implementing a Multi-period, Multi-mode, and Multi-objective Mixed integer linear programming (MoMilp) model developed at Imperial College London and considering all the elements of the CCS value chain after CO2 is captured (i.e. conditioning, intermediate storage and injection in the saline aquifer), allowing to account for individual regional characteristics in terms of design and network costs. The configurations of the different scenarios are used to analyse the implications of CCS network development hold up, e.g. for a part of the network to become available at a later period, or for the CO2 emission growth to occur at a later time in the planning horizon. The simulation results illustrate the interplay between postponing CCS network infrastructure investment and generating gains of scale in an existing network. This flexibility between CCS networks could provide relevant cost reduction while maximising the storage of CO2.</description>
      <author>Denis Fraga, Anna Korre, Zhenggang Nie, &#350;evket Durucan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5070419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology Adoption in the Power Sector: A Study of Recent Regulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5078735</link>
      <description>J&#233;r&#244;me Detemple, Yerkin Kitapbayev, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405979423

                This paper examines the effects of recent regulations (IRA) and proposals (EPA) pertaining to technology adoption in the power sector. We consider tax credits for carbon abatement, mandatory carbon capture and sequestration (CCS) equipment for gas plants and subsidies for carbon-free technologies. We quantify the impact on the optimal policies of a firm: the choice between carbon-intensive and Green technologies, the timing of investments, and the impact on CO2 emissions and welfare. Under the provisions of IRA, the likelihood of investing in wind generation increases, the likelihood of investing in CCS decreases, and emissions increase or decrease depending on prices. Implementing the EPA proposal instantaneously increases investment in CCS, but may result in increased emissions in the long run, depending on prices. Welfare improves under both regulations: negative effects on firm valuation and on society's cost of regulation are more than compensated by reductions in the social cost of carbon, even when low estimates of the social cost per ton of CO2 are used.</description>
      <author>J&#233;r&#244;me Detemple, Yerkin Kitapbayev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5078735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing the Synthesis for Perdeuterated Small Organic Chemicals via Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06353</link>
      <description>Bj&#248;rt &#211;lad&#243;ttir Joensen, Qiucheng Xu, Kasper Enemark&#8208;Rasmussen, Victoria L. Frankland, Arun Prakash Periasamy, John R. Varcoe, Ib Chorkendorff, Brian Seger, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406025115

                High deuteration yields are difficult to attain with conventional chemical synthesis methods. In this work, we demonstrate that deuterated chemicals can be produced using electrochemical CO2 reduction in the presence of D2O. The absence of H2O enables deuteration yields over 99% for products such as ethanol-d6 and formate-d. With a D2O solvent, the competing D2 evolution reaction is completely suppressed at low current densities while being kept &lt;10% at a higher 300 mA/cm2.</description>
      <author>Bj&#248;rt &#211;lad&#243;ttir Joensen, Qiucheng Xu, Kasper Enemark&#8208;Rasmussen, Victoria L. Frankland, Arun Prakash Periasamy, John R. Varcoe, Ib Chorkendorff, Brian Seger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design and Controlled Synthesis of MOF-Derived Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/accountsmr.4c00330</link>
      <description>Weibin Chen, Bingbing Ma, Ruqiang Zou, Accounts of Materials Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406065738

                ConspectusSingle-atom catalysts (SACs) represent a transformative advancement in heterogeneous catalysis, offering unparalleled opportunities for maximizing atomic efficiency and enhancing performance. SACs are characterized by isolated metal atoms uniformly dispersed on suitable supports, ensuring each metal atom serves as an independent catalytic site. This dispersion mitigates metal atom aggregation, a common issue in conventional nanocatalysts, thus enabling superior activity, selectivity, and stability. Metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) have emerged as an ideal platform for SAC synthesis due to their structural diversity, tunable coordination environments, and high surface areas. MOFs provide well-defined coordination sites that facilitate the precise stabilization of single metal atoms, presenting significant advantages over traditional supports like metal oxides and metal materials. Carbonization of MOFs yields MOF-derived carbon materials that retain key structural characteristics while offering enhanced electrical conductivity and stability, making them suitable for various catalytic applications.Recent advances in the rational design and controlled synthesis of MOF-derived SACs have significantly improved their performance in electrocatalytic processes such as the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). However, challenges remain, including maintaining structural integrity during high-temperature carbonization, enhancing mass and electron transport and ensuring the stability of isolated metal atoms under reaction conditions. To address these challenges, strategies such as using structure-directing agents to stabilize MOF frameworks, forming high-energy porous carbon networks, and optimizing support morphologies have been developed to maximize active site exposure and accessibility. On the other hand, the interplay between active metal sites and their coordination environments is crucial in determining the catalytic activity and selectivity of SACs. Advanced computational modeling, coupled with experimental validation, has provided insights into the electronic structure of SACs and the interactions between metal atoms and supports. These insights have enabled researchers to fine-tune local atomic coordination, leading to significant enhancements in performance. For instance, modifying the coordination environment of metal atoms optimizes the binding strength of reaction intermediates, thereby improving both activity and selectivity. This account highlights our group's contributions to MOF-derived SACs, focusing on innovative design, functionalization, and synthesis approaches that enhance catalytic activity. Notable strategies include using structure-directing agents to maintain pore connectivity during carbonization, preserving high surface areas, and enhancing mass transport. We also discuss the design of high-energy MOF-derived porous carbon networks that facilitate continuous electron transport and improve the interaction between active sites and reactants, ultimately boosting catalytic efficiency. Techniques such as electrospinning have also been employed to create hierarchical porous structures and one-dimensional nanofibers, enhancing mass transport and electron transfer. The rational design of SACs requires a comprehensive understanding of the microenvironment surrounding active sites, and by leveraging computational and experimental tools, researchers can precisely control these microenvironments to achieve desired outcomes.MOF-derived SACs hold substantial promise for energy conversion and chemical synthesis. Continued research is essential to optimize their design, improve scalability, and explore new applications, ultimately advancing sustainable catalysis. This account provides an overview of the latest advancements in MOF-derived SACs, highlighting their potential as next-generation electrocatalysts and their role in sustainable energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Weibin Chen, Bingbing Ma, Ruqiang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/accountsmr.4c00330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms and Production Enhancement Effects of CO2/CH4 Mixed Gas Injection in Shale Oil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010142</link>
      <description>Xiangyu Zhang, Qicheng Liu, Jieyun Tang, Xiangdong Cui, Shutian Zhang, Hong Zhang, Yinlong Lu, Xiaodong Dong, Hongxing Yan, Mingze Fu, Yuliang Su, Zheng Chen, Energies. 18(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405995356

                Shale oil, a critical unconventional energy resource, has received substantial attention in recent years. However, systematic research on developing shale oil using mixed gases remains limited, and the effects of various gas compositions on crude oil and rock properties, along with their potential for enhanced oil recovery, are not yet fully understood. This study utilizes PVT analysis, SEM, and core flooding tests with various gas mixtures to elucidate the interaction mechanisms among crude oil, gas, and rock, as well as the recovery efficiency of different gas types. The results indicate that increasing the mole fraction of CH4 substantially raises the oil saturation pressure, up to 1.5 times its initial value. Pure CO2, by contrast, exhibits the lowest saturation pressure, rendering it suitable for long-term pressurization strategies. CO2 shows exceptional efficacy in reducing interfacial tension, though the viscosity reduction effects of different gases exhibit minimal variation. Furthermore, CO2 markedly modifies the pore structure of shale through dissolution, increasing porosity by 2% and enhancing permeability by 61.63%. In both matrix and fractured cores, the recovery rates achieved with mixed gases were 36.9% and 58.6%, respectively, demonstrating improved production compared to single-component gases. This research offers a theoretical foundation and novel insights into shale oil development.</description>
      <author>Xiangyu Zhang, Qicheng Liu, Jieyun Tang, Xiangdong Cui, Shutian Zhang, Hong Zhang, Yinlong Lu, Xiaodong Dong, Hongxing Yan, Mingze Fu, Yuliang Su, Zheng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Carbon Reduction Benefits of Ecological Plastic Film Promotion and Use in Qingcheng Town, Shanxi Province</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010185</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Zhang, Xiaomeng Fang, Zhongliang Ge, Qi Zhang, Jiayu Xu, Jiaxing Zhao, Wanying Zhai, Jing Lv, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405944539

                This study applied a life cycle assessment (LCA) and SimaPro software to calculate the carbon footprint of ecological plastic film in Qingcheng Town. The results indicate that the carbon reduction efficiency of ecological plastic film compared to 0.01 mm PE film ranged from 30.8% to 40.0%, without accounting for the substitution of humus for chemical fertilizers. When humus substitution was considered, the range increased to 70.2% to 74.2%. Ecological plastic film achieved the greatest emission reduction in the final treatment stage, accounting for 54.1% of total CO2 reduction, followed by the production stage at 44.8%, while the transportation phase contributed only 1.1%. Projecting to 2030, if half of the cultivated land in Shanxi Province uses ecological plastic film instead of 0.01 mm PE film, a 19.7% reduction in carbon emissions is expected. Full coverage with ecological plastic film could raise this to 39.4%. To encourage its adoption, the study suggests that the government offers financial subsidies to enterprises or farmers, promotes agricultural carbon taxes, or supports carbon trading. With a carbon price or tax exceeding 67.1 CNY/t, ecological plastic film achieves cost parity with 0.01 mm PE plastic film.</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Zhang, Xiaomeng Fang, Zhongliang Ge, Qi Zhang, Jiayu Xu, Jiaxing Zhao, Wanying Zhai, Jing Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010185</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in low carbon emission cements for 3D printing a state-of-the-art review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7764/ric.00131.21</link>
      <description>Laura Silvestro, Rodrigo Scoczynski Ribeiro, Iv&#225;n Navarrete, Revista Ingenier&#237;a de Construcci&#243;n. 39(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406018913

                Concrete production, heavily reliant on Ordinary Portland Cement (OPC), is a significant contributor to global CO2 emissions, responsible for about 8% of human-related emissions. While past efforts to reduce the carbon footprint of cement focused on improving energy efficiency and incorporating supplementary cementitious materials (SCMs), recent innovations have shifted towards low-carbon binders like calcium sulfoaluminate (CSA) cement, limestone calcined clay (LC3) cement, and geopolymers. These alternatives offer considerable reductions in CO2 emissions during production. However, the adoption of these materials faces challenges, particularly in 3D-printed concrete (3DPC), an emerging construction method that demands specific rheological and mechanical properties. Research into these low-carbon binders shows that CSA cement provides rapid strength development, LC3 mixtures offer promising environmental benefits and structural integrity, and geopolymers achieve high compressive strength but require optimization for durability. This study summarizes a review of the effects of these binders on the fresh properties, mechanical performance, and durability of concrete, emphasizing their potential for use in 3DPC. The findings underscore the importance of optimizing material properties for enhanced performance and sustainability in the construction industry.</description>
      <author>Laura Silvestro, Rodrigo Scoczynski Ribeiro, Iv&#225;n Navarrete</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7764/ric.00131.21</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pollutant removal and greenhouse gas emissions in horizontal subsurface flow constructed wetlands with iron ore treating ammonium-rich wastewater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/09593330.2024.2443601</link>
      <description>Yan Zhang, LI Xin-hua, Hongyun Dong, Piet N.L. Lens, Environmental Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405935005

                Horizontal subsurface flow constructed wetlands (HFCWs) are capable of eliminating organic matter and nitrogen while emitting less methane (CH4) and nitrous oxide (N2O) than free water surface flow wetlands. However, the simultaneous removal of pollutants and reduction of greenhouse gases (GHG) emissions from high-strength wastewater containing high levels of organic matter and ammonium nitrogen (NH4+-N) has not get been investigated. The influent COD concentration affected the efficiency of nitrogen removal, GHG emissions and the presence of iron from iron ore, but the COD and TP removal efficiencies remained unaffected. CO2 and CH4 fluxes were significantly influenced by influent COD concentrations, whereas less N2O emissions were obtained during 7d. The highest CO2 and CH4 fluxes, along with the GHG emissions, were observed in HFCWs with COD concentrations of 375.6 mg/L and NH4+-N concentrations of 159.0 mg/L at a COD/N ratio of 2.4. Conversely, the lowest CH4 (&#8211;1.72 mg/m2/h) and N2O fluxes (0.13 mg/m2/h) were recorded in HFCWs with COD concentrations of 375.6 mg/L and NH4+-N concentrations of 162.4 mg/L at a COD/N of 4.5, although nitrogen removal was weak in these HFCWs. HFCWs at a COD/N ratio of 3.6 exhibited greater removal of nitrogen and other pollutants, along with a lower global warming potential (GWP). In conclusion, the concentrations of organic matter and NH4+-N in wastewater affected both pollutant removal and GHG emissions. The simultaneous enhancement of pollutant removal and the reduction of GHG emissions can be achieved in HFCWs with a COD/N ratio of 3.6.</description>
      <author>Yan Zhang, LI Xin-hua, Hongyun Dong, Piet N.L. Lens</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/09593330.2024.2443601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Framing Energy Sufficiency in a Swiss Mountain Resort</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010238</link>
      <description>Ivan Minguez, Tristan Loloum, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405942780

                This article analyses how energy sufficiency can be applied in tourism destinations. It begins by highlighting the importance of decarbonizing tourism for climate action, given the sector&#8217;s high CO2 emissions. Energy sufficiency, a key pillar of the energy transition, is defined as the voluntary reduction in energy demand within climate and CO2 emission constraints. The study investigates how stakeholders interpret and frame this concept, by focusing on strategies that align with the public image of the resort to reduce its energy requirements. The methodology includes semi-structured interviews with key players in Verbier&#8212;Val de Bagnes, focus groups with cooperation partners, participant observations at local meetings and events, and analysis of local documentation. Research was undertaken using living lab methods. The results reveal five main categories and eleven subcategories in which local stakeholders frame sufficiency, including oppositional framings, off-framings, selective framings, institutional framings, and disempowering framings. The article concludes with recommendations to reframe sufficiency in order to align with the destination&#8217;s strategy and representations. While energy sufficiency is often overshadowed by narratives of economic growth, technological innovation, and material abundance, it appears crucial to reframe these narratives and integrate post-growth strategies that prioritize sustainability in tourism planning.</description>
      <author>Ivan Minguez, Tristan Loloum</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010238</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrifying Public Transport Networks in Dubai</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1017/9781009471527.009</link>
      <description>Giovanna Potest&#224;, Mario Tartaglia, Cambridge University Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405970853

                This chapter explores the environmental benefits and social challenges for the city of Dubai's public transport network electrification plan. The Roads and Transport Authority (RTA) in Dubai is currently experimenting with the possibility of powering public buses with electric energy. The shift from fossil fuels to electric power has been experienced in many European cities with evidence of benefits for both the environment and citizens. The enhancement of public transport and the use of 'CO2-free' energy has made people less dependent on cars, reducing the amount of air pollution and easing traffic congestion on the roads. Air quality also improved significantly with direct and indirect results on people's health and life quality. In the pledge for a reduction of CO2 emissions, the coverage of the entire territory of Dubai with an interconnected transport system, fuelled by electric power, is an achievement to pursue. The authors show evidence of this statement using data collected from a number of European experiences. To simulate the feasibility of a similar model in Dubai, the authors consider different contextual situations, such as climatic variation, urban forms, and social and cultural characteristics of users, enhancing the specificities of present technological research in alternative energy sources. Electrified and hydrogen-fuelled vehicles are analysed and their potential and limitations explained based on data and tests conducted in Europe.</description>
      <author>Giovanna Potest&#224;, Mario Tartaglia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1017/9781009471527.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Ruthenium in Modified CeNi&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ru&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Perovskite Catalysts for the Bireforming of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04915</link>
      <description>Dunpin Hong, Ba Long, Ha Cam Anh, Tri Nguyen, L&#432;u C&#7849;m L&#7897;c, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405942973

                The study on modifying catalytic properties by partially substituting nickel with ruthenium on the perovskite precursor CeNiO3 has been conducted in this work. Catalysts were synthesized using a coprecipitation method, and their physicochemical properties were evaluated through analytical techniques, including X-ray diffraction (XRD), energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS), Brunauer&#8211;Emmett&#8211;Teller (BET) analysis, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM), H2 temperature-programmed reduction (H2-TPR), CO2 temperature-programmed desorption (CO2-TPD), and Raman spectroscopy. Additionally, thermogravimetric analysis coupled with differential scanning calorimetry (TGA-DSC) and XRD were employed to assess the carbon deposition and coke type on the catalyst after 100 h TOS. All ruthenium-modified CeNi1&#8211;xRuxO3 (x = 0.01, 0.05, and 0.10) catalysts showed good activity with CH4 and CO2 conversion rates exceeding 90% at 700 &#176;C. Ru modification facilitated the incorporation of Ni and Ru into the ceria lattice, resulting in the formation of Ru&#8211;O&#8211;Ce and Ni&#8211;O&#8211;Ce bonds, which significantly enhanced the catalyst's sintering resistance and Ni reducibility. Moreover, the Ru-modified catalyst exhibited a considerable increase in specific surface area, reduced Ni crystallite size, emergence of highly active basic sites, and an increase in oxygen vacancies. However, excessively loading Ru lowers the Ni dispersion, resulting in metal agglomeration and decreased catalytic activity. The optimal substitution ratio of Ru was determined to be 0.05. Catalyst CeNi0.95Ru0.05O3 showed the highest BRM activity with conversion of both CH4 and CO2 of approximately 95% at 700 &#176;C, compared to 88 and 90%, respectively, for CeNiO3 catalysts. The CeNi0.95Ru0.05O3 catalyst maintained good stability after 100 h of reaction with a 3 times lower coke accumulation rate compared to bare CeNiO3 perovskite. Thus, partially substituting Ru into the perovskite structure of CeNiO3 emerges as an effective strategy to improve the activity, durability, coke resistance, and sintering of the Ni catalyst in methane reforming reactions.</description>
      <author>Dunpin Hong, Ba Long, Ha Cam Anh, Tri Nguyen, L&#432;u C&#7849;m L&#7897;c</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Circular Nutrient Solution Management System Using a Cost Function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy15010051</link>
      <description>Yeong-Hyeon Shin, In-Su Kim, Myongkyoon Yang, Young-Kyun Jang, Ronaldo B. Saludes, Hak-Jin Kim, Woo-Jae Cho, Agronomy. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405934008

                In this study, an ion monitoring system using ion-selective electrodes (ISEs) was developed to maintain nutrient solutions in closed-loop hydroponic systems within plant factories. Based on this monitoring system, an algorithm and individual ion supplementation system were developed to calculate the optimal amounts of ion replenishment for crop growth. The developed algorithms adopt distinct cost functions to achieve their respective goals. The ion balance-prioritized algorithm minimizes the cost function, which is defined as the sum of the squared differences between the target ion concentrations and the calculated ion concentrations. In contrast, the carbon emission reduction algorithm minimizes the cost function defined as the total carbon emissions, which are calculated by multiplying the individual salt supplementation amounts by their respective carbon emission coefficients. Simulation results demonstrated that the ion balance-prioritized algorithm achieved average errors of 5.5 &#177; 5.5%, 0.4 &#177; 0.5%, and 5.0 &#177; 11.2% for Ca, NO3, and K, respectively, showing superior performance in maintaining ion balance. Meanwhile, the carbon emission reduction algorithm achieved a total of 0.064 kg CO2, representing a 50.19% reduction compared to the ion balance-prioritized type. The developed algorithms and system are expected to reduce costs by minimizing nutrient and water usage through the recycling of waste nutrient solutions. Furthermore, they are anticipated to improve crop productivity by maintaining an optimal ion composition and to contribute to sustainable agriculture through carbon emission reduction.</description>
      <author>Yeong-Hyeon Shin, In-Su Kim, Myongkyoon Yang, Young-Kyun Jang, Ronaldo B. Saludes, Hak-Jin Kim, Woo-Jae Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy15010051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Sr&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CoNbO&lt;sub&gt;6&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Sm&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;Ce&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;1.9&lt;/sub&gt; Composite Cathode to Enhance Oxygen Reduction Reaction and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Tolerance for the Application in Intermediate Temperature Solid Oxide Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02232</link>
      <description>Vicky Dhongde, Suddhasatwa Basu, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406048463

                Intermediate temperature (IT) solid oxide fuel cell (SOFC) development is hindered by slow oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and poor CO2 tolerance at the cathode electrode. Here, we present a successful synthesis of a composite cathode material consisting of double perovskite structure Sr2CoNbO6&#8722;&#948; (SCNO) and fluorite structure Sm0.2Ce0.8O2&#8722;&#948; (SDC), using one-pot synthesis method. Integrating SDC to form a composite SCNO&#8211;SDC substantially augments the number of active sites, resulting in high ORR activity and lower polarization resistance. Forming a tight, coherent interface structure between SCNO and SDC particles is advantageous in reducing the thermal expansion coefficient and significantly improving the oxygen ion transport by creating a 3D pathway through the self-assembled growth of SDC particles. At 700 &#176;C, the SOFC (full cell) utilizing SCNO&#8211;SDC composite cathode exhibits a peak power density (PPD) of 0.786 W cm&#8211;2, surpassing the PPD of 0.602 W cm&#8211;2 attained by the SCNO alone. Furthermore, upon exposure to CO2, SCNO&#8211;SDC demonstrated remarkable performance recovery and tolerance. This study offers insights into the cathode material functioning of IT-SOFCs with enhanced electrochemical performance and long-term stability.</description>
      <author>Vicky Dhongde, Suddhasatwa Basu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prospects of Attaining Thailand&#8217;s Carbon Neutrality Target Through Carbon Capture and Storage by Public Power Utility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010276</link>
      <description>Waranya Thepsaskul, Wongkot Wongsapai, Tassawan Jaitiang, Panuwich Jaekhajad, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405993147

                Thailand has committed to achieving carbon neutrality by 2050, targeting the power generation sector, which contributes 35% of the country&#8217;s CO2 emissions, as a critical area for intervention. This study explores the transition toward carbon neutrality in power generation, focusing on fossil-fuel-based plants, particularly lignite and natural gas, which remain central to Thailand&#8217;s electricity production. A key strategy adopted by the Electricity Generating Authority of Thailand (EGAT) is &#8220;Sink Co-creation&#8221;, which includes the deployment of Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS) technologies in existing and future lignite power plants, leveraging favorable storage conditions. Additionally, natural gas power plants exhibit significant CCS potential through source&#8211;sink matching mechanisms. This study finds that the total greenhouse gas (GHG) emission reductions from fossil-fuel-based power plants could reach 17.07 MtCO2. Of this total, lignite power plants are projected to achieve a reduction of 3.79 MtCO2 by 2036, while natural gas power plants are expected to contribute an additional 13.28 MtCO2 in reductions by 2050. However, the realization of these reductions faces significant challenges, including the high costs associated with CCS implementation and limited investor interest, underscoring the critical need for sustained government support and policy incentives to facilitate progress toward carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Waranya Thepsaskul, Wongkot Wongsapai, Tassawan Jaitiang, Panuwich Jaekhajad</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techniques for Determining Both the Indoor Pm2.5 Generation Rate and Non-Ventilation Removal Rate for Estimating Pm2.5 Concentrations in Classrooms Installed with Fresh Air Units</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5078995</link>
      <description>Chun&#8208;Yu Chen, C.L. Hsu, Gurumurthy Ramachandran, Thanawat Khajonklin, Chungsik Yoon, Perng-Jy Tsai, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405960247

                The fresh air unit (FAU) is one of control measures for reducing PM2.5 exposure for children in classrooms. Considering the fluctuations of ambient PM2.5 and varying classroom activities, traditional monitoring methods may be impractical for assessing long-term indoor PM2.5 levels. A well-mixed room modeling approach may offer a solution if the indoor PM2.5 generation rate (G) and non-ventilation removal rate (K) can be determined. This study develops a technique for quantifying both the G and K for classrooms equipped with FAUs. A typical elementary school classroom, installed with two FAUs and four electric fans, was selected to simultaneously monitor PM2.5 and CO2 concentrations both inside and outside the classroom. Significant reductions in indoor PM2.5 concentrations were observed. Although indoor CO2 levels exceeded outdoor levels, it remained well below the WHO's recommended limit. The first-order Runge-Kutta method and an iterative approach were adopted for determining G and K. The present study yielded G (GM (GSD)) as 10.7(2.1) and 19.2(1.2) &#181;g/min respectively for lecture sessions and noon rest periods, and K consistently as 0. No significant differences were found between measured and predicted PM2.5 levels further supporting the appropriateness of the developed approach for quantifying PM2.5 concentrations in classrooms equipped with FAUs.</description>
      <author>Chun&#8208;Yu Chen, C.L. Hsu, Gurumurthy Ramachandran, Thanawat Khajonklin, Chungsik Yoon, Perng-Jy Tsai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5078995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Applying Composts' Biochar for Gas Adsorption- Effect of Pyrolysis Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5081115</link>
      <description>Sylwia Stegenta-D&#261;browska, Martin Galik, Magdalena Bednik, Ewa Sygu&#322;a, Katarzyna E. Kosiorowska, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406025910

                Not all compost produced meets established quality standards, which can lead to environmental challenges. This study explores the compost, as a feedstock for biochar production. Mature compost was utilized as a substrate, and the pyrolysis process involved heating samples within a temperature range of 400-650 &#176;C, at 50 &#176;C intervals, with heating rates of 10 &#176;C&#183;min&#8315;&#185;, 15 &#176;C&#183;min&#8315;&#185;, or 20 &#176;C&#183;min&#8315;&#185; for a duration of 60 minutes. The resultant biochars were exposed to a gas mixture analogous to composting gas (CO2, CO, H2S, NH3, CH4 in N2).Our findings reveal a significant correlation between pyrolysis temperature and the sorption characteristics of compost-derived biochars. Specifically, biochars produced at temperatures of 550 &#176;C, 600 &#176;C, and 650 &#176;C (with a heating rate of 10 &#176;C&#183;min&#8315;&#185;) demonstrated the highest efficacy in reducing emissions of CO2, CH4, and H2S, achieving reductions of 69%, 69%, and 72%, respectively. In contrast, the performance of these biochars for CO and NH3 adsorption was comparatively lower. Notably, biochars produced at 400 &#176;C and 450 &#176;C exhibited enhanced adsorption properties for CO emissions.This study underscores the substantial potential of compost-derived biochar for gas adsorption applications. However, due to its marked capacity for CH4 sorption, it is more likely to serve in mitigating emissions during composting rather than for biogas purification.</description>
      <author>Sylwia Stegenta-D&#261;browska, Martin Galik, Magdalena Bednik, Ewa Sygu&#322;a, Katarzyna E. Kosiorowska</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5081115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloroplast genome editing of Rubisco boosts photosynthesis and plant growth</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.02.631008</link>
      <description>Wataru Yamori, Issei Nakazato, Yuchen Qu, Yukina Sanga, Tomoko Miyata, Ryo Uehara, Yuma Noto, Keiichi Namba, Hiroshi Fukayama, Hiroyoshi Matsumura, Shin&#8208;ichi Arimura, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406023239

                Photosynthetic inefficiencies limit the productivity and sustainability of crop production and the resilience of agriculture to future societal and environmental challenges. Ribulose-1,5-bisphosphate carboxylase/oxygenase (Rubisco) has inherently low catalytic efficiency, making it a key target for photosynthesis and crop improvement. However, introducing mutations to the chloroplast-encoded Rubisco large subunit (rbcL), which contains the enzyme's catalytic sites, is technically challenging. In this study, we successfully generated a range of chloroplast-genome-edited Arabidopsis thaliana plants targeting rbcL by a targeted base editor, ptpTALECD. The M309I and D397N substitutions in rbcL resulted in an increased Rubisco catalytic rate (kcat) without any reductions of Rubisco content, thereby enhancing photosynthetic rates and plant growth under both current atmospheric CO2 concentrations (i.e., 381 &#956;mol mol&#8722;1) and projected future concentrations (i.e., 549 &#956;mol mol&#8722;1). Cryo-electron microscopy (cryo-EM) structural analysis showed that the M309I and D397N substitutions, although located far from the catalytic site, induce structural alterations in the catalytic (60s) loops. Our findings highlight the potential of Rubisco engineering to improve plant photosynthesis and growth, and underscore the unique opportunities that chloroplast genome editing offers for enhancing photosynthesis and crop productivity and reducing atmospheric CO2 levels in a non-GMO context.</description>
      <author>Wataru Yamori, Issei Nakazato, Yuchen Qu, Yukina Sanga, Tomoko Miyata, Ryo Uehara, Yuma Noto, Keiichi Namba, Hiroshi Fukayama, Hiroyoshi Matsumura, Shin&#8208;ichi Arimura</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.02.631008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Investigations on Accelerated Solar Evaporation for Management of Concentrated Saline Liquor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34314/xad6dq57</link>
      <description>V. Veeravel, Gajendren Sathish, Nishanthi Rajendiran, S. V. Srinivasan, Journal of the American Leather Chemists Association. 120(01)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405989500

                Solar energy is an important energy sector that plays a crucial role in reducing greenhouse emission in different industrial sectors, including the leather sector, to control the pollution. Stringent environmental regulations of Zero Liquid Discharge (ZLD) in Indian tanneries are implemented as directed by regulatory authorities. The ZLD system resulted in the generation of saline rejected from membrane systems being evaporated by spending considerable energy. In this paper, the potential of solar energyfor evaporation of reject from ZLD in a closed accelerated solar dryer has been investigated. In this study, the evaporation of reject/ saline water using a solar dryer with different volumes has been experimented and the volume reduction and increase in Total Dissolved Solids (TDS) are monitored during the drying period. It is evident that the closed accelerated solar dryer has shown an increase in evaporation rate with reduction in the volume of water in a given area. The outcome of this study would lead to avoidance of mechanical evaporators in case of smaller capacity ZLD plants and also reduce the amount of water to be evaporated in the Multiple Effect Evaporator (MEE) in case of larger ZLD plants. By the application of the accelerated solar dryer for the evaporator, the potential CO2 emission reduction due to replacement of different fuels used for evaporation of reject has been estimated to reduce the carbon footprint and to ensure the sustainability of the leather industry.</description>
      <author>V. Veeravel, Gajendren Sathish, Nishanthi Rajendiran, S. V. Srinivasan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34314/xad6dq57</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of a diesel engine performance and emission using biogas in dual fuel mode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31603/mesi.11407</link>
      <description>Amar Kumar Das, Manas Ranjan Padhi, Debashree Debadatta Behera, Shiv Sankar Das, Mechanical Engineering for Society and Industry. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405903110

                Environmental pollution and the gradual depletion of fossil fuels have recently shifted the focus to alternate fuels. Hence, more diversified research on alternate fuels is necessary to deal with the global energy crisis. Biogas extracted from biomass is an excellent alternative to fossil fuels due to its low cost and good mixing ability. It is mainly generated by anaerobic digestion of organic waste products in a digester tank. The present paper investigates the performance and emission characteristics of diesel engine in dual fuel mode with biogas as main fuel and diesel as pilot fuel without any engine modification. The main aspect of the paper is to critically study the effect of supplementation of biogas on diesel engine efficiency and emission level of important constituent gases such as CO2 and NOX. Our findings demonstrate that the essential performance result of engine, such as Brake Thermal Efficiency (BTE) and Mechanical Efficiency for the biogas-air mixture of 20% (DB20), was slightly decreased. At the same time, there was a reduction in brake-specific fuel consumption (BSFC) compared to pure diesel. Furthermore, the exhaust emission of NOX and CO2 was lowered when the engine was operated in dual fuel induction mode. The results of engine performance were found to be better than the results of other researchers for engines of same specifications and operating conditions. Hence, biogas serves as a viable alternative fuel and contributes to cleaner combustion, offering a promising solution for reducing the environmental impact of diesel engines. The study provides critical insights into optimizing dual fuel systems for enhanced performance and sustainability.</description>
      <author>Amar Kumar Das, Manas Ranjan Padhi, Debashree Debadatta Behera, Shiv Sankar Das</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31603/mesi.11407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable broadcasting in Blockchain Network with Reinforcement
  Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.15616</link>
      <description>Danila Valko, Daniel Kudenko&#8902;, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406073343

                Recent estimates put the carbon footprint of Bitcoin and Ethereum at an average of 64 and 26 million tonnes of CO2 per year, respectively. To address this growing problem, several possible approaches have been proposed in the literature: creating alternative blockchain consensus mechanisms, applying redundancy reduction techniques, utilizing renewable energy sources, and employing energy-efficient devices, etc. In this paper, we follow the second avenue and propose an efficient approach based on reinforcement learning that improves the block broadcasting scheme in blockchain networks. The analysis and experimental results confirmed that the proposed improvement of the block propagation scheme could cleverly handle network dynamics and achieve better results than the default approach. Additionally, our technical integration of the simulator and developed RL environment can be used as a complete solution for further study of new schemes and protocols that use RL or other ML techniques.</description>
      <author>Danila Valko, Daniel Kudenko&#8902;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.15616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syngas Production Improvement from CO2RR Using Cu-Sn Electrodeposited Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18010105</link>
      <description>D. Herranz, Santiago Bernedo Biriucov, A. Arranz, Juan Ram&#243;n Avil&#233;s&#8208;Moreno, P. Oc&#243;n, Materials. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405948710

                Electrochemical reduction of CO2 is an efficient and novel strategy to reduce the amount of this greenhouse-effect pollutant gas in the atmosphere while synthesizing value-added products, all of it with an easy synergy with intermittent renewable energies. This study investigates the influence of different ways of combining electrodeposited Cu and Sn as metallic elements in the electrocatalyst. From there, the use of Sn alone or with a small amount of Cu beneath is investigated, and finally, the best catalyst obtained, which has Sn over a slight Cu layer, is evaluated in consecutive cycles to make an initial exploration of the catalyst durability. As a result of this work, after optimization of the Sn and Cu-based catalysts, it is possible to obtain more than 60% of the organic products of interest, predominantly CO, the main component of syngas. Finally, this great amount of CO is obtained under low cell potential (below 3 V), which is a remarkable result in terms of the cost of the process.</description>
      <author>D. Herranz, Santiago Bernedo Biriucov, A. Arranz, Juan Ram&#243;n Avil&#233;s&#8208;Moreno, P. Oc&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18010105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu&#8211;Co/In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Bimetallic Catalysts for Improved Methanol Synthesis: Synergistic Effect in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05059</link>
      <description>Zepu Jin, Likang Wang, Junxin Guo, Ziheng Li, Ziyan Liu, Zhao Wang, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406051687

                In this study, Cu&#8211;Co/In2O3 bimetallic catalysts were prepared by using a deposition precipitation method. The strong hydrogen dissociation ability of Cu decreased the reduction temperature of CoO to Co, thereby promoting the formation of the Cu&#8211;Co alloy. The interaction between Cu and Co led to electron transfer from Cu to Co, which effectively inhibited the formation of the harmful Cu&#8211;In alloy and facilitated the generation of oxygen vacancies in In2O3. The presence of abundant oxygen vacancies in Cu&#8211;Co/In2O3 increased CO2 adsorption and promoted the conversion of the methanol intermediate HCOO* to CH3O*. The Cu&#8211;Co/In2O3 catalyst exhibited 10.2% conversion and 72% methanol selectivity at 300 &#176;C and 5 MPa, which was higher than those of the monometallic catalyst Cu/In2O3 and Co/In2O3.</description>
      <author>Zepu Jin, Likang Wang, Junxin Guo, Ziheng Li, Ziyan Liu, Zhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STRATEGI PENGELOLAAN SAMPAH KOTA PALEMBANG UNTUK MENDUKUNG NET ZERO EMISSION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36982/jops.v1i2.4676</link>
      <description>Tuti Alawiyah, Journal of Plano Studies.. 1(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405953066

                The issue of climate change is a global concern, with a focus on reducing greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Indonesia, under the Paris Agreement, has set targets to reduce emissions by 29% independently and 41% with international support by 2030. At the local level, Palembang faces challenges in waste management, contributing to methane emissions, a GHG with 28 times the global warming potential of CO2. Although waste is not the largest source of emissions, Palembang, with over 1.6 million residents, must address this issue. This study analyzes GHG emission projections in Palembang&#8217;s waste management sector under different scenarios and offers policy recommendations for local authorities. Using the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) model, along with primary and secondary data, the results suggest that the most effective scenario for reducing emissions is a zero-landfill approach with full implementation of the 3R (Reduce, Reuse, Recycle) concept. Projections show that this scenario could reduce emissions by 64% by 2030 and 71% by 2045 compared to the baseline. Prioritizing waste management with the 3R concept and waste sorting at the source is essential to meet emission reduction goals. This paper also recommends integrating waste reduction targets into regional planning and assessing financial capacity to support thermal waste treatment technology as a sustainable urban waste management solution.</description>
      <author>Tuti Alawiyah</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36982/jops.v1i2.4676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Various Foaming Agents on Ceramic Foam from Solid Waste</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15010032</link>
      <description>Chenglin Zhao, Chunmin Wang, Z. Xia, Congcong Jiang, Yiran Dong, Zhiguo Lan, Crystals. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405927356

                Due to the significant amount of solid waste generated annually in China, the rational use of these wastes has become increasingly important. The production of foam ceramics is considered an effective method for the large-scale utilization of such solid waste. In this study, granite sawing mud was selected as the raw material, with SiC and MnO2 serving as foaming agent to prepare foam ceramics. The foaming behavior of sintered samples using different foaming agent was investigated to determine the most suitable type and amount of foaming agent for obtaining foam ceramics with excellent pore structures. Additionally, the effects of the foaming agent on the pore structure and physical mechanical properties of the foam ceramics were studied in detail. The results showed that SiC and MnO2 both resulted in the pronounced expansion to different extent, and increasing the content of foaming agent enhances foam expansion. The best dosage of SiC was 1%, the optimum additive amount of MnO2 is 2&#8211;3%. For SiC, the oxidation reduction reaction occurred between SiC and O2 to generate CO2/CO. For MnO2, firstly, the reduction of MnO2 to Mn2O3 occurred, and then the Mn2O3 dissolved in the glass melt and, subsequently, Mn3+ was reduced to Mn2+, leading to gas formation and foaming. Under the same dosage of foaming agent and preparation conditions, the sample prepared with SiC as the blowing agent has higher compressive strength, lower water absorption, and a more uniform pore structure.</description>
      <author>Chenglin Zhao, Chunmin Wang, Z. Xia, Congcong Jiang, Yiran Dong, Zhiguo Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15010032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Electrocatalytic Activity in Cu Nanoclusters: Interplay between Structural Confinement and Ligands Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mj882</link>
      <description>Sourav Biswas, Yamato Shingyouchi, Maho Kamiyama, Milan Kumar Jena, Masaki Ogami, Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Biswarup Pathak, Yuichi Negishi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405954375

                Ligand-protected copper nanoclusters (Cu NCs) with atomic precision have emerged rapidly due to their fascinating structural architectures and versatile catalytic properties, making them ideal for investigating structure&#8211;activity relationships. Despite their potential, challenges such as stability issues and limited structural diversity have restricted deeper exploration. In this study, three distinct Cu NCs were synthesized using a one-pot reduction strategy by carefully modifying reaction conditions. Intriguingly, the same p-toluenethiol ligand produced two different geometries, while varying ligand with m-aminobenzethiol&#8212;yielded clusters with similar geometric architectures. These NCs were evaluated for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction, uncovering diverse catalytic activities and product selectivity. Experimental and theoretical analyses revealed that the interplay between the core structure confinement and surface ligand environment governs their catalytic behavior. Specifically, the Cu11 NC with p-toluenethiol ligand exhibited selectivity toward HCOOH production (FEHCOOH~45% at -1.2 V vs. RHE), whereas substituting p-toluenethiol with m-aminobenzethiol shifted the selectivity to the competitive side reaction (FEH2~82% at -1.2 V vs. RHE). Conversely, altering the geometry of Cu18 NC while retaining the p-toluenethiol ligand decreased such selectivity (FEHCOOH~35% at -1.2 V vs. RHE). These findings highlight the tunability of Cu NCs for tailored catalytic applications through precise control of their structure and surface chemistry.</description>
      <author>Sourav Biswas, Yamato Shingyouchi, Maho Kamiyama, Milan Kumar Jena, Masaki Ogami, Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Biswarup Pathak, Yuichi Negishi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mj882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Transformation Within the Framework of Sustainable Development and Consumer Behavior</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010075</link>
      <description>Anna Szel&#261;g-Sikora, Aneta Oleksy-G&#281;bczyk, J&#243;zef Ciu&#322;a, Mariusz Cembruch-Nowakowski, Katarzyna Peter-Bombik, Paulina Rydwa&#324;ska, Tomasz Zac&#322;ona, Energies. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405974098

                The energy transition currently defines the economic development of all market sectors, driven by technological progress and increasing environmental awareness. The requirements of a sustainable economy and green energy are evolving dynamically to address environmental challenges, emphasizing the reduction of CO2 emissions as well as energy efficiency and renewable energy sources. It is essential to study consumer attitudes toward products manufactured using green energy, including FMCG (fast-moving consumer goods) products. The aim of this article is to examine the impact of the energy transformation, and consequently rising energy costs, on the decision-making process of consumers of FMCG products produced in accordance with the principles of sustainable development (including green energy). It explores the factors influencing their purchasing decisions and the role that generation plays in this process. Understanding how different generations respond to the energy aspects of economic functioning is crucial for the future development of the energy sector and the implementation of sustainable economic models. Therefore, it is essential to conduct research that demonstrates the extent of the influence of increasing consumer awareness of energy transformation within the framework of sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Anna Szel&#261;g-Sikora, Aneta Oleksy-G&#281;bczyk, J&#243;zef Ciu&#322;a, Mariusz Cembruch-Nowakowski, Katarzyna Peter-Bombik, Paulina Rydwa&#324;ska, Tomasz Zac&#322;ona</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The incoherence of emissions accounting principles and &lt;i&gt;Net-Zero&lt;/i&gt; targets in the buildings sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/14693062.2024.2446521</link>
      <description>Bashar Al Shawa, Climate Policy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405994436

                The buildings sector's energy demand and CO2 emissions are rising despite various energy standards and carbon disclosure initiatives. Drawing from the author's experience as the former buildings sector lead at the Science Based Targets initiative (SBTi), this paper investigates the suitability of the initiative's methodology and workflow for decarbonizing the sector. The paper demonstrates the incompatibility of current emissions accounting principles with the buildings sector and how this allowed companies to 'artificially' achieve emissions-reduction targets without tangibly improving the environmental performance of buildings. Given the sector's limited share of renewable energy, the paper critiques the initiative's disregard of buildings energy demand and questions how 'science-based' its interpretation of Net-Zero is. The paper introduces an alternative proposal whereby energy efficiency targets for buildings are derived from that share and, to be 1.5&#176;C-aligned, companies within the sector must demonstrate that buildings they own, finance, or design comply with these targets.</description>
      <author>Bashar Al Shawa</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/14693062.2024.2446521</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceria-based redox materials for thermochemical looping fuel generation: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/15435075.2024.2445091</link>
      <description>Deepak Sachan, Sujit Y. Pimple, Randhir Singh, International Journal of Green Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406025477

                The world needs alternative energy sources due to the aggravating problem of global warming with the use of fossil fuels. Thermochemical routes utilizing thermal energy, appears to be a promising method for splitting H2O/CO2 into green fuels such as H2/CO with the help of a redox mediator/oxygen carrier (OC). This review focuses on one of the most promising OC, ceria, as a redox material due to its exceptional thermal stability at elevated temperatures and rapid reaction kinetics. The influence of various parameters, such as reduction (TR), oxidation temperature (TO), and the difference (&#916;T= TR-TO) during the ceria-based thermochemical cycling process was analyzed utilizing data in open literature from 2006 onward. The discussion encompasses the impact of these parameters on fuel yield, oxygen yield, and fuel to oxygen yield ratio. Introduction of a novel reactor train system (RTS) combined with oxygen pumping is found to enhance thermal-to-fuel efficiency to an impressive 40%, marking a significant advancement in the field.</description>
      <author>Deepak Sachan, Sujit Y. Pimple, Randhir Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/15435075.2024.2445091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Assessment of Mine Water Resource Utilization in China: A Case Study of Xiegou Coal Mine in Shanxi Province</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010229</link>
      <description>Xuan Wang, Chi Zhang, Jin Yuan, Xin Sui, Di Su, Haoyu Wang, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405921753

                Climate change and water scarcity are two global challenges. Coal mining is the main source of carbon emissions. The utilization of mine water resources and its carbon footprint calculation are of paramount significance in promoting water conservation and carbon reduction in mining areas. However, research on the carbon footprint and other environmental indicators across the life cycle of mine water in developing countries, such as China, remains limited. This study focuses on a representative mine water resource utilization system in China and describes the method used to calculate carbon emissions associated with mine water resource utilization throughout its life cycle. Based on life cycle assessment (LCA) and using on-site investigations and analysis of environmental indicators, the study evaluates the environmental impacts at different stages of mine water resource utilization, identifies key processes, and provides some improvement suggestions. The research results indicate that the life cycle carbon emissions of mine water amount to 2.35 kg CO2 eq per 1 m3. The water extraction stage highlights the potential environmental impact, including water use (WU) and ozone depletion potential (ODP). By substituting traditional power generation methods and incorporating intelligent dosing equipment to optimize chemical usage, the global warming potential (GWP) has been decreased by over 90%, and the GWP of chemical consumption has also witnessed respective reductions of 21.5% and 10.1%. This study can serve as a basis for calculating carbon emissions in mining areas and formulating strategies to reduce their environmental impact.</description>
      <author>Xuan Wang, Chi Zhang, Jin Yuan, Xin Sui, Di Su, Haoyu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the effect of the Common Agricultural Policy post-2020 using an agent-based model based on PMP methodology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36253/bae-14592</link>
      <description>Lisa Baldi, Sara Calzolai, Filippo Arfini, Mich&#232;le Donati, Bio-based and Applied Economics. 13(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405947259

                The objective of this study is to perform an ex-ante assessment of the potential impacts of agro-environmental measures included in the post-2020 Common Agricultural Policy (CAP), by estimating farmers&#8217; responsiveness in adopting organic agricultural practices and an eco-scheme that incentivises extensive forage systems. This research is conducted by means of an Agent-Based Model (ABM), based on Positive Mathematical Programming (PMP), implemented in GAMS. The ABM facilitates the simulation of interaction among farmers, allowing for an analysis of farm heterogeneity. The PMP methodology adds a non-rational dimention to the farmers&#8217; economic drivers. The model is calibrated using 2019 Farm Accountancy Data Network (FADN) data specific to the Emilia Romagna region in Italy. Our findings reveal significant impacts on land use, with a notable decrease in cereal cultivation in favour of protein and fodder crops. Moreover, structural shifts are observed, notably a decrease in the number of small-scale farms. We also assess environmental and economic implications, observing a modest reduction in CO2 equivalent emissions per hectare, an increase in water demand, and an overall economic stability among farms, as indicated by changes in gross margin per hectare.</description>
      <author>Lisa Baldi, Sara Calzolai, Filippo Arfini, Mich&#232;le Donati</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36253/bae-14592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tourism Development and Environmental Sustainability: A Study on the Dual Impact on Economic Growth in Developing Countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2754-1169/2024.ga19197</link>
      <description>Hexu Cui, Advances in Economics Management and Political Sciences. 147(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406035866

                This study explores the intricate relationship between tourism development, economic growth, energy consumption, and environmental sustainability in developing countries, with a particular focus on Indonesia and Brazil. While tourism significantly contributes to economic growth and job creation, its rapid expansion often exacerbates environmental pressures, raising concerns about long-term sustainability. By analyzing the case of Indonesia, where tourism is both a vital economic driver and a source of environmental stress, this study highlights the importance of balancing economic growth with environmental protection. Furthermore, the paper performs an empirical investigation of the impact of international visitor arrivals, economic growth, and energy consumption on CO2 emissions in Brazil. Using the autoregressive distributed lag (ARDL) technique, the study aims to fill a gap in understanding the relationship between tourism and carbon emissions, particularly in the context of carbon neutrality and the Sustainable Development Goals. The findings aim to inform the development of policies that mitigate the environmental impact of tourism while fostering sustainable economic growth. This study contributes to the broader literature on the role of decarbonization in achieving emission reductions and promoting sustainable tourism practices.</description>
      <author>Hexu Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2754-1169/2024.ga19197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aquatic Sciences in the Tropics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003538509</link>
      <description>B. R. Jana, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406025249

                The tropical environment is unique due to its geographic location, climatic features, intense solar radiation, high temperature, heavy precipitation, less seasonal variation, enhanced food and productivity, faster metabolism, ecological dynamics and co-evolutionary processes that favor niches for specialized species. It also provides the richest biodiversity with endemic fish species that support millions of people in rural areas. This book Aquatic Sciences in the Tropics: Inland Waters, Domain and Nutrient Geochemistry comprises nine primary chapters that address various topics. Chapter 1 covers topics such as Water as a Substance, Water as a Medium, Fundamentals of Global Water Distribution and Hydrologic Cycle, Economics of Water and Challenges; Chapter 2: The Environment, Tropical Environment, Concept of Biosphere and Aquatic Biome, Tropical Aquatic Bionetwork, Tropical Limnology; Chapter 3: Origin of Lakes, General Classification of Lakes, Tropical Lakes, Lake Morphometry, Morpho-Edaphic Index, Trophic State Index of Lakes, Wetlands, Mangroves; Chapter 4: Concept of Stream Order, Streams and Rivers, The River Continuum Concept, Physico-chemical and Biological Features of Streams, Adaptations of Hill Stream Fishes; Chapter 5: Light as an Entity, Thermal Regime, Thermal Stratification, Lake Mixing, Turnover and Circulation; Chapter 6: Sources of CO2 in Inland Waters, Hydrogen Ion Concentration, The CO2&#8211;CO3&#8211;HCO3 System, Alkalinity, Hardness; Chapter 7: Dissolved Oxygen, Oxidation and Reduction Potential; Chapter 8: Total Dissolved Solids, Dissolved Organic Carbon; Chapter 9: Origin of Atmospheric Gases, Carbon and Carbon Cycle, Nitrogen, Nitrogen Fixation, Ammonification, Nitrification and Comammox, Denitrification and Anammox, Phosphorus and Sulphur. It is anticipated that the academic community, students, teachers, instructors, researchers, colleges, universities, institutions, administrators, policy makers, public libraries and the general public with an interest in these topics will find this text to be a valuable source of information and provide in-depth knowledge.</description>
      <author>B. R. Jana</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003538509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why issue green bonds? Examining their dual impact on environmental protection and economic benefits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-024-04318-1</link>
      <description>Di Zhou, Andrew P. Kythreotis, Humanities and Social Sciences Communications. 11(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405925707

                Abstract This article explores two primary questions: first, whether the issuance of green bonds contributes to environmental protection, particularly regarding their performance after the adoption of net-zero emission policies; and second, whether issuers of green bonds can have economic benefits. Using the Difference-in-Differences (DID) model to analyze green and conventional bonds issued from 2013 to 2023, the study finds no significant correlation between green bond issuance and CO 2 emissions following net-zero adoption. Nevertheless, our findings are important and deserve attention as they indicate that the carbon reduction policies have not exerted sufficient pressure on bond issuers to reduce emissions. At the same time, however, a closer examination of issuing entities reveals that those issuing only green bonds tend to have higher ESG ratings, lower CO2 emissions, and lower financing costs. This suggests that such issuers achieve substantial environmental benefits and economic advantages. In contrast, entities issuing both conventional and green bonds do not demonstrate the same environmental benefits. This finding raises concerns about potential greenwashing, suggesting that entities issuing both green and conventional bonds may engage in practices that contradict environmental protection while presenting their activities as environmentally friendly through green bonds. The study also highlights that the impact of bond features on ESG scores and CO 2 emissions varies significantly across different types of issuers. Finally, the paper recommends that policymakers strengthen carbon reduction policies, establish mechanisms to prevent greenwashing, and integrate CO 2 emissions and ESG factors into assessment systems. Additionally, it calls for special attention to the carbon emissions of entities in low- and middle-income countries, as well as those in the manufacturing sector, to support the healthy development of green finance.</description>
      <author>Di Zhou, Andrew P. Kythreotis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-024-04318-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Bro&#823;nsted Acidity by up to 12 p&lt;i&gt;K&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;a&lt;/sub&gt; Units in a Redox-Active Nanopore Lined with Multifunctional Metal Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15873</link>
      <description>Taro J. Jones, Kaitlyn G. Dutton, Harender S. Dhattarwal, P. Thomas Blackburn, Rupak Saha, Richard C. Remsing, Mark C. Lipke, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406003368

                Electrostatic interactions, hydrogen bonding, and solvation effects can alter the free energies of ionizable functional groups in proteins and other nanoporous architectures, allowing such structures to tune acid&#8211;base chemistry to support specific functions. Herein, we expand on this theme to examine how metal sites (M = H2, ZnII, CoII, CoI) affect the pKa of benzoic acid guests bound in discrete porphyrin nanoprisms (M3TriCage) in CD3CN. These host&#8211;guest systems were chosen to model how porous metalloporphyrin electrocatalysts might influence H+ transfer processes that are needed to support important electrochemical reactions (e.g., reductions of H+, O2, or CO2). Usefully, the cavities of the host&#8211;guest complexes become hydrated at low water concentrations (10&#8211;40 mM), providing a good representation of the active sites of porous electrocatalysts in water. Under these conditions, Lewis acidic CoII and ZnII ions increase the Bro&#823;nsted acidities of the guests by 4 and 8 pKa units, respectively, while reduction of the CoII sites to anionic CoI sites produces an electrostatic potential that lowers acidity by ca. 4 units (8 units relative to the CoII state). Lacking functional metal sites, H6TriCage increases the acidity of the guests by just 2.5 pKa units despite the 12+ charge of this host and contributions from other factors (hydrogen bonding, hydration) that might stabilize the deprotonated guests. Thus, the metal sites have dominant effects on acid&#8211;base chemistry in the M3TriCages, providing a larger pKa range (12.75 to &#8805;24.5) for an encapsulated acid than attained via other confinement effects in proteins and artificial porous materials.</description>
      <author>Taro J. Jones, Kaitlyn G. Dutton, Harender S. Dhattarwal, P. Thomas Blackburn, Rupak Saha, Richard C. Remsing, Mark C. Lipke</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15873</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-silica integration for superior properties in potassium feldspar-based phosphoric acid activated geopolymers: A sustainable approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31127/tuje.1536718</link>
      <description>M. Nanthini, R Ganesan, V.M. Jaganathan, Turkish Journal of Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405986391

                This study investigates the potential of Potassium Feldspar-phosphate-based geopolymer concrete as a sustainable alternative to conventional concrete, addressing the environmental concerns associated with CO2 emissions during cement production. While geopolymer concrete offers a promising path toward sustainability, its performance often falls short of Portland cement concrete. This study investigates utilizing nano-silica to enhance the performance of geopolymer concrete. Potassium feldspar powder, metakaolin, and rice husk ash were combined to create a ternary mixture that included different amounts of nano-silica. The resulting geopolymer composition's mechanical characteristics were assessed. The mechanical qualities were evaluated using split tensile and compressive strength tests. The findings revealed that a 4% nano-silica dosage (GC-N4) yielded the most significant improvement in strength and durability. The GC-N4 mix performed superior in all metrics, demonstrating the highest compressive (42.86 MPa) and split tensile (3.8 Mpa) strengths. Reduction in water absorption and durability aspects were also optimum in GC-N4. These results highlight the potential of incorporating nano-silica into a ternary mix of potassium feldspar powder, metakaolin, and rice husk ash to significantly enhance the overall performance of geopolymer concrete, promoting its wider adoption as a sustainable construction material.</description>
      <author>M. Nanthini, R Ganesan, V.M. Jaganathan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31127/tuje.1536718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-carbon optimization model of energy-transportation system based on parking processes and hydrogen conversion processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/15435075.2024.2448290</link>
      <description>Xiyun Yang, Weihao Guo, Xintao Gao, Zeyu Zhao, International Journal of Green Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405963966

                As the popularity of new energy vehicles increases and the transport network becomes increasingly linked to the energy system, the energy drive of electric and natural gas vehicles is directly dependent on the supply of the electrical network. Therefore, effective coordination of traffic flows can optimize energy consumption and reduce carbon emissions. This paper introduces an optimal scheduling model that integrates traffic flow and alkaline electrolyser operation to achieve economic efficiency and low carbon emissions. Firstly, a traffic flow model is developed, addressing path selection, parking queues and vehicle loads on gas and electricity systems, with the aim of reducing excessive emissions resulting from poor traffic distribution. Secondly, An electrolyser operation strategy is formulated for various conditions, enhancing system economics and dynamics. Finally, a two-stage low-carbon optimisation model is implemented.The first stage focuses on economic dispatch of the coupled electricity-gas system to minimize operating costs.In the second stage, a demand response model is developed to optimise the system by taking into account the integrated carbon price of the carbon emission streams. Tested in a modified energy transport network, the model demonstrates a CO2 reduction of 3.2 tons and a 14% improvement in economic efficiency.</description>
      <author>Xiyun Yang, Weihao Guo, Xintao Gao, Zeyu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/15435075.2024.2448290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Hydrothermal Conversion of Biomass Derivative Carbohydrates and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; into Value-Added Organic Acid over an NH&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-MIL-53(Fe) Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07721</link>
      <description>Xia Meng, Longqi Li, Xiaocong Wang, Kaihao Xu, Shuai Zhang, Chengxue Zhang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406025946

                During CO2/HCO3&#8211; reduction with renewable biomass, achieving high-efficiency production of the target products is vital but challenging. In this study, an NH2&#8211; functional-group-modified MIL-53(Fe) catalyst was synthesized using a facile and efficient method. Under the action of the NH2-MIL-53(Fe) catalyst, a clear synergistic effect was exhibited on the transformation of glucose and NaHCO3 into formic acid with a high yield of 50% at a low reaction temperature (190 &#176;C) via a three-pronged route, which mainly involved the decomposition of intermediates of glucose to gradually reduce NaHCO3 to formic acid under hydrothermal conditions. An in-depth analysis of the catalytic mechanism and density functional theory calculations demonstrated that the increased alkalinity of active sites by the NH2&#8211; functional group incorporation into the catalytic system enhanced the crucial reaction steps and reduced the activation energy of the crucial reactions, including glucose isomerization, aldehyde intermediate retro-aldol condensation, and redox of aldehyde compounds and NaHCO3 to formic acid, thereby promoting the generation of target products and suppressing side products. This study addresses the challenge of reducing NaHCO3 from renewable biomass to commercial formic acid by constructing multifunctional active sites, thus providing a new strategy for achieving carbon cycling.</description>
      <author>Xia Meng, Longqi Li, Xiaocong Wang, Kaihao Xu, Shuai Zhang, Chengxue Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MANAGERIAL CHALLENGES OF INDUSTRIAL ENTERPRISES IN THE CONTEXT OF DECARBONIZATION AND EUROPEAN INTEGRATION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33111/sedu.2024.55.160.173</link>
      <description>Oleksandr Vostriakov, Denys Stepura, Strategy of Economic Development of Ukraine. None(55)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405922793

                The article addresses the managerial challenges faced by Ukrainian industrial enterprises in the context of decarbonization and European integration. It systematically examines the key aspects of transitioning to low-carbon technologies and strategies required to align with European Union (EU) environmental goals, standards, and policies. Special emphasis is placed on the EU&#700;s carbon reduction targets, the Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM), and their impact on exporters of industrial goods, including Ukrainian companies. The study identifies strategic, operational, financial, and technological challenges that hinder decarbonization processes while highlighting opportunities for enterprises to adopt sustainable practices. The research underscores the importance of optimizing production processes through renewable energy sources, carbon capture technologies, and emission monitoring systems. Enterprises must address the costeffectiveness of transitioning to low-carbon technologies, ensure transparent CO2 emission reporting, and attract financial support for sustainable projects. Furthermore, the paper discusses the global carbon footprint and EU climate neutrality plans, including reducing emissions by 55% by 2030 and achieving net-zero emissions by 2050. The study concludes that Ukrainian industrial enterprises need to integrate environmental management systems and prioritize innovation-driven solutions to maintain competitiveness in the EU market. Collaboration with international consulting firms, securing financing for decarbonization projects, and fostering corporate sustainability cultures are critical steps toward achieving compliance with EU standards and advancing environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>Oleksandr Vostriakov, Denys Stepura</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33111/sedu.2024.55.160.173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow Porous Carbon Nanocubes with High-Loading Accessible Iron Atomic Sites for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05918</link>
      <description>Shuguang Wang, Ruihao Zhang, Cong Liu, Feng Wu, Ruirui Li, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406058555

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have exhibited enormous potential toward electrocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2RR). The accessibility of active sites has a significant influence on their catalytic performance, especially in the mass-transport-limited catalytic reaction like CO2RR. Therefore, the rational design of SACs with easily accessible and high-loading atomic sites is crucial but still remains a grand challenge. In this work, a thermally removable template strategy combined with emulsion-induced interface anisotropic assembly method was developed to prepare iron single-atom catalyst with easy accessibility and high loading amount. For CO2RR, as-synthesized Fe-SACs supported on hollow porous carbon nanocube (H&#8211;Fe&#8211;NC SACs) display high selectivity toward CO. Most importantly, the CO partial current density of H&#8211;Fe&#8211;NC SACs at &#8722;0.98 V can reach &#8722;23.5 mA cm&#8211;2, which is 2.3 times higher than that of Fe-SACs on solid carbon sphere. The hollow and porous carbon matrix efficiently enhances the accessibility of the active sites and promotes mass transport, thus accelerating the reaction kinetics of the catalysis reaction. It is expected that this carrier engineering can provide a versatile route to improve the catalyst performance of the mass-transport-limited electrocatalytic reaction.</description>
      <author>Shuguang Wang, Ruihao Zhang, Cong Liu, Feng Wu, Ruirui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Global Warming Potential and Acidification in Smoked Fish Production at University of Ibadan Fish Farm: A Life Cycle Assessment Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5455/jrafs.20241110085505</link>
      <description>Abdulfatai Aremu, bernard Igomu, Taiwo Oluwatoyin Ajao, Journal of Research in Agriculture and Food Sciences.. 2(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405906893

                Abstract Aim: Life cycle assessment (LCA) is an ISO-standardized analytical tool developed to evaluate environmental performance of products and processes. The aquaculture industry is one of the largest and fast-growing industries in the agricultural sector because of its health benefits. However, this growth comes with fuel combustion technologies and other operations. Therefore, quantifying the level of impact caused by these processes is imperative. The study was aimed at carrying out an LCA for the production and processing of smoked fish using the University of Ibadan Fish Farm as a case study to identify environmentally detrimental production and processing hotspots. Methods: The approach employed for this study is the cradle-to-gate approach, which involves the operations from breeding/hatching to the packaging of smoked fish. Relevant data was obtained through site visitation and physical interviews. The data on energy and material resources used in the processes were modeled on GaBi9 (Holistic Balancing) software. The tool used to analyze the life cycle inventories of smoked fish production is TRACI (Tool for the Reduction and Assessment of Chemical and other Environmental Impacts) midpoint assessment and modeling was for 1kg functional unit of smoked fish. Four scenarios were drawn out for assessing the impact by varying the energy and material resources. Results: The total energy used in the smoking kiln for the one month under study was 35,660.16MJ. Six impact categories were measured for all four scenarios and the following categories had the highest impact in order of ascension; Global Warming Potential (GWP) (0.438, 0.243, 0.609, 0.624) kg CO2-Eqiv., Smog Air (0.0702, 0.288, 0.478, 0.277) kg O3-Equiv., Human Health Criteria Air (4.173e-03, 3.502e-04, 1.503e-03, 3.443e-03) kg PM10-Equiv. and Acidification Potential (AP) (2.19e-04, 2.88e-04, 3.37e-04, 5.68e-04) kg SO2-Equiv. The unit process with the highest impact on the environment for all four scenarios is the fish smoking process. Transportation and burning of charcoal also contributed to the emission of gases such as CO2, CO, CH4, N2O, SO2, NOx, VOCs, PMs, etc. Also, the use of Polyethylene (PE) and Low-Density Polyethylene (LDPE) plastics as packaging materials contribute to the release of heavy metals such; Cr, Cd, Ar, Zn, Cu, Pb, etc. into the environment for all four scenarios. Conclusion: The fish smoking process has the highest impact on the environment for all four scenarios. However other unit processes also have contributory effect. At the end of the study, it was recommended that renewable energy sources as well as energy from bio-waste should be explored for the smoking kilns to achieve cleaner production.</description>
      <author>Abdulfatai Aremu, bernard Igomu, Taiwo Oluwatoyin Ajao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5455/jrafs.20241110085505</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Investigation of Methyl Ester&#8211;Ethanol Blends as a Sustainable Biofuel Alternative for Heavy Duty Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010253</link>
      <description>Michael Fr&#259;ti&#539;a, Robert M&#259;d&#259;lin Chivu, Eugen Rusu, Gabriel Bogdan Carp, Ion V. Ion, F. P. Brito, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405979654

                Agriculture may hold the key to a sustainable future. By efficiently capturing atmospheric CO2, we can simultaneously produce food, feed, biomass, and biofuels. For more eco-friendly soil processing practices, biofuels can replace diesel in agricultural machinery, significantly reducing the carbon footprint of crop production. Thus, biofuel production can be a sustainable solution for a future with a decreasing carbon footprint. This paper examines the possibility of replacing petroleum-based fuels with 100% biofuels to continue powering heavy-duty vehicles, where the use of electric vehicles is not the optimal solution. This study particularly focused on the operating scenario of heavy-duty engines under medium to high loads, typical of transport or soil processing in agriculture. Diesel was used as a benchmark, and each alternative, such as vegetable oil, methyl ester (B100), and methyl ester&#8211;ethanol blends (90B10E, 80B20E, and 70B30E), was tested individually. To find a sustainable fuel substitute, the goal was to identify a biofuel with a kinematic viscosity similar to that of diesel for a comparable spray process. Experimental results showed that an 80% methyl ester and 20% ethanol blend had a kinematic viscosity close to that of diesel. In addition to diesel, this blend resulted in a 48.6% reduction in exhaust gas opacity and a 6.54% lower specific fuel consumption (BSEC). The main aim of the tests was to find a 100% biofuel substitute without modifying the fuel injection systems of existing engines.</description>
      <author>Michael Fr&#259;ti&#539;a, Robert M&#259;d&#259;lin Chivu, Eugen Rusu, Gabriel Bogdan Carp, Ion V. Ion, F. P. Brito</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Regression Models for Evaluating Ultimate Performance of Cotton Rope-Confined Recycled Aggregate Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15010064</link>
      <description>Kittipoom Rodsin, Ali Ejaz, Huaping Wang, Panumas Saingam, Panuwat Joyklad, Wasim Khaliq, Qudeer Hussain, Chichaya Boonmee, Buildings. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405967630

                This study investigates the use of cotton ropes (CRs) as a sustainable and cost-effective substitute for synthetic fiber-reinforced polymers for concrete confinement, offering significant environmental benefits such as lower CO2 emissions and reduced energy consumption. The work evaluates the effectiveness of CR strips for confining concrete, including scenarios with recycled concrete aggregates (ReCA). Compressive strength improvements varied among specimens, with Specimen I-3F showing a 140.52% increase and Specimen II-3F achieving a 46.67% improvement. Strip configurations for Type I recycled aggregate concrete (RAC) outperformed full wraps on Type II RAC, exemplified by Specimen I-3S&#8217;s 84.51% improvement. Ultimate strain enhancements ranged from 915% to 4490.91%, driven by the significant rupture strain of cotton rope confinement. For Type I RAC, complete wrapping significantly outperformed strip configurations by 56%, 50%, and 32% in ultimate strength improvement for 1, 2, and 3 layers, respectively. The confinement ratio, varying from 0.10 to 0.70, greatly influenced the compressive behavior, with compressive strength normalized by unconfined strength increasing consistently with the confinement ratio. A minimum confinement ratio of roughly 0.40 is required to achieve an increasing second part in the compressive behavior. The initial parabolic branch was modeled using Popovics&#8217; formulation, revealing an elastic modulus approximately 20% lower than ACI 318-19 predictions. The second branch was described using a linear approximation, and nonlinear regression analysis produced expressions for key points on the idealized compressive curve, enhancing model accuracy for CR-confined RAC. The R2 values for the nonlinear regression analysis performed on experimental results were greater than 0.90. This study highlights the effectiveness of neural network expressions to predict the compressive strength of CR-confined concrete. A strength reduction (ratio of full wrap and strip wrap height CRs) factor of 0.67 was proposed and used for strip-wrapped specimens. It was seen that the neural network models also predicted the compressive strength of partially wrapped specimens with reasonable accuracy using the strength reduction factor.</description>
      <author>Kittipoom Rodsin, Ali Ejaz, Huaping Wang, Panumas Saingam, Panuwat Joyklad, Wasim Khaliq, Qudeer Hussain, Chichaya Boonmee</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15010064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMPROVEMENT OF EAEU LAW IN THE FIELD OF ENVIRONMENTAL TRANSPORT SYSTEMS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52026/2788-5291_2024_79_4_187</link>
      <description>&#1054;&#1083;&#1100;&#1075;&#1072; &#1053;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1083;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;&#1085;&#1072; &#1058;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1095;&#1082;&#1086;, Bulletin of Institute of Legislation and Legal Information of the Republic of Kazakhstan. 4(79)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406073174

                The article analyzes current problems of improving the rules of law of the EAEU aimed at greening the transport systems of the member states. The research was carried out using general and special methods of scientific knowledge, including formal-logical, comparative law, etc. The features of the development of world transport systems in connection with the global energy transition are analyzed, and the lack of alternative to the transition to green technologies in transport, in particular, the electrification of transport systems, is emphasized. The expediency of taking collective measures at the level of an integration association is substantiated, allowing to minimize costs and increase the efficiency of greening the transport systems of the member states. Contains proposals for improving the legal norms of the EAEU, such as the First Package of Measures (Road Map) for cooperation between the EAEU member states within the framework of the climate agenda and Appendix No. 24 to the Treaty (Protocol on Coordinated (Agreed) Transport Policy. The feasibility of forming a specialized structure in the EEC is substantiated, the functions of which would include calculating optimal target indicators for the transition to environmentally friendly transport technologies. In general, according to the author, the development of the most promising directions of transport policy in the EAEU, taking into account the energy transition and reduction of CO2 emissions, should be carried out not only by the EAEU bodies and representatives of relevant ministries (transport, environmental protection, energy, etc.), but also with the involvement of a wide range of specialists and experts, as well as members of the business community represented by transport companies, environmental non-governmental organizations and representatives of the public. The results of the study can be applied in the legislative and law enforcement practice of the EAEU, the Republic of Belarus and other member states of the EAEU.</description>
      <author>&#1054;&#1083;&#1100;&#1075;&#1072; &#1053;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1083;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;&#1085;&#1072; &#1058;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1095;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52026/2788-5291_2024_79_4_187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Evaluation of Photovoltaic Panels in Extreme Environments: A Machine Learning Approach on Horseshoe Island, Antarctica</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010174</link>
      <description>Mehmet Da&#351;, Erhan Arslan, Sule Kaya, Bilal Alata&#351;, Ebru Kavak Akp&#305;nar, Burcu &#214;zsoy, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405944458

                Due to the supply problems of fossil-based energy sources, the tendency towards alternative energy sources is relatively high. For this reason, the use of solar energy systems is increasing today. This study combines experimental data and machine learning algorithms to evaluate the energy performance of four different photovoltaic (PV) panel designs (monocrystalline, polycrystalline, flexible, and transparent) under harsh environmental conditions on Horseshoe Island (Antarctica). In this research, the effects of environmental factors, such as solar radiation, temperature, humidity, and wind speed, on the panels were analyzed. Electrical power output of the PV panels are analyzed using six machine learning models. Random forest (RF) and CatBoost (CB) models showed the highest accuracy and reliability among these models. According to the experimental results, Monocrystalline PV provided the highest electrical power (20.5 Watts on average), and Flexible PV provided the highest energy efficiency (19.67%). However, Flexible PV was observed to have higher surface temperatures compared to the other panel types. Furthermore, using Monocrystalline PV resulted in an average reduction of 4.1 tons of CO2 emissions per year, demonstrating the positive environmental impact of renewable energy systems. Thanks to this study, renewable energy research for temporary stations in Antarctica will focus on explainable and interpretable artificial intelligence models that will provide an understanding of the factors affecting the energy performance of PV panels. The research results will be an important guide for optimizing energy consumption, management, and demand forecasting in temporary research stations in Antarctica.</description>
      <author>Mehmet Da&#351;, Erhan Arslan, Sule Kaya, Bilal Alata&#351;, Ebru Kavak Akp&#305;nar, Burcu &#214;zsoy</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Retrofit Strategies on Thermal Comfort and Energy Performance in Social Housing for Current and Future Weather Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15010080</link>
      <description>Lucienne G. Basaly, Arman Hashemi, Heba Elsharkawy, Darryl Newport, Nancy Badawy, Buildings. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405968400

                With growing concerns over energy and heat-related mortality/morbidity rates, enhancing building performances is key to improving the health and well-being of building occupants while reducing CO2 emissions, in line with the UK Government&#8217;s Net-Zero targets. This study investigates the impacts of different retrofitting scenarios on overheating risk and energy performance in social housing for current and future climate conditions. Dynamic thermal simulations were carried out using Design Summer Year (DSY) weather files in DesignBuilder software for selected case study buildings. Winter performance was analysed using the Predicted Mean Vote (PMV) index, while summer results were assessed according to the Chartered Institution of Building Services Engineers Technical Memorandum 59 (CIBSE TM59) guidelines. The findings revealed that bedrooms, especially those facing south, were at high risk of overheating. Factors such as building construction, the number of exposed surfaces, and window area influenced the risks. External wall insulation outperformed internal wall insulation in improving summer comfort. In the winter, Passivhaus standards with natural ventilation ensured thermal comfort across all zones, with a 41&#8211;53% reduction in heating energy consumption under current weather conditions. The risk of overheating and associated health issues significantly increased for the future weather scenarios. Further investigation into ventilation strategies, occupant behaviour, and passive design is required to mitigate overheating risks while reducing energy consumption in buildings.</description>
      <author>Lucienne G. Basaly, Arman Hashemi, Heba Elsharkawy, Darryl Newport, Nancy Badawy</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15010080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial methanogenesis fueled by freshwater infiltration and oil biodegradation in the Siljan impact structure, Sweden</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42452-024-06418-8</link>
      <description>Femke van Dam, Riikka Kiet&#228;v&#228;inen, George Westmeijer, Manuel Reinhardt, Shuhei Ono, Mark Dopson, Marcelo Ketzer, Jennifer C. McIntosh, Henrik Drake, Deleted Journal. 7(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406020779

                Abstract Deeply fractured rocks of meteorite impact craters are suggested as prime niches for subsurface microbial colonization. Methane can be a product of such microbial communities and seeps of methane from impact craters on Earth are of strong interest as they act as analogs for Mars. Previous studies report signs of ancient microbial methanogenesis in the Devonian Siljan meteorite impact structure in Sweden, but the proportion of microbial methane, metabolic pathways, and potential modern activity remain elusive. In this study, gas composition, hydrochemistry, oil organic geochemistry, and microbial community analyses are reported in 400 m deep fractures of the Siljan impact structure. The results showed a dominantly microbial origin for methane, which was supported by highly negative &#948; 13 C CH4 and positive &#948; 13 C CO2 values along with multiply substituted isotopologues (&#916; 13 CH 3 D) that indicated disequilibrium fractionation due to microbial kinetic isotope effects. The presence of C 2 to C 5 hydrocarbons suggested a minor thermogenic input in the gas mix. Characterization of the microbial community via 16S rRNA gene amplicon sequencing and real-time PCR indicated a low abundance of several methanogenic archaeal populations, which is common for settings with active methanogenesis. Evidence of oil biodegradation suggested that secondary microbial hydrocarbon utilization was involved in the methanogenesis. Low sulfate and high alkalinity in the groundwaters also suggested a dominantly microbial methane formation driven by infiltration of freshwater that was coupled to sulfate reduction and secondary utilization of early mature thermogenic hydrocarbons.</description>
      <author>Femke van Dam, Riikka Kiet&#228;v&#228;inen, George Westmeijer, Manuel Reinhardt, Shuhei Ono, Mark Dopson, Marcelo Ketzer, Jennifer C. McIntosh, Henrik Drake</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42452-024-06418-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Assessment Concerning the Use of Char from Biomass in the Iron Ore Sintering Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32730/mswt.2023.67.5-6.3</link>
      <description>J. Stecko, No host. 67(5-6/2023)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405994107

                The article presents results of tests concerning the use of waste biomass-derived char as a partial substitute for solid fuel used in the iron ore sintering process (primarily coke breeze). The tests were performed in a system used for the physical simulation of the sintering process, making it possible for flue gases to be recycled back to the process. During the tests, particular attention was paid to the analysis of properties of flue gases with the simultaneous recirculation of these gases back to the process. The optimal fraction of char from biomass (i.e. not worsening either sintering process or sinter parameters) in the total fuel was determined on the basis of previous experience. It was found that the use of carbonised biomass improved the reducing properties of the sinter and had a positive effect on its strength. At the same time it was observed that the amounts of CO2 and NOx as well as of CO and CH4 emitted when using char were higher than those accompanying the use of coke breeze (only) as fuel. In order to reduce the impact of the char addition on flue gas parameters, sintering process-related tests also included the recycling of flue gas back to the sintering process. Flue gas properties were identified (both before dedusting and in the stack) using stationary flue gas analysers. The tests also included measurements of volatile organic compounds. The measurement results were used to determine the influence of the use of waste biomass-derived char on flue gas properties and primary parameters of the sintering process. The overall test results revealed failure to obtain expected reduction in the emission of undesirable compounds in off-gases (in relation to the use of the constant 15 % fraction of waste biomass-derived char and the gradual 45 % increase in the amount of off-gases recycled back to the process).</description>
      <author>J. Stecko</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32730/mswt.2023.67.5-6.3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KAJIAN PERUBAHAN SPASIAL LAHAN VEGETASI DAN CADANGAN KARBON TERSIMPAN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36982/jtg.v13i02.4669</link>
      <description>Anisa Rahma, Citra Dewi, Romi Fadly, Jurnal Tekno Global. 13(02)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405972063

                ABSTRACT The University of Lampung, commonly referred to as Unila, is known as a green campus with open green spaces featuring various types of vegetation, such as shrubs, trees, and grasslands. The university consists of several faculties, including the Faculty of Engineering. However, in recent years, land use changes have occurred within the Faculty of Engineering, where vegetated areas have been converted into built-up areas, such as the construction of retention ponds and new buildings. This change has impacted the available carbon stock. The reduction in vegetated land is directly proportional to the decrease in carbon reserves stored in plants, which contributes to climate change. In relation to climate change caused by deforestation and land degradation, it is necessary to conserve and manage vegetated lands, as well as enhance carbon reserves, to measure the extent of changes (reduction in carbon emissions) resulting from land conservation efforts (Hairiah et al., 2007). The more abundant the carbon stored in plant biomass; the more CO2 is absorbed by the plants. Biomass measurement can be conducted in two ways: non-destructively and destructively. The non-destructive method is considered effective because it requires less time, cost, and effort. One technology that can be used for biomass measurement is aerial photography using unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) or drones, which tend to be effective and efficient. The Object-Based Image Analysis (OBIA) approach is an object-based method that has high accuracy in determining the available carbon stock due to dynamic changes in the extent of vegetated land in the Faculty of Engineering area at Unila between 2019 and 2024. The vegetated area on the OBIA-processed map in 2019 was 6.9886 hectares. In 2024, the vegetated area on the OBIA-processed map was 6.6652 hectares. The change in vegetated land between 2019 and 2024 was 0.3234 hectares, indicating a reduction in vegetated land due to infrastructure development in the Faculty of Engineering area. The calculation of stored carbon stock, based on field measurements, was 197.129764 tons of carbon per hectare. Keywords : Universitas Lampung, Vegetation, UAV, Carbon, OBIA ABSTRAK Universitas Lampung atau disebut dengan Unila merupakan universitas yang dikenal sebagai kampus hijau (green campus) yang memiliki ruang terbuka hijau dengan vegetasi berupa semak belukar, pepohonan serta padang rumput. Universitas Lampung terdiri dari beberapa fakultas, salah satunya fakultas teknik. Namun, belakangan tahun terakhir terjadinya alih fungsi lahan di fakultas teknik dari lahan vegetasi menjadi lahan terbangun seperti dibangunnya embung, serta gedung-gedung baru. Hal tersebut mempengaruhi jumlah cadangan karbon yang tersedia. Pengurangan area vegetasi secara langsung berhubungan dengan penurunan cadangan karbon yang terdapat pada tanaman, yang pada gilirannya berkontribusi terhadap perubahan iklim. Dalam konteks perubahan iklim yang disebabkan oleh deforestasi dan degradasi lahan, sangat penting untuk melaksanakan upaya konservasi serta pengelolaan lahan vegetasi, sekaligus meningkatkan cadangan karbon. Hal ini bertujuan untuk memahami sejauh mana perubahan (penurunan emisi karbon) terjadi akibat kegiatan konservasi tersebut (Hairiah dkk., 2007).Jumlah karbon yang tersimpan dalam biomassa tanaman merupakan indikator dari seberapa banyak CO2 yang dapat diserap. Terdapat dua metode untuk mengukur biomassa, yaitu metode non-destruktif dan destruktif. Metode non-destruktif lebih disukai karena efisiensinya dalam hal waktu, biaya, dan tenaga. Salah satu teknologi yang dapat digunakan untuk pengukuran biomassa adalah pemotretan udara dengan menggunakan drone (UAV), yang menunjukkan efektivitas dan efisiensinya. Pendekatan Object Based Image Analysis (OBIA) adalah metode berbasis objek yang menawarkan akurasi tinggi dalam menentukan cadangan karbon yang tersedia akibat perubahan luas lahan vegetasi di Fakultas Teknik Unila antara tahun 2019 dan 2024.. Luasan vegetasi pada peta hasil pengolahan OBIA tahun 2019 luas vegetasi sebesar 6.9886 Ha. Dan untuk luasan vegetasi pada peta hasil pengolahan OBIA tahun 2024 luas vegetasi sebesar 6.6652 Ha. Hasil perubahan lahan vegetasi antara tahun 2019 dan 2024 sebesar 0.3234 Ha artinya terdapat pengurangan lahan vegetasi karena adanya pembangunan infrastruktur di area Fakultas Teknik. Perhitungan cadangan karbon tersimpan diperoleh berdasarkan pengukuran di lapangan sebesar 197.129764 Ton-C/ha Kata Kunci : Universitas lampung, Vegetasi, Karbon, UAV, OBIA.</description>
      <author>Anisa Rahma, Citra Dewi, Romi Fadly</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36982/jtg.v13i02.4669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anesthesia management of an infant with moyamoya disease posted for encephaloduroarteriomyosynosteosis procedure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4103/sja.sja_363_24</link>
      <description>Ruchi Pathak, M. Kaur, Ghazala Shabeen, Vikas Janu, Saudi Journal of Anaesthesia. 19(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405978389

                Dear Sir, Moyamoya disease is a chronic, usually bilateral, vasculopathy with progressive narrowing of the terminal intracranial portion of the internal carotid artery and circle of Willis leading to decreased blood supply to the brain resulting in chronic ischemia characterized by symptoms of transient ischemic attacks and stroke.[1,2] The usual presentation of moyamoya disease occurs in bimodal peaks, in the pediatric age group at 5&#8211;9 years of age and in adults at 35&#8211;39 years of age.[3] This disease has a rare occurrence in the infant population so nothing much is described in the literature about anesthetic management of moyamoya in infants.[4] We, hereby, discuss the anesthetic management of moyamoya disease in an infant posted for encephaloduroarteriomyosynosteosis procedure (EDAMS). An 11-month-old female, weighing 6 kg, was posted for an EDAMS procedure for moyamoya disease. The parents gave a history of multiple episodes of sudden clonic movements of the right upper limb (lasting for 1&#8211;2 min) till the seventh month of life. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) showed severe attenuation of the bilateral supraclinoid internal carotid artery and middle cerebral artery with A1 segment of the bilateral anterior cerebral artery with evident multiple lacunar chronic infarcts, encephalomalacia, and gliosis in bilateral cerebral hemispheres with multiple thalamo-perforating and lenticulostriate collaterals suggestive of moyamoya disease [Figure 1]. Routine investigations including complete blood count, coagulation profile, serum electrolytes, and renal function tests were normal. Her 2D echocardiography was normal. On examination, she also had microcephaly with fused fontanelles and overriding of sutures. The power was 4/5 in all limbs with increased tone in the right upper limb and lower limb and deep tendon reflexes of the right side were hyperactive grade +3. She was on tablet aspirin (25 mg), syrup clonazepam, and syrup levetiracetam.Figure 1: MRI image showing severe attenuation of bilateral supraclinoid internal carotid artery and middle cerebral arteryOn the day of surgery, she was calm and sleeping due to the morning dose of syrup clonazepam. She was shifted to the operation theater while in a state of sleep and there was no requirement of added sedation. All monitors were attached with pulse oximetry, electrocardiography, noninvasive blood pressure (BP), and nasopharyngeal temperature probe. She was induced with inj. fentanyl 12 mcg, inj. lignocaine (to avoid intubation response), inj. propofol 15 mg, and inj. atracurium 3 mg. Maintenance was done with O2/air (50:50) and sevoflurane to keep a minimal alveolar concentration (MAC 0.8). 4F triple lumen central line was inserted in right-sided internal jugular vein. Left radial artery was cannulated with 24-G arterial line for continuous BP monitoring. The vital parameters were maintained with mean arterial pressure (MAP) targeted above 55 mmHg. End-tidal carbon dioxide was maintained between 28 and 30 mmHg throughout the procedure. She was extubated smoothly at the end of the procedure and was shifted to neonatal intensive care unit for close observation. The goals of anesthesia in these surgeries included preservation of perfusion in areas prone to chronic ischemia by the maintenance of normothermia, normocarbia, normotension, prevention of hypoxia, and normal hematocrit.[5] Reduction in cerebral blood flow is less tolerated in pediatric patients than adults because children have a higher cerebral metabolic rate of oxygen consumption (CMRO2), hence they develop ischemia even if the cerebral blood flow is marginally reduced.[6] Any factor that reduces the cerebral blood flow like reduction in MAP or rise in intracranial pressure (ICP) should be specifically avoided in these patients as blood flow is already compromised. In our patient, the margin was even lesser due to the presence of fused sutures and microcephaly. Rise in ICP at various stages was prevented by shifting the child to OT in a sedated state, using lignocaine IV for attenuation of intubation response, smooth extubation, and good analgesia in the postoperative period. Invasive BP monitoring is required in such cases to continuously monitor for mean BP. To conclude, avoidance of factors leading to hypoxia and hyperventilation (crying, agitation), maintenance of cerebral blood flow, and normothermia are the keys to successful anesthetic management of moyamoya disease in the infant population. Declaration of patient consent The authors certify that they have obtained all appropriate patient consent forms. In the form the patient(s) has/have given his/her/their consent for his/her/their images and other clinical information to be reported in the journal. The patients understand that their names and initials will not be published and due efforts will be made to conceal their identity, but anonymity cannot be guaranteed. Financial support and sponsorship Nil. Conflicts of interest There are no conflicts of interest.</description>
      <author>Ruchi Pathak, M. Kaur, Ghazala Shabeen, Vikas Janu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4103/sja.sja_363_24</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IoT Enabled Motor Drive Vehicle for the Early Fault Detection in New Energy Conservation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69996/jsihs.2024018</link>
      <description>Sri Mythreyee B.V, T Snehanjali, K Rohitha, A. B., Journal of Sensors, IoT &amp; Health Sciences (JSIHS).. 2(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405979665

                The key areas of interest in respect of which analyses are provided within the context of the paper are sustainable business practices that can help drive the change towards a low carbon economy. The study focuses on advanced techniques for managing businesses to advance the link between economic development and environmental conservation to optimize economic and environmental performance. Furthermore, based on the features, discussed in the paper, it is possible to identify the meaning of the concepts making the organizations introduce sustainability factors, as well as the possible effect these decisions may have on their future performance. This paper explores the role of machine learning (ML) and data-driven business strategies in promoting sustainable business development within smart cities. By integrating ML models across various sectors such as energy management, transportation, waste management, water usage, public safety, and urban planning, cities can optimize resources, reduce environmental impact, and enhance overall efficiency. Results from implementing these strategies in a smart city context show a 10% reduction in energy consumption (from 200,000 kWh to 180,000 kWh), a 50% increase in renewable energy share (from 20% to 30%), and a 40% decrease in CO2 emissions (from 500 tons to 300 tons) due to the use of autonomous electric vehicles. In transportation, average traffic speed improved by 16.67% (from 30 km/h to 35 km/h), and public transport efficiency increased by 21.43% (from 70% to 85%). In waste management, waste collection costs were reduced by 20% (from $50,000 to $40,000), and the recycling rate increased by 40% (from 25% to 35%). Water usage efficiency rose by 12.5% (from 80% to 90%), while water leak incidents decreased by 60% (from 50 to 20). Additionally, predictive policing reduced crime rates by 40% (from 5 to 3 per 1,000 residents), and emergency response times improved by 33.33% (from 15 minutes to 10 minutes). Finally, urban planning efficiency increased by 25% (from 60% to 75%) in land use, and green space area expanded by 40% (from 50 to 70 square kilometers).</description>
      <author>Sri Mythreyee B.V, T Snehanjali, K Rohitha, A. B.</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69996/jsihs.2024018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Charging of Electric Transportation Based on Power Modes Model&#8212;A Practical Case of an Integrated Factory Grid with RES</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010196</link>
      <description>Dariusz Bober, Piotr Miller, Pawe&#322; Pijarski, Bart&#322;omiej Mroczek, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405945219

                The possibility of charging and possibly discharging electric cars can influence not only the balancing of power demand profiles in the grid and the stabilization of voltage profiles but also the appropriate management of electricity within the grid of an industrial plant equipped with its own RES resources. For this purpose, the concept of &#8220;power supply modes&#8221; can be introduced, which involves intelligent demand-side management. Each technological process in an industrial plant should be assigned a specific level of importance and priority. These priorities can be numbered according to their importance (weights) and marked with appropriate colors. One thus obtains a qualitative assessment of energy consumption within the plant (demand side) through the lens of power modes. With respect to the ability to charge electric vehicles within the plant grid, such priorities can also be assigned to individual charging options. If a given RES has sufficient generation capacity during a particular time period, the cost of charging is low. However, if the RESs are not operational during a given period (e.g., nighttime in the case of photovoltaics or during calm weather in the case of wind turbines), vehicles can still be charged but according to a different priority, which, of course, involves higher costs. By having access to data on the generation capacity of distributed RESs and knowing the preferences of employees, including the number of electric cars and the expected periods of vehicle charging, it is possible to predict the degree of use of available green energy and manage it efficiently. The analyses presented in the article represent an original approach to the flexibility of operation not only of the electricity grid but also of the internal energy system of industrial plants. It offers a novel perspective aimed at maximizing the share of RESs in the overall energy balance and minimizing the costs associated with the operation of RESs. The theoretical opportunity of sustainable sharing with employees a dedicated charging mode named &#8220;free charging&#8221;, powered by RESs, could represent an appropriate solution for CO2 emission reduction within Scope 3, Category 3, &#8220;employee commuting&#8221;, according to the GHG Protocol requirements. The original methodology proposed in the article aligns with activities related to the energy transition.</description>
      <author>Dariusz Bober, Piotr Miller, Pawe&#322; Pijarski, Bart&#322;omiej Mroczek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Continuous Positive Airway Pressure on Patient Outcomes in Acute Cardiogenic Pulmonary Edema Within Physician-Led Prehospital Care</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/medsci13010005</link>
      <description>Tatjana Jevti&#263; Drki&#263;, Armin &#352;ljivo, Kenan Ljuhar, Amela Tuco Ahmi&#263;, Lamija Huki&#263; Fetahovi&#263;, Emina Karamehi&#263;, Amna Paliku&#263;a Ljuhar, Jasna Husejinbegovi&#263; Musi&#263;, &#352;ejla Brkovi&#263; Jusufbegovi&#263;, Edin Jusufbegovi&#263;, Selma Terzi&#263; Salihba&#353;i&#263;, Melica Imamovi&#263; Bo&#353;njak, Riada Bla&#382;evi&#263;, Amina Valjevac, Medical Sciences. 13(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405966117

                Background: CPAP has been shown to be particularly beneficial in the management of acute cardiogenic pulmonary edema by reducing both preload and afterload, thus decreasing the work of breathing and improving oxygenation. Methods: This study was a prospective observational study, conducted in the period from 2022 to 2024, assessing the effectiveness and safety of prehospital CPAP therapy use in patients with acute cardiogenic pulmonary edema, administered alongside standard care. Results: In this study, 50 patients with acute cardiogenic pulmonary edema were treated by physician-led emergency teams in the Canton of Sarajevo. CPAP significantly improved clinical parameters across all time points. Systolic blood pressure decreased from 151.0 &#177; 41.0 mmHg at initial contact to 138.4 &#177; 32.0 mmHg before transportation and further to 130.2 &#177; 28.5 mmHg upon hospital admission (p &lt; 0.001). Diastolic pressure dropped from 85.6 &#177; 17.2 mmHg to 81.1 &#177; 15.2 mmHg before transportation (p = 0.018), with a slight further decrease to 80.2 &#177; 13.9 mmHg (p = 0.083). Heart rate fell from 114 &#177; 26.4 bpm to 111.3 &#177; 24.9 bpm before transportation (p = 0.003) and finally to 99.5 &#177; 18.2 bpm before hospital admission (p &lt; 0.001). Respiratory rate decreased from 31.0 &#177; 10.2 to 28.0 &#177; 10.5 breaths/min (p = 0.002) and further to 22.6 &#177; 7.3 breaths/min (p &lt; 0.001). End-tidal CO2 levels increased from 28.0 mmHg (23.5; 33.5) to 30.0 mmHg before transportation (p &lt; 0.001), and to 35.0 mmHg (32.0; 37.5) before hospital admission (p &lt; 0.001). Oxygen saturation improved from 79.0% (72.0; 81.0) to 84.0% before transportation (p &lt; 0.001) and reached 94.0% (91.0; 98.2) before hospital admission (p &lt; 0.001). VAS scores for dyspnea significantly dropped from 8.0 (6.0; 8.2) at initial contact to 6.0 (4.0; 8.0) before transportation (p &lt; 0.001) and further to 4.0 (3.0; 5.0) before hospital admission (p &lt; 0.001), indicating substantial symptom relief. ECG findings remained stable throughout the intervention. Conclusions: Prehospital CPAP therapy significantly improved clinical outcomes in cardiogenic pulmonary edema, including reductions in blood pressure, heart rate, respiratory rate, and enhanced oxygenation and symptom relief. These findings support its broader use in emergency care, even during short transport times.</description>
      <author>Tatjana Jevti&#263; Drki&#263;, Armin &#352;ljivo, Kenan Ljuhar, Amela Tuco Ahmi&#263;, Lamija Huki&#263; Fetahovi&#263;, Emina Karamehi&#263;, Amna Paliku&#263;a Ljuhar, Jasna Husejinbegovi&#263; Musi&#263;, &#352;ejla Brkovi&#263; Jusufbegovi&#263;, Edin Jusufbegovi&#263;, Selma Terzi&#263; Salihba&#353;i&#263;, Melica Imamovi&#263; Bo&#353;njak, Riada Bla&#382;evi&#263;, Amina Valjevac</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/medsci13010005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does hydration status affect ventilation during prolonged exercise?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1113/ep092332</link>
      <description>Naoto Fujii, Experimental Physiology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405961582

                Connections link a sequence of three related research papers. The central article which links the other two papers has been published in Experimental Physiology. In a Connections article, an author (or authors) of the central article outlines its principal novel findings, tracing how they were influenced by the first article and how the central article has contributed to the developments made in the third article. The author(s) may also speculate on the direction of future research in the field. Connections articles aim to set the research in a wide context. Pulmonary ventilation (hereafter referred to as ventilation) is tightly regulated in response to changes in metabolic rate (i.e., O2 consumption and CO2 production), maintaining arterial O2 and CO2 partial pressures. Therefore, it is not surprising that ventilation increases proportionally with exercise intensity and thus metabolic rate. As exercise intensity increases, wherein acidosis is intensified, ventilation increases exponentially relative to metabolic rate such that arterial partial pressures of CO2 decrease (hypocapnia) to minimize acidosis. In addition to metabolic rate, elevations in core temperature appear to increase ventilation with concomitant hypocapnia at rest and during prolonged submaximal exercise, particularly in the heat. My colleagues and I in Japan have conducted several experiments to assess this response, which we term hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation in our recent studies. I believe the underlying mechanisms and physiological significance of this response during exercise in humans remain to be elucidated. Nevertheless, hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation during prolonged exercise in the heat might occur to maintain homeostasis by: (1) mitigating acidosis through hypocapnia; (2) increasing respiratory heat loss; and (3) increasing blood oxygenation by elevating the arterial partial pressure of O2 and by a leftward shift in the haemoglobin&#8211;oxygen dissociation curve mediated by hypocapnia. The latter adaptation counteracts the rightward shift of the haemoglobin&#8211;oxygen dissociation curve induced by hyperthermia, which compromises oxygen loading to the blood. It should be noted that hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation leads to: (1) reduced cerebral blood flow owing to hypocapnia; (2) increased oxygen cost of ventilation; and (3) elevated breathing effort, all of which can increase physiological and psychological strain, potentially impairing exercise tolerance and endurance performance. Therefore, I believe that interventions aimed at mitigating hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation could potentially reduce physiological and psychological strain, thereby enhancing exercise tolerance and performance in the heat. Fluid loss through sweating often exceeds fluid intake during prolonged exercise in the heat, causing dehydration. The key question is whether dehydration contributes to hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation during prolonged exercise in the heat. Addressing this question could clarify whether proper hydration attenuates hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation, thereby improving exercise tolerance and performance in these conditions. As discussed earlier, ventilation can facilitate heat loss by increasing evaporative and dry heat dissipation. In this context, animals such as dogs and cats increase their ventilation during heat exposure, a response known as panting, serving as their primary heat-loss response. During exercise with heat stress, panting animals must regulate their ventilation to accommodate both metabolic and thermal demands. In this regard, Baker and Nijland (1993) reported that in goats, severe dehydration (9.2% body mass loss!) reduced respiratory evaporative heat loss (hence body water loss) at given central blood temperatures during treadmill walking with lost weight compensated by weighed saddlebags. Their data suggest an attenuated panting response, which aligns with fluid-conservation mechanisms. It should be emphasized that panting animals and humans exhibit distinct differences in heat-loss responses. Humans have evolved sweating function, enabling prolonged exercise in hot conditions, such as marathon races during the Summer Olympic Games. In contrast, although goats are capable of sweating, this response is short lived owing to sweat gland fatigue. Additionally, the extent of water and heat loss through ventilation in humans is minimal compared with panting animals. Therefore, in humans, although dehydration is known to impair the sweating response as a means to conserve body water, it remains unclear whether dehydration similarly attenuates hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation. As part of my master's thesis, I investigated whether dehydration influences hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation during exercise in the heat in sedentary or physically active male participants who performed both a fluid replacement trial and a no-fluid replacement trial in random order (Fujii et al., 2008). Participants completed two bouts of cycling exercise (30&#8211;60 min) at 50% of peak oxygen uptake in the heat, with a long recovery period between the bouts. During the recovery period in the fluid replacement trial, participants consumed water containing 25 mosmol/L of sodium, whereas no fluids were consumed in the no-fluid replacement trial. After the first exercise, participants lost 2.5% of their body mass in the no-fluid replacement trial, whereas the sodium drink successfully restored body fluid levels to a euhydrated state in the fluid replacement trial. Consequently, participants performed the second exercise bout with different hydration levels in each trial. Although the heat-loss response of cutaneous vasodilatation was attenuated in the no-fluid trial versus the fluid replacement trial, the slope relating minute ventilation and core temperature, an index of hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation, remained unaffected. Thus, we conclude that dehydration (2.5% body mass loss before exercise) does not influence hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation during exercise in humans. As a follow-up study, Gonz&#225;lez-Alonso et al. (2023) reanalysed previous data from studies conducted in Copenhagen, Denmark and Texas, USA. Their participants were endurance-trained individuals (cyclists) who exercised for a longer duration (&#8764;120 min) at a higher intensity (60%&#8211;70% of maximal O2 uptake) relative to our study. In addition, the extent of dehydration (&#8764;4% body mass loss) and hyperthermia (&#8764;39.5&#176;C core temperature) was more severe than in our study. Consistent with our findings, they demonstrated that minute ventilation was closely related to core temperature and that dehydration alone did not affect minute ventilation during exercise, because fluid replacement and blood volume restoration had no impact on ventilation. Based on measured blood variables, they found that circulating catecholamines were positively correlated with minute ventilation during exercise in the heat. Interestingly, they also discovered that infusion of adrenaline, a hormone known to mediate increases in body temperature and ventilation at rest, to levels comparable to those observed during high-intensity exercise, increased both core temperature and minute ventilation during prolonged exercise in the heat. Therefore, sympathoadrenal activation might partly mediate hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation during prolonged exercise in the heat. Baker, M. A., &amp; Nijland, M. J. (1993). Selective brain cooling in goats: effects of exercise and dehydration. The Journal of Physiology, 471, 679&#8211;692. Fujii, N., Honda, Y., Hayashi, K., Kondo, N., &amp; Nishiyasu, T. (2008). Effect of hypohydration on hyperthermic hyperpnea and cutaneous vasodilation during exercise in men. Journal of Applied Physiology, 105, 1509&#8211;1518. Gonzalez-Alonso, J., Calbet, J. A. L., Mora-Rodriguez, R., &amp; Kippelen, P. (2023). Pulmonary ventilation and gas exchange during prolonged exercise in humans: Influence of dehydration, hyperthermia and sympathoadrenal activity. Experimental Physiology, 108, 188&#8211;206. Based on combined data from our study (Fujii et al., 2008) and Gonz&#225;lez-Alonso et al. (2023), dehydration does not appear to affect hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation, as indicated by the linear relationship between minute ventilation and core temperature, during prolonged exercise in the heat in humans. However, dehydration can impair heat-loss responses, accelerating core temperature elevations, as observed by Gonz&#225;lez-Alonso et al. (2023), ultimately exacerbating hyperventilation. Therefore, minimizing dehydration through fluid ingestion before and during prolonged exercise in the heat can attenuate hyperventilation by preventing an excessive increase in core temperature, potentially improving exercise tolerance or endurance performance in hot conditions. Likewise, any intervention that reduces core temperature (e.g., heat acclimatization, cooling) could alleviate the physiological and psychological strain associated with hyperthermia-induced hyperventilation, possibly improving endurance performance in the heat. However, the potential advantages of body weight reduction owing to dehydration should also be considered when evaluating endurance performance in weight-bearing exercises, such as running. Lastly, I would like to highlight the knowledge gaps that need to be addressed in future research. We do not yet know whether the aforementioned findings obtained in human studies (Fujii et al., 2008; Gonzalez-Alonso et al., 2023) apply to severe-intensity exercise. It should be noted that during severe-intensity exercise, O2 uptake and CO2 output drift over time, complicating the distinction between the effects of hyperthermia and metabolic stimuli on ventilation. It also remains uncertain whether similar results would be observed in different populations, such as elite athletes, older adults, children and females. Regarding females, both our study (Fujii et al., 2008) and the study by Gonz&#225;lez-Alonso et al. (2023) tested males only, because limited attention was given to testing females when the original data in these studies were published [Gonz&#225;lez-Alonso et al. (2023) reanalysed data initially published between 1996 and 2000]. Sole author. None declared. None.</description>
      <author>Naoto Fujii</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1113/ep092332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon farming as a direction for solving modern climate problems: the search for a legal paradigm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33663/0869-2491-2024-35-442-457</link>
      <description>Pavlo Kulynych, Yearly journal of scientific articles &#8220;Pravova derzhava&#8221;. None(35)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405945324

                The problem of climate change has not only acquired the significance as a global ecological and socio-economic problem, but more and more citizens are disturbed of it. In recent years, the fight for climate safety has increasingly been seen as a fight for democratic values. After all, only in a democratic state is the fight for climate protection perceived as an unconditional imperative. At the initiative of the citizens of Portugal, the European Court of Human Rights (ECHR) considers the case of Duarte Agostinho and Others v. Portugal and Others (39371/20) regarding emissions of greenhouse gases in Portugal and other 32 states, which, according to the applicants, lead to an increase in the level of global warming and negatively a&#64256;ect the living conditions and health of the applicants. Obviously, the satisfaction of the application of the citizens of Portugal will create a precedent that will allow the citizens of one country to apply to the ECHR for climate damage compensation from any member state of the Council of Europe. Therefore, the growth of the legal capacity of citizens to protect their climate rights determines the need to improve legal mechanisms to strengthen control over the state of the climate. The negative impact on the climate is caused not only by such generally recognized industrial factors as industrial emissions, use of fossil fuels, etc., but also by many other types of human production activities that were previously not realized or considered insignificant. One of such types of production activity is agriculture. The issue of preventing or reducing the release of greenhouse gases in agriculture is becoming more and more important in the EU. In particular, in December 2019, the European Union introduced ambitious energy transition program &#8212; the European Green Deal, the implementation of which is designed to make Europe climate neutral by 2050. Adequate legal means are being sought in the EU to implement plans to achieve climate neutrality in agriculture as well. Thus, the European Commission plans to introduce an initiative that will include a new green business model to reward land managers for reducing greenhouse gas emissions. During the last decade, Ukraine's agriculture started also to be the sector with the sharpest tendency to increase greenhouse gas emissions. It is caused by the degradation of lands because of their intensive agricultural and other use, which leads to the release into the atmosphere of carbon accumulated in the soil during the thousand-year process of soil formation. Unfortunately, the compliance of Ukrainian legislation with EU law in terms of environmental and climate protection can be assessed as initial. In many new or updated national development strategies achieving climate neutrality is declared one of the priority targets. However, the legal acts of Ukraine do not contain e&#64256;ective legal mechanisms for ensuring climate neutrality. There are no norms in the legislation of Ukraine that would regulate the climate-protective use of land, aimed at preventing or at least reducing carbon emissions into the atmosphere in the process of farming. Farmers of Ukraine also faced the negative consequences of soil degradation. Despite the lack of a su&#64259;cient legal basis in national legislation, they began to search for ways to minimize such soil degradation by improving methods of soil cultivation in agriculture. One such method is carbon farming. It is a direction of climate protection activities, which involves the use of land resources, in which CO2 is e&#64256;ectively extracted from the atmosphere through plant photosynthesis and preserved in the form of organic matter in the soil and plant residues (carbon sequestration). In recent years, a new type of business activity has emerged in European countries &#8212; trading of reduced carbon emissions, and companies have appeared that o&#64256;er farmers to sell such reduced emissions. Recently, the international company Agreena entered the Ukrainian market, o&#64256;ering domestic agricultural producers to sell to it the amount of carbon retained in soils in the process of carbon farming. The Agreena company provides measurement and independent verification of the amount of carbon retained by a farm in the soil and turns it into a financial instrument in the form of carbon certificates. Such a system encourages those who have excess emissions to pay for it and allows those who reduce these emissions to earn from such reduction. At the same time, cases of the use of carbon farming technologies by Ukrainian agrarians are occurred solely as an initiative of the farmers themselves, who are guided by the motives of social responsibility, the desire to improve the environment, devotion to democratic values, etc. This state of legal regulation of carbon farming relations is unsatisfactory. Ukraine must significantly improve its climate policy and climate protection legislation in the sphere of regulation of agrarian and land relations. Obviously, the best option for the introduction of legal regulation of carbon farming is to combine in the legislation clear rules of behavior of the subjects of such relations, the introduction of a system of legal and economic incentives for the subjects to achieve the goal of the corresponding legal regulation, the provision of state support to farmers in the transition to carbon farming technologies, and as well as the implementation of state control over compliance of farmers who received state support in the application of carbon farming technologies with the relevant legal norms. It is expedient to base the formation of legal regulation of carbon farming on the principle of climate neutrality, which provides that any actions of subjects of legal relations must comply with carbon farming indicators established by the state. However, it is advisable to start the formation of a legal mechanism for the introduction of carbon farming based on &#171;soft&#187; law &#8212; a system of legal norms that contain recommendations and incentives for the transition of agricultural producers from traditional methods of farming to the standards of carbon farming. The state should promote the use of carbon farming methods by agrarians by approving and distributing recommendations on use of carbon farming methods by agricultural enterprises and farms in order to systematize and bring to the attention of agricultural producers the available, practice-tested knowledge in the field of modern climate protection farming technologies. The next step in the formation of legal support for carbon farming should be the introduction into legislation of legal norms aimed at providing economic stimulation of farmers' transition to carbon farming standards. The basis of such norms may be the carbon certification of soil cover of fields declared as lands of carbon agriculture. The legal mechanism for the transition of agricultural producers to the standards of carbon farming should be su&#64259;ciently simple and transparent. For its implementation, it seems appropriate to use the well-functioning system of the State Agrarian Register, which is an online platform for registering farmers who receive state support. Finally, as part of the legal mechanism for conducting carbon farming, might be provisions that regulate the carbon certification of agricultural producers who have switched to the principles of carbon farming. A clear system of carbon certification will ensure the implementation of e&#64256;ective state control over the achieved volumes of carbon retained in the soil and will contribute to the introduction of targeted stimulation of agricultural producers. In the future, with an increase in the level of e&#64256;ectiveness of state control over the use and protection of land with the use of advanced information technologies such as remote sensing of land and soil, the ratio between the norms of &#171;soft&#187; and &#171;hard&#187; law in the legal mechanism of conducting carbon farming will change to the benefit of the latter. Key words: climate, human rights, climate policy, green transition, carbon agriculture, land, law.</description>
      <author>Pavlo Kulynych</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33663/0869-2491-2024-35-442-457</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
