<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 01:19:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the Effect of Crystal Facet of Derived&#8208;Copper Catalysts on the Electroreduction of Carbon Dioxide under Unified Mass Transport Condition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415590</link>
      <description>Zi-Hao Zhao, Dan Ren, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403790511

                Altering the physical structure and chemical property of copper, i.e., particle size, surface morphology, composition or crystal facet, has been demonstrated to be effective in steering the selectivity of products in electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide. However, these modifications generally result in the change of active surface area, leading to differences in the geometric current density and local pH, which are also demonstrated to be the key factors for observed selectivity change. In this work, we deconvolute the effect of mass transport and local pH from the effect of crystal facet by investigating five copper&#8208;based catalysts with identical roughness factors for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide in an H&#8208;cell. Interestingly, CuO&#8208;derived catalyst stands out as the best catalyst for C&#8208;C coupling. At &#8208;1.07 V vs. RHE, the faradaic efficiency of C2+ product reaches 44.3%, with a partial current density of &#8208;10.8 mA cm&#8208;2. Electrochemical adsorption of *OH reveals that the C2+ product selectivity of derived&#8208;copper catalysts correlates positively with the ratio of Cu(100)/Cu(110) of five catalysts. Additionally, in situ Raman spectroscopy reveals that the percentage of low&#8208;frequency band linear CO (LFB&#8208;CO), which is attributed to the adsorbed *CO on Cu(100) facet, increases with the C&#8208;C coupling efficiency.</description>
      <author>Zi-Hao Zhao, Dan Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Spectroscopy in Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05827</link>
      <description>Yingshan Xue, Miao He, Ping Wang, Cheng Yang, Jiasai Yao, Tianbao Zhang, Hao Xu, Xiaohua Sun, Zhenxing Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403888921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingshan Xue, Miao He, Ping Wang, Cheng Yang, Jiasai Yao, Tianbao Zhang, Hao Xu, Xiaohua Sun, Zhenxing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of TM-based dual-atom catalysts supported by B,N-doped biphenylene for carbon dioxide reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161651</link>
      <description>Maryam Fallahzadeh, Alireza Kokabi, Zahra Nasiri, Mina Fayazi, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403909620

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maryam Fallahzadeh, Alireza Kokabi, Zahra Nasiri, Mina Fayazi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Charge Distribution in Atomically Precise Metal Nanoclusters for Boosted CO2 Reduction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402085</link>
      <description>Yuanxin Du, Sheng Wang, Yi Fang, Manzhou Zhu, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403915766

                Recently, atomically precise metal nanoclusters (NCs) have been widely applied in CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), achieving exciting activity and selectivity and revealing structure&#8208;performance correlation. However, at present, the efficiency of CO2RR is still unsatisfactory and cannot meet the requirements of practical applications. One of the main reasons is the difficulty in CO2 activation due to the chemical inertness of CO2. Constructing symmetry&#8208;breaking active sites is regarded as an effective strategy to promote CO2 activation by modulating electronic and geometric structure of CO2 molecule. In addition, in the subsequent CO2RR process, asymmetric charge distributed sites can break the charge balance in adjacent adsorbed C1 intermediates and suppress electrostatic repulsion between dipoles, benefiting for C&#8208;C coupling to generate C2+ products. Although compared to single atoms, metal nanoparticles, and inorganic materials the research on the construction of asymmetric catalytic sites in metal NCs is in a newly&#8208;developing stage, the precision, adjustability and diversity of metal NCs structure provide many possibilities to build asymmetric sites. This review summarizes several strategies of construction asymmetric charge distribution in metal NCs for boosting CO2RR, concludes the mechanism investigation paradigm of NCs&#8208;based catalysts, and proposes the challenges and opportunities of NCs catalysis.</description>
      <author>Yuanxin Du, Sheng Wang, Yi Fang, Manzhou Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 reduction by chars obtained by pyrolysis of real wastes: low temperature adsorption and high temperature CO2 capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100332</link>
      <description>Norbert Miskolczi, Ningbo Gao, C. Quan, Aradi L&#225;szl&#243;, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403915846

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Norbert Miskolczi, Ningbo Gao, C. Quan, Aradi L&#225;szl&#243;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando condition modeling CO2 electrocatalytic reduction on Ni-N-C single atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5283403/v1</link>
      <description>M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang, Fan Wu, Yulan Han, Zhiyao Duan, P. Hu, Ke Ye, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403903397

                Abstract The performance of electrocatalysts is shaped not solely by the inherent structures of active sites but also by factors like the charge accumulation on the electrode surface and the electric double-layer (EDL) structure formed at the interface between the electrode and electrolyte. At present, accurately modeling the electrochemical reactions occurring at EDL is a great challenge, mainly because the dynamic chemical change cannot be adequately captured by the commonly used static configurations. Ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations face difficulty sampling across both time and space scales. Here, utilizing Ni-N-C/G catalysis CO2 reduction to CO as a framework to examine, we explored the catalytic process affected by EDL and accumulated electron on electrode under operando conditions by integrating grand canonical density functional theory (GC-DFT) calculations with classical molecular dynamic (MD) simulations. The findings suggest that the negative charge accumulating on the cathode material plays a crucial role in facilitating the adsorption and activation of CO2. Additionally, incorporating two intermediates, *COO + OH- and *CO + OH-, can significantly enhance the accuracy of the free energy profile. Moreover, the EDL can not only enhance the adsorption of CO2 and promote the cleavage of the C-OH (in the *COOH intermediate) but also inhibit the desorption of CO to some extent. Compared to the promotional effect induced by cations coordinating with intermediates, the primary promoting factor lies in the electric field (EF around 85%) distributed around the intermediates. With the inclusion of the EDL correction, our calculations align well with experimental observations, showing that for the CO2 reduction to CO on the Ni-N-C site, as the applied potential becomes increasingly negative, the rate-determining step shifts from *COOH formation to CO desorption at -0.60 VRHE. Our work not only explains a long-standing puzzle for an important catalyst but also highlights the crucial roles of EDL effects, which provide guidance on investigating electrochemical reactions without compromising the complexity of the electrode environment.</description>
      <author>M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang, Fan Wu, Yulan Han, Zhiyao Duan, P. Hu, Ke Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5283403/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating butanol&#8211;gasoline blend reforming process towards sustainable CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133526</link>
      <description>Moloud Mardani, Jagdeep K Singh, Omid Doustdar, S. Zeraati-Rezaei, Jos&#233; Mart&#237;n Herreros, Paul Millington, John Pignon, A. Tsolakis, Fuel. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403917364

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Moloud Mardani, Jagdeep K Singh, Omid Doustdar, S. Zeraati-Rezaei, Jos&#233; Mart&#237;n Herreros, Paul Millington, John Pignon, A. Tsolakis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near&#8208;Infrared Light&#8208;Driven CO2 Reduction on Cup&#8208;Stacked Carbon Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415173</link>
      <description>Suchan Song, Cuncun Xin, Wei Liu, Wenzhe Shang, Tianna Liu, Wentao Peng, Jungang Hou, Yantao Shi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403914555

                Carbon nanotubes feature one&#8208;dimensional nature of collective excitations, wherein strong confinement of surface plasmons severely hinders the liberation of hot electrons (HEs), posing grand challenges for their utilization in photochemistry. In this study, we prototypically achieved directed HEs flow and extraction in hybrid plasmonic CNN based on cup&#8208;stacked carbon nanotubes (CSCNTs), taking advantage of their privileged edge&#8208;plane sites. The localized pz electronic states and accessible intersubband plasmon excitations in the near&#8208;infrared (NIR) regime stands in striking contrast to the conventional concentric carbon nanotubes, as evidenced by combined photo&#8208;induced force microscopy (PiFM) and transient photocurrent response. The hybrid comprising intimately integrated CSCNTs&#8208;C3N4 effectively sustains interfacial electronic states and underlies the energy extraction out of plasmonic components. The CNN demonstrates almost near&#8208;unity NIR light&#8208;driven CO2 reduction to CO with a rate of 1.35 &#181;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1. This work sheds light on the exploitation of metal&#8208;free carbon&#8208;based plasmonic nanostructures for photocatalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Suchan Song, Cuncun Xin, Wei Liu, Wenzhe Shang, Tianna Liu, Wentao Peng, Jungang Hou, Yantao Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near&#8208;Infrared Light&#8208;Driven CO2 Reduction on Cup&#8208;Stacked Carbon Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415173</link>
      <description>Suchan Song, Cuncun Xin, Wei Ma, Wenzhe Shang, Tianna Liu, Wentao Peng, Jungang Hou, Yantao Shi, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403915101

                Carbon nanotubes feature one&#8208;dimensional nature of collective excitations, wherein strong confinement of surface plasmons severely hinders the liberation of hot electrons (HEs), posing grand challenges for their utilization in photochemistry. In this study, we prototypically achieved directed HEs flow and extraction in hybrid plasmonic CNN based on cup&#8208;stacked carbon nanotubes (CSCNTs), taking advantage of their privileged edge&#8208;plane sites. The localized pz electronic states and accessible intersubband plasmon excitations in the near&#8208;infrared (NIR) regime stands in striking contrast to the conventional concentric carbon nanotubes, as evidenced by combined photo&#8208;induced force microscopy (PiFM) and transient photocurrent response. The hybrid comprising intimately integrated CSCNTs&#8208;C3N4 effectively sustains interfacial electronic states and underlies the energy extraction out of plasmonic components. The CNN demonstrates almost near&#8208;unity NIR light&#8208;driven CO2 reduction to CO with a rate of 1.35 &#181;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1. This work sheds light on the exploitation of metal&#8208;free carbon&#8208;based plasmonic nanostructures for photocatalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Suchan Song, Cuncun Xin, Wei Ma, Wenzhe Shang, Tianna Liu, Wentao Peng, Jungang Hou, Yantao Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Proton Source for CO2 Electro-reduction on Cu(100) using Many-body Perturbation Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l6k5g-v2</link>
      <description>Dongfang Cheng, Ziyang Wei, Philippe Sautet, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403873268

                The protonation of CO is recognized as the rate-determining step in the generation of C1 products during the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) on Cu surfaces. Despite its importance, the detailed mechanism and the precise proton source for this elementary step remain elusive and are under intense debate. Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations have been used to investigate such a mechanism. However, semi-local functionals at the generalized gradient approximation (GGA) level face significant challenges in accurately describing adsorbate-metal interactions and surface stability. In this work, we employed the Random Phase Approximation (RPA), a method based on many-body perturbation theory, to overcome these limitations. We coupled the RPA framework with the linearized Poisson&#8211;Boltzmann equation to model solvation effects and incorporated a surface charging method to account for the influence of the electrochemical potential. Our study reveals that, in neutral or alkaline electrolytes, adsorbed water at the surface acts as the proton source for the reduction of *CO to *COH over a wide range of potentials via the Grotthuss mechanism. At highly negative potentials, solvent water becomes the primary proton donor, with multiple competing mechanisms observed. In contrast, DFT-GGA functionals not only significantly underestimate the reaction barriers for *COH formation but also consistently predict solvent water as the proton source across all the potentials of interest. Additionally, RPA offers distinct insights into H2O adsorption and highlights the significant range of reducing potential within which surface *OH can exist, which is crucial for accurate CO2RR modeling. These potential-dependent thermodynamic and kinetic data illustrate a pronounced divergence between the mechanistic insights offered by RPA and those derived from DFT-GGA functionals. Our findings offer a fresh perspective on proton transfer in CO2RR and establish a framework for future theoretical studies of electrochemical processes.</description>
      <author>Dongfang Cheng, Ziyang Wei, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l6k5g-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Evaluation and Statistical Analysis of Green Materials for CO2 Reduction Using Fly Ash Mixture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003495437-4</link>
      <description>P. Manikandan, E. Veeramanipriya, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403915771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P. Manikandan, E. Veeramanipriya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003495437-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni@S-1 facilitated efficient reduction of CO2-containing CO via chemical looping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133475</link>
      <description>Ping Jin, Yuhao Wang, Kongzhai Li, Hua Wang, Yane Zheng, Fuel. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403918088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ping Jin, Yuhao Wang, Kongzhai Li, Hua Wang, Yane Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Limestone Powder as Concrete Addition -Recommendation for the Creditability Using K-Value and Potential for the Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999675</link>
      <description>Christian Herget, Tilo Proske, Moien Rezvani, Carl-Alexaner Graubner, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403757822

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Christian Herget, Tilo Proske, Moien Rezvani, Carl-Alexaner Graubner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible control of Co/Zn-nitrogen coordination in ZIFs for electrochemical CO2 reduction to tunable syngas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04624b</link>
      <description>Yanjun Liu, Ning Yuan, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403855446

                Bimetallic CoxZny-ZIF catalysts were synthesized with adjustable Co/Zn-nitrogen sites for the electrochemical CO2RR to tunable syngas, resulting in a H2/CO ratio ranging from 1:1 to 4:1. The excellent CO2 adsorption...</description>
      <author>Yanjun Liu, Ning Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04624b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering intricacies of implementing single-atom alloy catalysts for low-temperature electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101164</link>
      <description>Isaac Kojo Seim, Manjeet Chhetri, John&#8208;Paul Jones, Ming Yang, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403860092

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Isaac Kojo Seim, Manjeet Chhetri, John&#8208;Paul Jones, Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrophobic carbon quantum dots with Lewis-Basic nitrogen sites for electrocatalyst CO2 reduction to CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157207</link>
      <description>Shuai Fu, Bijun Tang, Zeming Wang, Guoliang An, Mingwan Zhang, Kang Wang, Wenhui Liu, Huazhang Guo, Baohua Zhang, Jiajia Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403904212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Fu, Bijun Tang, Zeming Wang, Guoliang An, Mingwan Zhang, Kang Wang, Wenhui Liu, Huazhang Guo, Baohua Zhang, Jiajia Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157207</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Co2 Reduction to Hcooh Over Heterostructured Cu/Sn Interface in a Wide Negative Potential Window</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5006239</link>
      <description>Wei Bing, Jinyong Zhang, Jingtong Zhang, Ling&#8208;Ling Li, Naidi Tan, Zhe Chen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403925337

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Bing, Jinyong Zhang, Jingtong Zhang, Ling&#8208;Ling Li, Naidi Tan, Zhe Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5006239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Carbon Support Ozonation on the Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 to Formate and Syngas in a Flow Cell on Pd Nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101727</link>
      <description>Milla Suominen, Junjie Shi, Jani Sainio, Amine Hammouali, Lilian Moumaneix, Anna Kobets, Tanja Kallio, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403916403

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Milla Suominen, Junjie Shi, Jani Sainio, Amine Hammouali, Lilian Moumaneix, Anna Kobets, Tanja Kallio</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>p-d Orbital Coupling in Silicon-Based Dual-Atom Catalysts for Enhanced CO2 Reduction: Insight into Electron Regulation of Active Center and Coordination Atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06642a</link>
      <description>Meijie Wang, Yaowei Xiang, Yuxing Lin, Jing Wang, Zi&#8208;Zhong Zhu, Shunqing Wu, Xinrui Cao, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403850850

                Transition metal (TM) dual-atom catalysts (DACs) show promise for carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) through d-d orbital cooperative interactions, but their effectiveness is often curtailed by the linear scaling relations...</description>
      <author>Meijie Wang, Yaowei Xiang, Yuxing Lin, Jing Wang, Zi&#8208;Zhong Zhu, Shunqing Wu, Xinrui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06642a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the potential of deep eutectic solvents in biocatalysis: design strategies using CO2 to formate reduction as a case study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1467810</link>
      <description>Marijan Logaru&#353;i&#263;, Karla &#352;ubar, Maja Nikoli&#263;, Ana Jurinjak Tu&#353;ek, Anja Damjanovi&#263;, Mia Radovi&#263;, Ivana Radoj&#269;i&#263; Redovnikovi&#263;, Polona &#381;nidar&#353;i&#269;&#8211;Plazl, Wolfgang Kroutil, Marina Cvjetko Bubalo, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403779153

                Introduction Deep eutectic solvents (DESs) have emerged as green solvents with versatile applications, demonstrating significant potential in biocatalysis. They often increase the solubility of poorly water-soluble substrates, serve as smart co-substrates, modulate enzyme stereoselectivity, and potentially improve enzyme activity and stability. Despite these advantages, screening for an optimal DES and determining the appropriate water content for a given biocatalytic reaction remains a complex and time-consuming process, posing a significant challenge. Methods This paper discusses the rational design of DES tailored to a given biocatalytic system through a combination of experimental screening and computational tools, guided by performance targets defined by solvent properties and process constraints. The efficacy of this approach is demonstrated by the reduction of CO 2 to formate catalyzed by NADH-dependent formate dehydrogenase (FDH). By systematically analyzing FDH activity and stability, NADH stability (both long-term and short-term stability after solvent saturation with CO 2 ), and CO 2 solubility in initially selected glycerol-based DESs, we were able to skillfully guide the DES screening process. Results and discussion Considering trade-offs between experimentally determined performance metrics of DESs, 20% solution of choline chloride:glycerol in phosphate buffer (ChCl:Gly 80%B ) was identified as the most promising solvent system for a given reaction. Using ChCl:Gly as a co-solvent resulted in an almost 15-fold increase in FDH half-life compared to the reference buffer and stabilized the coenzyme after the addition of CO 2 . Moreover, the 20% addition of ChCl:Gly to the buffer improved the volumetric productivity of FDH-catalyzed CO 2 reduction in a batch system compared to the reference buffer. The exceptional stability of the enzyme in this co-solvent system shows great potential for application in continuous operation, which can significantly improve process productivity. Additionally, based on easily measurable physicochemical solvent properties and molecular descriptors derived from COSMO-RS, QSAR models were developed, which successfully predicted enzyme activity and stability, as well as coenzyme stability in selected solvent systems with DESs.</description>
      <author>Marijan Logaru&#353;i&#263;, Karla &#352;ubar, Maja Nikoli&#263;, Ana Jurinjak Tu&#353;ek, Anja Damjanovi&#263;, Mia Radovi&#263;, Ivana Radoj&#269;i&#263; Redovnikovi&#263;, Polona &#381;nidar&#353;i&#269;&#8211;Plazl, Wolfgang Kroutil, Marina Cvjetko Bubalo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1467810</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining and Cybersecurity-Driven Solutions for CO2 Emissions Reduction of Different Maritime Shipping: A Multi-Faceted Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36227/techrxiv.173030522.24669178/v1</link>
      <description>Saeed Rahimpour, Mahtab Shahin, Yigit G&#252;lmez, Sanja Bauk, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403922693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saeed Rahimpour, Mahtab Shahin, Yigit G&#252;lmez, Sanja Bauk</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36227/techrxiv.173030522.24669178/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photoelectrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CO via structure-induced carrier separation in coral-like CuBi2O4-Bi2O3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130319</link>
      <description>Guorui Liu, Wei Ma, Haiqiang Mu, Jing Li, Feng Li, Min Zhu, J. Zhang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403915363

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guorui Liu, Wei Ma, Haiqiang Mu, Jing Li, Feng Li, Min Zhu, J. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental assessment of the use of ground olive stones in mortars. Reduction of CO2 emissions and production of sustainable mortars for buildings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eiar.2024.107709</link>
      <description>Jorge Los Santos-Ortega, Esteban Fraile-Garc&#237;a, Javier Ferreiro&#8208;Cabello, Environmental Impact Assessment Review. 110(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403929509

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jorge Los Santos-Ortega, Esteban Fraile-Garc&#237;a, Javier Ferreiro&#8208;Cabello</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eiar.2024.107709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green growth in Africa: The role of renewable energy, biocapacity, government policies, and R&amp;amp;D on CO2 emissions reductions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123089</link>
      <description>Kyei Emmanuel Yeboah, Junwen Feng, Seidu Abdulai Jamatutu, Prince Amoako, Felicia Esi Nyarko, Nabila Amin, Journal of Environmental Management. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403929354

                Africa's abundant natural resources and renewable energy potential offer long-term prosperity, but the continent is still challenged with several hurdles in exploiting these resources efficiently. This study examines the prospect for sustainable growth in Africa about the impacts of renewable energy, biocapacity, government policies, research and development (R&amp;D), and population growth on CO2 emissions. By employing multiple advanced regression modeling techniques such as Dynamic Common Correlated Effects (DCCE), Common Correlated Effects Generalized (CCEG), and Bootstrap Quantile Regression (BSQR), the study analyzed the correlations between these variables using data from 19 African countries, spanning from 2000 to 2020. While the results showed renewable energy and bio-capacity to significantly reduce CO2 emissions in all countries, government policies and R&amp;D expenditure show differentiated effects on CO2 emission across countries. Additionally, population growth was found to be a critical factor in exacerbating CO2 emissions in Africa. Observing the lack of connection between government policy and the taping of green potentials in Africa, the findings highlight the need for targeted government policies that can promote renewable energy infrastructure, protection of biocapacity through sustainable land use practices, and increased support of R&amp;D on green technologies.</description>
      <author>Kyei Emmanuel Yeboah, Junwen Feng, Seidu Abdulai Jamatutu, Prince Amoako, Felicia Esi Nyarko, Nabila Amin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogenization of a Sandwich [(PW9O34)2Co4(H2O)2]10&#8722; in PCN&#8211;222/PCN&#8211;222(M): Exploring the Electron Transfer for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400485</link>
      <description>Lei Shu, Can Li, Meng-Ting Peng, Mengjie Liu, Yun&#8208;Lei Teng, Bao&#8208;Xia Dong, European Journal of Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403901595

                In this study, we designed and prepared polyoxometalate@metal&#8208;organic framework (POM@MOF) composite catalysts through the anchoring of a sandwich POM [(PW9O34)2Co4(H2O)2]10&#8722; (shortened as P2W18Co4) to the hexagonal channel of the PCN&#8211;222 (metal&#8208;free) or PCN&#8211;222(M) (M=Fe, Co) frameworks. The composite materials were applied to the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 reaction (CO2RR) to analyse the effect of incorporating P2W18Co4 on catalytic activity. The P2W18Co4@PCN&#8211;222 composite exhibited enhanced activity across a wide potential range (&#8211;0.60~ &#8211;0.85 V vs. RHE) and an optimal FECO of 72% at &#8211;0.75 V vs. RHE, which was more than double that of PCN&#8211;222 (FECO= 33%). The current density surpassed that of the PCN&#8211;222 precursors by over sixteen times at the same potential. In contrast, the P2W18Co4@PCN&#8211;222(M) composite demonstrated decreased current density, minimal enhancement in CO2RR activity, and a competing HER behaviour. Density functional theory calculations were conducted on simplified models of P2W18Co4@H2&#8211;TCPP and P2W18Co4@M&#8211;TCPP to elucidate the divergent catalytic performances. The findings revealed that while both configurations exhibited the same rate&#8208;limiting step (formation of the *COOH intermediate), a significantly reduced reaction barrier was only observed in the P2W18Co4@H2&#8211;TCPP setup, explaining its substantial activity improvement.</description>
      <author>Lei Shu, Can Li, Meng-Ting Peng, Mengjie Liu, Yun&#8208;Lei Teng, Bao&#8208;Xia Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulations of Photovoltaic Systems on Different Types of Ships in Sweden; Solar Energy Generation, Comparison to Energy Consumption and Reduction of Co2 Emission</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5001638</link>
      <description>Joachim Wallenstein, Judi Ellis, Erik Johansson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403832145

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joachim Wallenstein, Judi Ellis, Erik Johansson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5001638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of H2-water mass transfer using methyl-modified hollow mesoporous silica nanoparticles for efficient microbial CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceja.2024.100666</link>
      <description>Xiaojun Bian, Qiangqiang Wang, Rufan Zhou, Ye Yang, Zhongjian Li, Chemical Engineering Journal Advances. 20(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403817319

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojun Bian, Qiangqiang Wang, Rufan Zhou, Ye Yang, Zhongjian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceja.2024.100666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature-controlled in-situ construction of composition-tunable nanoparticle-decorated SOFC cathodes with enhanced oxygen reduction kinetics and CO2 tolerance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compositesb.2024.111917</link>
      <description>Chuangang Yao, Baixi Xia, Haixia Zhang, Haocong Wang, Wenwen Zhang, Xiaoshi Lang, Kedi Cai, Composites Part B Engineering. 288(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403911658

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuangang Yao, Baixi Xia, Haixia Zhang, Haocong Wang, Wenwen Zhang, Xiaoshi Lang, Kedi Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compositesb.2024.111917</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect of multi-metal site provided by Ni-N4, adjacent single metal atom, and Fe6 nanoparticle to boost CO2 activation and reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.166</link>
      <description>Zongchang Mao, Guanping Wei, Lingli Liu, Tiantian Hao, Xijun Wang, Shaobin Tang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403876243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongchang Mao, Guanping Wei, Lingli Liu, Tiantian Hao, Xijun Wang, Shaobin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing a novel double Z-type junction BaTiO3/ZnIn2S4/ZnTiO3 by a new chemical reaction for antibiotics degradation, H2 production, and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114594</link>
      <description>Bangfu Ding, Kaitian Zuo, Lei Zhang, Shuaiqi Liu, Shukai Zheng, Liang Mao, Junying Zhang, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403926027

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bangfu Ding, Kaitian Zuo, Lei Zhang, Shuaiqi Liu, Shukai Zheng, Liang Mao, Junying Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;One stone two birds&#8221;&#8212;Solar energy driven CO2 reduction and seawater desalination coupling reactions using floatable and recyclable integrated system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157185</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Zhang, Shiye Lou, You Yin, Xing Lv, Hao Yu, Chendong Zhuge, Lina Zhang, Lili Liu, Dongen Zhang, Linxing Shi, Chemical Engineering Journal. 500(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885919

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Zhang, Shiye Lou, You Yin, Xing Lv, Hao Yu, Chendong Zhuge, Lina Zhang, Lili Liu, Dongen Zhang, Linxing Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157185</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lowering rate-determining step energy barrier to promote electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to multicarbon products over oxygen-rich vacancy CuO catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.260</link>
      <description>Zhiyuan Ni, Tao Yu, Xiang Li, Chunming Liu, Junhua You, Xuanwen Liu, Rui Guo, Hangzhou Zhang, Hongyu Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403906513

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyuan Ni, Tao Yu, Xiang Li, Chunming Liu, Junhua You, Xuanwen Liu, Rui Guo, Hangzhou Zhang, Hongyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal reduction of CO2 captured by aqueous amine solutions into formate: comparison between in situ generated H2 and gaseous H2 as reductant and evaluation of amine stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100333</link>
      <description>Laura Quintana-G&#243;mez, Luama Ara&#250;jo dos Santos, Fernando Cossio-Cid, V&#237;ctor Ciordia-Asenjo, Miguel Almarza, Alberto Goikoechea, Sergio Ferrero, Celedonio M. &#193;lvarez, Jos&#233; J. Segovia, &#193;ngel Mart&#237;n, M. Dolores Bermejo, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403901788

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Laura Quintana-G&#243;mez, Luama Ara&#250;jo dos Santos, Fernando Cossio-Cid, V&#237;ctor Ciordia-Asenjo, Miguel Almarza, Alberto Goikoechea, Sergio Ferrero, Celedonio M. &#193;lvarez, Jos&#233; J. Segovia, &#193;ngel Mart&#237;n, M. Dolores Bermejo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taming CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8226;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; via Synergistic Triple Catalysis in Anti-Markovnikov Hydrocarboxylation of Alkenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12294</link>
      <description>Pintu Ghosh, Sudip Maiti, Augustin Malandain, Dineshkumar Raja, Olivier Loreau, Bholanath Maity, Triptesh Kumar Roy, Davide Audisio, Debabrata Maiti, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403879351

                The direct utilization of carbon dioxide as an ideal one-carbon source in value-added chemical synthesis has garnered significant attention from the standpoint of global sustainability. In this regard, the photo/electrochemical reduction of CO2 into useful fuels and chemical feedstocks could offer a great promise for the transition to a carbon-neutral economy. However, challenges in product selectivity continue to limit the practical application of these systems. A robust and general method for the conversion of CO2 to the polarity-reversed carbon dioxide radical anion, a C1 synthon, is critical for the successful valorization of CO2 to selective carboxylation reactions. We demonstrate herein a hydride and hydrogen atom transfer synergy driven general catalytic platform involving CO2&#8226;&#8211; for highly selective anti-Markovnikov hydrocarboxylation of alkenes via triple photoredox, hydride, and hydrogen atom transfer catalysis. Mechanistic studies suggest that the synergistic operation of the triple catalytic cycle ensures a low-steady-state concentration of CO2&#8226;&#8211; in the reaction medium. This method using a renewable light energy source is mild, robust, selective, and capable of accommodating a wide range of activated and unactivated alkenes. The highly selective nature of the transformation has been revealed through the synthesis of hydrocarboxylic acids from the substrates bearing a hydrogen atom available for intramolecular 1,n-HAT process as well as diastereoselective synthesis. This technology represents a general strategy for the merger of in situ formate generation with a synergistic photoredox and HAA catalytic cycle to provide CO2&#8226;&#8211; for selective chemical transformations.</description>
      <author>Pintu Ghosh, Sudip Maiti, Augustin Malandain, Dineshkumar Raja, Olivier Loreau, Bholanath Maity, Triptesh Kumar Roy, Davide Audisio, Debabrata Maiti</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photothermal CO2 Hydrogenation to Methanol over Ni-In2O3/g-C3N4 Heterojunction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110756</link>
      <description>Xuekai Shan, Guolin Zhang, Shouxin Zhang, S. L. Zhang, Fang Guo, Qi Xu, Catalysts. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403835093

                Selective CO2 hydrogenation faces significant technical challenges, although many efforts have been made in this regard. Herein, a Ni-doped In2O3 catalyst supported by g-C3N4 was prepared using the co-precipitation method, and its composition, morphology, specific surface area, and band gap were characterized using TEM, XPS, BET, XRD, CO2-TPD, H2-TPR, UV-Vis, etc. The catalytic hydrogenation reduction of CO2 to produce methanol was tested. Under low-photothermal conditions (1.0 MPa), the hydrogenation of carbon dioxide to methanol is stable, effective, and highly selective, with a spatiotemporal yield of 86.0 gMeOHh&#8722;1 kgcat&#8722;1, which is 30.9% higher than that of Ni-In2O3 without g-C3N4 loading under the same conditions.</description>
      <author>Xuekai Shan, Guolin Zhang, Shouxin Zhang, S. L. Zhang, Fang Guo, Qi Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Synergy Between CO2 and Air Pollution Emissions in Chinese Cities by 2060: An Assessment Based on the Emissions Inventory and Dynamic Projection Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16219338</link>
      <description>Guosheng Wang, Wei Xia, Yang Xiao, X. L. Guan, Xin Zhang, Sustainability. 16(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403834976

                Synergizing air pollution control and climate change mitigation has been of significant academic and policy concern. The synergy between air pollution and carbon emissions is one of the measures to understand the characteristics and process of the air pollution&#8211;carbon synergistic control, which will also provide valuable information for collaboratively achieving Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) (such as SDGs 11 and 13). This study establishes a systematic framework integrating emissions inventory and projection models, correlation mining and typology analysis methods to predictively evaluate the synergy and comprehensive coordination between air pollution and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions in Chinese cities by 2030, 2050, and 2060 under different policy scenarios for air pollution and CO2 emissions control. The results reveal the significant effects of synergistically implementing clean air and aggressive carbon-reducing policies on mitigating air pollution and CO2 emissions. Under the On-time Peak-Net Zero-Clean Air and Early Peak-Net Zero-Clean Air scenarios, the total reduction and synergy for air pollution and CO2 emissions will be more significant, particularly by 2050 and 2060. This study is the first to integrate scenario projection and synergy evaluation in air pollution and CO2 research, providing a novel supplement to the air pollution&#8211;climate change synergy methodology based on co-benefit estimation. The methods and findings will also contribute to measuring the achievement and analyzing the interaction of the SDGs.</description>
      <author>Guosheng Wang, Wei Xia, Yang Xiao, X. L. Guan, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16219338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sources and Variability of Greenhouse Gases over Greece</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15111288</link>
      <description>A. Bougiatioti, Nikos Gialesakis, Yannis Sarafidis, Maria I. Gini, Marios Mermigkas, Panayiotis Kalkavouras, S. Mirasgedis, Michel Ramonet, Cl&#233;ment Narbaud, Morgan Lopez, Dimitris Balis, Konstantinos Eleftheriadis, Maria Kanakidou, N. Mihalopoulos, Atmosphere. 15(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403843514

                This study provides an overview of the atmospheric drivers of climate change over Greece (Eastern Mediterranean), focusing on greenhouse gases (GHG: carbon dioxide, CO2; methane, CH4; etc.). CO2 in Greece is mostly produced by energy production, followed by transport, construction, and industry. Waste management is the largest anthropogenic source of methane, accounting for 47% of total CH4 emissions, surpassing emissions from the agricultural sector in 2017, while the energy sector accounts for the remaining 10.5%. In situ simultaneous observations of GHG concentrations in Greece conducted at three sites with different topologies (urban background; Athens, regional background; Finokalia and free troposphere; and Helmos) during the last 5 years (2019&#8211;2023) showed increasing trends of the order of 2.2 ppm&#183;yr&#8722;1 and ~15 ppb&#183;yr&#8722;1 for CO2 and CH4, respectively, in line with the global trends. These increasing trends were found from both ground-based and satellite-based remote-sensing observations. Finally, during the lockdown period due to the COVID-19 global pandemic, a 58% reduction in CO2 levels was observed in the urban background site of Athens after subtracting the regional background levels from Finokalia, while the respective reduction in CH4 was of only the order of 15%, highlighting differences in emission sources.</description>
      <author>A. Bougiatioti, Nikos Gialesakis, Yannis Sarafidis, Maria I. Gini, Marios Mermigkas, Panayiotis Kalkavouras, S. Mirasgedis, Michel Ramonet, Cl&#233;ment Narbaud, Morgan Lopez, Dimitris Balis, Konstantinos Eleftheriadis, Maria Kanakidou, N. Mihalopoulos</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15111288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Circular Economy Principles for Electrical Submersible Pump Equipment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221530-ms</link>
      <description>Munder Al-Hashem, S. Al-Aseef, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403822091

                Abstract This paper presents a comprehensive analysis of implementing circular economy principles in the electrical submersible pump (ESP) industry to enhance sustainability and reduce carbon footprint. Focusing on the Dismantle, Inspection, and Failure Analysis (DIFA) process, the study quantifies its impact on carbon emissions and evaluates key practices, such as component refurbishment and recycling. The research examines how collaboration between vendors and customers for failure analysis generates valuable insights, leading to enhanced product life and decreased manufacturing requirements. The findings demonstrate significant reductions in carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions associated with rig operations and component production. This research contributes novel insights into ESP afterlife and circular business models, filling a gap in petroleum industry literature and offering a framework for sustainable practices in artificial lift systems.</description>
      <author>Munder Al-Hashem, S. Al-Aseef</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221530-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Methanation: A Bibliometric Analysis and Review of Activated Carbon-Based Materials (2014 &#8211; 2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ce/zkae082</link>
      <description>Stephen Okiemute Akpasi, Yusuf Makarfi Isa, Thembisile Patience Monama, Sammy Lewis Kiambi, Peterson Thokozani Ngema, Clean Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403851253

                Abstract This study highlights the significant potential of activated carbon-based materials in environmental remediation and energy production, particularly in converting carbon dioxide (CO2) and hydrogen (H2) into methane (CH4) and water (H2O) using transition metal-based catalysts. It emphasizes the role of porous AC in waste reduction and resource utilization, examining various applications of CO2 and evaluating environmental impacts. The research explores commercialization opportunities and specifically investigates CO2 methanation using activated carbon-based materials. Using bibliometric analyses of 4196 articles from the Web of Science database, the study identifies a growing research interest in porous activated carbon-related CO2 methanation from 2014 to 2024. The top three journals in this field are Environment Development and Sustainability, Biomass Conversion and Biorefinery, and Journal of Environment Science and Pollution. However, there is limited inter-institutional collaboration in this field, suggesting room for development towards commercializing sustainable CH4 production pathways. CH4 is highlighted as a crucial intermediate in industrial processes, and research directions are identified through co-occurring author keywords analysis. The study suggests the need for a comprehensive approach integrating activated carbon materials into carbon-neutral energy processes while addressing the potential adverse effects of activated carbon nanoparticles on biological and environmental factors. Ultimately, it clarifies the potential uses and commercialization prospects for porous AC materials, especially in conjunction with carbon capture and utilization technologies, promoting sustainable practices in energy production and environmental management.</description>
      <author>Stephen Okiemute Akpasi, Yusuf Makarfi Isa, Thembisile Patience Monama, Sammy Lewis Kiambi, Peterson Thokozani Ngema</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ce/zkae082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Carbon Potential of Mangrove Ecosystems and Its Management to Promote Climate Change Mitigation in Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22146/jik.v18i2.11447</link>
      <description>Rahman Rahman, Frijona F. Lokollo, Mintje Wawo, Ardan Ceanturi, Yona A. Lewerissa, Mahriyana Hulopi, Luluk Dwi Wulan Handayani, Muhammad Zuhri, Hefni Effendi, Yusli Wardiatno, Jurnal Ilmu Kehutanan. 18(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403909106

                This research aimed to analyze blue carbon potential and mangrove ecosystem management in promoting climate change mitigation in Indonesia. The collected data included mangrove area data obtained through the Indonesian National Ecosystem Monitoring System (SIMONTANA). This research calculated the carbon stock using the global average of mangrove carbon stock. The results showed that the total blue carbon stored in mangrove ecosystems reached 3,267.87 Megaton Carbon (MtC). Papua and Kalimantan regions contributed the most significant potential, with 1,707.22 MtC and 608.17 MtC, respectively. The absorption of carbon dioxide (CO2) reached 11,982.21 MtCO2e. The most significant CO2 gas emissions absorption was observed in the Papua region, amounting to 6,259.80 MtCO2e, followed by Sumatra with 2,118.59 MtCO2e. This high potential value correlated with mangrove ecosystem management policies, such as conservation, restoration, and blue carbon monetization. Mangrove management for climate change mitigation was carried out through national and international cooperation to achieve the 26% to 40% emission reduction target. The existing management model of mangrove ecosystems focused on improving ecological sustainability with less orientation on improving community welfare. Implementing blue carbon monetization at the district level by involving the community as the owners or managers of the mangrove ecosystems is crucial.</description>
      <author>Rahman Rahman, Frijona F. Lokollo, Mintje Wawo, Ardan Ceanturi, Yona A. Lewerissa, Mahriyana Hulopi, Luluk Dwi Wulan Handayani, Muhammad Zuhri, Hefni Effendi, Yusli Wardiatno</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22146/jik.v18i2.11447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDYING THE EFFECT OF MAGNETIC FLUX ON DIESEL FUEL LINE ON SOME PERFORMANCE AND EMISSION OF DIESEL ENGINE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36103/nt9myb06</link>
      <description>Moiz Mohammed, Naseer S. Kadhim, Naveed Imran, IRAQI JOURNAL OF AGRICULTURAL SCIENCES. 55(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403797003

                This study aimed to investigation was carried out to evaluate the performance and product emission of four cylinder 4- stroke water cooled direct injection (DI) diesel engine fueled by permanent magnet exposed diesel fuel compared with diesel fuel (DF). Three levels of magnet field intensity were used including Diesel fuel exposer to 3000 Gauss (DG3), Diesel fuel exposer to 5000 Gauss (DG5) and Diesel fuel exposer to 9000 Gauss (DG9) fuel respectively. Permanent magnetic device was employed and installed on fuel line before interring high pressure fuel injection pump . The engine run at constant speed 1500rpm(revolution per minute) and loaded by two levels 4.5 kW and 9 kW represented as L1and L2 respectively. Results obtained showed that fuel DG5 registered an increased in thermal efficiency(TE) about 20.09% at load L1 compared with DF. Maximum reduction in brake specific fuel consumption (bsfc) about 12.12%, when using DG5 fuel at load 1 compared to DF fuel. All exhaust emission Unburned Hydrocarbon (UHC), Carbon Monoxide (CO), Carbon Dioxide (CO2),Particular Maters (PM), and Nitrogen Oxides (NOx) are decreased when diesel fuel treated with different magnetic intensities 3000,5000 and 9000 Gauss. Compared with conventional diesel fuel. Maximum reduction in PM,HC,NOx,CO2,and CO about 16.56-27.08%, 3.89&#8211;64.26%, 4.79&#8211;7.91%, 4.05-5.71and 11.46-53.48% respectively. CO2 emission was increased by 1.65-4.28 at DG5 with L1 and L2 respectively due to the operating conditions.</description>
      <author>Moiz Mohammed, Naseer S. Kadhim, Naveed Imran</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36103/nt9myb06</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Study on the Potential for the Application of Peanut Shells as a Reducer in the Process of Metal Recovery from Metallurgical Slags</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16219261</link>
      <description>&#321;ukasz Kortyka, J. &#321;abaj, Szymon Ptak, A. Smalcerz, L. Blacha, &#321;ukasz My&#263;ka, T. Matu&#322;a, R&#243;bert Findor&#225;k, Sustainability. 16(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403765328

                Copper production technology is a complex process consisting of many stages. The combination of pyrometallurgical and hydrometallurgical stages, on the one hand, complicates production while, on the other hand, allowing for a relatively selective separation of intermediate or waste materials that can be subjected to the process of recovery of useful components. Materials of this type are characterised by a much higher copper content relative to the ore material. On the other hand, due to the oxide form, reduction processes are used in which coke is mainly applied. Reduction of the unfavourable phenomenon of CO2 emissions, in this case, can be performed through the use of bioreducers, which are characterised by an inert carbon footprint since the generation of carbon dioxides is the same as its absorption at the stage of vegetation and growth. In this paper, the topic of determining the feasibility of using selected bioreducers, such as peanut shells, to verify their suitability in the process of reducing copper oxides as well as the impact on the working components of the laboratory reactor in which the process is carried out are discussed. In this case, raw materials with a composition similar to the that of slags produced at the copper production stage in a flash furnace were tested for reduction. The results referring to reducing lead and copper contents above 88% Pb and 98% Cu indicate the great potential of this type of bioreducer. An additional advantage is the relatively wide availability of peanut resources. The effects of the copper reduction time on the degree of decopperisation performed with a constant reducer addition at 1300 &#176;C were studied in this paper. Following 1 h of the process, the copper content in the slag was 0.78 wt%, while the longer process duration resulted in a copper fraction of 0.19 wt%. Considering lead, its content was 0.33 wt% after the reduction process.</description>
      <author>&#321;ukasz Kortyka, J. &#321;abaj, Szymon Ptak, A. Smalcerz, L. Blacha, &#321;ukasz My&#263;ka, T. Matu&#322;a, R&#243;bert Findor&#225;k</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16219261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Price Distortions and Urban Carbon Emission Efficiency: Evidence from China&#8217;s Energy-Intensive Sectors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16219351</link>
      <description>Xiaozhen Wang, Binbin Liao, Cheng Li, Jing Wang, Xu Yang, Xiaolei Wang, Sustainability. 16(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403835076

                With a primary focus of achieving carbon neutrality, the energy-intensive industrial sectors (EIIs) contribute to more than half of China&#8217;s carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions. During the process of China&#8217;s rapid economic development, distorted energy prices gradually became the main obstacle to energy conservation and emission reductions in the EIIs. Therefore, this study focused on determining the mechanisms affecting the energy price distortions of carbon emission efficiency (CEE) in China&#8217;s EIIs. Based on a stochastic frontier analysis, the changing trend of CEE in China&#8217;s EIIs was evaluated. The channels impacting the energy price distortions of CEE were further analyzed by a mediating effect and moderated mediating effect model. The main contributions and findings include the following: energy price distortions have a significant negative impact on CEE by suppressing technological innovations and hindering the restructuring of energy consumption; governmental environmental regulatory policies mitigate their suppressing effect on technological innovations and reduce the preventing effect by improving the energy consumption structure. The results suggest that market-based price reforms and moderate environmental regulation by the government could help to improve CEE in China&#8217;s EIIs. These findings are of great significance for promoting the sustainable development of the energy-intensive industrial sectors and achieving carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Xiaozhen Wang, Binbin Liao, Cheng Li, Jing Wang, Xu Yang, Xiaolei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16219351</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interventions to reduce low-value care in intensive care settings: a scoping review of impacts on health, resource use, costs, and the environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00134-024-07670-7</link>
      <description>Jake T. W. Williams, Florencia Moraga Masson, Forbes McGain, Rachel Stancliffe, Julia Pilowsky, Nhi Nguyen, Katy Bell, Intensive Care Medicine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776479

                Low-value care is common in intensive care units (ICUs), unnecessarily exposing patients to risks and harms, incuring costs to the patient and healthcare system, and contributing to healthcare's carbon footprint. We aimed to identify, collate, and summarise published evidence on the impact of interventions to reduce low-value care in ICUs. We searched MEDLINE, Embase, and Cochrane CENTRAL from inception to 22 September 2023 for evaluations of interventions aiming to reduce low-value care, supplemented by reference lists and recently published articles. We recorded impacts on the low-value target, health outcomes, resource use, cost, and the environment. From 1155 studies screened, 32 eligible studies were identified evaluating interventions to reduce: routine blood testing (n = 13), routine chest X-rays (n = 10), and other types (or multiple types) of low-value care (n = 9). All but 3 of the interventions found reductions in the immediate low-value care target (usually the primary outcome). Although the small sample size of most included studies, limited their ability to detect impacts on other outcomes, many interventions were also associated with improved health outcomes and financial savings. The only study that reported environmental impacts found the intervention was associated with reduced carbon dioxide equivalent (CO2-e) emissions. Interventions to reduce low-value care in ICUs may have important health, financial, and environmental co-benefits. Further research may inform wider scale-up and sustainability of successful strategies to decrease low-value healthcare. More empirical evidence on potential environmental benefits may inform policies to lower healthcare's carbon footprint.</description>
      <author>Jake T. W. Williams, Florencia Moraga Masson, Forbes McGain, Rachel Stancliffe, Julia Pilowsky, Nhi Nguyen, Katy Bell</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00134-024-07670-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends in volatile anesthetic sevoflurane and desflurane usage and its impact on carbon emissions: A six-year audit at National Taiwan University Hospital (2018&#8211;2023)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfma.2024.10.021</link>
      <description>Kuang&#8208;Cheng Chan, Skye Hung&#8208;Chun Cheng, Wei&#8208;Jen Chang, Tin Lok Chiu, Shou&#8208;Zen Fan, Ming&#8208;Hui Hung, Journal of the Formosan Medical Association. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403814737

                This short communication presents an audit of anesthetic gas usage at National Taiwan University Hospital from 2018 to 2023. Using descriptive statistics and trend analysis, the data reveals trends in the consumption of sevoflurane and desflurane, associated costs, and their corresponding carbon emissions. A significant decrease in desflurane usage contributed to a 42.4% reduction in carbon dioxide equivalent (CO</description>
      <author>Kuang&#8208;Cheng Chan, Skye Hung&#8208;Chun Cheng, Wei&#8208;Jen Chang, Tin Lok Chiu, Shou&#8208;Zen Fan, Ming&#8208;Hui Hung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfma.2024.10.021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the Effect of Crystal Facet of Derived&#8208;Copper Catalysts on the Electroreduction of Carbon Dioxide under Unified Mass Transport Condition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415590</link>
      <description>Zi-Hao Zhao, Dan Ren, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403790287

                Altering the physical structure and chemical property of copper, i.e., particle size, surface morphology, composition or crystal facet, has been demonstrated to be effective in steering the selectivity of products in electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide. However, these modifications generally result in the change of active surface area, leading to differences in the geometric current density and local pH, which are also demonstrated to be the key factors for observed selectivity change. In this work, we deconvolute the effect of mass transport and local pH from the effect of crystal facet by investigating five copper&#8208;based catalysts with identical roughness factors for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide in an H&#8208;cell. Interestingly, CuO&#8208;derived catalyst stands out as the best catalyst for C&#8208;C coupling. At &#8208;1.07 V vs. RHE, the faradaic efficiency of C2+ product reaches 44.3%, with a partial current density of &#8208;10.8 mA cm&#8208;2. Electrochemical adsorption of *OH reveals that the C2+ product selectivity of derived&#8208;copper catalysts correlates positively with the ratio of Cu(100)/Cu(110) of five catalysts. Additionally, in situ Raman spectroscopy reveals that the percentage of low&#8208;frequency band linear CO (LFB&#8208;CO), which is attributed to the adsorbed *CO on Cu(100) facet, increases with the C&#8208;C coupling efficiency.</description>
      <author>Zi-Hao Zhao, Dan Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive review of building lifecycle carbon emissions and reduction approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44213-024-00036-1</link>
      <description>Guohao Wang, Tengqi Luo, Haizhi Luo, Ran Liu, Yanhua Liu, Zhengguang Liu, City and Built Environment. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403908148

                Abstract This paper presents a comprehensive review of building lifecycle carbon emissions (CEBL) and reduction approaches, analyzing over 300 recent publications and engaging in in-depth discussion of more than 100 key studies. The review systematically examines CO 2 emissions across all stages of a building's lifecycle, from material production and transportation to construction, operation, demolition, and material recycling. While existing research highlights the significance of operational energy efficiency, this review reveals critical research gaps in quantifying transportation emissions, accounting for on-site equipment emissions during construction, and addressing the unique characteristics of non-residential buildings. Furthermore, the paper underscores the urgent need for improved construction waste management practices, especially in developing countries where landfilling remains prevalent. For the building carbon reduction approaches, promising building carbon emission reduction approaches include leveraging carbon dioxide sinks, implementing integrated energy systems, integrating building-integrated photovoltaics (BIPV), and enacting effective policy interventions are separately discussed. By revealing data and theoretical limitations within current research, this review calls for more integrated and context-specific approaches to CEBL assessment, paving the way for a more sustainable built environment.</description>
      <author>Guohao Wang, Tengqi Luo, Haizhi Luo, Ran Liu, Yanhua Liu, Zhengguang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44213-024-00036-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Carbon Tax on Renewable Energy Development and Environmental&#8211;Economic Synergies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17215347</link>
      <description>Keying Feng, Jing Wang, Yu Zhuo, Lili Jiao, Bowen Wang, Zhi Liu, Energies. 17(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403836366

                Global warming caused by greenhouse gas emissions has become a worldwide environmental problem, posing a great threat to human survival. As the world&#8217;s largest emitter of carbon dioxide, China has pledged to reach peak carbon emissions by no later than 2030 and carbon neutrality by 2060. It is found that a carbon tax is a powerful incentive to reduce carbon emissions and promote an energy revolution, but it may have negative socio-economic impacts. Therefore, based on China&#8217;s 2020 input&#8211;output table, this paper systematically investigates the impacts of a carbon tax on China&#8217;s economy, carbon emissions, and energy by applying a computable general equilibrium model to determine the ideal equilibrium between socio-economic and environmental objectives. Based on energy use characteristics, we subdivided the energy sector into five major sectors: coal, oil, natural gas, thermal power generation, and clean power. The results show that when the carbon emission reduction target is less than 15%, that is, when the equilibrium carbon tax price is less than 54 yuan/ton, the implementation of a carbon tax policy can significantly reduce carbon emission and fossil fuel energy consumption, while only slightly reducing economic growth rate, and can achieve the double dividend of environment and economy. Moreover, because the reduction of coal consumption has the greatest impact on reducing carbon emissions, the ad valorem tax rate on coal after the carbon tax is imposed is the highest because coal has the highest carbon emission coefficient among fossil fuels. In addition, as an emerging clean energy source, hydrogen energy is the ideal energy storage medium for achieving clean power generation in power systems. If hydrogen energy can be vigorously developed, it is expected to greatly accelerate the deep decarbonization of power, industry, transportation, construction, and other fields.</description>
      <author>Keying Feng, Jing Wang, Yu Zhuo, Lili Jiao, Bowen Wang, Zhi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17215347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Distillation for Urban Tree Image Classification Based on the Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61173/9wjdn184</link>
      <description>Ruijing Shi, Science and Technology of Engineering Chemistry and Environmental Protection. 1(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403873896

                As urban areas continue to emerge as significant contributors to global carbon emissions, the classification of urban street trees has gained increasing importance in carbon sequestration research. By precisely identifying and categorizing different tree species, the carbon absorption capabilities of urban vegetation can be evaluated more accurately. This understanding is essential for addressing the growing environmental challenges posed by carbon emissions, as urban trees play a crucial role in absorbing carbon dioxide and mitigating the effects of climate change. In this study, a Feature Distillation Based on Diffusion Model (FDBD) framework was proposed, utilizing state-of-the-art image classification technology to enhance the accuracy of urban tree species identification. The framework utilized knowledge distillation, a process where a smaller, more efficient &#8220;student&#8221; model is trained to mimic the performance of a larger, more complex &#8220;teacher&#8221; model, significantly reducing computational demands while maintaining high accuracy. The model&#8217;s effectiveness has been validated through combination experiments with a selected backbone model, achieving promising results. This approach not only enhances the understanding of urban trees&#8217; carbon sequestration potential but also provides crucial insights for policymakers. By facilitating precise tree classification, it empowers urban planners to implement more informed and targeted strategies for carbon reduction, ultimately promoting more sustainable urban environments.</description>
      <author>Ruijing Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61173/9wjdn184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediksi Risiko Emisi Karbon Dioksida Melalui Pemodelan GSTAR Kriging di Wilayah Asia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35580/jmathcos.v7i2.4309</link>
      <description>Utriweni Mukhaiyar, Naila Ratu Dianti, Elizabet Sri Rezeki, Nicholas Ramos Richardo, Journal of Mathematics Computations and Statistics. 7(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403761172

                This study analyzes the variability of carbon dioxide emissions across Asia, revealing that China, India, and Indonesia are the primary contributors with extremely high average emissions and standard deviations. The GSTAR(3;1,1,1) model has been shown to be optimal for forecasting future emissions, based on lower RMSE and MAPE values. Ordinary Kriging analysis using the isotropic spherical semivariogram model provides the most accurate predictions for unobserved areas, with contour maps indicating that the northeastern region of Asia will continue to face high emission concentrations until 2027. While countries such as Brunei and Armenia have managed to keep emission levels low, the instability of emission trends across Asia underscores the need for emission reduction strategies tailored to the specific context of each country.</description>
      <author>Utriweni Mukhaiyar, Naila Ratu Dianti, Elizabet Sri Rezeki, Nicholas Ramos Richardo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35580/jmathcos.v7i2.4309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Copper Metal Catalyzing Deep CO2 Electroreduction to Hydrocarbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06902a</link>
      <description>chaojie chen, Xiaowan Bai, Yan Jiao, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403932985

                The copper (Cu) is recognized as a unique metal catalyst in the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) because its moderate *CO binding ability can accelerate the deep CO2 reduction to...</description>
      <author>chaojie chen, Xiaowan Bai, Yan Jiao, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06902a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Carbon Dioxide Emissions in Two California Cities Using Bayesian Inversion and Satellite Measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024gl111150</link>
      <description>Sofia D. Hamilton, Dien Wu, Matthew S. Johnson, Alexander J. Turner, M. L. Fischer, Nikhil Dadheech, Seongeun Jeong, Geophysical Research Letters. 51(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403772008

                Abstract NASA's Orbiting Carbon Observatories (OCO&#8208;2 and OCO&#8208;3) provide measurements of column&#8208;averaged carbon dioxide concentrations (XCO 2 ) with sufficient spatial resolution and precision to constrain bottom&#8208;up estimates of CO 2 fluxes at regional scales. We use Bayesian inversion methods assimilating satellite retrievals to improve estimates of CO 2 fluxes in the South Coast Air Basin (SoCAB) which surrounds Los Angeles, and in the San Francisco Bay Area Air Basin (SFBA). We study 2020 to understand the impact of the COVID&#8208;19 lockdowns and an active wildfire season. Our results indicated that a 50% (30%) reduction in CO 2 emissions relative to 2015 during the COVID&#8208;19 lockdown period was consistent with OCO measurements for SFBA (SoCAB). We find that posterior wildfire emissions differed significantly from the prior at the scale of individual wildfires, though with large uncertainties, and that wildfire emissions in SFBA are significant, attributing 72% of the region's CO 2 emissions during August 2020 to wildfires.</description>
      <author>Sofia D. Hamilton, Dien Wu, Matthew S. Johnson, Alexander J. Turner, M. L. Fischer, Nikhil Dadheech, Seongeun Jeong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024gl111150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical analysis of an anaerobic digestion model for biogas production from solid waste</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-77430-6</link>
      <description>Iliyass Ahlamine, Abdellah Alla, Noha El Khattabi, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403877287

                Municipal solid waste is one of the most significant sources of gas emissions. In a context of renewable energy production and greenhouse gas emission reduction, we focus on the amount of biogas produced by the anaerobic digestion of organic matter in a controlled landfill environment. We present a mathematical model describing this process from a microbiological and biochemical point of view, including the dynamics of the methane and carbon dioxide produced. A qualitative analysis of the dynamic system shows the existence of an infinite number of non-hyperbolic equilibria inducing an attractor that has been identified. Through numerical tests, we explore how the non-connectivity of the attractor resulting from the choice of growth functions can entirely transform the performance of the process, and highlight critical initial stock values that influence the amount of biogas produced.</description>
      <author>Iliyass Ahlamine, Abdellah Alla, Noha El Khattabi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-77430-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in Corrosion Protection Research for Supercritical CO2 Transportation Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14111378</link>
      <description>Cailing Zhao, Jianming Wang, Xin Li, Jinzhen Huang, Huikai Chen, Jinye Bi, Sawen Liu, Guoqiang L&#252;, Kun Song, Shengjun Guo, Coatings. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403918281

                Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage (CCUS) technology is an emergent field with the potential for substantial CO2 emissions reduction, enabling low-carbon utilization of fossil fuels. It is widely regarded as a critical technology for combating global climate change and controlling greenhouse gas emissions. According to recent studies, China has identified CCUS as a key emissions reduction technology in climate change response and carbon neutrality objectives. Within this framework, supercritical CO2 (SC-CO2) transport pipelines are an essential means for efficient and safe transportation of CO2. Corrosion protection of pipelines enhances the efficiency and safety of CCUS technology and supports broader implementation and application. This paper reviews the current research on corrosion protection for SC-CO2 transport pipelines, discusses effect factors, compares various corrosion protection strategies, and analyzes the challenges in corrosion protection of SC-CO2 transport pipelines. It concludes with a perspective on future research and development directions in this field. This paper is dedicated to providing new research strategies for pipeline corrosion protection in CCUS technology in the future, and providing technical support for pipeline corrosion protection in CCUS industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Cailing Zhao, Jianming Wang, Xin Li, Jinzhen Huang, Huikai Chen, Jinye Bi, Sawen Liu, Guoqiang L&#252;, Kun Song, Shengjun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14111378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Promoting Effect of Green Bonds on Reducing Carbon Emission Intensity Through Energy Structure Transition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16219318</link>
      <description>Yulei Zhang, Tao Xu, WU Song-qiang, Sustainability. 16(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403810162

                Climate change poses a significant threat to the sustainable development of all countries. The transition to low-carbon energy sources is a crucial strategy for reducing carbon emissions and mitigating climate change. We investigate the mediating role of clean energy consumption (EC) and fossil energy supply (ES) on the promoting of carbon emission intensity per unit of GDP (CO2/GDP) reduction by green bonds (GBs). We develop a mediating model to analyze how GB influences CO2/GDP reduction through EC and ES, utilizing panel data from 13 prefecture-level cities in Jiangsu province spanning the years 2007 to 2021. Additionally, we assess the model&#8217;s reliability through endogeneity and robustness tests. We find that GBs contribute to reducing CO2/GDP by facilitating the structural transition of energy supply and consumption. Furthermore, the development of GBs enhance the consumption of clean energy and plays a direct role in advancing the transition in structure of both energy supply and energy consumption. Notably, we observe heterogeneity in the effectiveness of GBs on CO2/GDP reduction across different regions. Therefore, it is imperative for the government to actively promote the development of GBs to achieve sustainable economic growth. Furthermore, both financial and energy policies should be tailored to align with the specific energy structures of various regions.</description>
      <author>Yulei Zhang, Tao Xu, WU Song-qiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16219318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radiative cooling capacity on Earth</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.04109</link>
      <description>Cun&#8211;Hai Wang, Hao Chen, Yanyan Feng, Ziming Cheng, Jingchong Liu, Fuqiang Wang, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403936518

                By passively dissipating thermal emission into the ultracold deep space, radiative cooling (RC) is an environment-friendly means for gaining cooling capacity, paving a bright future for global energy saving and carbon dioxide reduction. However, assessing the global RC capacity at the day-to-annual scale remains challenging as the RC capacity significantly depends on geographic and environmental conditions. To our knowledge, no analysis of global RC capacity has been reported. Herein, we show the distribution of RC capacity on Earth by establishing a precise assessment model for evaluating the performance of a radiative cooler. Our assessment is comprehensively validated against experimental data and extended to elucidate the capacity of representative broadband and selective cooler. We also categorize the global RC capacity into five representative regions based on the year-round cooling power. Our assessment can inform trade-offs between design and practical application for the RC systems, alongside promoting RC-based technologies to tackle worldwide energy and environment challenges.</description>
      <author>Cun&#8211;Hai Wang, Hao Chen, Yanyan Feng, Ziming Cheng, Jingchong Liu, Fuqiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.04109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical investigation on the OER and ORR activity of graphene-based TM-N3 and TM-N2X (X=B, C, O, P) single atom catalysts by density functional theory calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03779k</link>
      <description>Jiaxiang Wu, Erjun Kan, Cheng Zhan, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403772462

                Single-atom catalysts (SAC) have shown promising activity in electrocatalysis, such as CO2 reduction (CO2RR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Transition metal-embedded N-doped graphene (M-N-C) with TM-N4...</description>
      <author>Jiaxiang Wu, Erjun Kan, Cheng Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03779k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase equilibria, volumetric properties, viscosity, and thermal
  conductivity of hydrogen binary mixtures containing methane, nitrogen, carbon
  monoxide, and carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.19836</link>
      <description>Ehsan Heidaryan, Saman A. Aryana, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403814359

                TThis works proposes modifications to the values of input parameters in widely accepted semi-analytical models of thermodynamic properties of hydrogen and its binary mixtures to improve their prediction accuracy. The modifications include characterization parameters for the Peng and Robinson Equation of State (PR-EoS), the Jossi-Stiel-Thodos (JST)/Lohrenz-Bray-Clark (LBC) viscosity correlation, and the Chung-Lee-Starling (CLS) thermal conductivity correlation, applicable to pure hydrogen and its binary mixtures containing methane, nitrogen, carbon monoxide, and carbon dioxide. The changes preserve the mathematical structure of the models and ensure their compatibility with existing commercial packages. We consider temperatures ranging from 90 K (triple point of methane) to 1000 K, and pressures ranging from atmospheric up to 100 MPa. The revised characterization parameters of hydrogen lead to a reduction in the Absolute Average Deviation (AAD) of the PR-EoS calculation for hydrogen density from 2.76% (with a maximum of 8.05%) down to 0.182% (with a maximum of 1.9%). For the JST/LBC viscosity correlation, the AAD decreases from 11.82% (with a maximum of 54.3%) to 4.08% (with a maximum of 13%). Regarding thermal conductivity, the adjustments for the CLS correlation results in the AAD decreasing from 36% (with a maximum of 44%) to 2.14\% (with a maximum of 12.1%). Binary interaction parameters for gaseous mixtures containing hydrogen and phase equilibria calculation are also proposed. Finally, we investigage optimal mixing rules parameters for viscosity and thermal conductivity of mixtures for more accurate predictions of mixtures? transport properties.</description>
      <author>Ehsan Heidaryan, Saman A. Aryana</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.19836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of magnesium-containing fertilizers by priming method for regulation of physiological processes in winter wheat</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32634/0869-8155-2024-387-10-122-127</link>
      <description>Dmitry Zakharov, &#1045;. &#1042;. &#1057;&#1090;&#1077;&#1087;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, I. A. Ivanochkin, Agrarian science. 1(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403767866

                The studing the efficiency of new magnesium-containing fertilizer &#8220;AktiMax&#8221; use for priming soft winter wheat seeds of the &#8220;Skipetr&#8221; variety. The effect of the fertilizer is compared with the negative (no fertilizer) and positive (&#8220;Novosil&#8221;) controls. During the study, the optimal concentration 2.6 ml/l of the solution for processing by the selected method is found, which is equivalent to 20% of the recommended by the manufacturer (13 ml/l). At treating with a solution of this concentration, a slight decrease in seed germination is observed, and growth parameter records taken after 7 days showed an increase in leaf length by 15&#8211;20%. A slight decrease in the number of roots (by 10%) and branching of the root system is observed, which is presumably due to the availability of the fertilizer components. The effect fertilizer on the photosynthetic apparatus, carbon dioxide assimilation and transpiration rate when use in a range of concentrations is studied. On average, the transpiration activity increased by 2 times in the variant with the working concentration and by 1.8 times in the variant with one fifth of the working concentration. A slight increase in the efficiency of non-photochemical fluorescence quenching is revealed in plants at the &#8220;AktiMax&#8221; application. The efficiency of seed priming method use to stimulate the rate of winter wheat development is demonstrated that leads to reduction of unfavorable outcomes risks.</description>
      <author>Dmitry Zakharov, &#1045;. &#1042;. &#1057;&#1090;&#1077;&#1087;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, I. A. Ivanochkin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32634/0869-8155-2024-387-10-122-127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The aeration and dredging stimulate the reduction of pollution and carbon emissions in a sediment microcosm study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-75790-7</link>
      <description>Lixiang Liu, Ke Yang, Liangzhong Li, Weiwei Liu, Haoran Yuan, Yongwei Han, Enxiang Zhang, Yuping Zheng, Yajuan Jia, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403920948

                Sediment dredging and aeration are used as important technical measures to remediate internal loading of sediment in polluted rivers. However, previous studies have overlooked the impact of dredging and aeration on Greenhouse gases (GHGs) emission. We established three aeration rate(six different aeration intervals), one dredging treatment to investigate the effect of aeration and dredging on pollutant removals and CO2, CH4 and N2O emissions. The results indicated the pollutants and GHGs at 2.4, 3.4, 4.4 L min&#8722;1 aeration rates reached collaborative emission reduction after more than 3 h or within 1.5 h. Meanwhile, the GHGs fluxes after aeration decreased with the increasing aeration rate, with the mean CO2, CH4 and N2O fluxes of 69.74, 0.16, 7.53 mg m&#8722;2 h&#8722;1 and 33.64, 0.09, 4.17 mg m&#8722;2 h&#8722;1 before and after aeration, respectively. With respect to dredging, the pollutants and N2O reached synergic effects between reduction of pollution and carbon emissions after 1 h dredging. Specifically, the CO2 and CH4 emissions after dredging was lower than those of before dredging, but the N2O emissions was higher than those of before dredging. In addition, our analysis revealed that the dissolved oxygen (DO), oxidation-reduction potential (ORP), available potassium (AK) and ammoniacal nitrogen (NH4+-N) in the sediment influenced GHGs fluxes at the water-air interface in the aeration. Our study indicated moderate aeration and dredging can achieve the synergistic effect in reducing pollution and carbon emissions.</description>
      <author>Lixiang Liu, Ke Yang, Liangzhong Li, Weiwei Liu, Haoran Yuan, Yongwei Han, Enxiang Zhang, Yuping Zheng, Yajuan Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-75790-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Process Simulation and Life Cycle Assessment for Enhanced Process Efficiency and Reduced Environmental Impact in Ferromanganese Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14111212</link>
      <description>Trine Asklund Larssen, Vincent Canaguier, Markus A. Reuter, Eli Ringdalen, Metals. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403774392

                Process simulation was integrated with life cycle assessment to evaluate process efficiency and environmental impact of the production of manganese ferroalloys for various production modes and different ore mineralogies. Utilizing HSC Sim, the model was designed to evaluate the production process with or without a pretreatment step, where results for simulated cases using a four-zone ferromanganese furnace model were exported to openLCA for a complete life cycle assessment. Two main production scenarios were simulated: a closed ferromanganese furnace running on the duplex method and an open furnace running on the discard slag approach. The closed furnace scenario achieved a 17.5% reduction in energy consumption and a 16.2% decrease in direct CO2 emissions with CO-rich off-gas pretreatment. The open furnace scenario showed an 11.2% reduction in energy consumption with thermal solar energy pretreatment but no change in CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Trine Asklund Larssen, Vincent Canaguier, Markus A. Reuter, Eli Ringdalen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14111212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Visible Light for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion: The Role of Highly Reduced Phosphomolybdate Crystals as Powerful Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03810</link>
      <description>Yin-Hua Zhu, Jianbo Yang, Zhiming Dong, Hua Mei, Yan Xu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403768995

                Heterogeneous photocatalysts, characterized by well-defined atomic structures and the capacity for rapid, directional electron transfer, are pivotal in the exploration and development of highly efficient systems for visible-light-driven diluted CO2 reduction. Herein, we constructed highly reduced phosphomolybdates crystalline materials 1&#8211;3 to help this process, with the formula of [Co2(C8N3H7)4][Co2(C8N3H7)4(H2O)2][Co(H7P4Mo6O31)2]&#183;8H2O (1), [Ni2(C8N3H7)4(H2O)2][Ni2(C8N3H7)4][Ni(H2O)4][Ni(H6P4Mo6O31)2]&#183;3H2O&#183;2C2H5OH (2), and [Zn2(C8N3H7)2][Zn2(C8N3H7)4][Zn2(C8N3H7)2(H2O)2][Zn(H5P4Mo6O31)2] (3) [C8N3H7 = 2-(1H-pyrazol-3-yl)pyridine]. Specifically, catalyst 1 demonstrated a CO production rate of 3276.4 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 in an environment with 20% CO2 concentration, and an impressively elevated rate of 10740.3 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 in a pure CO2 atmosphere. Steady-state photoluminescence spectroscopy revealed that the directional migration of photoelectrons from the Ru complexes to the catalyst was instrumental in enhancing the catalytic activity. This study provides valuable insights into the rational operation of low-concentration CO2 conversion treatment and the design and synthesis of photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yin-Hua Zhu, Jianbo Yang, Zhiming Dong, Hua Mei, Yan Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03810</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalytic Urea Synthesis over Iron-Doped InOOH Nanosheets under Ambient Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03881</link>
      <description>Haoxiang Cai, Zhiwei Wang, Ge Meng, Tianran Wei, Yifan Liu, Jun Luo, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, X. Liu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403768436

                Ambient urea synthesis via C&#8211;N coupling from CO2 and nitrate reduction offers an attractive alternative to the Bosch-Meiser route, but it is hindered by the lack of efficient catalysts. Herein, we report that Fe-doped InOOH nanosheets effectively catalyze the coreduction of CO2 and nitrate, giving a high Faradaic Efficiency of 26.9%, a yield rate of 980.6 &#956;g h&#8211;1 mgcat.&#8211;1, and a good durability. Theoretical calculations further elucidate that iron dopants can tailor the reactivity of the In site, facilitating the hydrogenation of the key *CO2NH2 intermediate and suppressing the hydrogen production with a higher energy barrier.</description>
      <author>Haoxiang Cai, Zhiwei Wang, Ge Meng, Tianran Wei, Yifan Liu, Jun Luo, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, X. Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative evaluation of punch elevation combined with fractional CO2 laser resurfacing versus fractional CO2 laser alone in the treatment of atrophic acne scars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53730/ijhs.v5ns2.15297</link>
      <description>Seif&#8211;Allah Mohamed Refaat El-Fiky, Sahar El-Sayed Ahmed, Rania Mahmoud Elhusseiny, Mohamed Hussein AbouHadeed, Dalia Gamal Aly, International Journal of Health Sciences. 5(S2)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4403932360

                Background: Acne vulgaris is a chronic inflammatory skin condition that often results in atrophic scarring, impacting physical appearance and mental health. This study aims to evaluating the potential effect of combining punch elevation with fractional CO2 laser resurfacing versus laser treatment alone for moderate to severe atrophic acne scars. Patients and Methods: A split-face comparative study involved 20 adults aged 18 to 55 with moderate to severe atrophic acne scars. One side received punch elevation followed by fractional CO2 laser resurfacing, while the other side received fractional CO2 laser treatment alone. Clinical assessments included Goodman and Baron&#8217;s grading scale and patient satisfaction ratings. Histopathological evaluations analyzed fibroblast activity, epidermal thickness, and collagen composition. Results: The combined treatment significantly improved scar severity, with a mean reduction of 44.40% compared to 18.89% for the laser-only group (p &lt; 0.001). Histopathological analysis showed increases in fibroblast activity (5.87% to 19.14%, p &lt; 0.003) and epidermal thickness (635.65 &#181;m to 1497.35 &#181;m, p &lt; 0.001). Patient satisfaction was higher for the combined approach (6.80 &#177; 1.2) versus laser-only treatment (5.65 &#177; 1.3, p &lt; 0.001). Conclusion: Combining punch elevation technique with fractional CO2 laser resurfacing enhances treatment outcomes for atrophic acne scars,,,</description>
      <author>Seif&#8211;Allah Mohamed Refaat El-Fiky, Sahar El-Sayed Ahmed, Rania Mahmoud Elhusseiny, Mohamed Hussein AbouHadeed, Dalia Gamal Aly</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53730/ijhs.v5ns2.15297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the climate impact of food choices with comparable nutritional quality: a randomised trial</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/eurpub/ckae144.1427</link>
      <description>Luc&#237;a Aguirre S&#225;nchez, S Maione, Serge Maeder, Esther Infanger, L. Suzanne Suggs, European Journal of Public Health. 34(Supplement_3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403815542

                Abstract Background Diets largely contribute to the global disease burden, and a third of global warming emissions. We assessed the climate footprint reduction effect of framing the climate impact of diets as a collective action problem (social dilemma), compared or in combination with a reflective intervention (information) and a choice architecture intervention (nudge). Interactions with lifestyle factors were examined. Methods A randomised 2X2X2 between-subjects online experiment was conducted among university students &#8805;18 years, enrolled at a Swiss university, and not following a medically prescribed diet. The outcome was the mean climate footprint of food choices (in kg CO2-eq), based on a Life Cycle Assessment. Meals varied in climate footprints while adhering to the Swiss dietary guidelines. Results This analysis focused on the subset of meat eaters (n = 1691). Median age was 24 years, and 59.85% (n = 1012) were female. Seven intervention groups resulted in significantly lower climate footprints compared to the control. The social dilemma plus a nudge menu was the most effective behavioural intervention leading to 20.20% footprint reduction (b = -1.20 kg CO2-eq) compared to the control group (Mcontrol=5.94, SDcontrol=2.76; Mdilemma+nudge=4.74, SDdilemma+nudge=2.09 t(436) = -5.10, p &amp;lt; 0.001). Lifestyle factors linked to a higher climate footprint of food choices included adhering to a low-calorie diet (b = 1.21 kg CO2-eq, p &amp;lt; 0.05), or a muscle gain diet (b = 2.12 kg CO2-eq p &amp;lt; 0.05) and practising physical activities (PA) while adhering to a muscle-gain diet (Aerobic/Cardio: 3.82 kg CO2-eq, p &amp;lt; 0.05; Muscle-strengthening: 2.24 kg CO2-eq, p &amp;lt; 0.05). Conclusions The combination of reflective collective action communication and menu nudges is an effective strategy to mitigate the climate footprint of food choices in education institutions. Adherence to a muscle-gain diet was identified as a critical but manageable lifestyle factor linked to a higher climate footprint. Key messages &#8226; The dilemma plus a nudge was the most effective to reduce the climate footprint of food choices. &#8226; This combined intervention can manage the high climate footprints linked to lifestyle factors.</description>
      <author>Luc&#237;a Aguirre S&#225;nchez, S Maione, Serge Maeder, Esther Infanger, L. Suzanne Suggs</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/eurpub/ckae144.1427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hemoglobin value prediction with bayesian optimization assisted machine learning models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33769/aupse.1462331</link>
      <description>Koray A&#231;&#305;c&#305;, Communications Faculty of Sciences University of Ankara Series A2-A3 Physical Sciences and Engineering. 66(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403825000

                This study presents a framework for predicting hemoglobin (Hb) levels utilizing Bayesian optimization-assisted machine learning models, incorporating both time-domain and frequency-domain features derived from photoplethysmography (PPG) signals. Hemoglobin, a crucial protein for oxygen and carbon dioxide transport in the blood, has levels that indicate various health conditions, including anemia and diseases affecting red blood cell production. Traditional methods for measuring Hb levels are invasive, posing potential risks and discomfort. To address this, a dataset comprising PPG signals, along with demographic data (gender and age), was analyzed to predict Hb levels accurately. Our models employ support vector regression (SVR), artificial neural networks (ANNs), classification and regression trees (CART), and ensembles of trees (EoT) optimized through Bayesian optimization algorithm. The results demonstrated that incorporating age and gender as features significantly improved model performance, highlighting their importance in Hb level prediction. Among the tested models, ANN provided the best results, involving normalized raw signals, feature selection, and reduction methods. The model achieved a mean squared error (MSE) of 1.508, root mean squared error (RMSE) of 1.228, and R-squared (R&#178;) of 0.226. This study's findings contribute to the growing body of research on non-invasive hemoglobin prediction, offering a potential tool for healthcare professionals and patients for convenient and risk-free Hb level monitoring.</description>
      <author>Koray A&#231;&#305;c&#305;</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33769/aupse.1462331</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of a Hydrophobic Sputtered Cu Electrode to Electrocatalyze CO2 Towards a C2+ Product: The Effect of Substrate and Catalyst Thickness</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112374</link>
      <description>Dongdong Wang, Xiaoyu Mao, Yaqi Peng, Wei Zhang, Qiulin Ye, Yan Yang, Fengping Yu, Yan Ma, Angjian Wu, Zhifu Qi, Processes. 12(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403869114

                The overuse of fossil fuels has resulted in massive CO2 emissions, causing global environmental problems. Renewable energy-driven electrocatalysis, which can convert CO2 into fuels and chemicals, is considered an emerging technology for carbon resource recycling. Cu-based catalysts sputtered on hydrophobic carbon paper and a polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) membrane were comparatively investigated, while the effect of the thickness of the Cu sputtering layer on the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction performance was investigated. Additionally, the effect of substrate properties on the distribution and morphology of sputtered Cu metal was investigated by SEM and XRD. With carbon paper as the substrate, the highest FEC2+ achieved was 70% at 200 mA/cm2, while the maximum value of FEC2+ on the Cu/PTFE electrode was realized with a Cu thickness of 400 nm (72%). Additionally, the PTFE substrate demonstrated a better inhibiting effect on HER, with a lower FEH2 and high FEC2+ over different applied current densities.</description>
      <author>Dongdong Wang, Xiaoyu Mao, Yaqi Peng, Wei Zhang, Qiulin Ye, Yan Yang, Fengping Yu, Yan Ma, Angjian Wu, Zhifu Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112374</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of selective flocculation process in drilling operations to optimize per-flex fluid volume consumption and reduce the carbon footprint</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30574/wjaets.2024.12.2.0357</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ahsan, Daniela Serrano, World Journal of Advanced Engineering Technology and Sciences. 12(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403915167

                One of the significant challenges faced by the oil and gas industry is the reduction of the carbon footprint associated with drilling operations. This paper presents a case study on the implementation of a selective flocculation process to optimize the consumption of PER-FLEX fluid, a high-performance water-based mud (WBM), during drilling operations. Conducted in a Colombian oil field, this study demonstrates how the adjustment of polymer concentration and injection rates in the flocculation process can reduce the need for fluid dilution, thereby decreasing water and chemical consumption, waste production, and CO2 equivalent (CO2 eq.) emissions. The findings highlight the effectiveness of selective flocculation in enhancing drilling fluid performance and contributing to sustainability goals.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ahsan, Daniela Serrano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30574/wjaets.2024.12.2.0357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing urban mobility in developing countries: A mobile RSU approach for sustainable transportation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1049/itr2.12586</link>
      <description>Justin Moskola&#239; Ngossaha, L&#233;once Th&#233;r&#232;se Pidy Pidy, Thenuka Karunathilake, Anna F&#246;rster, Samuel Bowong, IET Intelligent Transport Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403914381

                Abstract The rapid and uncontrolled urbanization of cities in developing countries has engendered a plethora of urban mobility issues, including traffic congestion, accidents, and air pollution. To address these challenges, contemporary urban mobility trends are incorporating innovative technologies and sustainable governance practices. This article investigates how urban managers can leverage the opportunities presented by cost&#8208;effective technologies and the management of urban data to enhance urban mobility in developing countries. Within this discourse, an RSU&#8208;based approach is proposed that employs motorbike taxis for inter&#8208;vehicular communication, given their status as the most widely used form of public transportation. This approach substantially diminishes investment costs and reinforces the sustainability of urban mobility. Through the implementation of this solution, a noteworthy reduction is anticipated in the emission of gases such as CO2, and NOx, known contributors to climate change and various respiratory diseases. To validate the efficacy of the proposed solution, four distinct scenarios are scrutinized in a case study centered on the city of Douala in Cameroon, utilizing tools such as OMNET++, SUMO, Veins, and INET. The proposed framework offers significant benefits in terms of environmental sustainability and operational efficiency. It enables a 10% reduction in CO2 emissions, a 15% reduction in NOx emissions, an 11% drop in fuel consumption, and a 15% reduction in waiting time in traffic jams. The envisaged solution aims to aid urban managers in their decision&#8208;making processes, specifically in advancing sustainable urban mobility. Through the adoption of this approach, cities in developing countries can mitigate challenges associated with urban mobility and enhance the overall well&#8208;being of their residents.</description>
      <author>Justin Moskola&#239; Ngossaha, L&#233;once Th&#233;r&#232;se Pidy Pidy, Thenuka Karunathilake, Anna F&#246;rster, Samuel Bowong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1049/itr2.12586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Urban Breathability: Investigating the Synergistic Mitigation of PM2.5 and CO2 by Community Park Green Space in the Built Environment Using Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14113407</link>
      <description>Xina Ma, Sheng Wang, Xiaoling She, Jingyuan Zhao, Buildings. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403836900

                Reducing carbon emissions and controlling air pollution is a dual challenge for China in addressing climate change. Analyzing the synergistic relationship between PM2.5 and CO2 in urban green spaces has become an important part of promoting pollution control. The study investigated the influence and synergistic relationship between the spatial pattern of community parks on PM2.5 and CO2 in Xi&#8217;an City, Shaanxi Province, through practical measurement and ENVI-met/Open Studio simulation calculations. The results showed that: (1) Within the sphere of influence, community parks exhibit a positive synergy varying with distance, peaking at 400 m and declining as 300 m &gt; 500 m &gt; 200 m &gt; 100 m. (2) The green space rate, total edge (TE), and mean patch shape index (SHAPE_MN) positively influence the synergistic mitigation of PM2.5 and CO2, with a defined maximum impact boundary. The strongest synergistic reduction of PM2.5 and CO2 occurs at a green space rate of 85%, TE1200, and SHAPE1.2, with optimal influence boundaries of 300 m, 200 m, and 100 m, respectively. This conclusion demonstrates the key role of green space in community parks in the synergistic abatement and provides a scientific basis and practical guidance for the planning and design of urban green space under the goal of &#8220;dual-carbon&#8221;.</description>
      <author>Xina Ma, Sheng Wang, Xiaoling She, Jingyuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14113407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neutralization and CO2 fixation behavior of alkaline recycled soil using column tests with CO2 ventilation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11440-024-02441-6</link>
      <description>Su Myat Mon, Aya Sakaguchi, Kimitoshi Hayano, Hiromoto Yamauchi, Acta Geotechnica. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403827833

                Abstract Column tests were conducted to elucidate the pH neutralization and CO 2 fixation behavior of alkaline recycled soils permeated with CO 2 . The ventilation period required for complete CO 2 fixation ( t EOF ) was estimated from the test results of each column. The maximum amount of CO 2 captured per gram of dry soil (( m CO2 ) max ) was determined based on the inflow and outflow of CO 2 for each specimen. The investigation into the effects of soil density, specimen height, CO 2 gas concentration, and flow rate on t EOF and ( m CO2 ) max revealed that t EOF increased with higher dry density ( &#961; d ) or specimen height ( H ), as a denser and larger specimen consumed more CO 2 gas. Conversely, t EOF decreased with a higher CO 2 gas concentration ( C ) or flow volume ( Q ) because a low C or Q resulted in an insufficient CO 2 gas supply to match the consumption induced by the reaction. Lower C and Q tended to yield higher ( m CO2 ) max , whereas higher &#961; d and H resulted in higher ( m CO2 ) max . Furthermore, ( m CO2 ) max increased with t EOF , with a slight reduction in pH after neutralization with increased t EOF . This phenomenon was attributed to the longer ventilation period enabling more Ca to react with the CO 2 gas and maintain the equilibrium state of the reaction. Finally, the evaluation of the CO 2 consumption rate ( CSR ) for each column specimen revealed that a higher C and Q resulted in a lower CSR , whereas a higher H resulted in a higher CSR . Additionally, a longer t EOF was associated with a higher CSR , although some variation was observed.</description>
      <author>Su Myat Mon, Aya Sakaguchi, Kimitoshi Hayano, Hiromoto Yamauchi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11440-024-02441-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Operational Efficiency and Energy Saving Through the Implementation of Long Stroke Units in Field A: Mitigating High Failure Rates for Sustainable Deployment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221550-ms</link>
      <description>Ghosin Al Shukaili, Said Al Kindi, Haytham Rady, Fahad Al Hatmi, Ahmed Al Ajmi, Yaqoob Al Riyami, Mehdi Al Lawati, Adnan Al Ghadani, Marwan Sawafi, Saif Al Matroushi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403821824

                Abstract Field A, the largest cluster in Petroleum Development Oman (PDO), faced a significant challenge with a high overall artificial lift failure index, surpassing industry standards at 28% in 2020. The primary contributors to this index were beam pump (BP) wells. In response, a comprehensive workshop was conducted involving all stakeholders to address the issue of artificial lift failures. Field A's artificial lift fail-less strategy was formulated and implemented as a result of this workshop. A long stroke unit (LSU) was deployed in Field A as a result of the persistently high failure rates for conventional beam pump units (BP), which exceeded 32% in 2020. In an effort to mitigate these challenges, a series of successful trials were conducted to evaluate the efficacy of LSU, which led to the conversion of 70 conventional BP units to LSUs between 2020 and 2023. The results obtained from the deployment of LSU in Field A showcased significantly improved run life, indicated by a reduction in failure index. This increase in reliability contributed to the avoidance of subsurface deferments due to less failures and tripping, resulting in estimated additional production of 320 bbl/d. Additionally, LSUs reduced the number of well interventions, primarily due to fewer failures. It resulted in a substantial improvement in the life cycle of the wells, saving $2.94 million annually. As a result of the deployment of LSUs, power savings were also achieved. In comparison to conventional BP units, LSU demonstrated a remarkable 40% reduction in power consumption, resulting in a significant decrease in carbon dioxide equivalent emissions by 4575 tCO2e since LSUs deployment. This successful implementation not only addressed high failure rates but also enhanced system reliability, reduced corrective maintenance, lowered power consumption, and effectively reduced oil deferment. This abstract outlines these positive outcomes, the challenges faced during implementation, and strategies used to overcome them. Additionally, it presents a roadmap for deploying LSUs across Field &#8216;A, with plans for over 150 LSUs installation in the next five years. The study provides valuable insights for the oil and gas industry, showcasing the potential for wide adoption of LSUs to enhance performance in similar fields.</description>
      <author>Ghosin Al Shukaili, Said Al Kindi, Haytham Rady, Fahad Al Hatmi, Ahmed Al Ajmi, Yaqoob Al Riyami, Mehdi Al Lawati, Adnan Al Ghadani, Marwan Sawafi, Saif Al Matroushi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221550-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of drought on photosynthetic induction in leaves of different wheat genotypes under dark-to-light transition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15421/022471</link>
      <description>A.S. Kedruk, D.A. Kiriziy, &#1054;.&#1054;. &#1057;&#1090;&#1072;&#1089;&#1080;&#1082;, &#1054;. G. Sokolovska-Sergiienko, M.V. Tarasiuk, Regulatory Mechanisms in Biosystems. 15(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403770686

                Adjustment of photosynthetic processes to an increase in irradiance constrains the CO2 assimilation and photosynthetic carbon gain compared to that which would be obtained if photosynthesis reached its terminal value instantaneously. Acceleration of photosynthesis induction under field conditions of fluctuating light opens up new perspectives for increasing yields. However, there is little information on response of photosynthetic processes to changes in the light under drought conditions. In a pot experiment, we have studied the peculiarities of response of CO2- and H2O-gas exchange parameters in flag leaves of 3 winter wheat genotypes to a transition from dark to bright light under drought conditions, to reveal the features of drought effect on photosynthetic induction processes. The plants were exposed to a 7-day drought (30% FC) during the flowering stage. After that, the watering of the treated plants was restored to the control level (70% FC), which was maintained until the end of the growing season. Induction curves of CO2 assimilation and transpiration of the flag leaves were recorded after keeping them in the darkness for 30 minutes, then the light was turned on. It was revealed that drought impacts the photosynthetic apparatus by reducing its maximum functional intensity as well as by diminishing its ability to respond to changing light conditions. Specifically, drought slows the rate of gas exchange increase during transitions from dark to light. High-yielding wheat genotypes, which had higher assimilation rates and stomatal conductance under optimal watering, showed increased sensitivity to drought. The reduction in the CO2 assimilation rate in wheat leaves under drought was primarily due to damage to the photosynthetic apparatus in mesophyll cells, rather than inhibition of stomatal conductance. This conclusion is supported by Ci value calculations, which were highest at the lowest CO2 assimilation rate at the beginning of light exposure and lowest at the highest CO2 assimilation rate when reaching a steady-state plateau. The stronger impact of the drought on the biochemical components of the photosynthetic apparatus than on stomata is also suggested by a decrease in instantaneous water use efficiency (WUEi) during photosynthesis. The genotypic differences in the effects of drought on the dynamics of photosynthetic induction parameters during dark-to-light transitions in wheat leaves suggest the potential of these traits for evaluating breeding material. This could enhance the ecological plasticity of new wheat varieties.</description>
      <author>A.S. Kedruk, D.A. Kiriziy, &#1054;.&#1054;. &#1057;&#1090;&#1072;&#1089;&#1080;&#1082;, &#1054;. G. Sokolovska-Sergiienko, M.V. Tarasiuk</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15421/022471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OTIMIZA&#199;&#195;O LOG&#205;STICA SUSTENT&#193;VEL: ESTUDO DE CASO SOBRE A IMPLEMENTA&#199;&#195;O DE TECNOLOGIAS AVAN&#199;ADAS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69849/revistaft/ar10202006092043</link>
      <description>Regiane Marques Junger de Oliveira, No host. 24(87)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4403856426

                This article examines sustainable logistics optimization through the implementation of advanced technologies, using CEVA LOGISTICS as a case study. The introduction highlights the significance of sustainable logistics in light of increasing environmental concerns, with research objectives focused on assessing the effectiveness of these technologies in enhancing efficiency and minimizing environmental impacts. The discussion encompasses the intersection of logistics and sustainability, emphasizing the benefits of this integration, such as cost reduction and improved corporate image. Technologies like the Internet of Things (IoT), Artificial Intelligence, and robotics are analyzed for their potential to transform logistics operations. The methodology features a detailed case study of CEVA LOGISTICS, outlining the technologies implemented and the results achieved, including a 20% reduction in operational costs and a significant decrease in CO2 emissions. The analysis demonstrates improvements in logistics performance and highlights both economic and environmental benefits. Ultimately, the article provides insights into the critical role of advanced technologies in sustainable logistics, contributing to the theory and practice of the field while suggesting directions for future research.</description>
      <author>Regiane Marques Junger de Oliveira</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69849/revistaft/ar10202006092043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Artificial Neural Network Ensembles for Ship Design Optimization to Reduce Added Wave Resistance and CO2 Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17215326</link>
      <description>Tomasz Cepowski, Energies. 17(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403836845

                Increased maritime cargo transportation has necessitated stricter management of emissions from ships. The primary source of this pollution is fuel combustion, which is influenced by factors such as a ship&#8217;s added wave resistance. Accurate estimation of this resistance during ship design is crucial for minimizing exhaust emissions. The challenge is that, at the preliminary parametric design stage, only limited geometric data about the ship is available, and the existing methods for estimating added wave resistance cannot be applied. This article presents the application of artificial neural network (ANN) ensembles for estimating added wave resistance based on dimensionless design parameters available at the preliminary design stage, such as the length-to-breadth ratio (L/B), breadth-to-draught ratio (B/T), length-to-draught ratio (L/T), block coefficient (CB), and the Froude number (Fn). Four different ANN ensembles are developed to predict this resistance using both complete sets of design characteristics (i.e., L/B, B/T, CB, and Fn) and incomplete sets, such as L/B, CB, and Fn; B/T, CB, and Fn; and L/T, CB, and Fn. This approach allows for the consideration of CO2 emissions at the parametric design stage when only limited ship dimensions are known. An example in this article demonstrates that minor modifications to typical container ship designs can significantly reduce added wave resistance, resulting in a daily reduction of up to 2.55 tons of CO2 emissions. This reduction is equivalent to the emissions produced by 778 cars per day, highlighting the environmental benefits of optimizing ship design.</description>
      <author>Tomasz Cepowski</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17215326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameter inference from a non-stationary unknown process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0228236</link>
      <description>Kieran S. Owens, Ben Fulcher, Chaos An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science. 34(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403921616

                Non-stationary systems are found throughout the world, from climate patterns under the influence of variation in carbon dioxide concentration to brain dynamics driven by ascending neuromodulation. Accordingly, there is a need for methods to analyze non-stationary processes, and yet, most time-series analysis methods that are used in practice on important problems across science and industry make the simplifying assumption of stationarity. One important problem in the analysis of non-stationary systems is the problem class that we refer to as parameter inference from a non-stationary unknown process (PINUP). Given an observed time series, this involves inferring the parameters that drive non-stationarity of the time series, without requiring knowledge or inference of a mathematical model of the underlying system. Here, we review and unify a diverse literature of algorithms for PINUP. We formulate the problem and categorize the various algorithmic contributions into those based on (1) dimension reduction, (2) statistical time-series features, (3) prediction error, (4) phase-space partitioning, (5) recurrence plots, and (6) Bayesian inference. This synthesis will allow researchers to identify gaps in the literature and will enable systematic comparisons of different methods. We also demonstrate that the most common systems that existing methods are tested on&#8212;notably, the non-stationary Lorenz process and logistic map&#8212;are surprisingly easy to perform well on using simple statistical features like windowed mean and variance, undermining the practice of using good performance on these systems as evidence of algorithmic performance. We then identify more challenging problems that many existing methods perform poorly on and which can be used to drive methodological advances in the field. Our results unify disjoint scientific contributions to analyzing the non-stationary systems and suggest new directions for progress on the PINUP problem and the broader study of non-stationary phenomena.</description>
      <author>Kieran S. Owens, Ben Fulcher</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0228236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ones and Zeros of Carbon Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/1124-0046-jpt</link>
      <description>Blake Wright, Journal of Petroleum Technology. 76(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403932262

                Leading services companies and specialty software firms alike have launched various tools and digital suites to assist carbon capture and storage (CCS) project operators with everything from ideal siting of facilities and pipelines to the efficient operations and around-the-clock monitoring of those facilities. CCS holds the promise of big business if industry can efficiently and economically operate at scale the slate of planned facilities. Oil and gas companies have been making investments in the space with aims to become leaders in a segment&#8212;ironic since the petroleum business is also one of the emitters of CO2 into the atmosphere. Last month, supermajor ExxonMobil executed the largest offshore CO2 storage lease in the US with the Texas General Land Office. The 271,000-plus-acre site complements the onshore CO2 storage portfolio ExxonMobil is developing and further solidifies the US Gulf Coast as a CCS leader, according to the operator. In an October 2024 report, the US Department of Energy (DOE) issued a draft strategy for carbon management technologies through 2030, stating that carbon capture and direct air capture are &#8220;essential&#8221; to achieving net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050. The report says CCS projects will grow dramatically over the next decade and beyond, adding that 18 CCS facilities are operating now in the US. DOE&#8217;s near-term CCS strategy through 2030 incorporates focusing research, development, demonstration, and deployment funding on priority use cases; building out CO2 transportation and storage infrastructure where it likely will be needed most in the future; supporting the implementation of effective and evidence-driven policies and regulations related to carbon management at other federal agencies; engaging communities and workers to ensure projects deliver benefits and mitigate potential risks to public health and the environment; and supporting climate diplomacy efforts to accelerate the adoption of carbon management at scale globally in a way that aligns with the Paris Agreement. &#8220;DOE is funding a variety of technologies to assist in decarbonization in the industrial and power sectors,&#8221; the report explained. &#8220;These approaches include carbon management as well as electrification, fuel switching, materials substitution, efficiency, and other emissions-reductions measures. In parallel, DOE is working to envision and develop transformative emissions reductions approaches that will create new options in the long term.&#8221; The US government has been an active participant in making funding available for the advancement of CCS technologies. In 2024 alone, almost $3.5 billion was made available between two separate programs&#8212;CCS large-scale pilot projects ($937 million) and CCS demonstration projects ($2.5 billion)&#8212;as part of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. In June 2023, ceremonial shovels were plunged into the dirt in Ector County, Texas, to mark the start of construction for the largest direct air capture facility in the world, designed to capture 500,000 metric tons of CO2 from the atmosphere every year. Occidental subsidiary OnePointFive&#8217;s $1-billion Stratos project is located on a 65-acre site made up of a network of air contactors, pellet reactors, a centrifuge, and a calciner&#8212;all known components that operate in other industries.</description>
      <author>Blake Wright</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/1124-0046-jpt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Policies for the Energy Efficiency of Buildings in Mexico</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14113437</link>
      <description>Mirna Castro-Bello, Lizbeth G&#243;mez-Mu&#241;oz, Carlos Virgilio Marmolejo-Vega, Cornelio Morales-Morales, Eleazar Felipe Valencia-D&#237;az, Jos&#233; Filiberto Maldonado-Catal&#225;n, Carlos Ramiro Marmolejo Duarte, Buildings. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403876250

                In Latin America, the energy crisis has worsened due to the dependence on energy services and fossil fuel imports from highly industrialized countries at prices established by the international market; this is particularly relevant to the construction industry, which presents a significant deficit in optimal energy consumption. Hence, some governments have established public policies to maximize the efficiency of these services and, at the same time, minimize the carbon footprint. In this research study, we reviewed the public policies, strategies, and incentives for energy efficiency (EE) implementation in the residential sector established by the Mexican government. A scoping review methodology was chosen and implemented in the following steps: 1. Research inquiry identification. 2. Determination of the relevant literature and studies. 3. The literature selection. 4. Data graphing. 5. Results collection, overview, and submission. In this systematic review, we identified five mandatory standards (NOM-008-ENER-2001, NOM-009-ENER-2014, NOM-018-ENER-2011, NOM-020-ENER-2011, and NOM-024-ENER-2012), six optional standards, four strategies (Green Mortgage, Integral Sustainable Improvement in Existing Housing, ECOCASA, and NAMA), and three kinds of incentives (green bonds, credit and interest rates (Green Mortgage, FIDE, and Ecocasa), and taxes (Income Tax Reduction)). As a result of the implementation of the above, as of December 2020, NAMA financed 5106 developers of 38 projects in 15 states; contributed to a reduction of 126,779 tons of CO2; and aided 19,913 people. From 2013 to December 2023, EcoCasa subsidized 71,440 households for a total of 224 projects in 25 states; contributed to a reduction of 2.6 million tons of CO2; aided 285,760 Mexicans; and issued EcoCasa certificates for 3,473,556 m2. The results of the EE indicators in residential buildings showed an increase in the housing unit number as well as an increase in household appliances, with those based on power consumption prevailing. The residential sector ranks third in power consumption in Mexico, consuming an estimated 790 pj, of which 76% corresponds to thermal energy and 24% to electric power. Among countries in Latin America and the Caribbean, Mexico has achieved an Energy Transition Index of 62%.</description>
      <author>Mirna Castro-Bello, Lizbeth G&#243;mez-Mu&#241;oz, Carlos Virgilio Marmolejo-Vega, Cornelio Morales-Morales, Eleazar Felipe Valencia-D&#237;az, Jos&#233; Filiberto Maldonado-Catal&#225;n, Carlos Ramiro Marmolejo Duarte</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14113437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology Focus: Drilling and Completion Fluids (November 2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/1124-0072-jpt</link>
      <description>Chris Carpenter, Journal of Petroleum Technology. 76(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403931891

                This year&#8217;s primary selections for the Drilling and Completion Fluids Technology Focus reflect now-well-established industrywide emphases on machine learning (ML), automation, and the achievement of successful drilling of CO2 storage wells. Enhanced methods of modeling and monitoring allow time and cost savings while surpassing safety goals and furthering efforts to optimize CO2 storage. Paper OTC 35433 discusses a study centered on accurate gel-strength estimation. The authors leverage ML techniques, particularly the use of artificial neural networks, to develop predictive models for forecasting the gel strength of synthetic oil-based mud systems at both 10-second and 10-minute intervals, surpassing the precision and speed of techniques based on traditional rotational viscometers. In a similar vein, paper SPE 216322 seeks to bypass traditional manual methods of monitoring drilling fluids, its authors describing a novel online system that measures 10 key parameters continuously. They write that the system has been field-trialed across 200 wells with results that highlight the system&#8217;s reliability, with continuous operation for over 125 days. Finally, paper SPE 217711 involves evaluating the effects of an influx of CO2 into drilling fluids, a key task in the drilling of CO2 storage wells. Concentrating on oil-based drilling fluid, the presented study describes the development and integration of models for properties of drilling-fluid/CO2 mixtures into an existing software suite. Recommended-reading papers include an investigation of the use of microwave power in recovering oil from contaminated drill cuttings, reduction of the carbon footprint of drilling fluids, and sedimentation behavior of particles in fibrous sweep fluids. As always, the long-sighted ambition of such research, and the skill applied in its pursuit, reflects the commitment to excellence embodied by the authors of technical papers presented at SPE conferences. Recommended additional reading at OnePetro: www.onepetro.org. SPE 217140 Microwave-Assisted Technique for Oil Recovery From Oily Sludge Shale Drilled Cuttings by A. Agi, Universiti Malaysia Pahang, et al. OTC 34667 Successful Decarbonization of Drilling Fluids by Using Highly Efficient Technology and Reduced Chemical Usage, Logistics, and Casing Sections by Gerardo Jardinez, Pemex, et al. SPE 218631 Application of Machine-Learning Method for Modeling Settling Behavior of a Spherical Particle in Fibrous Drilling Fluids by R.M. Elgaddafi, Australian University, et al.</description>
      <author>Chris Carpenter</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/1124-0072-jpt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology Focus: EOR Operations (November 2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/1124-0084-jpt</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Barsotti, Journal of Petroleum Technology. 76(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403927732

                International agreements and national policies on environmental sustainability are changing the outlook for enhanced oil recovery (EOR) globally. These changes are highlighted by both monetary and intellectual commitments by oil companies around the world. Saudi Aramco has pledged $1.5 billion toward sustainable technology. In practice, members of Aramco&#8217;s EXPEC Advanced Research Center have collaborated with King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals to develop sustainable surfactants for use in high-temperature, high-pressure, and high-salinity carbonate reservoirs. They used no or only green solvents to produce soluble, stable surfactants with the potential for biodegradability. In Colombia, Ecopetrol is committed to reducing CO2 emission by 25% by 2030. As part of its efforts, it has been optimizing polymer injection in Chichimene, a heavy-oil field. By estimating life cycle greenhouse-gas emissions and energy consumption, it was able to show that polymer injection and its associated carbon intensity reduction could prevent the emission of 3,200 tons CO2 equivalent. To comply with the UK&#8217;s North Sea Transition Deal, which mandates a 50% reduction in offshore oil and gas emissions by 2030, Ithaca Energy and Energy Research Norway is using life-cycle assessment to guide more efficient heavy-oil recovery. By using low-dose polymer injection, instead of alternatives such as thermal EOR, it was able to increase exergy while also reducing CO2 emissions by 35%. In these studies, we already see the effect of the energy transition as companies turn away from traditionally effective but environmentally burdensome EOR methods such as steam injection and new polymers that show equal, if not greater, effectiveness with a reduced environmental cost. As we move forward with further regulation and innovation, it will be interesting to see how emerging technological developments in polymers, nanofluids, and even artificial intelligence can help producers meet both the economic and environmental criteria to maintain profitable fields. Recommended additional reading at OnePetro: www.onepetro.org. SPE 218653 Coinjection EOR Technology Increases Recovery and Reduces Greenhouse-Gas Emissions by G. Wasylchuk, GERI SPE 218690 Steam Generation Using Renewables Energy&#8212;An Integrated Approach for Enhanced Oil Recovery Applications by Mustafa Al Ajmi, Petroleum Development Oman, et al. SPE 218962 Reaching a Million Barrels in an Abu Dhabi Field by Focusing on Operations Efficiency by Masud J. Akhtar, Abu Dhabi National Oil Company, et al.</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Barsotti</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/1124-0084-jpt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Consumption, Emission, Transportation Sector in Malaysia: Review on Malaysia&#8217;s Road Transport</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22610/imbr.v16i3s(i)a.4130</link>
      <description>Fatin Farazh Yaacob, Basri Badyalina, Sazlin Suhalmie Mohd Shariff, Mohamad Faizal Ramli, Rabiatul Munirah Alpandi, Information Management and Business Review. 16(3S(I)a)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403827357

                Transportation is a major challenge for energy conservation, with road transport in Malaysia being a significant contributor to greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. In Malaysia, traditional fossil fuels such as gasoline and diesel dominate the transportation sector, which has become the second-largest source of GHG emissions, accounting for 20% in 2014. This increase in CO2 emissions, driven by rising vehicle ownership and economic growth, underscores the urgent need for effective emission reduction strategies. The rapid growth in road transportation in Malaysia is linked to socioeconomic factors, including rising incomes and urbanization, leading to higher energy consumption and pollution. Data indicates a significant increase in vehicle registrations from 1990 to 2018, with motorcars and motorcycles being the most common. This growth, fueled by subsidies and decentralization, has exacerbated the sector&#8217;s environmental impact. The Green Technology Master Plan Malaysia 2017&#8211;2040 aims to address these issues by setting ambitious targets to enhance renewable energy, improve energy efficiency, and promote eco-friendly fuels. Key strategies include expanding public transportation, increasing the adoption of electric vehicles (EVs), and introducing alternative fuels like hydrogen. Malaysia has substantial potential to reduce CO2 emissions through initiatives such as expanding EV infrastructure, promoting natural gas vehicles, and improving public transit. Effective implementation of these strategies can significantly lower the transportation sector&#8217;s carbon footprint, contributing to a more sustainable future.</description>
      <author>Fatin Farazh Yaacob, Basri Badyalina, Sazlin Suhalmie Mohd Shariff, Mohamad Faizal Ramli, Rabiatul Munirah Alpandi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22610/imbr.v16i3s(i)a.4130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy efficient heating and ventilation of a factory hall by monitoring the indoor air climate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.153972.1</link>
      <description>Yose Wandy, Ralf Gritzki, Markus R&#246;sler, Alf Perschk, Clemens Felsmann, F1000Research. 13(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403925808

                Background Different usage scenarios and design guidelines were considered when planning a factory building and its ventilation system. Accordingly, it often makes sense to analyze the actual operating conditions again during subsequent operations in order to optimally adapt the air supply to the respective conditions in terms of demand-responsive ventilation. The aim is to ensure good indoor air quality and thermal comfort while significantly reducing energy consumption. Methods For this purpose, in addition to the sensors in the building management system, approximately 120 wireless sensors were installed in the occupied areas to measure the air temperature, operating temperature, humidity, and CO2. In this way the spatial and temporal distributions of temperature, humidity, and CO2 in the hall were visualized and evaluated to reduce the volume flows of the ventilation systems. The recorded data and findings were used to optimize ventilation systems by gaining a deeper understanding of indoor air flow. Results As part of the investigation, a considerable reduction in the air volume flows and thus the required energy consumption of the air handling units was achieved while maintaining the same thermal comfort. It was shown that the temperature field and indoor air quality were not negatively affected by the change in the air volume flow over a wide range. Conclusions This was made possible by the well-designed ventilation system, which achieves a low-pulse, slightly stratified indoor airflow, and a structural envelope with very good thermal insulation.</description>
      <author>Yose Wandy, Ralf Gritzki, Markus R&#246;sler, Alf Perschk, Clemens Felsmann</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.153972.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring climate stabilisation at different global warming levels in ACCESS-ESM-1.5</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/esd-15-1353-2024</link>
      <description>Andrew D. King, Tilo Ziehn, Matthew A. Chamberlain, Alexander R Borowiak, Josephine R. Brown, Liam Cassidy, Andrea J. Dittus, Michael Grose, Nicola Maher, Seungmok Paik, Sarah E. Perkins&#8208;Kirkpatrick, Aditya Sengupta, Earth System Dynamics. 15(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403886533

                Abstract. Under the Paris Agreement, signatory nations aim to keep global warming well below 2 &#176;C above pre-industrial levels and preferably below 1.5 &#176;C. This implicitly requires achieving net-zero or net-negative greenhouse gas emissions to ensure long-term global temperature stabilisation or reduction. Despite this requirement, there have been few analyses of stabilised climates, and there is a lack of model experiments to address our need for understanding the implications of the Paris Agreement. Here, we describe a new set of experiments using the Australian Community Climate and Earth System Simulator Earth system model (ACCESS-ESM-1.5) that enables the analysis of climate evolution under net-zero emissions, and we present initial results. Seven 1000-year-long simulations were run with global temperatures stabilising at levels in line with the Paris Agreement and at a range of higher global warming levels (GWLs). We provide an overview of the experimental design and use these simulations to demonstrate the consequences of delayed attainment of global net-zero carbon dioxide emissions. We show that there are substantial differences between transient and stabilising climate states and differences in stabilisation between GWLs. As the climate stabilises under net-zero emissions, we identify significant and robust changes in temperature and precipitation patterns including continued Southern Ocean warming and changes in regional precipitation trends. Changes under net-zero emissions differ greatly between regions, including contrasting trajectories of sea ice extent between the Arctic and Antarctic. We also examine the El Ni&#241;o&#8211;Southern Oscillation (ENSO) and find evidence of reduced amplitude and frequency of ENSO events under climate stabilisation relative to projections under transient warming. An analysis at specific GWLs shows that significant regional changes continue for centuries after emission cessation and that these changes are stronger at higher GWLs. Our findings suggest substantial long-term climate changes are possible even under net-zero emission pathways. These simulations are available for use in the community and will hopefully motivate further experiments and analyses based on other Earth system models.</description>
      <author>Andrew D. King, Tilo Ziehn, Matthew A. Chamberlain, Alexander R Borowiak, Josephine R. Brown, Liam Cassidy, Andrea J. Dittus, Michael Grose, Nicola Maher, Seungmok Paik, Sarah E. Perkins&#8208;Kirkpatrick, Aditya Sengupta</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/esd-15-1353-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance and Emission Characteristics of a Diesel Engine Fueled by Biodiesel-Ethanol-Diesel Fuel Blends</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51141/ijatr.v4i1.27</link>
      <description>Hazir Farouk, International Journal of Advanced Thermofluid Research. 4(1)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4403799577

                There is growing interest to study the effect of blending various oxygenated additives with diesel or biodiesel fuel on engine performance and emission characteristics. This study aims to analyze the performance and exhaust emission of a four-stroke, four-cylinder diesel engine fueled with biodiesel-ethanol-diesel. Biodiesel was first produced from crude Jatropha oil, and then it was blended with ethanol and fossil diesel in different blend ratios (B10E10D80, B12.5E12.5D75, B15E15D70, B20E20D60 and B25E25D50). The engine performance and emission characteristics were studied at engine speeds ranging from 1200 to 2000 rpm. The results show that the brake specific fuel consumption increases while the brake power decreases as the percentage of biodiesel and ethanol increases in the blend. The exhaust emission analysis shows a reduction in CO2 emission and increase in NOx emission when the biodiesel -to-ethanol ratio increases in the blends, when compared with diesel as a reference fuel.</description>
      <author>Hazir Farouk</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51141/ijatr.v4i1.27</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Simulation of Nonpharmaceutical Interventions of Airborne Disease Transmission in Office Settings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph21111413</link>
      <description>Thomas Zimmerman, Neha Sharma, Hakan Bulu, Vanessa Burrowes, David Beymer, Vandana Mukherjee, International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 21(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403766483

                The COVID-19 pandemic has caused major disruptions to workplace safety and productivity. A browser-based interactive disease transmission simulation was developed to enable managers and individuals (agents) to optimize safe office work activities during pandemic conditions. The application provides a user interface to evaluate the impact of non-pharmaceutical interventions (NPIs) policies on airborne disease exposure based on agents&#8217; meeting patterns and room properties. Exposure is empirically calibrated using CO2 as a proxy for viral aerosol dispersion. For the building studied, the major findings are that the cubicles during low occupancy produce unexpectedly high exposure, upgrading meetings to larger rooms reduces total average exposure by 44%, and when all meetings are conducted in large rooms, a 79% exposure reduction is realized.</description>
      <author>Thomas Zimmerman, Neha Sharma, Hakan Bulu, Vanessa Burrowes, David Beymer, Vandana Mukherjee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph21111413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research and Case Application of Zero-Carbon Buildings Based on Multi-System Integration Function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14113394</link>
      <description>Jiaji Zhang, Yu-Ting Lin, Li Wang, Qiankun Wang, Ke Zhu, Shize Yang, Guoqing Guo, Buildings. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403761728

                This study focuses on developing and implementing zero-carbon buildings through the integration of multiple systems to meet China&#8217;s carbon neutrality goals. It emphasizes the significant role of the building sector in carbon emissions and highlights the challenge of increasing energy consumption conflicting with China&#8217;s &#8220;dual carbon&#8221; targets. To address this, the research proposes a comprehensive framework that combines multifunctional envelope structure (MES) systems, photovoltaic power generation, energy storage, direct current (DC) systems, flexible energy management (PEDF), and regional energy stations. This framework integrates different technologies such as phase change materials, radiation cooling, and carbon mineralized cement, aiming to reduce carbon emissions throughout the building&#8217;s lifecycle. The method has been successfully applied in the Yazhou Bay Zero Carbon Post Station project in Sanya, Hainan, with precise calculations of carbon emission reductions. The carbon emission calculations revealed a reduction of 44.13 tons of CO2 annually, totaling 1103.31 tons over 25 years, primarily due to the rooftop photovoltaic systems. It demonstrates that the multi-system integration can reduce carbon emissions and contribute to China&#8217;s broader carbon neutrality goals. This approach, if widely adopted, could accelerate the transition to carbon-neutral buildings in China.</description>
      <author>Jiaji Zhang, Yu-Ting Lin, Li Wang, Qiankun Wang, Ke Zhu, Shize Yang, Guoqing Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14113394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Formation of C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Products Steered by Bridge-Bonded *CO Confined by *OH Domains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08755</link>
      <description>Haibin Ma, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez-Al&#233;, Futian You, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z, Boon Siang Yeo, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403879378

                During the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) on copper catalysts, linear-bonded CO (*COL) is commonly regarded as the key intermediate for the CO-CO coupling step, which leads to the formation of multicarbon products. In this work, we unveil the significant role of bridge-bonded *CO (*COB) as an active species. By combining in situ Raman spectroscopy, gas and liquid chromatography, and density functional theory (DFT) simulations, we show that adsorbed *OH domains displace *COL to *COB. The electroreduction of a 12CO+13CO2 cofeed demonstrates that *COB distinctly favors the production of acetate and 1-propanol, while *COL favors ethylene and ethanol formation. This work enhances our understanding of the mechanistic intricacies of eCO(2)RR and suggests new directions for designing operational conditions by modifying the competitive adsorption of surface species, thereby steering the reaction toward specific multicarbon products.</description>
      <author>Haibin Ma, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez-Al&#233;, Futian You, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z, Boon Siang Yeo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persistent deep-water formation in the Nordic Seas during Marine Isotope Stages 5 and 4 notwithstanding changes in Atlantic overturning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3163</link>
      <description>Tim Beneke Stobbe, Henning A. Bauch, Daniel A. Frick, Jimin Yu, Julia Gottschalk, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403844336

                Abstract. Reductions in the extent and formation of North Atlantic Deep Water (NADW) and the expansion of southern-sourced waters in the Atlantic Ocean were linked to enhanced marine carbon storage during glacial and stadial periods and are considered a key mechanism explaining late Pleistocene atmospheric CO2 variations on glacial-interglacial and millennial timescales. However, changes in the formation of deep waters in the Nordic Seas, an important source of NADW, and their influence on the geometry and intensity of Atlantic overturning remain poorly understood, especially beyond the last glacial maximum, leaving possible impacts on atmospheric CO2 changes elusive. Here, we present high-resolution Cibicidoides wuellerstorfi B/Ca-based bottom water [CO32-] reconstructions, alongside with complementary C. wuellerstorfi stable oxygen and carbon isotopes and abundance estimates of aragonitic pteropods in marine sediment core PS1243 from the deep Norwegian Sea to investigate past deep-water dynamics in the Nordic Seas and potential impacts on Atlantic overturning and carbon cycling. Our data suggest continuous formation of dense and well-ventilated (high-[CO32-]) deep waters throughout Marine Isotope Stages (MIS) 5 and 4, alongside a deepening of the aragonite compensation depth by at least 700 m during the MIS 5b-to-4 transition, consistent with sustained Nordic Seas convection. In addition, higher-than-Holocene bottom water [CO32-] during MIS 5e highlight the resilience of Nordic Seas overturning towards a warmer North Atlantic, decreased Arctic sea ice extent and meltwater supply from surrounding ice sheets. A compilation of bottom water [CO32-] records from the Atlantic Ocean indicates that dense waters from the Nordic Seas may have continuously expanded into the intermediate and/or deep (western) North Atlantic via supply of dense water overflows across the Greenland-Scotland Ridge, diminishing the capacity of the North Atlantic to store carbon during MIS 4 and stadial conditions of MIS 5. Our study emphasises differences in the sensitivity of North Atlantic and Nordic Seas overturning dynamics to climate boundary conditions of the last glacial cycle that have implications for the carbon storage capacity of the Atlantic Ocean and its role in atmospheric CO2 variations.</description>
      <author>Tim Beneke Stobbe, Henning A. Bauch, Daniel A. Frick, Jimin Yu, Julia Gottschalk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Microgrid Deployment Framework to Support Drayage Electrification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.01684</link>
      <description>Joseph N. E. Lucero, Ruixiao Sun, Brandon A. Miller, Simona Onori, Vivek A. Sujan, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403851991

                The electrification of heavy-duty commercial vehicles (HDCVs) is pivotal in reducing greenhouse gas emissions and urban air pollution; however, this transition poses significant challenges for the existing electric grid, which is not designed to meet the high electricity demands of HDCVs. This can lead to a less effective reduction in freight transportation's carbon intensity despite significant electrification efforts. Deploying renewable energy sources, such as photovoltaics, alongside energy storage solutions, is essential to address these challenges. This paper examines the current grid limitations and explores the critical role of microgrid deployment, integrating solar and battery energy storage systems, in supporting the electrification of HDCVs. We propose an integrated framework that is designed to enhance regional grid capacity and decrease carbon intensity by identifying viable sites where a microgrid can be deployed and provide estimates for the deployment cost. Furthermore, using this framework, we quantify the maximal impact of microgrid deployment in reducing CO2 emissions when we optimize the use of the available power. As a demonstration, we apply our framework to the region of the Port of Savannah, GA USA.</description>
      <author>Joseph N. E. Lucero, Ruixiao Sun, Brandon A. Miller, Simona Onori, Vivek A. Sujan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.01684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Approach in ESP Power Optimization for Large Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221563-ms</link>
      <description>Mulad B. Winarno, M. A. Eissa, Mar&#237;a Flores, M. A. Khalifah, O. L. Isichei, Suleyman Malki, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403821887

                Abstract Electric Submersible Pump (ESP) is very popular artificial lift method to produce at high production rate. However, ESP power consumption is costly and mandate proper optimization to operate at the optimal condition. ESP energy optimization directly improve operational efficiency and reduces lifting cost and greenhouse gas emission. The ESP power optimization is challenging exercise and requires involvement from multiple organizations. The process has to go through excess of possible combinations of surface choke valve positions and pump speed until reaching an optimized setting. Optimization of ESP operations helps operators to meet production target while maximizing the efficiency of the pump operation. However, it cannot be achieved easily, especially where time and resources are scarce. An innovative approach capitalizing the digital-twin model and artificial intelligence technologies to optimize the ESP performance and adhering to the environmental challenges of reducing CO2 emission has been introduced to expedite the optimization process. The new approach automatically utilizes ESP real time data, ESP installation data along with the well model to determine the ESP's optimal WHP and ESP frequency. The modelling will be automatically updated based on real time data and provide predictions of recommended operation frequency and optimum wellhead pressure, which is translated to choke size, to operate the ESP at BEP (Best Efficiency Point) and to maximize production rate and minimize power consumption. The optimization process has been implemented in the field resulting in a significant power consumption saving and CO2 emission reduction. Further gains are also expected from ESP performance, resulting in longer ESP run life and reduce number of workover cost. This paper will share the ESP optimization journey using the advisory tool from obtaining the data, performing the calculations, providing the recommendations, and field implementation of these recommendations. The best practices and lessons learnt were captured as a reference for future ESP power optimization advisory tool enhancement.</description>
      <author>Mulad B. Winarno, M. A. Eissa, Mar&#237;a Flores, M. A. Khalifah, O. L. Isichei, Suleyman Malki</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221563-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health burden and costs attributed to the carbon footprint of health systems in the European Union</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/eurpub/ckae144.021</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Chen-Xu, M Corda, Orsolya Varga, Susana Viegas, European Journal of Public Health. 34(Supplement_3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403825534

                Abstract Background Health systems have an environmental impact of around 4.6% of global emissions, contributing to aggravating the climate crisis. However, the health impact of the carbon emissions originated by health systems is not regularly assessed. We aim to estimate the health burden and associated costs of the carbon footprint of health systems across the European Union (EU). Methods We calculated DALYs and associated costs based on human health damage factors (DALYs/kg-CO2e) by considering four scenarios. Three scenarios for shared socioeconomic pathways (S1 - high growth, S2 - baseline, and S3 - low growth) represented variations of global society, demographics, and economics until 2100. A fourth scenario (S4) considered the current EU&#8217;s 55% reduction goal of greenhouse gas emissions. The healthcare sector&#8217;s emissions per capita (in CO2-equivalent) in 2019 were extracted from the Lancet Countdown, and population data were retrieved from Eurostat for the same year. Results In the EU, 365,047 DALYs (95%CI: 194,692-535,403) are expected to be caused by health systems&#8217; emissions at baseline (S2). In an S1 scenario, the burden would slightly decrease to 315,374 DALYs (95%CI: 170,355-462,393), whereas a S3 scenario would increase 486,730 DALYs (95%CI: 243,365-681,422). If EU&#8217;s carbon goals are met, the burden could be substantially reduced to 164,271 DALYs (95%CI: 87,611-240,931). The monetisation of DALYs can result in costs amounting to 25.6 billion euros. Conclusions CO2 emissions from health systems are expected to significantly impact human health. It is therefore of the utmost importance to ensure that EU climate policies for healthcare buildings are in line with the Paris Agreement. This will require the implementation of climate mitigation programmes within the health sector and a review of clinical practices at the local level. Key messages &#8226; The carbon footprint of health systems is estimated to significantly impact health, with high economic burden. &#8226; EU climate policies for healthcare buildings and procurement must be aligned with the Paris Agreement.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Chen-Xu, M Corda, Orsolya Varga, Susana Viegas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/eurpub/ckae144.021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Waste Glass Powder Replacement of Hydraulic Lime on Properties of Natural Hydraulic Lime Mortars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17215247</link>
      <description>Murat &#350;ahin, P. &#214;zyigit, Materials. 17(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403835555

                This paper investigates the effects of the partial replacement of natural hydraulic lime (NHL) with waste glass powder (GP) on the physical, mechanical, and microstructural properties of NHL mortars. In the experimental study, five mixtures containing up to 50% GP were prepared to evaluate its effect on the flow, carbonation, unit weight, water absorption, porosity, ultrasonic pulse velocity, capillary water absorption, compressive strength, and microstructure of NHL mortars. The experimental results suggest that the partial replacement of NHL with GP significantly affects the properties of NHL mortars. A reduction in compressive strength was observed with increasing GP content in mortars at both early and later stages. Nevertheless, the compressive strength difference between samples containing 50% GP and the reference was found to be relatively minor at 91 days, implying an enhanced pozzolanic reaction over time. The incorporation of GP improved the consistency and capillary water absorption of mortars, while the opposite was observed for ultrasonic pulse velocity, porosity, and water absorption. The microstructural analysis revealed distinct changes in the structure of samples incorporating GP. The partial substitution of hydraulic lime with GP could be beneficial in reducing the CO2 emissions of NHL mortars.</description>
      <author>Murat &#350;ahin, P. &#214;zyigit</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17215247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fuel tax loss in a world of electric mobility: A window of opportunity
  for congestion pricing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.20033</link>
      <description>Thi Ngoc Nguyen, Felix Muesgens, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403814932

                The continued transition towards electric mobility will decrease energy tax revenues worldwide, which has substantial implications for government funds. At the same time, demand for transportation is ever increasing, which in turn increases congestion problems. Combining both challenges, this paper assesses the effectiveness of congestion pricing as a sustainable revenue stream to offset fuel tax loss in 2030 while simultaneously enhancing efficiency in the transport sector. A congestion-based toll that is road-and-time-variant is simulated for the greater Berlin area in Germany using the multi-agent transport simulation (MATSim) software. Through the simulation results, this paper quantifies the impacts of the toll on the governmental revenue, traffic management, environment, social welfare, and the distribution effects. We find that the revenue from congestion tolls in a metropolitan area can compensate the reduction in passenger car fuel tax. Furthermore, a remarkable welfare surplus is observed. The toll also successfully incentivises transport users to adjust their travel behaviour, which reduces traffic delay time by 28%. CO2 emissions as a key metric for decarbonisation of the transport sector decrease by more than 5%. The analysis of the distribution effects suggests that a redistribution plan with a focus on the middle-low-income residents and the outer boroughs could help the policy gain more public acceptance.</description>
      <author>Thi Ngoc Nguyen, Felix Muesgens</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.20033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability and Environmental Performance in Selective Collection of Residual Materials: Impact of Modulating Citizen Participation Through Policy and Incentive Implementation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/resources13110151</link>
      <description>Laurie Fontaine, Robert Legros, Jean&#8208;Marc Frayret, Resources. 13(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403773046

                The effective management of urban waste represents a growing challenge in the face of demographic evolution and increased consumption. This study explores the impacts of municipal strategic decisions on household waste management behaviours and sustainability performance outcomes through agent-based modelling. Using data from Gatineau and Beaconsfield in Quebec, Canada, the model is calibrated and validated to represent diverse urban contexts. Our analysis demonstrates that reducing collection frequency leads to notable increases in participation rates, reaching 78.2 &#177; 5.1% for collections every two weeks and 96.5 &#177; 8.3% for collections every five weeks. While this reduction improves bin filling levels, it concurrently decreases the recovery of recyclable materials by 2.8% and 19.5%, significantly undermining the environmental benefits of the recycling program. These findings highlight a complex interplay between collection frequency, citizen participation behaviour, waste stream characteristics, and overall environmental performance. While reducing collection frequency initially appears beneficial, it leads to operational challenges and increased CO2 emissions due to reduced material recovery. The research emphasises the need for tailored holistic waste management strategies that optimise performance outcomes while minimising environmental impacts. By understanding these dynamics, municipalities can develop more effective waste management policies that promote sustainability.</description>
      <author>Laurie Fontaine, Robert Legros, Jean&#8208;Marc Frayret</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/resources13110151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-replicating fuels via autocatalytic molecular bond fission</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.01282</link>
      <description>Peter Agbo, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885165

                This computational study advances a theoretical framework for practical, electrochemical fuel generation displaying exponential product yields and product formation rates as functions of time. Exponential reaction scaling is simulated through an autocatalytic cycle that emulates the process of DNA replication facilitated by the well-known polymerase chain reaction (PCR). Here, an initial buildup of formate into a two-carbon chain through CO2 carboxylation forms oxalate. A subsequent, two-electron reduction yields glyoxylate, with base-mediated hydrolysis driving C-C bond fission of glyoxylate into two molecules of formate. These products are then recycled back to serve as reactants. This recursive process chemistry displays 2^n stoichiometries with respect to formate growth in the limit of ideal reaction selectivity. Each step of the proposed fuel cycle shows direct analogy to the steps of DNA annealing, nucleotide polymerization and hybridized strand fission that are responsible for the exponential product yields observed in PCR-mediated DNA synthesis. As a consequence of this replication behavior, rapid rates of fuel production are accessible even when the individual rate constants for the cycle's constituent processes are slow. Significant focus is placed on practical routes for realizing each of the three steps comprising this model case of formate replication, particularly the challenge of formate carboxylation and the corresponding energy demands and power constraints of the overall process.</description>
      <author>Peter Agbo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.01282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon emission reduction associated with dapagliflozin compared to standard of care in the UK: translating the DAPA-HF and DELIVER trial findings to an environmental context</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae666.3618</link>
      <description>P. W. Ewan, Jihua Chen, Gwilym Roberts, Katherine Mullin, Laia Falc&#243;n, Mart&#237;n Cowie, European Heart Journal. 45(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403819082

                Abstract Background Healthcare systems account for 4&#8211;5% of UK national greenhouse gas emissions with delivery of care a major component.1 Preventing events that use healthcare resources should contribute to a reduction in emissions, in addition to the primary humanitarian aim of improving patient outcomes. The Dapagliflozin And Prevention of Adverse-outcomes in Heart Failure (DAPA-HF) and the Dapagliflozin Evaluation to Improve the Lives of Patient with Preserved Ejection Fraction Heart Failure (DELIVER) trials demonstrated that dapagliflozin reduced the frequency of hospitalizations for heart failure (hHF), urgent heart failure visits (UHFV) and cardiovascular (CV) death for patients with heart failure (HF).2,3 Purpose The study objective was to translate predicted differences in clinical events associated with dapagliflozin use in HF to a predicted carbon emission reduction from a UK perspective. Methods A previously published model4 based on pooled DAPA-HF and DELIVER event rates was used to predict hHF, UHFV and CV deaths in a cohort of 1,000 HF patients over a 3-year time horizon. Composite greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions (as kg CO2 equivalent) were calculated from components sourced from the Sustainable Healthcare Coalition&#8217;s Care Pathway Calculator according to assumed clinical pathways and were applied to predicted incidence of hHF, UHFV and CV death events. Average length of stay was sourced from the National Heart Failure Audit.5 CV deaths occurring outside hospital were assumed to incur no additional carbon emission except that associated with cremation. Proportion of funerals by cremation and associated GHG emissions were sourced from literature.6,7 Future emissions were not discounted, representing the NHS&#8217;s aim to approach &#8216;net zero&#8217;. Results Over a 3-year time horizon, treatment with dapagliflozin was projected to prevent 74 hHF events, 9 UHFV events and 20 CV deaths per 1,000 patients treated versus placebo. Total estimated GHG emissions associated with hHF (233.2 kg CO2e), UHFV (177.4 kg CO2e), and CV death (251.4 kg CO2e) were 85,660 kg CO2e per 1,000 patients treated with dapagliflozin versus 109,618 kg CO2e per 1,000 patients treated with placebo. The projected total reduction associated with dapagliflozin treatment was 23,958 kg CO2e over 3 years, a 22% reduction versus placebo. Per population (~690,000 HF patients), total emissions prevented by dapagliflozin over 3 years were projected to be equivalent to driving 42 million miles in an average gasoline-powered passenger vehicle. Conclusion While the main aim of any therapeutic intervention is to save lives and improve patient outcomes, to capture the full spectrum of benefit to stakeholders the environmental consequences of new therapies should be considered in addition to their clinical and economic effects. Our analysis suggests treating patients with dapagliflozin may contribute to reducing the environmental burden of HF in addition to improving patient outcomes.</description>
      <author>P. W. Ewan, Jihua Chen, Gwilym Roberts, Katherine Mullin, Laia Falc&#243;n, Mart&#237;n Cowie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae666.3618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Results on the Use of an Original Burner for Reducing the Three-Way Catalyst Light-Off Time</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inventions9060112</link>
      <description>Adrian Clenci, Bogdan Cioc, Julien Berquez, Victor Iorga-Sim&#259;n, Robert Stoica, Rodica Mariana Niculescu, Inventions. 9(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403867999

                Individual road mobility comes with two major challenges: greenhouse gas emissions related to global warming and chemical pollution. For the pollution reduction in the spark ignition engine vehicle, the standard and reliable aftertreatment technology is the three-way catalytic converter (TWC). However, the TWC starts to convert once an optimal temperature, usually known as the light-off temperature, is reached. There are many methods to reduce the warm-up period of the TWC, among which is using a burner. The initial question underlying this study was to see if the use of a relatively straightforward extra-combustion device mounted upstream the TWC, without complex elements, was able to serve the purpose of reducing the light-off time. Consequently, an original burner was designed and investigated numerically via the CFD method and experimentally via measurements of the temperature evolution within a TWC, along with the emissions specific to the burner&#8217;s operation. The main findings of this study are: (1) the CFD-based examination is a good way to decide on how to achieve the so-called fit-for-purpose internal aerodynamics of the burner (i.e., to obtain a homogeneous mixture) and (2) to reach the light-off temperature, conventionally taken as 500 K, the burner was operated for 5.2 s, i.e., 3.6 g of gasoline injected, 2.7 g of CO2 and 1.351 g of CO, respectively, emitted. Moreover, this study identified measures for improving the burner&#8217;s design as well as an enhanced procedure for the burner&#8217;s operating control both aiming to produce a cleaner combustion during the TWC pre-heating.</description>
      <author>Adrian Clenci, Bogdan Cioc, Julien Berquez, Victor Iorga-Sim&#259;n, Robert Stoica, Rodica Mariana Niculescu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inventions9060112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Hydrogen Production System Performance Using Photovoltaic/Thermal-Coupled PEM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17215405</link>
      <description>Guorong Li, Chen Song, Guangchao Han, Zihao Chen, Jiwei Huang, Energies. 17(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403893320

                A proton exchange membrane electrolyzer can effectively utilize the electricity generated by intermittent solar power. Different methods of generating electricity may have different efficiencies and hydrogen production rates. Two coupled systems, namely, PV/T- and CPV/T-coupling PEMEC, respectively, are presented and compared in this study. A maximum power point tracking algorithm for the photovoltaic system is employed, and simulations are conducted based on the solar irradiation intensity and ambient temperature of a specific location on a particular day. The simulation results indicate that the hydrogen production is relatively high between 11:00 and 16:00, with a peak between 12:00 and 13:00. The maximum hydrogen production rate is 99.11 g/s and 29.02 g/s for the CPV/T-PEM and PV/T-PEM systems. The maximum energy efficiency of hydrogen production in CPV/T-PEM and PV/T-PEM systems is 66.7% and 70.6%. Under conditions of high solar irradiation intensity and ambient temperature, the system demonstrates higher total efficiency and greater hydrogen production. The CPV/T-PEM system achieves a maximum hydrogen production rate of 2240.41 kg/d, with a standard coal saving rate of 15.5 tons/day and a CO2 reduction rate of 38.0 tons/day. Compared to the PV/T-PEM system, the CPV/T-PEM system exhibits a higher hydrogen production rate. These findings provide valuable insights into the engineering application of photovoltaic/thermal-coupled hydrogen production technology and contribute to the advancement of this field.</description>
      <author>Guorong Li, Chen Song, Guangchao Han, Zihao Chen, Jiwei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17215405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Carbon Footprint Reduction During Hydrogen Co-Combustion in a Turbojet Engine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17215397</link>
      <description>Bartosz Ciupek, &#321;ukasz Brodzik, Andrzej Fr&#261;ckowiak, Energies. 17(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403893739

                The paper presents experimental studies on the effect of co-combustion of aviation kerosene with hydrogen in the GTM400 turbojet engine on the change in the carbon footprint generated by the engine in relation to its standard operation without hydrogen in the fuel. This research is in line with current research and development trends carried out in the EU, linking them to the issues of the European Green Deal, the Fit for 55 directive and current environmental trends in aviation and energy. The main objective of the research was to check the effect of hydrogen co-combustion in a turbojet engine on the change of the carbon footprint, while a secondary objective was to verify the impact of higher exhaust gas temperatures generated by the new, high-calorific fuel on the secondary generation of nitrogen oxides (NOx), especially in the thermal mechanism, as an undesirable effect. The research shows that the co-combustion of hydrogen with aviation kerosene in a turbojet engine reduces the carbon footprint (reduction of CO2 maximum of 15% and CO emissions maximum of 24%), but also increases the emission of nitrogen oxides (NOx) maximum of 58%, including those generated in the thermal mechanism (significant increase in the temperature of exhaust gases), moreover, the increase in nitrogen oxide emissions is proportional to the amount of co-combusted hydrogen, which is directly related to the stoichiometry of the combustion process. The main conclusion of the research is that technologies for the combustion or co-combustion of hydrogen in turbojet engines require further research and development, mainly on the side of the use of excess exhaust gas temperature generated during combustion and methods of reducing secondary nitrogen oxides.</description>
      <author>Bartosz Ciupek, &#321;ukasz Brodzik, Andrzej Fr&#261;ckowiak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17215397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hospital design and planning in the line of foresight of health needs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/eurpub/ckae144.087</link>
      <description>M Jevti&#263;, Catherine Bouland, D Polic, European Journal of Public Health. 34(Supplement_3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403825047

                Abstract The health needs of the population are increasingly difficult to plan and predict. Technological progress, artificial intelligence, new medicines, but also ecological disasters, humanitarian crises, energy crisis and other challenges (as a Covid 19 pandemic) represent the image of our time. New design of hospitals should be able to respond to the challenges of the future: comprehensive provision of health services taking into account the patient&#8217;s needs, working conditions taking into account the hospital staff, energy efficiency and construction in accordance with high standards and reduction of CO2 emissions (green hospitals), to ensure alternative sources of electricity and water supply bearing in mind potential emergencies. The big challenge of long-term construction in which advanced technologies and new procedures cannot simply fit into a rigid building structure that is several decades old (example Serbia), so it is necessary to apply precise planning and efficient and high-quality construction in the next generation hospitals, taking into account current modern equipment and that which will appear in the future. Designing hospitals involves anticipating future healthcare challenges, technological advancements, demographic shifts, and changes in patient expectations. Hospitals emphasis on patient-centered design principles, creating environments that prioritize comfort, privacy, and dignity for patients and their families, accessibility and inclusivity, infection control and prevention, sustainability and resilience. Modern hospitals should create collaborative spaces for interdisciplinary teamwork and communication among healthcare providers, research and innovation units, but also community engagement and health promotion activities. Future hospital design requires strong multidisciplinary and cross-sectional cooperation, in which priority is given to architects dedicated to this field and their cooperation with public health and health management experts.</description>
      <author>M Jevti&#263;, Catherine Bouland, D Polic</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/eurpub/ckae144.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Combined Effect of Mixed Multi-Microplastic Types on Growth and Yield of Tomato</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.2190.v1</link>
      <description>C. U. Emenike, Adeola Adelugba, Mason T. MacDonald, Samuel K. Asiedu, Raphael Ofoe, Lord Abbey, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403819567

                Microplastics (MPs) are plastic particles ranging from 1,000 to 5,000 &#181;m in diameter, posing a growing environmental and health risk. Composting is an excellent way to add nutrient-rich humus to the soil to boost plant development, but it also pollutes agricultural soil with MPs. Previous research has shown that MPs can threaten plant development, production, and quality, hence they must be studied. This study examined how a mixture of three MP types&#8212;polyethylene (PE), polystyrene (PS), and polypropylene (PP)&#8212;affected greenhouse tomato plant development. MP types were spiked at 1% w/w (MPs/soil) in tomato pots, whereas non-spiked growth medium was the control. Statistical analysis was conducted using an analysis of variance (ANOVA) and Tukey test (95% confidence) to compare treatments and controls. Soil spiked with MPs increased chlorophyll content (SPAD), transpiration rate, photosynthetic rate, and stomata conductance by 5.16%, 16.71%, 25.81%, and 20.75%, respectively, compared to the control but decreased sub-stomata CO2 concentration by 3.23%. However, MPs did not significantly affect tomato plant morpho-physiological features (p &amp;gt; 0.05). Biochemical analysis of tomato fruits showed significant (p &amp;lt; 0.05) reduction effects of MPs on carotenoid, total flavonoid, and sugar but increased protein, ascorbate, and peroxidase activity. However, there was no significant difference (p &amp;gt; 0.05) in the effects of the combined MPs on total phenolic content. These data imply that whereas MPs did not influence tomato plant physiological and morphological properties, tomato fruit biochemistry was reduced. This raise concerns that an increase in MPs in soils may reduce antioxidant content and negatively affect human health contributing to a decrease in food security.</description>
      <author>C. U. Emenike, Adeola Adelugba, Mason T. MacDonald, Samuel K. Asiedu, Raphael Ofoe, Lord Abbey</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.2190.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymer Flooding Reduces Emissions and Energy Consumption in the North Sea</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/1124-0092-jpt</link>
      <description>Chris Carpenter, Journal of Petroleum Technology. 76(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403931920

                _ This article, written by JPT Technology Editor Chris Carpenter, contains highlights of paper SPE 218231, How Polymer Flooding Reduces CO2 Emissions and Energy Consumption at the Captain Field: An Exergy-Return-on-Exergy-Investment Case Study,&#8221; by Tormod Skauge, SPE, and Arne Skauge, SPE, Energy Research Norway, and Nancy Lugo, Ithaca Energy UK, et al. The paper has not been peer reviewed. _ Insights into the energy efficiency and environmental performance of the extraction of heavy oil from the Captain field in the UK sector of the North Sea are gained using life-cycle assessment (LCA), which incorporates the concept of exergy-return-on-exergy-investment (ERoEI). The LCA allows for separation of the process into material and work streams, assessing the effect of each separately. In the complete paper, the authors compare waterflooding (WF) to polymer flooding (PF) as primary extraction strategies. Introduction The Captain field is approximately 145 km northeast of Aberdeen, Scotland. The reservoirs lie at shallow depths of approximately 900 m true vertical depth with correspondingly low temperatures of 31&#176;C and low pressures of 87 bar. A primary challenge is the relatively viscous oil of 40&#8211;140 cp. The field was initially developed with long horizontal wells and downhole pumps. Viscous oil implies mobility challenges, however, and water injection could lead to unstable displacement, early water breakthrough, and possible coning issues. After a successful pilot PF at Captain during 2010&#8211;2017, a staged enhanced oil recovery (EOR) development approach was adopted in 2016 aiming to extend the pilot polymer-solution-injection scheme to the full field through a phased development. Following the pilot study, the Captain EOR project was split into Stage 1 and Stage 2. The first stage involved drilling of five producers and two EOR injectors by 2022. The second stage included some brownfield modifications across the three Captain installations (two installations and a floating production, storage, and offloading vessel) and a significant expansion in the subsea area. The complete paper concentrates on the expansion in the subsea areas, Areas B and C. The methodology of the study, including the development of simulation cases, LCA, exergy analysis, system boundaries, material and work streams, and CO2 emissions, is detailed in the complete paper. Production Profiles The Stage 2 EOR development evaluates PF for Areas B and C. The baseline is WF with fully produced water reinjection. WF was scheduled to begin in January 2024 and to end in December 2099. The PF case also was slated to begin in January 2024 and to end in 2035 and 2034 for Area B and Area C, respectively. The field is operated on pressure maintenance, and the voidage replacement ratio is kept close to 1.0. This means that the PF injects more liquid than the WF case during the first 5 years of injection when the oil production is higher for PF. After polymer injection ends, the PF case injects less liquid than the WF case. In Area B, water cut is high from the start for the WF case. Because of the high mobility of the water, it fingers through the oil. In contrast, when polymer is injected, the water cut falls to approximately 80% and does not reach the starting value of 94.1% before 7 years, more than 2.5 years after having stopped the polymer injection in this area. The low water cut is the result of production of a large oil bank generated by the improved sweep and mobility reduction of the injected polymer.</description>
      <author>Chris Carpenter</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/1124-0092-jpt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experience of Production Increases in High Run Life Wells by Injection Optimization and the Inclusion of PMM Technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221522-ms</link>
      <description>Fabio Pino, E. G. Siri, Gonzalo Maldonado, Marco Orozco, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403821830

                Abstract Optimizing extensive ESP fields is a mandatory task in terms of carbon footprint and efficiency. The main goal is to keep the equipment running with the best efficiency as long as possible, acknowledging the ESP will show normal wear due to the operation. This analysis focuses on enhancing energy efficiency, allowing the definition of the true production capabilities by comparing operating conditions related to the motor technologies available for generating the best opportunities of improvement. By observing the well production response to increased injection in a seemingly optimized condition, it was proceeded to replace the ESP, incorporating PMM technology and a downhole sensor. This enabled us to: Define the actual IPR curve Simulate the condition on the extracted equipment (IM without a downhole sensor) Validate the deviation in ESP system efficiency Verify ESP wear through bench testing This approach allows for a comparison of extraction efficiency and the impact of wear associated with extended equipment run life. Based on the study findings, it is inferred that in ESPs with extended run life (&amp;gt;2000 days), wear leads to a decline in energy and production efficiency, reducing efficiency by up to 18.6%. These results prompt preventive measures to optimize wells, boosting production without significantly altering energy consumption. This is achievable by transitioning to PMM-equipped systems, significantly enhancing overall efficiency. With these results, preventive actions can be taken to adapt the wells and obtain an increase in production without considerably modifying energy consumption. This is possible through changing technology, installing PMM equipment and significantly improving the efficiency of the system. In addition, it allows capturing production that was not considered, establishing the correct extractive status of the well. Additionally, the impact on energy efficiency contributes to the reduction of CO2 emissions and improvement in specific consumption (KW/m3/d). Ultimately, assessing a well's extractive condition considering wear, reduced lifting capacity, and increased power consumption of an ESP is crucial. This approach facilitates well adaptation planning, minimizing downtime impact, enhancing system efficiency, and capturing additional oil in genuinely underexploited wells, thus preventing equipment failure This analysis provides an opportunity to accurately measure production status and true well potential. Enhancing extraction in these cases can significantly boost oil production (69% of increase in total fluid and about 150% in terms of net oil). The comparison performed considers post injection changes versus adequation of the system installing motors with PMM technology also around 17% savings in terms of energy are reached.</description>
      <author>Fabio Pino, E. G. Siri, Gonzalo Maldonado, Marco Orozco</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221522-ms</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
