<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 01:12:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of Pynaphthyridine and Binaphthyridine Manganese(I) Tricarbonyl Complexes: Influence on Carbon Dioxide Reduction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.4c00008</link>
      <description>Kailyn Y. Cohen, Hovnan Simonyan, Mar&#237;a J. Ortiz, Benjamin F. Solomon, Luke Simkins, Raymond N. Dominey, Emma W. Goldman, Andrew B. Bocarsly, Organometallics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400544982

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kailyn Y. Cohen, Hovnan Simonyan, Mar&#237;a J. Ortiz, Benjamin F. Solomon, Luke Simkins, Raymond N. Dominey, Emma W. Goldman, Andrew B. Bocarsly</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.4c00008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover Picture: Light&#8208;Induced Dynamic Activation of Copper/Silicon Interface for Highly Selective Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412574</link>
      <description>Jiali Wang, Tai Ying Lai, Han&#8208;Ting Lin, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Hsiao&#8208;Chien Chen, C. C. Tseng, Ching&#8208;Wei Tung, Chia&#8208;Ying Chien, Hao Ming Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400540527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiali Wang, Tai Ying Lai, Han&#8208;Ting Lin, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Hsiao&#8208;Chien Chen, C. C. Tseng, Ching&#8208;Wei Tung, Chia&#8208;Ying Chien, Hao Ming Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover Picture: Light&#8208;Induced Dynamic Activation of Copper/Silicon Interface for Highly Selective Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412574</link>
      <description>Jiali Wang, Tai Ying Lai, Han&#8208;Ting Lin, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Hsiao&#8208;Chien Chen, C. C. Tseng, Ching&#8208;Wei Tung, Chia&#8208;Ying Chien, Hao Ming Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400542014

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiali Wang, Tai Ying Lai, Han&#8208;Ting Lin, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Hsiao&#8208;Chien Chen, C. C. Tseng, Ching&#8208;Wei Tung, Chia&#8208;Ying Chien, Hao Ming Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd doped tin oxide nanostructured catalysts for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4621090/v1</link>
      <description>Shuting Tan, Zhuo Xiong, Zuwei Xu, Junying Zhang, Yongchun Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400678732

                Abstract Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 can convert CO2 into a variety of carbon-based fuels and achieve carbon neutrality. Tin oxide (SnO2) electrocatalytic materials have the advantages of low cost and low toxicity, and the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formic acid is highly selective. In this paper, Pd-doped SnO2 nanoparticle materials were synthesized by flame spray pyrolysis and their properties for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formic acid were explored in a gas diffusion electrolytic cell. The results showed that the Pd/SnO2 catalysts could improve the catalytic activity for the conversion of CO2 to formate, and the most superior 0.5 Pd/SnO2 showed a Faraday efficiency of 63% for formate at -1.20 V vs. RHE and a current density of 90.59 mA.cm&#8722; 2, which were 1.4 and 2.7 times higher than that of pure SnO2, respectively. The modified catalyst grains were refined, and the charge transfer resistance at the catalyst interface was reduced and the electrochemically active area was increased, generating more catalytically active sites and increasing the contact between CO2, electrolyte, and electrode-catalyst. Density-functional theory calculations showed that the doping of Pd element changed the local structure of SnO2, and the Pd/SnO2 surface was more favorable for the generation of the intermediate products *HCOO&#8722; and formate as well as the inhibition of hydrogen precipitation, which was consistent with the experimental results.</description>
      <author>Shuting Tan, Zhuo Xiong, Zuwei Xu, Junying Zhang, Yongchun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4621090/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide to Formate in the Acetylene-Black Gas-Diffusion Electrode with a Tin Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700149</link>
      <description>G. A. Kolyagin, &#1054;xana P. &#1058;aran, Russian journal of electrochemistry. 60(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400737610

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. A. Kolyagin, &#1054;xana P. &#1058;aran</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving co-electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction by optimizing the relative potentials of the redox mediator and catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01988a</link>
      <description>Amelia G. Reid, Ethan A. Zelenke, Megan E. Moberg, Diane A. Dickie, Charles W. Machan, Chemical communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400742285

                The effects of fixing the redox mediator (RM) reduction potential relative to a series of Cr-centered complexes capable of the reduction of CO</description>
      <author>Amelia G. Reid, Ethan A. Zelenke, Megan E. Moberg, Diane A. Dickie, Charles W. Machan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01988a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance evaluation of nonthermal plasma carbon dioxide reduction to fuel with dielectric barrier discharge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elstat.2024.103952</link>
      <description>Hiroyuki Wakimoto, Hiroyuki Yamasaki, Tetsuo Kuroki, Masaaki Okubo, Journal of electrostatics. 130(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400601775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hiroyuki Wakimoto, Hiroyuki Yamasaki, Tetsuo Kuroki, Masaaki Okubo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elstat.2024.103952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the energy efficiency and carbon dioxide reduction of a long-haul bus through aerodynamic design optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06173</link>
      <description>, Global NEST Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741600

                &lt;p&gt;Exhaustion of fossil fuel resources, inconsistent fuel costs and the difficulty of adopting electric vehicle technology in commercial vehicles support the idea that there is an opportunity for research in public transit regarding the correlation between energy efficiency and aerodynamic drag. The turbulent external airflow over a bus at high speeds impacts acceleration, speed, and fuel economy. The fundamental bus's design is intended to carry enough passengers for a reasonable run. Envisaging the factors influencing aerodynamic drag is defiant due to the convoluted relationship between the moving bus and the air. Consequently, a comprehensive numerical and experimental exploration is executed on the bodywork of a bus to improve its aerodynamic efficiency. The aerodynamic drag is directly proportional to the variations in the air density, frontal area, freestream velocity and the drag coefficient. Minimal design reforms are performed on a distinctive long-haul bus. The exertion aims to minimize the drag coefficient, thereby improving the flow characteristics of the bus's bodywork. Through the shape optimization of the bus's bodywork, the modified design has attained a forty-five percent reduction in the drag coefficient. This substantial reduction in drag coefficient directly impacts the reduction of drag force, energy efficiency improvement, and carbon emissions reduction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 reduction in strong acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00608-3</link>
      <description>Taito Watanabe, Shigeyuki Masaoka, Nature synthesis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400657511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Taito Watanabe, Shigeyuki Masaoka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00608-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of organic ligands for metal-organic frameworks as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02635g</link>
      <description>Ya Zhang, Wei&#8208;Yin Sun, Chemical communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400722259

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction to valuable chemical compounds is a sustainable technology with enormous potential to facilitate carbon neutrality by transforming intermittent energy sources into stable fuels. Among various...</description>
      <author>Ya Zhang, Wei&#8208;Yin Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02635g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cleaner separation and recovery of valuable metals from spent ternary cathode via carbon dioxide synergetic thermite reduction strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121853</link>
      <description>Cheng Yang, Qiong Wang, Liang Xu, Yongpan Tian, Zhuo Zhao, Journal of environmental management. 366(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400673266

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Yang, Qiong Wang, Liang Xu, Yongpan Tian, Zhuo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distinct CO2-run-out regime from steric effect of electric double layer in electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214255</link>
      <description>Longfei Chen, Hao Feng, Ying Zhang, Dong Liu, Qiang Li, Applied physics reviews. 11(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400654483

                The field of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) is pursuing high operating current densities, eventually controlled by CO2 transport. Here, we develop a new multiscale modeling approach that is able to more generally describe the effects of the electric double layer (EDL) on CO2 transport over a wide potential window extending to utmost potentials. By leveraging it, we identify a distinct CO2-run-out regime where the supply of CO2 runs out due to the EDL steric effect from a dense layer of solvated cations with the maximum layer thickness equal to the solvated cation size. Consequently, CO2RR current density drops at a relatively negative transition potential generating a bell-shaped polarization curve, which is in contrast to the CO2-transport-limited regime where the current density reaches a plateau. Furthermore, we develop a graphical method, verified by experimental data, to generally predict the transition to the CO2-run-out regime. This work sheds new light on the EDL effects for catalyst design and electrolyzer engineering.</description>
      <author>Longfei Chen, Hao Feng, Ying Zhang, Dong Liu, Qiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact-electro-catalytic CO2 reduction from ambient air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50118-1</link>
      <description>Nannan Wang, Wenbin Jiang, Jing Yang, Haisong Feng, Youbin Zheng, Sheng Wang, Bofan Li, Jerry Zhi Xiong Heng, Wai Chung Ong, Hui Ru Tan, Yong&#8208;Wei Zhang, Daoai Wang, Enyi Ye, Yupeng Liu, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400601546

                Abstract Traditional catalytic techniques often encounter obstacles in the search for sustainable solutions for converting CO 2 into value-added products because of their high energy consumption and expensive catalysts. Here, we introduce a contact-electro-catalysis approach for CO 2 reduction reaction, achieving a CO Faradaic efficiency of 96.24%. The contact-electro-catalysis is driven by a triboelectric nanogenerator consisting of electrospun polyvinylidene fluoride loaded with single Cu atoms-anchored polymeric carbon nitride (Cu-PCN) catalysts and quaternized cellulose nanofibers (CNF). Mechanistic investigation reveals that the single Cu atoms on Cu-PCN can effectively enrich electrons during contact electrification, facilitating electron transfer upon their contact with CO 2 adsorbed on quaternized CNF. Furthermore, the strong adsorption of CO 2 on quaternized CNF allows efficient CO 2 capture at low concentrations, thus enabling the CO 2 reduction reaction in the ambient air. Compared to the state-of-the-art air-based CO 2 reduction technologies, contact-electro-catalysis achieves a superior CO yield of 33 &#956;mol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 . This technique provides a solution for reducing airborne CO 2 emissions while advancing chemical sustainability strategy.</description>
      <author>Nannan Wang, Wenbin Jiang, Jing Yang, Haisong Feng, Youbin Zheng, Sheng Wang, Bofan Li, Jerry Zhi Xiong Heng, Wai Chung Ong, Hui Ru Tan, Yong&#8208;Wei Zhang, Daoai Wang, Enyi Ye, Yupeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50118-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Impacts of CO2 Reduction and Utilization Technologies on Regional Freshwater Resources</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2396748</link>
      <description>May Wu, Hannah Kim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400597659

                No abstract</description>
      <author>May Wu, Hannah Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2396748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 electrochemical reduction: a state-of-the-art review with economic and environmental analyses</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cherd.2024.07.014</link>
      <description>Grazia Leonzio, G. H. Kelsall, Nilay Shah, Process safety and environmental protection/Transactions of the Institution of Chemical Engineers. Part B, Process safety and environmental protection/Chemical engineering research and design/Chemical engineering research &amp; design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400612469

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Grazia Leonzio, G. H. Kelsall, Nilay Shah</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cherd.2024.07.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highthroughput Screening of CuBi Bimetallic Catalyst Array for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction Reaction by Scanning Electrochemical Microscope</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400536</link>
      <description>Xiaofeng Gu, Zhen Wang, Zhanwen Liu, Gang Ni, Limin Liu, Dongping Zhan, Juan Peng, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400558904

                The testing and evaluation of catalysts in CO2 electroreduction is a very tedious process. To study the catalytic system of CO2 reduction more quickly and efficiently, it is necessary to establish a method that can detect multiple catalysts at the same time. Herein, a series of CuBi bimetallic catalysts have been successfully prepared on a single glass carbon electrode by a scanning micropieptte contact method. The application of scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM) enabled the visualization of the CO2 reduction activity in diverse catalyst micro&#8208;points. The SECM imaging with Substrate generation/tip collection (SG/TC) mode was conducted on CuBi bimetallic micro&#8208;points, revealing that HER reaction emerged as the prevailing reaction when a low overpotential was employed. While the applied potential was lower than &#8208;1.5 V (vs Ag/AgCl), the reduction of CO2 to formic acid became dominant. Increasing the bismuth proportion in the bimetallic catalyst can inhibit the hydrogen evolution reaction at low potential and enhances the selectivity of the CO product at high cathode overpotential.This research offers a novel approach to examining arrays of catalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Xiaofeng Gu, Zhen Wang, Zhanwen Liu, Gang Ni, Limin Liu, Dongping Zhan, Juan Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu into Cu2O/RuAl intermetallic heterojunction for lowering the thermodynamic energy barrier of the CO2 reduction and evolution reactions in Li&#8211;CO2 battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.016</link>
      <description>Wenqing Ma, Jiagang Hou, Siyu Liu, Tianzhen Jian, Jianping Ma, Caixia Xu, Hong Liu, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400673212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenqing Ma, Jiagang Hou, Siyu Liu, Tianzhen Jian, Jianping Ma, Caixia Xu, Hong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High selectivity and abundant active sites in atomically dispersed TM2C12 monolayer for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuproc.2024.108106</link>
      <description>Shulong Li, Song Yu, Tian Guo, Qiaoling Liu, Liang Qiao, Yong Zhao, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Fuel processing technology. 261(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400576723

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shulong Li, Song Yu, Tian Guo, Qiaoling Liu, Liang Qiao, Yong Zhao, Li&#8208;Yong Gan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuproc.2024.108106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 and NO Reduction Characteristics from Biomass-Ammonia Co-firing in a Circulating Fluidized Bed Combustor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1868-9_86</link>
      <description>Sung Jin Park, Seong&#8208;Ju Kim, Sung-Ho Jo, Jae Goo Lee, Tae Young Mun, Green energy and technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400584385

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sung Jin Park, Seong&#8208;Ju Kim, Sung-Ho Jo, Jae Goo Lee, Tae Young Mun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1868-9_86</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Augmentation and Fundamental Mechanistic Exploration of &#946;-Ga2O3-rGO Photocatalyst for Efficient CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00408f</link>
      <description>Hyein Jeong, Hangyeol Choi, Yujin Song, Jung Han Kim, Yohan Yoon, Nanoscale advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400663272

                We explore the novel photodecomposition capabilities of &#946;-Ga2O3 when augmented with reduced graphene oxide (rGO). Employing real-time spectroscopy, this study unveils the sophisticated mechanisms of photodecomposition, identifying an optimal 1...</description>
      <author>Hyein Jeong, Hangyeol Choi, Yujin Song, Jung Han Kim, Yohan Yoon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00408f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photothermal-boosted S-scheme heterojunction of &#945;-Fe2O3@NiOx for high-selective reduction of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160747</link>
      <description>Xiao Liu, Bai Kaihui, Yuhang Nie, Xusheng Wang, Lang Pei, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400644913

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao Liu, Bai Kaihui, Yuhang Nie, Xusheng Wang, Lang Pei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redistributing the local electron density of bismuth via introducing halogen atoms for boosting CO2 reduction to formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101057</link>
      <description>Haidong Shen, H. N. Wang, Tianshuai Wang, Jiarui Zhang, Shaowei Yang, Hao Jiang, Peng Zhao, Runze Gao, Xinrui Linghu, Ying Guo, Hepeng Zhang, Chem catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400652055

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haidong Shen, H. N. Wang, Tianshuai Wang, Jiarui Zhang, Shaowei Yang, Hao Jiang, Peng Zhao, Runze Gao, Xinrui Linghu, Ying Guo, Hepeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 and CO reduction using Au/TiO2 model catalysts for syngas and Fischer-Tropsch chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.184</link>
      <description>So Young Kim, Seon Young Hwang, Gak-Won Yun, Yunji Gwon, Sooyeon Bae, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400720613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>So Young Kim, Seon Young Hwang, Gak-Won Yun, Yunji Gwon, Sooyeon Bae, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water-induced Switching in Selectivity and Steric Control of Activity in Photochemical CO2 Reduction Catalyzed by RhCp*(bpy) Derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-t3ltd-v2</link>
      <description>Dongseb Lee, Kosei Yamauchi, Ken Sakai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400664492

                Photocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formic acid (HCOOH) was investigated in either organic or aqueous/organic media by employing three water-soluble Rh(Cp*)(n,n&#8217;-dihydroxy-2,2&#8217;-bipyridine) (n = 4, 5, or 6) in the presence of [Ru(bpy)3]2+, 1,3-dimethyl-2-phenyl-2,3-dihydro-1H-benzo[d]imidazole (BIH) and triethanolamine (TEOA). Through studying the electron-donating effects of two hydroxyl groups introduced to the bipyridyl ligand, we found that the substituent positions greatly affect both the catalytic efficiency and selectivity in CO2 reduction. More importantly, the HCOOH selectivity shows a dramatic increase from 14% to 83% upon switching the solvent media from pure organic to aqueous/organic mixture, where the H2 selectivity shows a reverse phenomenon. The enhanced HCOOH selectivity and the drastic decrease in the apparent H2 yield are well rationalized by the fact that the catalytic CO2 hydrogenation by the evolved H2 simultaneously proceeds as a dark catalytic reaction, which was also separately investigated under the dark conditions. Our DFT studies unveil that the exceptionally large structural strain given by the steric contacts between the 6,6&#8217;-dihydroxyl groups and the Cp* moiety plays a significant role in bringing about an outstanding catalytic performance of the 6,6&#8217;-subsituted derivative. The intrinsic reaction coordinate calculations were carried out to clarify the mechanism of hydride transfer steps leading to generate formate together the heterolytic H2 cleavage steps leading to afford the key hydridorhodium intermediates. This study represents the first report on the water-induced high selectivity in CO2-to-HCOOH conversion, shedding a new light on the strategy to control the efficiency and selectivity in the catalysis of CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Dongseb Lee, Kosei Yamauchi, Ken Sakai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-t3ltd-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective scission of glucose molecule by a Pd-modulated Co-based catalyst for efficient CO2 reduction under mild conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.07.020</link>
      <description>Peidong Zhu, Jiacong Li, Yang Yang, Heng Zhong, Fangming Jin, Science Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400645946

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peidong Zhu, Jiacong Li, Yang Yang, Heng Zhong, Fangming Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.07.020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tensile&#8208;Strained Cu Penetration Electrode Boosts Asymmetric C&#8211;C Coupling for Ampere&#8208;Level CO2&#8208;to&#8208;C2+ Reduction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407612</link>
      <description>Shoujie Li, Gangfeng Wu, Jianing Mao, Aohui Chen, Xiaohu Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Yiheng Wei, Jiangjiang Wang, Haili Zhu, Jian&#8208;Bai Xia, Li Wang, Guihua Li, Yanfang Song, Xiao Dong, Wei Wei, Wei Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400658650

                The synthesis of multicarbon (C2+) products remains a substantial challenge in sustainable CO2 electroreduction owing to the need for sufficient current density and faradaic efficiency alongside carbon efficiency. Herein, we demonstrate ampere&#8208;level high&#8208;efficiency CO2 electroreduction to C2+ products in both neutral and strongly acidic (pH = 1) electrolytes using a hierarchical Cu hollow&#8208;fiber penetration electrode (HPE). High concentration of K+ could concurrently suppress hydrogen evolution reaction and facilitate C&#8211;C coupling, thereby promoting C2+ production in strong acid. By optimizing the K+ and H+ concentration and CO2 flow rate, a faradaic efficiency of 84.5% and a partial current density as high as 3.1 A cm&#8211;2 for C2+ products, alongside a single&#8208;pass carbon efficiency of 81.5% and stable electrolysis for 240 h were demonstrated in a strong acidic solution of H2SO4 and KCl (pH = 1). Experimental measurements and density functional theory simulations suggested that tensile&#8208;strained Cu HPE enhances the asymmetric C&#8211;C coupling to steer the selectivity and activity of C2+ products.</description>
      <author>Shoujie Li, Gangfeng Wu, Jianing Mao, Aohui Chen, Xiaohu Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Yiheng Wei, Jiangjiang Wang, Haili Zhu, Jian&#8208;Bai Xia, Li Wang, Guihua Li, Yanfang Song, Xiao Dong, Wei Wei, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effectiveness of Agricultural Carbon Dioxide Removal using the University of Victoria Earth System Climate Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1810</link>
      <description>Rebecca C. Evans, H. Damon Matthews, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400661486

                Abstract. A growing body of evidence suggests that to achieve the temperature goals of the Paris Agreement, carbon dioxide removal (CDR) will likely be required in addition to massive carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions reductions. Nature-based CDR, which includes a range of strategies to sequester carbon in natural reservoirs, could play an important role in efforts to limit climate warming to well below 2 &#176;C above preindustrial levels. Agricultural CDR could enhance soil carbon sequestration, though the climate efficacy of such methods remains uncertain. Here, we use an intermediate complexity climate model to perform simulations of agricultural CDR in the form of soil carbon sequestration at a range of possible rates for different costs under three future emissions scenarios. We found that plausible levels of agricultural CDR were able to reduce CO2 concentration by 5&#8211;19 ppm and global surface air temperature by 0.02&#8211;0.10 &#176;C by the end of century. This temperature decrease was non-linear with respect to cumulative removals, as any carbon removed remained part of the active carbon cycle, lessening the climate benefit compared to if the removed carbon was permanently stored in geological reservoirs. CDR was found to be more effective at reducing surface air temperature in low emissions scenarios, but less effective at reducing atmospheric CO2, compared to high emissions scenarios. This was because the weaker CO2 sinks in a high CO2 world had a more muted response to removal, so a substantially higher proportion of carbon was removed from the atmosphere for a given amount of CDR in a higher emissions scenario. The enhanced temperature response to CDR in lower emissions scenarios was due to the logarithmic response of radiative effects to changes in CO2, where at low atmospheric CO2 concentrations, small changes in CO2 are more effective at changing the global radiative balance than at higher CO2 concentrations. CDR was substantially more effective when implemented at a higher rate, as CDR makes a proportionally larger difference in a climate with lower cumulative air fraction of CO2. Land and soil carbon responses were driven by the scenario-dependent balances between the impacts of CDR on primary productivity from CO2 fertilization, and the impacts on soil respiration from increased soil carbon availability and global temperatures.</description>
      <author>Rebecca C. Evans, H. Damon Matthews</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1810</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Analysis of Carbon Emissions from Highway Construction Based on Life Cycle Assessment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145897</link>
      <description>Shuohan Gao, Xuexin Liu, Chunying Lu, H Zhang, Xinjun Wang, Yaping Kong, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400522787

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions from the construction of road infrastructure have been of growing interest in recent years. This paper proposes a binary statistical method for highway construction based on project cost control and a construction management system. A quantitative analysis of the CO2 emissions from highway construction activities was also conducted to guide the formulation of a carbon reduction strategy. Taking an expressway in central China as a case study, the CO2 emissions from different construction activities were calculated. The results revealed that the CO2 emissions for the whole construction project reached 10,605.2 t&#183;km&#8722;1&#183;lane&#8722;1, with the raw material production and on-site construction phases accounting for 95.2% and 4.8%, respectively. The values for bridge and tunnel engineering were much higher than those for other engineering types. In the raw material production phase, steel and cement production contributed the most to emissions (more than 99%). During the on-site construction phase, diesel and electricity consumption contributed 90% to CO2 emissions, especially from earthwork, subgrade protection, bridge engineering, tunnel excavation, and pavement surfacing. Accordingly, efforts should be focused on the key points and directed toward using recycled and low-carbon materials and improving working efficiency, machinery performance, and construction technology.</description>
      <author>Shuohan Gao, Xuexin Liu, Chunying Lu, H Zhang, Xinjun Wang, Yaping Kong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the hydropower vulnerability to drought in the United States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad6200</link>
      <description>Pouya Moghaddasi, Keyhan Gavahi, Hamed Moftakhari, Hamid Moradkhani, Environmental research letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400520128

                Abstract Drought, a potent natural climatic phenomenon, significantly challenges hydropower systems, bearing adverse consequences for economies, societies, and the environment. This study delves into the profound impact of drought on hydropower generation in the United States, revealing a robust correlation between hydrologic drought and hydroelectricity generation. Our analysis of the period from 2003 to 2020 for the Contiguous United States (CONUS) indicates that drought events led to a considerable decline in hydroelectricity generation, amounting to approximately 300 million MWh, and resulting in an estimated loss of $28 billion to the sector. Moreover, our findings highlight the adverse environmental effect of drought-induced hydropower generation reductions, which are often compensated by increased reliance on natural gas usage, which led to substantial emissions of carbon dioxide (CO2), sulfur dioxide (SO2), and nitrogen oxide (NOX), totaling 161,700 kilotons, 119,9 tons, and 181,977 tons, respectively. In addition to these findings, we assess the state-level vulnerability of hydropower to drought, identifying Washington and California as the most vulnerable states, while Nevada exhibits the least vulnerability. Overall, this study enhances understanding of the multifaceted effects of drought on hydropower, which can assist in informing policies and practices related to drought management and energy production.</description>
      <author>Pouya Moghaddasi, Keyhan Gavahi, Hamed Moftakhari, Hamid Moradkhani</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad6200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide Oil Repulsion in the Sandstone Reservoirs of Lunnan Oilfield, Tarim Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143503</link>
      <description>Zangyuan Wu, Qihong Feng, Liming Lian, Xiangjuan Meng, Daiyu Zhou, Min Luo, Hanlie Cheng, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400728892

                The Lunnan oilfield, nestled within the Tarim Basin, represents a prototypical extra-low-permeability sandstone reservoir, distinguished by high-quality crude oil characterised by a low viscosity, density, and gel content. The effective exploitation of such reservoirs hinges on the implementation of carbon dioxide (CO2) flooding techniques. This study, focusing on the sandstone reservoirs of Lunnan, delves into the mechanisms of CO2-assisted oil displacement under diverse operational parameters: injection pressures, CO2 concentration levels, and variations in crude oil properties. It integrates analyses on the high-pressure, high-temperature behaviour of CO2, the dynamics of CO2 injection and expansion, prolonged core flood characteristics, and the governing principles of minimum miscible pressure transitions. The findings reveal a nuanced interplay between variables: CO2&#8217;s density and viscosity initially surge with escalating injection pressures before stabilising, whereas they experience a gradual decline with increasing temperature. Enhanced CO2 injection correlates with a heightened expansion coefficient, yet the density increment of degassed crude oil remains marginal. Notably, CO2 viscosity undergoes a substantial reduction under stratigraphic pressures. The sequential application of water alternating gas (WAG) followed by continuous CO2 flooding attains oil recovery efficiency surpassing 90%, emphasising the superiority of uninterrupted CO2 injection over processes lacking profiling. The presence of non-miscible hydrocarbon gases in segmented plug drives impedes the oil displacement efficiency, underscoring the importance of CO2 purity in the displacement medium. Furthermore, a marked trend emerges in crude oil recovery rates as the replacement pressure escalates, exhibiting an initial rapid enhancement succeeded by a gradual rise. Collectively, these insights offer a robust theoretical foundation endorsing the deployment of CO2 flooding strategies for enhancing oil recovery from sandstone reservoirs, thereby contributing valuable data to the advancement of enhanced oil recovery (EOR) technologies in challenging, low-permeability environments.</description>
      <author>Zangyuan Wu, Qihong Feng, Liming Lian, Xiangjuan Meng, Daiyu Zhou, Min Luo, Hanlie Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the near- and long-term role of carbon dioxide removal in meeting global climate objectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01527-z</link>
      <description>Gaurav Ganti, Thomas Gasser, Mai Bui, Oliver Geden, William F. Lamb, Jan C. Minx, Carl-Friedrich Schleu&#223;ner, Matthew Gidden, Communications earth &amp; environment. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400656455

                Abstract The 6th Assessment Report from the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change lacked sufficient land-sector scenario information to estimate total carbon dioxide removal deployment. Here, using a dataset of land-based carbon dioxide removal based on the scenarios assessed by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, we show that removals via afforestation and reforestation play a critical near-term role in mitigation, accounting for around 10% (median) of the net greenhouse gas emission reductions between 2020 and 2030 in scenarios that limit warming to 1.5 &#176;C with limited overshoot. Novel carbon dioxide removal technologies such as direct air carbon capture and storage scale to multi-gigatonne levels by 2050 and beyond to balance residual emissions and draw down warming. We show that reducing fossil fuel and deforestation emissions (gross emissions) accounts for over 80% of net greenhouse gas reductions until global net zero carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) independent of climate objective stringency. We explore the regional distributions of gross emissions and total carbon dioxide removal in cost-effective mitigation pathways and highlight the importance of incorporating fairness and broader sustainability considerations in future assessments of mitigation pathways with carbon dioxide removal.</description>
      <author>Gaurav Ganti, Thomas Gasser, Mai Bui, Oliver Geden, William F. Lamb, Jan C. Minx, Carl-Friedrich Schleu&#223;ner, Matthew Gidden</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01527-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capacity Expansion Planning of Hydrogen-Enabled Industrial Energy Systems for Carbon Dioxide Peaking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143400</link>
      <description>Kai Zhang, Xiangxiang Dong, Chaofeng Li, Li Wang, Kun Liu, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400533623

                As the main contributor of carbon emissions, the low-carbon transition of the industrial sector is important for achieving the goal of carbon dioxide peaking. Hydrogen-enabled industrial energy systems (HIESs) are a promising way to achieve the low-carbon transition of industrial energy systems, since the hydrogen can be well coordinated with renewable energy sources and satisfy the high and continuous industrial energy demand. In this paper, the long-term capacity expansion planning problem of the HIES is formulated from the perspective of industrial parks, and the targets of carbon dioxide peaking and the gradual decommissioning of existing equipment are considered as constraints. The results show that the targets of carbon dioxide peaking before different years or with different emission reduction targets can be achieved through the developed method, while the economic performance is ensured to some extent. Meanwhile, the overall cost of the strategy based on purchasing emission allowance is three times more than the cost of the strategy obtained by the developed method, while the emissions of the two strategies are same. In addition, long-term carbon reduction policies and optimistic expectations for new energy technologies will help industrial parks build more new energy equipment for clean transformation.</description>
      <author>Kai Zhang, Xiangxiang Dong, Chaofeng Li, Li Wang, Kun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Selective Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion to Tailored Products through Precise Regulation of Hydrogenation and C&#8211;C Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07502</link>
      <description>Bao Yu Xia, Tao Wang, Chaohui He, Ruijuan Qi, Deyu Zhu, Ruihu Lu, Fumin Li, Yu Chen, Shenghua Chen, Bo You, Tao Yao, Wei Guo, Fei Song, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400524077

                The electrochemical reduction reaction of carbon dioxide (CO</description>
      <author>Bao Yu Xia, Tao Wang, Chaohui He, Ruijuan Qi, Deyu Zhu, Ruihu Lu, Fumin Li, Yu Chen, Shenghua Chen, Bo You, Tao Yao, Wei Guo, Fei Song, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of the digital economy on carbon dioxide emissions in resource-based cities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-66005-0</link>
      <description>Yang Kuang, Yaojun Fan, Jie Bin, Min Fan, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400738479

                Abstract With the rapid development of the digital economy, its environmental impact, particularly on carbon dioxide emissions in resource-based cities, has emerged as a vital research topic. Resource-based cities, often central to traditional industries, are confronted with the dual challenges of environmental pollution and economic transformation. This study employs empirical analysis to examine the influence of the digital economy on carbon dioxide emissions in these cities. The findings reveal that the digital economy significantly reduces carbon dioxide emissions, with this impact being more pronounced in the early stages of digital economic development and gradually diminishing thereafter. In the mechanism analysis, we found that the digital economy can reduce carbon dioxide emissions in resource-based cities by raising public concern about the environment. Moreover, the study highlights significant variations in carbon reduction effects among different types of resource-based cities, noting that stronger environmental regulations further enhance these effects. These insights not only provide a new theoretical perspective but also offer practical guidance for policymakers in promoting sustainable development within the digital economy.</description>
      <author>Yang Kuang, Yaojun Fan, Jie Bin, Min Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-66005-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medical hypnosis mitigates laboratory dyspnoea in healthy humans: a randomised, controlled experimental trial</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.00485-2024</link>
      <description>Capucine Mor&#233;lot-Panzini, C&#233;cile Arveiller-Carvallo, Isabelle Rivals, Nicolas Wattiez, Sophie Lavault, A. Brion, Laure Serresse, Christian Straus, Marie&#8208;C&#233;cile Nierat, Thomas Similowski, European respiratory journal/&#152;The &#156;European respiratory journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400532967

                Question Dyspnoea persisting despite treatments of underlying causes requires symptomatic approaches. Medical hypnosis could provide relief without the untoward effects of pharmacological approaches. We addressed this question through experimentally induced dyspnoea in healthy humans (inspiratory threshold loading &#8211;excessive inspiratory effort&#8211; and carbon dioxide stimulation &#8211;air hunger&#8211;) Material and Methods 20 volunteers (10 women, 21&#8211;40) were studied on 4 separate days. The order of the visits was randomised in two steps, firstly &#8220;inspiratory threshold loading first&#8221; versus &#8220;carbon dioxide first&#8221; group (n=10 in each group), secondly &#8220;medical hypnosis first&#8221; versus &#8220;visual distraction first&#8221; subgroup (n=5 in each subgroup). Each visit comprised three 5-minutes periods (reference, intervention, washout) during which participants used visual analog scales to rate dyspnoea's sensory and affective dimensions and after which they completed the Multidimensional Dyspnea Profile. Results Medical hypnosis reduced both dimensions of dyspnoea significantly more than visual distraction (inspiratory threshold loading: sensory reduction after 5 min 34% of full VAS versus 8% &#8211;p=0.0042&#8211;; affective reduction 17.6% versus 2.4% &#8211;p=0.044&#8211;; carbon dioxide; sensory reduction after 5 min 36.9% versus 3% &#8211;p=0.0015&#8211;; affective reduction 29.1% versus 8.7% &#8211;p=0.0023&#8211;). The Multidimensional Dyspnea Profile showed more marked sensory effects during inspiratory threshold loading and more marked affective effects during carbon dioxide stimulation. Answer to the question Medical hypnosis was more effective than visual distraction at attenuating the sensory and affective dimensions of experimentally induced dyspnoea. This provides a strong rationale for clinical studies of hypnosis in persistent dyspnoea patients.</description>
      <author>Capucine Mor&#233;lot-Panzini, C&#233;cile Arveiller-Carvallo, Isabelle Rivals, Nicolas Wattiez, Sophie Lavault, A. Brion, Laure Serresse, Christian Straus, Marie&#8208;C&#233;cile Nierat, Thomas Similowski</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.00485-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewable Energy, Economic Policy Uncertainty and Climate Policy Uncertainty: New Evidence for Environmental Kuznets Curve from Emerging and Developed Countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146049</link>
      <description>Canan &#214;zkan, Nesrin Okay, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400641011

                Recent events, such as the financial crisis, oil price shocks or fluctuations, Brexit, the US&#8211;China trade war, the COVID-19 pandemic, the Russia&#8211;Ukraine conflict and the subsequent energy crisis, have surged global economic policy uncertainty. As climate change has recently been more pronounced around the globe, discussions about climate policies and related uncertainties have also become a major concern. This study investigates the role of economic policy uncertainty (EPU) and climate policy uncertainty (CPU) on climate change (environmental degradation) for selected emerging and developed economies, expanding the IPAT framework and merging it with the Environmental Kuznets Curve (EKC) hypothesis. The IPAT framework examines the impact (I) of population (P), affluence (A), and technology (T) on the environment, whereas the EKC hypothesis proposes an inverted U-shaped curve between affluence and environmental degradation. Two models were created and tested for emerging and developed countries, namely Model 1 with EPU and Model 2 with CPU. A Pooled Mean Group (PMG) estimator is employed to investigate the interrelation between carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions and selected variables; namely the real Gross Domestic Product (GDP) per capita, squared real GDP per capita, renewable share in consumption, the EPU, the CPU and population. Test results indicate that the EKC hypothesis is verified only in Model 1 and for emerging countries, whereas population escalates climate change in both country groups. Furthermore, in line with the consumption effect theorized earlier in the literature, EPU is negatively related to carbon emissions in emerging countries. Thus, the EPU leads to a decrease in the use of energy and pollution-intensive commodities and mitigates climate change in EMEs. Compatible with our ex-ante expectations, renewable energy consumption alleviates climate change in both country groups in the short term. In Model 2, with CPU, we find no evidence supporting the EKC hypothesis for any country groups. However, we reaffirm that renewable energy consumption decreases CO2 emissions in developed countries, which is in support of the argument that energy transition holds the key to tackling climate change. Finally, CPU is associated with a decrease in CO2 emissions in emerging countries in the short term, potentially leading to a reduction in overall economic activity and alleviating climate change. This might also be attributable to the fact that the decisions of economic agents substantially rely on current and future policy (both economic and climate) expectations. Overall, verifying the EKC hypothesis for emerging countries in Model 1, we might argue that there is good potential for emerging countries to save money and time on environmental costs via the adoption of clean technologies and related policies. Last but not least, on a global scale, energy transition with better utilization of renewable sources holds the key to tackling climate change and reducing emissions.</description>
      <author>Canan &#214;zkan, Nesrin Okay</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greening the Economy from the Ground Up: How the Minimum Wage Affects Firms&#8217; Pollution Emissions in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146020</link>
      <description>Haili Ren, Ming&#8208;Liang Zhu, Baolei Lyu, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400643532

                The implications of minimum wage standards have been widely debated, but their effects on firms&#8217; pollution emissions and the underlying mechanisms remain underexplored. This paper finds that the introduction of minimum wage standards significantly reduces emissions of pollutants such as carbon dioxide and sulfur dioxide. Firms respond to rising minimum wages by optimizing their product mix, enhancing technological innovation, and improving managerial efficiency, which collectively curb pollution outputs. Our analysis using a random forest model shows that these effects are most pronounced in regions with higher economic development, stringent environmental regulations, and elevated minimum wage standards. Our findings augment the body of research on minimum wage standards and introduce novel insights for emission reduction strategies for firms.</description>
      <author>Haili Ren, Ming&#8208;Liang Zhu, Baolei Lyu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Empowerment and Enterprise Carbon Risk Management: Evidence from Manufacturing Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2478/eces-2024-0013</link>
      <description>Yan Han, Ecological Chemistry and Engineering. S. 31(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400522918

                Abstract The paper addresses the imperative of empowering enterprises to achieve energy savings and emission reductions through digital development amidst the backdrop of peak carbon dioxide emissions and carbon neutrality. This study integrates digital empowerment and enterprise carbon risk management into a unified analytical framework, utilising panel data from listed companies spanning from 2011 to 2020 as research samples. The empirical investigation aims to ascertain whether there exist carbon risks impacting the operational performance of manufacturing enterprises and whether digital empowerment can mitigate these risks. The findings reveal that carbon intensity exerts an inhibitory influence on the enhancement of enterprise performance, indicating the presence of carbon risk issues faced by enterprises. Furthermore, it is observed that these carbon risk challenges escalate over time, a trend supported by robustness tests. Digital empowerment emerges as an effective mechanism in slowing down the carbon risks encountered by enterprises, albeit exhibiting characteristics of time lag. The study identifies notable heterogeneity in the role of digital empowerment in mitigating the carbon risks of enterprises.</description>
      <author>Yan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2478/eces-2024-0013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A win-win strategy to enhance the energy transition, improve air quality and reduce associated health threats</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-plinius18-26</link>
      <description>Victoria Gallardo, Pedro Jim&#233;nez&#8208;Guerrero, S&#243;nia Jerez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400565045

                This contribution shows the co-benefits of an optimal deployment of renewable energy infrastructure, particularly wind and solar photovoltaics, on air quality and associated health impact. The term "optimal" here specifically refers to leveraging the spatio-temporal complementarity of both resources in order to minimize the fluctuations of their combined electricity production, and so easing their integration in the energy mix. In a previous work by Jerez et al. (2023), the open-access CLIMAX tool was developed for that purpose, and utilized to delineate optimal capacity density scenarios across five European regions. We now show that, under these optimized scenarios, the European CO2-equivalent emissions could decrease by 1%, accompanied by a significant reduction in pollutant emissions from combustion power plants, potentially amounting to hundreds of kilotons of fine particulate matter and nitrogen dioxide saved. Exposure to these contaminants caused approximately three hundred thousands deaths in Europe in 2021, as reported by EEA (2023). In this sense, building upon the methodology employed by Tar&amp;#237;n-Carrasco et al. (2021), our estimates corroborate that implementing the CLIMAX scenarios could substantially avoid human fatalities associated with air pollution. Hence, pursuing carbon neutrality through a judicious energy transition emerges as a win-win strategy. Not only does it contribute to climate change mitigation by curbing greenhouse gas emissions, but it also fosters healthier, more breathable environments, thus preventing premature mortality as it relates to poor air quality. REFERENCES: EEA (2023). Harm to human health from air pollution in Europe: burden of disease 2023. Jerez, S., Barriopedro, D., Garc&amp;#237;a-L&amp;#243;pez, A., Lorente-Plazas, R., Somoza, A. M., Turco, M., Carrillo, J., &amp;amp; Trigo, R. M. (2023). An action-oriented approach to make the most of the wind and solar power complementarity. Earth's Future, 11, e2022EF003332. Tar&amp;#237;n-Carrasco, P., Im, U., Geels, C., Palacios-Pe&amp;#241;a, L., &amp;amp; Jim&amp;#233;nez-Guerrero, P. (2021). Contribution of fine particulate matter to present and future premature mortality over Europe: A non-linear response. Environment International, 153, 106517.</description>
      <author>Victoria Gallardo, Pedro Jim&#233;nez&#8208;Guerrero, S&#243;nia Jerez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-plinius18-26</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plant diversity decreases greenhouse gas emissions by increasing soil and plant carbon storage in terrestrial ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/ele.14469</link>
      <description>Pengfei Dang, Miaomiao Zhang, Han Y. H. Chen, Michel Loreau, J. Emmett Duffy, Xine Li, Shuyue Wen, Xiaoqing Han, Lin Liao, Tiantian Huang, Chenxi Wan, Xiaoliang Qin, Kadambot H. M. Siddique, Bernhard Schmid, Ecology letters. 27(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400526337

                Abstract The decline in global plant diversity has raised concerns about its implications for carbon fixation and global greenhouse gas emissions (GGE), including carbon dioxide (CO 2 ), nitrous oxide (N 2 O) and methane (CH 4 ). Therefore, we conducted a comprehensive meta&#8208;analysis of 2103 paired observations, examining GGE, soil organic carbon (SOC) and plant carbon in plant mixtures and monocultures. Our findings indicate that plant mixtures decrease soil N 2 O emissions by 21.4% compared to monocultures. No significant differences occurred between mixtures and monocultures for soil CO 2 emissions, CH 4 emissions or CH 4 uptake. Plant mixtures exhibit higher SOC and plant carbon storage than monocultures. After 10 years of vegetation development, a 40% reduction in species richness decreases SOC content and plant carbon storage by 12.3% and 58.7% respectively. These findings offer insights into the intricate connections between plant diversity, soil and plant carbon storage and GGE&#8212;a critical but previously unexamined aspect of biodiversity&#8211;ecosystem functioning.</description>
      <author>Pengfei Dang, Miaomiao Zhang, Han Y. H. Chen, Michel Loreau, J. Emmett Duffy, Xine Li, Shuyue Wen, Xiaoqing Han, Lin Liao, Tiantian Huang, Chenxi Wan, Xiaoliang Qin, Kadambot H. M. Siddique, Bernhard Schmid</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/ele.14469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Agroforestry in Ecosystem Services and Mitigation of Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18619/2072-9146-2024-4-111-119</link>
      <description>A. Worku, Ovo&#349;i Rossii. None(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400548840

                Relevance. Agroforestry systems are believed to provide a multitude of ecological services. It is thought that agroforestry enhances resilience to the impacts of climate change and aids in adaptation by supporting diverse land use practices, sustainable lifestyles, and income streams, as well as increasing productivity in both forests and agriculture, and reducing weather-related losses in production. Results and Discussion. The aim of this review was to present genuine evidence on the role of agroforestry in ecosystem conservation and mitigation of climate change impacts. Compared to monocropping and open cereal-based agriculture, agroforestry has made a more significant contribution to ecosystem conservation and in reducing carbon dioxide emissions. However, it has been found that agroforestry contributes less to carbon sequestration than natural forests. Carbon sequestration through above-ground and underground biomass, carbon emission reduction from deforestation, and microclimate adjustment are key measures for mitigating climate change. Agroforestry systems provide essential ecosystem services, such as food, fuel wood, fodder, income, and improved soil production, which enable communities to cope better with the impacts of climate change. Therefore, agroforestry must be given significant attention if it is to play a crucial role in ecosystem management.</description>
      <author>A. Worku</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18619/2072-9146-2024-4-111-119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Cover Picture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202490162</link>
      <description>, Chinese journal of chemistry. 42(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400655497

                Copper&#8208;based catalysts are frequently employed for carbon dioxide reduction reactions (CO 2 RR), yet the regulation of pore structure and surface state of electrocatalysts remains a prominent challenge in previous research endeavors. In this study, we introduce a novel technique to produce mesoporous Cu 2 O nanocrystals, with finely tuned pore size and surface amine functionality leveraging the incorporation of various amine compounds during the oxidative process of copper nanocrystals. The synergistic effect of pore structure confinement and surface amine functionalization culminates in an impressive Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 51.9% for the selective production of C 2 H 4 . More details are discussed in the article by Huang et al . on page 1846&#8212;1852. image</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202490162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental emission characteristics of diesel engine performance using biodiesel by cotton and pumpkin seed</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06066</link>
      <description>, Global NEST Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741908

                &lt;p&gt;The hunt for alternative fuels that may be utilized in place of conventional fuels is intensifying quickly since the availability of fossil fuels is dwindling daily. In this work, biodiesel derived from pumpkin and cotton seed oils is presented for use as diesel engine fuel. Related to diesel, the calorific value of this precise biodiesel is low. In a 4-stroke diesel engine, four mixes (B0, B25, B50, B75 and B100) of biodiesel were evaluated. The engine's emissions and combustion results were contrasted with the diesels. When all blended fuels are related to diesel fuel, the test repercussions illustrate a small increase in the thermal efficiency of the brakes and a decrease in the consumption of fuel specifically for the brake. Emissions of Carbon monoxide and the usage of biodiesel subsequent in a reduction in hydrocarbon emissions and an upsurge in carbon dioxide and nitrogen oxide emissions. The experiment's results showed that biodiesel, which is derived from these seed oils, maybe a useful diesel replacement for compression ignition engines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Hydrogen Embrittlement in Pipeline Steels for Natural Gas-Hydrogen Blends: Implications for Existing Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/solids5030025</link>
      <description>Hesamedin Ghadiani, Zoheir Farhat, Tahrim Alam, Md. Aminul Islam, Solids. 5(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400674742

                Governments worldwide are actively committed to achieving their carbon emission reduction targets, and one avenue under exploration is harnessing the potential of hydrogen. Blending hydrogen with natural gas is emerging as a promising strategy to reduce carbon emissions, as it burns cleanly without emitting carbon dioxide. This blending could significantly contribute to emissions reduction in both residential and commercial settings. However, a critical challenge associated with this approach is the potential for Hydrogen Embrittlement (HE), a phenomenon wherein the mechanical properties of pipe steels degrade due to the infiltration of hydrogen atoms into the metal lattice structure. This can result in sudden and sever failures when the steel is subjected to mechanical stress. To effectively implement hydrogen-natural gas blending, it is imperative to gain a comprehensive understanding of how hydrogen affects the integrity of pipe steel. This necessitates the development of robust experimental methodologies capable of monitoring the presence and impact of hydrogen within the microstructures of steel. Key techniques employed for this assessment include microscopic observation, hydrogen permeation tests, and tensile and fatigue testing. In this study, samples from two distinct types of pipeline steels used in the natural gas distribution network underwent rigorous examination. The findings from this research indicate that charged samples exhibit a discernible decline in fatigue and tensile properties. This deterioration is attributed to embrittlement and reduced ductility stemming from the infiltration of hydrogen into the steel matrix. The extent of degradation in fatigue properties is correlated not only to the hydrogen content but also to the hydrogen permeability and diffusion rate influenced by steel&#8217;s microstructural features, with higher charging current densities indicating a more significant presence of hydrogen in the natural gas pipeline blend.</description>
      <author>Hesamedin Ghadiani, Zoheir Farhat, Tahrim Alam, Md. Aminul Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/solids5030025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review on Absorption Refrigeration Technology and Its Potential in Energy-Saving and Carbon Emission Reduction in Natural Gas and Hydrogen Liquefaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143427</link>
      <description>Lisong Wang, Linli He, Yijian He, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400523011

                With the requirement of energy decarbonization, natural gas (NG) and hydrogen (H2) become increasingly important in the world&#8217;s energy landscape. The liquefaction of NG and H2 significantly increases energy density, facilitating large-scale storage and long-distance transport. However, conventional liquefaction processes mainly adopt electricity-driven compression refrigeration technology, which generally results in high energy consumption and carbon dioxide emissions. Absorption refrigeration technology (ART) presents a promising avenue for enhancing energy efficiency and reducing emissions in both NG and H2 liquefaction processes. Its ability to utilize industrial waste heat and renewable thermal energy sources over a large temperature range makes it particularly attractive for sustainable energy practices. This review comprehensively analyzes the progress of ART in terms of working pairs, cycle configurations, and heat and mass transfer in main components. To operate under different driven heat sources and refrigeration temperatures, working pairs exhibit a diversified development trend. The environment-friendly and high-efficiency working pairs, in which ionic liquids and deep eutectic solvents are new absorbents, exhibit promising development potential. Through the coupling of heat and mass transfer within the cycle or the addition of sub-components, cycle configurations with higher energy efficiency and a wider range of operational conditions are greatly focused. Additives, ultrasonic oscillations, and mechanical treatment of heat exchanger surfaces efficiently enhance heat and mass transfer in the absorbers and generators of ART. Notably, nanoparticle additives and ultrasonic oscillations demonstrate a synergistic enhancement effect, which could significantly improve the energy efficiency of ART. For the conventional NG and H2 liquefaction processes, the energy-saving and carbon emission reduction potential of ART is analyzed from the perspectives of specific power consumption (SPC) and carbon dioxide emissions (CEs). The results show that ART integrated into the liquefaction processes could reduce the SPC and CE by 10~38% and 10~36% for NG liquefaction processes, and 2~24% and 5~24% for H2 liquefaction processes. ART, which can achieve lower precooling temperatures and higher energy efficiency, shows more attractive perspectives in low carbon emissions of NG and H2 liquefaction.</description>
      <author>Lisong Wang, Linli He, Yijian He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Electrochemical Urea Synthesis via Constructing Ordered Pd&#8211;Zn Active Pair</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01462-w</link>
      <description>Weiliang Zhou, Chao Feng, Xuan Li, Xingxing Jiang, Lingyan Jing, Qi Shuai, Qihua Huo, Miaoyuan Lv, Xinbao Chen, T. W. Huang, Jing Wang, Na Meng, Hengpan Yang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He, Nano-micro letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400658782

                Abstract Electrochemical co-reduction of nitrate (NO 3 &#8211; ) and carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) has been widely regarded as a promising route to produce urea under ambient conditions, however the yield rate of urea has remained limited. Here, we report an atomically ordered intermetallic pallium-zinc (PdZn) electrocatalyst comprising a high density of PdZn pairs for boosting urea electrosynthesis. It is found that Pd and Zn are responsible for the adsorption and activation of NO 3 &#8211; and CO 2 , respectively, and thus the co-adsorption and co-activation NO 3 &#8211; and CO 2 are achieved in ordered PdZn pairs. More importantly, the ordered and well-defined PdZn pairs provide a dual-site geometric structure conducive to the key C&#8211;N coupling with a low kinetical barrier, as demonstrated on both operando measurements and theoretical calculations. Consequently, the PdZn electrocatalyst displays excellent performance for the co-reduction to generate urea with a maximum urea Faradaic efficiency of 62.78% and a urea yield rate of 1274.42 &#956;g mg &#8211;1 h &#8211;1 , and the latter is 1.5-fold larger than disordered pairs in PdZn alloys. This work paves new pathways to boost urea electrosynthesis via constructing ordered dual-metal pairs.</description>
      <author>Weiliang Zhou, Chao Feng, Xuan Li, Xingxing Jiang, Lingyan Jing, Qi Shuai, Qihua Huo, Miaoyuan Lv, Xinbao Chen, T. W. Huang, Jing Wang, Na Meng, Hengpan Yang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01462-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Studies on Solid Oxide Ceria Electrodes during CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-b3lvx-v2</link>
      <description>Vipin Kamboj, Soham Raychowdhury, Chinmoy Ranjan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400541254

                Abstract: CeOx-YSZ electrode performed well for CO2 electro-reduction in both pure CO2 and CO2 (+H2) feeds.. In pure CO2, operando Raman and online mass spectroscopy studies revealed that, upon application of the bias, CO production correlated with the reduction of Ce4+ sites to Ce3+ sites as evidenced by decay in the intensity of the Raman band at 450 cm-1 (&#945;). The electronic conductivity increased with applied bias due to an increase in Ce3+ sites. The addition of H2 (~5%) resulted in reverse Water Gas Shift reaction and an additional Raman band at 480 cm-1 (&#966;). The CO formation was more facile in presence of H2 at a lower bias compared to the pure CO2 stream. The electronic conductivity showed a slight dip at low biases (5% H2) due to the reoxidation of Ce3+ sites to Ce4+-H- (hydridic) sites. Both H2 and CO2 concentrations positively correlated with CO formation and supressed H2O electrolysis. First principles-based calculations indicate that adsorption of H into bulk makes it easier to create oxygen defect in CeO2 making the creation of Ce3+ sites easier. When adsorbed around oxygen defects the H acquires a hydridic (H-) nature. The &#966; band is likely to be associated with phonon modes containing H adsorbed around undefective sites. No coking was observed in both pure CO2 and CO2 (+H2) feed streams.</description>
      <author>Vipin Kamboj, Soham Raychowdhury, Chinmoy Ranjan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-b3lvx-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Trends in the Research and Development of Petrochemical Waste Gas from 1981 to 2022</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145972</link>
      <description>Mengting Wu, Wei Liu, Zhifei Ma, Tian Qin, Ying Feng, Yalan Zhang, Ning Cao, Xianchuan Xie, Sunlin Chi, Jinying Xu, &#19968;&#26391; &#28422;&#23822;, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400578462

                As a highly energy-intensive and carbon-emitting industry with significant emissions of volatile organic compounds (VOCs), the petroleum and chemical industry is a major contributor to the global greenhouse effect and ozone layer destruction. Improper treatment of petrochemical waste gas (PWG) seriously harms human health and the natural environment. This study uses CiteSpace and VOSviewer to conduct a scientometric analysis of 1384 scholarly works on PWG and carbon sequestration published between 1981 and 2022, revealing the basic characteristics, knowledge base, research topic evolution, and research hotspots of the field. The results show the following: (1) In the early stages of the petrochemical industry, it was processed tail gas, plant leakage waste gas, and combustion flue gas that were investigated in PWG research. (2) Later, green environmental protection technology was widely studied in the field of PWG treatment, such as biotechnology, catalytic oxidation technology, membrane separation technology, etc., in order to achieve efficient, low energy consumption and low emissions of waste gas treatment, and the number of publications related to this topic has increased rapidly. In addition, researchers studied the internet of things and technology integration, such as the introduction of artificial intelligence, big data analysis, and other technologies, to improve the accuracy and efficiency of exhaust gas monitoring, control, and management. (3) The department has focused on how to reduce emissions by optimizing petrochemical process lines or improving energy efficiency. Emission reduction and low-carbon transition in the petrochemical industry will become the main trend in the future. Switching from renewable carbon to feedstock carbon derived from captured carbon dioxide, biomass, or recycled chemicals has become an attractive strategy to help curb emissions from the chemical industry. The results of our analysis can provide funding agencies and research groups with information to better understand the global trends and directions that have emerged in this field from 1981 to 2022 and serve as a reference for future research.</description>
      <author>Mengting Wu, Wei Liu, Zhifei Ma, Tian Qin, Ying Feng, Yalan Zhang, Ning Cao, Xianchuan Xie, Sunlin Chi, Jinying Xu, &#19968;&#26391; &#28422;&#23822;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrochar from Pine Needles as a Green Alternative for Catalytic Electrodes in Energy Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29143286</link>
      <description>Assunta Marrocchi, Elisa Cerza, Suhas Chandrasekaran, Emanuela Sgreccia, S. Ka&#269;iulis, Luigi Vaccaro, Suanto Syahputra, Florence Vacandio, Philippe Knauth, Maria Luisa Di Vona, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400522909

                Hydrothermal carbonization (HTC) serves as a sustainable method to transform pine needle waste into nitrogen-doped (N-doped) hydrochars. The primary focus is on evaluating these hydrochars as catalytic electrodes for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR), which are pivotal processes with significant environmental implications. Hydrochars were synthesized by varying the parameters such as nitrogen loading, temperature, and residence time. These materials were then thoroughly characterized using diverse analytical techniques, including elemental analysis, density measurements, BET surface area analysis, and spectroscopies like Raman, FTIR, and XPS, along with optical and scanning electron microscopies. The subsequent electrochemical assessment involved preparing electrocatalytic inks by combining hydrochars with an anion exchange ionomer (AEI) to leverage their synergistic effects. To the best of our knowledge, there are no previous reports on catalytic electrodes that simultaneously incorporate both a hydrochar and AEI. Evaluation metrics such as current densities, onset and half-wave potentials, and Koutecky&#8211;Levich and Tafel plots provided insights into their electrocatalytic performances. Notably, hydrochars synthesized at 230 &#176;C exhibited an onset potential of 0.92 V vs. RHE, marking the highest reported value for a hydrochar. They also facilitated the exchange of four electrons at 0.26 V vs. RHE in the ORR. Additionally, the CO2RR yielded valuable C2 products like acetaldehyde and acetate. These findings highlight the remarkable electrocatalytic activity of the optimized hydrochars, which could be attributed, at least in part, to their optimal porosity.</description>
      <author>Assunta Marrocchi, Elisa Cerza, Suhas Chandrasekaran, Emanuela Sgreccia, S. Ka&#269;iulis, Luigi Vaccaro, Suanto Syahputra, Florence Vacandio, Philippe Knauth, Maria Luisa Di Vona</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29143286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altitude controller influence on environmental and economic performance of NGV fuel-powered engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202454907010</link>
      <description>A.R. Simonyan, Karapet Mosikyan, Razmik Balayan, V.A. Shaghoyan, E3S web of conferences. 549(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400659711

                The relevance of research is conditioned by the need to ensure efficient operation of the internal combustion engine ICE on NGV fuel at different altitudes above sea level, where there is atmospheric air rarefaction up to 20&#247;25%. This direction is dictated by the fact that when transferring the ICE operation from gasoline to gas-engine fuel, the engine power decreases from 5 to 15%, moreover, the atmospheric air rarefaction leads to an even greater reduction in engine power and ultimately reduces the performance of the vehicle. Due to violation of the process of combustion of gas-air charge in the cylinder is formed a large amount of carbon monoxide (CO). Research objective is to develop and propose a method of providing such a stoichiometric, fractional composition of the gas-air charge, which will ensure the restoration of the lost power of ICE and provide the optimal value of traction-dynamic characteristics of the car, without increasing toxic emissions. Research object: Variable crosssectional area of the intake manifold path (ICE), adjustable lumen for atmospheric air intake, atmospheric air pressure sensors adjustable diaphragm with stepper motor. Research methods: analytical modeling of the relationship of the aperture diameter depending on the altitude of the terrain above sea level, on the number of revolutions of the ICE, on the density and temperature of the ambient air. The process of combustion of the gas-air charge in the combustion chamber will be evaluated by the fractional composition of the exhaust, exhaust gases. Research results: Qualitative and quantitative assessment of the application of altitude corrector on the ICE operation mode, stability of the value of excess air ratio at different altitudes above sea level, formation of toxic gas, carbon monoxide, as well as carbon dioxide, hydrocarbon, oxygen, etc. is given.</description>
      <author>A.R. Simonyan, Karapet Mosikyan, Razmik Balayan, V.A. Shaghoyan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202454907010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The combined effect of the oxidizing agent and its concentration on the oxidative coupling of methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400877</link>
      <description>Wei Zhou, Pedro S. F. Mendes, Parviz Yazdani, Christophe Detavernier, Joris Thybaut, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400681384

                The combined use of O2 and CO2 as oxidizing agents in the oxidative coupling of methane (OCM) has been assessed over two representative OCM catalysts, i.e., La&#8208;Sr/CaO and NaMnW/SiO2, under a wide range of inlet O2 and CO2 concentrations. The overall impact of CO2 was found to depend on the operating conditions and the catalyst used. At O2&#8208;rich conditions, a negative effect of CO2 was observed on C2 selectivity. At O2&#8208;lean conditions, a positive effect of CO2 on both catalysts was observed, likely originating from an enhanced dehydrogenation of C2H6 to C2H4 and limited deep oxidation of the involving hydrocarbons and reaction intermediates. The behavior induced by CO2 is attributed to its mild oxidizing ability and interactions with the catalysts. The enhanced dehydrogenation of C2H6 was observed and confirmed by specific tests with a CO2 and C2H6 feed. Well&#8208;controlled CO2 addition improved the value of the OCM product mixture, mainly due to a 9% increase in C2H4 and a 19% increase in CO selectivity, resulting in a 25% reduction of CO2 at the outlet over the La&#8208;Sr/CaO catalyst. These findings provide new insight into the CO2 effect on OCM and the data to translate this research into OCM process alternatives.</description>
      <author>Wei Zhou, Pedro S. F. Mendes, Parviz Yazdani, Christophe Detavernier, Joris Thybaut</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Impacts on Legume Physiology and Ecosystem Dynamics: A Multifaceted Perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146026</link>
      <description>Kirtan Dave, Anand Kumar, N.K. Dav&#233;, Mukul Jain, Parmdeep Singh Dhanda, Alpa Yadav, Prashant Kaushik, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400643467

                As valuable sources of plant-based protein, leguminous vegetables (grain legumes) are essential for global food security and contribute to body growth and development in humans as well as animals. Climate change is a major challenge for agriculture development that creates major problems for the growth and development of plants. However, legume productivity is threatened by climate change factors, including rising temperatures, shifting precipitation patterns, increased atmospheric carbon dioxide levels, intensified extreme events, and altered pest/pathogen activity. This review synthesizes approximately 136 studies to assess the climate effects on major legume crops. Under all the global emissions trajectories, the mean temperatures are projected to rise beyond the optimal legume growing thresholds by 2050, carrying yield reductions between 10 and 49% for beans, soybeans, cowpeas, and lentils without adaptation measures. The elevated carbon dioxide may transiently enhance the yields up to 18%, but the benefits dramatically decline above 550 ppm and cannot offset the other climate impacts. Altered rainfall along with recurrent drought and heat waves are also expected to decrease the legume crop yields, seed quality, and soil nitrogen levels worldwide. Furthermore, the proliferation of legume pests and fungal diseases poses significant risks, amplified by climate shifts in 84% of the reviewed studies. These multifaceted impacts threaten the productivity gains in leguminous vegetables essential to sustainably meeting the global protein demand. Realizing resilience will require the accelerated development of heat/drought-tolerant legume varieties, enhanced climate-informed agronomic practices, strong policy interventions, and social safety nets explicitly supporting legume producers, in addition to the policies/steps that governments are taking to address the challenges of the climate crisis. This review highlights the essential adaptations and mechanisms required for legume crops to thrive and fulfill their significant roles in global nutrition. It explores how these crops can be improved to better withstand the environmental stresses, enhance their nutritional profiles, and increase their yields. Additionally, the review discusses the importance of legumes in sustainable agriculture and food security, emphasizing their potential to address the future challenges in feeding the growing global population. By focusing on these critical aspects, the review aims to underscore the importance of legumes in ensuring a healthy and sustainable food supply.</description>
      <author>Kirtan Dave, Anand Kumar, N.K. Dav&#233;, Mukul Jain, Parmdeep Singh Dhanda, Alpa Yadav, Prashant Kaushik</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-CO Performance by Ag Morphology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/2162-8777/ad620f</link>
      <description>Guanhua Xu, xudong qiu, xiaoguang li, ECS journal of solid state science and technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400520478

                Abstract Highly selective conversion of CO2 into CO molecules remains a major challenge in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reactions, and metallic silver-based materials have great potential. However, the selectivity and activity of traditional silver (Ag)-based materials cannot reach the desired level, and the development of new Ag-based materials has become a hot research topic. Here, novel ag-glomerated spore-shaped Ag nanomaterials are reported for the efficient reduction of CO2 to CO. The unique nanostructures endowed with larger specific surface area, and the spore-like dispersed Ag nanoparticles (NPs) have more unsaturated Ag sites, which endowed the catalysts with higher intrinsic activity. Electrochemical tests show that spore-like Ag can obtain a Faraday efficiency (FE) of 95.6% at -1 V vs. RHE, which is much higher than that of Ag nanowires (NWs) (73%) and ordinary Ag NPs (83%) synthesized in the same period. By using the three different morphologies of Ag synthesized as a research platform and statistically comparing the FE in the corresponding voltage interval, we obtained the influence of morphology effect on the selectivity of CO product production by electrocatalytic CO2 production over Ag-based catalysts, which can be further used as a guideline for catalyst development.</description>
      <author>Guanhua Xu, xudong qiu, xiaoguang li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/2162-8777/ad620f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core Flooding Experiments on the Impact of CO2-EOR on the Petrophysical Properties and Oil Recovery Parameters of Reservoir Sandstones in Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences14070185</link>
      <description>Ainash Shabdirova, Ashirgul Kozhagulova, Yernazar Samenov, Rinat Merbayev, Ainur Niyazbayeva, Daryn Shabdirov, Geosciences. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400531088

                This study investigates the impact of CO2-enhanced oil recovery (CO2-EOR) on the petrophysical properties and oil recovery potential of sandstone reservoirs in the oilfields located in the east-southern Precaspian region of Kazakhstan. Despite the recognized potential of CO2-EOR for improving oil recovery and aiding carbon sequestration, there is limited understanding of how CO2-EOR specifically affects the petrophysical properties of sandstone reservoirs in this region. Laboratory experiments were conducted using two core samples from the selected oilfields to examine changes in porosity, permeability, and oil recovery coefficients. The results demonstrated that porosity changes ranged from a slight increase of 1.1% to a decrease of 1.5%, while permeability reduction was significant, with decreases ranging from 29% to 50% due to clay alteration and halite precipitation. The oil recovery coefficient after CO2 flooding was found to be between 0.49 and 0.54. These findings underscore the complex interactions between CO2 and reservoir rocks, emphasizing the need for tailored EOR strategies in different geological settings.</description>
      <author>Ainash Shabdirova, Ashirgul Kozhagulova, Yernazar Samenov, Rinat Merbayev, Ainur Niyazbayeva, Daryn Shabdirov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences14070185</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>effectiveness of dolomite and Ni-catalyst mixtures for pure H 2 production by methane steam reforming via CO 2 capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62721/diffusion-fundamentals.7.149</link>
      <description>N. Zh. Seitkaliyeva, Nader Jand, Pier Ugo Foscolo, No host. 7(None)] 2007. https://openalex.org/W4400600053

                High hydrogen yields have been obtained continuously from steam reforming of methane coupled with simultaneous CO2 capture[1], at lower temperature (630oC) and pressure (1 atm) than those typical of traditional processes (800-900oC,15-30 atm), using calcined dolomite and a pulverized commercial Ni catalyst, in a single step. On the other hand, a pure CO2 stream is obtained by subsequent regeneration of the sorbent, which could be stored. A bubbling fluidized bed contained in a quartz vessel was operated batchwise. First, the durability of a dolomite in multi-cycle CO2 sorption/desorption runs has been investigated: a remarkable reduction of dolomite activity is observed after the first calcination, but substantially stable activity was conserved up to the fifth cycle. Then the performance of sorption enhanced catalytic steam reforming of methane to pure hydrogen has been evaluated. Two well distinct operation regimes have been found: before dolomite saturation, H2 concentration in the dry product gas remained stable at 94-96%, and CO2 was completely converted into calcium carbonate; after a short breakthrough period, concentration of H2 at the exit of the reactor reduced its value that became approximately equal to the equilibrium value expected for methane reforming and water gas shift reactions.</description>
      <author>N. Zh. Seitkaliyeva, Nader Jand, Pier Ugo Foscolo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62721/diffusion-fundamentals.7.149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density-Driven CO2 Dissolution in Depleted Gas Reservoirs with Bottom Aquifers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143491</link>
      <description>Xiaocong Lyu, Fang Cen, Rui Wang, Huiqing Liu, Sheng Wang, Jin&#8208;Xin Xiao, Xudong Shen, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400677287

                Depleted gas reservoirs with bottom water show significant potential for long-term CO2 storage. The residual gas influences mass-transfer dynamics, further affecting CO2 dissolution and convection in porous media. In this study, we conducted a series of numerical simulations to explore how residual-gas mixtures impact CO2 dissolution trapping. Moreover, we analyzed the CO2 dissolution rate at various stages and delineated the initiation and decline of convection in relation to gas composition, thereby quantifying the influence of residual-gas mixtures. The findings elucidate that the temporal evolution of the Sherwood number observed in the synthetic model incorporating CTZ closely parallels that of the single-phase model, but the order of magnitude is markedly higher. The introduction of CTZ serves to augment gravity-induced convection and expedites the dissolution of CO2, whereas the presence of residual-gas mixtures exerts a deleterious impact on mass transfer. The escalation of residual gas content concomitantly diminishes the partial pressure and solubility of CO2. Consequently, there is an alleviation of the concentration and density differentials between saturated water and fresh water, resulting in the attenuation of the driving force governing CO2 diffusion and convection. This leads to a substantial reduction in the rate of CO2 dissolution, primarily governed by gravity-induced fingering, thereby manifesting as a delay in the onset and decay time of convection, accompanied by a pronounced decrement in the maximum Sherwood number. In the field-scale simulation, the injected CO2 improves the reservoir pressure, further pushing more gas to the producers. However, due to the presence of CH4 in the post-injection process, the capacity for CO2 dissolution is reduced.</description>
      <author>Xiaocong Lyu, Fang Cen, Rui Wang, Huiqing Liu, Sheng Wang, Jin&#8208;Xin Xiao, Xudong Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking ionomers for CO2 electroreduction to multicarbon products in zero-gap electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02332c</link>
      <description>Fanxin Zeng, Huihua Deng, Mengjiao Zhuansun, Wenzhi Teng, Yuhang Wang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400570987

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an emerging carbon utilization technology. The use of ionomers in fabricating the catalytic electrode was found to exert substantial effects on activity and product...</description>
      <author>Fanxin Zeng, Huihua Deng, Mengjiao Zhuansun, Wenzhi Teng, Yuhang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02332c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering and Oxygen Vacancy Derived from Plasma-treated Cu2O Synergistically Enhancing Electrocatalytic CO2-to-C2+ Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03492a</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Wang, Xue Yao, Subhajit Jana, Yongzan Zhou, Chunlan Qin, Hongwei Shou, Youchao Teng, Hao Chen, Lidong Zhang, Chandra Veer Singh, Zhongchao Tan, Yimin A. Wu, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400640883

                Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction (ECR) into value-added chemicals and fuels helps tackle the challenges of the energy crisis and global warming. However, this strategy relies heavily on the rational design of...</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Wang, Xue Yao, Subhajit Jana, Yongzan Zhou, Chunlan Qin, Hongwei Shou, Youchao Teng, Hao Chen, Lidong Zhang, Chandra Veer Singh, Zhongchao Tan, Yimin A. Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03492a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Methane Emissions from Natural Gas Integral Compressor Engines through Fuel Injection Control</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145943</link>
      <description>Titilope I. Banji, Gregg Arney, Mark Patterson, Daniel B. Olsen, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400584498

                Methane emissions from over 7000 large-bore natural gas engines used for gas compression in the United States result from combustion inefficiency and the escape of unburned methane through the crevices. Methane is a strong greenhouse gas with a warming potential 28 times that of carbon dioxide. The Inflation Reduction Act passed by the Biden administration in 2022 imposes a methane &#8220;waste&#8221; fee that accumulates yearly to invest in clean energy and climate action starting in 2024. This study aims to reduce the amount of methane emissions from large bore engines through fuel injection techniques, thereby advancing sustainable energy development. The strategies explored investigate fuel injection pressure and timing optimization, crankcase methane emissions quantification and mitigation, and ring-pack methane quantification. While varying injection pressures and injection timing on the engine, the performance and methane emission characteristics were measured. Also, a model of the engine was created for computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations using CONVERGE Studio v 3.0. Experimental results showed that methane emissions are minimized with late-cycle fuel injection at 500 psi and 100 degrees BTDC. Computational results showed that the ring pack contributes up to 34% of methane emissions in the large bore engine model.</description>
      <author>Titilope I. Banji, Gregg Arney, Mark Patterson, Daniel B. Olsen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145943</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate-dependent oxidative inactivation of a W-dependent formate dehydrogenase involving selenocysteine displacement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02394c</link>
      <description>Guilherme Vilela-Alves, Rita Rebelo Manuel, Aldino Viegas, Philippe Carpentier, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Biaso, Bruno Guigliarelli, In&#234;s A. C. Pereira, Maria Jo&#227;o Rom&#227;o, Cristiano Mota, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400681578

                Metal-dependent formate dehydrogenases are very promising targets for enzyme optimization and design of bio-inspired catalysts for CO2 reduction, towards innovative strategies for climate change mitigation. For effective application of these...</description>
      <author>Guilherme Vilela-Alves, Rita Rebelo Manuel, Aldino Viegas, Philippe Carpentier, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Biaso, Bruno Guigliarelli, In&#234;s A. C. Pereira, Maria Jo&#227;o Rom&#227;o, Cristiano Mota</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02394c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Smart Home Technologies on Energy Efficiency, Cost Savings, and Environmental Benefits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55529/jeet.44.21.32</link>
      <description>C. Ukpene Patience, Tessy N. Apaokueze, Journal of energy engineering and thermodynamics. None(44)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400688412

                The results of this study addressed the effectiveness of smart home technologies in terms of energy consumption, cost reduction, and environmental advantages in Nigerian homes. Given the growing energy requirements and concern for the environment, assessing the efficiency of such technologies is critical for socioeconomic development. We collected data using a combination of surveys and statistical analysis in five major Nigerian cities: Lagos, Abuja, Kano, Port Harcourt, and Enugu. We evaluated smart home technologies such as smart thermostats, lighting systems, appliances, plugs, and energy monitoring systems based on their energy savings (%), monthly cost savings (NGN), kilogram of CO2 emissions cut, and percent adoption. We used descriptive analysis and regression modeling to analyze the data collected from the respondents. The introduction of smart technologies reduced general energy use by fifteen to twenty-five percent, with smart appliances recording the highest reduction of up to 25%. This feature demonstrated how monthly cost savings varied depending on the technology and geographical location, resulting in significant increases of up to 4000 NGN per household, each household saw a reduction in CO2 emissions by 500 kg to 700 kg annually, resulting in significant environmental benefits. According to the studies, smart home technologies can help promote energy conservation and therefore reduce CO2 emissions in Nigerian households. However, there are still widely recognized obstacles, like high initial costs and a low level of awareness. offering financial incentives, improving Information Promotion of existing policies and overhauling the distribution systems to increase the pace of uptake and impact returns.</description>
      <author>C. Ukpene Patience, Tessy N. Apaokueze</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55529/jeet.44.21.32</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Policies and Countermeasures for Phase-Out of Ozone-Depleting Substances (ODS) over the Last 30 Years: Case Study in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202407.1142.v1</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Tien Tsai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400686943

                It is well established that the reaction cycles involving some halogenated alkanes (so-called ozone-depleting substances, ODS) contribute to the depletion of ozone in the stratosphere, thus causing the Montreal Protocol (initially signed in 1987) and later amendments. The Protocol called for the scheduled phase-out of ODS, including chlorofluorocarbons (CFC), hydrochloro-fluorocarbons (HCFC), carbon tetrachloride (CCl4), halon, methyl chloroform (CH3CCl3), me-thyl chloride (CH3Cl), and even hydrofluorocarbons (HFCs). In view of the urgent importance of ozone layer protection to the globally ecological environment, the Taiwan government took regulatory actions on reducing ODS consumption since 1993 by the joint-venture of the central competent authorities. Under the regulatory requirements and the industry&#8217;s efforts by adopt-ing the alternatives to ODS and abatement technologies, the phase-out of some ODS (i.e., CFC, CCl4, halon, and CH3CCl3) have been achieved prior to 2010. The consumptions of HCFCs and methyl chloride have been significantly declined over the past three decades (1993-2022). However, HFC emission indicated a V-type variation during the period. Due to the local pro-duction and extensive use of HFC in Taiwan, its emissions increased from 663 kilotons of carbon dioxide equivalents (CO2eq) in 1993 to 2,330 kilotons of CO2eq in 2001, and then decreased to 373 kilotons of CO2eq in 2011. Since then, the emissions of HFC largely used as the alternatives to ODS showed an upward trend, increasing to 1,555 kilotons of CO2eq in 2022. To be in compliance with the Kigali Amendment (KA-2015) to the Montreal Protocol for mitigating global warming, the Taiwan government has taken regulatory actions in reducing the consumption of some HFC substances with high global warming potential (GWP) under the authorization of the Climate Change Response Act in 2023, aiming at the baseline consumption in 2024 by 80 % reduction by 2045.</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Tien Tsai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202407.1142.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of solar thermal in district heating systems &#8211; the case of parabolic trough collectors in a high-latitude region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00607k</link>
      <description>Nguyen Le Truong, Itai Danielski, Benjamin Ahlgren, Gireesh Nair, Sustainable energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400700929

                This study investigates primary energy use and CO2 emission reduction potential resulted by the integration of solar thermal heating in biomass-based district heating systems in high-latitude regions. A newly commissioned...</description>
      <author>Nguyen Le Truong, Itai Danielski, Benjamin Ahlgren, Gireesh Nair</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00607k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the single-basket mindset: A multi-gas approach to better constrain overshoot in near term warming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad6461</link>
      <description>Julie Miller, G. Dreyfus, John Daniel, Stephen G. Willis, Yangyang Xu, Environmental research letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400720502

                Abstract The remaining carbon budget framework tracks progress towards the Paris Agreement&#8217;s goal to limit longer-term warming to well below 2 &#186;C, but no analogous framework exists for constraining mid-century warming. Established single-basket methods of combining gases into CO2-equivalents using Global Warming Potentials (GWPs) lead to ambiguity over what combination of short- and long-lived emissions reductions are needed because they obscure the distinct warming impacts of each. We investigate to what extent a multi-basket approach that separates short-lived and long-lived pollutants can better estimate the likelihood for emission pathways to meet a near-term warming goal. We develop logistic regression models to categorize IPCC emission pathways (AR6) based on whether they exceed a mid-century temperature threshold. We focus on two baskets, using CO2 for long-lived and methane (CH4) for short-lived gases. For comparison, we consider several single-basket approaches (e.g., GWP100, GWP20, GWP*). We further apply our framework to a synthetic dataset covering a broader emissions space. Across both datasets, the two-basket outperforms all single-baskets. Using an illustrative near-term goal (1.7&#186;C), the two-basket approach reduces the magnitude of overshoot by a factor of 7 compared with the traditional single-basket. The two-basket&#8217;s advantage is smaller with the AR6 pathways, which we attribute to the high correlation between CO2 and CH4 emissions and confounding effects from other pollutants. Our results indicate that the two-basket approach better constrains overshoot magnitude, particularly if future emissions deviate from the AR6 assumption of correlated CO2 and CH4 reductions. Our approach allows the determination of a metric value and reduction target in the context of a chosen set of scenarios and temperature threshold; the outcome is a near-term methane-specific emissions budget that can be adopted by decisionmakers in a way that is analogous and complementary to the carbon budget. Future work could consider a third basket for very short-lived pollutants.</description>
      <author>Julie Miller, G. Dreyfus, John Daniel, Stephen G. Willis, Yangyang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad6461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics Investigation of Copper Ore Oxygen Carrier for Chemical Looping Combustion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7070245</link>
      <description>Xin Tian, Mingze Su, Haibo Zhao, Fire. 7(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400581486

                Chemical looping combustion (CLC) has been validated as one of the most promising technologies for fossil fuel combustion, which can produce high-purity CO2 streams ready for capture and sequestration in power production. The selection of an appropriate oxygen carrier is one of the most important issues for the CLC process, and the reduction kinetics investigation of the oxygen carrier with fuel gas can provide the basis for CLC reactor design and simulation optimization. In this study, copper ore was chosen as an oxygen carrier, and the oxygen release property of copper ore under a nitrogen environment at various temperatures (1073&#8211;1193 K) was first investigated in a thermogravimetric analyzer (TGA). Subsequently, the reduction kinetics of copper ore with CO and H2 were evaluated by the TGA at temperatures ranging from 773 K to 1073 K, using a continuous stream of 5, 10, 15, 20, 25, and 30 vol. % of CO or H2 balanced by CO2 or N2. It was found that the reaction rates of these reactions accelerated with the increase in temperature and fuel gas concentration in inlet gas. Both the oxygen release process of copper ore and the reduction process of copper ore with reducing gases can be described by the unreacted shrinking core model (USCM). The reaction mechanism function for the oxygen-releasing and reduction process of copper ore oxygen carrier was varied. The activation energy of the oxygen-releasing process, reduction process with CO, and reduction process with H2 were calculated as 99.35, 5.08, and 4.28 kJ/mol, respectively. The pre-exponential factor ranged from 1.96 &#215; 10&#8722;1 to 1.84 &#215; 103. The reaction order depended on the fuel gas, which was 1 and 0.86, respectively, for reaction with CO and H2.</description>
      <author>Xin Tian, Mingze Su, Haibo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7070245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of the industrial emissions impact on the quality of atmospheric air in the Burlin district of West Kazakhstan region DEVELOPMENT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37878/2708-0080/2024-2.14</link>
      <description>S.O. Kozhagulov, Vitaliy Salnikov, Neft&#697; i gaz. 140(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741889

                The article is devoted to the study of air pollution in the Burlin district of the West Kazakhstan region, where one of the main sources of air pollution is the Karachagan oil and gas condensate field, the main feature of which is the high content of hydrogen sulfide in natural gas from 4 to 4.3%. The analysis showed that the atmospheric air state in the specified area is determined by the characteristics of harmful emissions sources, composition, volumes of pollutant emissions and climatic characteristics of the territory, which determine the conditions for the polluting components dispersion. The qualitative and quantitative characteristics of the chemical composition of the atmospheric air in the study area, as well as the features of their changes over the years end climatic seasons, are largely determined by emissions of nitrogen oxides, carbon, sulfur dioxide, hydrogen sulfide, volatile organic compounds and inorganic dust into the atmosphere by oil and gas facilities. The anthropogenic influence of industry in this area is also evidenced by the calculated value of the integral coefficient of air pollution. At the same time, industrial enterprises, having increased the anthropogenic impact on the environment, have the ability to prevent negative environmental consequences. The system of industrial environmental control of the chemical composition of industrial emissions at the Karachagnak field facilities is carried out on an ongoing basis. The analysis showed that a reduction in emissions and, accordingly, a reduction in ground-level concentrations of air pollutants at the Karachagnak field facilities is ensured by a whole range of technological and organizational measures, among which the technology of high-pressure gas reinjection deserves special attention. It necessitates the need to carry out systematic work to study the ecological state of the territory of the Karachagnak field, using not only ground-based research methods, but also modern geoinformation and aerospace technologies that make it possible to dynamically assess the changes taking place, conduct a geo-ecological assessment and make a forecast for the development of the environmental situation in this area. territories. The work carried out contributes to further analysis of the regional assessment of the environmental state of the atmosphere of large industrial centers.</description>
      <author>S.O. Kozhagulov, Vitaliy Salnikov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37878/2708-0080/2024-2.14</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pathways Towards Improving the Energy Efficiency of Residential Air &amp;amp;#x96; Conditioning Systems in Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4065973</link>
      <description>Abdulaziz M. Alotaibi, Taha K. Makhdoom, Awad B. S. Alquaity, Journal of solar energy engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400683596

                Abstract In Saudi Arabia, the residential electricity consumption approaches 50%, primarily driven by air conditioners (AC). This study explores the potential energy savings and CO2 emission reductions up to 2030 through three scenarios: Business as Usual (BAU), Continuous Improvement Scenario (CIS), and Accelerated Improvement Scenario (AIS). BAU scenario assumes that the current Energy Efficiency Ratio (EER) of 11.8 BTU/Wh is maintained until 2030. CIS considers a 5% EER improvement in new AC stock every 2 or 5 years, while AIS assumes a 10% improvement in EER at the same intervals. Additionally, energy savings and emission reductions possible from varying adoption levels of a new refrigerant (R32) are estimated for three scenarios. Lastly, the CO2 emission reduction under each scenario is computed for two extreme cases of grid emission factor. BAU scenario predicts energy savings of up to 17.7 TWh in 2030 compared to 2020 energy consumption figures. AIS with 2 year intervals results in additional energy savings of 10.1 TWh in 2030 and cumulative energy savings of 37.1 TWh over a decade compared to the BAU scenario. Even CIS with 5 year intervals yields additional energy savings of 1.69 TWh in 2030 and 5.1 TWh cumulatively compared to the BAU scenario. In comparison, the introduction of the new refrigerant results in cumulative energy savings of 10.2 TWh in the best-case scenario. These findings emphasize the importance of enhancing the EER of residential AC systems as a priority in energy efficiency policy.</description>
      <author>Abdulaziz M. Alotaibi, Taha K. Makhdoom, Awad B. S. Alquaity</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4065973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling boreal forest's mineral soil and peat C dynamics with the Yasso07 model coupled with the Ricker moisture modifier</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-17-5349-2024</link>
      <description>Boris &#356;upek, Aleksi Lehtonen, Alla Yurova, Rose Abramoff, Bertrand Guenet, Elisa Bruni, Samuli Launiainen, Mikko Peltoniemi, Shoji Hashimoto, Xianglin Tian, Juha Heikkinen, Kari Minkkinen, Raisa M&#228;kip&#228;&#228;, Geoscientific model development. 17(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400549125

                Abstract. As soil microbial respiration is the major component of land CO2 emissions, differences in the functional dependence of respiration on soil moisture among Earth system models (ESMs) contributes significantly to the uncertainties in their projections. Using soil organic C (SOC) stocks and CO2 data from a boreal forest&#8211;mire ecotone in Finland and Bayesian data assimilation, we revised the original precipitation-based monotonic saturation dependency of the Yasso07 soil carbon model using the non-monotonic Ricker function based on soil volumetric water content. We fit the revised functional dependency of moisture to the observed microbial respiration and SOC stocks and compared its performance against the original Yasso07 model and the version used in the JSBACH land surface model with a reduction constant for decomposition rates in wetlands. The Yasso07 soil C model coupled with the calibrated unimodal Ricker moisture function with an optimum in well-drained soils accurately reconstructed observed SOC stocks and soil CO2 emissions and clearly outperformed previous model versions on paludified organo-mineral soils in forested peatlands and water-saturated organic soils in mires. The best estimate of the posterior moisture response of decomposition used both measurements of SOC stocks and CO2 data from the full range of moisture conditions (from dry and xeric to wet and water-saturated soils). We observed unbiased residuals of SOC and CO2 data modelled with the moisture optimum in well-drained soils, suggesting that this modified function accounts more precisely for the long-term SOC change dependency according to ecosystem properties as well as the contribution of short-term CO2 responses including extreme events. The optimum moisture for decomposition in boreal forests was found in well-drained soils instead of the mid-range between dry and water-saturated conditions as is commonly assumed among soil C and ESMs. Although the unimodal moisture modifier with an optimum in well-drained soils implicitly incorporates robust biogeochemical mechanisms of SOC accumulation and CO2 emissions, it needs further evaluation with large-scale data to determine if its use in land surface models will decrease the uncertainty in projections.</description>
      <author>Boris &#356;upek, Aleksi Lehtonen, Alla Yurova, Rose Abramoff, Bertrand Guenet, Elisa Bruni, Samuli Launiainen, Mikko Peltoniemi, Shoji Hashimoto, Xianglin Tian, Juha Heikkinen, Kari Minkkinen, Raisa M&#228;kip&#228;&#228;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-17-5349-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quantitative study on the impact of a community falls pharmacist role, on medicines optimisation in older people at risk of falls</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12877-024-05189-6</link>
      <description>Paula Crawford, Robert C. Plumb, Paula Burns, Stephen Flanagan, Carole Parsons, BMC geriatrics. 24(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400655149

                Abstract Background The World Falls guidance includes medication review as part of its recommended multifactorial risk assessment for those at high risk of falling. Use of Falls Risk Increasing Drugs (FRIDs) along with polypharmacy and anticholinergic burden (ACB) are known to increase the risk of falls in older people. Method The impact of a community falls pharmacist within a hospital Trust, working as part of a multi-professional community falls prevention service, was evaluated in 92 people aged 65 years or older, by analysing data before and after pharmacist review, namely: number and type of FRIDs prescribed; anticholinergic burden score using ACBcalc &#174; ; appropriateness of medicines prescribed; bone health review using an approved too; significance of clinical intervention; cost avoidance, drug cost savings and environmental impact. Results Following pharmacist review, there was a reduction in polypharmacy (mean number of medicines prescribed per patient reduced by 8%; p &lt; 0.05) and anticholinergic burden score (average score per patient reduced by 33%; p &lt; 0.05). Medicines appropriateness improved (Medicines Appropriateness Index score decreased by 56%; p &lt; 0.05). There were 317 clinically significant interventions by the community falls pharmacist. One hundred and one FRIDs were deprescribed. Annual cost avoidance and drug cost savings were &#163;40,689-&#163;82,642 and avoidable carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) emissions from reducing inappropriate prescribing amounted to 941 kg CO 2 . Conclusion The community falls pharmacist role increases prescribing appropriateness in the older population at risk of falls, and is an effective and cost-efficient means to optimise medicines in this population, as well as having a positive impact on the environment.</description>
      <author>Paula Crawford, Robert C. Plumb, Paula Burns, Stephen Flanagan, Carole Parsons</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12877-024-05189-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Sludge Management in China: Quantifying GHG Emissions and Exploring Its Reduction Strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12071481</link>
      <description>Dongming Hu, Peng Jiang, Yipei Chen, Fuyan Gao, Shuai Liu, Processes. 12(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400668208

                This study aims to evaluate the emissions of greenhouse gases (GHGs) stemming from the sludge treatment sector in China and to investigate the feasibility of novel technologies in curtailing these emissions, with the aim of fostering sustainable sludge management methodologies. Employing a life-cycle assessment (LCA) methodology, the research computed the comprehensive GHG emissions resulting from sludge treatment, taking into consideration diverse elements such as treatment techniques (e.g., landfills, incineration, and land application) and the geographical variations among China&#8217;s 660 municipalities. Findings indicate that the total amount of GHG emissions from sludge treatment amounted to 18.54 Mt CO2-eq in 2017, with incineration registering the highest emissions (10,011.53 kg CO2-eq/t dry sludge (DS)), followed by landfills (717.51 kg CO2-eq/t DS) and land application (276.41 kg CO2-eq/t DS). The geographical dispersion of emissions characteristics reveal notable regional disparities, with the top 1% of cities responsible for 34.2% of the overall emissions. The concentration of emissions in the top 1 percent of cities underscores the necessity for tailored mitigation measures that consider localized sustainable development challenges. Principal component analysis (PCA) demonstrates that economic determinants and treatment scales exert substantial influence on emissions, underscoring the imperative of aligning Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) with economic advancement. To curtail the carbon footprint associated with sludge treatment and enhance sustainability, the study evaluated the emission mitigation potential and expenses of diverse technologies, encompassing thermal conversion, anaerobic digestion, hydrothermal treatment, and wet oxidation. These technologies have the capacity to slash GHG emissions by 0.09&#8211;0.46 t CO2-eq/t DS in comparison to traditional approaches, while concurrently advancing resource recuperation and principles of circular economy. For instance, gasification could diminish GHG emissions by 0.33&#8211;0.46 t CO2-eq/t DS, whereas anaerobic digestion could yield reductions of 0.09&#8211;0.30 t CO2-eq/t DS. The implementation of these innovative technologies across 660 Chinese municipalities could potentially curtail total GHG emissions from sludge treatment by 15&#8211;40%. Nevertheless, further enhancements are imperative to refine their environmental and economic efficiency and guarantee enduring sustainability. By deploying these technologies and embracing optimization tactics, China&#8217;s sludge treatment sector can make a substantial contribution towards attaining national carbon neutrality objectives and advancing sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Dongming Hu, Peng Jiang, Yipei Chen, Fuyan Gao, Shuai Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12071481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional Electrocatalytic CO Conversion to C2 Products on Single&#8208;Atomic Pd&#8208;Agn Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411194</link>
      <description>Yali Ji, Ximeng Lv, Ruilin Wei, Anxiang Guan, Chao Yang, Yaqin Yan, Min Kuang, Gengfeng Zheng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400581425

                The electrochemical reduction of CO or CO2 into C2+ products has mostly been focused on Cu&#8208;based catalysts. Although Ag has also been predicted as a possible catalyst for the CO&#8208;to&#8208;C2+ conversion from the thermodynamic point of view, however, due to its weak CO binding strength, CO rapidly desorbs from the Ag surface rather than participates in deep reduction. In this work, we demonstrate that single&#8208;atomic Pd sites doped in Ag lattice can tune the CO adsorption behavior and promote the deep reduction of CO toward C2 products. The monodispersed Pd&#8208;Agn sites enable the CO adsorption with both Pd&#8208;atop (PdL) and Pd&#8208;Ag bridge (PdAgB) configurations, which can increase the CO coverage and reduce the C&#8722;C coupling energy barrier. Under room temperature and ambient pressure, the Pd1Ag10 alloy catalyst exhibited a total CO&#8208;to&#8208;C2 Faradaic efficiency of ~37% at &#8210;0.83 V, with appreciable current densities and electrochemical stability, thus featuring unconventional non&#8208;Cu electrocatalytic CO&#8208;to&#8208;C2 conversion capability.</description>
      <author>Yali Ji, Ximeng Lv, Ruilin Wei, Anxiang Guan, Chao Yang, Yaqin Yan, Min Kuang, Gengfeng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional Electrocatalytic CO Conversion to C2 Products on Single&#8208;Atomic Pd&#8208;Agn Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411194</link>
      <description>Yali Ji, Ximeng Lv, Ruilin Wei, Anxiang Guan, Chao Yang, Yaqin Yan, Min Kuang, Gengfeng Zheng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400581880

                The electrochemical reduction of CO or CO2 into C2+ products has mostly been focused on Cu&#8208;based catalysts. Although Ag has also been predicted as a possible catalyst for the CO&#8208;to&#8208;C2+ conversion from the thermodynamic point of view, however, due to its weak CO binding strength, CO rapidly desorbs from the Ag surface rather than participates in deep reduction. In this work, we demonstrate that single&#8208;atomic Pd sites doped in Ag lattice can tune the CO adsorption behavior and promote the deep reduction of CO toward C2 products. The monodispersed Pd&#8208;Agn sites enable the CO adsorption with both Pd&#8208;atop (PdL) and Pd&#8208;Ag bridge (PdAgB) configurations, which can increase the CO coverage and reduce the C&#8722;C coupling energy barrier. Under room temperature and ambient pressure, the Pd1Ag10 alloy catalyst exhibited a total CO&#8208;to&#8208;C2 Faradaic efficiency of ~37% at &#8210;0.83 V, with appreciable current densities and electrochemical stability, thus featuring unconventional non&#8208;Cu electrocatalytic CO&#8208;to&#8208;C2 conversion capability.</description>
      <author>Yali Ji, Ximeng Lv, Ruilin Wei, Anxiang Guan, Chao Yang, Yaqin Yan, Min Kuang, Gengfeng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Cu-Based Monatomic Alloys: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01246</link>
      <description>Xiaojiao Li, Liyun Jiang, Yong Zhou, Qi Yu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400651340

                In recent years, single-atom alloy catalysts (SAAs) have received much attention due to the combination of structural features of both single-atom and alloy catalysts, as well as their efficient catalytic activity, high selectivity, and high stability in various chemical reactions. In this work, we designed a series of Cu-based SAAs by doping isolated 3d transition metal (TM1) atoms on the surface of Cu(111) (TM1 = Fe, Co, Ru, Rh, Os and Ir), in which Ir1/Cu(111) SAAs are considered to be the most stable among 3d-series SAAs due to their optimal binding energy (Eb). The density of states of SAAs have been systematically investigated to further discuss structural properties. Based on density functional theory calculations, the activity and selectivity of Ir1/Cu(111) SAAs are investigated for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). The initial hydrogenation of CO2 on Ir1/Cu(111) SAAs can form *CO intermediates, which will be further to CH4 production by the pathway of *CO &#8594; *CHO &#8594; *CHOH &#8594; *CH2OH &#8594; *CH2 &#8594; *CH3 &#8594; CH4. This study provides theoretical insights for the rational design of selective Cu-based monatomic alloy catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaojiao Li, Liyun Jiang, Yong Zhou, Qi Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Phase-Change Materials in Ventilated Fa&#231;ades: A Review Regarding Fire Safety and Future Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7070244</link>
      <description>Emanuil-Petru Ovadiuc, R&#259;zvan Calot&#259;, Ilinca N&#259;stase, Florin Bode, Fire. 7(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400581524

                The increasing concerns about CO2 emissions and climate change have pointed out the urgency of promoting sustainability in the building sector. One promising solution to enhance the energy efficiency of buildings and diminish environmental impact is the integration of phase-change materials (PCMs) into ventilated fa&#231;ade systems. This review article critically examines the current state of research on this innovative approach, with a particular focus on fire safety considerations. The paper explores the integration of PCM into ventilated fa&#231;ades, highlighting the potential for significant improvements in energy consumption, thermal comfort, and reductions in CO2 emissions. However, the flammability of PCMs introduces substantial fire safety challenges that must be addressed to ensure the safe application of this solution. The fire safety of both ventilated fa&#231;ades and PCMs is approached, followed by specific fire safety concerns when PCMs are integrated into ventilated fa&#231;ade systems. The conclusion states that while the integration of PCMs into ventilated fa&#231;ades offers substantial environmental benefits, attention to fire safety is essential. This necessitates the implementation of rigorous fire protection measures during the design and construction phases. By addressing both the environmental advantages and fire safety challenges, this review aims to provide a comprehensive understanding of the potential and limitations of PCM-integrated ventilated fa&#231;ades, offering valuable insights for researchers, engineers, and policymakers in the field of sustainable buildings.</description>
      <author>Emanuil-Petru Ovadiuc, R&#259;zvan Calot&#259;, Ilinca N&#259;stase, Florin Bode</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7070244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Experience With a New Miniaturized Pump-Driven Venovenous Extracorporeal CO2 Removal System (iLA Activve): A Retrospective Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003543480-43</link>
      <description>Alexander Hermann, Thomas Staudinger, Andja Bojic, Katharina Riss, Philipp Wohlfarth, Oliver Robak, Wolfgang R. Sperr, Peter Schellongowski, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400685349

                iLA Activve is a new minimally invasive device for extracorporeal CO2 removal (ECCO2-R) using a miniaturized pump, a special gas exchange membrane, and a double-lumen cannula. We retrospectively analyzed our experiences in 12 patients with hypercapnic respiratory failure undergoing ECCO2-R. Indication for ECCO2-R was hypercapnia due to terminal lung failure during bridging to lung transplantation, pneumonia, and chronic obstructive lung disease or asthma. The median duration of ECCO2-R was 8 days (range 2&#8211;30). Seven patients were successfully weaned and five died. Patients with primarily hypoxic lung failure were significantly longer ventilated before ECCO2-R and had a higher mortality rate. Complications were retroperitoneal hematoma after cannulation in one patient and repeated system changes because of clotting in two patients. We observed effective CO2 removal in all patients, with significant reduction in ventilation pressures and minute volumes at median blood flow rates of 1.2&#8211;1.4 L/ min. The iLA Activve system using venous double-lumen cannulas proved to be an effective method for ECCO2-R. Invasiveness of ventilation could be reduced. Additional severe impairment of oxygenation and prolonged mechanical ventilation before ECCO2-R are factors of adverse prognosis. The use of ECCO2-R should be thoroughly reconsidered in these cases. ASAIO Journal 2014; 60:342&#8211;347. ECCO2-R, iLA Activve, hypercapnia, decarboxylation, extracorporeal</description>
      <author>Alexander Hermann, Thomas Staudinger, Andja Bojic, Katharina Riss, Philipp Wohlfarth, Oliver Robak, Wolfgang R. Sperr, Peter Schellongowski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003543480-43</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for carbon farming schemes (Road4Schemes) : Deliverable D2.1-2, D2.4-5 : carbon farming schemes throughout Europe, an overall inventory and analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18174/654551</link>
      <description>A.B. Smit, Martin Hvarregaard Thors&#248;e, J.W.H. van der Kolk, K. Nikolaus, Laura B. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Ennio Facq, Ilaria Falconi, &#220;lfet Erdal, Claudia Heidecke, Alessandra Martelli, Irene Criscuoli, Giovanni Dara Guccione, Morten Graversgaard, Jana Pol&#225;kov&#225;, S. G&#246;tzinger, A. Baumgarten, Suzanne Reynders, M. Nogu&#232;s, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400559880

                Carbon farming is considered as one of the mitigation options to reach the targets of the Paris Agreement and the European Green Deal.The purpose of this report is to assess which carbon farming schemes are available throughout Europe, how they can be characterised and to which extent they deal with principles like additionality, fairness and long-term carbon storage, besides the issues of a proper MRV(monitoring, reporting and verification)-system with acceptable costs and sufficient payments for the farmers.The way in which carbon farming is organised is very different depending on the type of scheme.In this report, a carbon farming scheme is defined as any voluntary agreement in which a farmer or a group of farmers commit themselves to apply carbon farming measures to get a positive balance between soil carbon accumulation and GHG emissions (possibly measured as CO2 equivalents) or reduction of GHG-emissions in return for a payment or compensation in any form.</description>
      <author>A.B. Smit, Martin Hvarregaard Thors&#248;e, J.W.H. van der Kolk, K. Nikolaus, Laura B. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Ennio Facq, Ilaria Falconi, &#220;lfet Erdal, Claudia Heidecke, Alessandra Martelli, Irene Criscuoli, Giovanni Dara Guccione, Morten Graversgaard, Jana Pol&#225;kov&#225;, S. G&#246;tzinger, A. Baumgarten, Suzanne Reynders, M. Nogu&#232;s</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18174/654551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Biomass Transformation to Hydrocarbons under Supercritical Conditions over Nickel Supported on Schungite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12071503</link>
      <description>Elena O. Schipanskaya, &#1040;ntonina &#1040;. Stepacheva, Mariia E. Markova, Alexey V. Bykov, &#1040;. &#1048;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Valentina G. Matveeva, Mikhail G. Sulman, Lioubov Kiwi&#8208;Minsker, Processes. 12(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400723682

                Liquid fuel production from biomass-derived molecules has received great attention due to the diminished fossil fuel reserves, growing energy demand, and the necessity of CO2 emission reduction. The deoxygenation of oils and fatty acids is a promising process to obtain &#8220;green&#8221; diesel. Herein, we report the results of the study of the deoxygenation of stearic acid to alkanes as a model reaction. Series of Ni-supported on schungite were obtained by precipitation in subcritical water (hydrothermal deposition) and for comparison via wetness impregnation followed, in both cases, by calcination at 500 &#176;C and a reduction in H2 at 300 &#176;C. The catalyst obtained via hydrothermal synthesis showed a three-fold higher specific surface area with a four-fold higher active phase dispersion compared to the catalysts synthesized via conventional impregnation. The catalysts were tested in stearic acid deoxygenation in supercritical n-hexane as the solvent. Under optimized process conditions (temperature of 280 &#176;C, hydrogen partial pressure of 1.5 MPa, and 13.2 mol of stearic acid per mol of Ni), a close to 100% yield of C10&#8211;C18 alkanes, containing over 70 wt.% of targeted n-heptadecane, was obtained after 60 min of reaction.</description>
      <author>Elena O. Schipanskaya, &#1040;ntonina &#1040;. Stepacheva, Mariia E. Markova, Alexey V. Bykov, &#1040;. &#1048;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Valentina G. Matveeva, Mikhail G. Sulman, Lioubov Kiwi&#8208;Minsker</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12071503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Optimization of Natural Gas Injection Timing in a Dual-Fuel Marine Engine to Minimize GHG Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/gases4030011</link>
      <description>Luigi De Simio, Luca Marchitto, Sabato Iannaccone, Vincenzo Pennino, Nunzio Altieri, Gases. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400679400

                Phased injection of natural gas into internal combustion marine engines is a promising solution for optimizing performance and reducing harmful emissions, particularly unburned methane, a potent greenhouse gas. This innovative practice distinguishes itself from continuous injection because it allows for more precise control of the combustion process with only a slight increase in system complexity. By synchronizing the injection of natural gas with the intake and exhaust valve opening and closing times while also considering the gas path in the manifolds, methane release into the atmosphere is significantly reduced, making a substantial contribution to efforts to address climate change. Moreover, phased injection improves the efficiency of marine engines, resulting in reduced overall fuel consumption, lower fuel costs, and increased ship autonomy. This technology was tested on a single-cylinder, large-bore, four-stroke research engine designed for marine applications, operating in dual-fuel mode with diesel and natural gas. Performance was compared with that of the conventional continuous feeding method. Evaluation of the effect on equivalent CO2 emissions indicates a potential reduction of up to approximately 20%. This reduction effectively brings greenhouse gas emissions below those of the diesel baseline case, especially when injection control is combined with supercharging control to optimize the air&#8211;fuel ratio. In this context, the boost pressure in DF was reduced from 3 to 1.5 bar compared with the FD case.</description>
      <author>Luigi De Simio, Luca Marchitto, Sabato Iannaccone, Vincenzo Pennino, Nunzio Altieri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/gases4030011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Leveling Mortars Produced with Different Types of Cement: Physical&#8211;Mechanical Properties and Carbon Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145898</link>
      <description>Brenda Maiara Oliveira Alves, M&#237;sley Da Cruz Teixeira, Karen Suely Martins Bernardo, Luciana de Nazar&#233; Pinheiro Cordeiro, Edna Possan, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400523218

                Self-leveling mortars are a product that stands out in the market for optimizing production. Greater speed of application is achieved due to its high fluidity, and the ability to level without segregation. This paper approaches self-leveling mortars formulated with different types of cement and additions and evaluates these material&#8217;s effect on the rheological behavior, physical&#8211;mechanical characteristics, and environmental aspects of this type of mortar. The results indicate that rheological aspects can be achieved regardless of the type of cement and addition. With proper proportioning, the normative requirements in terms of mechanical properties are met. When using lower-fineness cement, the risk of cracking and the demand for water and chemicals increases. Mineral additions contributed to the mortars&#8217; cohesion and reduced shrinkage in mixtures with contents of up to 25% metakaolin and 15% silica fume. Regarding the decarbonization process, opting for cement with pozzolanic additions becomes a favorable solution as it presents a reduction in CO2 emissions of around 170 kg per m3 of mortar produced.</description>
      <author>Brenda Maiara Oliveira Alves, M&#237;sley Da Cruz Teixeira, Karen Suely Martins Bernardo, Luciana de Nazar&#233; Pinheiro Cordeiro, Edna Possan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Retrospective Audit with Subsequent Cost and Environmental Analysis of a Denosumab Self Injection Programme</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jbmrpl/ziae092</link>
      <description>Jack Boylan, Jane F. Turton, Zita R. Hicks, Julia Cottam, Michael D. Stone, JBMR plus. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400728745

                Abstract The Metabolic Bone Health Department, Cardiff and Vale University Health Board, serves a local population of approximately 445 000 people. A retrospective audit of attendance data regarding the Denosumab treatment clinic (the traditional treatment pathway) and the Denosumab Self Injection Programme (SIP) was conducted to determine whether the Self Injection Programme is both cost effective and environmentally beneficial, compared to the traditional treatment pathway. Cost analysis was then conducted by the Finance Department. The audit was conducted over 3 years following the implementation of the service development; 233 patients had enrolled in the program at the time of the audit and 69 had completed 3 years of self- injected treatment. A control group of 497 patients were identified by the service. This group remained on the historical pathway and had consistent attendance activity over the three-year period from 2017 to 2019. Pre and post period activity of all patients on the program was compared, together with the activity for the independent control group. The SIP resulted in a reduction in clinical contacts, with financial analysis showing a total opportunity cost saving per patient of &#163;420 per annum. There were obvious benefits to the patient of a reduced number of visits to a clinical site, which also resulted in an estimated carbon footprint reduction of 59 KG CO2 per patient per annum. The cost analysis is based on our organisation&#8217;s 2022 charges. The SIP demonstrates that through focusing on care &#8220;closer to home&#8221;, it is possible to maximise resources, improve the patient experience through reduced travel and reduce the environmental impact of healthcare.</description>
      <author>Jack Boylan, Jane F. Turton, Zita R. Hicks, Julia Cottam, Michael D. Stone</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jbmrpl/ziae092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the potential of Easy Language for enhancing website sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10209-024-01129-8</link>
      <description>Mariona Gonz&#225;lez-Sord&#233;, Universal access in the information society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400534852

                Abstract Sustainable design principles have become increasingly important in website development, mainly focusing on reducing carbon emissions and energy consumption. Easy language (EL) is a simplified language variety that makes websites more accessible to a wider range of users; but there has been no attention given to its usefulness in sustainability efforts. As such, this study is intended to become a starting point for future research in the area. By examining the intersection between EL and website sustainability guidelines and practices, the study highlights the potential for EL to contribute to sustainable website design. Along the paper, the following theory is defended: when adapted to Easy Language, text and interactions in websites are simplified, which makes them require less data transfer, become more efficient and, ultimately, more sustainable. The paper also presents a small comparative analysis of the sustainability of websites in EL and standard language that indicated that EL generally enhanced the sustainability of websites. The nine websites in EL analysed showed a mean reduction of CO2 production of 42% in comparison to their equivalents in standard language ( p = 0.049, F = 2.42). The discussion and results presented open potential solutions for an urgent problem that deserve to be considered and researched further.</description>
      <author>Mariona Gonz&#225;lez-Sord&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10209-024-01129-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic Order Quantity: A State-of-the-Art in the Era of Uncertain Supply Chains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145965</link>
      <description>Mohammed Alnahhal&#8236;&#8207;, Batin Latif Aylak, Muataz Hazza Faizi Al Hazza, Ahmad Sakhrieh, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400578514

                Inventory management is crucial for companies to minimize unnecessary costs associated with overstocking or understocking items. Utilizing the economic order quantity (EOQ) to minimize total costs is a key decision in inventory management, particularly in achieving a sustainable supply chain. The classical EOQ formula is rarely applicable in practice. For example, suppliers may enforce a minimum order quantity (MOQ) that is much larger than the EOQ. Some conditions such as imperfect quality and growing items represent variants of EOQ. Moreover, some requirements, such as the reduction of CO2 emissions, can alter the formula. Moreover, disruptions in the supply chain, such as COVID-19, can affect the formula. This study investigates which requirements must be considered during the calculation of the EOQ. Based on a literature review, 18 requirements that could alter the EOQ formula were identified. The level of coverage for these requirements has been tracked in the literature. Research gaps were presented to be investigated in future research. The analysis revealed that, despite their importance, at least 11 requirements have seldom been explored in the literature. Among these, topics such as EOQ in Industry 4.0, practical EOQ, and resilient EOQ have been identified as promising areas for future research.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Alnahhal&#8236;&#8207;, Batin Latif Aylak, Muataz Hazza Faizi Al Hazza, Ahmad Sakhrieh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Partial Oxidation of Methane at Different Reaction Parameters by Adding Ni to CeO2 and ZrO2 Supported Cordierite Monolith Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12071463</link>
      <description>Ilke Ilicak Bayraktar, Halit Eren Figen, Processes. 12(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400600073

                The climate crisis, driven by increasing CO2 levels in the atmosphere, has heightened the need for new, environmentally friendly energy sources. Hydrogen gas, which can meet our energy needs, has become a particularly intriguing topic. This study investigated the partial oxidation reaction of methane with cordierite monolith catalysts. The Ni-coated catalysts were supported with &#947;-Al2O3, CeO2, ZrO2, and CeO2-ZrO2. The catalysts were tested at temperatures of 750, 800, and 850 &#176;C with different flow rates and methane feed concentrations (2%, 5%, and 10%). It was demonstrated that catalyst activity varies depending on these parameters. It has been found that high gas hourly space velocity (GHSV) and CH4 feed rates decrease catalyst activity. The obtained reaction results indicated that the optimal reaction parameters were 800 &#176;C, a GHSV of 1.104 h&#8722;1, and a CH4 feed concentration of 2%. By optimizing these parameters, catalysts with high CH4 conversion and selectivity for H2 and CO were achieved. The prepared catalysts were characterized using scanning electron microscopy with energy dispersive X-ray analysis (SEM-EDX), X-ray diffraction (XRD), Brunauer-Emmett-Teller (BET), and temperature-programmed reduction (TPR).</description>
      <author>Ilke Ilicak Bayraktar, Halit Eren Figen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12071463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flammability, Toxicity, and Microbiological Properties of Polyurethane Flexible Foams</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17143517</link>
      <description>A. Glowacki, Przemys&#322;aw Rybi&#324;ski, Grzegorz Czerwonka, Witold &#379;ukowski, Ulugbek Zakirovich Mirkhodjaev, Monika &#379;elezik, Materials. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400683024

                The aim of the research was to investigate the influence of calcium phosphinate (HPCA) and aluminum phosphinate (HPAL) in synergistic systems with organophosphorus compounds, i.e., diphenylcresyl phosphate (CDP) and trichloropropyl phosphate (TCPP), on the thermal stability, flammability, smoke density, and emission of toxic gases during the thermal decomposition of polyurethane (PUR) foams. Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA), along with cone calorimetry and microcalorimetry, were used to assess the influence of fillers on the thermal stability and flammability of PUR foams. The analysis of toxic gas products was performed with the use of a coupled TG&#8211;gas analyzer system. The optical density of gases was measured with the use of a smoke density chamber (SDC). The obtained results showed an increase in thermal stability and a decrease in the flammability of the PUR composites. However, the results regarding smoke and gas emissions, as well as toxic combustion by-products, present ambiguity. On one hand, the applied flame retardant systems in the form of PUR-HPCA-CDP and PUR-HPCA-TCPP led to a reduction in the concentration of CO and HCN in the gas by-products. On the other hand, they clearly increased the concentration of CO2, NOx, and smoke emissions. Microbiological studies indicated that the obtained foam material is completely safe for use and does not exhibit biocidal properties.</description>
      <author>A. Glowacki, Przemys&#322;aw Rybi&#324;ski, Grzegorz Czerwonka, Witold &#379;ukowski, Ulugbek Zakirovich Mirkhodjaev, Monika &#379;elezik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17143517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction in Nitrogen Fertilization Rate for Spring Wheat Due to Carbon Mineralization-Induced Nitrogen Mineralization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agrochemicals3030014</link>
      <description>Upendra M. Sainju, Agrochemicals. 3(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400575477

                Using predicted potential N mineralization (PNM) from its relationship with CO2 flush at 1 d incubation (CF) of soil samples in recommended N rates can reduce N fertilization rates for crops. This study used predicted PNM at the 0&#8211;15 cm depth to reduce N fertilization rates and examined spring wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) yields at two sites (Froid and Sidney) in Montana, USA. Cropping sequences at Froid were fall and spring till continuous spring wheat (FSTCW), no-till continuous spring wheat (NTCW1), no-till spring wheat&#8211;pea (Pisum sativum L.) (NTWP1), and spring till spring wheat&#8211;fallow (STWF). At Sidney, cropping sequences were conventional till spring wheat&#8211;fallow (CTWF), no-till spring wheat&#8211;fallow (NTWF), no-till continuous spring wheat (NTCW2), and no-till spring wheat&#8211;pea (NTWP2). Soil samples collected to a depth of 15 cm in September 2021 at both sites were analyzed for CF, PNM, and NO3-N contents, from which the reduction in N fertilization rate (RNFA) and the amount of N fertilizer applied (ANFA) to 2022 spring wheat were determined. In April 2022, spring wheat was grown with or without predicted PNM and annualized crop yields were compared. The CF and PNM were 114&#8211;137% greater for NTWP1 than STWF at Froid and 26&#8211;80% greater for NTCW2 than CTWF and NTWF at Sidney. The reduction in N fertilization rate was 26&#8211;102% greater for NTWP1 at Froid and 8&#8211;10% greater for NTCW2 and NTWF than other cropping sequences at Sidney. Annualized crop yield was 26&#8211;60% lower for crop&#8211;fallow than continuous cropping, but was not significantly different between with or without PNM at both sites. Using PNM can significantly reduce N fertilization rates for crops while sustaining dryland yields.</description>
      <author>Upendra M. Sainju</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agrochemicals3030014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Dry Mix Alkali Activated Slag Binder Composite Properties Cured in Ambient Condition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.05746</link>
      <description>, Global NEST Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400727261

                &lt;p&gt;A dry mix (solution-free) alkali-activated slag (a primary cementitious material) and/or fly ash based binder composition is developed that can be cast in-site and consequently cured at ambient temperature. Mortar specimens were cast by mixing slag and or fly ash, river sand, powder form alkaline activators (NaOH 14M, varying solids percentage of Na2SiO3) and water were thoroughly mixed in fabricated equipment. The dry density (28 days) of all specimens showed greater than 2200 kg/m3. The compressive strength (28 days) of all mixes was resulted in higher than 40 N/mm2. Among all the four mixes, a mix F103 with 90% slag, 10% fly ash, 30% Na2SiO3 and 14M NaOH at 3, 7 and 28 days curing showed overall higher compressive strength. It is due to fewer solids content of Na2SiO3. The experimental results indicated that solution free studied binder composite can be developed under ambient conditions eliminating other curing types without compromising in the strength. The studied sustainable mixes require only 12-15 percent water which is less compared to regular used mixes. Thus reduced water quantities can be achieved thereby protects the reduction in volume of water bodies, environment hazards, reduces CO2 emissions due to use of industrial by-products as main binders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.05746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reconstruction of Bi 2 Te 4 O 11 Nanorods for Efficient and pH&#8208;universal Electrochemical CO 2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408849</link>
      <description>Jiadong Chen, Tingjie Mao, Juan Wang, Jichang Wang, Huile Jin, Shun Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400593019

                The practical application of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is hindered by the competing CO production, hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and the lack of pH&#8208;universal catalysts. Here, Te&#8208;modified Bi nanorods (Te&#8208;Bi NRs) were synthesized through in situ reconstruction of Bi2Te4O11 NRs under the CO2RR condition. Our study illustrates that the complex reconstruction process of Bi2Te4O11 NRs during CO2RR could be decoupled into three distinct steps, i.e., the destruction of Bi2Te4O11, the formation of Te/Bi phases, and the dissolution of Te. The thus&#8208;obtained Te&#8208;Bi NRs exhibit remarkably high performance in CO2RR towards formate production, showing high activity, selectivity, and stability across all pH conditions (acidic, neutral, and alkaline). In a flow cell reactor under neutral, alkaline, or acidic conditions, the catalysts achieved HCOOH Faradaic efficiencies of up to 94.3%, 96.4%, and 91.0%, respectively, at a high current density of 300 mA cm&#8208;2. DFT calculations, along with operando spectral measurements, reveal that Te manipulates the Bi sites to an electron&#8208;deficient state, enhancing the adsorption strength of the *OCHO intermediate, and significantly suppressing the competing HER and CO production. This study highlights the substantial influence of catalyst reconstruction under operational conditions and offers insights into designing highly active and stable electrocatalysts towards CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Jiadong Chen, Tingjie Mao, Juan Wang, Jichang Wang, Huile Jin, Shun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reconstruction of Bi 2 Te 4 O 11 Nanorods for Efficient and pH&#8208;universal Electrochemical CO 2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408849</link>
      <description>Jiadong Chen, Tingjie Mao, Juan Wang, Jichang Wang, Lianghao Yu, Shun Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400592992

                The practical application of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is hindered by the competing CO production, hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and the lack of pH&#8208;universal catalysts. Here, Te&#8208;modified Bi nanorods (Te&#8208;Bi NRs) were synthesized through in situ reconstruction of Bi2Te4O11 NRs under the CO2RR condition. Our study illustrates that the complex reconstruction process of Bi2Te4O11 NRs during CO2RR could be decoupled into three distinct steps, i.e., the destruction of Bi2Te4O11, the formation of Te/Bi phases, and the dissolution of Te. The thus&#8208;obtained Te&#8208;Bi NRs exhibit remarkably high performance in CO2RR towards formate production, showing high activity, selectivity, and stability across all pH conditions (acidic, neutral, and alkaline). In a flow cell reactor under neutral, alkaline, or acidic conditions, the catalysts achieved HCOOH Faradaic efficiencies of up to 94.3%, 96.4%, and 91.0%, respectively, at a high current density of 300 mA cm&#8208;2. DFT calculations, along with operando spectral measurements, reveal that Te manipulates the Bi sites to an electron&#8208;deficient state, enhancing the adsorption strength of the *OCHO intermediate, and significantly suppressing the competing HER and CO production. This study highlights the substantial influence of catalyst reconstruction under operational conditions and offers insights into designing highly active and stable electrocatalysts towards CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Jiadong Chen, Tingjie Mao, Juan Wang, Jichang Wang, Lianghao Yu, Shun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the effect of dynamic traffic distribution on network-wide traffic emissions: An empirical study in Ningbo, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0305481</link>
      <description>Shuichao Zhang, Jianan Shi, Yizhe Huang, Hao Shen, He Kangkang, Hongjie Chen, PloS one. 19(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400583330

                Urban road traffic is one of the primary sources of carbon emissions. Previous studies have demonstrated the close relationship between traffic flow characteristics and carbon emissions (CO2). However, the impact of dynamic traffic distribution on carbon emissions is rarely empirically studied on the network level. To fill this gap, this study proposes a dynamic network carbon emissions estimation method. The network-level traffic emissions are estimated by combining macroscopic emission models and recent advances in dynamic network traffic flow modeling, namely, Macroscopic Fundamental Diagram. The impact of traffic distribution and the penetration of battery electric vehicles on total network emissions are further investigated using the Monte Carlo method. The results indicate the substantial effect of network traffic distribution on carbon emissions. Using the urban expressway network in Ningbo as an example, in the scenario of 100% internal combustion engine vehicles, increasing the standard deviation of link-level traffic density from 0 to 15 veh/km-ln can result in an 8.9% network capacity drop and a 15.5% reduction in network carbon emissions. This effect can be moderated as the penetration rate of battery electric vehicles increases. Based on the empirical and simulating evidence, different expressway pollution management strategies can be implemented, such as petrol vehicle restrictions, ramp metering, congestion pricing, and perimeter control strategies.</description>
      <author>Shuichao Zhang, Jianan Shi, Yizhe Huang, Hao Shen, He Kangkang, Hongjie Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0305481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Social Determinants of Household Carbon Emissions for Carbon Mitigation Policies: The Case of Mersin, Turkey</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146012</link>
      <description>Ali Cenap Yolo&#287;lu, Bulent Halisdemir, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400644633

                Households are the main consumer-side source of carbon emissions. In Europe, consumer-based CO2 consumption per capita fell from 10.8 tons to 7.8 tons between 1990 and 2022, but in Turkey, the same data showed a rise from 4 tons to 5 tons. Strategies to reduce carbon emissions have recently shifted their focus from the production side to the consumption side. However, because different social segments have varying levels of price sensitivity and differing levels of necessity regarding consuming different items, a simple tax policy only targeting the consumption side is doomed to fail. This has prompted a discussion of the factors influencing carbon emissions on the consumption side and how those factors affect the amount of emissions. This study aims to identify the social determinants affecting household carbon emission levels and to demonstrate that such differences play an important role in effective and efficient carbon emission reduction strategies. In this case study, an appropriate testing method was used to test whether there are significant differences in dependent variables (carbon emissions) between categories of independent variables (the social determinants of households). As our literature review demonstrates, the social determinants of households and the local context were found to have an impact on carbon emissions in the case study. Nevertheless, we found that the degree of association lessens when the relationship between the dependent variables and the independent variables is re-evaluated while controlling for income level. Consequently, it may be concluded that the primary element influencing carbon emissions is income. In our field study, on the other hand, poverty stood out as another important factor affecting the level of carbon emissions. Poverty affects total household carbon emissions in two different ways, causing both carbon-intensive consumer goods and household appliances with low energy efficiency to be preferred because they are cheap to purchase. Therefore, the fight against poverty should be recognized as an important component of carbon reduction policies in Turkey, and the issue of environmental justice should not be ignored, because we know that 30% of the population was living in poverty (compared to the other 70% receiving the national median income) in 2022.</description>
      <author>Ali Cenap Yolo&#287;lu, Bulent Halisdemir</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Effect of Fly Ash on Mechanical Properties and Seawater Freeze&#8211;Thaw Resistance of Seawater Sea Sand Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14072191</link>
      <description>Jingjing He, Chuanwu Sun, Xuezhi Wang, Buildings. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400676666

                When using seawater and sea sand as mixes, the mechanical properties and durability of concrete are adversely affected because the raw materials themselves contain harmful ions. Fly ash is the tailings formed in the process of industrial production, the use of which does not require the burning of clinker, reducing CO2 emissions. Moreover, it belongs to a new type of cementitious materials with low emissions and high environmental protection. Fly ash enhances the properties of concrete and reduces the effect of harmful ions on concrete. Based on the above considerations, the corresponding specimens were prepared and subjected to cubic compressive strength, flexural strength, and seawater freezing and thawing resistance tests by using fly ash admixture as the main variable. A combination of macro-analysis and micro-analysis was used to investigate the effect of fly ash on the performance of seawater sea sand concrete. The results showed that fly ash significantly enhanced the mechanical properties and resistance to seawater freezing and thawing of seawater sea sand concrete. The best improvement in compressive strength and resistance to seawater freezing and thawing was achieved at a substitution rate of 20%. The maximum increase in compressive strength was 13.22%. The maximum reduction in mass loss rate was 57.26% and the strength loss rate was 43.14% after the specimens were subjected to seawater freezing and thawing 75 times. The maximum enhancement in flexural strength was 17.06% for a substitution rate of 10%. Through microanalysis, it can be seen that the incorporation of coal ash can enhance the compactness of concrete through the microaggregate effect as well as the volcanic ash reaction to promote the secondary hydration reaction, so as to strengthen the seawater freeze&#8211;thaw resistance of seawater sea sand concrete. Finally, the damage prediction model established using the mean GM (1, 1) model of gray system theory meets the requirements of the first level of prediction accuracy and can accurately predict the damage of seawater sea sand concrete under seawater freezing and thawing.</description>
      <author>Jingjing He, Chuanwu Sun, Xuezhi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14072191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight on Secondary Metabolites Produced by an Early-Flowering Apulian Artichoke Ecotype Sanitized from Virus Infection by Meristem-Tip-Culture and Thermotherapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox13070852</link>
      <description>Roberta Span&#242;, Patrizia Gena, V. Linsalata, Valeria Sini, Isabella D&#8217;Antuono, Angela Cardinali, Pietro Cotugno, Giuseppe Calamita, Tiziana Mascia, Antioxidants. 13(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400682113

                Globe artichoke (Cynara cardunculus L. subsp. scolymus) is an important crop of the Mediterranean basin characterized by many properties, like hepatoprotective, anticarcinogenic, antioxidant, antibacterial, and beneficial to human health. The high bioactive compounds (BACs) content, as polyphenols, has attracted the research interest in artichoke extracts. We analysed the changes in polyphenol transcriptome profile between sanitized (S) virus-free and non-sanitized (NS) artichoke plants, focusing on genes involved in phenylpropanoid metabolic pathway and flavonoid biosynthesis. A total of 2458 upregulated and 2154 downregulated differentially expressed genes (DEGs) were functionally characterized. Among them, 31 and 35 KEGG orthology entries characterized by upregulated and downregulated DEGs, respectively, were involved in the biosynthesis of other secondary metabolites. A downregulation of PAL, C4H, 4CL, HST/HQT, C3&#8242;H, CCoAMT, CCR1, and F5H, was observed in S artichoke compared to NS one, whereas the CSE, CHS, and CHI genes were upregulated in S samples. Transcriptome results were compared to the polyphenols accumulation in S and NS artichoke leaves. A higher content of total polyphenols was observed in older leaves of NS samples, compared to extracts obtained from young leaves or from S plants, and this result was associated with the presence of viral infections in NS plants. In all the conditions tested, the most represented compound was chlorogenic acid, followed by luteolin-7-O-glucoside. The different composition of each extract was evaluated by a polyphenol dose&#8211;response treatment on the rodent hepatoma FaO cell line to the accumulation of reactive oxygen species (ROS). A significant reduction in ROS content ranging between &#8722;40% and &#8722;48% was observed when 10&#8211;20 mg/L of polyphenols from NS or S plants were used, characterized by a specific profile of compounds. To reduce MetOH residues in polyphenol extracts, a supercritical fluid CO2 extraction was evaluated to propose a sustainable green extraction.</description>
      <author>Roberta Span&#242;, Patrizia Gena, V. Linsalata, Valeria Sini, Isabella D&#8217;Antuono, Angela Cardinali, Pietro Cotugno, Giuseppe Calamita, Tiziana Mascia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox13070852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOLD ENRICHMENT MECHANISM IN MID-OCEAN RIDGE HYDROTHERMAL SYSTEMS: AN EXAMPLE FROM THE LONGQI HYDROTHERMAL FIELD ON THE ULTRASLOW-SPREADING SOUTHWEST INDIAN RIDGE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5382/econgeo.5095</link>
      <description>Kean Chen, Huichao Zhang, Nigel J. Cook, Tao Wu, Fang An, Jin Liang, Weifang Yang, Economic geology and the bulletin of the Society of Economic Geologists. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400642729

                Abstract In mid-ocean ridge (MOR) hydrothermal systems, the gold grade of sea-floor massive sulfides (SMSs) is negatively correlated with the spreading rate of the ridge. Previous investigations have addressed the distribution of gold in sulfides from hydrothermal fields hosted by ultramafic rocks. In contrast, the gold enrichment mechanisms in sulfides from hydrothermal fields hosted by mafic rocks in ultraslow-spreading ridge environments are less well constrained. The basalt-hosted Longqi hydrothermal field, located on the classic ultraslow-spreading Southwest Indian Ridge, provides an opportunity to examine gold enrichment mechanisms in such an environment. Two ore-forming stages are identified in chimney fragments: anhydrite + barite + colloidal/porous pyrite (Py1) + marcasite + fine-grained sphalerite (stage 1); euhedral-subhedral pyrite (Py2) + coarse-grained sphalerite + chalcopyrite + isocubanite (stage 2). Py1 is usually overgrown by marcasite, which is in turn enclosed by Py2. Py2 coexists with coarse-grained sphalerite and chalcopyrite. Abundant native gold nanoparticles occur in Py1 or at the transition zone between Py1 and Py2. Laser ablation inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (LA-ICP-MS) analysis suggests that Py1 contains higher Mo, V, Sn, and Pb and lower As, Co/Ni, and Se/Tl values compared to Py2. In situ LA-multicollector (MC)-ICP-MS analyses show that Py1 has a higher mean &#948;34S (+7.1&#8240;) value than Py2 (+6.6&#8240;). Sulfur primarily derives from MORB and seawater sulfate, of which the proportion of sulfur from seawater sulfate is between 20.5 and 47.6%. Textures, mineral assemblages, and trace element contents of sulfides indicate that the degree of mixing between hydrothermal fluids and seawater decreases as the chimney grows and is accompanied by a gradual increase in temperature. Based on data compiled from 41 hydrothermal fields hosted by basalt, the large range of sulfide &#948;34S from slow- and ultraslow-spreading MORs may be attributed to the wide range of sulfur sources (e.g., leaching from MOR basalt, thermochemical reduction of seawater sulfate, magma degassing, and bacterial activity), fluid-basalt interaction, and redox state (CH4/CO2 ratios). Prolonged fluid-basalt interaction and the type of chimneys, such as beehive chimneys, may lead to higher gold grades in hydrothermal fields. Moreover, low H2S content may be an important contributor to gold enrichment in basalt-hosted SMS deposits in ultraslow-spreading MOR environments.</description>
      <author>Kean Chen, Huichao Zhang, Nigel J. Cook, Tao Wu, Fang An, Jin Liang, Weifang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5382/econgeo.5095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International convergence towards a climate-neutral economy: modeling the agricultural sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51599/are.2024.10.02.03</link>
      <description>Andriy Krysovatyy, Iryna Maksymova, Vitalina Kuryliak, Michael A. Radin, Maksym Kurilyak, Agricultural and resource economics. 10(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400700094

                Purpose. This article aims to construct a comprehensive convergent model for assessing the global and EU&#8217;s progress, degree of consolidation and symmetry of agricultural economies towards climate neutrality in the context of key international green initiatives. Methodology / approach. This research employs both qualitative and quantitative analyses to assess convergence measures in the agricultural sector&#8217;s carbon emissions. The quantitative component relies on the sigma and beta convergence models to evaluate international convergence in carbon emissions CO2 dynamics. The dimensions of modeling are as follows: global sample within 194 countries with reliable emissions data; European Union, focusing on convergence within the EU27 member states, the United Kingdom, and Ukraine. The time period covers open data from 1972&#8211;2022. The dynamics of sigma and beta convergence is determined for the points, namely UN Stockholm Conference (1972), UN Rio Conference (1992), Kyoto Protocol (entry into force in 2005), Paris Agreement (2015). Additionally, statistical indicators of variation, skewness, Gini and Theil indices were calculated for delineating global smoothness and the concentration of agricultural emissions. Results. The results of the study reveal an inertial and divergent trend of the agricultural economy towards decarbonisation, which slows down the overall movement towards &#8220;net zero&#8221; due to the presence of clubs of lagging agricultural countries that increase emissions in violation of international agreements. The reduction in emissions skewness in recent years shows that more countries are &#8220;pulling&#8221; decarbonisation due to their high capacity to move towards net zero, but this is not enough. The EU is the most prominent example of accelerated climate convergence, but markers of its weakening in recent years are identified due to the inability of economies to maintain the pace of decarbonisation caused by economic constraints, technological barriers, policy and regulatory issues, and misunderstandings of climate neutrality goals. It is shown that the long-term decarbonisation capacity of the agricultural sector is the key trigger for a country to make a positive contribution to the global convergence towards climate neutrality. At the current stage, the pace of decarbonisation plays a much greater role for consolidating efforts in the agricultural economy and achieving climate neutrality than the initial level of emissions in the sector. Factors in this process include proactive compliance with global climate agreements, technology sharing and cooperation, digitalisation and smart agriculture, and green financing and investment. Its implementation requires a three-way integration of stakeholder actions, strategy selection and results evaluation. Originality / scientific novelty. The study&#8217;s originality lies in its large-scale analysis of over 50 years of emissions dynamics and the context of five key green agreements that provided support for the green transition. It allows studying international convergence in agricultural sectors globally and within the EU. The novelty implies the integrated use of sigma and beta convergence models that identifies predictors of convergent and divergent processes and separates countries into leaders and laggards of agricultural decarbonisation. This approach provides a comprehensive view of modern climate policy, the impact of international green initiatives, and the position of individual towards climate neutrality in agriculture. Practical value / implications. The practical value lies in the ability to adjust climate policies for the agricultural economy&#8217;s decarbonisation, facilitating the determination of prospective outcomes for achieving climate neutrality. The aforementioned factors facilitate the process of governmental decision-making. The assessment of international programmatic agreements' effectiveness is enhanced through these models. The study offers a framework for global convergence towards climate neutrality in agriculture, highlighting the importance of digital technologies and smart agriculture as significant factors in global convergence.</description>
      <author>Andriy Krysovatyy, Iryna Maksymova, Vitalina Kuryliak, Michael A. Radin, Maksym Kurilyak</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51599/are.2024.10.02.03</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
