<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 01:26:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) using coal-based nano-carbon materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03407d</link>
      <description>Han-Sheng Luo, Xinjuan Liu, RSC Advances. 14(37)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401915374

                Coal-based carbon materials (CCMs) can function as either standalone catalysts or as components of composite catalysts, making them promising materials for CO 2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Han-Sheng Luo, Xinjuan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03407d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metrics for quantifying the efficiency of atmospheric CO2 reduction by marine carbon dioxide removal (mCDR)"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad7477/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401984994

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad7477/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metrics for quantifying the efficiency of atmospheric CO2 reduction by marine carbon dioxide removal (mCDR)"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad7477/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401984995

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad7477/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metrics for quantifying the efficiency of atmospheric CO2 reduction by marine carbon dioxide removal (mCDR)"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad7477/v1/review4</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401985061

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad7477/v1/review4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Metrics for quantifying the efficiency of atmospheric CO2 reduction by marine carbon dioxide removal (mCDR)"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad7477/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401984935

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad7477/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling key impact parameters and mechanistic insights towards activated biochar performance for carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131355</link>
      <description>Wen Qian Chen, Foo Jit Cyrus Loong, Wen&#8208;Da Oh, Wei Ping Chan, Li Ya Ge, Grzegorz Lisak, Bioresource Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401859355

                Chemically activated biochar is effective in supercapacitors and water splitting, but low conductivity hinders its application as a carbon support in carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO</description>
      <author>Wen Qian Chen, Foo Jit Cyrus Loong, Wen&#8208;Da Oh, Wei Ping Chan, Li Ya Ge, Grzegorz Lisak</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Understanding of CO2 Reduction and Evolution Reaction in Li-CO2 batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02633k</link>
      <description>Lang Zhou, yaohui huang, Yuzhe Wang, Bo Wen, Zhenan Jiang, Fujun Li, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935022

                Rechargeable Li-CO2 batteries have garnered extensive attention due to their high theoretical energy density (1876 W h Kg-1). However, their practical application is hindered by large polarization, low Coulombic efficiency,...</description>
      <author>Lang Zhou, yaohui huang, Yuzhe Wang, Bo Wen, Zhenan Jiang, Fujun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02633k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Impacts of CO2 Reduction and Utilization Technologies on Regional Freshwater Resources</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2433822</link>
      <description>May Wu, Hannah Kim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401854817

                No abstract</description>
      <author>May Wu, Hannah Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2433822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Based Materials for Low Concentration CO2 Capture and Electrocatalytic Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119574</link>
      <description>Yanxi Hu, Yangyang Ding, Lily Y. Xie, Hanyu Li, Yujing Jiang, Ke Gong, Aidi Zhang, Wenlei Zhu, Yuanyuan Wang, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401933113

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanxi Hu, Yangyang Ding, Lily Y. Xie, Hanyu Li, Yujing Jiang, Ke Gong, Aidi Zhang, Wenlei Zhu, Yuanyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dinuclear Iron Porphyrin as a Homogeneous Photocatalyst for Visible Light-Driven Reduction of Co2 to Co</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4937732</link>
      <description>Yaju Chen, Jun Jiang, Lin Lei, Hongbing Ji, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401875611

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaju Chen, Jun Jiang, Lin Lei, Hongbing Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4937732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Phosphorus-doped Cu-based Catalysts by Electrodeposition Modulates *CHxO Adsorption to Facilitate Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO2 to CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124525</link>
      <description>Zhishuncheng Li, Yongheng Yuan, Guangfei Qu, Kaixiong Xiang, Ping Ning, Du Weijun, Keheng Pan, Yingying Cai, Junyan Li, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401862448

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhishuncheng Li, Yongheng Yuan, Guangfei Qu, Kaixiong Xiang, Ping Ning, Du Weijun, Keheng Pan, Yingying Cai, Junyan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Methanol Production Via Co2 Reduction on Cu2o Revealed by Micro-Kinetic Study Combined with Constant Potential Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4937201</link>
      <description>Yifan Sun, Liu&#8208;Bin Zhao, Zhen Liu, Haibo Liu, Li&#8208;Hua Gan, Wei Zhang, Xueliang Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401884592

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifan Sun, Liu&#8208;Bin Zhao, Zhen Liu, Haibo Liu, Li&#8208;Hua Gan, Wei Zhang, Xueliang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4937201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Electron Effects on the Performance of Metal-Coordinated Catalysts for Electrochemical Co2 Reduction: The Influence of Electron-Donating and Withdrawing Group Modifications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4938660</link>
      <description>Jinyang Guo, Qian Zhang, Yudong Xue, Haibo Liu, Jing Wang, Dalei Song, Chunyang Xiong, Rumin Li, Li Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401903886

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinyang Guo, Qian Zhang, Yudong Xue, Haibo Liu, Jing Wang, Dalei Song, Chunyang Xiong, Rumin Li, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4938660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why CO2 Emissions Reductions Does Not Bring Climate Coldening Anymore &#8211; the Effect of Thermally Efficient Motors &#8211; a Study Confirmed by AI</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47485/2766-2624.1055</link>
      <description>, Advances in Earth and Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402051761

                Thermal motor emissions have grown cold and colder over time thanks to the betterment of the yield of motors. This contributes to an inversion of behaviour of CO2, since photosynthesis is endothermic, absorbs heat together with it. New CO2 emissions are coldening the climate where thermal motor efficiency is good. This is confirmed with AI support and shown to explain the late snows this Spring in Europe, as well as the &#8220;La Ni&#241;a&#8221; trend that has been announced. Global warming can be totally reduced and reversed with a consistent pattern of smart CO2 emissions, without the heat associated, thanks to new thermally efficient motors.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47485/2766-2624.1055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Trends in CO2 Electroreduction over Metal-Organic Framework-Derived Materials: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03502j</link>
      <description>Nadia Gholampour, Chizoba I. Ezugwua, Hussein A. Younus, Damien P. Debecker, Mohammed Al&#8208;Abri, Rashid Al&#8208;Hajri, Jimmy Kao, Francis Verpoort, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401865023

                Carbon dioxide reduction through electrochemical energy is an emerging and appealing approach towards CO2 mitigation, and it is a potential technique in which the current and Faradaic efficiencies can be...</description>
      <author>Nadia Gholampour, Chizoba I. Ezugwua, Hussein A. Younus, Damien P. Debecker, Mohammed Al&#8208;Abri, Rashid Al&#8208;Hajri, Jimmy Kao, Francis Verpoort</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03502j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Carbon Assessment of Mortars with Carbonated and Non-Carbonated Recycled Aggregates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14177442</link>
      <description>Catarina Braz&#227;o Farinha, Cinthia Maia Pederneiras, Ricardo Infante Gomes, David Bastos, Ros&#225;rio Veiga, Applied Sciences. 14(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401897908

                Global warming is one of the most important issues that the world is currently facing. The cement industry accounts for around 7% of total global CO2 emissions. According to the 13th United Nations Sustainable Development Goals, cement plants must become carbon neutral by 2050. This neutrality may be achieved by a reduction in CO2 emissions complemented with carbon capture, utilization and storage (CCUS) technologies. In accordance with these sustainable goals, several approaches have been studied. This paper investigates life cycle carbon of mortars produced with carbonated recycled aggregates. In previous works, the carbon dioxide capture capacity of construction and demolition waste (CDW) was analysed, and mortars with CDW recycled aggregates submitted to high levels of CO2 were evaluated in terms of their mechanical performance. This paper focus on the life cycle carbon impact assessment (LCCA) of industrial mortar formulations in a cradle-to-gate boundary. This assessment is carried out through a global warming potential environment impact assessment, since it represents the amount of CO2 equivalent that is sent to the atmosphere and contributes to the &#8220;greenhouse effect&#8221;. This LCCA includes the impacts associated with the treatment and additional transportation routes of the recycled aggregates. With this work, it was found that mortars with carbonated recycled aggregates have a considerably lower global warming potential impact than mortars without recycled aggregates. The mortars with recycled aggregates presented lower CO2 emissions of up to 6.31% for 100% incorporation of non-carbonated recycled aggregates. These values were incremented with the carbonation of the recycled aggregates, achieving a reduction of CO2 emissions of up to 36.75% for 100% of incorporation.</description>
      <author>Catarina Braz&#227;o Farinha, Cinthia Maia Pederneiras, Ricardo Infante Gomes, David Bastos, Ros&#225;rio Veiga</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14177442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the Problem in Controlling the Air&#8211;Fuel Mixture Ratio (Lambda Coefficient &#955;) in Small Spark-Ignition Engines for Positive Pressure Ventilators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174241</link>
      <description>&#321;ukasz Wargu&#322;a, Piotr Kaczmarzyk, Bartosz Wieczorek, &#321;ukasz Gierz, Daniel Ma&#322;ozi&#281;&#263;, Tomasz G&#243;ral, Boris Kostov, Grigor Stambolov, Energies. 17(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401893110

                The air&#8211;fuel ratio is a crucial parameter in internal combustion engines that affects optimal engine performance, emissions, fuel efficiency, engine durability, power, and efficiency. Positive pressure ventilators (PPVs) create specific operating conditions for drive units, characterized by a reduced ambient pressure compared to standard atmospheric pressure, which is used to control carburetor-based fuel supply systems. The impact of these conditions was investigated for four commonly used PPVs (with internal combustion engines) in fire services across the European Union (EU), using a lambda (&#955;), carbon dioxide (CO2), carbon monoxide (CO), and hydrogen carbon (HC) analyser for exhaust gases. All four ventilators were found to operate with lean and very lean mixtures, with their lambda coefficients ranging from 1.6 to 2.2. The conducted tests of the CO2, CO, and HC concentrations in the exhaust gases of all four fans show dependencies consistent with theoretical analyses of the impact of the fuel&#8211;air mixture on emissions. It can be observed that as the amount of burned air decreases, the values of CO and HC decrease, while the concentration of CO2 increases with the increase in engine load. Such an operation can accelerate engine wear, increase the emission of harmful exhaust gases, and reduce the effective performance of the device. This condition is attributed to an inadequate design process, where drive units are typically designed to operate within atmospheric pressure conditions, as is common for these engines. However, when operating with a PPV, the fan&#8217;s rotor induces significant air movement, leading to a reduction in ambient pressure on the intake side where the engine is located, thereby disrupting its proper operation.</description>
      <author>&#321;ukasz Wargu&#322;a, Piotr Kaczmarzyk, Bartosz Wieczorek, &#321;ukasz Gierz, Daniel Ma&#322;ozi&#281;&#263;, Tomasz G&#243;ral, Boris Kostov, Grigor Stambolov</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of the European Union emissions trading system on carbon dioxide emissions: a matrix completion analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-70260-6</link>
      <description>Francesco Biancalani, Giorgio Gnecco, Rodolfo Metulini, Massimo Riccaboni, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401850351

                Despite the negative externalities on the environment and human health, today's economies still produce excessive carbon dioxide emissions. As a result, governments are trying to shift production and consumption to more sustainable models that reduce the environmental impact of carbon dioxide emissions. The European Union, in particular, has implemented an innovative policy to reduce carbon dioxide emissions by creating a market for emission rights, the emissions trading system. The objective of this paper is to perform a counterfactual analysis to measure the impact of the emissions trading system on the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions. For this purpose, a recently-developed statistical machine learning method called matrix completion with fixed effects estimation is used and compared to traditional econometric techniques. We apply matrix completion with fixed effects estimation to the prediction of missing counterfactual entries of a carbon dioxide emissions matrix whose elements (indexed row-wise by country and column-wise by year) represent emissions without the emissions trading system for country-year pairs. The results obtained, confirmed by robust diagnostic tests, show a significant effect of the emissions trading system on the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions: the majority of European Union countries included in our analysis reduced their total carbon dioxide emissions (associated with selected industries) by about 15.4% during the emissions trading system treatment period 2005&#8211;2020, compared to the total carbon dioxide emissions (associated with the same industries) that would have been achieved in the absence of the emissions trading system policy. Finally, several managerial/practical implications of the study are discussed, together with its possible extensions.</description>
      <author>Francesco Biancalani, Giorgio Gnecco, Rodolfo Metulini, Massimo Riccaboni</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-70260-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison Study of Cascaded Organic Rankine Cycles with Single and Dual Working Fluids for Waste Heat Recovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15377/2409-5826.2024.11.1</link>
      <description>Gerutu Bosinge Gerutu, Yossapong Laoonual, Journal of Advanced Thermal Science Research. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401872871

                This study compares thermodynamics, economics, and environmental performance of cascaded ORCs operated under a single and dual fluids. In the single fluid cascaded ORC, toluene, benzene, acetone and cyclopentane are run in high and low temperature cycles, whereas in dual fluid cascaded ORC, toluene, benzene, acetone and cyclopentane are run in high temperature cycle and R601a in the low temperature cycle. The analysis compares variations in expander inlet temperature and condensation temperature. Thermodynamic performance involved net power output (Pnet) and thermal efficiency (&#951;th), while economic indicators included net present value (NPV) and levelized cost of electricity (LCOE). In environmental performance, the annual reduction in carbon dioxide emission (CO2-eq) is assessed. The findings revealed that dual fluid cascaded ORC generated the highest Pnet of 1245.11 kW while single fluid cascaded ORC reached 1170.27 kW. The dual fluid cascaded ORC showed the significant increase in Pnet (%DPnet) for about 43% at the lowest expander inlet temperature (500 K). In terms of &#951;th, dual fluid cascaded ORC attained 37.23 % while single fluid cascaded ORC reached 33.25%. It is further found that acetone+R601a performed well in dual fluid cascaded ORC, resulting in the highest Pnet and allowing system&#8217;s NPV to turn positive sooner than other fluids. Furthermore, cyclopentane+R601a had the lowest LCOE of 0.0158 US$/kWh, which is 1.1% lower compared to the single fluid cascaded ORC and competitive in the Thai electricity market. In environmental saving, dual fluid cascaded ORC reduced about 144.96 tCO2-eq/year, and outperformed single fluid cascaded ORC by roughly 6.39%.</description>
      <author>Gerutu Bosinge Gerutu, Yossapong Laoonual</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15377/2409-5826.2024.11.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-thermal plasma-catalytic processes for CO2 conversion toward circular economy: fundamentals, current status, and future challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-34751-3</link>
      <description>Ahmad Mukhtar, Sidra Saqib, Dinithi Mohotti, Robinson Ndeddy Aka, Md. Mokter Hossain, Ekow Agyekum-Oduro, Sarah Wu, Environmental Science and Pollution Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401843849

                Abstract Practical and energy-efficient carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) conversion to value-added and fuel-graded products and transitioning from fossil fuels are promising ways to cope with climate change and to enable the circular economy. The carbon circular economy aims to capture, utilize, and minimize CO 2 emissions as much as possible. To cope with the thermodynamic stability and highly endothermic nature of CO 2 conversion via conventional thermochemical process, the potential application of non-thermal plasma (NTP) with the catalyst, i.e., the hybrid plasma catalysis process to achieve the synergistic effects, in most cases, seems to promise alternatives under non-equilibrium conditions. This review focuses on the NTP fundamentals and comparison with conventional technologies. A critical review has been conducted on the CO 2 reduction with water (H 2 O), methane (CH 4 ) reduction with CO 2 to syngas (CO + H 2 ), CO 2 dissociation to carbon monoxide (CO), CO 2 hydrogenation, CO 2 conversion to organic acids, and one-step CO 2 &#8211;CH 4 reforming to the liquid chemicals. Finally, future challenges are discussed comprehensively, indicating that plasma catalysis has immense investigative areas.</description>
      <author>Ahmad Mukhtar, Sidra Saqib, Dinithi Mohotti, Robinson Ndeddy Aka, Md. Mokter Hossain, Ekow Agyekum-Oduro, Sarah Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-34751-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser-Assisted Preparation of TiO2/Carbon/Ag Nanocomposite for Degradation of Organic Pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17164118</link>
      <description>S.A.R Tabatabaee Nezhad, Babak Jaleh, Elham Darabi, Davoud Dorranian, Materials. 17(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401856260

                The ever-increasing expansion of chemical industries produces a variety of common pollutants, including colors, which become a global and environmental problem. Using a nanocatalyst is one of the effective ways to reduce these organic contaminants. With this in mind, a straightforward and effective method for the production of a novel nanocatalyst based on lignin-derived carbon, titanium dioxide nanoparticles, and Ag particles (TiO2/C/Ag) is described. The preparation of carbon and Ag particles (in sub-micro and nano size) was carried out by laser ablation in air. The nanocomposite was synthesized using a facile magnetic stirrer of TiO2, C, and Ag. According to characterization methods, a carbon nanostructure was successfully synthesized through the laser irradiation of lignin. According to scanning electron microscope images, spherical Ag particles were agglomerated over the nanocomposite. The catalytic activities of the TiO2/C/Ag nanocomposite were tested for the decolorization of methylene blue (MB) and Congo red (CR), employing NaBH4 in a water-based solution at 25 &#176;C. After adding fresh NaBH4 to the mixture of nanocomposite and dyes, both UV absorption peaks of MB and CR completely disappeared after 10 s and 4 min, respectively. The catalytic activity of the TiO2/C/Ag nanocomposite was also examined for the reduction of 4-nitrophenol (4-NP) using a NaBH4 reducing agent, suggesting the complete reduction of 4-NP to 4-aminophenol (4-AP) after 2.30 min. This shows excellent catalytic behavior of the prepared nanocomposite in the reduction of organic pollutants.</description>
      <author>S.A.R Tabatabaee Nezhad, Babak Jaleh, Elham Darabi, Davoud Dorranian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17164118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Mechanism of Converting CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; into Methanol by the Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O and Oxygen Vacancy on MgO: Experiments and Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09920</link>
      <description>Yayu Chen, Ting Li, Hongxia Guo, Xiao Wang, Wenquan Cui, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401873030

                Given the great significance of defect and Cu compounds for the reduction of CO2 as well as the few reaction mechanisms of converting CO2 into different hydrocarbons, the effects of oxygen vacancies and Cu2O on the reduction of CO2 were thoroughly investigated, and possible mechanisms were also proposed. A series of Cu2O/Ov-MgO catalysts were synthesized for photothermal catalytic reduction of CO2 to methanol under visible-light irradiation, among which the 7%Cu2O/Ov-MgO composite exhibited the best reduction activity and the yield of methanol was 19.78 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8211;1&#183;h&#8211;1. The successful composite of Cu2O and Ov-MgO can yield a loose and porous nanosheet, uniform distribution, favorable absorbance and photoelectric performance, and increased specific surface area and adsorption ability of CO2, which are all vital to the adsorption and conversion of CO2. The introduction of oxygen vacancy and Cu2O not only promotes the adsorption of CO2 but also provides more electron-triggered CO2 activation. Density functional theory (DFT) calculation was also performed to reveal the reaction mechanism for effective enhanced CO2 reduction to ethanol or methanol by the comparison of CuO/MgO and Cu2O/Ov-MgO composites, illustrating the reaction pathways of different products. By comparing the key steps in determining the selectivity of C1 or C2, the kinetic barriers of obtaining CH3OH for the Cu2O/Ov-MgO composite with CH3OH as the main product were found to be lower than those of generating CH2*, while the opposite is true for CuO/MgO composites, whereby it may be easier to obtain more C2 products. These insights into the reaction mechanism of converting CO2 into different hydrocarbons are expected to provide guidance for the further design of high-performance photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yayu Chen, Ting Li, Hongxia Guo, Xiao Wang, Wenquan Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09920</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence-Based Performance Maps for Expander-Compressor Analysis in Energy Transition Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/gt2024-128901</link>
      <description>Fabrizio Lottini, Marco Bicchi, Andrea Agnolucci, Michele Marconcini, Andrea Arnone, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401941105

                Abstract Limiting the global warming impact requires a drastic reduction of greenhouse gas emissions (GHG) to reach a zero-carbon growth by 2050. Against this backdrop, turbomachinery designers are asked to develop more compact, efficient, and reliable machines. The research focuses on developing machines able to reduce energy losses and overall footprint, thus improving power plants efficiency and operability. To this end, expander-compressors (EC) seem to play a key role in the energy transition and appear a promising technology for high-density plants, especially together with hydrogen (H2) or supercritical carbon dioxide (sCO2) as working fluid. However, when operating conditions changes, a reduction in machine efficiency may be expected, with a consequent degradation of the overall system performance. In order to optimize the operation of the power plant, it is crucial to understand how the variation of the expander-compressor behavior affects the working conditions of the other components of the plant. In this perspective, a fast and reliable way to estimate the EC performance at different operating conditions is necessary. Although the scientific literature shows several studies on mean-line approaches for expanders and centrifugal compressors, the joint use of 1D models with artificial neural networks (ANN) for ECs combined machine is still overlooked. To fill this gap, the prediction of artificial intelligence (AI)-based performance maps is proposed in this work. The tool has been tested in a case study based on a real EC. Results showed a rapid evaluation of EC efficiency while varying the operating conditions.</description>
      <author>Fabrizio Lottini, Marco Bicchi, Andrea Agnolucci, Michele Marconcini, Andrea Arnone</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/gt2024-128901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lubricity of Gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11249-024-01911-y</link>
      <description>Jie Zhang, Janet S. S. Wong, H. A. Spikes, Tribology Letters. 72(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401944858

                Abstract A sealed reciprocating tribometer has been used to study the influence of different gaseous environments on the friction and wear properties of AISI52100 bearing steel at atmospheric pressure and 25 &#176;C. Helium, argon, hydrogen, carbon dioxide and nitrogen all give high friction and wear, suggestive of very little, if any tribofilm formation under the conditions studied. Dry air and oxygen also give high friction, slightly lower than the inert gases, but produce extremely high wear, much higher than the inert gases. This is characteristic of the phenomenon of &#8220;oxidational wear&#8221;. The two gases ammonia and carbon monoxide give relatively low friction and wear, and XPS analysis indicates that this is due to the formation of adsorbed ammonia/nitride and carbonate films respectively. For the hydrocarbon gases studied, two factors appear to control friction and wear, degree of unsaturation and molecular weight. For the saturated hydrocarbons, methane and ethane give high friction and wear but propane and butane give low friction after a period of rubbing that decreases with molecular weight. The unsaturated hydrocarbons all give an immediate reduction in friction with correspondingly low wear. Raman analysis shows that all the hydrocarbons that reduce friction and wear form a carbonaceous tribofilm on the rubbed surfaces. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Zhang, Janet S. S. Wong, H. A. Spikes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11249-024-01911-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rutile-Type Co&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Ti&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;NbO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Cathode with In Situ Exsolved Metal Particles for Direct CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11593</link>
      <description>Wenji Ruan, Xiaojing Liu, Jiupai Ni, Chengsheng Ni, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401844254

                Rutile-type Co0.5Ti0.5NbO4 (CTO)-based materials doped with Fe3+ or Ni2+ were investigated as cathode electrodes to modify their electrical conductivity and electrocatalysis toward CO2 splitting. Higher electric conductivity was found in Co0.4Fe0.2Ti0.4NbO4 (CTO-Fe, 0.78 S cm&#8211;1) and Co0.25Ni0.25Ti0.5NbO4 (CTO-Ni, 2.10 S cm&#8211;1) compared to CTO (0.49 S cm&#8211;1) after the reduction at 800 &#176;C in Ar-5% H2. Co and Co&#8211;Ni particles exsolved in situ from the surface of CTO, CTO-Fe, and CTO-Ni after reduction. CTO-Ni and CTO-Fe cathodes did better in the CO2 electrolysis at 800 &#176;C than the CTO one, but the CTO-Ni cell was unstable after 10 h of operation due to the carbon deposition that blocked the electrode. The cell with CTO-Fe demonstrated a good stability for CO2 splitting in 100 h. This work demonstrates that rutile-type CTO-based cathodes are promising to provide an efficient and candidate oxide cathode for the electrolysis of CO2.</description>
      <author>Wenji Ruan, Xiaojing Liu, Jiupai Ni, Chengsheng Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Dynamic Change and Driving Force of Vegetation Carbon Sink in Taihang Mountain, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/land13091348</link>
      <description>Qiushi Qu, Jian Sun, Anguo Chen, Chiwei Xiao, Land. 13(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401893496

                Vegetation plays an important role in absorbing carbon dioxide and accelerating the achievement of carbon neutrality. As the ecological barrier of North China, the Taihang Mountains are pivotal to the ecological construction project of China. Nevertheless, the dynamic development of the vegetation carbon sink in the region and the impact factors on the sink have not been systematically evaluated. This study employed a comprehensive approach, utilising remote sensing technology and meteorological and topographic data, in conjunction with the net ecosystem productivity (NEP) estimation model to reveal the characteristics of vegetation carbon sinks in the Taihang Mountain, and then revealed the dynamics evolution of the NEP and the inter-annual trend by using Theil&#8211;Sen Median slope estimation, the Mann&#8211;Kendall test, and the coefficient of dissociation and analysed the driving roles of the influencing factors by using the parameter optimal geographic detector. Our findings suggest that the NEP in the Taihang Mountain area has a clear growth trend in time, the average value of NEP in the Taihang Mountain area is 289 gC-m&#8722;2-a&#8722;1 from 2000 to 2022, and the spatial distribution shows the characteristics of high in the northeast and low in the middle and west, with a gradual increase from the northeast to the southwest; the areas with high fluctuation of NEP are mainly distributed in the areas around some cities that are susceptible to the interference of natural or anthropogenic factors. The vegetation carbon sinks in the Taihang Mountains are influenced by a variety of natural factors, among which the explanatory power of each natural factor is as follows: DEM (0.174) &gt; temperature (0.148) &gt; precipitation (0.026) &gt; slope (0.017) &gt; slope direction (0.003). The natural factor DEM had the strongest explanatory power for NEP changes, and the two-by-two effects of the natural factors on vegetation carbon sinks were all significantly stronger than the effects of a single factor, in which the interaction between DEM and precipitation had the strongest explanatory power; distinguishing from climate change factors, the contribution of anthropogenic activities to NEP changes in more than 90% of the area of the Taihang Mountainous Region was more than 60%, and the driving force of anthropogenic factors on NEP changes in the Taihang Mountainous Region was significantly stronger than that of natural climate change. The contribution of anthropogenic factors to NEP changes in the Taihang Mountains was significantly stronger than that of natural climate change. The results of this study can not only provide a reference for carbon reduction and sink increase and ecological restoration projects in the Taihang Mountains but also benefit the research paradigm of vegetation carbon sequestration in other regions.</description>
      <author>Qiushi Qu, Jian Sun, Anguo Chen, Chiwei Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/land13091348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Gas-Assisted NO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Abatement Using Chemical Looping Scheme</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01843</link>
      <description>Pinak Mohapatra, Sonu Kumar, Ashin A. Sunny, M. Marx, Yehia Khalifa, Amanda H. Trout, Liang&#8208;Shih Fan, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401976157

                In this study, we explore a novel approach to nitrogen oxide (NOx) purification based on the principles of the chemical looping (CL) platform. This technique harnesses the reducing power of natural gas (CH4), instead of ammonia, to eliminate NOx in the flue gas, addressing environmental concerns such as ammonia slip in the state-of-the-art selective catalytic reduction process. The CL scheme involves utilizing nickel oxide (NiO) as the solid oxygen carrier to facilitate oxygen transfer from NOx to CH4 in two steps. In the first step (carrier oxidation), NOx in the flue gas reacts with reduced nickel (Ni), transferring its [O] to the carrier, thereby forming NiO. In the subsequent step (carrier reduction), CH4 reacts with the lattice oxygen of the oxidized carrier, generating a pure stream of CO2 and reducing NiO to Ni. We designed a high-performance carrier by dispersing NiO on an inert support to enhance the carrier's kinetics and thermal stability. We evaluated various support materials, and among them, alumina (Al2O3) and zirconia (ZrO2) demonstrated significantly superior reactivity. Notably, the Al2O3-supported carrier outperformed the ZrO2-supported carrier in NO purification and CH4 reduction and demonstrated stable performance over 10 redox cycles. Furthermore, fixed-bed experiments revealed 100% NO conversion during carrier oxidation, with optimal reaction kinetics achieved at lower space velocities, resulting in an overall high carrier utilization. Importantly, CO2 showcased no adverse effects during the NOx purification step. During the carrier reduction, complete combustion was favored, leading to CH4 conversion exceeding 95% and a CO2 selectivity of 90% at 400 &#176;C. The CL NOx purification approach represents a promising strategy for mitigating NOx emissions.</description>
      <author>Pinak Mohapatra, Sonu Kumar, Ashin A. Sunny, M. Marx, Yehia Khalifa, Amanda H. Trout, Liang&#8208;Shih Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Pressure Heliox-based Rebreather System to Reduce Work of Breathing and Conserve Gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4187/respcare.12184</link>
      <description>Sairam Parthasarathy, Christopher J. Morton, Respiratory Care. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401908687

                Background: To test the ability of a low-pressure, low-flow, Heliox-based rebreathing system to reduce work of breathing and conserve gas while preserving CO2 concentration, temperature, and humidity at physiological levels in a bench study. Methods: We performed a bench study of a novel low-pressure, low-flow, noninvasive Heliox rebreathing system with CO2 scrubber that was connected to an artificial lung simulator with careful monitoring of flow, pressure, work of breathing, oxygen (O2), carbon-dioxide (CO2), temperature, and humidity levels. Multiple runs of breathing were performed while manipulating levels of resistance (5 &#8211; 30 cm H2O/L/sec), gas mixtures (room air, 79% Helium 21% O2, and 70% Helium and 30% O2), and leak levels (ultra-low, low, and high). Results: We found significant reductions in work of breathing (up to 64%) while conserving gas with estimates of up to 54-fold reduction in medical gas wastage (P&lt;0.001). Specifically, at resistances of 5, 10, 20, and 30 cm H2O/L/sec we demonstrated 64%, 57%, 36%, and 7% reduction in work of breathing (P&lt;0.0001). Gas wastage was reduced by 10- to 54-fold while the end-tidal CO2 concentration, humidity, and temperature were maintained by the device at physiological levels. Conclusions: In a bench-test, a low-pressure, low-flow, noninvasive Heliox rebreathing system with CO2 scrubber reduced work of breathing and conserved gas while preserving CO2 concentration, temperature, and humidity at physiological levels. Future studies in human subjects need to be performed to determine whether reduction of work of breathing and gas conservation can be achieved.</description>
      <author>Sairam Parthasarathy, Christopher J. Morton</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4187/respcare.12184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic and Environmental Analyses of an Integrated Power and Hydrogen Production Systems Based on Solar Thermal Energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174264</link>
      <description>Zarif Aminov, Khusniddin Alikulov, Tran Dang Xuan, Energies. 17(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401895079

                This study introduces a novel hybrid solar&#8211;biomass cogeneration power plant that efficiently produces heat, electricity, carbon dioxide, and hydrogen using concentrated solar power and syngas from cotton stalk biomass. Detailed exergy-based thermodynamic, economic, and environmental analyses demonstrate that the optimized system achieves an exergy efficiency of 48.67% and an exergoeconomic factor of 80.65% and produces 51.5 MW of electricity, 23.3 MW of heat, and 8334.4 kg/h of hydrogen from 87,156.4 kg/h of biomass. The study explores four scenarios for green hydrogen production pathways, including chemical looping reforming and supercritical water gasification, highlighting significant improvements in levelized costs and the environmental impact compared with other solar-based hybrid systems. Systems 2 and 3 exhibit superior performance, with levelized costs of electricity (LCOE) of 49.2 USD/MWh and 55.4 USD/MWh and levelized costs of hydrogen (LCOH) of between 10.7 and 19.5 USD/MWh. The exergoenvironmental impact factor ranges from 66.2% to 73.9%, with an environmental impact rate of 5.4&#8211;7.1 Pts/MWh. Despite high irreversibility challenges, the integration of solar energy significantly enhances the system&#8217;s exergoeconomic and exergoenvironmental performance, making it a promising alternative as fossil fuel reserves decline. To improve competitiveness, addressing process efficiency and cost reduction in solar concentrators and receivers is crucial.</description>
      <author>Zarif Aminov, Khusniddin Alikulov, Tran Dang Xuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Maize Yield Variability under Climate Change Using DSSAT Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/jsrr/2024/v30i92333</link>
      <description>Sanjay Koushal, G. Rajesh, J. B. Kambale, Hridesh Harsha Sarma, Bhim Pratap Singh, S P Sharan, Okram Ricky Devi, Bibek Laishram, Journal of Scientific Research and Reports. 30(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401845087

                Crop production is inherently sensitive to variability in climate. Temperature and CO2 are two important parameters related to climate change, affecting crop yield in a particular region. In this study, an attempt has been made to assess the impact of these two parameters on the productivity of maize crop taking sub tropical region of Jammu as study area. A CERES-Maize model 4.0 was used for this purpose. Three-year weather data (2004-06) is used to simulate the actual yield under rainfed and irrigated conditions. Yield was simulated with elevated temperature (1, 3 and 5oC) and CO2 (440, 550 and 660 ppm) during the growing season. As changes in CO2 concentration and temperature likely to occur concomitantly, so growth and development of maize plant at three temperature regimes (1, 3 and 5oC) under double (660 ppm) CO2 concentration to the baseline (330 ppm) was also assessed. The difference in yield, biomass, grain number and LAI was estimated and analyzed to assess the effect of elevated temperature and CO2. Results revealed that the rise in temperature accelerated plant phenology, reducing dry matter accumulation and crop yield by 5 to 60 per cent. Elevation of CO2 in the level of 440, 550 and 660 ppm showed gradual yield increment of 2.01, 3.92 and 5.37 per cent under rainfed conditions and 2.33, 4.52 and 7.41 per cent under irrigated conditions, respectively. Doubled CO2 increased yield at all the temperature rise situation and completely mitigated the yield and biomass reduction due to temperature rise up to 1oC.</description>
      <author>Sanjay Koushal, G. Rajesh, J. B. Kambale, Hridesh Harsha Sarma, Bhim Pratap Singh, S P Sharan, Okram Ricky Devi, Bibek Laishram</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.9734/jsrr/2024/v30i92333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composite nanocapsules of phase change materials using a supercritical carbon dioxide (&lt;scp&gt;SC&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;&lt;scp&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt;) assisted process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjce.25472</link>
      <description>Ida Palazzo, Gianluca Viscusi, Giuliana Gorrasi, Ernesto Reverchon, The Canadian Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401969605

                Abstract This work reports the production of polymeric nanocapsules of polymethyl methacrylate (PMMA)/phase change materials (PCM), using continuous supercritical emulsion extraction (SEE&#8208;C). Five fatty acids (FAs) were tested: capric (CA), lauric (LA), myristic (MA), palmitic (PA), and stearic (SA) acid, using supercritical carbon dioxide (SC&#8208;CO 2 ) operating at 80 bar and 38&#176;C in a tower apparatus. The two fatty acids with lower molecular weight (CA and LA) were extracted by the supercritical solvent and capsules were not obtained. The other three FAs formed spherical, non&#8208;coalescing nanocapsules characterized by mean diameters ranging between 134 and 252 nm, as shown by scanning electron microscope (SEM) images and dynamic light scattering (DLS) analysis, with a sharp particles size distribution and encapsulation efficiencies up to 99.8%. Differential scanning calorimetric analysis (DSC), thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) and derivative thermogravimetric analysis (DTG) analyses confirmed the successful encapsulation, allowing the measurement of the energy storage properties of produced capsules. Stability analysis performed over 5 months showed that the nanocapsules were stable in this time interval. Thermal cycles experiments confirmed the thermal stability of the capsules. The best performance was obtained for PA based nanocapsules, which showed a stability reduction of only 0.43% after 25 thermal cycles.</description>
      <author>Ida Palazzo, Gianluca Viscusi, Giuliana Gorrasi, Ernesto Reverchon</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjce.25472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging electrochemical double layer structure to rationally control electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwae299</link>
      <description>Gong Zhang, Marcel Schreier, National Science Review. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401857577

                This perspective delves into the electrochemical microenvironment, uncovering entropic effects in CO2 reduction, revealing neutral molecule electrosorption under polarization, highlighting challenges in the classical double layer model, and proposing research approaches for future interface studies.</description>
      <author>Gong Zhang, Marcel Schreier</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwae299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Pressure on the Gas Diffusion Electrodes during CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02212</link>
      <description>Yi Chen, Tengfei Ma, Feng Wang, Ya Liu, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401842805

                Electrocatalytic conversion of CO2 is a promising process to produce renewable chemical feedstocks, such as CO, formic acid, ethylene, and ethanol. To overcome mass transfer limitations imposed by the low solubility of CO2 in the liquid phase, gas diffusion electrodes (GDEs) are used to ensure an adequate supply of CO2. The gas&#8211;liquid interface within the GDEs is crucial for achieving high selectivity and stability of CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), but it is prone to flooding, which can terminate the reactions. Here, we built electrochemical models of silver-based and copper-based GDEs for studying intrinsic factors related to flooding. Our results reveal that there is a narrow "pressure window" for CO2RR, which has a negative correlation with current density. We further define three regions based on the "pressure window": the bubbling zone, the normal working condition zone, and the permeable zone. Our research shows that the bubbling zone offers better selectivity for gaseous products, while the permeable zone favors the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction. Furthermore, electrochemical characterization testing investigated the characteristics of each zone and its impact on CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Yi Chen, Tengfei Ma, Feng Wang, Ya Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in Methane Dry Reforming: Investigating Nickel&#8211;Zeolite Catalysts Enhanced by Promoter Integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091826</link>
      <description>Anis H. Fakeeha, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Ahmed I. Osman, Ahmed E. Abasaeed, Yousef Mohammed Alanazi, Fahad S. Al&#8208;Mubaddel, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh, Processes. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401958087

                A promising method for converting greenhouse gases such as CO2 and CH4 into useful syngas is the dry reformation of methane (DRM). 5Ni-ZSM-5 and 2 wt.% Ce, Cs, Sr, Fe, and Cu-promoted 5Ni-ZSM-5 catalysts are investigated for the DRM at 700 &#176;C under atmospheric pressure. The characterization, including XRD, TPR, TPD, TPO, N2 adsorption&#8211;desorption, TGA, TEM, and Raman spectroscopy, revealed that the catalyst&#8217;s active sites are distributed throughout the pore channels and on the surface, contributing to the stability of the catalyst. Specifically, the CO2-TPO followed by the O2-TPO experiment using spent catalysts confirmed the oxidizing capacity of CO2 during the DRM reaction. The Ce-promoted catalyst showed the greatest increase in catalytic activity among other catalysts. The 5Ni+2Ce-ZSM-5 catalyst exhibited twice the concentration of acid sites compared to the Cs-promoted counterpart, even though both catalysts achieved similar quantities of active and basic sites. Without compromising H2 and CO selectivity, this finding underscores the crucial role of acid sites in enhancing CH4 and CO2 conversion. With a GHSV of 42,000 mL/(h.gcat), the 5Ni+2Ce-ZSM-5 catalyst demonstrated impressive CH4 conversion rates of 42% at 700 &#176;C and 70% at 800 &#176;C. The reactants spend more time over catalysts during the subsequent reduction of GHSV to 21,000 mL/(h.gcat), resulting in the best catalytic performance with 80% CH4 and 83% CO2 conversions.</description>
      <author>Anis H. Fakeeha, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Ahmed I. Osman, Ahmed E. Abasaeed, Yousef Mohammed Alanazi, Fahad S. Al&#8208;Mubaddel, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reply on RC2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-748-ac3</link>
      <description>Stephen E. Schwartz, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401915683

                Abstract. The rate at which atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) would decrease in response to decrease of anthropogenic emissions or cessation (net zero emissions) is of great scientific and societal interest. Such decrease in atmospheric CO2 on the centennial scale would be due essentially entirely to transfer of carbon into the world ocean (WO) and the terrestrial biosphere (TB), which are sink compartments on this time scale. The rate of decrease of excess atmospheric CO2 and the apportionment of this decrease into the two sink compartments has been examined in two prior model intercomparison studies, subsequent either to a pulse emission of CO2 or to abrupt cessation of anthropogenic CO2 emissions. The present study examines and quantifies inter-model anticorrelation in those studies in the net rate and extent of uptake of CO2 into the two sink compartments. Specifically, in each study the time-dependent coefficients characterizing the net transfer rate into the two sink compartments, (evaluated as the net transfer rate normalized to excess atmospheric CO2 above pre-pulse amount, for the pulse experiment; or as the net transfer rate divided by excess atmospheric CO2 above preindustrial amount, for the abrupt cessation experiment) was found to exhibit strong anticorrelation across the participating models. That is, models for which the normalized rate of uptake into the WO was high exhibited low uptake rate into the TB, and vice versa. This anticorrelation in net transfer rate results in anticorrelation in net uptake extent into the two compartments that is substantially greater than would be expected simply from competition for excess CO2 between the two sink compartments. This anticorrelation, which is manifested in diminished inter-model diversity, can lead to artificially enhanced confidence in current understanding of the consequences of potential future reductions of CO2 emissions and in the global warming potentials of non-CO2 greenhouse gases relative to that of CO2.</description>
      <author>Stephen E. Schwartz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-748-ac3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reply on RC1</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-748-ac2</link>
      <description>Stephen E. Schwartz, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401915325

                Abstract. The rate at which atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) would decrease in response to decrease of anthropogenic emissions or cessation (net zero emissions) is of great scientific and societal interest. Such decrease in atmospheric CO2 on the centennial scale would be due essentially entirely to transfer of carbon into the world ocean (WO) and the terrestrial biosphere (TB), which are sink compartments on this time scale. The rate of decrease of excess atmospheric CO2 and the apportionment of this decrease into the two sink compartments has been examined in two prior model intercomparison studies, subsequent either to a pulse emission of CO2 or to abrupt cessation of anthropogenic CO2 emissions. The present study examines and quantifies inter-model anticorrelation in those studies in the net rate and extent of uptake of CO2 into the two sink compartments. Specifically, in each study the time-dependent coefficients characterizing the net transfer rate into the two sink compartments, (evaluated as the net transfer rate normalized to excess atmospheric CO2 above pre-pulse amount, for the pulse experiment; or as the net transfer rate divided by excess atmospheric CO2 above preindustrial amount, for the abrupt cessation experiment) was found to exhibit strong anticorrelation across the participating models. That is, models for which the normalized rate of uptake into the WO was high exhibited low uptake rate into the TB, and vice versa. This anticorrelation in net transfer rate results in anticorrelation in net uptake extent into the two compartments that is substantially greater than would be expected simply from competition for excess CO2 between the two sink compartments. This anticorrelation, which is manifested in diminished inter-model diversity, can lead to artificially enhanced confidence in current understanding of the consequences of potential future reductions of CO2 emissions and in the global warming potentials of non-CO2 greenhouse gases relative to that of CO2.</description>
      <author>Stephen E. Schwartz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-748-ac2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Urea Production over Diatomic Fe&#8211;Ni Catalyst: a Mechanism for C&#8211;N Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09346</link>
      <description>Zengying Ma, Xueqian Xia, Bowen Song, Renjie Li, Xiufeng Wang, Yucheng Huang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401843372

                Co-electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 and nitrate/nitrite as carbon and nitrogen sources to synthesize urea is an effective strategy to solve the energy problem and alleviate environmental pollution. In this work, combined density functional theory calculations with a constant-potential implicit solvent model, we proposed a strategy for the determination of the preferred reaction pathway and the potential window that is guided by the potential-dependent free energy change. It was found that on the FeNi-N6-C surface, the C&#8211;N coupling occurs between *NHO and the protonated CO2 in the potential window of &#8722;2.43 to &#8722;1.34 V for the urea electrochemical production, where the predicted onset potential accords well with the experimental results. The activity originates from the less weak bonding strength of N&#8211;O and the negatively charged N atom in *NHO. This study offers a general approach to determining the optimal reaction pathway in electrochemistry and insights into the mechanism of electrochemical synthesis of urea.</description>
      <author>Zengying Ma, Xueqian Xia, Bowen Song, Renjie Li, Xiufeng Wang, Yucheng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Environmental Sustainability: The Role of Renewable Energy Systems and Environmental Taxes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14167404</link>
      <description>Yugang He, Applied Sciences. 14(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401888867

                This study examines the effects of renewable energy consumption and environmental taxes on CO2 emissions in OECD countries from 1990 to 2022, employing the cross-sectional autoregressive distributed lag (CS-ARDL) approach. The findings reveal that both renewable energy consumption and environmental taxes significantly reduce CO2 emissions in both the short and the long term, emphasizing their crucial roles in climate change mitigation and sustainability promotion. Furthermore, this study identifies that industrialization and urbanization contribute to increased emissions, whereas foreign direct investment aids in emission reduction through the facilitation of green technology transfer. Economic growth is initially associated with higher emissions, but this trend reverses as economies mature and adopt sustainable practices. These results highlight the importance of continuous investment in renewable energy infrastructure and the implementation of robust environmental tax policies to achieve long-term sustainability goals. The integration of environmental considerations into economic and urban planning, along with leveraging foreign direct investment for technological advancements, is imperative for balancing economic growth with the necessity to reduce carbon emissions and effectively address climate change. This research provides a better understanding of the diverse factors influencing CO2 emissions and offers critical insights for policymakers.</description>
      <author>Yugang He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14167404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Low-Temperature CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrolysis: Current Status and Outlook</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00583</link>
      <description>Hojeong Lee, Seontaek Kwon, Namgyoo Park, Sun Gwan, Eunyoung Lee, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kong, Jihoo Cha, Youngkook Kwon, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401843733

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction (eCO2R) in membrane electrode assemblies (MEAs) has brought e-chemical production one step closer to commercialization because of its advantages of minimized ohmic resistance and stackability. However, the current performance of reported eCO2R in MEAs is still far below the threshold for economic feasibility where low overall cell voltage (&lt;2 V) and extensive stability (&gt;5 years) are required. Furthermore, while the production cost of e-chemicals heavily relies on the carbon capture and product separation processes, these areas have received much less attention compared to CO2 electrolysis, itself. In this perspective, we examine the current status of eCO2R technologies from both academic and industrial points of view. We highlight the gap between current capabilities and commercialization standards and offer future research directions for eCO2R technologies with the hope of achieving industrially viable e-chemical production.</description>
      <author>Hojeong Lee, Seontaek Kwon, Namgyoo Park, Sun Gwan, Eunyoung Lee, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kong, Jihoo Cha, Youngkook Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of PM2.5 and CO2 Concentrations in Typical Functional Areas of a University Campus in Beijing Based on Low-Cost Sensor Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15091044</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Ruoxi Ao, Wei Wang, Jia Li, Lianfang Wei, Zifa Wang, Atmosphere. 15(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402006596

                The air quality in educational campuses affects the health and work efficiency of teachers and students. Studies into this matter are of great significance for optimizing the management of campus living environments. Low-cost online sensors to monitor PM2.5 and CO2 levels were used in typical functional areas of a university campus in Beijing, China, including offices, dormitories, leisure spaces, canteens, and laboratories. By comparing the findings with data from nearby national monitoring stations, the seasonal and spatial variations in PM2.5 and CO2 concentrations were analyzed. Findings indicate PM2.5 levels within the campus were notably lower compared to the surrounding urban environment. There was variation in PM2.5 and CO2 concentrations across different functional areas. Typically, indoor PM2.5 levels were lower than outdoor ones, while CO2 concentrations in enclosed indoor spaces with human activities progressively escalated. The main internal emission sources affecting the PM2.5 level on campus included traffic emissions, dust generated by human activities, and emissions from catering. In contrast, in areas with better green coverage or where a lake system participates in the atmospheric circulation, the PM2.5 level and CO2/PM2.5 were lower. This indicates that the cleansing impact of plants and aquatic systems is instrumental in lowering PM2.5 concentrations, offering healthier leisure spaces. Seasonal variations also impact PM2.5 levels. During the non-heating period, less pollution source emissions led to decreased outdoor PM2.5 concentrations. The campus monitoring sites experienced an approximate 5 &#181;g/m3 and 29 &#181;g/m3 reduction in the average PM2.5 levels as compared to the PM2.5 of the surrounding urban environment, respectively, during the non-heating and heating period. During indoor activities or sleep, CO2 levels can build up to as high as 2303 ppm due to breathing. It is advisable to stay indoors on days when pollution levels are high, whereas on days with clean air, it is healthier to be outdoors or to air out indoor areas by opening windows. Our research provides clearer scientific evidence for incorporating behavioral strategies for improving air quality into both daily work and life. Moreover, the findings are quite meaningful for the widespread adoption of low-cost sensor monitoring in various environments, with applications beyond just the campus settings.</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Ruoxi Ao, Wei Wang, Jia Li, Lianfang Wei, Zifa Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15091044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2-Based Power Cycles: What Effect Does Additive Molecular Complexity Have on the Cycle Layout?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/gt2024-128133</link>
      <description>Omar Aqel, Martin T. White, A. I. Sayma, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401941401

                Abstract Since their inception, CO2 power cycles have gained prominence for their superior performance and compactness. However, the efficiency of the simple supercritical CO2 cycle is hindered by relatively large temperature differences in the recuperator, leading to increased exergy destruction. Although complex cycles like the recompression or precompression cycles can reduce recuperator irreversibility, their higher complexity and additional equipment requirements raise the cost of the power plant. This paper aims to demonstrate that recuperator irreversibility in a simple recuperated transcritical cycle can be alleviated using CO2-based mixtures, without resorting to complex cycles. This is achieved by comparing the efficiencies of simple and recompression cycles using CO2-based mixtures with nine additives of various molecular complexities: H2S, SO2, C3H8, C4H10, C5H12, C6H6, C4H4S, TiCl4, and C6F6. The effect of additive molar fraction (ranging from 0.05 to 0.5) on the efficiency of both cycles is examined. Thermal efficiency optimisation reveals a correlation between the efficiency difference of the simple and recompression cycles and the molecular complexity of the working fluid. The reduction in recuperator irreversibility is attributed to the decrease in the difference in the isobaric specific heat capacities between the streams in the recuperator with the use of complex additives. Consequently, the advantage of a recompression cycle diminishes as the aggregate molecular complexity of the working fluid increases. Simple additives like H2S, SO2, and C3H8 result in recompression cycles outperforming simple recuperated cycles by 4% to 8% in terms of absolute thermal efficiency, depending on the additive and its molar fraction. Conversely, more complex additives like C4H4S, TiCl4, and C6F6, exhibit thermal efficiencies in simple recuperated cycles comparable to those of recompression cycles. The additive molar fraction at which both cycles achieve similar performances depends on the molecular complexity of the additive; the more complex the additive, the lower the additive molar fraction required to create a complex working fluid. Moreover, the split fraction in recompression cycles exhibits a similar correlation with molecular complexity as observed in the efficiency difference, suggesting that recompression cycles will morph into simple recuperated cycles as molecular complexity increases. In conclusion, the use of additives provides an additional dimension through which the efficiency of CO2 cycles can be optimised, enabling improved performance without the need for complex cycles.</description>
      <author>Omar Aqel, Martin T. White, A. I. Sayma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/gt2024-128133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effectiveness of the EU ETS Policy in Changing the Energy Mix in Selected European Countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174243</link>
      <description>Ma&#322;gorzata B&#322;a&#380;ejowska, Anna Czarny, Iwona Kowalska, Andrzej Michalczewski, Pawe&#322; St&#281;pie&#324;, Energies. 17(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401893614

                In the field of economic analysis, the study of the EU ETS policy has primarily focused on the impact of renewable energy consumption on economic growth, as well as the role of legal and fiscal instruments in the development of clean energy. This study aimed to evaluate the effectiveness of the EU ETS policy in altering the energy mix of selected European countries, providing both cognitive and applicational value. The evaluation of the effectiveness of this policy focused on the structure of the energy mix and the relationship between rising CO2 emission allowance prices and the decreasing share of coal in the energy mix. The goal was achieved through statistical analysis of secondary sources, primarily sourced from Bloomberg (2016&#8211;2024). The research findings indicated that changes in the structure of energy sources varied across the studied European countries, due to the adopted energy source utilization strategy, resource availability, and geopolitical situations. Additionally, different correlation values were noted between rising CO2 emission allowance prices and the expected reduction in fossil fuel use. Therefore, the EU ETS policy does not fulfill its assigned role&#8212;its implementation contributes to disparities in the economic situations of European economies and creates conditions for unequal competition.</description>
      <author>Ma&#322;gorzata B&#322;a&#380;ejowska, Anna Czarny, Iwona Kowalska, Andrzej Michalczewski, Pawe&#322; St&#281;pie&#324;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaCoO3 is a promising catalyst for dry reforming of benzene used as a surrogate of biomass tar</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55730/1300-0527.3685</link>
      <description>Ba&#351;ar &#199;a&#287;lar, Deniz &#220;ner, TURKISH JOURNAL OF CHEMISTRY. 48(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401854464

                Tar build-up is one of the bottlenecks of biomass gasification process. Dry reforming of tar is an alternative solution if oxygen chemical potential on the catalyst surface is at sufficient levels. For this purpose, an oxygen donor perovskite, LaCoO3, was used as a catalyst for dry reforming of tar. To circumvent the complexity of the tar and its constituents, benzene molecule was chosen as a model compound. Dry reforming of benzene vapour on the LaCoO3 catalyst was investigated at temperatures of 600, 700, 800 &#176;C, at the CO2/C6H6 ratios of 3, 6, 12 and at space velocities of 14000 and 28000 h-1. The conventional Ni(15 wt.%)/Al2O3 catalyst was also used as a reference material to determine the relative activity of the LaCoO3 catalyst. Different characterization techniques, such as X-Ray Diffraction, N2 adsorption-desorption, Temperature-programmed reduction, and oxidation were used to determine physicochemical characteristics of catalysts. The findings demonstrate that the LaCoO3 catalyst has a higher CO2 conversion, H2 and CO yields and better stability than the Ni(15 wt.%)/&#947;-Al2O3 catalyst. The improvement in activity is attributed to the strong capacity of LaCoO3 for oxygen exchange. The transfer of lattice oxygen from the surface of the LaCoO3 catalyst facilitates the oxidation of carbon and other surface species and leads to higher conversion and yields.</description>
      <author>Ba&#351;ar &#199;a&#287;lar, Deniz &#220;ner</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55730/1300-0527.3685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realization of Bio-Coal Injection into the Blast Furnace</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14090969</link>
      <description>Lena Sundqvist &#214;kvist, Maria Lundgren, Lars-Erik From, Joakim Eck, Martin Kjellberg, Hesham M. Ahmed, Metals. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401911750

                The steel industry accounts, according to the International Energy Agency, for ~6.7% of global CO2 emissions, and the major portion of its contribution is from steelmaking via the blast furnace (BF) route. In the short term, a significant reduction in fossil CO2 emissions can be achieved through the introduction of bio-coal into the BF as part of cold bonded briquettes, by injection, or as part of coke. The use of bio-coal-containing residue briquettes was previously demonstrated in industrial trials in Sweden, whereas bio-coal injection was only tested on a pilot scale or in one-tuyere tests. Therefore, industrial trials replacing part of the pulverized coal (PC) were conducted. It was concluded that the grinding, conveying, and injection of up to 10% of charcoal (CC) with PC can be safely achieved without negative impacts on PC injection plant or BF operational conditions and without losses of CC with the dust. From a process point of view, higher addition is possible, but it must be verified that grinding and conveying is feasible. Through an experimentally validated computational fluid flow model, it was shown that a high moisture content and the presence of oversized particles delay devolatilization and ignition, lowering the combustion efficiency. By using CC with similar heating value to PC, compositional variations in the injected blend are not critical.</description>
      <author>Lena Sundqvist &#214;kvist, Maria Lundgren, Lars-Erik From, Joakim Eck, Martin Kjellberg, Hesham M. Ahmed</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14090969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental impact assessment and comparative analysis of hot stamping and cold stamping processes: A cradle-to-gate lifecycle assessment study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21741/9781644903254-29</link>
      <description>Marco Bucconi, Materials research proceedings. 44(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401881225

                Abstract. This manuscript presents the results of a cradle-to-gate lifecycle assessment (LCA) conducted on a component manufactured through two distinct process routes: Hot stamping of AA6082-T6 and cold stamping of AA5251-H22. The primary objective of this study is to provide a detailed understanding of the environmental impact associated with these processes and to conduct a comparative analysis of their environmental profiles. A comprehensive process map was developed for each manufacturing route, delineating all inputs and outputs at each step. Forming trials were executed during the LCA, capturing equipment energy consumption. When immediate data was unavailable from trials, the LCA model was supplemented with information from the Ecoinvent 3.6 database. The analysis demonstrates that the adoption of advanced near-net-shape manufacturing, specifically hot stamping, can significantly diminish the environmental impact compared to traditional cold stamping processes. Despite the additional energy requirements for heating in hot stamping, the overall environmental savings, supported by uncertainty analysis, are considerable. In the case of the examined demonstrator part, hot stamping showcased a noteworthy 35% reduction in CO2 equivalent emissions, equivalent to 6 kg CO2e per part. This reduction is primarily attributed to two key factors: the decreased material thickness achievable in hot stamping while preserving equivalent mechanical characteristics in the final part and the recycling of any material waste after forming. The results underscore the environmental advantages of embracing advanced manufacturing techniques, contributing valuable insights for environmentally conscious decision-making in the manufacturing industry.</description>
      <author>Marco Bucconi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21741/9781644903254-29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Study on Management of Administrative Challenges and Market Strategies in the Implementation of Carbon Tax in Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46799/adv.v2i7.270</link>
      <description>Trio Ardhimansyah, Muammar Khaddafi, Deleted Journal. 2(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401897653

                This research discusses administrative challenges and market strategies in implementing a carbon tax in Indonesia. The carbon tax was introduced through the 2021 Harmonization of Tax Regulations Law to control CO2 emissions from fossil fuels such as coal, oil and natural gas. Key challenges include administrative complexity, strong inter-agency coordination, effective monitoring systems, and consistent law enforcement. The global carbon market in 2023 shows great potential for economically efficient emissions reductions, but implementing this model requires adapting to Indonesia's socio-economic landscape. The research method used is a qualitative approach with case studies, combining data from policy documents, interviews with tax experts, and local carbon market analysis. The research results show that the implementation of a carbon tax is faced with several major challenges, including a lack of accurate data on emissions, an immature monitoring system, and resistance from certain industrial sectors. Effective market management strategies, such as the allocation of tax revenues to sustainable projects, are key to mitigating negative economic impacts and encouraging investment in green technologies. This research makes a significant contribution to the understanding of the complexity of carbon tax implementation in developing countries and its relevance in the global context for achieving climate change goals.</description>
      <author>Trio Ardhimansyah, Muammar Khaddafi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46799/adv.v2i7.270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Tunability of Ruthenium Formyl and Hydroxymethyl Intermediates Relevant to Sustainable CO-to-Methanol Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.4c00252</link>
      <description>Jared Z. Litman, Rida Farhat, Kaitlin Branch, Sasha Cryan, Kaeden Teindl, Brian O. Patrick, Eva M. Nichols, Organometallics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401877776

                Metal formyl and hydroxymethyl complexes are implicated as key intermediates in the (photo)electrochemical reduction of carbon oxides (CO2 or CO) to liquid fuels, such as methanol. Formyl complexes, and to a lesser extent hydroxymethyl complexes, have been previously synthesized and characterized; nevertheless, the influence of electronic modifications to ligands supporting these reactive carbon fragments is not well understood. Herein, we report the synthesis of a family of ruthenium polypyridyl carbonyl complexes of the form [Ru(4,4&#8242;-R,R-bpy)(tpy)(CO)]2+ bearing different substituents on the bipyridyl (bpy) ligand (R = OMe, H, CF3). Treatment with NaBH4 as a chemical reductant results in the formation of the formyl and subsequently the hydroxymethyl and methyl complexes; each is characterized by comprehensive NMR spectroscopy, mass spectrometry, and isotopic labeling studies. An electron-donating modification (R = OMe) to the bpy ligand is shown to significantly increase the lifetime of the formyl intermediate and the yield of released methanol. We observe a clear linear dependence of thermodynamic parameters on bpy electronics; however, the stability of the formyl complex and the reactivity of the resulting hydroxymethyl complex do not depend linearly on ligand electronics. We anticipate that these results may be extended to future development of (photo)electrocatalytic systems for CO-to-methanol conversion.</description>
      <author>Jared Z. Litman, Rida Farhat, Kaitlin Branch, Sasha Cryan, Kaeden Teindl, Brian O. Patrick, Eva M. Nichols</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.4c00252</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heating and ventilation efficiencies of a solar chimney integrated system in a low-energy office building</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0210530</link>
      <description>Leila Moosavi, Journal of Renewable and Sustainable Energy. 16(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401953774

                Mechanical air conditioning systems have a significant share of energy consumption in the building sector. Passive solar systems, such as solar chimneys, can reduce building energy demand by supplying space heating, cooling, and ventilation, significantly decreasing greenhouse gas emissions. Therefore, this study aimed to evaluate the heating and ventilation efficiencies of a solar chimney integrated system, including a roof solar chimney coupled with an air channel, for a two-story office building in Tehran, Iran. The studied system's conditions are switchable from heating to cooling by changing the opening positions. Computational Fluid Dynamics was employed to numerically investigate the heating and ventilation efficiencies of the proposed solar system. The results confirmed that the system could be utilized for pre-heating purposes during working hours but that the building should be ventilated only for 35% of this time with an air change rate of 0.8 during the year's coldest month. The arrangement could provide thermal and ventilation comfort for the occupied space only at solar intensity and ambient temperature higher than 550 W/m2 and 10 &#176;C, respectively. In addition, the solar system could reduce 32% of the annual heating demand (918 kWh), which is equal to a reduction of 1865 kg of CO2 emissions during working hours.</description>
      <author>Leila Moosavi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0210530</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Properties of Green SCC with and without Novel Additive</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55041/ijsrem37187</link>
      <description>IJSREM Journal, INTERANTIONAL JOURNAL OF SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH IN ENGINEERING AND MANAGEMENT. 08(008)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401893700

                Concrete is the most widely used construction material in civil engineering industry because of its proved structural strength and stability when made properly. The concrete industry is constantly trying to evolve to make concrete more sustainable replacing a part of full cement with additives and Supplementary Cementitious Materials (SCMs). Each tonne of cement production releases one tonne of CO2 into the atmosphere and hence to greenhouse effect and global warming. A cost effective, alternative and innovative materials called novel additive is taken up for present study to reduce the cement consumption per m3 of concrete/SCC without reduction in strength of required grade. In this project an effort is made replacing cement content of SCC partially with Fly Ash, Ground Granulated Blast Furnace Slag (GGBS) in combination of novel additive. The study focused at studying the properties of fresh SCC and hardened SCC. The design mix proportion of 1: 2.63: 1.86 with a W/B ratio of 0.36 is taken up and 4 different mixes with different combinations of varied percentage replacement materials with 2% by weight of cement of novel additive. The properties of green SCC showed that fresh properties get enhanced through usage of mineral admixtures including a novel additive and hence, the addition of mineral admixture improve the flowability or rheology of SCC mixes. The strength of SCC achieved is ranging from 32- 46 N/mm2 for a cementitious content of 400 kg/m3 , highest being with lowest cement content with novel additive. Keywords: Rheology of SCC, Mineral Admixtures, Novel Additive, Sustainability</description>
      <author>IJSREM Journal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55041/ijsrem37187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Assessment of Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles Considering Different Vehicle Working Conditions and Battery Degradation Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174283</link>
      <description>Yaning Zhang, Ziqiang Cao, Chunmei Zhang, Yisong Chen, Energies. 17(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401910945

                This study establishes a life cycle assessment model to quantitively evaluate and predict material resource consumption, fossil energy consumption and environmental emissions of plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEVs) by employing the GaBi software. This study distinguishes the environmental impact of different vehicle working conditions, power battery degradation scenarios, and mileage scenarios on the operation and use stages of PHEVs, BEVs, and HEVs. The findings indicate that under urban, highway, and aggressive driving conditions, PHEVs&#8217; life cycle material resource and fossil fuel consumption exceed that of BEVs but are less than HEVs. Battery degradation leads to increased material resource consumption, energy use, and environmental emissions for both PHEVs and BEVs. When the power battery degrades to 85%, the material resource and fossil energy consumption during the operation and use phase increases by 51.43%, 72.68% for BEVs and 29.37%, 36.21% for PHEVs compared with no degradation, respectively, indicating that the environmental impact of BEVs are more sensitive than those of PHEVs to the impact of power battery degradation. Among different mileage scenarios, PHEVs demonstrate the lowest sensitivity to increased mileage regarding life cycle material resource consumption, with the smallest increase. Future projections for 2025 and 2035 suggest life cycle GWP of HEV, PHEV and BEV in 2035 is 1.21 &#215; 104, 1.12 &#215; 104 and 1.01 &#215; 104 kg CO2-eq, respectively, which shows reductions of 48.7%, 30.9% and 36.1% compared with those in 2025. The outcomes of this study are intended to bolster data support for the manufacturing and development of PHEV, BEV and HEV under different scenarios and offer insights into the growth and technological progression of the automotive sector.</description>
      <author>Yaning Zhang, Ziqiang Cao, Chunmei Zhang, Yisong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174283</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of an Improved Workflow for the Identification of Flame Dynamics to Swirl Stabilized Wet Combustion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/gt2024-125057</link>
      <description>Marcel D&#233;sor, Matthias Haeringer, Marian Hiestermann, Korbinian Niebler, Camilo F. Silva, Wolfgang Polifke, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401942310

                Abstract The estimation of a flame transfer function (FTF)from time series data generated by large eddy simulation (LES) via system identification (SI) is an established and important element of thermoacoustic analysis. To achieve results with low uncertainties, continuous (non-truncated) time series of adequate length are required. This can be a challenge in the case of turbulent flames, where signal-to-noise ratio may be low. Because LES codes do not scale to an arbitrarily high degree of parallelism, the wall-clock-time required for confident FTF estimation may be excessive. The present paper tackles this challenge by exploiting characteristic features of linear time-invariant systems. Specifically, we explore how the superposition of multiple simulations with the same excitation signal, but varying initial conditions, increases signal-to-noise ratio and leads to more robust identification, i.e. estimates with narrow confidence intervals. In addition, the established SI approach, which relies on broadband excitation, is compared to excitation with approximate Dirac and Heaviside signals, with the advantage of simpler pre- and post-processing. Results demonstrate that the proposed workflow, which is inherently parallel because it is based on superposition, reduces significantly the wall-clock-time required for robust FTF identification in the case of broadband excitation. This reduction in wall-clock-time requires more simultaneous simulation runs, i.e. more parallel computational resources, but it does not significantly increase the overall computational cost. Furthermore, the new workflow facilitates FTF estimation when exciting with a Heaviside signal. The proposed method is assessed for the case of a partially premixed, steam enriched (&#8220;WET&#8221;) swirl burner with significant turbulent noise levels. Steam enrichment is a combustion concept that reduces harmful emissions such as NOx and CO2 while increasing engine efficiency. However, the effect of steam on the flame response, i.e. the FTF, needs to be better understood. To this end, a combustion model that includes an optimized global chemical mechanism for partially premixed wet methane combustion, has been formulated and validated against experimental data.</description>
      <author>Marcel D&#233;sor, Matthias Haeringer, Marian Hiestermann, Korbinian Niebler, Camilo F. Silva, Wolfgang Polifke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/gt2024-125057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biocatalysis in Asia and the Pacific</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00693</link>
      <description>Sabine L. Flitsch, Nicholas J. Turner, Zhi Li, JACS Au. 4(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401891208

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. JACS AuVol 4/Issue 8Article This publication is Open Access under the license indicated. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse EditorialAugust 26, 2024Biocatalysis in Asia and the PacificClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Sabine L. Flitsch*Sabine L. FlitschMIB &amp; School of Chemistry, The University of Manchester, 131 Princess Street, Manchester M1 7DN, United Kingdom*Email: [email protected]More by Sabine L. Flitschhttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-3974-646XNicholas J. Turner*Nicholas J. TurnerMIB &amp; School of Chemistry, The University of Manchester, 131 Princess Street, Manchester M1 7DN, United Kingdom*Email: [email protected]More by Nicholas J. Turnerhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-8708-0781Zhi Li*Zhi LiDepartment of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, National University of Singapore, 4 Engineering Drive 4, Singapore 117585*Email: [email protected]More by Zhi Lihttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-7370-2562Open PDFJACS AuCite this: JACS Au 2024, 4, 8, 2713&#8211;2714Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/jacsau.4c00693https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00693Published August 26, 2024 Publication History Received 2 August 2024Accepted 2 August 2024Published online 26 August 2024Published in issue 26 August 2024editorialCopyright &#169; Published 2024 by American Chemical Society. This publication is licensed under CC-BY-NC-ND 4.0. License Summary*You are free to share (copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below:Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license.Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license*DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. This publication is licensed underCC-BY-NC-ND 4.0 . License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. ACS PublicationsCopyright &#169; Published 2024 by American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.BiocatalysisBioengineering and biotechnologyCarbohydratesGoldPeptides and proteinsBiocatalysis has entered its Golden Age (1) with increasing adoption in organic chemistry, (2) pharmaceutical research and development, (3) and exciting new applications in biopharmaceuticals. (4) Interest is particularly growing in the Asia-Pacific area with its expanding population, urbanization, and rising disposable incomes which in turn drives the need for innovative green and sustainable chemical technologies that biocatalysis can provide [https://www.unescap.org/projects/gd]. This strong interest in new green technologies has caused a dramatic increase in fundamental research in biocatalysis, with large numbers of research groups from different disciplines entering the field. The breadth of research in biocatalysis in the Asia-Pacific area is showcased in this Virtual Special Issue, titled Biocatalysis in Asia and Pacific, which includes a snapshot of a collection of articles published in JACS Au in 2023/2024.Despite many successes in the general application of biocatalysis in industry, there remain many fundamental scientific challenges, some of which are addressed in this selection of papers. One particular challenge concerns the need for expensive cofactors such as nicotinamides which are for example needed for reduction and oxidation reactions. A perspective describes the very elegant solution of "biocatalytic hydrogen borrowing", which uses multistep sequences including dehydrogenation and hydrogenation in one pot by hydride shuffling between NAD(P)+ and NAD(P)H [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00026]. Another common challenge is active protein expression, and in a novel approach, unspecific peroxygenases have been successfully expressed using a superfolder-green-fluorescent protein in bacteria [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00129]. For multistep biocatalytic processes, cellular engineering guided by proteomic analysis can dramatically increase product titers, as shown for the production of &#945;-bisabolene in yeast [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00106].An area of great interest is the design of reactions and reaction sequences beyond those found in nature. Some successful approaches shown here explore substrate promiscuity for challenging CO2 fixation reactions [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00290] or atroposelective synthesis of aldehydes [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.3c00814]. Alternatively, biocatalysis can be combined with chemical reactions in chemo-enzymatic strategies, including for example Au catalysis [DOIs: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00222, 10.1021/jacsau.3c00688]. Such biocatalytic processes are not only applicable to the synthesis of target molecules but also in bioremediation strategies as demonstrated by removal of the toxic metabolite deoxynivalenol in plants [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.3c00696] and engineering of a metal reductase for the bioremediation of anthropogenic electronic wastes [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00297].In addition to small molecule substrates, biocatalysis is also very attractive for larger biomolecules, such as complex glycoproteins that make up a significant number of the leading biopharmaceutical products. Glycoengineering using biocatalysis provides a tool for improving the therapeutic profile of antibodies, and using a structure-based design approach, an endoglycosidase was engineered to provide a novel toolbox for conjugating glycans to specific glycoprotein sites [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00004]. Glycoengineering often requires sugar nucleotide cofactor regeneration systems, and one such example for UDP-Xylose has been designed as bifunctional chimeras to minimize the need for additional proteins and improved activity [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00288].Computational tools are making a great impact in biocatalysis, in particular in protein engineering, and it is interesting that several papers in this Virtual Special Issue make use of machine learning and modeling tools to find new and better activities: directed evolution and machine learning are used in combination to enhance the diastereoselectivity of a ketoreductase [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00284]. Molecular dynamics simulations and quantum mechanical calculations have been used to redesign a P450 monooxygenase [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.4c00075]. Computational enzyme redesign has been used to find mutants of a lyase with enhanced tolerance to denaturants for peptide C-terminal amidation [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.3c00792]. Finally, density functional theory calculations and molecular dynamic simulations were used to identify and reduce energy barriers of key transition states to enhance C&#8211;N cleavage efficiency of an amino acid oxidase [DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.3c00672].It is striking how even a small collection of papers in biocatalysis from Asia and the Pacific showcases the engagement of a very diverse group of scientists in areas ranging from computational to synthetic chemistry, chemical biology, biochemistry, and synthetic biology to applications in engineering, cell biology, and medicine. Similarly diverse are the challenges addressed beyond the synthesis of bioactive compounds, driven by demands to solve societal problems in medicine with a more green and sustainable production of pharmaceutical and biopharmaceutical entities. There are also contributions from biocatalysis in directly solving environmental issues such as detoxification, removal of waste from the environment, and CO2 fixation. This Virtual Special Issue clearly shows that the topic of biocatalysis is very actively pursued at the highest international level using leading experimental and computational tools. Biocatalysis is very important to Asia and the Pacific, and the community is well placed to solve many of the challenges that lie ahead.Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorsSabine L. Flitsch, MIB &amp; School of Chemistry, The University of Manchester, 131 Princess Street, Manchester M1 7DN, United Kingdom, https://orcid.org/0000-0003-3974-646X, Email: [email protected]Nicholas J. Turner, MIB &amp; School of Chemistry, The University of Manchester, 131 Princess Street, Manchester M1 7DN, United Kingdom, https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8708-0781, Email: [email protected]Zhi Li, Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, National University of Singapore, 4 Engineering Drive 4, Singapore 117585, https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7370-2562, Email: [email protected]NotesViews expressed in this editorial are those of the authors and not necessarily the views of the ACS.ReferencesClick to copy section linkSection link copied! This article references 4 other publications. 1Turner, N. J.; Kumar, R. The golden age of biocatalysis. Curr. Opin. Chem. Biol. 2018, 43, A1&#8211; A3, DOI: 10.1016/j.cbpa.2018.02.012 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.2Romero, E. O.; Saucedo, A. T.; Hernandez-Melendez, J. R.; Yang, D.; Chakrabarty, S.; Narayan, A. R. H. Enabling broader adoption of biocatalysis in organic chemistry. JACS Au 2023, 3 (8), 2073&#8211; 2085, DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.3c00263 Google Scholar2Enabling broader adoption of biocatalysis in organic chemistryRomero, Evan O.; Saucedo, Anthony T.; Hernandez-Melendez, Jose R.; Yang, Di; Chakrabarty, Suman; Narayan, Alison R. H.JACS Au (2023), 3 (8), 2073-2085CODEN: JAAUCR; ISSN:2691-3704. (American Chemical Society) A review. Biocatalysis is becoming an increasingly impactful method in contemporary synthetic chem. for target mol. synthesis. The selectivity imparted by enzymes has been leveraged to complete previously intractable chem. transformations and improve synthetic routes toward complex mols. However, the implementation of biocatalysis in mainstream org. chem. has been gradual to this point. This is partly due to a set of historical and technol. barriers that have prevented chemists from using biocatalysis as a synthetic tool with utility that parallels alternative modes of catalysis. In this Perspective, we discuss these barriers and how they have hindered the adoption of enzyme catalysts into synthetic strategies. We also summarize tools and resources that already enable org. chemists to use biocatalysts. Furthermore, we discuss ways to further lower the barriers for the adoption of biocatalysis by the broader synthetic org. chem. community through the dissemination of resources, demystifying biocatalytic reactions, and increasing collaboration across the field. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3sXhsVyksL%252FP&amp;md5=c75f4b0fa7f76b51151b2a63beb2b5a43France, S. P.; Lewis, R. D.; Martinez, C. A. The evolving nature of biocatalysis in pharmaceutical research and development. JACS Au 2023, 3 (3), 715&#8211; 735, DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.2c00712 Google Scholar3The Evolving Nature of Biocatalysis in Pharmaceutical Research and DevelopmentFrance, Scott P.; Lewis, Russell D.; Martinez, Carlos A.JACS Au (2023), 3 (3), 715-735CODEN: JAAUCR; ISSN:2691-3704. (American Chemical Society) A review. Biocatalysis is a highly valued enabling technol. for pharmaceutical research and development as it can unlock synthetic routes to complex chiral motifs with unparalleled selectivity and efficiency. This perspective aims to review recent advances in the pharmaceutical implementation of biocatalysis across early and late-stage development with a focus on the implementation of processes for preparative-scale syntheses. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3sXjvVajsbo%253D&amp;md5=71ea4afe11c8a0b80ddcbad75af67a054Debon, A.; Siirola, E.; Snajdrova, R. Enzymatic bioconjugation: a perspective from the pharmaceutical industry. JACS Au 2023, 3 (5), 1267&#8211; 1283, DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.2c00617 Google Scholar4Enzymatic Bioconjugation: A Perspective from the Pharmaceutical IndustryDebon, Aaron; Siirola, Elina; Snajdrova, RadkaJACS Au (2023), 3 (5), 1267-1283CODEN: JAAUCR; ISSN:2691-3704. (American Chemical Society) A review. Enzymes have firmly established themselves as bespoke catalysts for small mol. transformations in the pharmaceutical industry, from early research and development stages to large-scale prodn. In principle, their exquisite selectivity and rate acceleration can also be leveraged for modifying macromols. to form bioconjugates. However, available catalysts face stiff competition from other bioorthogonal chemistries. In this review, we seek to illuminate applications of enzymic bioconjugation in the face of an expanding palette of new drug modalities. With these applications, we wish to highlight some examples of current successes and pitfalls of using enzymes for bioconjugation along the pipeline and try to illustrate opportunities for further development. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3sXptFCisLs%253D&amp;md5=63e807436aa50bfb6f4f9406650aaf73Cited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferencesOpen PDF Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsJACS AuCite this: JACS Au 2024, 4, 8, 2713&#8211;2714Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00693Published August 26, 2024 Publication History Received 2 August 2024Accepted 2 August 2024Published online 26 August 2024Published in issue 26 August 2024Copyright &#169; Published 2024 by American Chemical Society. This publication is licensed under CC-BY-NC-ND 4.0. License Summary*You are free to share (copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below:Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license.Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license*DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. Article Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesThis publication has no figures.References This article references 4 other publications. 1Turner, N. J.; Kumar, R. The golden age of biocatalysis. Curr. Opin. Chem. Biol. 2018, 43, A1&#8211; A3, DOI: 10.1016/j.cbpa.2018.02.012 There is no corresponding record for this reference.2Romero, E. O.; Saucedo, A. T.; Hernandez-Melendez, J. R.; Yang, D.; Chakrabarty, S.; Narayan, A. R. H. Enabling broader adoption of biocatalysis in organic chemistry. JACS Au 2023, 3 (8), 2073&#8211; 2085, DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.3c00263 2Enabling broader adoption of biocatalysis in organic chemistryRomero, Evan O.; Saucedo, Anthony T.; Hernandez-Melendez, Jose R.; Yang, Di; Chakrabarty, Suman; Narayan, Alison R. H.JACS Au (2023), 3 (8), 2073-2085CODEN: JAAUCR; ISSN:2691-3704. (American Chemical Society) A review. Biocatalysis is becoming an increasingly impactful method in contemporary synthetic chem. for target mol. synthesis. The selectivity imparted by enzymes has been leveraged to complete previously intractable chem. transformations and improve synthetic routes toward complex mols. However, the implementation of biocatalysis in mainstream org. chem. has been gradual to this point. This is partly due to a set of historical and technol. barriers that have prevented chemists from using biocatalysis as a synthetic tool with utility that parallels alternative modes of catalysis. In this Perspective, we discuss these barriers and how they have hindered the adoption of enzyme catalysts into synthetic strategies. We also summarize tools and resources that already enable org. chemists to use biocatalysts. Furthermore, we discuss ways to further lower the barriers for the adoption of biocatalysis by the broader synthetic org. chem. community through the dissemination of resources, demystifying biocatalytic reactions, and increasing collaboration across the field. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3sXhsVyksL%252FP&amp;md5=c75f4b0fa7f76b51151b2a63beb2b5a43France, S. P.; Lewis, R. D.; Martinez, C. A. The evolving nature of biocatalysis in pharmaceutical research and development. JACS Au 2023, 3 (3), 715&#8211; 735, DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.2c00712 3The Evolving Nature of Biocatalysis in Pharmaceutical Research and DevelopmentFrance, Scott P.; Lewis, Russell D.; Martinez, Carlos A.JACS Au (2023), 3 (3), 715-735CODEN: JAAUCR; ISSN:2691-3704. (American Chemical Society) A review. Biocatalysis is a highly valued enabling technol. for pharmaceutical research and development as it can unlock synthetic routes to complex chiral motifs with unparalleled selectivity and efficiency. This perspective aims to review recent advances in the pharmaceutical implementation of biocatalysis across early and late-stage development with a focus on the implementation of processes for preparative-scale syntheses. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3sXjvVajsbo%253D&amp;md5=71ea4afe11c8a0b80ddcbad75af67a054Debon, A.; Siirola, E.; Snajdrova, R. Enzymatic bioconjugation: a perspective from the pharmaceutical industry. JACS Au 2023, 3 (5), 1267&#8211; 1283, DOI: 10.1021/jacsau.2c00617 4Enzymatic Bioconjugation: A Perspective from the Pharmaceutical IndustryDebon, Aaron; Siirola, Elina; Snajdrova, RadkaJACS Au (2023), 3 (5), 1267-1283CODEN: JAAUCR; ISSN:2691-3704. (American Chemical Society) A review. Enzymes have firmly established themselves as bespoke catalysts for small mol. transformations in the pharmaceutical industry, from early research and development stages to large-scale prodn. In principle, their exquisite selectivity and rate acceleration can also be leveraged for modifying macromols. to form bioconjugates. However, available catalysts face stiff competition from other bioorthogonal chemistries. In this review, we seek to illuminate applications of enzymic bioconjugation in the face of an expanding palette of new drug modalities. With these applications, we wish to highlight some examples of current successes and pitfalls of using enzymes for bioconjugation along the pipeline and try to illustrate opportunities for further development. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3sXptFCisLs%253D&amp;md5=63e807436aa50bfb6f4f9406650aaf73</description>
      <author>Sabine L. Flitsch, Nicholas J. Turner, Zhi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precision Chemistry for Two-Dimensional Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00065</link>
      <description>Xiangfeng Duan, Precision Chemistry. 2(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401891950

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. Precision ChemistryVol 2/Issue 8Article This publication is Open Access under the license indicated. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse EditorialAugust 26, 2024Precision Chemistry for Two-Dimensional MaterialsClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Xiangfeng Duan*Xiangfeng DuanDepartment of Chemistry and Biochemistry and California NanoSystems Institute, University of California, Los Angeles, California 90095, United States*[email protected]More by Xiangfeng Duanhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-4321-6288Open PDFPrecision ChemistryCite this: Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 8, 376&#8211;379Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/prechem.4c00065https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00065Published August 26, 2024 Publication History Received 4 August 2024Published online 26 August 2024Published in issue 26 August 2024editorialUniversity of Science and Technology of China and American Chemical Society. Co-published 2024 by University of Science and Technology of China and American Chemical Society. This publication is licensed under CC-BY-NC-ND 4.0. License Summary*You are free to share (copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below:Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license.Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license*DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. This publication is licensed underCC-BY-NC-ND 4.0 . License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. ACS PublicationsUniversity of Science and Technology of China and American Chemical Society. Co-published 2024 by University of Science and Technology of China and American Chemical Society.Subjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.CrystallizationDopingHeterostructuresInsulatorsTwo dimensional materialsSPECIAL ISSUEThis article is part of the Precision Chemistry for Two-Dimensional Materials special issue.Two-dimensional (2D) materials have garnered enormous interest as a novel platform for exploring fundamental chemistry and physics at the single-atom thickness limit. These materials encompass various categories and types, including graphene, (1) hexagonal boron nitride (hBN), (2) transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs), (3) MXenes, (4) graphdiyne, (5) covalent organic frameworks (COFs), (6) and monolayer molecular crystals. (7) These materials can exhibit diverse properties as metals, semiconductors, superconductors, insulators, dielectrics, and magnets. Their unique electronic, optical, mechanical, and quantum properties make them suitable for a wide range of applications, from transistors and sensors to quantum information sciences and energy storage. With their highly tunable and versatile physical properties, these atomically thin materials could promise technological opportunities beyond the reach of existing materials.With a thickness measured by a single atom or a few atoms and lateral dimensions extending up to the meter scale, 2D materials feature an extreme aspect ratio of up to 109 or larger. This extreme aspect ratio necessitates highly anisotropic growth, with growth rates differing by millions or billions of times across different dimensions, posing a fundamentally new synthetic challenge. Achieving consistent single-atom thickness while expanding laterally to macroscopic scale requires fine-tuned control over the nucleation and growth process. Precision chemistry holds the key to the production of uniform 2D materials, (8) their heterostructures, (9) and superlattices, (10,11) which are central for consistent electronic and optical properties. Understanding the fundamental growth mechanisms is essential for the controlled synthesis of 2D materials with specific stacking orders, symmetry, and phase characteristics, fundamentally determining their properties. (12) By precisely controlling doping levels, edge termination, heterostructure formation, and intercalation of functional species, researchers can further tailor the electronic and chemical properties of 2D materials, enhancing their functionality for various applications. (13) Given the extreme surface-to-volume ratio of 2D materials, precision surface chemistry is also critical for manipulating and optimizing relevant physical properties, including surface functionalization, surface protection, charge density, and other exotic properties such chiral optical and spintronic properties. Proper surface modification may also enhance the stability and performance of 2D materials in various applications.Precision chemistry plays a central role in tailoring the atomic and molecular structures of 2D materials, thereby unlocking their full potential in various high-impact areas such as lower-power electronics, energy storage, catalysis, and sensing. Precise control over dimensions, chemical compositions, impurity doping, heterostructure interface, or surface modification makes it possible to finely tune the electronic properties of 2D materials, including bandgap engineering, carrier density, and mobility regulation, which are crucial for applications in transistors, sensors, and other electronic devices. 2D materials exhibit unique optical properties, such as layer-number tunable photoluminescence and strong light&#8211;matter interactions. (14,15) Precision control over their synthesis allows for the optimization of these properties for use in optoelectronic devices and photodetectors. At the atomic scale, quantum effects become significant. Precision chemistry allows for the control over quantum properties such as spin, (16) valley polarization, (17) charge correlation, (18) and single photon emission, (19) which are important for emerging quantum technologies. (20) Additionally, 2D materials are also promising candidates for energy conversion and storage applications due to their high surface area and unique electrochemical properties. A precise control of their synthesis, surface modification, heteroatom doping, and assembly in higher-order superstructures is critical for capturing the merits of 2D materials in supercapacitors, batteries, fuel cells, or green hydrogen production. (21&#8722;24)This Special Issue (including Part I and Part II) in Precision Chemistry titled "Precision Chemistry for Two-Dimensional Materials" features the latest research and perspectives from the leading scientists in this rapidly developing field, highlighting the development and application of precision chemistry for scalable synthesis of 2D materials, including large-area thin films, single crystals, heterostructures, and superlattices of various 2D materials, as well as rational tailoring of their chemical and physical properties for various applications in unconventional electronics, sensing, catalysis, energy storage, and molecular nanofiltration.The liquid-phase exfoliation technique offers a top-down strategy for scalable processing of 2D-TMDs in large quantities. The review authored by Pawin Iamprasertkun et al. offers insights into liquid exfoliation, particularly focusing on optimizing nanosheet yield while preserving their intrinsic properties. (25) Advocating for a data-driven approach and the integration of machine learning, this review offers a comprehensive guide for researchers and practitioners in the field of 2D materials, providing valuable insights for optimizing production processes and enhancing material properties through an integration of traditional synthesis techniques with modern analytical tools.The chemical vapor deposition (CVD) process offers an appealing bottom-up strategy for the large-area synthesis of high-quality 2D materials. Xidong Duan and colleagues review the spin-coating precursor mediated CVD (SCVD) strategy for the growth of high-quality 2D TMDs. (26) This method offers a refined and scalable alternative to traditional CVD, providing more facile control over material thickness and purity. The review illuminates a path toward uniform production of TMDs over large areas. The exploration of novel precursors and substrate engineering within the SCVD process is particularly noteworthy, as it expands the horizons for TMD synthesis and integration into heterostructures and selectively doped materials.In semiconductor electronics, the integration of high-&#954; dielectric materials is essential for next-generation electronics. Li Lin and co-authors report the successful synthesis of large-sized van der Waals layered MoO3 single crystals. (27) These layered crystals, with their improved dielectric performance, offer an attractive dielectric material for future 2D electronics, particularly for applications requiring strong gate control and low power consumption. This work is crucial for those seeking to enhance gate control and reduce power consumption in electronic components.Taking a step further, Kaihui Liu and co-workers address the critical challenge of growing noncentrosymmetric 2D materials on centrosymmetric substrates, a process complicated by the energetic equivalency of antiparallel islands on centrosymmetric substrates. (28) Their review outlines strategies and advancements in producing noncentrosymmetric 2D materials over large-area substrates, a critical step toward large-area 2D single crystals for high-end electronic and optoelectronic devices. They further provide a forward-looking perspeptive on the growth of layer-, stacking-, and twist-controlled noncentrosymmetric 2D single crystals and their heterostructures, providing a beacon for future direction in synthetic control of 2D materials.In a theory study, Feng Ding and co-workers used density functional theory (DFT) to examine the gold surface reconstruction processes that occur in sulfur-rich environments during the growth of TMDs, (29) shedding light on an important yet underexplored aspect of 2D material synthesis. The study fundamentally revealed the formation of stable metal sulfide buffer layers, offering insights into the underlying mechanisms that influence TMDs growth on gold substrates. This research highlights how theory can help develop a precision understanding and guide further optimization of 2D material growth on the optimum substrates.2D van der Waals heterostructures consisting of vertically stacked 2D atomic layers have emerged as a rich testing bed for uncovering new electronic, magnetic, and other unique properties, defining a versatile material platform for fundamental physics and device applications. Libo Gao and co-workers present a perspective on the emerging field of 2D van der Waals superconductor heterostructures, (30) focusing on Josephson junctions and their potential applications in condensed matter physics and materials science, highlighting the exciting potential of 2D superconductor heterostructures for future technological innovations.Impurity doping offers a powerful stragey to manipulate the electronic properties of 2D materials. Xiangfeng Duan and co-workers present the precision control of amphoteric doping in CuxBi2Se3 nanoplates. (31) The research uncovers a transition from intercalative to substitutional doping sites with increasing copper concentrations, which significantly alters the electronic behavior of the materials. Notably, the study demonstrates that a specific doping level in Cu0.18Bi2Se3 induces superconducting properties not found in the undoped Bi2Se3, further underscoring the transformative potential of precise doping on materials properties. This work highlights intercalation as a versatile avenue for the design of materials with tailored electronic properties and quantum behaviors for applications in advanced electronics and quantum technologies.Monolayer molecular crystals (MMCs) have emerged as an intriguing class of 2D materials, offering exciting potential for wide tunability and a myriad of applications. The quest for precision in their preparation is not just a scientific endeavor but a critical foundation for technological innovation. Lang Jiang and his colleagues review the progress in solution-processed MMCs, (32) presenting the current challenges and future prospects and highlighting their exceptional properties for applications in organic field-effect transistors, sensing technologies, and optoelectronic devices.Forming 2D organic/inorganic hybrids provides a versatile strategy to further tailor the physical properties and and enrich the chemical functionalities. Jun Lou and co-workers report a general approach for the seamless integration of 2D COFs with inorganic 2D materials. (33) This controlled synthesis method leverages the unique chemical nature of 2D inorganic materials to catalyze formation of COFs with diverse functionalities. The resulting hybrids exhibit well-controlled 2D morphology together with excellent dispersibility and processibility. This work offers a facile strategy for the scalable production of 2D organic/inorganic hybrids that of are great interest for diverse technologies including water treatment and energy storage.Graphdiyne represents a newer and rapidly evolving 2D carbon material with unique structure and fascinating properties. The discovery of graphdiyne has opened up exciting opportunities in the fundamental research and practical applications of carbon nanomaterials. (5) Yuliang Li and co-workers provide a systematic review of the precisely controlled synthesis of graphdiyne-based materials (34) and highlight how precision chemistry can be used to tailor this unique class of materials as multiscale catalysts in various catalysis and energy conversion areas, including ammonia synthesis, hydrogen production, and CO2 conversion, showcasing the potential of precisely engineered 2D materials for targeted applications.In summary, this two-part Special Issue of Precision Chemistry highlights the critical role of precision chemistry in the synthesis, control, and utilization of atomically thin 2D materials. It enables the fine-tuning of their properties, paving the way for advancements in electronics, quantum electronics, energy applications, and beyond. Precise control of the growth and surface chemistry of 2D materials is essential for unlocking their full potential in a wide range of technological fields. This collection of papers is a celebration of the progress that has been made and a call to action for researchers to continue pushing the boundaries of what is possible with 2D materials through precision chemical control.Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorXiangfeng Duan, Executive Editor, Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry and California NanoSystems Institute, University of California, Los Angeles, California 90095, United States, https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4321-6288, Email: [email protected]NotesViews expressed in this editorial are those of the author and not necessarily the views of the ACS.ReferencesClick to copy section linkSection link copied! This article references 34 other publications. 1Novoselov, K. S.; Geim, A. K.; Morozov, S. V.; Jiang, D.; Zhang, Y.; Dubonos, S. V.; Grigorieva, I. V.; Firsov, A. A. Electric field effect in atomically thin carbon films. Science 2004, 306, 666&#8211; 669, DOI: 10.1126/science.1102896 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.2Zhi, C.; Bando, Y.; Tang, C.; Kuwahara, H.; Golberg, D. Large-scale fabrication of boron nitride nanosheets and their utilization in polymeric composites with improved thermal and mechanical properties. Adv. Mater. 2009, 21, 2889&#8211; 2893, DOI: 10.1002/adma.200900323 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.3Chhowalla, M.; Shin, H. S.; Eda, G.; Li, L.-J.; Loh, K. P.; Zhang, H. The chemistry of two-dimensional layered transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets. Nat. Chem. 2013, 5, 263&#8211; 275, DOI: 10.1038/nchem.1589 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.4Naguib, M.; Mochalin, V. N.; Barsoum, M. W.; Gogotsi, Y. 25th anniversary article: Mxenes: a new family of two-dimensional materials. Adv. Mater. 2014, 26, 992&#8211; 1005, DOI: 10.1002/adma.201304138 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.5Li, G.; Li, Y.; Liu, H.; Guo, Y.; Li, Y.; Zhu, D. Architecture of graphdiyne nanoscale films. Chem. Commun. 2010, 46, 3256&#8211; 3258, DOI: 10.1039/b922733d Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.6Zhong, Y.; Cheng, B.; Park, C.; Ray, A.; Brown, S.; Mujid, F.; Lee, J.-U.; Zhou, H.; Suh, J.; Lee, K.-H.; Mannix, A. J.; Kang, K.; Sibener, S. J.; Muller, D. A.; Park, J. Wafer-scale synthesis of monolayer two-dimensional porphyrin polymers for hybrid superlattices. Science 2019, 366, 1379&#8211; 1384, DOI: 10.1126/science.aax9385 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.7Dong, J.; Liu, L.; Tan, C.; Xu, Q.; Zhang, J.; Qiao, Z.; Chu, D.; Liu, Y.; Zhang, Q.; Jiang, J.; Han, Y.; Davis, A. P.; Cui, Y. Free-standing homochiral 2D monolayers by exfoliation of molecular crystals. Nature 2022, 602, 606&#8211; 611, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-022-04407-8 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.8Zhang, Z.; Chen, P.; Yang, X.; Liu, Y.; Ma, H.; Li, J.; Zhao, B.; Luo, J.; Duan, X.; Duan, X. Ultrafast growth of large single crystals of monolayer WS2 and WSe2. Natl. Sci. Rev. 2020, 7, 737&#8211; 744, DOI: 10.1093/nsr/nwz223 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.9Li, J.; Yang, X.; Liu, Y.; Huang, B.; Wu, R.; Zhang, Z.; Zhao, B.; Ma, H.; Dang, W.; Wei, Z.; Wang, K.; Lin, Z.; Yan, X.; Sun, M.; Li, B.; Pan, X.; Luo, J.; Zhang, G.; Liu, Y.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X.; Duan, X. General synthesis of two-dimensional van der Waals heterostructure arrays. Nature 2020, 579, 368&#8211; 374, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-020-2098-y Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.10Wang, C.; He, Q.; Halim, U.; Liu, Y.; Zhu, E.; Lin, Z.; Xiao, H.; Duan, X.; Feng, Z.; Cheng, R.; Weiss, N. O.; Ye, G.; Huang, Y.-C.; Wu, H.; Cheng, H.-C.; Shakir, I.; Liao, L.; Chen, X.; Goddard, W. A., III; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Monolayer atomic crystal molecular superlattices. Nature 2018, 555, 231&#8211; 236, DOI: 10.1038/nature25774 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.11Zhou, J.; Zhang, W.; Lin, Y.-C.; Cao, J.; Zhou, Y.; Jiang, W.; Du, H.; Tang, B.; Shi, J.; Jiang, B.; Cao, X.; Lin, B.; Fu, Q.; Zhu, C.; Guo, W.; Huang, Y.; Yao, Y.; Parkin, S. S. P.; Zhou, J.; Gao, Y.; Wang, Y.; Hou, Y.; Yao, Y.; Suenaga, K.; Wu, X.; Liu, Z. Heterodimensional superlattice with in-plane anomalous Hall effect. Nature 2022, 609, 46&#8211; 51, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-022-05031-2 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.12Chen, P.; Zhang, Z.; Duan, X.; Duan, X. Chemical synthesis of two-dimensional atomic crystals, heterostructures and superlattices. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2018, 47, 3129&#8211; 3151, DOI: 10.1039/C7CS00887B Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.13Zhou, J.; Lin, Z.; Ren, H.; Duan, X.; Shakir, I.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Layered intercalation materials. Adv. Mater. 2021, 33, 2004557, DOI: 10.1002/adma.202004557 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.14Ross, J. S.; Klement, P.; Jones, A. M.; Ghimire, N. J.; Yan, J.; Mandrus, D. G.; Taniguchi, T.; Watanabe, K.; Kitamura, K.; Yao, W.; Cobden, D. H.; Xu, X. Electrically tunable excitonic light-emitting diodes based on monolayer WSe2 p&#8211;n junctions. Nat. Nanotechnol. 2014, 9, 268&#8211; 272, DOI: 10.1038/nnano.2014.26 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.15Regan, E. C.; Wang, D.; Paik, E. Y.; Zeng, Y.; Zhang, L.; Zhu, J.; MacDonald, A. H.; Deng, H.; Wang, F. Emerging exciton physics in transition metal dichalcogenide heterobilayers. Nat. Rev. Mater. 2022, 7, 778&#8211; 795, DOI: 10.1038/s41578-022-00440-1 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.16Qian, Q.; Ren, H.; Zhou, J.; Wan, Z.; Zhou, J.; Yan, X.; Cai, J.; Wang, P.; Li, B.; Sofer, Z.; Li, B.; Duan, X.; Pan, X.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Chiral molecular intercalation superlattices. Nature 2022, 606, 902&#8211; 908, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-022-04846-3 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.17Schaibley, J. R.; Yu, H.; Clark, G.; Rivera, P.; Ross, J. S.; Seyler, K. L.; Yao, W.; Xu, X. Valleytronics in 2D materials. Nat. Rev. Mater. 2016, 1, 16055, DOI: 10.1038/natrevmats.2016.55 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.18Wan, Z.; Qiu, G.; Ren, H.; Qian, Q.; Li, Y.; Xu, D.; Zhou, J.; Zhou, J.; Zhou, B.; Wang, L.; Yang, T.-H.; Sofer, Z.; Huang, Y.; Wang, K. L.; Duan, X. Unconventional superconductivity in chiral molecule-TaS2 hybrid superlattices. Nature 2024, 632, 69&#8211; 74, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-024-07625-4 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.19Toth, M.; Aharonovich, I. Single photon sources in atomically thin materials. Annu. Rev. Phys. Chem. 2019, 70, 123&#8211; 142, DOI: 10.1146/annurev-physchem-042018-052628 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.20Liu, X.; Hersam, M. C. 2D materials for quantum information science. Nat. Rev. Mater. 2019, 4, 669&#8211; 684, DOI: 10.1038/s41578-019-0136-x Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.21Sun, H.; Mei, L.; Liang, J.; Zhao, Z.; Lee, C.; Fei, H.; Ding, M.; Lau, J.; Li, M.; Wang, C.; Xu, X.; Hao, G.; Papandrea, B.; Shakir, I.; Dunn, B.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Three-dimensional holey-graphene/niobia composite architectures for ultrahigh-rate energy storage. Science 2017, 356, 599&#8211; 604, DOI: 10.1126/science.aam5852 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.22Fei, H.; Dong, J.; Chen, D.; Hu, T.; Duan, X.; Shakir, I.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Single atom electrocatalysts supported on graphene or graphene-like carbons. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2019, 48, 5207&#8211; 5241, DOI: 10.1039/C9CS00422J Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.23Xia, C.; Qiu, Y.; Xia, Y.; Zhu, P.; King, G.; Zhang, X.; Wu, Z.; Kim, J. Y.; Cullen, D. A.; Zheng, D.; Li, P.; Shakouri, M.; Heredia, E.; Cui, P.; Alshareef, H. N.; Hu, Y.; Wang, H. General synthesis of single-atom catalysts with high metal loading using graphene quantum dots. Nat. Chem. 2021, 13, 887&#8211; 894, DOI: 10.1038/s41557-021-00734-x Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.24Peng, L.; Wei, Z.; Wan, C.; Li, J.; Chen, Z.; Zhu, D.; Baumann, D.; Liu, H.; Allen, C. S.; Xu, X.; Kirkland, A. I.; Shakir, I.; Almutairi, Z.; Tolbert, S.; Dunn, B.; Huang, Y.; Sautet, P.; Duan, X. A fundamental look at electrocatalytic sulfur reduction reaction. Nat. Catal. 2020, 3, 762&#8211; 770, DOI: 10.1038/s41929-020-0498-x Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.25Chavalekvirat, P.; Hirunpinyopas, W.; Deshsorn, K.; Jitapunkul, K.; Iamprasertkun, P. Liquid phase exfoliation of 2D materials and its electrochemical applications in the data-driven future. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 300&#8211; 329, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00119 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.26Shen, D.; Jin, Y.; Zhang, Z.; Song, R.; Liu, M.; Li, W.; Li, X.; Wu, R.; Li, B.; Li, J.; Zhao, B.; Duan, X. Recent advances in spin-coating precursor mediated chemical vapor deposition of two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 282&#8211; 299, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00115 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.27Zhu, Y.; Yu, B.; Liu, X.; Zhang, J.; Shi, Z.; Hu, Z.; Bu, S.; Li, C.; Zhang, X.; Lin, L. Synthesis of large-sized van der Waals layered MoO3 single crystals with improved dielectric performance. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.4c00014 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.28Cui, G.; Qi, J.; Liang, Z.; Zeng, F.; Zhang, X.; Xu, X.; Liu, K. Growth of noncentrosymmetric two-dimensional single crystals. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 330&#8211; 354, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00122 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.29Yin, Y.; Li, J.; Ding, F. Reconstruction of gold surface with excessive sulfur source during transition metal disulfide growth. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.4c00018 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.30Wang, C.; Zhou, Z.; Gao, L. Two-dimensional van der Waals superconductor heterostructures: Josephson junctions and beyond. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 273&#8211; 281, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00126 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.31Ren, H.; Zhou, J.; Zhang, A.; Wu, Z.; Cai, J.; Fu, X.; Zhou, J.; Wan, Z.; Zhou, B.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Precision control of amphoteric doping in CuxBi2Se3 nanoplates. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.4c00046 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.32Zhang, J.; Guo, J.; Zhang, H.; Liu, J.; You, S.-Y.; Jiang, L. Solution-processed monolayer molecular crystals: from precise preparation to advanced applications. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00124 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.33Zhu, Y.; Yan, Y.; Feng, Y.; Liu, Y.; Lin, C.-Y.; Ai, Q.; Zhai, T.; Shin, B.; Xu, R.; Shen, H.; Fang, Q.; Zhang, X.; Bhagwandin, D.; Han, Y.; Zhu, H.; Glavin, N. R.; Ajayan, P. M.; Li, Q.; Lou, J. A general synthesis method for covalent organic framework and inorganic 2D materials hybrids. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00118 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.34Chen, S.; Zheng, X.; Gao, Y.; Ping, X.; Xue, Y.; Li, Y. Controlled synthesis of graphdiyne-based multiscale catalysts for energy conversion. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 355&#8211; 375, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00125 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.Cited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferencesOpen PDF Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsPrecision ChemistryCite this: Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 8, 376&#8211;379Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00065Published August 26, 2024 Publication History Received 4 August 2024Published online 26 August 2024Published in issue 26 August 2024University of Science and Technology of China and American Chemical Society. Co-published 2024 by University of Science and Technology of China and American Chemical Society. This publication is licensed under CC-BY-NC-ND 4.0. License Summary*You are free to share (copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format within the parameters below:Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license.Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.Non-Commercial (NC): Only non-commercial uses of the work are permitted. No Derivatives (ND): Derivative works may be created for non-commercial purposes, but sharing is prohibited. View full license*DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. Article Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesThis publication has no figures.References This article references 34 other publications. 1Novoselov, K. S.; Geim, A. K.; Morozov, S. V.; Jiang, D.; Zhang, Y.; Dubonos, S. V.; Grigorieva, I. V.; Firsov, A. A. Electric field effect in atomically thin carbon films. Science 2004, 306, 666&#8211; 669, DOI: 10.1126/science.1102896 There is no corresponding record for this reference.2Zhi, C.; Bando, Y.; Tang, C.; Kuwahara, H.; Golberg, D. Large-scale fabrication of boron nitride nanosheets and their utilization in polymeric composites with improved thermal and mechanical properties. Adv. Mater. 2009, 21, 2889&#8211; 2893, DOI: 10.1002/adma.200900323 There is no corresponding record for this reference.3Chhowalla, M.; Shin, H. S.; Eda, G.; Li, L.-J.; Loh, K. P.; Zhang, H. The chemistry of two-dimensional layered transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets. Nat. Chem. 2013, 5, 263&#8211; 275, DOI: 10.1038/nchem.1589 There is no corresponding record for this reference.4Naguib, M.; Mochalin, V. N.; Barsoum, M. W.; Gogotsi, Y. 25th anniversary article: Mxenes: a new family of two-dimensional materials. Adv. Mater. 2014, 26, 992&#8211; 1005, DOI: 10.1002/adma.201304138 There is no corresponding record for this reference.5Li, G.; Li, Y.; Liu, H.; Guo, Y.; Li, Y.; Zhu, D. Architecture of graphdiyne nanoscale films. Chem. Commun. 2010, 46, 3256&#8211; 3258, DOI: 10.1039/b922733d There is no corresponding record for this reference.6Zhong, Y.; Cheng, B.; Park, C.; Ray, A.; Brown, S.; Mujid, F.; Lee, J.-U.; Zhou, H.; Suh, J.; Lee, K.-H.; Mannix, A. J.; Kang, K.; Sibener, S. J.; Muller, D. A.; Park, J. Wafer-scale synthesis of monolayer two-dimensional porphyrin polymers for hybrid superlattices. Science 2019, 366, 1379&#8211; 1384, DOI: 10.1126/science.aax9385 There is no corresponding record for this reference.7Dong, J.; Liu, L.; Tan, C.; Xu, Q.; Zhang, J.; Qiao, Z.; Chu, D.; Liu, Y.; Zhang, Q.; Jiang, J.; Han, Y.; Davis, A. P.; Cui, Y. Free-standing homochiral 2D monolayers by exfoliation of molecular crystals. Nature 2022, 602, 606&#8211; 611, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-022-04407-8 There is no corresponding record for this reference.8Zhang, Z.; Chen, P.; Yang, X.; Liu, Y.; Ma, H.; Li, J.; Zhao, B.; Luo, J.; Duan, X.; Duan, X. Ultrafast growth of large single crystals of monolayer WS2 and WSe2. Natl. Sci. Rev. 2020, 7, 737&#8211; 744, DOI: 10.1093/nsr/nwz223 There is no corresponding record for this reference.9Li, J.; Yang, X.; Liu, Y.; Huang, B.; Wu, R.; Zhang, Z.; Zhao, B.; Ma, H.; Dang, W.; Wei, Z.; Wang, K.; Lin, Z.; Yan, X.; Sun, M.; Li, B.; Pan, X.; Luo, J.; Zhang, G.; Liu, Y.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X.; Duan, X. General synthesis of two-dimensional van der Waals heterostructure arrays. Nature 2020, 579, 368&#8211; 374, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-020-2098-y There is no corresponding record for this reference.10Wang, C.; He, Q.; Halim, U.; Liu, Y.; Zhu, E.; Lin, Z.; Xiao, H.; Duan, X.; Feng, Z.; Cheng, R.; Weiss, N. O.; Ye, G.; Huang, Y.-C.; Wu, H.; Cheng, H.-C.; Shakir, I.; Liao, L.; Chen, X.; Goddard, W. A., III; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Monolayer atomic crystal molecular superlattices. Nature 2018, 555, 231&#8211; 236, DOI: 10.1038/nature25774 There is no corresponding record for this reference.11Zhou, J.; Zhang, W.; Lin, Y.-C.; Cao, J.; Zhou, Y.; Jiang, W.; Du, H.; Tang, B.; Shi, J.; Jiang, B.; Cao, X.; Lin, B.; Fu, Q.; Zhu, C.; Guo, W.; Huang, Y.; Yao, Y.; Parkin, S. S. P.; Zhou, J.; Gao, Y.; Wang, Y.; Hou, Y.; Yao, Y.; Suenaga, K.; Wu, X.; Liu, Z. Heterodimensional superlattice with in-plane anomalous Hall effect. Nature 2022, 609, 46&#8211; 51, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-022-05031-2 There is no corresponding record for this reference.12Chen, P.; Zhang, Z.; Duan, X.; Duan, X. Chemical synthesis of two-dimensional atomic crystals, heterostructures and superlattices. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2018, 47, 3129&#8211; 3151, DOI: 10.1039/C7CS00887B There is no corresponding record for this reference.13Zhou, J.; Lin, Z.; Ren, H.; Duan, X.; Shakir, I.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Layered intercalation materials. Adv. Mater. 2021, 33, 2004557, DOI: 10.1002/adma.202004557 There is no corresponding record for this reference.14Ross, J. S.; Klement, P.; Jones, A. M.; Ghimire, N. J.; Yan, J.; Mandrus, D. G.; Taniguchi, T.; Watanabe, K.; Kitamura, K.; Yao, W.; Cobden, D. H.; Xu, X. Electrically tunable excitonic light-emitting diodes based on monolayer WSe2 p&#8211;n junctions. Nat. Nanotechnol. 2014, 9, 268&#8211; 272, DOI: 10.1038/nnano.2014.26 There is no corresponding record for this reference.15Regan, E. C.; Wang, D.; Paik, E. Y.; Zeng, Y.; Zhang, L.; Zhu, J.; MacDonald, A. H.; Deng, H.; Wang, F. Emerging exciton physics in transition metal dichalcogenide heterobilayers. Nat. Rev. Mater. 2022, 7, 778&#8211; 795, DOI: 10.1038/s41578-022-00440-1 There is no corresponding record for this reference.16Qian, Q.; Ren, H.; Zhou, J.; Wan, Z.; Zhou, J.; Yan, X.; Cai, J.; Wang, P.; Li, B.; Sofer, Z.; Li, B.; Duan, X.; Pan, X.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Chiral molecular intercalation superlattices. Nature 2022, 606, 902&#8211; 908, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-022-04846-3 There is no corresponding record for this reference.17Schaibley, J. R.; Yu, H.; Clark, G.; Rivera, P.; Ross, J. S.; Seyler, K. L.; Yao, W.; Xu, X. Valleytronics in 2D materials. Nat. Rev. Mater. 2016, 1, 16055, DOI: 10.1038/natrevmats.2016.55 There is no corresponding record for this reference.18Wan, Z.; Qiu, G.; Ren, H.; Qian, Q.; Li, Y.; Xu, D.; Zhou, J.; Zhou, J.; Zhou, B.; Wang, L.; Yang, T.-H.; Sofer, Z.; Huang, Y.; Wang, K. L.; Duan, X. Unconventional superconductivity in chiral molecule-TaS2 hybrid superlattices. Nature 2024, 632, 69&#8211; 74, DOI: 10.1038/s41586-024-07625-4 There is no corresponding record for this reference.19Toth, M.; Aharonovich, I. Single photon sources in atomically thin materials. Annu. Rev. Phys. Chem. 2019, 70, 123&#8211; 142, DOI: 10.1146/annurev-physchem-042018-052628 There is no corresponding record for this reference.20Liu, X.; Hersam, M. C. 2D materials for quantum information science. Nat. Rev. Mater. 2019, 4, 669&#8211; 684, DOI: 10.1038/s41578-019-0136-x There is no corresponding record for this reference.21Sun, H.; Mei, L.; Liang, J.; Zhao, Z.; Lee, C.; Fei, H.; Ding, M.; Lau, J.; Li, M.; Wang, C.; Xu, X.; Hao, G.; Papandrea, B.; Shakir, I.; Dunn, B.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Three-dimensional holey-graphene/niobia composite architectures for ultrahigh-rate energy storage. Science 2017, 356, 599&#8211; 604, DOI: 10.1126/science.aam5852 There is no corresponding record for this reference.22Fei, H.; Dong, J.; Chen, D.; Hu, T.; Duan, X.; Shakir, I.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Single atom electrocatalysts supported on graphene or graphene-like carbons. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2019, 48, 5207&#8211; 5241, DOI: 10.1039/C9CS00422J There is no corresponding record for this reference.23Xia, C.; Qiu, Y.; Xia, Y.; Zhu, P.; King, G.; Zhang, X.; Wu, Z.; Kim, J. Y.; Cullen, D. A.; Zheng, D.; Li, P.; Shakouri, M.; Heredia, E.; Cui, P.; Alshareef, H. N.; Hu, Y.; Wang, H. General synthesis of single-atom catalysts with high metal loading using graphene quantum dots. Nat. Chem. 2021, 13, 887&#8211; 894, DOI: 10.1038/s41557-021-00734-x There is no corresponding record for this reference.24Peng, L.; Wei, Z.; Wan, C.; Li, J.; Chen, Z.; Zhu, D.; Baumann, D.; Liu, H.; Allen, C. S.; Xu, X.; Kirkland, A. I.; Shakir, I.; Almutairi, Z.; Tolbert, S.; Dunn, B.; Huang, Y.; Sautet, P.; Duan, X. A fundamental look at electrocatalytic sulfur reduction reaction. Nat. Catal. 2020, 3, 762&#8211; 770, DOI: 10.1038/s41929-020-0498-x There is no corresponding record for this reference.25Chavalekvirat, P.; Hirunpinyopas, W.; Deshsorn, K.; Jitapunkul, K.; Iamprasertkun, P. Liquid phase exfoliation of 2D materials and its electrochemical applications in the data-driven future. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 300&#8211; 329, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00119 There is no corresponding record for this reference.26Shen, D.; Jin, Y.; Zhang, Z.; Song, R.; Liu, M.; Li, W.; Li, X.; Wu, R.; Li, B.; Li, J.; Zhao, B.; Duan, X. Recent advances in spin-coating precursor mediated chemical vapor deposition of two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 282&#8211; 299, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00115 There is no corresponding record for this reference.27Zhu, Y.; Yu, B.; Liu, X.; Zhang, J.; Shi, Z.; Hu, Z.; Bu, S.; Li, C.; Zhang, X.; Lin, L. Synthesis of large-sized van der Waals layered MoO3 single crystals with improved dielectric performance. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.4c00014 There is no corresponding record for this reference.28Cui, G.; Qi, J.; Liang, Z.; Zeng, F.; Zhang, X.; Xu, X.; Liu, K. Growth of noncentrosymmetric two-dimensional single crystals. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 330&#8211; 354, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00122 There is no corresponding record for this reference.29Yin, Y.; Li, J.; Ding, F. Reconstruction of gold surface with excessive sulfur source during transition metal disulfide growth. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.4c00018 There is no corresponding record for this reference.30Wang, C.; Zhou, Z.; Gao, L. Two-dimensional van der Waals superconductor heterostructures: Josephson junctions and beyond. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 273&#8211; 281, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00126 There is no corresponding record for this reference.31Ren, H.; Zhou, J.; Zhang, A.; Wu, Z.; Cai, J.; Fu, X.; Zhou, J.; Wan, Z.; Zhou, B.; Huang, Y.; Duan, X. Precision control of amphoteric doping in CuxBi2Se3 nanoplates. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.4c00046 There is no corresponding record for this reference.32Zhang, J.; Guo, J.; Zhang, H.; Liu, J.; You, S.-Y.; Jiang, L. Solution-processed monolayer molecular crystals: from precise preparation to advanced applications. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00124 There is no corresponding record for this reference.33Zhu, Y.; Yan, Y.; Feng, Y.; Liu, Y.; Lin, C.-Y.; Ai, Q.; Zhai, T.; Shin, B.; Xu, R.; Shen, H.; Fang, Q.; Zhang, X.; Bhagwandin, D.; Han, Y.; Zhu, H.; Glavin, N. R.; Ajayan, P. M.; Li, Q.; Lou, J. A general synthesis method for covalent organic framework and inorganic 2D materials hybrids. Precis. Chem. 2024, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00118 There is no corresponding record for this reference.34Chen, S.; Zheng, X.; Gao, Y.; Ping, X.; Xue, Y.; Li, Y. Controlled synthesis of graphdiyne-based multiscale catalysts for energy conversion. Precis. Chem. 2024, 2, 355&#8211; 375, DOI: 10.1021/prechem.3c00125 There is no corresponding record for this reference.</description>
      <author>Xiangfeng Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00065</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
