<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 01:10:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Concept of Utilizing Ionic Liquids for the Co&#8208;electroreduction of Carbon Dioxide and Nitrogen&#8208;containing Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400966</link>
      <description>Burcu Gurkan, Saudagar Dongare, Oguz Kagan Coskun, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400325291

                Formation of C&#8208;N bonds through the electrochemical utilization of CO2 and nitrogen containing compounds (N&#8208;compounds) is appealing for the purpose of converting waste and readily available sources or pollutants into value added chemicals at ambient conditions. Existing research predominantly explores these electrochemical reactions independently, often in aqueous electrolytes, leading to challenges associated with competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), low product selectivity, and yield. Functional electrolytes such as those containing ionic liquids (ILs) present selective solubility to the solute reactants and present unique interactions with the electrode surface that can suppress the undesired side reaction HER while simultaneously co&#8208;catalyzing the conversion of CO2 and N&#8208;compounds such as N2, NO, NO2, andNO3. In this concept paper, we discuss how the microenvironment enabled by ILs can be leveraged to stabilize reaction intermediates at the electrode&#8208;electrolyte interface, thereby promoting C&#8208;N bond formation on an active electrode surface at reduced overpotential, with the case study of CO2 and N&#8208;compounds co&#8208;catalysis to generate urea.</description>
      <author>Burcu Gurkan, Saudagar Dongare, Oguz Kagan Coskun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400966</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scale-up study of electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction process through data-driven modelling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132400</link>
      <description>G.Q. Zhang, Xiaoteng Liu, Hanhui Lei, Yucheng Wang, Denise Bildan, Xiangqun Zhuge, Lei Xing, Zhihong Luo, Fuel. 373(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400334040

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G.Q. Zhang, Xiaoteng Liu, Hanhui Lei, Yucheng Wang, Denise Bildan, Xiangqun Zhuge, Lei Xing, Zhihong Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coinage metal effect on the reduction of carbon dioxide with monomeric metal&#8208;hydride complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400280</link>
      <description>Diego Sorbelli, Leonardo Belpassi, Paola Belanzoni, European journal of inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400382434

                The role of the coinage metal in monomeric hydride complexes for the reduction of carbon dioxide to formate has been computationally addressed in this work. The common reaction mechanism, i.e. a concerted M&#8208;H (M = Cu, Ag, Au) bond attack to the CO2 carbon atom with one oxygen atom coordinating to the metal center, has been analyzed, revealing a kinetically less favorable reactivity for the gold&#8208;hydride complex. A thorough computational investigation discloses that, while all complexes feature covalent electron&#8208;sharing M&#8208;H bonds, copper&#8208; and silver&#8208;hydride complexes display a relevant M(&#948;+)&#8208;H(&#948;&#8208;) bond polarization, which enables an enhanced basicity of the hydride and, thereby, a more kinetically favorable CO2 reduction process. This study provides useful guidelines for the design of monomeric metal hydride complexes as promising candidates for the CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Diego Sorbelli, Leonardo Belpassi, Paola Belanzoni</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; Raman reveals the critical role of Pd in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4 on Cu-based catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213850</link>
      <description>Zi&#8208;Yu Du, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhengxin Qian, Shikang Li, Qing&#8208;Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Alexander V. Rudnev, Yue&#8208;Jiao Zhang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 161(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400422736

                Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) for CH4 production presents a promising strategy to address carbon neutrality, and the incorporation of a second metal has been proven effective in enhancing catalyst performance. Nevertheless, there remains limited comprehension regarding the fundamental factors responsible for the improved performance. Herein, the critical role of Pd in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4 on Cu-based catalysts has been revealed at a molecular level using in situ surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS). A &#8220;borrowing&#8221; SERS strategy has been developed by depositing Cu&#8211;Pd overlayers on plasmonic Au nanoparticles to achieve the in situ monitoring of the dynamic change of the intermediate during CO2RR. Electrochemical tests demonstrate that Pd incorporation significantly enhances selectivity toward CH4 production, and the Faradaic efficiency (FE) of CH4 is more than two times higher than that for the catalysts without Pd. The key intermediates, including *CO2&#8722;, *CO, and *OH, have been directly identified under CO2RR conditions, and their evolution with the electrochemical environments has been determined. It is found that Pd incorporation promotes the activation of both CO2 and H2O molecules and accelerates the formation of abundant active *CO and hydrogen species, thus enhancing the CH4 selectivity. This work offers fundamental insights into the understanding of the molecular mechanism of CO2RR and opens up possibilities for designing more efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zi&#8208;Yu Du, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhengxin Qian, Shikang Li, Qing&#8208;Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Alexander V. Rudnev, Yue&#8208;Jiao Zhang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Well-defined asymmetric nitrogen/carbon-coordinated single metal sites for carbon dioxide conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.064</link>
      <description>Senhe Huang, Ziyu Fang, Chenbao Lu, Jichao Zhang, Jie Sun, Heng Ji, Jinhui Zhu, Jinhui Zhu, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400478062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Senhe Huang, Ziyu Fang, Chenbao Lu, Jichao Zhang, Jie Sun, Heng Ji, Jinhui Zhu, Jinhui Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover Picture: Light&#8208;Induced Dynamic Activation of Copper/Silicon Interface for Highly Selective Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412574</link>
      <description>Jiali Wang, Tsung-Chyan Lai, Han&#8208;Ting Lin, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Hsiao&#8208;Chien Chen, Chun&#8208;Sheng Tseng, Ching&#8208;Wei Tung, Chia&#8208;Ying Chien, Hao Ming Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400542014

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiali Wang, Tsung-Chyan Lai, Han&#8208;Ting Lin, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Hsiao&#8208;Chien Chen, Chun&#8208;Sheng Tseng, Ching&#8208;Wei Tung, Chia&#8208;Ying Chien, Hao Ming Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of Pynaphthyridine and Binaphthyridine Manganese(I) Tricarbonyl Complexes: Influence on Carbon Dioxide Reduction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.4c00008</link>
      <description>Kailyn Y. Cohen, Hovnan Simonyan, Mar&#237;a J. Ortiz, Bogdan Solomon, Luke Simkins, Raymond N. Dominey, Emma W. Goldman, Andrew B. Bocarsly, Organometallics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400544982

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kailyn Y. Cohen, Hovnan Simonyan, Mar&#237;a J. Ortiz, Bogdan Solomon, Luke Simkins, Raymond N. Dominey, Emma W. Goldman, Andrew B. Bocarsly</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.4c00008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can carbon emission trading policy enhance the synergistic emission reduction of carbon dioxide and air pollutants? A comparative study considering different pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132364</link>
      <description>Zhihao Chen, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400412621

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhihao Chen, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag-Precipitated CuO Nanospheres for Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145888</link>
      <description>Jingkun Xu, Ming Li, Liping Zhao, Guoqiang Zhong, Yu Zhang, Ziqi Zhang, Yu Sun, Xudong Hu, Zh&#233; Peng, Yicong Wang, Chunming Zheng, Xiaohong Sun, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400484824

                An electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an effective way to reduce greenhouse gases by converting CO2 into high-value-added chemical products using electricity generated from renewable energy. In this paper, a Cu2O spherical catalyst was prepared by ascorbic acid reduction. The precipitated Cu-Ag spherical catalyst (P-CuO-Ag) was successfully prepared by calcining Cu2O-Ag with the introduction of an Ag component as the substrate. During the electrochemical reduction of CO2, the FE of the P-CuO-Ag catalyst for C2H4 at a potential of &#8722;1.1 V vs. RHE was as high as 39.8%, which was nearly twice that of the CuO catalyst, while the local current density JC2H4 for C2H4 reached 6 mA cm&#8722;2. The incorporation of Ag gives the spherical CuO catalyst higher electrochemical activity and better kinetic performance than the catalyst without Ag.</description>
      <author>Jingkun Xu, Ming Li, Liping Zhao, Guoqiang Zhong, Yu Zhang, Ziqi Zhang, Yu Sun, Xudong Hu, Zh&#233; Peng, Yicong Wang, Chunming Zheng, Xiaohong Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of Co2 on Pure and Doped Cu2o(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4888703</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhichao Yu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400405522

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhichao Yu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4888703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction to Multicarbon Products on Non&#8208;Copper Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401173</link>
      <description>Jiayi Huang, Qianwen Liu, Jianmei Huang, Ming Xu, Wenchuan Lai, Zhi&#8208;Yuan Gu, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400509915

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) to value&#8208;added multicarbon (C2+) products offers a promising approach for achieving carbon neutrality and storing intermittent renewable energy. Copper (Cu)&#8208;based electrocatalysts generally play the predominant role in this process. Yet recently, more and more non&#8208;Cu materials have demonstrated the capability to convert CO2 into C2+, which provides impressive production efficiency even exceeding those on Cu, and a wider variety of C2+ compounds not achievable with Cu counterparts. This motivates us to organize the present review to make a timely and tutorial summary of recent progresses on developing non&#8208;Cu based catalysts for CO2&#8208;to&#8208;C2+. We begin by elucidating the reaction pathways for C2+ formation, with an emphasis on the unique C&#8208;C coupling mechanisms in non&#8208;Cu electrocatalysts. Subsequently, we summarize the typical C2+&#8208;involved non&#8208;Cu catalysts, including ds&#8208;, d&#8208; and p&#8208;block metals, as well as metal&#8208;free materials, presenting the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art design strategies to enhance C2+ efficiency. The system upgrading to promote C2+ productivity on non&#8208;Cu electrodes covering microbial electrosynthesis, electrolyte engineering, regulation of operational conditions, and synergistic co&#8208;electrolysis, is highlighted as well. Our review concludes with an exploration of the challenges and future opportunities in this rapidly evolving field.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Huang, Qianwen Liu, Jianmei Huang, Ming Xu, Wenchuan Lai, Zhi&#8208;Yuan Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on catalyst convergence: Unleashing the potential of MXenes for CO2 electrochemical reduction into high-value liquid product</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.06.006</link>
      <description>Samia, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Mohd Zul Hilmi Mayzan, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Nano materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400421350

                The electrochemical reduction reaction of carbon dioxide (CO2-ERR) holds tremendous potential as a key approach for achieving carbon neutrality by harnessing renewable resources. However, the current state of CO2-ERR encounters challenges in terms of efficiency and selectivity. Overcoming these obstacles requires the development of a robust electrocatalyst capable of enhancing process efficiency and improving selectivity towards desired products. In recent years, 2D materials have garnered significant attention as efficient catalysts. Among them, MXene stands out of high interest due to unique multilayered structure and presence of surface functional moieties. The MXene material offers high electrical conductivity, versatile surface chemistry, and tunable interface designs. This comprehensive review explores the utilization of MXene-based catalysts for CO2-ERR into valuable products. It covers fundamental aspects of electrochemical conversion, including CO2 adsorption on MXene Ti3C2Tx, the mechanism of CO2-ERR on MXene (Mo2CS2) single-atom catalysts, applications, synthesis methods of MXene production, and future prospects. Additionally, the review highlights the significance of modern artificial intelligence techniques, particularly machine learning, in screening and activating CO2, making it a pioneering scientific endeavor.</description>
      <author>Samia, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Mohd Zul Hilmi Mayzan, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.06.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomimetic Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Covalent Organic Frameworks with Tunable Pendant Groups for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411188</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Shuai Chen, Yunfei Yan, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Ning Huang, Yi Xiong, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400415878

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an effective way of converting CO2 into value&#8208;added products using renewable energy, whose activity and selectivity can be in principle maneuvered by tuning the microenvironment near catalytic sites. Here, we demonstrate a strategy for tuning the microenvironment of CO2RR by learning from the natural chlorophyll and heme. Specifically, the conductive covalent organic frameworks (COFs) linked by piperazine serve as versatile supports for single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs), and the pendant groups modified on the COFs can be readily tailored to offer different push&#8208;pull electronic effects for tunable microenvironment. As a result, while all the COFs exhibit high chemical structure stability under harsh conditions and good conductivity, the addition of &#8208;CH2NH2 can greatly enhance the activity and selectivity of CO2RR. As proven by experimental characterization and theoretical simulation, the electron&#8208;donating group (&#8208;CH2NH2) not only reduces the surface work function of COF, but also improves the adsorption energy of the key intermediate *COOH, compared with the COFs with electron&#8208;withdrawing groups (&#8208;CN, &#8208;COOH) near the active sites. This work provides insights into the microenvironment modulation of CO2RR electrocatalysts at the molecular level.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Shuai Chen, Yunfei Yan, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Ning Huang, Yi Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomimetic Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Covalent Organic Frameworks with Tunable Pendant Groups for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411188</link>
      <description>Tao Xie, Shuai Chen, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Ning Huang, Yi Xiong, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400415075

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an effective way of converting CO2 into value&#8208;added products using renewable energy, whose activity and selectivity can be in principle maneuvered by tuning the microenvironment near catalytic sites. Here, we demonstrate a strategy for tuning the microenvironment of CO2RR by learning from the natural chlorophyll and heme. Specifically, the conductive covalent organic frameworks (COFs) linked by piperazine serve as versatile supports for single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs), and the pendant groups modified on the COFs can be readily tailored to offer different push&#8208;pull electronic effects for tunable microenvironment. As a result, while all the COFs exhibit high chemical structure stability under harsh conditions and good conductivity, the addition of &#8208;CH2NH2 can greatly enhance the activity and selectivity of CO2RR. As proven by experimental characterization and theoretical simulation, the electron&#8208;donating group (&#8208;CH2NH2) not only reduces the surface work function of COF, but also improves the adsorption energy of the key intermediate *COOH, compared with the COFs with electron&#8208;withdrawing groups (&#8208;CN, &#8208;COOH) near the active sites. This work provides insights into the microenvironment modulation of CO2RR electrocatalysts at the molecular level.</description>
      <author>Tao Xie, Shuai Chen, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Ning Huang, Yi Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local microenvironment modulation of zirconium-porphyrinic frameworks for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153875</link>
      <description>Xue Zhao, Changyan Zhu, Heng Rao, Dong&#8208;Ying Du, Min Zhang, Ping She, Li Li, Jun&#8208;Sheng Qin, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400459415

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Zhao, Changyan Zhu, Heng Rao, Dong&#8208;Ying Du, Min Zhang, Ping She, Li Li, Jun&#8208;Sheng Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorinated chlorin chromophores for red-light-driven CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50084-8</link>
      <description>Shuang Yang, Zhiji Han, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Jueming Yi, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400426847

                Abstract The utilization of low-energy photons in light-driven reactions is an effective strategy for improving the efficiency of solar energy conversion. In nature, photosynthetic organisms use chlorophylls to harvest the red portion of sunlight, which ultimately drives the reduction of CO 2 . However, a molecular system that mimics such function is extremely rare in non-noble-metal catalysis. Here we report a series of synthetic fluorinated chlorins as biomimetic chromophores for CO 2 reduction, which catalytically produces CO under both 630 nm and 730 nm light irradiation, with turnover numbers of 1790 and 510, respectively. Under appropriate conditions, the system lasts over 240 h and stays active under 1% concentration of CO 2 . Mechanistic studies reveal that chlorin and chlorinphlorin are two key intermediates in red-light-driven CO 2 reduction, while corresponding porphyrin and bacteriochlorin are much less active forms of chromophores.</description>
      <author>Shuang Yang, Zhiji Han, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Jueming Yi, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50084-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the electrochemical reduction of CO2 on Au25(SR)18&#8722; nanocluster</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141462</link>
      <description>Dominic Alfonso, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400400371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dominic Alfonso</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Light-Matter Interaction with Photonic Architectures for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003463009-6</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Hui Cheng, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400350249

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Hui Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003463009-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure-performance relationships in MOF-derived electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pecs.2024.101175</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yuman Guo, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yi Liu, J Baeyens, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Progress in energy and combustion science. 104(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400405756

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yuman Guo, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yi Liu, J Baeyens, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pecs.2024.101175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Spatial Effects of Influencing Factors and Zoning Strategies for PM2.5 and CO2 Synergistic Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics12070498</link>
      <description>Zimu Jia, Shida Sun, Deming Zhao, Bo Yu, Yele Sun, Toxics. 12(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400444660

                China has identified the synergistic reduction of pollution and carbon emissions as a critical component of its environmental protection and climate mitigation efforts. An assessment of this synergy can provide clarity on the strategic management of both air pollution and carbon emissions. Due to the extensive regional differences in China, the spatial effects of influencing factors on this synergy exhibit variation across different provinces. In this study, the reduction indexes of PM2.5 and CO2 were calculated based on their reduction bases, reduction efforts, and reduction stabilities across provinces. Then, the synergistic reduction effect was assessed using an exponential function with the PM2.5 reduction index as the base and the CO2 reduction index as the exponent. Next, the MGWR model was applied in order to analyze the influencing factors of the synergistic reduction effect, considering natural settings, socioeconomic conditions, and external emission impacts. Finally, the k-means clustering method was utilized to classify provinces into different categories based on the degree of impact of each influencing factor. The results indicated that air circulation, vegetation, tertiary industry ratio, and emission reduction efficiency are major impact indicators that have a positive effect. The topography and emissions from neighboring provinces have a statistically significant negative impact. The spatial influences of different factors exhibit a distribution trend characterized by a high-high cluster and a low-low cluster. A total of 31 provinces are divided into three categories, and suggestions on the corresponding category are proposed, to provide a scientific reference to the synergistic reduction of PM2.5 and CO2.</description>
      <author>Zimu Jia, Shida Sun, Deming Zhao, Bo Yu, Yele Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics12070498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Design Innovation &#8211; A Case Study of 20% Weight Reduction and CO2 Emission Reduction in Door Panels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51202/9783181024355-213</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Paul Scholz, NULL AUTHOR_ID, VDI Verlag eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400430775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Paul Scholz, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51202/9783181024355-213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of crystal defects on the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction performance of pure copper</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2024.116268</link>
      <description>Shuai Hao, Kaveh Edalati, Qingsheng Gao, Huaijun Lin, Scripta materialia. 252(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400496350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Hao, Kaveh Edalati, Qingsheng Gao, Huaijun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2024.116268</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Based Materials for Low Concentration Co2 Capture and Electrocatalytic Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4891233</link>
      <description>Yanxi Hu, Yangyang Ding, Lily Y. Xie, Hanyu Li, Yujing Jiang, F. Gargano, Aidi Zhang, Wenlei Zhu, Yuanyuan Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400484792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanxi Hu, Yangyang Ding, Lily Y. Xie, Hanyu Li, Yujing Jiang, F. Gargano, Aidi Zhang, Wenlei Zhu, Yuanyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4891233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron distribution regulating of nonmetal doped monolayer g-GaN for enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160683</link>
      <description>Yafei Zhao, Liang He, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400398871

                Exploring inexpensive electrocatalysts that can efficiently and selectively convert CO2 into hydrocarbon fuels is important to promote carbon neutrality and solve the energy crisis. Current electrocatalysts, such as Cu-based alloys, single-atom catalysts, and dual-atom catalysts, use the d states of metal in the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction. Inspired by this, this work studies CO2 reduction reaction from another approach. Herein, using first principles study, we systematically investigate the prospect of nonmetal (B, C, O and F) doped monolayers g-GaN as electrocatalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction. We found that nonmetal doping can effectively regulate the electron distribution and p-band center of the active center (N site), which can adjust the initial adsorption, activation degree, charge transfer amount of CO2, and promote the formation of intermediates. Interestingly, B and C doped systems have better catalytic activity for CH4, with limiting potentials of &#8722;0.61 and &#8722;0.53 V, respectively. More importantly, F doped system has higher activity and selectivity for CH3OH production and inhibit competitive HER, with lower limiting potentials of &#8722;0.60 V. This study provides a new theoretical basis for the design and screening of electrocatalysts with high activity and product selectivity using nonmetal as the active site.</description>
      <author>Yafei Zhao, Liang He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction on Pd-Based Electrodes: From Mechanism Understanding to Rational Catalyst Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02379j</link>
      <description>Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Kun Jiang, Wen Cai, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400477996

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) driven by clean electricity to valuable chemicals provides a feasible way to carbon neutrality and thus attracts increasing attention. Among different transition-metal based CO2RR catalysts,...</description>
      <author>Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Kun Jiang, Wen Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02379j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highthroughput Screening of CuBi Bimetallic Catalyst Array for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction Reaction by Scanning Electrochemical Microscope</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400536</link>
      <description>X. Gu, Zhen Wang, Jie Li, Gang Ni, Limin Liu, Dongping Zhan, Juan Peng, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400558904

                The testing and evaluation of catalysts in CO2 electroreduction is a very tedious process. To study the catalytic system of CO2 reduction more quickly and efficiently, it is necessary to establish a method that can detect multiple catalysts at the same time. Herein, a series of CuBi bimetallic catalysts have been successfully prepared on a single glass carbon electrode by a scanning micropieptte contact method. The application of scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM) enabled the visualization of the CO2 reduction activity in diverse catalyst micro&#8208;points. The SECM imaging with Substrate generation/tip collection (SG/TC) mode was conducted on CuBi bimetallic micro&#8208;points, revealing that HER reaction emerged as the prevailing reaction when a low overpotential was employed. While the applied potential was lower than &#8208;1.5 V (vs Ag/AgCl), the reduction of CO2 to formic acid became dominant. Increasing the bismuth proportion in the bimetallic catalyst can inhibit the hydrogen evolution reaction at low potential and enhances the selectivity of the CO product at high cathode overpotential.This research offers a novel approach to examining arrays of catalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>X. Gu, Zhen Wang, Jie Li, Gang Ni, Limin Liu, Dongping Zhan, Juan Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of biochar-Cu-based catalysts construction and its electrochemical CO2 reduction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100250</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dongdong Feng, Yuxin Zhang, Zhaolin Wang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Shaozeng Sun, Carbon capture science &amp; technology. 13(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400411428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dongdong Feng, Yuxin Zhang, Zhaolin Wang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Shaozeng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alignment of Active Sites on Ag-Ni Catalysts for Highly Selective Co2 Reduction to Co</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4885315</link>
      <description>Huangdong Wang, Zhihua Guo, Heng Zhang, Jun Lin, Min Sun, Lei Han, Haorun Li, Yan Guo, Shanghong Zeng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400314636

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huangdong Wang, Zhihua Guo, Heng Zhang, Jun Lin, Min Sun, Lei Han, Haorun Li, Yan Guo, Shanghong Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4885315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-section design of the flow channels in membrane electrode assembly electrolyzer for CO2 reduction reaction through numerical simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110204</link>
      <description>Lili Zhang, Hui Gao, Gong Zhang, Yuning Dong, Kai Huang, Zifan Pang, Tuo Wang, Chunlei Pei, Peng Zhang, Jinlong Gong, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400388025

                Membrane electrode assembly (MEA) is widely considered to be the most promising type of electrolyzer for the practical application of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). In MEAs, a square-shaped cross-section in the flow channel is normally adopted, the configuration optimization of which could potentially enhance the performance of the electrolyzer. This paper describes the numerical simulation study on the impact of the flow-channel cross-section shapes in the MEA electrolyzer for CO2RR. The results show that wide flow channels with low heights are beneficial to the CO2RR by providing a uniform flow field of CO2, especially at high current densities. Moreover, the larger the electrolytic cell, the more significant the effect is. This study provides a theoretical basis for the design of high-performance MEA electrolyzers for CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Lili Zhang, Hui Gao, Gong Zhang, Yuning Dong, Kai Huang, Zifan Pang, Tuo Wang, Chunlei Pei, Peng Zhang, Jinlong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the SO2 tolerance of CO2 reduction electrocatalysts using a polymer/catalyst/ionomer heterojunction design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01577-9</link>
      <description>Panagiotis Papangelakis, Rui Kai Miao, Ruihu Lu, Hanqi Liu, Xi Wang, Adnan Ozden, Shijie Liu, Ning Sun, Colin P. O&#8217;Brien, Yongfeng Hu, Mohsen Shakouri, Qinghua Xiao, Mengsha Li, Behrooz Khatir, Jianan Erick Huang, Ya&#8208;Kun Wang, Yurou Celine Xiao, Feng Li, Ali Shayesteh Zeraati, Qiang Zhang, P. Liu, Kevin Golovin, Jane Y. Howe, Hongyan Liang, Ziyun Wang, Jun Li, Edward H. Sargent, David Sinton, Nature energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400324950

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Panagiotis Papangelakis, Rui Kai Miao, Ruihu Lu, Hanqi Liu, Xi Wang, Adnan Ozden, Shijie Liu, Ning Sun, Colin P. O&#8217;Brien, Yongfeng Hu, Mohsen Shakouri, Qinghua Xiao, Mengsha Li, Behrooz Khatir, Jianan Erick Huang, Ya&#8208;Kun Wang, Yurou Celine Xiao, Feng Li, Ali Shayesteh Zeraati, Qiang Zhang, P. Liu, Kevin Golovin, Jane Y. Howe, Hongyan Liang, Ziyun Wang, Jun Li, Edward H. Sargent, David Sinton</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01577-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The solvation environment of molecularly dispersed cobalt phthalocyanine determines methanol selectivity during electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01190-9</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Changfeng Zeng, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Elad Gross, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400423217

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Changfeng Zeng, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Elad Gross, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01190-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au depositing and Mg doping synergistically regulates In2O3 photocatalyst for promoting CO2 reduction and CH4 exclusive generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01381f</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400427821

                The photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) into methane (CH4) is of great significance in the field of energy conversion. In this study, magnesium-gold (Mg-Au) bimetallic-modified indium oxide (In2O3) microspheres...</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01381f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ synthesis of SnO/CuSnO3 nanostructures to catalyze azo dye degradation, CO2 reduction, and amines direct alkylation reactions under visible light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102515</link>
      <description>Mohsen Padervand, Alireza Bargahi, Bagher Efteakhri-Sis, Mohamed Saadi, Shahnaz Ghasemi, Elmuez A. Dawi, Abdelkader Labidi, Ghodrat Mahmoudi, Masoumeh Servati Gargari, Results in engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400381086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Padervand, Alireza Bargahi, Bagher Efteakhri-Sis, Mohamed Saadi, Shahnaz Ghasemi, Elmuez A. Dawi, Abdelkader Labidi, Ghodrat Mahmoudi, Masoumeh Servati Gargari</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the CO2 Emissions and Energy Source Consumption Nexus in Japan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16135742</link>
      <description>Kentaka Aruga, MN Islam, Arifa Jannat, Sustainability. 16(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400351835

                This research investigates the variation in the impact of different energy sources on carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions in Japan during the period from January 2019 to March 2023. The results of the Autoregressive Distributed Lag (ARDL) model suggest that a 1% increase in energy consumption produced through the photovoltaic (PV) decreases carbon emission by 0.053% in the short-run. Conversely, a 1% increase in coal, oil, and liquefied natural gas (LNG) leads to an increase in CO2 emissions by 0.317%, 0.038%, and 0.214%, respectively. The study also reveals an inverted-U-shaped relationship between CO2 emissions and economic growth, represented by the Nikkei stock index. The research emphasizes the critical need for Japan to prioritize investments and incentives in renewable energy technologies such as the PV systems, which have been demonstrated to effectively reduce CO2 emissions in Japan. This is essential to uphold long-term ecological balance and to proactively support the ongoing reduction in CO2 intensity, a key objective outlined in the Paris Agreement.</description>
      <author>Kentaka Aruga, MN Islam, Arifa Jannat</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16135742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Biochar on Gaseous Carbon and Nitrogen Emissions in Paddy Fields: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071461</link>
      <description>Yidi Sun, Xuetao Wang, Chenxia Yang, Xiaoping Xin, Junlin Zheng, Tao Zong, Chaoyin Dou, Agronomy. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400351960

                The paddy field is a major source of gaseous carbon and nitrogen emissions, and reducing these emissions is of great significance for mitigating greenhouse effects and non-point source pollution in farmland. Biochar, derived from agricultural waste, possesses a stable structure, large specific surface area, abundant pore structures, and surface functional groups. These characteristics could enhance soil physicochemical properties and microbial activity, thereby facilitating the dual goals of increasing crop yield and reducing emissions. Based on numerous studies, this review summarizes the effects of biochar on the emissions of carbon dioxide (CO2), methane (CH4), nitrous oxide (N2O), and ammonia volatilization (NH3), as well as on global warming potential (GWP) and greenhouse gas emission intensity (GHGI). It elucidates the mechanism of emission reduction by biochar amendment from the perspective of carbon and nitrogen conversion processes and soil physicochemical and biological properties. Numerous studies showed the application of 5~40 t ha&#8722;1 biochar reduced CO2, CH4, N2O, and NH3 emissions by 1.64~89.6%, 8.6~89.6%, 10~90%, and 12.27~53%, respectively. A small number of studies found that the application of 5~48 t ha&#8722;1 biochar increased CO2, CH4, N2O, and NH3 emissions by 12~37%, 19.85~176%, 13~84.23%, and 5.47~70.9%, respectively. Most scholars have found that biochar has varying degrees of emission reduction capabilities in different parts of the world. Therefore, future research directions have been suggested for utilizing biochar to reduce carbon and nitrogen emissions in paddy fields.</description>
      <author>Yidi Sun, Xuetao Wang, Chenxia Yang, Xiaoping Xin, Junlin Zheng, Tao Zong, Chaoyin Dou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon taxation on high utility transport fuels: An implementation of enviro-economic analysis for the sustainable environment&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e33786</link>
      <description>Muhammad Usman, Amna Malik, Hafiz Zahid Nabi, Muhammad Imran Masood, M.A. Mujtaba, Yasser Fouad, H. Fayaz, Atika Qazi, Heliyon. 10(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400310986

                The humongous increase in carbon emissions in the past few decades presents an environmental challenge to the scientific community. The current study proposes a method of taxation on high-carbon emission fuels. For this purpose, a comparative enviro-economic analysis is carried out on the three most commonly used fuels (gasoline, Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG), and Compressed Natural Gas (CNG)). The speed of the test engine varied from 1800 to 4200 Revolution per Minute (RPM) in increments of 400 RPM. Performance parameters (Brake Power (BP), Brake Thermal Efficiency (BTHE), and Brake Specific Fuel Consumption (BSFC)) were measured using a hydro dynamometer. Emission analysis, including Carbon Dioxide (CO2), Carbon Monoxide (CO), Unburned Hydrocarbons (HC), and Nitrogen Oxide (NOx), was conducted using the TESTO 350 analyzer. The application of Weibull distribution with a 95 % confidence interval, on emission data, explained the adequacy of the data. Among test fuels, CNG emerged as an environment-friendly fuel with an emission reduction of 16, 42, and 43 percent for CO2, CO, and HC in comparison to gasoline. Also, BTHE and BSFC of CNG were better than other alternatives. Moreover, the carbon penalty for CNG fuel showed a price reduction of 32 and 20.8 percent in comparison to gasoline and LPG respectively. The study provides a novel approach to assess the environmental impact of fuels by economic analysis based on emitted carbon quantity. In addition, this very idea is novel in promoting the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) of the United Nations (UN) through carbon taxation.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Usman, Amna Malik, Hafiz Zahid Nabi, Muhammad Imran Masood, M.A. Mujtaba, Yasser Fouad, H. Fayaz, Atika Qazi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e33786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Analysis of Carbon Emissions from Highway Construction Based on Life Cycle Assessment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145897</link>
      <description>Shuohan Gao, Xuexin Liu, Chunying Lu, H Zhang, Xinjun Wang, Yaping Kong, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400522787

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions from the construction of road infrastructure have been of growing interest in recent years. This paper proposes a binary statistical method for highway construction based on project cost control and a construction management system. A quantitative analysis of the CO2 emissions from highway construction activities was also conducted to guide the formulation of a carbon reduction strategy. Taking an expressway in central China as a case study, the CO2 emissions from different construction activities were calculated. The results revealed that the CO2 emissions for the whole construction project reached 10,605.2 t&#183;km&#8722;1&#183;lane&#8722;1, with the raw material production and on-site construction phases accounting for 95.2% and 4.8%, respectively. The values for bridge and tunnel engineering were much higher than those for other engineering types. In the raw material production phase, steel and cement production contributed the most to emissions (more than 99%). During the on-site construction phase, diesel and electricity consumption contributed 90% to CO2 emissions, especially from earthwork, subgrade protection, bridge engineering, tunnel excavation, and pavement surfacing. Accordingly, efforts should be focused on the key points and directed toward using recycled and low-carbon materials and improving working efficiency, machinery performance, and construction technology.</description>
      <author>Shuohan Gao, Xuexin Liu, Chunying Lu, H Zhang, Xinjun Wang, Yaping Kong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforming CO2 into Synthetic Fuels: Modeling, Simulation, and Optimization Analysis of Methanol Production from Industrial Wastes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/eng5030070</link>
      <description>Vasiliki Kontou, Antonis Peppas, Sotiris Kottaridis, Chrysa Politi, Sotiri&#959;s Karellas, Eng. 5(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400443949

                Carbon capture and utilization (CCU) has emerged in recent years as a promising decarbonization solution for hard-to-abate industries. Compared to carbon capture and storage (CCS), CCU aims not for the storage of carbon dioxide (CO2) but for its use in the production of synthetic fuels, such as synthetic methanol (MeOH). Synthetic MeOH is produced through CO2 hydrogenation, utilizing green hydrogen (H2). Efficient use of CO2 and H2 feedstocks is essential to maximize the carbon reduction potential and energy efficiency of the process. This study performed an optimization analysis on a small-scale, containerized, and portable CO2 hydrogenation unit with a 5 kg MeOH/h production capacity goal, focusing on carbon conversion efficiency (CCE), MeOH yield, H2 consumption, and MeOH purity. The analysis was conducted using Aspen Plus V12. A single-pass model was used first to evaluate an initial reactor design. The reactor was then re-designed according to the results of the gas hourly space velocity (GHSV). The model was then expanded to include a recycling loop and the final reactor design was validated, aiming to maximize overall efficiency. The effects of the operational parameters including the reactor inlet temperature, reactor pressure, thermal fluid temperature, and condensation temperature were examined. The model was then further expanded to include the MeOH distillation process, and the effect of the distillation temperature was examined. The final product of the analysis was a fully-defined and optimized unit, achieving an 87.97% CCE and an 84.99% MeOH yield, consuming 1.11 kg H2/h for the production of 5.01 kg MeOH/h of 99.86 wt% purity. This study can provide valuable information and guidelines for designing small-scale, containerized, and portable CO2 hydrogenation units, which can serve as alternative solutions to address issues of H2 production and transportation related to large-scale installations.</description>
      <author>Vasiliki Kontou, Antonis Peppas, Sotiris Kottaridis, Chrysa Politi, Sotiri&#959;s Karellas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/eng5030070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seamless Reconstruction and Spatiotemporal Analysis of Satellite-based XCO2 Incorporating Temporal Characteristics: A Case Study in China during 2015-2020</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asr.2024.07.007</link>
      <description>Junchen He, Wei Wang, Nan Wang, Advances in space research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400392011

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) is a crucial greenhouse gas, and its concentration and spatiotemporal characteristics are among the principal sources of uncertainty in global warming assessments. Satellite remote sensing is a widely adopted, high-accuracy approach for monitoring atmospheric CO2. However, limited swath width and cloud cover significantly reduce satellite observation coverage. This study addresses the temporal changes in CO2 concentration and utilizes a machine learning-based fusion of multiple data sources to generate daily, full-coverage, 0.05&#176; spatial resolution column-averaged CO2 concentration data for China from 2015 to 2020. Ten-fold cross-validation yielded a determination coefficient R2 of 0.97, root mean square error of 0.92 ppm, and mean absolute error of 0.59 ppm. Compared to other datasets, this study's dataset exhibits superior accuracy and spatiotemporal detail. Using the produced CO2 concentration in this study, we conducted a spatiotemporal analysis of CO2 concentrations in China. The results indicate that, in general, the Western region exhibits a higher growth rate in CO2 concentration than the Eastern and Central regions, with areas of lower CO2 concentration experiencing higher growth rates while regions with higher CO2 concentration have lower growth rates. Moreover, the highest increase in CO2 concentration occurred in 2016, with a substantial decrease in CO2 concentration growth observed in 2018. Notably, the reduction in CO2 concentration in the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau region during the summer is considerably smaller than in other regions, possibly due to atmospheric transport from the Indian Peninsula.</description>
      <author>Junchen He, Wei Wang, Nan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asr.2024.07.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel interdisciplinary model for optimizing coalbed methane recovery and carbon dioxide sequestration: Fracture dynamics, gas mechanics, and its application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213984</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Feng Gao, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Danqi Li, Physics of fluids. 36(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400422279

                The Carbon Dioxide Enhanced Coalbed Methane (CO2-ECBM) technique significantly enhances clean energy extraction and mitigates climate change. Central to this process is the dynamic evolution of rough fracture networks within coal seams, influencing the migration of CO2 and natural gas. However, existing research lacks a comprehensive, quantitative approach to examining the micro-evolution of these fractures, including fracture roughness, fracture density, fracture touristy, and fracture size, particularly under thermo-hydro-mechanical effects. Addressing this gap, our study introduces an innovative, fractal model for quantitative analysis. This model intricately characterizes fracture networks in terms of number, tortuosity, length, and roughness, integrating them with fluid dynamics affected by external disturbances in CO2-ECBM projects. Upon rigorous validation, the finite element method analysis reveals significant impacts of micro-parameters on permeability and natural gas extraction. For instance, increasing CO2 injection pressure from 4 to 6 MPa changes fracture network density by up to 6.4%. A decrease in fracture density (Df) from 1.6 to 1.5 raises residual gas pressure by 2.7% and coal seam stress by 9.5%, indicating crucial considerations for project stability. Applying the proposed interdisciplinary model to assess CO2 emissions in Australia, it is can be obtained that when Df decreases from 1.6 to 1.5, the total amount of CO2 storage reduces by 17.71%&#8211;18.04%. Our results demonstrate the substantial influence of micro-fracture behaviors on CO2-ECBM projects, offering a ground-breaking solution for efficient greenhouse gas reduction and clean energy extraction, with practical implications for the energy sector's sustainability.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Feng Gao, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Danqi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Targeting of the Isocitrate Dehydrogenase Pathway and the Implications for Cancer Therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25137337</link>
      <description>Stanislav Ivanov, Olger Nano, Caroline Hana, Amalia Bonano-Rios, Atif M. Hussein, International journal of molecular sciences. 25(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400324206

                The advent of comprehensive genomic profiling using next-generation sequencing (NGS) has unveiled an abundance of potentially actionable genetic aberrations that have shaped our understanding of the cancer biology landscape. Isocitrate dehydrogenase (IDH) is an enzyme present in the cytosol (IDH1) and mitochondria (IDH2 and IDH3). In the mitochondrion, it catalyzes the irreversible oxidative decarboxylation of isocitrate, yielding the production of &#945;-ketoglutarate and nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NADPH) as well as carbon dioxide (CO2). In the cytosol, IDH catalyzes the decarboxylation of isocitrate to &#945;-ketoglutarate as well as the reverse reductive carboxylation of &#945;-ketoglutarate to isocitrate. These rate-limiting steps in the tricarboxylic acid cycle, as well as the cytoplasmic response to oxidative stress, play key roles in gene regulation, cell differentiation, and tissue homeostasis. Mutations in the genes encoding IDH1 and IDH2 and, less commonly, IDH3 have been found in a variety of cancers, most commonly glioma, acute myeloid leukemia (AML), chondrosarcoma, and intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma. In this paper, we intend to elucidate the theorized pathophysiology behind IDH isomer mutation, its implication in cancer manifestation, and discuss some of the available clinical data regarding the use of novel IDH inhibitors and their role in therapy.</description>
      <author>Stanislav Ivanov, Olger Nano, Caroline Hana, Amalia Bonano-Rios, Atif M. Hussein</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25137337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Biochar Supplementation on Grazing Beef Cow and Calf Performance, Enteric Methane and Carbon Dioxide Emissions, Fecal Egg Counts and Fecal Nutrient Composition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5539/sar.v13n2p40</link>
      <description>Daalkhaijav Damiran, Kathy Larson, H.A. Lardner, Sustainable agriculture research. 13(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400338176

                A three-year beef cow grazing study (2020-2022) was conducted to evaluate the effects of biochar supplementation on grazing cow performance, ruminal fermentation, fecal egg and oocyst count, fecal nutrient composition, and enteric methane (CH4) and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions. Each year, forty-eight spring-calving Angus beef cows (BW = 669 &amp;plusmn; 95 kg; mean &amp;plusmn; STD) stratified by BW, were randomly assigned to 1 of 2 treatments. Treatments included either (i) pelleted supplement with biochar (Biochar; 405 g/d) inclusion at 2.2% of DMI or (ii) control pellet (Control; base fiber - no biochar). Twenty-four ha meadow bromegrass (Bromus riparius Rehm.)-alfalfa (Medicago sativa L.) paddocks (8.6% CP, 51.1% TDN) were assigned to each treatment group for the 92-d grazing trial. Enteric CH4 and CO2 emissions were measured using SF6 tracer gas technique. Cow and calf performance, rumen fluid parameters were not (p &amp;gt; 0.05) affected by biochar supplementation. During trial biochar supplementation reduced fecal oocyst (Eimeria spp.) count (p &amp;lt; 0.011; 3.9 vs. 15.0 count/g DM) but increased carbon:nitrogen ratio (p &amp;lt; 0.029; 26.1 vs. 21.3) relative to initial measurements. The enteric methane emission reduction in response to biochar supplementation at 2.2% of DMI, was negligible (~6.0% reduced compared to control).</description>
      <author>Daalkhaijav Damiran, Kathy Larson, H.A. Lardner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5539/sar.v13n2p40</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUEL CONSUMPTION OF BELAZ DUMPERS AND CARBON DIOXIDE EMISSIONS USING THE EXAMPLE OF OPEN PIT 'TURIJA' OF THE BROWN COAL MINE BANOVI&#262;I</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51558/2303-5161.2024.12.12.77</link>
      <description>Jasmin Jamakovi&#263;, Sun&#269;ica Ma&#353;i&#263;, Glasnik Rudarsko-geolos&#780;ko-gra&#273;evinskog fakulteta/Glasnik rudarsko-geolos&#780;ko-gra&#273;evinskog fakulteta. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400460640

                This work sets out the methodology and presents the calculation results of the amount of carbon dioxide emitted into the atmosphere of the BelAz dump truck at the Open Pit "Turija" BCM Banovi&#263;i d.d., based on the fuel consumption monitoring data. Properly determined fuel consumption enables the calculation of the amount of carbon dioxide emitted and preventive measures, as well as the choice of its reduction strategy. Data collection took six months, then the data were analyzed, and thus the results were given for all dump trucks by months. Key words: fuel, open pit mining, BelAz dump truck, maintenance, Coal Mine Banovi&#263;i, carbon dioxide</description>
      <author>Jasmin Jamakovi&#263;, Sun&#269;ica Ma&#353;i&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51558/2303-5161.2024.12.12.77</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anionic Surfactant&#8211;Tailored Interfacial Microenvironment for Boosting Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07258</link>
      <description>Xin Yuan, Wangxin Ge, Yihua Zhu, Lei Dong, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400484381

                Both the catalyst and electrolyte deeply impact the performance of the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO</description>
      <author>Xin Yuan, Wangxin Ge, Yihua Zhu, Lei Dong, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnesium hydroxide addition reduces aqueous carbon dioxide in wastewater discharged to the ocean</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01506-4</link>
      <description>Vassilis Kitidis, Stephen A. Rackley, William J. Burt, Greg H. Rau, Sarah Fawcett, Miles Taylor, Glen A. Tarran, E. Malcolm S. Woodward, Carolyn Harris, T.W. Fileman, Communications earth &amp; environment. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400399728

                Abstract Ocean alkalinity enhancement (OAE) reduces the concentration of dissolved carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) in seawater, leading to atmospheric carbon dioxide removal (CDR). Here we report laboratory experiments and a field-trial of alkalinity enhancement through addition of magnesium hydroxide to wastewater and its subsequent discharge to the coastal ocean. In wastewater, a 10% increase of average alkalinity (+0.56 mmol/kg) led to a 74% reduction in aqueous CO 2 (&#8722;0.41 mmol/kg) and pH increase of 0.4 units to 7.78 (efficiency 0.73 molCO 2 /mol alkalinity). The alkalinization signal was limited to within a few metres of the ocean discharge, evident as 27.2 &#956;atm reduction in CO 2 partial pressure and 0.017 unit pH increase, and was consistent with rapid dilution of the alkali-treated wastewater. While this proof of concept field trial did not achieve CDR due to its small scale, it demonstrated the potential of magnesium hydroxide addition to wastewater as a CDR solution.</description>
      <author>Vassilis Kitidis, Stephen A. Rackley, William J. Burt, Greg H. Rau, Sarah Fawcett, Miles Taylor, Glen A. Tarran, E. Malcolm S. Woodward, Carolyn Harris, T.W. Fileman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01506-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Green Finance on Agricultural Pollution and Carbon Reduction: The Case of China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145832</link>
      <description>Li Cao, Jiaqi Gao, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400456873

                Based on the double-carbon target, the agricultural sector has implemented the concept of being green and synergistically promoted pollution and carbon reduction. Positioned as a novel financial paradigm, green finance places greater emphasis on environmental stewardship compared to its traditional counterparts. This focus enhances resource allocation efficiency, thereby achieving the goal of reducing pollution and carbon emissions. To research the influence of green finance on agricultural pollution and carbon reduction, this study leverages panel data spanning 2011 to 2021 from 31 provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities across China. It employs the fixed-effect model and mediating-effect model. The findings reveal that: (1) Green finance exerts a notable influence on reducing both pollution and carbon emissions in agriculture, with the latter showing a more pronounced effect. (2) Regional disparities exist in green finance, affecting agricultural pollution and carbon reduction. (3) By fostering technological innovation and optimizing industrial frameworks, green finance emerges as a catalyst for curbing surface pollution and carbon dioxide emissions in agriculture. On this basis, relevant suggestions are put forward to provide policy insights for improving the green financial system, which will help further promote carbon and pollution reduction.</description>
      <author>Li Cao, Jiaqi Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Emission Accounting and Reduction for Buildings Based on a Life Cycle Assessment: A Case Study in China&#8217;s Hot-Summer and Warm-Winter Region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145842</link>
      <description>Wanying Wang, Luyan Li, Victor Shi, Shervin Espahbod, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400448560

                At the 75th United Nations General Assembly, China committed to peaking carbon dioxide emissions by 2030 and achieving carbon neutrality by 2060. In response, the national standard &#8220;General Specification for Building Energy Conservation and Utilization of Renewable Energy&#8221; has been adopted across 20 provinces and cities in seven major regions, including North China, Northeast China, and South China. These regions have implemented stringent energy-saving and emission reduction reviews and quota requirements. Despite this, there is limited research on comprehensive life cycle carbon emission calculations and carbon reduction designs. This study addresses this gap by focusing on economically developed regions with high population density and substantial energy-saving potential, specifically targeting the warm winter and hot summer regions of China. Using a commercial building in Shenzhen as a case study, we established a carbon emission accounting model based on the life cycle assessment (LCA) method. We calculated carbon emissions during the material phase using the project&#8217;s bill of quantities and relevant carbon emission factors. Additionally, we used the CEEB 2023 software to design energy-saving and emission reduction solutions for the building. Our comparative analysis reveals that the new design reduces the carbon emissions of the case study building by 13.5%. This reduction not only mitigates the environmental impact of construction but also contributes to the fight against the greenhouse effect, supporting the broader goal of sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Wanying Wang, Luyan Li, Victor Shi, Shervin Espahbod</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Low-Carbon Economic Optimization Using CCUS and Two-Stage P2G with Multiple Hydrogen Utilizations for an Integrated Energy System with a High Penetration Level of Renewables</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16135722</link>
      <description>Junqiu Fan, Jing Zhang, Long Yuan, Rujing Yan, Yu He, Weixing Zhao, Nicol&#225;s Nin, Sustainability. 16(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400365975

                Integrating carbon capture and storage (CCS) technology into an integrated energy system (IES) can reduce its carbon emissions and enhance its low-carbon performance. However, the full CCS of flue gas displays a strong coupling between lean and rich liquor as carbon dioxide liquid absorbents. Its integration into IESs with a high penetration level of renewables results in insufficient flexibility and renewable curtailment. In addition, integrating split-flow CCS of flue gas facilitates a short capture time, giving priority to renewable energy. To address these limitations, this paper develops a carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS) method, into which storage tanks for lean and rich liquor and a two-stage power-to-gas (P2G) system with multiple utilizations of hydrogen including a fuel cell and a hydrogen-blended CHP unit are introduced. The CCUS is integrated into an IES to build an electricity&#8211;heat&#8211;hydrogen&#8211;gas IES. Accordingly, a deep low-carbon economic optimization strategy for this IES, which considers stepwise carbon trading, coal consumption, renewable curtailment penalties, and gas purchasing costs, is proposed. The effects of CCUS, the two-stage P2G system, and stepwise carbon trading on the performance of this IES are analyzed through a case-comparative analysis. The results show that the proposed method allows for a significant reduction in both carbon emissions and total operational costs. It outperforms the IES without CCUS with an 8.8% cost reduction and a 70.11% reduction in carbon emissions. Compared to the IES integrating full CCS, the proposed method yields reductions of 6.5% in costs and 24.7% in emissions. Furthermore, the addition of a two-stage P2G system with multiple utilizations of hydrogen further amplifies these benefits, cutting costs by 13.97% and emissions by 12.32%. In addition, integrating CCUS into IESs enables the full consumption of renewables and expands hydrogen utilization, and the renewable consumption proportion in IESs can reach 69.23%.</description>
      <author>Junqiu Fan, Jing Zhang, Long Yuan, Rujing Yan, Yu He, Weixing Zhao, Nicol&#225;s Nin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16135722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigation of satellite OCO-2 CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; biases in the vicinity of clouds with 3D calculations using the Education and Research 3D Radiative Transfer Toolbox (EaR3T)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1936</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Hong Chen, Steven T. Massie, S. S. Kulawik, NULL AUTHOR_ID, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400420320

                Abstract. Accurate and continuous measurements of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) are essential for climate change research and monitoring of emission reduction efforts. NASA's Orbiting Carbon Observatory (OCO-2/3) satellites have been deployed to measure the column-averaged CO2 dry air mixing ratio (XCO2) with very high precision. Although cloudy measurements are screened out, nearby clouds can still cause retrieval biases because the forward one-dimensional (1D) radiative transfer (RT) model used in the OCO retrieval algorithm does not account for the scattering induced by clouds in the vicinity of the OCO-2/3 footprints. These biases, referred to as the three-dimensional (3D) effects, can be quantified effectively using 3D-RT calculations, but these are computationally expensive, especially for hyperspectral applications (e.g., OCO-2/3). To reduce the prohibitive computational demands of 3D-RT radiance simulations across all three OCO spectral bands, this paper employs a linear approximation with two metrics (called slope and intercept) for each of the OCO bands that represent the 3D-RT perturbations on the OCO-2 spectra and accelerate the radiative transfer by a factor of 100. This is implemented by the Education and Research 3D Radiation Transfer Toolbox for OCO (EaR3T-OCO). EaR3T-OCO estimates OCO-2 satellite radiances using all available footprint-level data and imagery from the Aqua satellite, which orbits in close proximity to the OCO-2 satellite. EaR3T-OCO can calculate 3D-RT spectral perturbations for any OCO-2 footprint. These calculations can be used to spectrally adjust the OCO-2 radiance measurements with scene-dependent EaR3T-OCO perturbation calculations prior to the actual retrieval to undo cloud vicinity effects in the radiance spectra, which can subsequently be processed with the standard OCO-2 retrieval code. We find that this adjustment largely mitigates XCO2 retrieval biases in proximity to clouds over land &#8211; the first physics-based correction of 3D-RT effects on OCO-2/3 retrievals. Although the accelerated 3D-RT radiance adjustment step is faster than full 3D-RT calculations for all OCO spectral bands, it still requires at least as much computational effort as the XCO2 retrieval itself. To bypass 3D-RT altogether, the slope and intercept metrics are parameterized as a function of the weighted cloud distance of a footprint and several other scene parameters, all of which can be derived directly from Aqua-MODIS imagery. While this method is fastest and thus feasible for operational use, it requires careful validation for various surface and atmospheric conditions. For the case we analyzed, both the 3D-RT calculation method and the parametric bypass method successfully corrected XCO2 biases, which exceeded 2 ppm at the footprint level, and reached up to 0.7 ppm in the regional average. We find that the biases depend most strongly on the cloud field morphology and surface reflectance, but also on secondary factors such as aerosol layers and sun-sensor geometry.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Hong Chen, Steven T. Massie, S. S. Kulawik, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances on Photocatalytic CO2 reduction using CeO2-based Photocatalysts: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113487</link>
      <description>Khondaker Afrina Hoque, Sharmin Ara Sathi, Farjana Akter, Tania Akter, Tahsin Ahmed, Wahid Ullah, Kazi Arafin, Mohammad Sayadur Rahaman, Hossain M. Shahadat, Abu Bin Imran, Al&#8208;Nakib Chowdhury, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400390549

                Efforts to combat global warming and energy-related issues involve the solar-driven reduction of CO2 into worthy fuels and substances. However, the stable nature of CO2 demands high energy input for transformation. CO2 reduction using semiconductor materials activated by sunlight is gaining attention for its eco-friendly and economically viable nature. Despite progress, many solar-active catalysts for CO2 photoreduction encounter challenges like low efficiency and uncontrollable selectivity. The commonly used rare earth oxide ceria (CeO2) has low sunlight absorption, necessitating changes such as metal-nonmetal doping oxygen vacancy creation, the addition of co-catalysts, and the development of binary, ternary, Z-scheme, and S-scheme heterostructures to improve its use in visible light. Although there has been considerable research on CeO2 modifications, there is a lack of comprehensive study regarding their characteristics and the precise photochemical reduction mechanisms. This review aims to bridge this gap by thoroughly examining recent breakthroughs in CeO2-based photo reductants for CO2 reduction. It focuses on the synthetic techniques of photocatalysts and CO2 reduction processes, assesses photoactivity enhancement strategies, investigates underlying mechanisms, and addresses the factors influencing CO2 reduction, efficiencies and selectivity. Finally, the review concludes by offering insights into future challenges and prospects, guiding upcoming research toward sustainable and efficient CO2 reduction strategies.</description>
      <author>Khondaker Afrina Hoque, Sharmin Ara Sathi, Farjana Akter, Tania Akter, Tahsin Ahmed, Wahid Ullah, Kazi Arafin, Mohammad Sayadur Rahaman, Hossain M. Shahadat, Abu Bin Imran, Al&#8208;Nakib Chowdhury</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of slag-based foam concrete by chemical foaming for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; sequestration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37190/epe240206</link>
      <description>Wei Li, Zhi-wen Lyu, Jian Liu, Wei Li, Zhaoqing Sun, Ying Ma, Weimin Cheng, Xin Meng, Lin Xin, Xingshu Sun, Environment Protection Engineering. 50(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400322852

                Carbon dioxide emissions are among the most influential causes of global warming, and the recovery, capture, and comprehensive utilization of CO 2 are the keys to carbon emissions reduction. High-porosity foam concrete was prepared using CaO as the alkali activator, and H 2 O 2 as the foaming agent. Based on a single-factor experiment and response surface analysis, the best preparation conditions for foam concrete were obtained (water-to-cement ratio 0.4, alkali excitation dosage 10.73%, foaming agent dosage 8.26%). The porous material prepared under the optimal process conditions can achieve a CO 2 sequestration performance of 91.59 kg/m 3 , and the actual sequestration capacity is consistent with the theoretical prediction value of 90.89 kg/m 3 . Mechanistic analysis shows that the precarbonation hydration products of foam concrete are mainly C-S-H gel, Ca(OH) 2 , and hydrotalcite-like compounds, which bond the slag particles together to form a three-dimensional spatially firmly connected structure. This study provides a reference for the application of alkaline solid waste materials in the field of carbon sequestration.</description>
      <author>Wei Li, Zhi-wen Lyu, Jian Liu, Wei Li, Zhaoqing Sun, Ying Ma, Weimin Cheng, Xin Meng, Lin Xin, Xingshu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37190/epe240206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in the microscopic and mesoscopic simulation technologies developed for subsurface gas storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2024.10.01</link>
      <description>Tao Zhang, Jie Liu, Xuguang Yang, Shuyu Sun, Advances in Geo-energy research/Advances in geo-energy research. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400387333

                Subsurface gas storage refers to the practice of storing natural gas or other gases in underground reservoirs. It plays a crucial role in ensuring a stable and reliable supply of energy, especially during periods of high demand or supply disruptions. This work collectively highlights the significance of the microscopic and mesoscopic reservoir simulation techniques developed for subsurface gas storage. Specific technology progresses are demonstrated for a better storage of hydrogen and carbon dioxide, which meets well with the current focus on carbon reduction. In particular, molecular dynamics simulations can provide insight for the microscopic mechanisms affecting the adsorption and leakage of stored gas. Pore-network model generated using the advanced algorithm can determine the geological scenario for further flow and transport simulations. Document Type: Perspective Cited as: Zhang, T., Liu, J., Yang, X., Sun, S. Advances in the microscopic and mesoscopic simulation technologies developed for subsurface gas storage. Advances in Geo-Energy Research, 2024, 14(1): 1-3. https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2024.10.01</description>
      <author>Tao Zhang, Jie Liu, Xuguang Yang, Shuyu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2024.10.01</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data collection framework for enhanced carbon intensity indicator (&lt;scp&gt;CII&lt;/scp&gt;) in the oil tankers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjce.25384</link>
      <description>Abdullah Sh. Sardar, Mohan Anantharaman, T. M. Rabiul Islam, Vikram Garaniya, Canadian journal of chemical engineering/&#152;The &#156;Canadian journal of chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400508698

                Abstract The International Maritime Organization (IMO) aims to reduce greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions by 40% by 2030 compared with 2008. The carbon intensity indicator (CII) calculates the annual reduction factor required to continuously improve a ship's operational carbon intensity at a specific rating level. Verification and documentation of the achieved annual operational CII against the prescribed target are necessary to establish the operational carbon intensity rating. This study focuses on the intricate process of data collection for CII within the oil shipping industry, targeting engineering departments and shipboard management teams. Against the backdrop of the industry's substantial carbon dioxide emissions, the IMO has mandated the calculation of CII values for ships exceeding 5000 gross tons to promote sustainability and reduce environmental impact. We have collected emission data of 20 oil tankers over a period of 2 years using our ship maintenance and operating system (SMOS) and analyzed the data to compare the CII ratings. Our results indicate that a staggering ~63% of the vessels had the lowest CII rating of category E. It is therefore crucial to properly collect, organize, and evaluate data for CII calculation and take necessary measures to improve rating. This paper provides a deeper insight into the evolving CII calculation methodology, emphasizing the incorporation of correction factors and exclusions, and delineates the essential data collection practices needed to facilitate accurate CII calculations.</description>
      <author>Abdullah Sh. Sardar, Mohan Anantharaman, T. M. Rabiul Islam, Vikram Garaniya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjce.25384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cellular heterogeneity in hypertrophic burn scars in response to carbon dioxide laser therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.05.600800</link>
      <description>Chen Yy, C. R. Mahon, Jason D. Turner, Colum J Smith, Abdulrazak Abdulsalam, Ezekwe Amirize, Amy Preszler Prince, Adrian Heagerty, Claudia Roberts, Adam P. Croft, Yvonne Wilson, Naiem Moiemen, Janet M. Lord, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400386532

                Fractional carbon dioxide (AFCO2) laser therapy is used for treating pathological scarring, but the clinical outcomes are variable and the mechanisms of scar reduction poorly understood. We investigated the mechanisms underpinning efficacy of AFCO2 laser therapy, performing single-cell RNA sequencing in skin biopsies from patients with hypertrophic scars after AFCO2 laser therapy. Patients with younger scars (Good Responder, GR, &lt;6 years from healing) had better scar reduction than patients with older scars (Poor Responder, PR, &gt;6 years from healing) by various measures of scarring. scRNAseq analysis revealed that genes enriched in GR were associated with extracellular matrix and structure organisation (COL14A1, POSTN, SPARC); whereas genes enriched in PR were related to enhanced immune responses (IL-12, MSTN, HLA-DQA). The groups had distinct intercellular communication networks and differentiation trajectories after AFCO2, with regenerative Mesenchymal fibroblasts associated with a good response and inflammatory Secretory Papillary and Inflammatory Fibroblasts with a poor response.</description>
      <author>Chen Yy, C. R. Mahon, Jason D. Turner, Colum J Smith, Abdulrazak Abdulsalam, Ezekwe Amirize, Amy Preszler Prince, Adrian Heagerty, Claudia Roberts, Adam P. Croft, Yvonne Wilson, Naiem Moiemen, Janet M. Lord</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.05.600800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyelectrolyte mannan from diatoms reshapes sunlit ocean microbiome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.03.601839</link>
      <description>Joris Krull, Cynda Crawford, Chandni Sidhu, Vipul Solanki, Margot Bligh, Leonard R&#246;&#223;ler, Rajat Singh, Guoyin Huang, C.S. Robb, Hanno Teeling, Peter H. Seeberger, Thomas Schweder, Jan&#8208;Hendrik Hehemann, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400354227

                Algae catalyze half of the global solar powered reduction of carbon dioxide to organic molecules. While this organic synthesis shapes genomes of heterotrophic microbiota globally, many corresponding structures remain elusive. We show that diatoms release a mannan polyelectrolyte selecting for bacteria with a specifically adapted enzymatic cascade. NMR spectroscopy, chromatography, automated glycan assembly and enzymatic dissection resolved the structure of a C6 sulfated &#945;-1,3-mannan with exceptional simplicity for a sulfated polysaccharide from algae. Biochemical, physiological and structural analyses demonstrated that some bacteria can hydrolyze this mannan with a cascade of just four enzymes. Circumnavigation metagenome data revealed corresponding genes in Atlantic, Pacific, Southern and Indian Ocean surface waters. We show that this sulfated mannan may exert substantial selection pressure on marine microbiota around the globe.</description>
      <author>Joris Krull, Cynda Crawford, Chandni Sidhu, Vipul Solanki, Margot Bligh, Leonard R&#246;&#223;ler, Rajat Singh, Guoyin Huang, C.S. Robb, Hanno Teeling, Peter H. Seeberger, Thomas Schweder, Jan&#8208;Hendrik Hehemann</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.03.601839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A parametric study on syngas production by adding CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; on steam gasification of biomass system using ASPEN Plus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/cppm-2023-0100</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Chemical product and process modeling. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400417545

                Abstract Biomass gasification technology is increasingly employed as an environmentally friendly energy source, primarily due to its minimal impact on the environment and its ability to mitigate pollution. This technology excels in producing gas with exceptionally high hydrogen content, making it a valuable source for both fuel and energy carriers. Hydrogen (H 2 ), renowned for its stability and lack of detrimental environmental effects, holds great significance in various applications related to energy utilization and sustainability. In the current work, wood sawdust was utilized as the biomass feedstock for syngas production. The research focused on examining the impact of introducing carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) and methane (CH 4 ) gases into the Gibbs reactors. The steam gasification process was modeled by the ASPEN Plus software, allowing for comprehensive analysis and simulation of the gasification reactions. According to the obtained results, the modeling performed in this study demonstrates good predictive capability when compared to the experimental data. It was shown that when the ratio of CO 2 to biomass (C/B) increases, the MFR (mass flow rates) of H 2 as well as CH 4 decrease, whereas the flow rates of CO 2 and carbon monoxide (CO) increase. These findings indicate the influence of the C/B ratio on the distribution of different gases within the gasification process. The reduction in MFR of hydrogen when transitioning from C/B = 0 to C/B = 1 in modes a and b is quantified as 17.51 % and 16.39 %, respectively. These percentages represent the magnitude of the decrease in hydrogen MFR for each specific mode when comparing two carbon dioxide to biomass ratios. When the CH 4 to biomass (M/B) ratio increases, the mass flow rates of H 2 exhibit a consistent upward trend, while the MFR of CO 2 displays a descending form. Specifically, when in the Gibbs reactor, M/B rises from 0 to 1 for modes a and b, the mass flow rates of H 2 experience significant increases of 265 % and 243 %, respectively. These findings underscore the direct relationship between the M/B ratio and hydrogen production, highlighting the potential for enhanced hydrogen yields with higher M/B ratios in the studied modes.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/cppm-2023-0100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation-Dependent Impact of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on Cu-Catalyzed Electrochemical CO Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02498</link>
      <description>Yifei Xu, Wenqiang Gao, Zong-Xian Chen, Zhihui Yin, Zhuoyi Chen, Xiaoxia Chang, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng, Bingjun Xu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400331415

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) on Cu occurs via two tandem steps, i.e., the CO2-to-CO conversion and the electrochemical CO reduction reaction (CORR). Thus, Cu-catalyzed CO2RR on Cu is, in fact, coelectrolysis of CO2 and CO, which makes the impact of interfacial CO2 on the CORR a relevant factor in determining the overall CO2RR performance. In this work, we report the surprising observation that the effect of interfacial CO2 on the formation rate of C2+ products depends on the nature of cations in the electrolyte, i.e., beneficial with K+ and Cs+ while inhibitory with Li+ and Na+. Density functional theory calculations indicate that interfacial CO2&#948;&#8722; affects electrode-mediated reactions in two distinct modes with opposite effects, i.e., a general inhibitory effect of CO2&#948;&#8722; as an interfacial negatively charged species and a cation-specific promoting effect via direct CO2-cation interactions. The relative contributions of these two competing effects determine the overall impact of CO2 on the CORR. Furthermore, analysis of isotopologue distributions of products in the coelectrolysis of mixtures of 13CO/12CO2 reveals the influence of cations on the multiple steps of the CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Yifei Xu, Wenqiang Gao, Zong-Xian Chen, Zhihui Yin, Zhuoyi Chen, Xiaoxia Chang, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng, Bingjun Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of green finance on environmental protection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31893/multiscience.2024220</link>
      <description>Krenare Shahini Gollopeni, Jeton Mazllami, Multidisciplinary Science Journal. 6(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400349268

                Green finance, in contrast to traditional finance, has a close relationship with the environment and offers several advantages. This is why the study tries to illustrate how green financing affects environmental protection and evaluates its contribution to reducing environmental pollution. Green finance is an innovative method of funding with the goal of preserving the environment. It is crucial, widely discussed, and has caught the interest of many academics. They include programs that stimulate spending on initiatives aimed at minimizing adverse environmental effects. This study highlights the importance of green finance in environmental protection for the 36 OECD countries for the 11 years from 2010 to 2021. Panel data is used to derive results by applying models such as OLS, OLS Robust, Fixed effect, Random effects, and GMM. Empirical results according to the GMM method show that green finance has a positive impact on environmental protection, so the growth of green finance affects the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions.</description>
      <author>Krenare Shahini Gollopeni, Jeton Mazllami</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31893/multiscience.2024220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enzymatic Activation and Continuous Electrochemical Production of Methane from Dilute CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Sources with a Self-Healing Capsule</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03367</link>
      <description>Jinfeng Wang, Jing Xu, Yang Yang, Baijie Xu, Ruiming Jia, Chunying Duan, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400316114

                Converting dilute CO2 source into value-added chemicals and fuels is a promising route to reduce fossil fuel consumption and greenhouse gas emission, but integrating electrocatalysis with CO2 capture still faced marked challenges. Herein, we show that a self-healing metal&#8211;organic macrocycle functionalized as an electrochemical catalyst to selectively produce methane from flue gas and air with the lowest applied potential so far (0.06 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode, RHE) through an enzymatic activation fashion. The capsule emulates the enzyme' pocket to abstract one in situ-formed CO2-adduct molecule with the commercial amino alcohols, forming an easy-to-reduce substrate-involving clathrate to combine the CO2 capture with electroreduction for a thorough CO2 reduction. We find that the self-healing system exhibited enzymatic kinetics for the first time with the Michaelis&#8211;Menten mechanism in the electrochemical reduction of CO2 and maintained a methane Faraday efficiency (FE) of 74.24% with a selectivity of over 99% for continuous operation over 200 h. A consecutive working lab at 50 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2, in an eleven-for-one (10 h working and 1 h healing) electrolysis manner, gives a methane turnover number (TON) of more than 10,000 within 100 h. The integrated electrolysis with CO2 capture facilitates the thorough reduction of flue gas (ca. 13.0% of CO2) and first time of air (ca. 400 ppm of CO2 to 42.7 mL CH4 from 1.0 m3 air). The new self-healing strategy of molecular electrocatalyst with an enzymatic activation manner and anodic shifting of the applied potentials provided a departure from the existing electrochemical catalytic techniques.</description>
      <author>Jinfeng Wang, Jing Xu, Yang Yang, Baijie Xu, Ruiming Jia, Chunying Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical investigation of combustion characteristics of extended coherent flame model 3 zones (ECFM&#8208;3Z) in diesel engines running with biodiesel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.14422</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Hakan Kaleli&#775;, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Environmental progress &amp; sustainable energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400421585

                Abstract This research investigates the application of Extended Coherent Flame Model&#8208;3 Zones (ECFM&#8208;3Z) to assess the performance and emissions of rapeseed oil methyl ester (ROME). Experimental tests were carried out using a Lombardini 3 LD 350 model single&#8208;cylinder diesel engine, at 1600&#8211;3000 rpm with 200 rpm speed increments, under full load conditions. For numerical analysis, STAR&#8208;CD/ESICE software was employed. Methyl Oleate (C 19 H 36 O 2 ) was predicted as the surrogate biodiesel based on Gas Chromatography (GC) analysis and average mass calculation. Notably, the numerical analysis revealed a remarkable similarity in brake power between the experimental and computational investigations. In the range of 2400&#8211;3000 rpm, the biodiesel's performance exhibited a maximum deviation of 5%, primarily attributed to pumping, thermal, and friction losses. In terms of emissions, carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) emissions were consistent with the findings of the experimental study, with a maximum disparity of 10%. However, carbon monoxide (CO) emissions ranged from 57% to 65% lower than those observed in the experimental study, while nitrogen oxide (NO x ) emissions exhibited a reduction of 63% to 84%. In contrast, oxygen (O 2 ) emissions were notably higher, ranging from 93% to 117% compared to the experimental study, and exhaust temperatures were elevated by 33% to 49% in comparison to the experimental results.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Hakan Kaleli&#775;, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.14422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Izmenjava CO2 plodi&#269;ev jablane v &#269;asu trebljenja</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14720/aas.1998.71.1.16015</link>
      <description>M. Stopar, A. Gregor&#269;i&#269;, Franc Bati&#269;, Acta agriculturae Slovenica. 71(1)] 1998. https://openalex.org/W4400359710

                Fruit CO2 exchange at the time of fruit setting period was evaluated on mature cv. 'Jonagold' apple trees after 4 days artificial shading with 90 % photosynthetic photon flux (PPF) reduction and after NAA 15 ppm and BA 50 ppm applied immediately after the end of shading. Light reduction which accelerated fruitlets abscission very quickly had a depressive effect on fruits CO2 dark respiration rate (Rd) and gross assimilation rate (Ag) 3 days after the end of shading. Similarly, reduced Rd and less negative net CO2 assimilation rate (A) was recorded on fruitlets 7 days after NAA and BA application what is explained as a diminished metabolism of fruits starting with abscission. The fruitlets from shaded trees, which did not tend to abscission any more, showed an enhanced Rd and more negative A on 7th or 8th day after the end of shading. Ethylene evolution from fruits 2nd and 7th day after NAA 15 ppm application was enhanced comparing to control fruits. BA 50 ppm enhanced ethylene evolution on 2nd day after spraying, however on 7th day the ethylene evolution was lower than in control fruits. Healthy, not to drop inclined fruitlets retained on trees 7 days after shading treatment, showed stronger fruit ethylene production.</description>
      <author>M. Stopar, A. Gregor&#269;i&#269;, Franc Bati&#269;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 1998 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14720/aas.1998.71.1.16015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Design of an Electro-Organocatalyst for Conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; into Long Chain Aldehydes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00780</link>
      <description>Foroogh Khezeli, Craig Plaisance, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A/&#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A.. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400329981

                Density functional theory calculations employing a hybrid implicit/explicit solvation method were used to demonstrate that an electro-organocatalyst designed in our previous work for reducing CO2 to formaldehyde could also be capable of coupling formaldehyde to form long chain aldehydes. The catalytic activity is enabled by an electron-rich vicinal enediamine (&gt;N&#8211;C&#9552;C&#8211;N&lt;) backbone that activates formaldehyde by reversing the polarity on the carbon atom, enabling it to act as a nucleophile in the subsequent aldol addition step. The catalyst then enables reductive dehydroxylation of the aldol addition product by facilitating outer-sphere electron transfer. The optimal pH as well as the limiting potential and formaldehyde concentration are identified and related to the kinetic balance between several rate limiting steps. Finally, the optimal conditions for coupling with the CO2 reduction cycle are discussed, demonstrating that the electro-organocatalyst is capable of efficiently converting CO2 into aldehyde products with a turnover frequency (per carbon atom) on the order of 0.1&#8211;1 s&#8211;1.</description>
      <author>Foroogh Khezeli, Craig Plaisance</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00780</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financing Strategy Of Refuse Derived Fuel (Rdf) Plant Based On Investment Project Analysis (Case Study Cilacap RDF Plant)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31539/costing.v7i4.10879</link>
      <description>Reni Romaulina, Taufik Faturohman, Costing. 7(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400390118

                Refused Derived Fuel (RDF) is a waste processing method that can be used as co-firing in the cement industry. Currently, the Cilacap RDF Plant is one of the RDFs successfully operating in Indonesia, with a machine capacity of up to 200 tons/day. This success has encouraged many local governments to build RDF facilities to handle waste. The research aims to propose alternative funding scenarios for the development of RDF so that it can be applied in other places. Not all regions have the same opportunities as RDF Cilacap, where investment financing includes the construction of RDF facilities and machinery covered by many stakeholders. This study also calculates the potential for reducing CO2 emissions with the RDF plant and estimates the potential carbon trading value from the reduction in CO2 emissions. The analysis method in alternative scenario studies uses investment project analysis such as Discounted Cash Flow (DCF), NPV, IRR, Profitability Index, Payback Period, Discounted Payback Period, and IPCC 2006 to calculate CO2 emission reductions. The potential for reducing CO2 emissions in this study is calculated by comparing the value of CO2 produced if waste is disposed of in a landfill (open dumping) and the waste is processed into RDF. The research results show that the third scenario is suitable and feasible for regions planning to build an RDF Factory. It is recommended that the Central Government bear the responsibility for the RDF Factory building infrastructure and the investors or third parties take responsibility for the machinery. The potential for reducing CO2 emissions with the existence of the RDF Plant Cilacap for 20 years is 231,944.86 tons. If multiplied by the average price in the secondary market, IDR 69,600 (USD 4.45), the potential for obtaining funds is IDR 16,143 million, or equivalently, we calculate it in present value to IDR 5,284 million.</description>
      <author>Reni Romaulina, Taufik Faturohman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31539/costing.v7i4.10879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication and Characterization of PLA/PBAT Blends, Blend-Based Nanocomposites, and Their Supercritical Carbon Dioxide-Induced Foams</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16141971</link>
      <description>Kartik Behera, Chung-Hsien Tsai, Xia Liao, Fang-Chyou Chiu, Polymers. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400486574

                In this study, a twin-screw extruder was used to fabricate poly(lactic acid) (PLA)/poly(butylene adipate-co-terephthalate) (PBAT) blends and blend-based nanocomposites with carbon nanotube (CNT) or nanocarbon black (CB) as nanofillers. The fabricated samples were subsequently treated with supercritical carbon dioxide (scCO2) to fabricate the corresponding foams. Bi-phasic morphology and selective distribution of CNTs or CBs in the PBAT phase were observed in the blends/composites through scanning electron microscopy. After the scCO2 treatment, the selective foaming of the PBAT phase in the prepared blends/composites was confirmed. The cellular structure of PBAT phase in scCO2-treated blends is similar to the size/shape of PBAT domains in untreated blends or treated neat PBAT foam. The addition of CNTs or CBs in the blends led to a slight reduction in cell size of the foamed PBAT phase, demonstrating CNT/CB-induced cell nucleation. Differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) results showed that CNTs and CBs played as nucleating agents and increased the initial crystallization temperature up to 14 &#176;C compared with neat PBAT for PBAT in different composites during cooling. The scCO2 treatment induced the bimodal stability of PBAT crystals in different samples, which melted mainly in two temperature regions in DSC studies. Thermogravimetric analyses revealed that compared with parent blends, the addition of CNTs or CBs increased the temperature at 80 wt.% loss (degradation of PBAT portion) up to 6 &#176;C. The electrical resistivity decreased by more than six orders of magnitude for certain CNT- or CB-added composites compared with the parent blends. The hardness of the blends slightly increased after forming the corresponding composites and then declined after the scCO2 treatment.</description>
      <author>Kartik Behera, Chung-Hsien Tsai, Xia Liao, Fang-Chyou Chiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16141971</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 fixation in molten salts: A pathway towards the fabrication of exceptional carbon-based materials for pollutant removal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.07.004</link>
      <description>Zeyu Fan, Zhuo Fan Gao, Xian Zhou, Ziling Peng, Shanshan Deng, Qi Lu, Yuanyi Wang, Wei Yang, Xia Chen, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400386901

                Carbon-based materials have been widely applied for pollutant removal relying on their rich pore structure, functional groups, chemical stability, and expandability. However, the traditional manufacturing process of carbon materials based on organic compounds pyrolysis is high energy-consuming and high-emission, which is not conducive to addressing the climate crisis and achieving the goal of carbon neutrality. Molten salt electrolysis technology enables the direct capture and reduction of CO2 to produce solid carbon, resulting in significant environmental benefits while achieving carbon emissions reduction. The molten salt also has a purification function, enabling the production of high-purity carbon materials. The kinetics of the electrochemical reduction process can be easily controlled, and the co-reduction of multiple elements provides convenience for the in-situ optimization of carbon material structure and the expansion of its applications. Therefore, this review focuses on the thermodynamics &amp; kinetics processes of molten salt capture and electrochemical reduction of CO2 to prepare carbon materials. It further reviews the recent research progress on the preparation of carbon materials for pollutant removal based on molten salt electrochemical processes for the first time. Finally, we analyze the advantages and challenges of the current molten salt electrochemical processes and offers prospects for future research directions.</description>
      <author>Zeyu Fan, Zhuo Fan Gao, Xian Zhou, Ziling Peng, Shanshan Deng, Qi Lu, Yuanyi Wang, Wei Yang, Xia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.07.004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ammonia and Greenhouse Gas Emissions from Organic Manure Composting: The Effect of Membrane Cover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071471</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Muhammad Wajahat Ramay, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Csaba Gyuricza, NULL AUTHOR_ID, L&#225;szl&#243; Aleksza, Agronomy. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400424679

                The current scientific literature predominantly focuses on pilot-scale studies concerning the effectiveness of membrane covers in reducing gas emissions during cattle manure composting. Our study centers on the application of a leading market commercial membrane cover (ePTE-TEXcomm) and a locally manufactured one (ProfiCover&#174;) at industrial processing levels, evaluating their efficacy in mitigating gas emission during the fifth day of the thermophilic phase. Taking into account material inhomogeneities, work environment impact, and efficiency, the results are characteristic of industrial-scale processes rarely discussed in the scientific literature. Our results, obtained with a portable gas sampler and FTIR spectroscopy measurements using corresponding standards, indicate that ePTE-TEXcomm manifested a reduction of 90.8% for NH3 and 59.6% for CO2. CH4 emissions increased, suggesting their potential entrapment. N2O and propane equivalent experienced reductions of 23.1% and 44.8%, respectively. On the other hand, ProfiCover&#174; presented emission reductions for NH3 and CO2 of 93.3% and 85.9%, respectively. CH4, contrasting with ePTE-TEXcomm, showed a significant reduction of 55.6%. N2O and propane equivalent followed with reductions of 56.7% and 84.5%, respectively. All of this divergence in performance implies a potential trade-off in emission reduction efficacy between the covers. Knowledge sharing between researchers and industry partners is key to translating these technologies into widespread adoption.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Muhammad Wajahat Ramay, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Csaba Gyuricza, NULL AUTHOR_ID, L&#225;szl&#243; Aleksza</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the mechanism of CO2 huff-n-puff enhanced oil recovery and storage in shale porous media considering heterogeneous structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0210933</link>
      <description>Dian Zhang, Lei Li, Han Wang, Yuliang Su, X. Zhang, Nai-Yuan Zheng, Zhenguang Huang, Chuanjin Yao, Physics of fluids. 36(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400498486

                CO2 possesses several advantages, including strong solubility, effective viscosity reduction ability, and low miscible pressure, making it a promising candidate for enhanced oil recovery (EOR). Additionally, due to its adsorption capture mechanism, shale formations are considered ideal environments for CO2 storage. However, the influence of heterogeneity of shale multi-scale structure on CO2 migration mechanism, EOR, and storage mechanism is not clear. In this study, a heterogeneous shale structure model containing fractures and matrix was designed based on scanning electron microscope. The multiphase&#8211;multicomponent&#8211;multirelaxation model was used to study the fluid migration mechanism in the process of miscible CO2 huff-n-puff in shale reservoir. By analyzing density variations, velocity changes, and pressure distributions, the effects of diffusion coefficient, adsorption parameters, and fracture size were studied. Furthermore, by changing the matrix structure, the influence of heterogeneity on the law of oil and gas migration was explored. Additionally, a comparison between CO2 and water was performed. Finally, the influence of reservoir heterogeneity on fluid transport mechanism was studied. The results show that EOR and CO2 storage rate (CSR) are proportional to the diffusion coefficient. The main factor affecting the CSR is the adsorption capacity of rock to CO2. The larger CO2&#8211;oil contact area between the fracture and the matrix leads to a larger CSR, highlighting the importance of induced fractures. In addition, it was found that CO2 huff-n-puff was superior to water flooding, showing an EOR performance advantage of about 15%. This study is helpful for the practical application of CO2 huff-n-puff technology in the field of unconventional oil and gas development and CO2 storage.</description>
      <author>Dian Zhang, Lei Li, Han Wang, Yuliang Su, X. Zhang, Nai-Yuan Zheng, Zhenguang Huang, Chuanjin Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0210933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of High-Temperature CO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; Capture by Lithium Orthosilicate-Based Sorbents Using Response Surface Methodology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202407.0448.v1</link>
      <description>Eleonora Stefanelli, Flavio Francalanci, Sandra Vitolo, Monica Puccini, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400470320

                The major challenge in the current context of a rising world&#8217;s energy demand is to limit the global temperature increase for mitigating climate change. This goal requires a large reduction of CO2 emissions, mainly produced by power generation and industrial processes using fossil fuels. In this study, a novel methodology for K2CO3-doped Li4SiO4 sorbents production for CO2 capture at high temperature was adopted based on the Design of Experiments (DoE). Different synthesis (temperature and K2CO3 content) and adsorption conditions (sorption temperature and CO2 concentration) were systematically tested by Response Surface Methodology (RSM) to obtain predictive models of CO2 uptake and Li4SiO4 conversion. The results of RSM analysis evidenced a maximum adsorption capacity of 196.4 mg/g for a sorbent produced at 600 &#176;C and with 36.9 wt% of K2CO3, tested at 500 &#176;C and 4 vol% of CO2. Whereas at 50 vol% of CO2, the best uptake of 295.6 mg/g was obtained with a sorbent synthesized at 600 &#176;C, containing less K2CO3 (17.1 wt%) and tested at higher temperature (662 &#176;C). The obtained results highlight that K2CO3-doped Li4SiO4 sorbents can be tailored for maximizing CO2 capture at different operating conditions, making them suitable for use in industrial processes.</description>
      <author>Eleonora Stefanelli, Flavio Francalanci, Sandra Vitolo, Monica Puccini</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202407.0448.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Individual grain mass of inbred rice cultivars does not benefit from elevated [CO2]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envexpbot.2024.105888</link>
      <description>Yao Huang, Wenke Sun, Zhenghua Hu, Environmental and experimental botany. 226(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400371569

                Climate warming has led to a reduction of global crop yields. Elevated atmospheric [CO2] is believed to promote crop production by increasing photosynthesis, and thus partly offset the yield losses due to climate warming. However, photosynthetic acclimation may occur when the plant is exposed to long-term high [CO2] conditions, suggesting that elevated [CO2] (e[CO2]) might not bring benefits for cereal crops as the growing season proceeds. To assess the effect of long-term e[CO2] on rice yield, particularly on individual grain mass determined post-heading, we synthesized existing data from FACE (free-air CO2 enrichment) experiments across four locations in Japan and China. We also conducted a five-year field experiment with different [CO2] treatments using OTC (open-top chamber) facility. A novel experiment of pot replacement at heading was conducted in 2018 to evaluate the effect of post-heading e[CO2] on individual grain mass of rice. Meanwhile, we measured net photosynthetic rates under ambient [CO2] (a[CO2]) and e[CO2] (ambient + 200 &#956;mol mol&#8722;1) at different developmental stages to identify the occurrence of photosynthetic acclimation. We show that FACE condition did not increase individual grain mass across thirty-six inbred rice cultivars at various rates of nitrogen application, and that the replacement of potted plants either from a[CO2] to e[CO2] or from e[CO2] to a[CO2] did not impact the individual grain mass. The yield benefit from e[CO2] was primarily attributed to an increase in the spikelet density determined pre-heading. We conclude that the individual grain mass of inbred rice does not benefit from e[CO2], which is most likely attributed to a loss of the advantage in CO2 gain induced by photosynthetic acclimation. Our findings suggest the necessity for selective breeding strategies to make better use of post-heading e[CO2] and for crop modelers to incorporate updated knowledge into models in the context of elevated [CO2].</description>
      <author>Yao Huang, Wenke Sun, Zhenghua Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envexpbot.2024.105888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructed PbCO3 with abundant oxygen vacancies for efficient CO2-to-formate electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02989e</link>
      <description>Huan Wang, Jie Zhao, Qianqian Yang, Jingjie Wu, Xin Yu Zhang, Haiyang Yuan, Xiaolei Xu, Jingjing He, Qiang Niu, Pengfei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400461023

                The electrosynthesis of valuable chemical feedstocks and fuels through CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) provides a promising approach to solve the global warming problem and the energy crisis. Numerous researches have...</description>
      <author>Huan Wang, Jie Zhao, Qianqian Yang, Jingjie Wu, Xin Yu Zhang, Haiyang Yuan, Xiaolei Xu, Jingjing He, Qiang Niu, Pengfei Liu, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02989e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on methane degradation by microbial agents based on chelating wetting agent carriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-66399-x</link>
      <description>Yilong Han, Lianman Xu, Runjie Zhang, Longzhe Jin, Fengshuo Yang, Chao Ma, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400319509

                Abstract Due to the low permeability characteristics of the deep gas-containing coal seam, the conventional prevention and control measures that cannot solve the problems of gas outbursts are unsatisfactory for the prevention and control of the coal and gas outbursts disaster. Therefore, in this study, a strain of methane-oxidizing bacteria M 07 with high-pressure resistance, strong resistance, and high methane degradation rate was selected from coal mines. The growth and degradation abilities of M 07 in chelating wetting agent solutions to assess its adaptability and find the optimal agent-to-M07 ratio. It provides a new method for integrating the reduction of impact tendency and gas pressure in deep coal mines. The experimental results show that M 07 is a Gram-positive bacterium of the genus Bacillus , which has strong resistance and adaptability to high-pressure water injection. By degrading 70 mol of methane, M 07 produces 1 mol of carbon dioxide, which can reduce gas pressure and reduce the risk of gas outbursts in coal mines. As the experiment proves, the best effect was achieved when the M 07 concentration of the chelating wetting agent was 0.05%. The methane-oxidizing bacteria based on the chelating wetting agent as carriers prove a new prevention and control method for the integrated prevention and control of coal and gas outbursts in coal mines and also provide a new idea for microbial application in coal mine disaster control.</description>
      <author>Yilong Han, Lianman Xu, Runjie Zhang, Longzhe Jin, Fengshuo Yang, Chao Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-66399-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Iron Production via Highly Efficient Low-Temperature Electrolysis of 3D Conductive Colloidal Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00698d</link>
      <description>Panya Thanwisai, Zeyi Yao, Muntasir Shahabuddin, Jiahui Hou, Jinzhao Fu, Adam Powell, Yan Wang, Green chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400356479

                Towards decarbonizing the carbothermic reduction of iron and steelmaking which produces around 5% of global CO2 emissions, we herein propose a low-temperature electrolysis (100 &#176;C) with 3D electrically-ionically conductive colloidal...</description>
      <author>Panya Thanwisai, Zeyi Yao, Muntasir Shahabuddin, Jiahui Hou, Jinzhao Fu, Adam Powell, Yan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00698d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting CO2 electrolysis via synergy between active heterogeneous interface and oxygen defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175417</link>
      <description>Jing Yan, Shufeng Li, Yawei Li, Si&#8208;Dian Li, Jaka Sunarso, Huili Chen, Journal of alloys and compounds. 1002(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400336905

                The commercial viability of solid oxide electrolysis cells (SOECs) for the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO is hampered by the sluggish electrocatalytic activity of the electrode materials. In this study, a series of perovskites, Pr0.5Sr0.5Cr0.1Fe0.9-xNixO3-&#948; (x = 0.1, 0.2, PSCFNx) with different Ni doping levels were synthesized. The results showed that increasing Ni doping led to the creation of more oxygen vacancies. Furthermore, treatment of PSCFNx in a reducing atmosphere resulted in a structural transformation into a composite with a heterogeneous interface between the Ruddlesden-Popper perovskite (RP-PSCFNx) and an exsolved Ni-Fe metal alloy. The re-PSCFN0.2-based cell showed a current density of 2.40 A cm-2 and a Faraday efficiency (FE%) of almost 100% at 850 &#176;C and 1.6 V, an improvement of 18% in comparison to the re-PSCFN0.1-based cell. This study provides a strategy to synergistically improve the electrochemical reduction of CO2 activity of SOECs by constructing an active heterogeneous interface and increasing the oxygen vacancy content.</description>
      <author>Jing Yan, Shufeng Li, Yawei Li, Si&#8208;Dian Li, Jaka Sunarso, Huili Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal thermal energy storage employing solar heat: A case study of Heilongjiang, China, exploring the transition to clean heating and renewable power integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132334</link>
      <description>Tianrun Yang, Wen Liu, Gert Jan Kramer, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400388103

                Seasonal thermal energy storage (STES) offers an attractive option for decarbonizing heating in the built environment to promote renewable energy and reduce CO2 emissions. A literature review revealed knowledge gaps in evaluating the technical feasibility of replacing district heating (DH) with STES in densely populated areas and its impact on costs, fossil fuel consumption, CO2 emission reduction, and renewable power integration. The effects of large-scale STES applications on the power and DH sectors in a regional energy system were quantified by applying the 2030 and 2050 power structure scenarios. The results indicated that STES reduces fossil fuel consumption and CO2 emissions at an affordable cost. It facilitates the integration of wind and solar power into power grids. With 100% replacement of DH by STES, fossil fuel consumption and CO2 emissions can be reduced by approximately 40% and 45% in 2030 and 2050, respectively, with an annual cost increase of 20%. The CO2 avoidance costs were predicted to be approximately 60 &#8364;/t in 2030 and well below 50 &#8364;/t in 2050. STES will reduce renewable power curtailment by 10% in 2030 and 18% in 2050. This study investigated STES from an energy-system perspective, supporting the formulation of clean heating transition policies.</description>
      <author>Tianrun Yang, Wen Liu, Gert Jan Kramer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Review on Effects of Material Composition, Mix Design, and Mixing Regimes on Rheology of 3D-Printed Geopolymer Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/0118748368292859240313061706</link>
      <description>P. S. Barve, Alireza Bahrami, NULL AUTHOR_ID, &#152;The &#156;Open construction &amp; building technology journal. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400421748

                Recent years have witnessed a significant growth in the research and development of additive manufacturing methods involving concrete and cementitious materials, with technologies like three-dimensional (3D) printing becoming more widely used in the construction industry. Construction has the possibility to be revolutionized, not only in the context of cost savings but also in the context of increased sustainability and functionality. 3D printing of concrete is a cutting-edge technology that has the potential to speed up construction, reduce labor costs, give architects more creative freedom, improve precision, obviate requirements for formwork, and result in less construction wastes. In addition, 3D printing can be a long-term solution for both economy and environment. Even though 3D printing in concrete has made tremendous strides recently, developing an effective 3D-printable material that decreases material usage and enhances performance is critical for carbon dioxide reduction. Robust geopolymer formulations for 3D printing concrete technology in current construction applications have emerged as the subject of much research among scientists to find novel ways to circumvent this constraint. This study intends to highlight the current state of the art in developing 3D-Printed Geopolymer Concrete (3DPGC) with a comprehensive review related to the material composition, mix design, and mixing regimes on rheology of 3DPGC. The rheology of 3DPGC in terms of printability and buildability is discussed. The mixing regimes employed for the preparation of one-part and two-part 3DPGC are tabulated and commented on. Lastly, the research gaps are identified and summarized, and several research directions are also provided for future investigations to expedite the ubiquitous use of 3DPGC in versatile construction applications.</description>
      <author>P. S. Barve, Alireza Bahrami, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/0118748368292859240313061706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Sustainability Dimensions Verses Climate Change Act 2008: A Retrospective Numerical Modelling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5130/ajceb.v24i3.9008</link>
      <description>K. S. Getvoldsen, A. K. Chandragiri, Ahmed Khalafallah, Monjia Belizaire, John Weirs, H. M. J. Raheem, Michael Gerges, Talib E. Butt, Construction economics and building. 24(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400325654

                Sustainability continues to be a key field of study, encapsulating three principle dimensions: social, economic and environmental, which are also found within the context of climate change. However, there appears to be limited literature drawing upon the between sustainability and climate change. relationship, particularly in connection to carbon emissions and energy management. These issues have already been the subject of legislation in different countries, though still, predominantly individually rather than from an integrated perspective. The Climate Change At (2008) provides a platform through which the relationship between sustainability and climate change can be considered. This paper establishes this relationship aspects of this relationship by employing the increased use of insulation within the UK housing stock to contribute to achieving the carbon reduction set by the Act. Taking a retrospective view through theoretical numerical modelling, this paper demonstrates that CO2 reductions were achievable. The results demonstrate that links can be drawn between sustainability and climate change and identifies that significant CO2 savings, through robust energy management of the UK housing stock, these results can be achieved. It is also suggested that the theoretical mole developed can be reproduced to consider climate change targets and provide benchmarks, not only in the UK but in other countries.</description>
      <author>K. S. Getvoldsen, A. K. Chandragiri, Ahmed Khalafallah, Monjia Belizaire, John Weirs, H. M. J. Raheem, Michael Gerges, Talib E. Butt</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5130/ajceb.v24i3.9008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the bis&#8208;carbene ligand on manganese catalysts for CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401007</link>
      <description>Matthias H. Richter, Eduardo Peris, Sergio Gonell, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400324213

                First row transition metal complexes have attracted attention as abundant and affordable electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction. Manganese complexes bearing bis-N-heterocyclic carbene ligands defining 6-membered ring metallacycles have proven to reduce CO2 to CO selectively at very high rates. Herein, we report the synthesis of manganese carbonyl complexes supported by a rigid ortho-phenylene bridged bis-N-heterocyclic carbene ligand (orthophenylene-bis(N-methylimidazol-2-ylidene, Ph-bis-mim), which defines a 7-membered ring metallacycle. We performed a comparative study with the analogues bearing an ethylene-bis(Nmethylimidazol-2-ylidene ligand (C2H4-bis-mim) and a methylenebis(N-methylimidazol-2-ylidene ligand (CH2-bis-mim) and found that catalysts comprising a seven-membered metallacycle retain similar selectivity and high activity as those with six-membered metallacycles, while reducing the overpotential by 120-190 mV. This study reveals general design principles for manganese bis-N-heterocyclic carbene electrocatalysts which can guide further designs of affordable, fast and low overpotential catalysts for CO2 electroreduction.</description>
      <author>Matthias H. Richter, Eduardo Peris, Sergio Gonell</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Chelation Effect in MOF-253 Materials: Guest Molecule Adsorption Dynamics and Proposed Formic Acid Synthesis Investigated by Atomistic Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29133211</link>
      <description>Meng-Chi Hsieh, Wenchao Liang, Chun-Chih Chang, Ming&#8208;Kang Tsai, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400353252

                The dynamic characterization of guest molecules in the metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) can always provide the insightful and inspiring information to facilitate the synthetic design of MOF materials from the bottom-up design of perspective. Herein, we present a series of atomistic molecular dynamics simulation for investigating the bipyridine dicarboxylate (bpydc) linker rotation effect on guest molecule adsorption with and without considering the transition metal (TM) chelation in MOF-253 materials. The simulated PXRD patterns of the various linker orientations present the challenge of distinguishing these structural varieties by the conventional crystalline spectroscopic measurements. The observed short inter-TM stable structure may subsequently lead to the formation of a binuclear TM catalytic site, and a proposed formic acid generation mechanism from CO2 and H2 is derived based upon the density functional theory calculations for the application of CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Meng-Chi Hsieh, Wenchao Liang, Chun-Chih Chang, Ming&#8208;Kang Tsai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29133211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Effect of Pd Nanoparticles on SrTi0.8Mn0.2O3 in the Reverse Water&#8208;Gas Shift Reaction via the Mars&#8211;van Krevelen Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400871</link>
      <description>Minori Kobayashi, Shimpei Naniwa, Keita Goto, Hideo Matsuo, Shoji Iguchi, Tsunehiro Tanaka, Kentaro Teramura, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400340074

                The reverse water&#8208;gas shift (RWGS) reaction serves as a critical pathway for converting CO2 into diverse chemicals. The Mars&#8211;van Krevelen (MvK) mechanism, which leverages lattice oxygen as the oxidant and oxygen vacancies as reductants, offers an alternative catalytic strategy for the selective RWGS reaction. While Mn&#8208;substituted SrTiO3 (i.e., SrTi0.8Mn0.2O3) has been shown to promote the RWGS reaction selectively via the MvK mechanism, achieving a sufficient conversion of CO2 necessitates elevated temperatures. This study investigated the effect of Pd&#8208;loaded SrTi0.8Mn0.2O3 on the activation of adsorbed H2 molecules, which generated oxygen vacancies and enhanced CO2 conversion. Notably, 1.0 wt% Pd&#8208;loaded SrTi0.8Mn0.2O3 yielded 13.4% of CO at 673 K, whereas pristine SrTi0.8Mn0.2O3 and Pd&#8208;loaded SrTiO3 yielded negligible or minimal amount of CO. Hydrogen temperature&#8208;programmed reduction and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy measurements revealed that Pd promoted the formation of oxygen vacancies via both thermodynamic and kinetic mechanisms. Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy and kinetic studies revealed that the RWGS reaction over Pd&#8208;loaded SrTi0.8Mn0.2O3 proceeded primarily via the MvK mechanism with a partial contribution from the Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood mechanism. This study underscores the effectiveness of combining metal and MvK&#8208;type catalysts to enhance the efficiency of the RWGS reaction.</description>
      <author>Minori Kobayashi, Shimpei Naniwa, Keita Goto, Hideo Matsuo, Shoji Iguchi, Tsunehiro Tanaka, Kentaro Teramura</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400871</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the impact of the circular economy concept on economic development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5937/odrraz2401007j</link>
      <description>Gordan Jankovi&#263;, Milo&#353; Golubovi&#263;, Odr&#382;ivi razvoj. 6(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400353478

                Unlike the linear model of economic development, which is based on taking resources from nature, turning them into a finished product and using that product as the final stage of the life cycle of resources, without taking into account the degree of pollution they cause, there is a so-called circular model. The circular model of the economy is an alternative to the linear model. This means that with the circular model, the use of the finished product does not represent the last phase of the life cycle of the resource, but that used product, through the application of various processes, serves as a resource in further production. The main goal of the circular economic model is to reduce waste and pollution, but also to increase the productivity of resources. Longer use of products, machines, and other fixed assets results in higher productivity of the resources that make up their basic input. One of the main goals of the circular economy is the elimination or at least reduction of pollution, and one of the biggest pollutants is the excessive emission of carbon dioxide, whose chemical formula is &#12310;CO&#12311;2. For this reason, the authors of this research recognized this area as crucial for further economic development. By applying various processes and procedures in developed countries, there was a decrease in the amount of &#12310;CO&#12311;2emissions, while at the same time there was no decrease in economic activities and production in the economies of those countries, but quite the opposite, at the same time there was an increase in the gross national product (GDP). Serbia should use these countries as an example and, using the good practice of developed countries, start as soon as possible with a more extensive transition from a linear to a circular model of economic development, i.e. bring a series of measures, procedures, laws as soon as possible in order to reduce the emission of &#12310;CO&#12311;2. In accordance with this, the logical conclusion would be that the scientific goal of this research work is to identify the role of reducing &#12310;CO&#12311;2 emissions as an important potential for the transition from a linear to a circular model of economic development, without jeopardizing the level of real GDP.</description>
      <author>Gordan Jankovi&#263;, Milo&#353; Golubovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5937/odrraz2401007j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing insights into the phenomena of deep eutectic solvents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e01039</link>
      <description>David S. Freitas, Artur Cavaco&#8208;Paulo, Carla Silva, Sustainable materials and technologies. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400336788

                Environmental concerns have spurred a quest for more sustainable and safer solvents, aiming to replace aggressive and harmful chemical products in industrial processes. In response to this need, deep eutectic solvents (DES) have emerged as a progressive evolution from ionic liquids. These innovative solvents result from the synergistic combination of two or more chemical compounds, exhibiting a significant reduction in melting point when blended in specific molar fractions, ultimately achieving a liquid state at room temperature. In recent years, a natural variant known as Natural Deep Eutectic Solvents (NADES) has gained prominence. This environmentally friendly alternative is derived by skilfully combining compounds such as sugars, amino acids, or organic acids, presenting a promising avenue for sustainable and eco-friendly chemical processes. These "green" solvents go beyond applications in chemical or materials engineering, finding application in diverse fields such as biocatalysis, extraction processes, and carbon dioxide capture, among others. Despite their numerous advantages, including low cost, ease of preparation, tuneable properties, and biorenewability, the full potential of DES remains elusive due to insufficient understanding, hindering their seamless integration into industrial applications. While previous reviews have predominantly focused on defining and showcasing the applications of DES, they often overlook the crucial aspect of physicochemical characterization. Similar to other solvent classes, the physicochemical properties of DES such as polarity, viscosity, density, and conductivity play a pivotal role in determining their applicability. Recognizing this gap, the primary objective of this review is to provide a practical guide encompassing the preparation, characterization, and application of DES, thereby facilitating a comprehensive understanding of these solvents for both researchers and practitioners alike. Moreover, the manuscript will delve into the diverse types of DES, exploring their unique physicochemical properties and potential modifications tailored for various applications across different fields.</description>
      <author>David S. Freitas, Artur Cavaco&#8208;Paulo, Carla Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e01039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Performance Packages on Fuel Consumption and Exhaust Emissions of Passenger Cars and Commercial Vehicles under WLTP</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143356</link>
      <description>Luca Marchitto, Maria Antonietta Costagliola, Alessandra Berra, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400460455

                The transportation sector is responsible for about 16% of worldwide greenhouse gas emissions. Despite efforts for a sensible reduction by means of new technologies&#8217; development, the average age of a vehicle fleet is 12.3 years in the European Union. In light of this, actions aiming at improving the efficiency of circulating vehicles can prove effective in the short to mid-term. Introducing performance packages in standard fuels could allow a reduction in the CO2 emissions of whole vehicle fleets without any modification to powertrain. Such a kind of additive is generally used in premium fuels; deposit control additives can reduce or control the deposits at intake valves and at nozzle holes with benefits for the fuel efficiency and exhaust emissions. Further improvements in combustion phasing can be achieved with cetane/octane improver. This paper aims to assess the influence of two performance packages on the exhaust emissions and fuel consumption of five vehicles set to be as representative as possible of circulating Italian passenger cars and light commercial fleet vehicles (LCVs). Based on the literature datasets, three Euro 4 vehicles were selected with a mileage representative of each single vehicle class: two passenger cars (one spark ignition and one diesel) and an LCV. Further, two diesel Euro 6 vehicles, a passenger car and an LCV, were tested to investigate the effect of fuel additives on the combustion of vehicles compliant with current homologation regulation. Exhaust emissions and fuel consumption were experimentally estimated on a chassis dynamometer over a worldwide harmonized light vehicles test cycle (WLTC) in a climate-controlled laboratory. Each vehicle was preliminarily tested when running with base fuel, then a 3000 km clean-up stage was performed using the additive package. Finally, WLTC tests were repeated. Results demonstrated the efficiency of the performance packages with a reduction between 1.2% (diesel Euro 6 passenger car) and 8.1% (diesel Euro 4 passenger car) in fuel consumption. Similar trends were found for CO2 emissions. Further, a sensible reduction in THCs, CO and PM was found for each vehicle class.</description>
      <author>Luca Marchitto, Maria Antonietta Costagliola, Alessandra Berra</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An audit of corporate decarbonisation ambition against low-carbon futures.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3367979/v2</link>
      <description>Iain S. Weaver, Jesse F. Abrams, Jeffrey C. Oliver, Nikolaos Dimakis, Andrew Parry, Timothy M. Lenton, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400459950

                Abstract Atmospheric greenhouse gas concentration has been steadily increasing since the 19th century, causing global warming. Despite efforts to reduce emissions, current projections anticipate a significant increase in global mean temperature by the end of the century, which may push us beyond a safe and just operating space. We must develop emissions pathways that take into account renewable technology innovation, climate policy development and consumer behavior change. In this manuscript we assess corporate emissions reduction ambition in the context of reduction pathways, and in doing so show that company reporting has reached a scale and quality that it can be used to supplement global emissions forecasting. We find emissions disclosures of target-setting companies to account for roughly a fifth of global CO2 emissions and three-fifths of total market capitalisation. Of these, we find near-term targets to be consistent with the aggressive reduction requirements of the divergent net-zero scenario published by the Network for Greening the Financial System, but commitments to 2050 are lacking. There is a large disparity between the total market capitalisation of disclosing companies and the total emissions they cover, a disconnect which we emphasise must be addressed by future</description>
      <author>Iain S. Weaver, Jesse F. Abrams, Jeffrey C. Oliver, Nikolaos Dimakis, Andrew Parry, Timothy M. Lenton</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3367979/v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CRITICAL EXAMINATION OF THE CONSTRUCTION SECTOR IN TURKEY IN TERMS OF SUSTAINABILITY</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47933/ijeir.1491574</link>
      <description>P&#305;nar Usta, Kamertap Cirik, Elifnur &#350;akalak, Ali Ekber SEVER, International journal of engineering and innovative research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400496991

                The construction sector is of critical importance for economic growth and employment creation. However, it also has significant environmental impacts, including high energy consumption, extensive use of natural resources, and substantial waste production. Currently, the construction sector in Turkey accounts for 35% of the country&#8217;s total energy consumption, making it a significant energy consumer. Research conducted in European Union countries indicates that buildings are responsible for 40% of total energy consumption and 36% of total CO2 emissions. It is believed that a similar situation exists in Turkey. Furthermore, the long lifespan of structures built in the sector is of great importance for sustainability. The contribution of poor-quality and unhealthy structures to environmental stress further highlights the role of the construction sector in sustainability. The study addresses the impacts of strategic goals such as the design and construction of sustainable building models, the recyclability and reuse of building materials, energy efficiency, and the reduction of CO2 emissions on the construction sector. The findings indicate that the integration of energy efficiency and renewable energy technologies is crucial for the Turkish construction sector to move towards a sustainable future. In this context, it is recommended that the Turkish construction sector implement the necessary steps and engage in strategic planning in order to achieve its sustainability goals. The findings of the study emphasise the pivotal role and significance of the construction sector in this regard.</description>
      <author>P&#305;nar Usta, Kamertap Cirik, Elifnur &#350;akalak, Ali Ekber SEVER</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47933/ijeir.1491574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Carbon Footprint of Spanish University Websites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202407.0396.v1</link>
      <description>Sonia S&#225;nchez-Cuadrado, Jorge Morato, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400334134

                first_pagesettingsOrder Article ReprintsOpen AccessArticleThe Carbon Footprint of Spanish University Websitesby Sonia Sanchez-Cuadrado 1 andJorge Morato 2,*1Department of Library and Information Science, Complutense University of Madrid, 28010 Madrid, Spain2Department of Computer Science, Carlos III University of Madrid, Leganes, 28911 Madrid, Spain*Author to whom correspondence should be addressed.Sustainability 2024, 16(13), 5670; https://doi.org/10.3390/su16135670 (registering DOI)Submission received: 31 May 2024 / Revised: 22 June 2024 / Accepted: 23 June 2024 / Published: 3 July 2024(This article belongs to the Special Issue Sustainable Education in the Digital Society: Applying Communication Technologies and Digital Tools to Education) Downloadkeyboard_arrow_down Browse Figures Versions NotesAbstractThe consumption of digital content is essential for economic and scientific development, leading to a high dependence on information and communication technologies, which significantly impacts the environment. Quantifying this ecological impact is challenging due to its intangible nature and the diversity of factors. This research focuses on assessing the energy consumption and CO2 production of Spanish university websites to evaluate their levels of digital pollution and environmental impact. The calculation of the carbon footprint considers factors related to energy consumption and the use of green or renewable energies. The findings indicate that only 17% of university websites can be considered environmentally friendly. There are significant differences in CO2 consumption and emissions depending on whether the websites implement environmentally sound practices. This study highlights the lack of initiatives aimed at reducing energy consumption and greenhouse gas emissions associated with web information management. The study shows that Spanish universities have the potential to contribute to the reduction in CO2 emissions by implementing sustainable development practices on their websites. Furthermore, it fosters awareness about technology usage and its environmental impact, promoting the adoption of green and sustainable approaches.</description>
      <author>Sonia S&#225;nchez-Cuadrado, Jorge Morato</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202407.0396.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From forests to farming: identification of photosynthetic limitations in breadfruit across diverse environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.08.602079</link>
      <description>Graham J. Dow, Noa Kekuewa Lincoln, Dolly Autufuga, Robert E. Paull, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400488734

                Breadfruit (Artocarpus altilis) is a prolific tropical tree producing highly nutritious and voluminous carbohydrate-rich fruits. Already recognized as an underutilized crop, breadfruit could ameliorate food insecurity and protect against climate-related productivity shocks in undernourished equatorial regions. However, a lack of fundamental knowledge impedes widespread agricultural adoption, from modern agroforestry to plantation schemes. Here, we used a multi-environment breadfruit variety trial across the Hawaiian Islands to determine photosynthetic limitations, understand the role of site conditions or varietal features, and define their contributions to agronomic efficiency. Photosynthetic rates were dependent on location and variety, and strongly correlated with fruit yield (r2=0.80, p&lt;0.001). Photochemistry was suitable to full-sunlight conditions, with a saturation point of 1545 PAR, Vcmax of 151 umol m-2s-1, and Jmax of 128 umol m-2s-1, which are high-end compared to other tropical and temperate tree crops. However, limitations on CO2 assimilation were imposed by stomatal characteristics, including stomatal density (p&lt;0.05) and diurnal oscillations of stomatal conductance (&gt;50% reductions from daily maxima). These constraints on CO2 diffusion are likely to limit maximum productivity more than photochemistry. Our results comprise the first comprehensive analysis of breadfruit photosynthesis, successfully links ecophysiology with fruit yield, and identifies vital traits for future research and management optimization.</description>
      <author>Graham J. Dow, Noa Kekuewa Lincoln, Dolly Autufuga, Robert E. Paull</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.08.602079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ALPINE: An adaptive language-agnostic pruning method for language models
  for code</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.04147</link>
      <description>Mootez Saad, Jos&#233; Antonio Hern&#225;ndez L&#243;pez, Boqi Chen, D&#225;niel Varr&#243;, Tushar Sharma, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400434361

                Language models of code have demonstrated state-of-the-art performance across various software engineering and source code analysis tasks. However, their demanding computational resource requirements and consequential environmental footprint remain as significant challenges. This work introduces ALPINE, an adaptive programming language-agnostic pruning technique designed to substantially reduce these models' computational overhead. The proposed method offers a pluggable layer that can be integrated with all Transformer-based models. With ALPINE, input sequences undergo adaptive compression throughout the pipeline, reaching a size up to $\times 3$ less their initial size, resulting in significantly reduced computational load. Our experiments on two software engineering tasks, defect prediction and code clone detection across three language models CodeBERT, GraphCodeBERT and UniXCoder show that ALPINE achieves up to a 50% reduction in FLOPs, a 58.1% decrease in memory footprint, and a 28.1% improvement in throughput on average. This led to a reduction in CO2 by up to $44.85$%. Importantly, it achieves the reduction in computation resources while maintaining up to 98.1% of the original predictive performance. These findings highlight the potential of ALPINE in making language models of code more resource-efficient and accessible while preserving their performance, contributing to the overall sustainability of adopting language models in software development. Also, it sheds light on redundant and noisy information in source code analysis corpora, as shown by the substantial sequence compression achieved by ALPINE.</description>
      <author>Mootez Saad, Jos&#233; Antonio Hern&#225;ndez L&#243;pez, Boqi Chen, D&#225;niel Varr&#243;, Tushar Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.04147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circular Economy Integration in 1G+2G Sugarcane Bioethanol Production: Application of Carbon Capture, Utilization and Storage, Closed-Loop Systems, and Waste Valorization for Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14416/j.asep.2024.07.005</link>
      <description>Rich Jhon Paul Latiza, Rugi Vicente C. Rubi, Applied Science and Engineering Progress. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400428585

                Bioethanol production is a vital player in the renewable energy landscape. However, it faces pressing issues regarding carbon emissions and resource management. Traditional open-loop systems generate substantial waste and pollution, exacerbating environmental concerns. Various emerging technologies offer promising solutions. Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage (CCUS) presents avenues for tackling carbon emissions. Utilization transforms CO2 emissions into valuable products, while Storage securely stores emissions to prevent atmospheric release. Closed-loop processes and waste valorization capitalize on material reuse, conserving natural resources, and minimizing waste. By promoting resource efficiency and waste minimization, circular economy principles align seamlessly with CCUS, closed-loop systems, and waste valorization. This study delves into utilizing Utilization technologies tailored to sugarcane 1G+2G bioethanol production, evaluates CO2 capture options, and presents applications. Storage strategies suitable for bioethanol production facilities are scrutinized, and deployment options are explored, highlighting the closed-loop system and waste valorization's role in waste reduction and environmental preservation. Through synergistic integration, these technologies pave the way for sustainable sugarcane bioethanol production, addressing economic and technological challenges while fostering innovation and collaboration. This comprehensive study will serve as a guide for transitioning to a circular economy model in bioethanol production.</description>
      <author>Rich Jhon Paul Latiza, Rugi Vicente C. Rubi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14416/j.asep.2024.07.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative life cycle assessment of organic industrial solid waste co-disposal in a MSW incineration plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132322</link>
      <description>Kun Wang, Aijun Li, Guangzhao Guo, Junwei Zhang, Yong&#8208;Xiang Ren, Lu Dong, Lifang Gong, Hongyun Hu, Hong Yao, Ichiro Naruse, Energy. 305(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400377882

                Co-disposal experiments involving industrial solid waste (ISW) are conducted at a municipal solid waste (MSW) incineration plant in this study, investing the environmental impact of co-disposal with different ISW addition proportions using life cycle assessment (LCA). Results show that increasing ISW proportions improves economic indicators, reducing the payback period from 7.92 years (0 % ISW) to 6.58 years (40 % ISW). Environmental impact indicators initially decrease and then increase. The indicator with the greatest environmental impact is Eutrophication Potential (EP), the only major indicator with positive values in all scenarios when considering power output. Its normalization value reaches a minimum at 30 % ISW blending, at 7.85 &#215; 10&#8722;12. Contribution analysis reveals that the direct emissions of N-containing gases are the primary cause, while the addition of urea, ammonia water, and quicklime in flue gas treatment, as well as the ash-slag landfill, also have significant effects. Technical optimization of stepwise co-disposal, denitrification system and ash-slag reduction will be the focus. Compared to the existing conventional situation, the co-disposal system exhibits considerable improvements in environmental benefits and carbon reduction potential. Notably, there is a significant reduction in non-CO2 greenhouse gas emissions. This study offers theoretical insights for multi-source waste disposal in MSW incineration plants.</description>
      <author>Kun Wang, Aijun Li, Guangzhao Guo, Junwei Zhang, Yong&#8208;Xiang Ren, Lu Dong, Lifang Gong, Hongyun Hu, Hong Yao, Ichiro Naruse</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing climatic controls on the greenhouse gas balance of thermokarst bogs during succession after permafrost thaw</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.17388</link>
      <description>Liam Heffernan, Cristian Estop&#8208;Aragon&#233;s, McKenzie A. Kuhn, Klaus&#8208;Holger Knorr, David Olefeldt, Global change biology. 30(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400361624

                Abstract Permafrost thaw in northern peatlands causes collapse of permafrost peat plateaus and thermokarst bog development, with potential impacts on atmospheric greenhouse gas exchange. Here, we measured methane and carbon dioxide fluxes over 3 years (including winters) using static chambers along two permafrost thaw transects in northwestern Canada, spanning young (~30 years since thaw), intermediate and mature thermokarst bogs (~200 years since thaw). Young bogs were wetter, warmer and had more hydrophilic vegetation than mature bogs. Methane emissions increased with wetness and soil temperature (40 cm depth) and modelled annual estimates were greatest in the young bog during the warmest year and lowest in the mature bog during the coolest year (21 and 7 g C&#8208;CH 4 m &#8722;2 year &#8722;1 , respectively). The dominant control on net ecosystem exchange (NEE) in the mature bog (between +20 and &#8722;54 g C&#8208;CO 2 m &#8722;2 year &#8722;1 ) was soil temperature (5 cm), causing net CO 2 loss due to higher ecosystem respiration (ER) in warmer years. In contrast, wetness controlled NEE in the young and intermediate bogs (between +55 and &#8722;95 g C&#8208;CO 2 m &#8722;2 year &#8722;1 ), where years with periodic inundation at the beginning of the growing season caused greater reduction in gross primary productivity than in ER leading to CO 2 loss. Winter fluxes (November&#8211;April) represented 16% of annual ER and 38% of annual CH 4 emissions. Our study found NEE of thermokarst bogs to be close to neutral and rules out large CO 2 losses under current conditions. However, high CH 4 emissions after thaw caused a positive net radiative forcing effect. While wet conditions favouring high CH 4 emissions only persist for the initial young bog period, we showed that continued climate warming with increased ER, and thus, CO 2 losses from the mature bog can cause net positive radiative forcing which would last for centuries after permafrost thaw.</description>
      <author>Liam Heffernan, Cristian Estop&#8208;Aragon&#233;s, McKenzie A. Kuhn, Klaus&#8208;Holger Knorr, David Olefeldt</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.17388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Blast Furnace Ingredient Optimization Based on Improved Grey Wolf Optimization Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14070798</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qing Lv, Metals. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400407088

                Blast furnace ironmaking plays an important role in modern industry and the development of the economy. A reasonable ingredient scheme is crucial for energy efficiency and emission reduction in blast furnace production. Determining the right blast furnace ingredients is a complicated process; therefore, this study examines the optimization of the ingredient ratio. In this paper a model of the blast furnace ingredients is established by considering cost of per ton iron, CO2 emissions, and the theoretical coke ratio as the objective functions; ingredient parameters, process parameters, main and by-product parameters as variables; and the blast furnace smelting theory and equilibrium equation as constraints. Then, the model is solved by using an improved grey wolf optimization algorithm and an improved multi-objective grey wolf optimization algorithm. Using the data collected from the steel mill, the conclusion is that multi-objective optimization can consider the indexes of each target, so that the values of all the targets are excellent; we also compared the multi-objective solution results with the original production scheme of the steel mill, and we found that using the blast furnace ingredient scheme optimized in this study can reduce the cost of iron per ton, CO2 emissions per ton, and the theoretical coke ratio in blast furnace production by 350 CNY/t, 1000 kg/t, and 20 kg/t, respectively, compared with the original production plan. Thus, steel mill decision makers can choose the blast furnace ingredients according to different business strategies and the actual needs of steel mills can be better met.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qing Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14070798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for carbon farming schemes (Road4Schemes) : Deliverable D2.1-2, D2.4-5 : carbon farming schemes throughout Europe, an overall inventory and analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18174/654551</link>
      <description>Bert Smit, Martin Hvarregaard Thors&#248;e, J.W.H. van der Kolk, K. Nikolaus, Laura B. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Ennio Facq, Ilaria Falconi, &#220;lfet Erdal, Claudia Heidecke, Alessandra Martelli, Irene Criscuoli, Giovanni Dara Guccione, Morten Graversgaard, Jana Pol&#225;kov&#225;, S. G&#246;tzinger, A. Baumgarten, Suzanne Reynders, M. Nogu&#232;s, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400559880

                Carbon farming is considered as one of the mitigation options to reach the targets of the Paris Agreement and the European Green Deal.The purpose of this report is to assess which carbon farming schemes are available throughout Europe, how they can be characterised and to which extent they deal with principles like additionality, fairness and long-term carbon storage, besides the issues of a proper MRV(monitoring, reporting and verification)-system with acceptable costs and sufficient payments for the farmers.The way in which carbon farming is organised is very different depending on the type of scheme.In this report, a carbon farming scheme is defined as any voluntary agreement in which a farmer or a group of farmers commit themselves to apply carbon farming measures to get a positive balance between soil carbon accumulation and GHG emissions (possibly measured as CO2 equivalents) or reduction of GHG-emissions in return for a payment or compensation in any form.</description>
      <author>Bert Smit, Martin Hvarregaard Thors&#248;e, J.W.H. van der Kolk, K. Nikolaus, Laura B. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Ennio Facq, Ilaria Falconi, &#220;lfet Erdal, Claudia Heidecke, Alessandra Martelli, Irene Criscuoli, Giovanni Dara Guccione, Morten Graversgaard, Jana Pol&#225;kov&#225;, S. G&#246;tzinger, A. Baumgarten, Suzanne Reynders, M. Nogu&#232;s</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18174/654551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diurnal High Temperatures Affect the Physiological Performance and Fruit Quality of Highbush Blueberry (Vaccinium corymbosum L.) cv. Legacy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13131846</link>
      <description>Jorge Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Villagra, Kelly Johanna &#193;vila, Humberto A. Gajardo, Le&#243;n A. Bravo, Alejandra Ribera-Fonseca, Emilio Jorquera-Fontena, Gustavo Curaqueo, Cecilia Soledad Rold&#225;n, Priscilla Falquetto-Gomes, Adriano Nunes&#8208;Nesi, Marjorie Reyes-D&#237;az, Plants. 13(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400363503

                In this study, the physiological performance and fruit quality responses of the highbush blueberry (Vaccinium corymbosum) cultivar Legacy to high temperatures (HTs) were evaluated in a field experiment. Three-year-old V. corymbosum plants were exposed to two temperature treatments between fruit load set and harvest during the 2022/2023 season: (i) ambient temperature (AT) and (ii) high temperature (HT) (5 &#176;C &#177; 1 &#176;C above ambient temperature). A chamber covered with transparent polyethylene (100 &#181;m thick) was used to apply the HT treatment. In our study, the diurnal temperature was maintained with a difference of 5.03 &#176;C &#177; 0.12 &#176;C between the AT and HT treatments. Our findings indicated that HT significantly decreased CO2 assimilation (Pn) by 45% and stomatal conductance (gs) by 35.2% compared to the AT treatment. By contrast, the intercellular CO2 concentration (Ci) showed higher levels (about 6%) in HT plants than in AT plants. Fruit quality analyses revealed that the fruit weight and equatorial diameter decreased by 39% and 13%, respectively, in the HT treatment compared to the AT treatment. By contrast, the firmness and total soluble solids (TSS) were higher in the HT treatment than in the AT treatment. Meanwhile, the titratable acidity showed no changes between temperature treatments. In our study, Pn reduction could be associated with stomatal and non-stomatal limitations under HT treatment. Although these findings improve our understanding of the impact of HTs on fruit growth and quality in V. corymbosum, further biochemical and molecular studies are need.</description>
      <author>Jorge Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Villagra, Kelly Johanna &#193;vila, Humberto A. Gajardo, Le&#243;n A. Bravo, Alejandra Ribera-Fonseca, Emilio Jorquera-Fontena, Gustavo Curaqueo, Cecilia Soledad Rold&#225;n, Priscilla Falquetto-Gomes, Adriano Nunes&#8208;Nesi, Marjorie Reyes-D&#237;az</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13131846</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Lean and Rich Vapor Compression with Solar Assistance for Post-combustion Carbon Capture in Natural Gas-Fired Power Plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205400</link>
      <description>Farzin Hosseinifard, Milad Hosseinpour, Mohsen Salimi, Majid Amidpour, Gas science and engineering. 128(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400324776

                The integration of post-combustion capture (PCC) CO2 technologies with power plants and high-emission industrial processes has become imperative for reducing carbon emissions and mitigating environmental impacts. This study focuses on addressing the significant energy consumption associated with PCC and explores the potential of using solar thermal energy to optimize configurations, thereby enhancing sustainability and reducing dependency on conventional power sources. Simulate various configurations under steady-state conditions using Aspen HYSYS V11 and Aspen Economic Evaluation software. The results indicate a substantial reduction in energy consumption to 2.1 GJ/ton CO2 after the initial optimization steps. The key innovations involve the integration of Lean Vapor Compression (LVC), Solvent Split Flow (SSF), Rich Solvent Recycle (RSR), and Rich Vapor Compression (RVC). Further optimization was conducted by integrating a reboiler with parabolic trough collectors (PTC), to reduce energy penalties. The LVC+RVC+RSR+SSF+PTC configuration results reveal a notable improvement in exergoeconomic factors, ranging from 3.13% to 7.8%, highlighting the economic feasibility of the optimized configurations. Simultaneously, the energy penalty decreased by 11.1%, signifying enhanced sustainability in the proposed PCC system. This study contributes to the gap in research by demonstrating the efficacy of solar thermal energy in optimizing PCC configurations, providing a pathway towards more sustainable and energy-efficient solutions for carbon capture in high-emission industrial sectors. The findings offer insights for researchers, engineers, and policymakers aiming to address the pressing issue of carbon emissions from industrial processes.</description>
      <author>Farzin Hosseinifard, Milad Hosseinpour, Mohsen Salimi, Majid Amidpour</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The application of zeolite in reducing green house gases in agriculture field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61511/jbiogritech.v1i1.2024.674</link>
      <description>Ketut Putra, Yunita Ismail Masjud, No host. 1(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400352026

                Background: The addition of Zeolite 4A affected cumulative greenhouse emissions from rice. Zeolite 4A has been found to adsorb CH4 and CO2, reducing overall emissions. The combination of zeolite and fertilizer administration in one or two applications provided an anti-synergistic effect. Methods: The chemical fertilizers and sustained release organic fertilizers used were 16200, 4600 and 666, respectively, and the amount was 31.25 gm2. Findings: Higher fertilization stimulated harvesting, resulting in higher yields and higher proportions of good grain, but less efficient GHG reductions. The ratio of zeolite 4A to fertilizer should be higher than 3: 1 to reduce the increase in greenhouse gas emissions from the use of fertilizer. This treatment resulted in an emission reduction efficiency of 34.69% in proportion to 21.62 g CO2eq m2 g1 zeolite. Conclusion: In the current study, two applications, fertilizer and zeolite 4A, showed the best performance in reducing emissions. However, it is advisable to increase the ratio of zeolite to fertilizer. Similarly, sustained release organic fertilizers resulted in increased CH4 emissions due to the action of methanogens on organic matter. However, plant growth, good grain proportions, and total grain yields increased. Further research is recommended to investigate the optimal ratio of zeolite 4A to organic and synthetic fertilizers for rice cultivation.</description>
      <author>Ketut Putra, Yunita Ismail Masjud</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61511/jbiogritech.v1i1.2024.674</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimising solar: A techno-economic assessment and government facility compensation framework power generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21741/9781644903216-45</link>
      <description>Navaid ALI, Materials research proceedings. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400454504

                Abstract. In light of the necessity to meet growing energy demands while minimising expenses, this article examines two solar power system designs, considering peak and average load situations. The peak system, designed to handle a peak load of 190 MW with 260,568 PV panels installed, generates a significant excess of approximately 49,911 MWh annually. On the other hand, the average load design suggests a little deficit in energy. The monetary analysis reveals considerable capital expenditures for the total installation costs, totalling $58.77 million for an average system and $66.71 million for the peak system. However, the Levelized Cost of Energy (LCOE) rates are relatively competitive, at 0.0835 USD/kWh and 0.0736 USD/kWh respectively. Notably, the study highlights that the environmental impact analysis demonstrates a significant decrease in CO2 emissions, with the peak system achieving a reduction of up to 3,601,588 tonnes per year. This research has explicitly validated the capabilities of centralised solar power systems in addressing the current and future energy difficulties faced by the Government of Sindh in a sustainable and economically viable manner.</description>
      <author>Navaid ALI</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21741/9781644903216-45</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of proposals from key suppliers of small-scale photovoltaic installations for single-family homes considering current regulations and environmental and economic criteria&#8212;A case study in Malaga, Spain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i6.5205</link>
      <description>Enrique Navarrete de G&#225;lvez, Luis Rodr&#237;guez-Passolas Cantal, Francisco Zamora, Shakir Mohamed, Laia Miravet Garret, Journal of infrastructure, policy and development. 8(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400516247

                The economic viability of a photovoltaic (PV) installation depends on regulations regarding administrative, technical and economic conditions associated with self-consumption and the sale of surplus production. Royal Decree (RD) 244/2019 is the Spanish legislation of reference for this case study, in which we analyse and compare PV installation offers by key suppliers. The proposals are not optimal in RD 244/2019 terms and appear not to fully contemplate power generation losses and seem to shift a representative percentage of consumption to the production period. In our case study of a residential dwelling, the best option corresponds to a 5 kWp installation with surplus sale to the market, with a payback period of 18 years and CO2 emission reductions of 1026 kg/year. Demand-side management offers a potential improvement of 6%&#8211;21.8%. Based on the increase in electricity prices since 2020, the best option offers savings of up to &#8364;1507.74 and amortization in 4.24 years. Considering costs and savings, sale to the market could be considered as the only feasible regulatory mechanism for managing surpluses, accompanied by measures to facilitate administrative procedures and guarantees for end users.</description>
      <author>Enrique Navarrete de G&#225;lvez, Luis Rodr&#237;guez-Passolas Cantal, Francisco Zamora, Shakir Mohamed, Laia Miravet Garret</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i6.5205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching Product Selectivity in CO2 Electroreduction via Cu&#8211;S Bond Length Variation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409206</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zijian Li, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Min Gyu Kim, Shangguo Liu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400420646

                Regulating competitive reaction pathways to direct the selectivity of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction toward a desired product is crucial but remains challenging. Herein, switching product from HCOOH to CO is achieved by incorporating Sb element into the CuS, in which the Cu&#8211;S ionic bond is coupled with S&#8211;Sb covalent bond through bridging S atoms that elongates the Cu&#8211;S bond from 2.24 &#197; to 2.30 &#197;. Consequently, CuS with a shorter Cu&#8211;S bond exhibited a high selectivity for producing HCOOH, with a maximum Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 72%. Conversely, Cu3SbS4 characterized by an elongated Cu&#8211;S bond exhibited the most pronounced production of CO with a maximum FE of 60%. In situ spectroscopy combined with density functional theory calculations revealed that the altered Cu&#8210;S bond length and local coordination environment make the *HCOO binding energy weaker on Cu3SbS4 compared to that on CuS. Notably, a volcano&#8208;shaped correlation between the Cu&#8211;S bond length and adsorption strength of *COOH indicates that Cu&#8211;S in Cu3SbS4 as double&#8208;active sites facilitates the adsorption of *COOH, and thus results in the high selectivity of Cu3SbS4 toward CO.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zijian Li, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Min Gyu Kim, Shangguo Liu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching Product Selectivity in CO2 Electroreduction via Cu&#8211;S Bond Length Variation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409206</link>
      <description>Xiaoqian Wei, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Haeseong Jang, Min Kim, Shangguo Liu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400420692

                Regulating competitive reaction pathways to direct the selectivity of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction toward a desired product is crucial but remains challenging. Herein, switching product from HCOOH to CO is achieved by incorporating Sb element into the CuS, in which the Cu&#8211;S ionic bond is coupled with S&#8211;Sb covalent bond through bridging S atoms that elongates the Cu&#8211;S bond from 2.24 &#197; to 2.30 &#197;. Consequently, CuS with a shorter Cu&#8211;S bond exhibited a high selectivity for producing HCOOH, with a maximum Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 72%. Conversely, Cu3SbS4 characterized by an elongated Cu&#8211;S bond exhibited the most pronounced production of CO with a maximum FE of 60%. In situ spectroscopy combined with density functional theory calculations revealed that the altered Cu&#8210;S bond length and local coordination environment make the *HCOO binding energy weaker on Cu3SbS4 compared to that on CuS. Notably, a volcano&#8208;shaped correlation between the Cu&#8211;S bond length and adsorption strength of *COOH indicates that Cu&#8211;S in Cu3SbS4 as double&#8208;active sites facilitates the adsorption of *COOH, and thus results in the high selectivity of Cu3SbS4 toward CO.</description>
      <author>Xiaoqian Wei, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Haeseong Jang, Min Kim, Shangguo Liu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decomposition Analysis of Carbon Emission Drivers and Peaking Pathways for Key Sectors under China&#8217;s Dual Carbon Goals: A Case Study of Jiangxi Province, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16135811</link>
      <description>Xinjie Jiang, Fei Xie, Sustainability. 16(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400410302

                Clarifying the factors influencing CO2 emissions and their peaking pathways in major sectors holds significant practical importance for achieving regional dual-carbon goals. This paper takes Jiangxi, a less developed demonstration zone in central China, as an example. It pioneeringly combines the LMDI method, Tapio decoupling model, and LEAP model to multi-dimensionally analyze the driving mechanisms, evolution patterns, and dynamic relationships with the economic development of carbon emissions in Jiangxi&#8217;s key sectors from 2007 to 2021. It also explores the future carbon emission trends and peaking potentials of various sectors under different scenarios. Our results show that (1) Carbon emissions in various sectors in Jiangxi have continued to grow over the past fifteen years, and although some sectors have seen a slowdown in emission growth, most still rely on traditional fossil fuels; (2) Economic growth and industrial structure effects are the main drivers of carbon emission increases, with a general trend towards decoupling achieved across sectors, while agriculture, forestry, animal husbandry and fishery, and ferrous metal smelting have shown a decline in their decoupling status; (3) In the carbon reduction and low-carbon scenarios, the carbon emission peaks in Jiangxi are estimated to be 227.5 Mt and 216.4 Mt, respectively, and targeted strategies for high-emission industries will facilitate a phased peak across sectors and enhance emissions reduction benefits. This has significant reference value for the central region and even globally in formulating differentiated, phased, sector-specific carbon peaking plans, and exploring pathways for high-quality economic development in tandem with ecological civilization construction.</description>
      <author>Xinjie Jiang, Fei Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16135811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogeological and Mining Considerations in the Design of a Pumping Station in a Shaft of a Closed Black Coal Mine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17133297</link>
      <description>Kajetan d&#8217;Obyrn, Pawe&#322; Kami&#324;ski, Damian Cie&#324;, Sebastian Jendrysik, D. Prosta&#324;ski, Energies. 17(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400366397

                In an overwhelming number of cases, the closure of a coal mine in Poland, for safety reasons, requires the installation of a pumping station and systems for the drainage of inflowing water due to its connection via roadways, goaves, or water-leaking pillars with other adjacent active mines. Due to operational costs, stationary pumping stations are being replaced with submersible pumping stations, wherever the geological/mining conditions allow this. The key factors to be considered when designing a submersible pumping station include the estimated water influx and the storage and emergency reservoir fill-up time. If the water level in the emergency reservoir exceeds the level of the maximum ordinate, there is the risk of water flooding an adjacent active mine, which poses a serious safety risk to this mine. A pumping station design must ensure that water can be pumped out also in emergency situations and must ensure permanent control over the level of the water table. The pumped-out water, after potential treatment, can be utilized as technological water in industrial plants. In the designed pumping station, it is also feasible to establish underground pumped-storage hydropower. This would enable the storage of energy from renewable sources, thereby contributing to CO2 emission reduction.</description>
      <author>Kajetan d&#8217;Obyrn, Pawe&#322; Kami&#324;ski, Damian Cie&#324;, Sebastian Jendrysik, D. Prosta&#324;ski</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17133297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unconventional Grain Fragmentation Creates High-Density Boundaries for Efficient CO2-to-C2+ Electro-conversion at Ampere-Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109945</link>
      <description>Junjie Ding, Qianling Song, Xin L&#252;, Lujie Ruan, Min Zhang, Chao Ban, Jiazhi Meng, Jiangping Ma, Yajie Feng, Yang Wang, Xiaoping Tao, Danmei Yu, Jiyan Dai, Li Gan, Xiaoyuan Zhou, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400345495

                Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to produce multi-carbon products (C2+) is one of the most sustainable manners to achieve net-zero carbon emissions. Among many approaches, enriching grain boundaries (GBs) in copper (Cu) catalysts has been demonstrated to enable enhancement for C2+ production. However, it still lacks effective strategies to controllably synthesize abundant GBs, rendering efficient C2+ production a persistent challenge, especially at ampere-level current density. Herein, we propose a novel strategy, which can achieve unconventional grain fragmentation during thermal annealing and thus create controllable GB densities. The catalyst with the utmost GB density exhibits a peak C2+ faradaic efficiency (FE) of ca. 70.0% in an H-type cell and 68.2% in a flow cell; even more impressively, it delivers an ultra-high C2+ current density of 0.768 A cm-2, outperforming most recently reported results. A combination of in situ spectroscopies and theoretical calculations reveal that the enrichment of GBs yields more active sites for a higher &#8270;CO coverage, leading to promotion of the &#8270;CO-&#8270;CO coupling process and ultimately high C2+ production performance.</description>
      <author>Junjie Ding, Qianling Song, Xin L&#252;, Lujie Ruan, Min Zhang, Chao Ban, Jiazhi Meng, Jiangping Ma, Yajie Feng, Yang Wang, Xiaoping Tao, Danmei Yu, Jiyan Dai, Li Gan, Xiaoyuan Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu Regulating the Bifunctional Activity of Co-O Sites for the High-Performance Rechargeable Zinc-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04853</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dandan Yue, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qingyu Li, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400422879

                The rational design of cost-effective and highly active electrocatalysts becomes the crucial energy storage technology to boost the kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which hinders the large-scale application of metal-air batteries under the situation of increasingly pressing energy anxiety. Herein, the Co-based ZIF introduced the moderate amount of Cu2+-derived Cu/Co metal nanoparticles (NPs) embedded in carbon frameworks after high-temperature calcination. The Co-O bond on the surface of Co nanoparticles is modulated by adjacent Cu nanoparticles with the surface Cu-O bonds. The resulted increase of the Co2+/Co3+ ratio in 0.1CuCo-NC enhances the ORR/OER bifunctional catalytic kinetics along with the &#916;E of 0.639 V. In situ Raman spectra of the catalyst on the three-electrode system as well as in the driven zinc-air battery (ZAB) show that the Co-O active sites regulated by Cu nanoparticles with Cu-O bonds maintain a periodic lattice expansion and compression during discharging and charging. The zinc-air battery based on 0.1CuCo-NC has a peak power density of up to 198.3 mW cm&#8211;2, a mass-specific capacity of 798.2 mAh g&#8211;1, and a cycling stability of 923 h at room temperature. This work makes up the research gap of a Co-based metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF)-derived catalyst regulated by a transition metal.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dandan Yue, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qingyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidation of synergism in Ce-Zr/SBA-15 mesoporous catalysts and the effects on the activity in selective glycerol to lactic acid reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.powtec.2024.120048</link>
      <description>Salmiza Saleh, Muhammad Yusri Ahmad, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Ahmad Zuhairi Abdullah, Powder technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400392020

                The continued conversion of glycerol to value-added chemicals is essential in ensuring the sustainable development of the biodiesel industry. Selective catalytic oxidation of glycerol to lactic acid provides an alternative approach to valorizing glycerol. A mesoporous SBA-15 supported mixed-metallic oxide catalyst is deemed essential to selectively produce lactic acid in this mixed parallel and multi-step reaction. SBA-15-supported bimetallic Ce and Zr oxides were proved to be highly efficient catalysts for the selective glycerol oxidation into lactic acid in base-free media. The synergism between Ce and Zr in the bimetallic oxide compounds could enhance the creation of oxygen vacancies in the catalyst via the reduction of Ce4+ to Ce3+. The 2:1CeZr/SBA-15 catalyst exhibited prominent catalytic activity in selectively oxidizing glycerol to lactic acid, with a glycerol conversion of 91.8% and a lactic acid yield of 35.1%. This work achieved superior catalytic performance compared to previously conducted studies, primarily due to the significantly higher initial glycerol concentration employed in this study. To ascertain the intrinsic active sites of the catalyst, the physicochemical properties of the catalyst were thoroughly examined using BET, FTIR, XRD, FESEM, TEM, CO2-TPD, O2-TPD, and H2-TPR analysis. This work concluded that the synergistic interaction of the active sites, which led to the formation of active oxygen species, facilitated primary dehydrogenation of the terminal -OH bond in glycerol. Hence, in this work, a plausible glycerol conversion mechanism over the 2:1CeZr/SBA-15 catalyst was also proposed.</description>
      <author>Salmiza Saleh, Muhammad Yusri Ahmad, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Ahmad Zuhairi Abdullah</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.powtec.2024.120048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights On Liquid Jet Breakup And Spray Formation Of An Air-Assisted Atomizer: Conventional And Alternative Jet Fuel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55037/lxlaser.21st.186</link>
      <description>In&#234;s Ferr&#227;o, Miguel A.A. Mendes, Ana Moita, Andr&#233; R. Silva, No host. 21(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400450791

                Presently, it is imperative to address global environmental challenges. The concerns are related to the depletion of non-renewable fossil fuels, greenhouse gases, and pollutant emissions. The transportation sector contributes significantly to these issues. In particular, the aviation industry primarily relies on jet fuel, a fossil fuel responsible for around 2% of anthropogenic CO2 emissions. As a result, to address contemporary society environmental concerns and energy requirements, promising renewable and green energy sources are being intensively investigated, especially in air transportation. Sustainable aviation fuels (SAF), particularly biofuels, have been explored and indicated as a short-term solution to address the energy transition in the aviation sector. Implementing alternative fuels requires a deeper investigation regarding the spray dynamics. Following this, the present study explores conventional (Jet A-1) and alternative jet fuel (HVO) atomization, and the breakup length is explored in a wide range of operating conditions. The normalized mean breakup length was measured, and a correlation was proposed based on the experimental data. Additionally, the droplets released by the jet breakup are compared for both fuels in terms of diameter. Observations reveal the occurrence of jet flapping and bag breakup, affected by the air flowrate. The results also show that regardless of the fuel, increasing the momentum flux leads to a reduction in the normalized mean breakup length. An increase in the air flowrate promotes a shorter breakup length, resulting in a secondary droplet with smaller secondary droplet diameters. An empirical correlation was developed based on the fitting of the experimental data. This correlation indicates that the normalized mean breakup length exhibits a power law relation with M, which is consistent with the literature. This experimental study is essential to research on biofuels and aids in the development of new injectors and the precision of theoretical models integrated into numerical algorithms.</description>
      <author>In&#234;s Ferr&#227;o, Miguel A.A. Mendes, Ana Moita, Andr&#233; R. Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55037/lxlaser.21st.186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported Single-Atom Cu Catalysts Modified with Fe for RWGS Reaction: Deciphering the Role of Fe in the Reaction Mechanism by In Situ/Operando Spectroscopic Techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01493</link>
      <description>Abdallah I.M. Rabee, Hayder Abed, Thanh Huyen Vuong, Stephan Bartling, Laura Krau&#223;er, Hanan Atia, Nils Rockstroh, Evgenii V. Kondratenko, Angelika Br&#252;ckner, Jabor Rabeah, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400342470

                Reverse water&#8211;gas shift (RWGS) reaction has attracted much attention as a potential approach for CO2 valorization via the production of synthesis gas, especially over Fe-modified supported Cu catalysts on CeO2. However, most studies have focused solely on investigating the RWGS reaction over catalysts with high Cu and Fe loadings, thus leading to an increase in the complexity of the catalytic system and, hence, preventing the gain of any reliable information about the nature of the active sites and reaction mechanism. In this work, a CeO2-supported single-atom Cu catalyst modified with iron was synthesized and evaluated for the RWGS reaction. The catalytic results reveal a significant synergistic effect between CuCeO2 and Fe, demonstrating an activity up to three times higher than the combined catalytic activities of monometallic catalysts (Fe/CeO2 + CuCeO2) under identical conditions. Various ex situ and in situ/operando techniques are employed to unveil the concealed role of Fe in catalyst activity enhancement. The combined findings from hydrogen temperature-programmed reduction (H2-TPR) and operando electron paramagnetic resonance spectroscopy (EPR) reveal that the added Fe predominantly interacts with Cu-containing surface sites, resulting in the stabilization of higher proportions of Cu single sites. Near-ambient pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (NAP-XPS) and operando EPR results unveil a synergistic interplay of Fe with Cu-containing sites and CeOx domains, efficiently enhancing both the reoxidation of Cu+ in Cu+&#8211;Ov&#8211;Ce3+ moieties and the reducibility of Ce4+ in CeOx domains under RWGS conditions. Detailed mechanistic studies reveal that the RWGS reaction predominantly proceeds via the redox mechanism.</description>
      <author>Abdallah I.M. Rabee, Hayder Abed, Thanh Huyen Vuong, Stephan Bartling, Laura Krau&#223;er, Hanan Atia, Nils Rockstroh, Evgenii V. Kondratenko, Angelika Br&#252;ckner, Jabor Rabeah</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Obesity on Respiratory Health: The Role of Sport and Physical Activity in Prevention and Management</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12775/qs.2024.15.52231</link>
      <description>RW Makuch, Amir N. Kucharski, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Alicja Chro&#347;cicka, Khushboo Gala, Andrzej Czajka, Pawe&#322; Lenard, Sara Michalska, Martyna Dewicka, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Quality in Sport. 15(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400425212

                Introduction and Objective: Obesity is a major social and economic problem. Since the 1980s, the number of overweight and obese people has doubled. Treatment of such patients is 30% more expensive than for people of normal weight. The main aim of the article is to present the impact of the occurrence of respiratory diseases and the deterioration of the system function. In addition, the article reviews the impact of physical activity and diet on weight loss and the prevention of further weight gain. Review and Methods: Review and summary of studies and meta-analysis of studies available in open-source format on Google Scholar and PubMed. Abbreviated Description of the State of Knowledge: One of the most common diseases in the population is bronchial asthma. People with excess body weight have a more severe course, and numerous studies have been carried out to explain the cause. The main mechanism that worsens respiratory function is mechanical compression by fatty tissue. It has also been observed that the inflammatory response, underlying the etiopathogenesis of asthma, may be caused by the secretion of inflammatory mediators by adipocytes. This is currently being investigated. Obstructive sleep apnea is a disorder that results in a fragmentation of sleep, which has serious health consequences and leads to a reduction in quality of life. Obesity is a major risk factor. The severity of the condition is strongly related to excess body weight. Obese hypoventilation syndrome is a condition in which obesity impairs alveolar ventilation and CO2 removal, resulting in hypercapnia, which can lead to respiratory failure. Summary: Weight loss and interventions to prevent weight gain in people with a baseline BMI &gt;25 kg/m2 are fundamental to good health. For best results, a calorie-restricted diet should be combined with physical activity. The WHO has created recommendations for the amount of physical activity needed each week.</description>
      <author>RW Makuch, Amir N. Kucharski, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Alicja Chro&#347;cicka, Khushboo Gala, Andrzej Czajka, Pawe&#322; Lenard, Sara Michalska, Martyna Dewicka, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12775/qs.2024.15.52231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time LNG Buses Emissions Prediction Based on a Temporal Fusion Trans-Formers Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3808/jei.202400517</link>
      <description>Qing Liu, Fei Gao, Jun Zhao, Yafei Cai, Lei Chen, Cheng Lv, Journal of environmental informatics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400515183

                Emissions from transportation are one of the key factors preventing the achievement of carbon peaking and carbon neutrality by 2050, with particular attention to emissions from buses. Specifically, few research has been conducted on the exhaust emissions characteristics of liquified natural gas (LNG) buses under different driving scenarios. This study proposed a framework for predicting exhaust emissions of LNG buses based on the portable emission measurement system and GPS collaborative perception data. Firstly, the emission distribution characteristics of CO2, CO, HC, and NOx from LNG buses in real-world driving were analyzed by visualization methods. Then, the real-time exhaust emissions of LNG buses were predicted based on the temporal fusion transformers model for both urban and suburban sections of Zhenjiang City, and the model validity was verified. The current and past 10 s driving states were used for predicting the emission rate of LNG buses. The results showed that the proposed model outperforms other advanced algorithms in real-time exhaust emissions prediction of LNG buses, with an average R2 value higher than 0.94 and an average MAPE reduction of 14.19%. The error assessment revealed that the emission values and average emission rates are higher when driving in the urban section compared to the suburban section. Among the influencing factors, traffic conditions have the most significant impacts on the exhaust emissions of LNG buses, followed by road conditions and driving states, with relative feature importance of 48.9, 34.8, and 16.3%, respectively. Additionally, the current and past 10 s driving states also significantly influenced real-time predictions. This study provides an essential theoretical reference for reducing exhaust emissions for city buses.</description>
      <author>Qing Liu, Fei Gao, Jun Zhao, Yafei Cai, Lei Chen, Cheng Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3808/jei.202400517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Modeling of the Local Reaction Environment in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-t37bp-v2</link>
      <description>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400469170

                Electrocatalytic reactions, such as oxygen reduction/evolution reactions and CO2 reduction reaction that are pivotal for the energy transition, are multi-step processes that occur in a nanoscale electric double layer (EDL) at a solid-liquid interface. Conventional analyses based on the Sabatier principle, using binding energies or effective electronic structure properties such as the d-band center as descriptors, are able to grasp overall trends in catalytic activity in specific groups of catalysts. However, thermodynamic approaches often fail to account for a plethora of electrolyte effects that arise in the EDL, including pH, cation, and anion effects. These effects have been observed to exert strong impacts on electrocatalytic reactions. There is growing consensus that the local reaction environment (LRE) prevailing in the EDL is the key to deciphering these complex and hitherto perplexing electrolyte effects. Increasing attention is thus paid to designing appropriate electrolytes, positioning the LRE at center stage. To this end, unraveling the LRE is becoming essential for designing electrocatalysts with specifically tailored properties, which could enable much needed breakthroughs in electrochemical energy science. Theory and modeling are getting more and more important and powerful in addressing this multifaceted problem that involves physical phenomena at different scales and interacting in a multidimensional parametric space. Theoretical models developed for this purpose should treat intrinsic multistep kinetics of electrocatalytic reactions, EDL effects from sub-nm scale to the scale of 10 nm, and mass transport phenomena bridging scales from &lt; 0.1 to 100 &#956;m. Given the diverse physical phenomena and scales involved, it is evident that the challenge at hand surpasses the capabilities of any single theoretical or computational approach. In this Account, we present a hierarchical theoretical framework to address the above challenge. It seamlessly integrates several modules: (i) microkinetic modelling that accounts for various reaction pathways; (ii) an LRE model that describes the interfacial region extending from the nanometric EDL continuously to the solution bulk; (iii) first-principles calculations that provide parameters, e.g., adsorption energies, activation barriers and EDL parameters. The microkinetic model considers all elementary steps without designating an a priori rate-determining step. The kinetics of these elementary steps are expressed in terms of local concentrations, potential and electric field that are co-determined by EDL charging and mass transport in the LRE model. Vital insights on electrode kinetic phenomena, i.e., potential-dependent Tafel slopes, cation effects, and pH effects, obtained from this hierarchical framework are then reviewed. Finally, an outlook on further improvement of the model framework is presented, in view of recent developments in first-principles based simulation of electrocatalysis, observations of dynamic reconstruction of catalysts, and machine-learning assisted computational simulations.</description>
      <author>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-t37bp-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Catalonia facing a Megadrought episode?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/ems2024-783</link>
      <description>Vicent Altava-Ortiz, M. Barnolas, A. Barrera-Escoda, Sotiris Assimenidis, Mar&#237;a Cort&#232;s, Marc Prohom, Jordi Mor&#233;, Javier Mart&#237;n&#8208;Vide, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400363843

                Drought is a defining feature of the Mediterranean climate, characterized by frequent periods of precipitation significantly below average. However, the ongoing drought episode affecting Catalonia shows a severity never recorded in the instrumental period 1915-2023. In the case of the city of Barcelona, where precipitation data stretches back to 1786, one must go back to the early 19th century to find a similar 3-year drought period.&amp;#160; Observing the trend of drought episodes over last few decades, the current drought is the latest in a series of episodes of shorter duration and intensity, but which can be also locally classified as exceptional at the time of their occurrence. Consequently, some areas of North-eastern Catalonia have endured conditions similar to semi-permanent drought over the past decade, or even beyond.&amp;#160; The current drought in Catalonia is not an isolated event but part of a broader regional pattern. In general, the entire South-western Europe and Northern Africa have been under drought conditions to a greater or lesser extent in recent years (Faranda et al, 2023). Moreover, other Mediterranean climate regions across the globe, such as Central Chile and California, have lately witnessed record-breaking droughts during the instrumental period, some being classified as Megadroughts (Garreaud et al., 2020; Williams et al., 2022).&amp;#160; More recently, some authors (Cook et al, 2022) have further explored the concept of Megadrought. These episodes have common characteristics beyond their impacts that justify this qualification, including remarkable temporal persistence, unprecedented nature compared with previous events, links with external climatic forcings, or their connection with SST anomalies. &amp;#160; Currently, the global climate system is strongly forced by the increase in CO2 concentrations in the atmosphere. Climate projections point to a reduction in precipitation for the Mediterranean climate area, which, combined with the increase in temperature values, will lead to greater aridity and the occurrence of droughts with a magnitude never recorded before. In light of these projections and the characteristics exhibited by the current Catalan drought, the question arises: Is Catalonia facing a Megadrought episode?&amp;#160; REFERENCES Cook, B.I., Smerdon, J.E., Cook, E.R. et al. Megadroughts in the Common Era and the Anthropocene. Nat Rev Earth Environ 3, 741&amp;#8211;757 (2022).&amp;#160; Faranda D., Pascale S., Bulut B. Persistent anticyclonic conditions and climate change exacerbated the exceptional 2022 European-Mediterranean drought. Environ. Res. Lett. 18, 034030 (2023)&amp;#160; Garreaud RD, Boisier JP, Rondanelli R, Montecinos A, Sep&amp;#250;lveda HH, Veloso-Aguila D. The Central Chile Mega Drought (2010&amp;#8211;2018): A climate dynamics perspective. Int J Climatol. 2020; 40: 421&amp;#8211;439. &amp;#160; Williams, A.P., Cook, B.I. &amp;amp; Smerdon, J.E. Rapid intensification of the emerging southwestern North American megadrought in 2020&amp;#8211;2021. Nat. Clim. Chang. 12, 232&amp;#8211;234 (2022).</description>
      <author>Vicent Altava-Ortiz, M. Barnolas, A. Barrera-Escoda, Sotiris Assimenidis, Mar&#237;a Cort&#232;s, Marc Prohom, Jordi Mor&#233;, Javier Mart&#237;n&#8208;Vide</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/ems2024-783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oral and e&#8208;Poster Presentations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1471-0528.17881</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, in high-income countries., BJOG. 131(S1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400337590

                BJOG: An International Journal of Obstetrics &amp; GynaecologyVolume 131, Issue S1 p. 3-88 ABSTRACTFree Access Oral and e-Poster Presentations First published: 03 July 2024 https://doi.org/10.1111/1471-0528.17881AboutSectionsPDF ToolsRequest permissionExport citationAdd to favoritesTrack citation ShareShare Give accessShare full text accessShare full-text accessPlease review our Terms and Conditions of Use and check box below to share full-text version of article.I have read and accept the Wiley Online Library Terms and Conditions of UseShareable LinkUse the link below to share a full-text version of this article with your friends and colleagues. Learn more.Copy URL Share a linkShare onEmailFacebookTwitterLinkedInRedditWechat Oral 3 The association between socio-economic disadvantage and severe maternal morbidity and mortality in high-income countries: A systematic review Miranda Geddes-Barton; Rema Ramakrisnan; Marian Knight University of Oxford, Oxford, United Kingdom Introduction: There is an increasing appreciation for the impact of socio-economic disadvantage on maternal health outcomes. This systematic review aimed to summarise the evidence for severe maternal morbidity (SMM) and maternal mortality (MM) in women who are socio-economically disadvantaged compared to those who are not, in high-income countries. Methods: A comprehensive search was conducted in MEDLINE, EMBASE, CINAHL, and PsycInfo databases. Peer-reviewed papers from observational studies were included. A narrative synthesis and meta-analyses of comparable studies, structured around the different definitions of socio-economic disadvantage and type of outcome (SMM or MM) were undertaken. Risk of bias was assessed using a modified Newcastle-Ottawa tool. Results: The final review included 49 papers; 27 cohort studies, 10 case-control and four cross-sectional and eight National Maternal Mortality Surveillance Programs. 30 papers reported SMM and 22 MM, as the outcome. In the meta-analyses, in the most compared to the least amount of neighbourhood deprivation, neighbourhood income, neighbourhood poverty and low education, the odds of SMM were 1.45 (95% CI 1.13&#8211;1.85), 1.44 (95% CI 1.32&#8211;1.57), 1.61 (95% CI 0.97&#8211;2.66) and 1.33 (95% CI 1.19&#8211;1.49) respectively. In the most compared to the least amount of unemployment, neighbourhood deprivation, lowest occupational group and low education the odds of MM were 1.86 (95% CI 0.95&#8211;3.66), 2.10 (95% CI 1.57&#8211;2.81), 1.61 (95% CI 1.03&#8211;2.51), 1.90 (95% CI 1.29&#8211;2.79) respectively. Discussion: Across high-income countries there is a consistent association between socio-economic disadvantage and SMM and MM. Further research is needed to identify targeted interventions to reduce increased risk. 9 Virtual reality for the management of pain and anxiety during manual vacuum aspiration: A randomized control trial Shereen Ibrahim1; Anna Mcdougall2; Eleanor Bard3; Deo Nandita4; Schahrazed Rouabhi5 1Lister Hospital, Stevenage, United Kingdom; 2Chelsea and Westminster Hospital, London, United Kingdom; 3Barnet Hospital, London, United Kingdom; 4Barts NHS Hospital, London, United Kingdom; 5North Middlesex University Hospital, London, United Kingdom Introduction: Manual vacuum aspiration (MVA) stands as an effective outpatient alternative for managing miscarriage and retained products of conception. Virtual Reality (VR), a novel intervention, has emerged as a potential distraction technique for pain management in ambulatory gynaecology settings. Methods: A prospective randomized controlled trial was conducted involving 50-eligible women scheduled for MVA across two hospital sites. Participants were randomized into standard care or VR intervention groups, with stratification by site, BMI and parity. Data were collected through questionnaires, numerical rating scales, and audio-recorded interviews. Statistical analysis utilized quantitative comparisons and qualitative analysis of interview content. Results: Out of 72-women approached, 50 (69%) were randomized, with exclusion primarily due to language barriers. Baseline characteristics showed balance between VR and standard groups. Pain and anxiety scores pre-procedure were similar in both groups. No significant differences in experienced pain or anxiety were observed between the VR and standard care groups. Patient feedback revealed 100% positive experiences with VR, reporting reduced anxiety (91%) and pain distraction (73%). However, no statistical significance was found in self-reported pain or anxiety scores between the groups. Reasons for this discrepancy may include varying pain perceptions during MVA and incomplete immersion in the VR world. Conclusion: The VR intervention was well-received by participants, with reported reductions in anxiety and perceived pain distraction. Despite positive patient experiences, no statistically significant variance in pain or anxiety scores was identified between the VR and standard care groups. Further investigations are warranted to discern the impact of VR immersion on pain management. 10 Obstetric and perinatal outcomes in women with Turner's syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis Alicia Walker1, Zachary Nash1,2; Hajra Khattak1,2; Bassel Wattar3,4; Aviva Petrie5; Melanie Davies1,2 1UCL Institute for Women's Health, London, United Kingdom; 2Reproductive Medicine Unit, Elizabeth Garrett Anderson Wing, University College London Hospitals, London, United Kingdom; 3Beginnings Assisted Conception Unit, Epsom and St Helier University Hospitals, London, United Kingdom; 4Institute for Clinical Trials and Methodology, University College London, London, United Kingdom; 5University College London, London, United Kingdom Introduction: Turner's Syndrome (TS) affects 1 in 2,000 live female births. The 2017 'Clinical Practice Guidelines for the Care of Girls and Women with Turner Syndrome' acknowledges women with TS possess an increased risk of adverse obstetric and perinatal outcomes. However, no overall risk estimate for each outcome has been reported. This study reports pooled risk for each outcome and compares risk between egg donation and spontaneous pregnancies. Methods: We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis with a prospectively registered protocol, under PRISMA Guidelines. 30 studies reporting obstetric or perinatal outcomes of pregnancies in women with TS were included. Eligibility screening was conducted by 2 independent reviewers. Obstetric and perinatal outcome data was extracted and tabulated using a standard proforma. Results: 1724 pregnancies were included. Pooled risks: Obstetric outcomes: caesarean section (62.8%) (95% CI: 57&#8211;76%), pregnancy-associated hypertensive disorders (21%) (95% CI: 13&#8211;29%), pre-eclampsia (10%) (95% CI: 6&#8211;14%), gestational diabetes mellitus (6.0%) (95% CI: 4&#8211;8%), aortic dissection (1.1%) (95% CI: 0&#8211;2%), intrahepatic cholestasis of pregnancy (4.6%) (95% CI: 0&#8211;7%), post-partum haemorrhage (17.9%) (95% CI: &#8722;3 to 37%), and maternal mortality (0.3%) (95% CI: 0&#8211;1%). Perinatal outcomes: prematurity (14.1%) (95% CI: 8&#8211;18%), low birthweight (25.1%) (95% CI: 12&#8211;23%), and perinatal mortality (1.2%) (95% CI: 0&#8211;1%). Egg-donation pregnancies yield significantly higher rates of: caesarean section (82.8% vs. 55.7%) (RR 1.49) (95% CI: 1.27&#8211;1.76), pregnancy-associated hypertensive disorder (33.0% vs 12.9%: p = 0.001), pre-eclampsia (16.9% vs 8.2%: p = 0.0023), gestational hypertension (17.9% vs 0.0%: p = 0.082), low-birthweight (43.0% vs 1.9%: p &lt; 0.001) and preterm birth (17.5% vs 0.0%: p &lt; 0.001) than spontaneous pregnancies. Multiple pregnancies resulted in high rates of prematurity (70.0%), low birth-weight (73.3%) and pregnancy-associated hypertensive disorders (60.9%). Conclusion: TS women experience high rates of pregnancy complications. Risks are increased in egg donation pregnancies and multiple pregnancies compared to singleton spontaneous pregnancies. 22 Teaching of undergraduate medical students in obstetrics and gynaecology: Enablers and deterrents for clinicians in women's health Sophie Bracke1; Prithi Uthayananthan2; Simran Jolly2; Irene Gafson1 1Whittington Health, London, United Kingdom; 2University College London, London, United Kingdom Introduction: Ensuring high-quality undergraduate education in Obstetrics and Gynaecology is essential for cultivating proficient healthcare professionals and generating interest in the specialty. To optimise educational delivery, it is crucial to comprehend factors that enable and deter staff engagement in medical education. Methods: An online, anonymised survey was conducted in November 2023 amongst midwives and doctors within a London Obstetrics &amp; Gynaecology department. Collected data included staff designation, levels of enablement and deterrence of various teaching-related factors, frequency of interaction with medical students, and suggestions for enhancing teaching effectiveness. Results: Twenty staff members (12 midwives, 8 doctors) participated, highlighting the role of teaching enjoyment and students' enthusiasm as primary enablers. Conversely, the perception of students attending solely for specific sign-offs emerged as significant deterrents. Mixed results were observed for other enablers (e.g., feedback, senior support) and deterrents (e.g., punctuality issues, lack of reward). Free-text responses highlighted the need for enhanced communication between staff and the medical school, especially regarding curriculum and timetable awareness. Conclusion: This study identifies key factors which enable or deter the teaching of medical students, emphasising the role of factors such as enthusiastic students and enjoyment of teaching. Recognising factors that enable and deter staff member from teaching offers opportunities for targeted improvements in education. In order to address shortcomings regarding enablers or deterrents identified, a student-led teaching handbook was developed, and a dedicated teaching session occurred to update staff on learning needs of students. Ongoing student feedback demonstrates upward-trending student satisfaction with their clinical placement. 28 Trainee management of undiagnosed emergency placenta accrete spectrum PASD Anas Alojayli1; Chineze Otigbah2; Sorina Bologa1; Michael Magro1 1Queen's Hospital, Romford, United Kingdom; 2Queen's Hospital, Romford, United Kingdom Background: Teaching video to show how to manage emergency presentations of placenta accrete spectrum disorder (PASD) by a trainee on call duty. This video consists of two parts; the first part will be presented by the trainee and the steps should the trainee do, and the second part will be presented by the consultant. Short video to show pre-op preparation, identification of PASD intra-operatively, delivery of the baby, use of simple vaso-occulsive techniques, managing the affected area by wedge resection (excision) and managing transfusion including the use of cell salvage and post op complications. Method: Video presentation of one case showing how to excise an anterior PASD. This includes. Identification of a PASD in an emergency How to proceed to delivering the fetus avoiding the placenta, (pre-op mapping, fundal classical incision) and closing the incision. The use of simple vaso-occlusive techniques in an emergency (flexible ligatures). Results: The stepwise method of pre-op ultrasound placental mapping, recognising features of PASD and avoiding the area by applying a fundal incision delivering the baby and closing the incision with placenta in-situ. This method helps in an emergency to reduce maternal morbidity and facilitated the fertility sparing surgery, reduced length of stay needs for intensive care and morbidity. This video should enable trainees to learn how to manage these conditions in an emergency. Conclusion: These video aim to show how to manage these conditions in a stepwise manner with techniques that can be used in low resource countries saving lives. 31 Say no to wasting N2O, Entonox waste reduction project Amy Manning; Katherine Whitehouse Royal Victoria Infirmary, Newcastle upon Tyne, United Kingdom Introduction: Entonox is a valuable, versatile analgesic and has unique properties to support a woman in labour. However, N2O is a significant potent greenhouse gas contributing to climate change. 1 kg N2O is equivalent to 298 kg CO2. It is a medical gas that is exhaled by the patient virtually unchanged and remains stable in the atmosphere for 115 years. Entonox has occupational hazards to staff, it's associated with miscarriage and B12 deficiency. A significant proportion of Entonox is wasted before it even reaches the patient, in the pipework and the bedheads. Methods: A team was set up, an anaesthetist, estates manager, pharmacist and obstetric and gynaecology trainee. Tests had been carried out on the pipework system and leaks identified and fixed. However, a functioning demand valve can leak 2 litres per minute and a faulty valve may exceed this without audibility. It was decided to focus on asking staff to unplug at the bedheads when not in use. Signs were made to place next to each plug in site. Educational posters and information distributed to all staff. Results: In November 2023 one cylinder less of Entonox was used from simply unplugging at the bedheads. One cylinder per month equates to 195,300 liters Entonox per year. Conclusion: As O&amp;G doctors our aim is to bring healthy babies into the world, we should be bringing them into a healthy world. Simple changes in our practice can significantly reduce the carbon footprint of healthcare, reduce costs and staff exposure. 34 The management of menopause in women with a history of breast cancer at Guy's Tertiary Menopause Clinic Sarah Aulds; Deborah Bruce; Debra Holloway; Janice Rymer Guy's and St Thomas Hospital, London, United Kingdom Introduction: The HABITS trial reported that HRT increased the risk of breast cancer recurrence. However, no studies have reported an increased mortality rate, thus questioning its use. The risk of recurrence with HRT is thought to be higher in women with previous hormone receptor positive disease. Methods: Women with a history of breast cancer were assessed over six months at Guy's Hospital. The hormone status, treatment of breast cancer, menopausal symptoms and management options were assessed. Results: Lifestyle counselling, trials of vaginal moisturisers and referral to our psychosexual service where indicated were offered to all 43 women. In 23% of women, solely lifestyle modifications and vaginal moisturisers were advocated. In 42% of women struggling with predominantly vasomotor symptoms venlafaxine was initiated. Oxybutynin was prescribed in 12% of women with associated genitourinary symptoms. Gabapentin was prescribed for 9% who suffered with bony joint pains. In a third of women prescribed non-hormonal medications, a vaginal oestrogen was also prescribed. Intrarosa was given in 2% of women with severe vaginal dryness. Transdermal HRT was commenced in 12% of women with symptoms severely impairing their quality of life. Conclusion: Lifestyle modifications, psychosexual counselling and non-hormonal treatment always formed the first line of treatment. Venlafaxine was the most prescribed medication in this cohort. Interestingly, the hormone receptor status did not seem to impact the decision; the 12% of women who were started on HRT all had a history of hormone receptor positive breast cancer. All forms of oestrogen were avoided in women on aromatase inhibitors. 35 "Does my baby look big in this?" An investigation of the accuracy of estimated fetal weight (EFW) on ultrasound scan in suspected large (LGA) babies compared to appropriately grown (AGA) babies, at a North London Hospital in 2020 Ellie Bard1; Edwin Ruhinda2; Deepa Janga2 1Barnet Hospital, London, United Kingdom; 2North Middlesex University Hospital, London, United Kingdom Introduction: Big babies are at increased risk of difficult births. However, the baby's size is uncertain until birth. Methods: The LGA dataset included all women presenting in June-August 2020 with customised EFW &gt;90th centile or AC &gt;95th centile at &gt;34 weeks' gestation, and EFW &gt;90th centile at final scan (n = 91). The AGA dataset included all babies born in 2020 with EFW obtained within four weeks of birth; and normal fetal size, growth and liquor at final scan (n = 414). We calculated actual and absolute (positive) percentage scan error using birthweight and a growth-adjusted projection formula. Analysis with STATA-12 used t-tests, chi-squared and Wilcoxon rank-sum tests. Results: The datasets were similar regarding gestation at final scan, scan-to-birth interval, maternal age and BMI. Birthweights were higher among suspected LGAs: mean 3.72 kg compared to 3.27 kg, p &lt; 0.001. 31/91 (34.1%) babies in the LGA group were LGA at birth. EFWs were generally over-estimated, and EFW error was higher in the LGA group: mean actual error +9.6% compared to +5.6%, p &lt; 0.001. The proportion of observations within 10%, 15% and 20% absolute error margins were significantly lower in the LGA group: 52.8%, 75.8% and 87.9% compared to 71%, 90.8% and 96.9% in the AGA group, p-values &lt; 0.001. Mode of birth was significantly different: 35% vaginal and 61.6% caesarean among LGAs compared to 61.7% vaginal and 32.7% caesarean among AGAs, p &lt; 0.001. Conclusion: Most suspected LGA babies are normal size at birth. EFW error was greater in suspected LGA babies. Women need counselling about the uncertainty in EFW to enable informed birth choices. 41 10 Year review of the prognostic characteristics and recurrence patterns of G1 endometrial carcinoma; large retrospective analysis of a tertiary centre Negin Sadeghi1,2; Andreas Zouridis1; Kianoush Zarrindej1; Chritina Pappa1; Ammara Kashif1; Sarah Smyth2; Alisha Sattar1; Stephen Damato1; Mostafa Abdalla1; Susan Addley1; Sean Kehoe1; Hooman Soleymani Majd1 1Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Oxford, United Kingdom; 2Frimley Health NHS Trust, Slough, United Kingdom Introduction: Grade 1 (G1) endometrial cancer (EC) are well differentiated cells which, most are confined to the uterus and ovary (stage 1), hence mainly treated with surgery alone and often in benign gynaecology service. The aim of this study is to evaluate the independent risk factors for recurrence and mortality and to describe the recurrence patterns. Methods: Data from 238 cases of G1 endometrial cancer who were operated at Oxford University Hospitals between 2009 and 2019, were analysed. We used independent samples t-test to compare continuous variables and Pearson chi-square or Fisher's extract test for categorical variables. Survival rates were calculated from Kaplan&#8211;Meier curves and compared using log-rank tests. Univariate and multivariate Cox proportional hazards analysis was conducted to assess the potential risk factors for relapse and mortality. Results: 14/238 cases had recurrence (5.88%) with Cancer specific death rate of 2/238 = 0.84%. Mean time interval from surgery until relapse was 30 months and half the patients were asymptomatic, with relapse occurring mainly in the vaginal vault. The multivariable Cox proportional hazards analysis demonstrated that only depth of myometrial invasion &gt;50% (p value 0.049) and serosal breach (p value 0.017) were independent risk factors of recurrence in our study. Conclusion: Despite the overall promising outcome of G1 EC, recurrence rate is 2&#8211;26% worldwide. Identifying independent risk factors, aid planning of surgery, need for surgical staging and targeted therapy. We emphasise the importance of regular follow up to detect early symptoms of recurrence and increase overall survival. 58 Endometriosis and the complications of pregnancy: A systematic review and meta-analysis Bethany Parry1; Chloe Stone1; Amy Newnham-Hill1,2; Siobhan Quenby1,2; Joshua Odendaal1,2 1Warwick Medical School, Coventry, United Kingdom; 2University Hospitals Coventry and Warwickshire NHS Trust, Coventry, United Kingdom Introduction: Endometriosis is a prevalent gynaecological condition. It's pathophysiology, whilst unclear, is in part immune-mediated. It has previously been associated with infertility but its role in obstetric complications is less clear, despite it sharing pathophysiological pathways with several obstetric complications. This study aimed to further elucidate the relationship between endometriosis and key obstetric complications including miscarriage, pre-eclampsia, preterm birth, placenta previa, placenta abruption and small for gestational age (SGA) infants. Methods: A systematic review was conducted, where EMBASE, Medline and CINAHL were searched for all studies published before 9th October 2023, limited by the English language. 61 cohort and case-control studies met the inclusion criteria and were included in the review. A meta-analysis was performed where the data allowed, and risk of bias was assessed using the Newcastle Ottawa Scale. Results: Women with endometriosis had a higher risk of preterm birth (OR 2.02; 95% CI, 1.54&#8211;2.65), pre-eclampsia (OR 1.29; 95% CI, 1.20&#8211;2.40), placenta previa (OR 3.18; 95% CI, 2.66&#8211;3.81), placenta abruption (OR 2.44; 95% CI, 1.41&#8211;4.19), and SGA infants (OR 1.61; 95% CI, 1.16&#8211;2.25). No difference in the incidence of miscarriage (OR 1.95; 95% CI, 0.86&#8211;4.42) was found. Heterogeneity between studies was high for all outcomes except pre-eclampsia but a low risk of bias was seen. Conclusion: Endometriosis is associated with increased risk of key pregnancy complications. These women should therefore be streamed for high-risk care in pregnancy. Future work should focus on standardised methodology for associative cohort studies to reduce study heterogeneity. 59 A rare case of toxic megacolon, subtotal-colectomy and formation of end ileostomy with mucus fistula in a 15-year-old primiparous women post caesarean section Shayda Yazdani1; Fariha Rahim1; Frances Ibison2; Charlotte Cox1; Paul Barrow3; Alice Schofield4; Sara El Falaha1 1Department of Obstetrics, Sharoe Green Unit, Women's Division, Lancashire Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, Fulwood, Preston, United Kingdom; 2Department of Histopathology, Lancashire Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, Fulwood, Preston, United Kingdom; 3Department of Colorectal Surgery, Lancashire Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, Fulwood, Preston, United Kingdom; 4Department of Gynaecological Oncology, Sharoe Green Unit, Women's Division, Lancashire Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, Fulwood, Preston, United Kingdom Background: Clostridioides difficile infection (CDI) is a gram-positive, spore-forming, anaerobic bacillus, associated with severe diarrhoea and colonic inflammation. Toxic megacolon is a rare but reported presentation of pseudomembranous colitis. Pregnant women have a unique immune state, and often have more severe presentation of CDI. Case: We present a case of 15-year-old woman, G1P0, concealed pregnancy, late-booker (29-weeks). Confirmed Escherichia-coli urinary-tract-infection, treated with Trimethoprim (30-weeks). At induction (40-weeks), Maternal Early Warning Score totalled five (Bp 121/65 mmHg, heart-rate 118 bpm, temperature 38.4&#176;C, respiratory-rate 20/min, saturations 98%). Maternal sepsis was diagnosed, pathological Cardiotocography recorded, and category two caesarean section performed. Post-operatively, persistent elevated temperature, 38.4&#176;C, lower abdominal pain and loose stools were observed. Senior review suspected CDI, oral Vancomycin commenced. Day three post-operative Computerised-Tomography abdomen and pelvis demonstrated; pan-colonic mural thickening, dilation of the ascending colon. Differentials included pseudo-obstruction / infective colitis. Intravenous Tazocin, Cefuroxime, Rifampicin and Gentamicin were commenced. Urgent surgical review was conducted. Managed with an emergency laparotomy, subtotal-colectomy and formation of end ileostomy with mucus fistula. Unplanned admission to intensive care was required. In total 5.5 cm of terminal-ileum and 73 cm of colon were resected. Histopathology revealed acute inflammation of colon in keeping with pseudomembranous colitis. Conclusion: Antibiotics can disrupt normal gut bacteria, allowing growth of CDI. These effects may last from weeks to months. A low threshold for suspecting CDI peri-partum is crucial. Caesarean section remains a major abdominal surgery. Peri-operative complications can be life threatening with significant morbidity. Senior review, enhanced imaging and multidisciplinary involvement is key for optimal management. 61 Cardiovascular morbidity and mortality in women with PCOS: A cohort study of 75142 participants from the UK biobank Triada (Iriana) Doulgeraki1; Eleanor Barry1; Annie Wright2; Ho Frederick3; Carlos Celis-Morales4; Jill Pell3; Naveed Sattar4; Stamatina Iliodromiti1 1Women's Health Research Unit, Wolfson Institute of Population Health, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, United Kingdom; 2School of Public Health, Imperial College London, London, United Kingdom; 3School of Health and Wellbeing, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom; 4School of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Health, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom Introduction: Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) has been associated with cardiovascular risk factors, however, it remains unclear whether it is associated with greater risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD). Methods: We conducted a cohort study on 75,142 women of reproductive age without cardiovascular disease when recruited to UK Biobank, of whom 15,747 had PCOS. The primary outcome was fatal and non-fatal events for ischemic heart and cerebrovascular disease. We constructed Cox regression analysis adjusted for confounders to estimate the magnitude of association between PCOS and incident events (fatal or non-fatal) for ischemic heart and cerebrovascular disease. Results: Women were followed up for a mean of 11.1 years. The incidence rate of ischemic heart and cerebrovascular events was 1.92/1,000 person years in the PCOS population and 1.90/1,000 person years in women without PCOS. PCOS was associated with a higher risk of obesity (OR 1.88, 95% CI 1.80&#8211;1.96), hypertension (OR 1.38, 95% CI 1.1.33&#8211;1.44) and type 2 diabetes (OR 1.92, 95% CI 1.75&#8211;2.11). In the adjusted Cox regression model, PCOS was not associated with increased risk of incident events (fatal or non-fatal) for ischemic heart and cerebrovascular disease (HR 0.90, 95% CI 0.79&#8211;1.02). Conclusion: Although PCOS is strongly associated with cardiovascular risk factors such as obesity, high blood pressure and type 2 diabetes, this did not translate into higher risk of ischemic heart and cerebrovascular events. Further research is warranted to determine whether this is true across different subtypes of PCOS or in menopausal women with a history of PCOS. 83 Introduction of a multi-professional maternal medicine and human factors-based simulation Danielle Davies; Sarah Woods; Alex Rutherford; Alexandra Van Der Meer Great Western Hospital, Swindon, United Kingdom Introduction: Human factors are increasingly recognised as important in healthcare training. Simulation participants report improvements in clinical and human factors skills during emergencies. MBBRACE continues to find cardiac disease the largest cause of indirect maternal deaths (excluding COVID-19). With more complex maternity patients, education on cardiology complications and collaboration between unfamiliar teams is necessary to manage patients who may quickly deteriorate. Methods: We introduced multi-professional simulation-based training over 3 years at Great Western Hospital, Swindon. Initially aimed at improving training for medical registrars, this evolved to include obstetricians and anaesthetists in training, alongside experienced midwives. Simulation scenarios included palpitations (SVT), shortness of breath (peripartum cardiomyopathy), chest pain (aortic dissection) and headache/seizure (intracranial haemorrhage). Sessions were held within the simulation suite, with real-time monitors of observations and staff acting as patients to increase fidelity. Senior obstetricians and medical doctors ran the debrief to discuss key learning points. Results: This year we have already held 3 sessions (each with 4 scenarios), a total of 15 doctors participating. 100% of the participants scored sessions 5/5 overall. Qualitative feedback focused on how valuable it was to have all members of the MDT participating. In addition, participants felt the complexity of medical scenarios allowed truly realistic and challenging human factors situations to arise. The learning environment and debrief were highlighted as constructive. Participants felt more sessions and widening participation would be beneficial. Conclusion: Our MDT simulations received overwhelmingly positive feedback from staff within three specialities and helped O&amp;G doctors complete e-portfolio CiP5. 97 Superior hypogastric plexus block in laparoscopic and robotic hysterectomy: An audit of patient outcomes at Northumbria Healthcare NHS Foundation Trust Hannah Bhopal1; Amy Tuddenham1; Onyebuchi Udegbunam2; Ahmed Etman2 1Northern Deanery, Newcastle upon Tyne, United Kingdom; 2Northumbria Healthcare NHS Foundation Trust, Northumbria, United Kingdom Introduction: We looked at the impact of Superior Hypogastric Plexus (SHP) Block on post operative pain and discharge timing following Laparoscopic &amp; Robotic Hysterectomy. Methods: This was a retrospective audit of 149 patients undergoing laparoscopic or robotic hysterectomy. We compared outcomes of patients who received an SHP block with those who did not. We used electronic case notes to collect data for the following outcomes: post-operative analgesia, post</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, in high-income countries.</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1471-0528.17881</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
