<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 01:16:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Coinage metal effect on the reduction of carbon dioxide with monomeric metal&#8208;hydride complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400280</link>
      <description>Diego Sorbelli, Leonardo Belpassi, Paola Belanzoni, European journal of inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400382434

                The role of the coinage metal in monomeric hydride complexes for the reduction of carbon dioxide to formate has been computationally addressed in this work. The common reaction mechanism, i.e. a concerted M&#8208;H (M = Cu, Ag, Au) bond attack to the CO2 carbon atom with one oxygen atom coordinating to the metal center, has been analyzed, revealing a kinetically less favorable reactivity for the gold&#8208;hydride complex. A thorough computational investigation discloses that, while all complexes feature covalent electron&#8208;sharing M&#8208;H bonds, copper&#8208; and silver&#8208;hydride complexes display a relevant M(&#948;+)&#8208;H(&#948;&#8208;) bond polarization, which enables an enhanced basicity of the hydride and, thereby, a more kinetically favorable CO2 reduction process. This study provides useful guidelines for the design of monomeric metal hydride complexes as promising candidates for the CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Diego Sorbelli, Leonardo Belpassi, Paola Belanzoni</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; Raman reveals the critical role of Pd in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4 on Cu-based catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213850</link>
      <description>Zi&#8208;Yu Du, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhengxin Qian, Shikang Li, Qing&#8208;Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Alexander V. Rudnev, Yue&#8208;Jiao Zhang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 161(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400422736

                Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) for CH4 production presents a promising strategy to address carbon neutrality, and the incorporation of a second metal has been proven effective in enhancing catalyst performance. Nevertheless, there remains limited comprehension regarding the fundamental factors responsible for the improved performance. Herein, the critical role of Pd in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4 on Cu-based catalysts has been revealed at a molecular level using in situ surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS). A &#8220;borrowing&#8221; SERS strategy has been developed by depositing Cu&#8211;Pd overlayers on plasmonic Au nanoparticles to achieve the in situ monitoring of the dynamic change of the intermediate during CO2RR. Electrochemical tests demonstrate that Pd incorporation significantly enhances selectivity toward CH4 production, and the Faradaic efficiency (FE) of CH4 is more than two times higher than that for the catalysts without Pd. The key intermediates, including *CO2&#8722;, *CO, and *OH, have been directly identified under CO2RR conditions, and their evolution with the electrochemical environments has been determined. It is found that Pd incorporation promotes the activation of both CO2 and H2O molecules and accelerates the formation of abundant active *CO and hydrogen species, thus enhancing the CH4 selectivity. This work offers fundamental insights into the understanding of the molecular mechanism of CO2RR and opens up possibilities for designing more efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zi&#8208;Yu Du, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhengxin Qian, Shikang Li, Qing&#8208;Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Alexander V. Rudnev, Yue&#8208;Jiao Zhang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Well-defined asymmetric nitrogen/carbon-coordinated single metal sites for carbon dioxide conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.064</link>
      <description>Senhe Huang, Ziyu Fang, Chenbao Lu, Jichao Zhang, Jie Sun, Heng Ji, Jinhui Zhu, Jinhui Zhu, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400478062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Senhe Huang, Ziyu Fang, Chenbao Lu, Jichao Zhang, Jie Sun, Heng Ji, Jinhui Zhu, Jinhui Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover Picture: Light&#8208;Induced Dynamic Activation of Copper/Silicon Interface for Highly Selective Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412574</link>
      <description>Jiali Wang, Tsung-Chyan Lai, Han&#8208;Ting Lin, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Hsiao&#8208;Chien Chen, Chun&#8208;Sheng Tseng, Ching&#8208;Wei Tung, Chia&#8208;Ying Chien, Hao Ming Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400542014

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiali Wang, Tsung-Chyan Lai, Han&#8208;Ting Lin, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Hsiao&#8208;Chien Chen, Chun&#8208;Sheng Tseng, Ching&#8208;Wei Tung, Chia&#8208;Ying Chien, Hao Ming Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of Pynaphthyridine and Binaphthyridine Manganese(I) Tricarbonyl Complexes: Influence on Carbon Dioxide Reduction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.4c00008</link>
      <description>Kailyn Y. Cohen, Hovnan Simonyan, Mar&#237;a J. Ortiz, Bogdan Solomon, Luke Simkins, Raymond N. Dominey, Emma W. Goldman, Andrew B. Bocarsly, Organometallics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400544982

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kailyn Y. Cohen, Hovnan Simonyan, Mar&#237;a J. Ortiz, Bogdan Solomon, Luke Simkins, Raymond N. Dominey, Emma W. Goldman, Andrew B. Bocarsly</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.4c00008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can carbon emission trading policy enhance the synergistic emission reduction of carbon dioxide and air pollutants? A comparative study considering different pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132364</link>
      <description>Zhihao Chen, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400412621

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhihao Chen, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag-Precipitated CuO Nanospheres for Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145888</link>
      <description>Jingkun Xu, Ming Li, Liping Zhao, Guoqiang Zhong, Yu Zhang, Ziqi Zhang, Yu Sun, Xudong Hu, Zh&#233; Peng, Yicong Wang, Chunming Zheng, Xiaohong Sun, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400484824

                An electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an effective way to reduce greenhouse gases by converting CO2 into high-value-added chemical products using electricity generated from renewable energy. In this paper, a Cu2O spherical catalyst was prepared by ascorbic acid reduction. The precipitated Cu-Ag spherical catalyst (P-CuO-Ag) was successfully prepared by calcining Cu2O-Ag with the introduction of an Ag component as the substrate. During the electrochemical reduction of CO2, the FE of the P-CuO-Ag catalyst for C2H4 at a potential of &#8722;1.1 V vs. RHE was as high as 39.8%, which was nearly twice that of the CuO catalyst, while the local current density JC2H4 for C2H4 reached 6 mA cm&#8722;2. The incorporation of Ag gives the spherical CuO catalyst higher electrochemical activity and better kinetic performance than the catalyst without Ag.</description>
      <author>Jingkun Xu, Ming Li, Liping Zhao, Guoqiang Zhong, Yu Zhang, Ziqi Zhang, Yu Sun, Xudong Hu, Zh&#233; Peng, Yicong Wang, Chunming Zheng, Xiaohong Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of Co2 on Pure and Doped Cu2o(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4888703</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhichao Yu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400405522

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhichao Yu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4888703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction to Multicarbon Products on Non&#8208;Copper Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401173</link>
      <description>Jiayi Huang, Qianwen Liu, Jianmei Huang, Ming Xu, Wenchuan Lai, Zhi&#8208;Yuan Gu, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400509915

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) to value&#8208;added multicarbon (C2+) products offers a promising approach for achieving carbon neutrality and storing intermittent renewable energy. Copper (Cu)&#8208;based electrocatalysts generally play the predominant role in this process. Yet recently, more and more non&#8208;Cu materials have demonstrated the capability to convert CO2 into C2+, which provides impressive production efficiency even exceeding those on Cu, and a wider variety of C2+ compounds not achievable with Cu counterparts. This motivates us to organize the present review to make a timely and tutorial summary of recent progresses on developing non&#8208;Cu based catalysts for CO2&#8208;to&#8208;C2+. We begin by elucidating the reaction pathways for C2+ formation, with an emphasis on the unique C&#8208;C coupling mechanisms in non&#8208;Cu electrocatalysts. Subsequently, we summarize the typical C2+&#8208;involved non&#8208;Cu catalysts, including ds&#8208;, d&#8208; and p&#8208;block metals, as well as metal&#8208;free materials, presenting the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art design strategies to enhance C2+ efficiency. The system upgrading to promote C2+ productivity on non&#8208;Cu electrodes covering microbial electrosynthesis, electrolyte engineering, regulation of operational conditions, and synergistic co&#8208;electrolysis, is highlighted as well. Our review concludes with an exploration of the challenges and future opportunities in this rapidly evolving field.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Huang, Qianwen Liu, Jianmei Huang, Ming Xu, Wenchuan Lai, Zhi&#8208;Yuan Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on catalyst convergence: Unleashing the potential of MXenes for CO2 electrochemical reduction into high-value liquid product</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.06.006</link>
      <description>Samia, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Mohd Zul Hilmi Mayzan, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Nano materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400421350

                The electrochemical reduction reaction of carbon dioxide (CO2-ERR) holds tremendous potential as a key approach for achieving carbon neutrality by harnessing renewable resources. However, the current state of CO2-ERR encounters challenges in terms of efficiency and selectivity. Overcoming these obstacles requires the development of a robust electrocatalyst capable of enhancing process efficiency and improving selectivity towards desired products. In recent years, 2D materials have garnered significant attention as efficient catalysts. Among them, MXene stands out of high interest due to unique multilayered structure and presence of surface functional moieties. The MXene material offers high electrical conductivity, versatile surface chemistry, and tunable interface designs. This comprehensive review explores the utilization of MXene-based catalysts for CO2-ERR into valuable products. It covers fundamental aspects of electrochemical conversion, including CO2 adsorption on MXene Ti3C2Tx, the mechanism of CO2-ERR on MXene (Mo2CS2) single-atom catalysts, applications, synthesis methods of MXene production, and future prospects. Additionally, the review highlights the significance of modern artificial intelligence techniques, particularly machine learning, in screening and activating CO2, making it a pioneering scientific endeavor.</description>
      <author>Samia, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Mohd Zul Hilmi Mayzan, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.06.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomimetic Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Covalent Organic Frameworks with Tunable Pendant Groups for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411188</link>
      <description>Tao Xie, Shuai Chen, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Ning Huang, Yujie Xiong, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400415075

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an effective way of converting CO2 into value&#8208;added products using renewable energy, whose activity and selectivity can be in principle maneuvered by tuning the microenvironment near catalytic sites. Here, we demonstrate a strategy for tuning the microenvironment of CO2RR by learning from the natural chlorophyll and heme. Specifically, the conductive covalent organic frameworks (COFs) linked by piperazine serve as versatile supports for single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs), and the pendant groups modified on the COFs can be readily tailored to offer different push&#8208;pull electronic effects for tunable microenvironment. As a result, while all the COFs exhibit high chemical structure stability under harsh conditions and good conductivity, the addition of &#8208;CH2NH2 can greatly enhance the activity and selectivity of CO2RR. As proven by experimental characterization and theoretical simulation, the electron&#8208;donating group (&#8208;CH2NH2) not only reduces the surface work function of COF, but also improves the adsorption energy of the key intermediate *COOH, compared with the COFs with electron&#8208;withdrawing groups (&#8208;CN, &#8208;COOH) near the active sites. This work provides insights into the microenvironment modulation of CO2RR electrocatalysts at the molecular level.</description>
      <author>Tao Xie, Shuai Chen, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Ning Huang, Yujie Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomimetic Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Covalent Organic Frameworks with Tunable Pendant Groups for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411188</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Shuai Chen, Yunfei Yan, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Ning Huang, Yi Xiong, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400415878

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an effective way of converting CO2 into value&#8208;added products using renewable energy, whose activity and selectivity can be in principle maneuvered by tuning the microenvironment near catalytic sites. Here, we demonstrate a strategy for tuning the microenvironment of CO2RR by learning from the natural chlorophyll and heme. Specifically, the conductive covalent organic frameworks (COFs) linked by piperazine serve as versatile supports for single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs), and the pendant groups modified on the COFs can be readily tailored to offer different push&#8208;pull electronic effects for tunable microenvironment. As a result, while all the COFs exhibit high chemical structure stability under harsh conditions and good conductivity, the addition of &#8208;CH2NH2 can greatly enhance the activity and selectivity of CO2RR. As proven by experimental characterization and theoretical simulation, the electron&#8208;donating group (&#8208;CH2NH2) not only reduces the surface work function of COF, but also improves the adsorption energy of the key intermediate *COOH, compared with the COFs with electron&#8208;withdrawing groups (&#8208;CN, &#8208;COOH) near the active sites. This work provides insights into the microenvironment modulation of CO2RR electrocatalysts at the molecular level.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Shuai Chen, Yunfei Yan, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Ning Huang, Yi Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the electrochemical reduction of CO2 on Au25(SR)18&#8722; nanocluster</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141462</link>
      <description>Dominic Alfonso, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400400371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dominic Alfonso</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure-performance relationships in MOF-derived electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pecs.2024.101175</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yuman Guo, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yi Liu, J Baeyens, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Progress in energy and combustion science. 104(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400405756

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yuman Guo, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yi Liu, J Baeyens, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pecs.2024.101175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local microenvironment modulation of zirconium-porphyrinic frameworks for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153875</link>
      <description>Xue Zhao, Changyan Zhu, Heng Rao, Dong&#8208;Ying Du, Min Zhang, Ping She, Li Li, Jun&#8208;Sheng Qin, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400459415

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Zhao, Changyan Zhu, Heng Rao, Dong&#8208;Ying Du, Min Zhang, Ping She, Li Li, Jun&#8208;Sheng Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorinated chlorin chromophores for red-light-driven CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50084-8</link>
      <description>Shuang Yang, Zhiji Han, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Jueming Yi, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400426847

                Abstract The utilization of low-energy photons in light-driven reactions is an effective strategy for improving the efficiency of solar energy conversion. In nature, photosynthetic organisms use chlorophylls to harvest the red portion of sunlight, which ultimately drives the reduction of CO 2 . However, a molecular system that mimics such function is extremely rare in non-noble-metal catalysis. Here we report a series of synthetic fluorinated chlorins as biomimetic chromophores for CO 2 reduction, which catalytically produces CO under both 630 nm and 730 nm light irradiation, with turnover numbers of 1790 and 510, respectively. Under appropriate conditions, the system lasts over 240 h and stays active under 1% concentration of CO 2 . Mechanistic studies reveal that chlorin and chlorinphlorin are two key intermediates in red-light-driven CO 2 reduction, while corresponding porphyrin and bacteriochlorin are much less active forms of chromophores.</description>
      <author>Shuang Yang, Zhiji Han, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Jueming Yi, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50084-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Spatial Effects of Influencing Factors and Zoning Strategies for PM2.5 and CO2 Synergistic Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics12070498</link>
      <description>Zimu Jia, Shida Sun, Deming Zhao, Bo Yu, Yele Sun, Toxics. 12(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400444660

                China has identified the synergistic reduction of pollution and carbon emissions as a critical component of its environmental protection and climate mitigation efforts. An assessment of this synergy can provide clarity on the strategic management of both air pollution and carbon emissions. Due to the extensive regional differences in China, the spatial effects of influencing factors on this synergy exhibit variation across different provinces. In this study, the reduction indexes of PM2.5 and CO2 were calculated based on their reduction bases, reduction efforts, and reduction stabilities across provinces. Then, the synergistic reduction effect was assessed using an exponential function with the PM2.5 reduction index as the base and the CO2 reduction index as the exponent. Next, the MGWR model was applied in order to analyze the influencing factors of the synergistic reduction effect, considering natural settings, socioeconomic conditions, and external emission impacts. Finally, the k-means clustering method was utilized to classify provinces into different categories based on the degree of impact of each influencing factor. The results indicated that air circulation, vegetation, tertiary industry ratio, and emission reduction efficiency are major impact indicators that have a positive effect. The topography and emissions from neighboring provinces have a statistically significant negative impact. The spatial influences of different factors exhibit a distribution trend characterized by a high-high cluster and a low-low cluster. A total of 31 provinces are divided into three categories, and suggestions on the corresponding category are proposed, to provide a scientific reference to the synergistic reduction of PM2.5 and CO2.</description>
      <author>Zimu Jia, Shida Sun, Deming Zhao, Bo Yu, Yele Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics12070498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Design Innovation &#8211; A Case Study of 20% Weight Reduction and CO2 Emission Reduction in Door Panels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51202/9783181024355-213</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Paul Scholz, NULL AUTHOR_ID, VDI Verlag eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400430775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Paul Scholz, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51202/9783181024355-213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Based Materials for Low Concentration Co2 Capture and Electrocatalytic Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4891233</link>
      <description>Yanxi Hu, Yangyang Ding, Lily Y. Xie, Hanyu Li, Yujing Jiang, F. Gargano, Aidi Zhang, Wenlei Zhu, Yuanyuan Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400484792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanxi Hu, Yangyang Ding, Lily Y. Xie, Hanyu Li, Yujing Jiang, F. Gargano, Aidi Zhang, Wenlei Zhu, Yuanyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4891233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron distribution regulating of nonmetal doped monolayer g-GaN for enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160683</link>
      <description>Yafei Zhao, Liang He, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400398871

                Exploring inexpensive electrocatalysts that can efficiently and selectively convert CO2 into hydrocarbon fuels is important to promote carbon neutrality and solve the energy crisis. Current electrocatalysts, such as Cu-based alloys, single-atom catalysts, and dual-atom catalysts, use the d states of metal in the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction. Inspired by this, this work studies CO2 reduction reaction from another approach. Herein, using first principles study, we systematically investigate the prospect of nonmetal (B, C, O and F) doped monolayers g-GaN as electrocatalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction. We found that nonmetal doping can effectively regulate the electron distribution and p-band center of the active center (N site), which can adjust the initial adsorption, activation degree, charge transfer amount of CO2, and promote the formation of intermediates. Interestingly, B and C doped systems have better catalytic activity for CH4, with limiting potentials of &#8722;0.61 and &#8722;0.53 V, respectively. More importantly, F doped system has higher activity and selectivity for CH3OH production and inhibit competitive HER, with lower limiting potentials of &#8722;0.60 V. This study provides a new theoretical basis for the design and screening of electrocatalysts with high activity and product selectivity using nonmetal as the active site.</description>
      <author>Yafei Zhao, Liang He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of crystal defects on the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction performance of pure copper</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2024.116268</link>
      <description>Shuai Hao, Kaveh Edalati, Qingsheng Gao, Huaijun Lin, Scripta materialia. 252(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400496350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Hao, Kaveh Edalati, Qingsheng Gao, Huaijun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2024.116268</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction on Pd-Based Electrodes: From Mechanism Understanding to Rational Catalyst Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02379j</link>
      <description>Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Kun Jiang, Wen Cai, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400477996

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) driven by clean electricity to valuable chemicals provides a feasible way to carbon neutrality and thus attracts increasing attention. Among different transition-metal based CO2RR catalysts,...</description>
      <author>Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Kun Jiang, Wen Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02379j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highthroughput Screening of CuBi Bimetallic Catalyst Array for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction Reaction by Scanning Electrochemical Microscope</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400536</link>
      <description>X. Gu, Zhen Wang, Jie Li, Gang Ni, Limin Liu, Dongping Zhan, Juan Peng, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400558904

                The testing and evaluation of catalysts in CO2 electroreduction is a very tedious process. To study the catalytic system of CO2 reduction more quickly and efficiently, it is necessary to establish a method that can detect multiple catalysts at the same time. Herein, a series of CuBi bimetallic catalysts have been successfully prepared on a single glass carbon electrode by a scanning micropieptte contact method. The application of scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM) enabled the visualization of the CO2 reduction activity in diverse catalyst micro&#8208;points. The SECM imaging with Substrate generation/tip collection (SG/TC) mode was conducted on CuBi bimetallic micro&#8208;points, revealing that HER reaction emerged as the prevailing reaction when a low overpotential was employed. While the applied potential was lower than &#8208;1.5 V (vs Ag/AgCl), the reduction of CO2 to formic acid became dominant. Increasing the bismuth proportion in the bimetallic catalyst can inhibit the hydrogen evolution reaction at low potential and enhances the selectivity of the CO product at high cathode overpotential.This research offers a novel approach to examining arrays of catalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>X. Gu, Zhen Wang, Jie Li, Gang Ni, Limin Liu, Dongping Zhan, Juan Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of biochar-Cu-based catalysts construction and its electrochemical CO2 reduction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100250</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dongdong Feng, Yuxin Zhang, Zhaolin Wang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Shaozeng Sun, Carbon capture science &amp; technology. 13(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400411428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dongdong Feng, Yuxin Zhang, Zhaolin Wang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Shaozeng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-section design of the flow channels in membrane electrode assembly electrolyzer for CO2 reduction reaction through numerical simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110204</link>
      <description>Lili Zhang, Hui Gao, Gong Zhang, Yuning Dong, Kai Huang, Zifan Pang, Tuo Wang, Chunlei Pei, Peng Zhang, Jinlong Gong, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400388025

                Membrane electrode assembly (MEA) is widely considered to be the most promising type of electrolyzer for the practical application of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). In MEAs, a square-shaped cross-section in the flow channel is normally adopted, the configuration optimization of which could potentially enhance the performance of the electrolyzer. This paper describes the numerical simulation study on the impact of the flow-channel cross-section shapes in the MEA electrolyzer for CO2RR. The results show that wide flow channels with low heights are beneficial to the CO2RR by providing a uniform flow field of CO2, especially at high current densities. Moreover, the larger the electrolytic cell, the more significant the effect is. This study provides a theoretical basis for the design of high-performance MEA electrolyzers for CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Lili Zhang, Hui Gao, Gong Zhang, Yuning Dong, Kai Huang, Zifan Pang, Tuo Wang, Chunlei Pei, Peng Zhang, Jinlong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The solvation environment of molecularly dispersed cobalt phthalocyanine determines methanol selectivity during electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01190-9</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Changfeng Zeng, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Elad Gross, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400423217

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Changfeng Zeng, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Elad Gross, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01190-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au depositing and Mg doping synergistically regulates In2O3 photocatalyst for promoting CO2 reduction and CH4 exclusive generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01381f</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400427821

                The photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) into methane (CH4) is of great significance in the field of energy conversion. In this study, magnesium-gold (Mg-Au) bimetallic-modified indium oxide (In2O3) microspheres...</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01381f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ synthesis of SnO/CuSnO3 nanostructures to catalyze azo dye degradation, CO2 reduction, and amines direct alkylation reactions under visible light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102515</link>
      <description>Mohsen Padervand, Alireza Bargahi, Bagher Efteakhri-Sis, Mina Saadi, Shahnaz Ghasemi, Elmuez A. Dawi, Abdelkader Labidi, Ghodrat Mahmoudi, Masoumeh Servati Gargari, Results in engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400381086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Padervand, Alireza Bargahi, Bagher Efteakhri-Sis, Mina Saadi, Shahnaz Ghasemi, Elmuez A. Dawi, Abdelkader Labidi, Ghodrat Mahmoudi, Masoumeh Servati Gargari</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Analysis of Carbon Emissions from Highway Construction Based on Life Cycle Assessment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145897</link>
      <description>Shuohan Gao, Xuexin Liu, Chunying Lu, H Zhang, Xinjun Wang, Yaping Kong, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400522787

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions from the construction of road infrastructure have been of growing interest in recent years. This paper proposes a binary statistical method for highway construction based on project cost control and a construction management system. A quantitative analysis of the CO2 emissions from highway construction activities was also conducted to guide the formulation of a carbon reduction strategy. Taking an expressway in central China as a case study, the CO2 emissions from different construction activities were calculated. The results revealed that the CO2 emissions for the whole construction project reached 10,605.2 t&#183;km&#8722;1&#183;lane&#8722;1, with the raw material production and on-site construction phases accounting for 95.2% and 4.8%, respectively. The values for bridge and tunnel engineering were much higher than those for other engineering types. In the raw material production phase, steel and cement production contributed the most to emissions (more than 99%). During the on-site construction phase, diesel and electricity consumption contributed 90% to CO2 emissions, especially from earthwork, subgrade protection, bridge engineering, tunnel excavation, and pavement surfacing. Accordingly, efforts should be focused on the key points and directed toward using recycled and low-carbon materials and improving working efficiency, machinery performance, and construction technology.</description>
      <author>Shuohan Gao, Xuexin Liu, Chunying Lu, H Zhang, Xinjun Wang, Yaping Kong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforming CO2 into Synthetic Fuels: Modeling, Simulation, and Optimization Analysis of Methanol Production from Industrial Wastes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/eng5030070</link>
      <description>Vasiliki Kontou, Antonis Peppas, Sotiris Kottaridis, Chrysa Politi, Sotiri&#959;s Karellas, Eng. 5(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400443949

                Carbon capture and utilization (CCU) has emerged in recent years as a promising decarbonization solution for hard-to-abate industries. Compared to carbon capture and storage (CCS), CCU aims not for the storage of carbon dioxide (CO2) but for its use in the production of synthetic fuels, such as synthetic methanol (MeOH). Synthetic MeOH is produced through CO2 hydrogenation, utilizing green hydrogen (H2). Efficient use of CO2 and H2 feedstocks is essential to maximize the carbon reduction potential and energy efficiency of the process. This study performed an optimization analysis on a small-scale, containerized, and portable CO2 hydrogenation unit with a 5 kg MeOH/h production capacity goal, focusing on carbon conversion efficiency (CCE), MeOH yield, H2 consumption, and MeOH purity. The analysis was conducted using Aspen Plus V12. A single-pass model was used first to evaluate an initial reactor design. The reactor was then re-designed according to the results of the gas hourly space velocity (GHSV). The model was then expanded to include a recycling loop and the final reactor design was validated, aiming to maximize overall efficiency. The effects of the operational parameters including the reactor inlet temperature, reactor pressure, thermal fluid temperature, and condensation temperature were examined. The model was then further expanded to include the MeOH distillation process, and the effect of the distillation temperature was examined. The final product of the analysis was a fully-defined and optimized unit, achieving an 87.97% CCE and an 84.99% MeOH yield, consuming 1.11 kg H2/h for the production of 5.01 kg MeOH/h of 99.86 wt% purity. This study can provide valuable information and guidelines for designing small-scale, containerized, and portable CO2 hydrogenation units, which can serve as alternative solutions to address issues of H2 production and transportation related to large-scale installations.</description>
      <author>Vasiliki Kontou, Antonis Peppas, Sotiris Kottaridis, Chrysa Politi, Sotiri&#959;s Karellas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/eng5030070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seamless Reconstruction and Spatiotemporal Analysis of Satellite-based XCO2 Incorporating Temporal Characteristics: A Case Study in China during 2015-2020</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asr.2024.07.007</link>
      <description>Junchen He, Wei Wang, Nan Wang, Advances in space research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400392011

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) is a crucial greenhouse gas, and its concentration and spatiotemporal characteristics are among the principal sources of uncertainty in global warming assessments. Satellite remote sensing is a widely adopted, high-accuracy approach for monitoring atmospheric CO2. However, limited swath width and cloud cover significantly reduce satellite observation coverage. This study addresses the temporal changes in CO2 concentration and utilizes a machine learning-based fusion of multiple data sources to generate daily, full-coverage, 0.05&#176; spatial resolution column-averaged CO2 concentration data for China from 2015 to 2020. Ten-fold cross-validation yielded a determination coefficient R2 of 0.97, root mean square error of 0.92 ppm, and mean absolute error of 0.59 ppm. Compared to other datasets, this study's dataset exhibits superior accuracy and spatiotemporal detail. Using the produced CO2 concentration in this study, we conducted a spatiotemporal analysis of CO2 concentrations in China. The results indicate that, in general, the Western region exhibits a higher growth rate in CO2 concentration than the Eastern and Central regions, with areas of lower CO2 concentration experiencing higher growth rates while regions with higher CO2 concentration have lower growth rates. Moreover, the highest increase in CO2 concentration occurred in 2016, with a substantial decrease in CO2 concentration growth observed in 2018. Notably, the reduction in CO2 concentration in the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau region during the summer is considerably smaller than in other regions, possibly due to atmospheric transport from the Indian Peninsula.</description>
      <author>Junchen He, Wei Wang, Nan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asr.2024.07.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel interdisciplinary model for optimizing coalbed methane recovery and carbon dioxide sequestration: Fracture dynamics, gas mechanics, and its application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213984</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Feng Gao, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Danqi Li, Physics of fluids. 36(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400422279

                The Carbon Dioxide Enhanced Coalbed Methane (CO2-ECBM) technique significantly enhances clean energy extraction and mitigates climate change. Central to this process is the dynamic evolution of rough fracture networks within coal seams, influencing the migration of CO2 and natural gas. However, existing research lacks a comprehensive, quantitative approach to examining the micro-evolution of these fractures, including fracture roughness, fracture density, fracture touristy, and fracture size, particularly under thermo-hydro-mechanical effects. Addressing this gap, our study introduces an innovative, fractal model for quantitative analysis. This model intricately characterizes fracture networks in terms of number, tortuosity, length, and roughness, integrating them with fluid dynamics affected by external disturbances in CO2-ECBM projects. Upon rigorous validation, the finite element method analysis reveals significant impacts of micro-parameters on permeability and natural gas extraction. For instance, increasing CO2 injection pressure from 4 to 6 MPa changes fracture network density by up to 6.4%. A decrease in fracture density (Df) from 1.6 to 1.5 raises residual gas pressure by 2.7% and coal seam stress by 9.5%, indicating crucial considerations for project stability. Applying the proposed interdisciplinary model to assess CO2 emissions in Australia, it is can be obtained that when Df decreases from 1.6 to 1.5, the total amount of CO2 storage reduces by 17.71%&#8211;18.04%. Our results demonstrate the substantial influence of micro-fracture behaviors on CO2-ECBM projects, offering a ground-breaking solution for efficient greenhouse gas reduction and clean energy extraction, with practical implications for the energy sector's sustainability.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Feng Gao, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Danqi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUEL CONSUMPTION OF BELAZ DUMPERS AND CARBON DIOXIDE EMISSIONS USING THE EXAMPLE OF OPEN PIT 'TURIJA' OF THE BROWN COAL MINE BANOVI&#262;I</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51558/2303-5161.2024.12.12.77</link>
      <description>Jasmin Jamakovi&#263;, Sun&#269;ica Ma&#353;i&#263;, Glasnik Rudarsko-geolos&#780;ko-gra&#273;evinskog fakulteta/Glasnik rudarsko-geolos&#780;ko-gra&#273;evinskog fakulteta. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400460640

                This work sets out the methodology and presents the calculation results of the amount of carbon dioxide emitted into the atmosphere of the BelAz dump truck at the Open Pit "Turija" BCM Banovi&#263;i d.d., based on the fuel consumption monitoring data. Properly determined fuel consumption enables the calculation of the amount of carbon dioxide emitted and preventive measures, as well as the choice of its reduction strategy. Data collection took six months, then the data were analyzed, and thus the results were given for all dump trucks by months. Key words: fuel, open pit mining, BelAz dump truck, maintenance, Coal Mine Banovi&#263;i, carbon dioxide</description>
      <author>Jasmin Jamakovi&#263;, Sun&#269;ica Ma&#353;i&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51558/2303-5161.2024.12.12.77</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anionic Surfactant&#8211;Tailored Interfacial Microenvironment for Boosting Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07258</link>
      <description>Xin Yuan, Wangxin Ge, Yihua Zhu, Lei Dong, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400484381

                Both the catalyst and electrolyte deeply impact the performance of the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO</description>
      <author>Xin Yuan, Wangxin Ge, Yihua Zhu, Lei Dong, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnesium hydroxide addition reduces aqueous carbon dioxide in wastewater discharged to the ocean</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01506-4</link>
      <description>Vassilis Kitidis, Stephen A. Rackley, William J. Burt, Greg H. Rau, Sarah Fawcett, Miles Taylor, Glen A. Tarran, E. Malcolm S. Woodward, Carolyn Harris, T.W. Fileman, Communications earth &amp; environment. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400399728

                Abstract Ocean alkalinity enhancement (OAE) reduces the concentration of dissolved carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) in seawater, leading to atmospheric carbon dioxide removal (CDR). Here we report laboratory experiments and a field-trial of alkalinity enhancement through addition of magnesium hydroxide to wastewater and its subsequent discharge to the coastal ocean. In wastewater, a 10% increase of average alkalinity (+0.56 mmol/kg) led to a 74% reduction in aqueous CO 2 (&#8722;0.41 mmol/kg) and pH increase of 0.4 units to 7.78 (efficiency 0.73 molCO 2 /mol alkalinity). The alkalinization signal was limited to within a few metres of the ocean discharge, evident as 27.2 &#956;atm reduction in CO 2 partial pressure and 0.017 unit pH increase, and was consistent with rapid dilution of the alkali-treated wastewater. While this proof of concept field trial did not achieve CDR due to its small scale, it demonstrated the potential of magnesium hydroxide addition to wastewater as a CDR solution.</description>
      <author>Vassilis Kitidis, Stephen A. Rackley, William J. Burt, Greg H. Rau, Sarah Fawcett, Miles Taylor, Glen A. Tarran, E. Malcolm S. Woodward, Carolyn Harris, T.W. Fileman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01506-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Green Finance on Agricultural Pollution and Carbon Reduction: The Case of China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145832</link>
      <description>Li Cao, Jiaqi Gao, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400456873

                Based on the double-carbon target, the agricultural sector has implemented the concept of being green and synergistically promoted pollution and carbon reduction. Positioned as a novel financial paradigm, green finance places greater emphasis on environmental stewardship compared to its traditional counterparts. This focus enhances resource allocation efficiency, thereby achieving the goal of reducing pollution and carbon emissions. To research the influence of green finance on agricultural pollution and carbon reduction, this study leverages panel data spanning 2011 to 2021 from 31 provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities across China. It employs the fixed-effect model and mediating-effect model. The findings reveal that: (1) Green finance exerts a notable influence on reducing both pollution and carbon emissions in agriculture, with the latter showing a more pronounced effect. (2) Regional disparities exist in green finance, affecting agricultural pollution and carbon reduction. (3) By fostering technological innovation and optimizing industrial frameworks, green finance emerges as a catalyst for curbing surface pollution and carbon dioxide emissions in agriculture. On this basis, relevant suggestions are put forward to provide policy insights for improving the green financial system, which will help further promote carbon and pollution reduction.</description>
      <author>Li Cao, Jiaqi Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Emission Accounting and Reduction for Buildings Based on a Life Cycle Assessment: A Case Study in China&#8217;s Hot-Summer and Warm-Winter Region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145842</link>
      <description>Wanying Wang, Luyan Li, Victor Shi, Shervin Espahbod, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400448560

                At the 75th United Nations General Assembly, China committed to peaking carbon dioxide emissions by 2030 and achieving carbon neutrality by 2060. In response, the national standard &#8220;General Specification for Building Energy Conservation and Utilization of Renewable Energy&#8221; has been adopted across 20 provinces and cities in seven major regions, including North China, Northeast China, and South China. These regions have implemented stringent energy-saving and emission reduction reviews and quota requirements. Despite this, there is limited research on comprehensive life cycle carbon emission calculations and carbon reduction designs. This study addresses this gap by focusing on economically developed regions with high population density and substantial energy-saving potential, specifically targeting the warm winter and hot summer regions of China. Using a commercial building in Shenzhen as a case study, we established a carbon emission accounting model based on the life cycle assessment (LCA) method. We calculated carbon emissions during the material phase using the project&#8217;s bill of quantities and relevant carbon emission factors. Additionally, we used the CEEB 2023 software to design energy-saving and emission reduction solutions for the building. Our comparative analysis reveals that the new design reduces the carbon emissions of the case study building by 13.5%. This reduction not only mitigates the environmental impact of construction but also contributes to the fight against the greenhouse effect, supporting the broader goal of sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Wanying Wang, Luyan Li, Victor Shi, Shervin Espahbod</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16145842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigation of satellite OCO-2 CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; biases in the vicinity of clouds with 3D calculations using the Education and Research 3D Radiative Transfer Toolbox (EaR3T)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1936</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Hong Chen, Steven T. Massie, S. S. Kulawik, NULL AUTHOR_ID, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400420320

                Abstract. Accurate and continuous measurements of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) are essential for climate change research and monitoring of emission reduction efforts. NASA's Orbiting Carbon Observatory (OCO-2/3) satellites have been deployed to measure the column-averaged CO2 dry air mixing ratio (XCO2) with very high precision. Although cloudy measurements are screened out, nearby clouds can still cause retrieval biases because the forward one-dimensional (1D) radiative transfer (RT) model used in the OCO retrieval algorithm does not account for the scattering induced by clouds in the vicinity of the OCO-2/3 footprints. These biases, referred to as the three-dimensional (3D) effects, can be quantified effectively using 3D-RT calculations, but these are computationally expensive, especially for hyperspectral applications (e.g., OCO-2/3). To reduce the prohibitive computational demands of 3D-RT radiance simulations across all three OCO spectral bands, this paper employs a linear approximation with two metrics (called slope and intercept) for each of the OCO bands that represent the 3D-RT perturbations on the OCO-2 spectra and accelerate the radiative transfer by a factor of 100. This is implemented by the Education and Research 3D Radiation Transfer Toolbox for OCO (EaR3T-OCO). EaR3T-OCO estimates OCO-2 satellite radiances using all available footprint-level data and imagery from the Aqua satellite, which orbits in close proximity to the OCO-2 satellite. EaR3T-OCO can calculate 3D-RT spectral perturbations for any OCO-2 footprint. These calculations can be used to spectrally adjust the OCO-2 radiance measurements with scene-dependent EaR3T-OCO perturbation calculations prior to the actual retrieval to undo cloud vicinity effects in the radiance spectra, which can subsequently be processed with the standard OCO-2 retrieval code. We find that this adjustment largely mitigates XCO2 retrieval biases in proximity to clouds over land &#8211; the first physics-based correction of 3D-RT effects on OCO-2/3 retrievals. Although the accelerated 3D-RT radiance adjustment step is faster than full 3D-RT calculations for all OCO spectral bands, it still requires at least as much computational effort as the XCO2 retrieval itself. To bypass 3D-RT altogether, the slope and intercept metrics are parameterized as a function of the weighted cloud distance of a footprint and several other scene parameters, all of which can be derived directly from Aqua-MODIS imagery. While this method is fastest and thus feasible for operational use, it requires careful validation for various surface and atmospheric conditions. For the case we analyzed, both the 3D-RT calculation method and the parametric bypass method successfully corrected XCO2 biases, which exceeded 2 ppm at the footprint level, and reached up to 0.7 ppm in the regional average. We find that the biases depend most strongly on the cloud field morphology and surface reflectance, but also on secondary factors such as aerosol layers and sun-sensor geometry.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Hong Chen, Steven T. Massie, S. S. Kulawik, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plant diversity decreases greenhouse gas emissions by increasing soil and plant carbon storage in terrestrial ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/ele.14469</link>
      <description>Pengfei Dang, Miaomiao Zhang, Han Y. H. Chen, Michel Loreau, J. Emmett Duffy, Xine Li, Shuyue Wen, Xiaoqing Han, Lin Liao, Tiantian Huang, Chenxi Wan, Xiaoliang Qin, Kadambot H. M. Siddique, Bernhard Schmid, Ecology letters. 27(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400526337

                Abstract The decline in global plant diversity has raised concerns about its implications for carbon fixation and global greenhouse gas emissions (GGE), including carbon dioxide (CO 2 ), nitrous oxide (N 2 O) and methane (CH 4 ). Therefore, we conducted a comprehensive meta&#8208;analysis of 2103 paired observations, examining GGE, soil organic carbon (SOC) and plant carbon in plant mixtures and monocultures. Our findings indicate that plant mixtures decrease soil N 2 O emissions by 21.4% compared to monocultures. No significant differences occurred between mixtures and monocultures for soil CO 2 emissions, CH 4 emissions or CH 4 uptake. Plant mixtures exhibit higher SOC and plant carbon storage than monocultures. After 10 years of vegetation development, a 40% reduction in species richness decreases SOC content and plant carbon storage by 12.3% and 58.7% respectively. These findings offer insights into the intricate connections between plant diversity, soil and plant carbon storage and GGE&#8212;a critical but previously unexamined aspect of biodiversity&#8211;ecosystem functioning.</description>
      <author>Pengfei Dang, Miaomiao Zhang, Han Y. H. Chen, Michel Loreau, J. Emmett Duffy, Xine Li, Shuyue Wen, Xiaoqing Han, Lin Liao, Tiantian Huang, Chenxi Wan, Xiaoliang Qin, Kadambot H. M. Siddique, Bernhard Schmid</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/ele.14469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances on Photocatalytic CO2 reduction using CeO2-based Photocatalysts: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113487</link>
      <description>Khondaker Afrina Hoque, Sharmin Ara Sathi, Farjana Akter, Tania Akter, Tahsin Ahmed, Wahid Ullah, Kazi Arafin, Mohammad Sayadur Rahaman, Hossain M. Shahadat, Abu Bin Imran, Al&#8208;Nakib Chowdhury, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400390549

                Efforts to combat global warming and energy-related issues involve the solar-driven reduction of CO2 into worthy fuels and substances. However, the stable nature of CO2 demands high energy input for transformation. CO2 reduction using semiconductor materials activated by sunlight is gaining attention for its eco-friendly and economically viable nature. Despite progress, many solar-active catalysts for CO2 photoreduction encounter challenges like low efficiency and uncontrollable selectivity. The commonly used rare earth oxide ceria (CeO2) has low sunlight absorption, necessitating changes such as metal-nonmetal doping oxygen vacancy creation, the addition of co-catalysts, and the development of binary, ternary, Z-scheme, and S-scheme heterostructures to improve its use in visible light. Although there has been considerable research on CeO2 modifications, there is a lack of comprehensive study regarding their characteristics and the precise photochemical reduction mechanisms. This review aims to bridge this gap by thoroughly examining recent breakthroughs in CeO2-based photo reductants for CO2 reduction. It focuses on the synthetic techniques of photocatalysts and CO2 reduction processes, assesses photoactivity enhancement strategies, investigates underlying mechanisms, and addresses the factors influencing CO2 reduction, efficiencies and selectivity. Finally, the review concludes by offering insights into future challenges and prospects, guiding upcoming research toward sustainable and efficient CO2 reduction strategies.</description>
      <author>Khondaker Afrina Hoque, Sharmin Ara Sathi, Farjana Akter, Tania Akter, Tahsin Ahmed, Wahid Ullah, Kazi Arafin, Mohammad Sayadur Rahaman, Hossain M. Shahadat, Abu Bin Imran, Al&#8208;Nakib Chowdhury</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in the microscopic and mesoscopic simulation technologies developed for subsurface gas storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2024.10.01</link>
      <description>Tao Zhang, Jie Liu, Xuguang Yang, Shuyu Sun, Advances in Geo-energy research/Advances in geo-energy research. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400387333

                Subsurface gas storage refers to the practice of storing natural gas or other gases in underground reservoirs. It plays a crucial role in ensuring a stable and reliable supply of energy, especially during periods of high demand or supply disruptions. This work collectively highlights the significance of the microscopic and mesoscopic reservoir simulation techniques developed for subsurface gas storage. Specific technology progresses are demonstrated for a better storage of hydrogen and carbon dioxide, which meets well with the current focus on carbon reduction. In particular, molecular dynamics simulations can provide insight for the microscopic mechanisms affecting the adsorption and leakage of stored gas. Pore-network model generated using the advanced algorithm can determine the geological scenario for further flow and transport simulations. Document Type: Perspective Cited as: Zhang, T., Liu, J., Yang, X., Sun, S. Advances in the microscopic and mesoscopic simulation technologies developed for subsurface gas storage. Advances in Geo-Energy Research, 2024, 14(1): 1-3. https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2024.10.01</description>
      <author>Tao Zhang, Jie Liu, Xuguang Yang, Shuyu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2024.10.01</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data collection framework for enhanced carbon intensity indicator (&lt;scp&gt;CII&lt;/scp&gt;) in the oil tankers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjce.25384</link>
      <description>Abdullah Sh. Sardar, Mohan Anantharaman, T. M. Rabiul Islam, Vikram Garaniya, Canadian journal of chemical engineering/&#152;The &#156;Canadian journal of chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400508698

                Abstract The International Maritime Organization (IMO) aims to reduce greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions by 40% by 2030 compared with 2008. The carbon intensity indicator (CII) calculates the annual reduction factor required to continuously improve a ship's operational carbon intensity at a specific rating level. Verification and documentation of the achieved annual operational CII against the prescribed target are necessary to establish the operational carbon intensity rating. This study focuses on the intricate process of data collection for CII within the oil shipping industry, targeting engineering departments and shipboard management teams. Against the backdrop of the industry's substantial carbon dioxide emissions, the IMO has mandated the calculation of CII values for ships exceeding 5000 gross tons to promote sustainability and reduce environmental impact. We have collected emission data of 20 oil tankers over a period of 2 years using our ship maintenance and operating system (SMOS) and analyzed the data to compare the CII ratings. Our results indicate that a staggering ~63% of the vessels had the lowest CII rating of category E. It is therefore crucial to properly collect, organize, and evaluate data for CII calculation and take necessary measures to improve rating. This paper provides a deeper insight into the evolving CII calculation methodology, emphasizing the incorporation of correction factors and exclusions, and delineates the essential data collection practices needed to facilitate accurate CII calculations.</description>
      <author>Abdullah Sh. Sardar, Mohan Anantharaman, T. M. Rabiul Islam, Vikram Garaniya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjce.25384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cellular heterogeneity in hypertrophic burn scars in response to carbon dioxide laser therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.05.600800</link>
      <description>Chen Yy, C. R. Mahon, Jason D. Turner, Colum J Smith, Abdulrazak Abdulsalam, Ezekwe Amirize, Amy Preszler Prince, Adrian Heagerty, Claudia Roberts, Adam P. Croft, Yvonne Wilson, Naiem Moiemen, Janet M. Lord, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400386532

                Fractional carbon dioxide (AFCO2) laser therapy is used for treating pathological scarring, but the clinical outcomes are variable and the mechanisms of scar reduction poorly understood. We investigated the mechanisms underpinning efficacy of AFCO2 laser therapy, performing single-cell RNA sequencing in skin biopsies from patients with hypertrophic scars after AFCO2 laser therapy. Patients with younger scars (Good Responder, GR, &lt;6 years from healing) had better scar reduction than patients with older scars (Poor Responder, PR, &gt;6 years from healing) by various measures of scarring. scRNAseq analysis revealed that genes enriched in GR were associated with extracellular matrix and structure organisation (COL14A1, POSTN, SPARC); whereas genes enriched in PR were related to enhanced immune responses (IL-12, MSTN, HLA-DQA). The groups had distinct intercellular communication networks and differentiation trajectories after AFCO2, with regenerative Mesenchymal fibroblasts associated with a good response and inflammatory Secretory Papillary and Inflammatory Fibroblasts with a poor response.</description>
      <author>Chen Yy, C. R. Mahon, Jason D. Turner, Colum J Smith, Abdulrazak Abdulsalam, Ezekwe Amirize, Amy Preszler Prince, Adrian Heagerty, Claudia Roberts, Adam P. Croft, Yvonne Wilson, Naiem Moiemen, Janet M. Lord</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.05.600800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A parametric study on syngas production by adding CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; on steam gasification of biomass system using ASPEN Plus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/cppm-2023-0100</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Chemical product and process modeling. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400417545

                Abstract Biomass gasification technology is increasingly employed as an environmentally friendly energy source, primarily due to its minimal impact on the environment and its ability to mitigate pollution. This technology excels in producing gas with exceptionally high hydrogen content, making it a valuable source for both fuel and energy carriers. Hydrogen (H 2 ), renowned for its stability and lack of detrimental environmental effects, holds great significance in various applications related to energy utilization and sustainability. In the current work, wood sawdust was utilized as the biomass feedstock for syngas production. The research focused on examining the impact of introducing carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) and methane (CH 4 ) gases into the Gibbs reactors. The steam gasification process was modeled by the ASPEN Plus software, allowing for comprehensive analysis and simulation of the gasification reactions. According to the obtained results, the modeling performed in this study demonstrates good predictive capability when compared to the experimental data. It was shown that when the ratio of CO 2 to biomass (C/B) increases, the MFR (mass flow rates) of H 2 as well as CH 4 decrease, whereas the flow rates of CO 2 and carbon monoxide (CO) increase. These findings indicate the influence of the C/B ratio on the distribution of different gases within the gasification process. The reduction in MFR of hydrogen when transitioning from C/B = 0 to C/B = 1 in modes a and b is quantified as 17.51 % and 16.39 %, respectively. These percentages represent the magnitude of the decrease in hydrogen MFR for each specific mode when comparing two carbon dioxide to biomass ratios. When the CH 4 to biomass (M/B) ratio increases, the mass flow rates of H 2 exhibit a consistent upward trend, while the MFR of CO 2 displays a descending form. Specifically, when in the Gibbs reactor, M/B rises from 0 to 1 for modes a and b, the mass flow rates of H 2 experience significant increases of 265 % and 243 %, respectively. These findings underscore the direct relationship between the M/B ratio and hydrogen production, highlighting the potential for enhanced hydrogen yields with higher M/B ratios in the studied modes.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/cppm-2023-0100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical investigation of combustion characteristics of extended coherent flame model 3 zones (ECFM&#8208;3Z) in diesel engines running with biodiesel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.14422</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Hakan Kaleli&#775;, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Environmental progress &amp; sustainable energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400421585

                Abstract This research investigates the application of Extended Coherent Flame Model&#8208;3 Zones (ECFM&#8208;3Z) to assess the performance and emissions of rapeseed oil methyl ester (ROME). Experimental tests were carried out using a Lombardini 3 LD 350 model single&#8208;cylinder diesel engine, at 1600&#8211;3000 rpm with 200 rpm speed increments, under full load conditions. For numerical analysis, STAR&#8208;CD/ESICE software was employed. Methyl Oleate (C 19 H 36 O 2 ) was predicted as the surrogate biodiesel based on Gas Chromatography (GC) analysis and average mass calculation. Notably, the numerical analysis revealed a remarkable similarity in brake power between the experimental and computational investigations. In the range of 2400&#8211;3000 rpm, the biodiesel's performance exhibited a maximum deviation of 5%, primarily attributed to pumping, thermal, and friction losses. In terms of emissions, carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) emissions were consistent with the findings of the experimental study, with a maximum disparity of 10%. However, carbon monoxide (CO) emissions ranged from 57% to 65% lower than those observed in the experimental study, while nitrogen oxide (NO x ) emissions exhibited a reduction of 63% to 84%. In contrast, oxygen (O 2 ) emissions were notably higher, ranging from 93% to 117% compared to the experimental study, and exhaust temperatures were elevated by 33% to 49% in comparison to the experimental results.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Hakan Kaleli&#775;, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.14422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financing Strategy Of Refuse Derived Fuel (Rdf) Plant Based On Investment Project Analysis (Case Study Cilacap RDF Plant)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31539/costing.v7i4.10879</link>
      <description>Reni Romaulina, Taufik Faturohman, Costing. 7(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400390118

                Refused Derived Fuel (RDF) is a waste processing method that can be used as co-firing in the cement industry. Currently, the Cilacap RDF Plant is one of the RDFs successfully operating in Indonesia, with a machine capacity of up to 200 tons/day. This success has encouraged many local governments to build RDF facilities to handle waste. The research aims to propose alternative funding scenarios for the development of RDF so that it can be applied in other places. Not all regions have the same opportunities as RDF Cilacap, where investment financing includes the construction of RDF facilities and machinery covered by many stakeholders. This study also calculates the potential for reducing CO2 emissions with the RDF plant and estimates the potential carbon trading value from the reduction in CO2 emissions. The analysis method in alternative scenario studies uses investment project analysis such as Discounted Cash Flow (DCF), NPV, IRR, Profitability Index, Payback Period, Discounted Payback Period, and IPCC 2006 to calculate CO2 emission reductions. The potential for reducing CO2 emissions in this study is calculated by comparing the value of CO2 produced if waste is disposed of in a landfill (open dumping) and the waste is processed into RDF. The research results show that the third scenario is suitable and feasible for regions planning to build an RDF Factory. It is recommended that the Central Government bear the responsibility for the RDF Factory building infrastructure and the investors or third parties take responsibility for the machinery. The potential for reducing CO2 emissions with the existence of the RDF Plant Cilacap for 20 years is 231,944.86 tons. If multiplied by the average price in the secondary market, IDR 69,600 (USD 4.45), the potential for obtaining funds is IDR 16,143 million, or equivalently, we calculate it in present value to IDR 5,284 million.</description>
      <author>Reni Romaulina, Taufik Faturohman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31539/costing.v7i4.10879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core Flooding Experiments on the Impact of CO2-EOR on the Petrophysical Properties and Oil Recovery Parameters of Reservoir Sandstones in Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences14070185</link>
      <description>Ainash Shabdirova, Ashirgul Kozhagulova, Yernazar Samenov, Rinat Merbayev, Ainur Niyazbayeva, Daryn Shabdirov, Geosciences. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400531088

                This study investigates the impact of CO2-enhanced oil recovery (CO2-EOR) on the petrophysical properties and oil recovery potential of sandstone reservoirs in the oilfields located in the east-southern Precaspian region of Kazakhstan. Despite the recognized potential of CO2-EOR for improving oil recovery and aiding carbon sequestration, there is limited understanding of how CO2-EOR specifically affects the petrophysical properties of sandstone reservoirs in this region. Laboratory experiments were conducted using two core samples from the selected oilfields to examine changes in porosity, permeability, and oil recovery coefficients. The results demonstrated that porosity changes ranged from a slight increase of 1.1% to a decrease of 1.5%, while permeability reduction was significant, with decreases ranging from 29% to 50% due to clay alteration and halite precipitation. The oil recovery coefficient after CO2 flooding was found to be between 0.49 and 0.54. These findings underscore the complex interactions between CO2 and reservoir rocks, emphasizing the need for tailored EOR strategies in different geological settings.</description>
      <author>Ainash Shabdirova, Ashirgul Kozhagulova, Yernazar Samenov, Rinat Merbayev, Ainur Niyazbayeva, Daryn Shabdirov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences14070185</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication and Characterization of PLA/PBAT Blends, Blend-Based Nanocomposites, and Their Supercritical Carbon Dioxide-Induced Foams</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16141971</link>
      <description>Kartik Behera, Chung-Hsien Tsai, Xia Liao, Fang-Chyou Chiu, Polymers. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400486574

                In this study, a twin-screw extruder was used to fabricate poly(lactic acid) (PLA)/poly(butylene adipate-co-terephthalate) (PBAT) blends and blend-based nanocomposites with carbon nanotube (CNT) or nanocarbon black (CB) as nanofillers. The fabricated samples were subsequently treated with supercritical carbon dioxide (scCO2) to fabricate the corresponding foams. Bi-phasic morphology and selective distribution of CNTs or CBs in the PBAT phase were observed in the blends/composites through scanning electron microscopy. After the scCO2 treatment, the selective foaming of the PBAT phase in the prepared blends/composites was confirmed. The cellular structure of PBAT phase in scCO2-treated blends is similar to the size/shape of PBAT domains in untreated blends or treated neat PBAT foam. The addition of CNTs or CBs in the blends led to a slight reduction in cell size of the foamed PBAT phase, demonstrating CNT/CB-induced cell nucleation. Differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) results showed that CNTs and CBs played as nucleating agents and increased the initial crystallization temperature up to 14 &#176;C compared with neat PBAT for PBAT in different composites during cooling. The scCO2 treatment induced the bimodal stability of PBAT crystals in different samples, which melted mainly in two temperature regions in DSC studies. Thermogravimetric analyses revealed that compared with parent blends, the addition of CNTs or CBs increased the temperature at 80 wt.% loss (degradation of PBAT portion) up to 6 &#176;C. The electrical resistivity decreased by more than six orders of magnitude for certain CNT- or CB-added composites compared with the parent blends. The hardness of the blends slightly increased after forming the corresponding composites and then declined after the scCO2 treatment.</description>
      <author>Kartik Behera, Chung-Hsien Tsai, Xia Liao, Fang-Chyou Chiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16141971</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 fixation in molten salts: A pathway towards the fabrication of exceptional carbon-based materials for pollutant removal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.07.004</link>
      <description>Zeyu Fan, Zhuo Fan Gao, Xian Zhou, Ziling Peng, Shanshan Deng, Qi Lu, Yuanyi Wang, Wei Yang, Xia Chen, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400386901

                Carbon-based materials have been widely applied for pollutant removal relying on their rich pore structure, functional groups, chemical stability, and expandability. However, the traditional manufacturing process of carbon materials based on organic compounds pyrolysis is high energy-consuming and high-emission, which is not conducive to addressing the climate crisis and achieving the goal of carbon neutrality. Molten salt electrolysis technology enables the direct capture and reduction of CO2 to produce solid carbon, resulting in significant environmental benefits while achieving carbon emissions reduction. The molten salt also has a purification function, enabling the production of high-purity carbon materials. The kinetics of the electrochemical reduction process can be easily controlled, and the co-reduction of multiple elements provides convenience for the in-situ optimization of carbon material structure and the expansion of its applications. Therefore, this review focuses on the thermodynamics &amp; kinetics processes of molten salt capture and electrochemical reduction of CO2 to prepare carbon materials. It further reviews the recent research progress on the preparation of carbon materials for pollutant removal based on molten salt electrochemical processes for the first time. Finally, we analyze the advantages and challenges of the current molten salt electrochemical processes and offers prospects for future research directions.</description>
      <author>Zeyu Fan, Zhuo Fan Gao, Xian Zhou, Ziling Peng, Shanshan Deng, Qi Lu, Yuanyi Wang, Wei Yang, Xia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.07.004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ammonia and Greenhouse Gas Emissions from Organic Manure Composting: The Effect of Membrane Cover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071471</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Muhammad Wajahat Ramay, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Csaba Gyuricza, NULL AUTHOR_ID, L&#225;szl&#243; Aleksza, Agronomy. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400424679

                The current scientific literature predominantly focuses on pilot-scale studies concerning the effectiveness of membrane covers in reducing gas emissions during cattle manure composting. Our study centers on the application of a leading market commercial membrane cover (ePTE-TEXcomm) and a locally manufactured one (ProfiCover&#174;) at industrial processing levels, evaluating their efficacy in mitigating gas emission during the fifth day of the thermophilic phase. Taking into account material inhomogeneities, work environment impact, and efficiency, the results are characteristic of industrial-scale processes rarely discussed in the scientific literature. Our results, obtained with a portable gas sampler and FTIR spectroscopy measurements using corresponding standards, indicate that ePTE-TEXcomm manifested a reduction of 90.8% for NH3 and 59.6% for CO2. CH4 emissions increased, suggesting their potential entrapment. N2O and propane equivalent experienced reductions of 23.1% and 44.8%, respectively. On the other hand, ProfiCover&#174; presented emission reductions for NH3 and CO2 of 93.3% and 85.9%, respectively. CH4, contrasting with ePTE-TEXcomm, showed a significant reduction of 55.6%. N2O and propane equivalent followed with reductions of 56.7% and 84.5%, respectively. All of this divergence in performance implies a potential trade-off in emission reduction efficacy between the covers. Knowledge sharing between researchers and industry partners is key to translating these technologies into widespread adoption.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Muhammad Wajahat Ramay, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Csaba Gyuricza, NULL AUTHOR_ID, L&#225;szl&#243; Aleksza</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking ionomers for CO2 electroreduction to multicarbon products in zero-gap electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02332c</link>
      <description>Fanxin Zeng, Huihua Deng, Mengjiao Zhuansun, Wenzhi Teng, Yuhang Wang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400570987

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an emerging carbon utilization technology. The use of ionomers in fabricating the catalytic electrode was found to exert substantial effects on activity and product...</description>
      <author>Fanxin Zeng, Huihua Deng, Mengjiao Zhuansun, Wenzhi Teng, Yuhang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02332c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructed PbCO3 with abundant oxygen vacancies for efficient CO2-to-formate electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02989e</link>
      <description>Huan Wang, Jie Zhao, Qianqian Yang, Jingjie Wu, Xin Yu Zhang, Haiyang Yuan, Xiaolei Xu, Jingjing He, Qiang Niu, Pengfei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400461023

                The electrosynthesis of valuable chemical feedstocks and fuels through CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) provides a promising approach to solve the global warming problem and the energy crisis. Numerous researches have...</description>
      <author>Huan Wang, Jie Zhao, Qianqian Yang, Jingjie Wu, Xin Yu Zhang, Haiyang Yuan, Xiaolei Xu, Jingjing He, Qiang Niu, Pengfei Liu, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02989e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal thermal energy storage employing solar heat: A case study of Heilongjiang, China, exploring the transition to clean heating and renewable power integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132334</link>
      <description>Tianrun Yang, Wen Liu, Gert Jan Kramer, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400388103

                Seasonal thermal energy storage (STES) offers an attractive option for decarbonizing heating in the built environment to promote renewable energy and reduce CO2 emissions. A literature review revealed knowledge gaps in evaluating the technical feasibility of replacing district heating (DH) with STES in densely populated areas and its impact on costs, fossil fuel consumption, CO2 emission reduction, and renewable power integration. The effects of large-scale STES applications on the power and DH sectors in a regional energy system were quantified by applying the 2030 and 2050 power structure scenarios. The results indicated that STES reduces fossil fuel consumption and CO2 emissions at an affordable cost. It facilitates the integration of wind and solar power into power grids. With 100% replacement of DH by STES, fossil fuel consumption and CO2 emissions can be reduced by approximately 40% and 45% in 2030 and 2050, respectively, with an annual cost increase of 20%. The CO2 avoidance costs were predicted to be approximately 60 &#8364;/t in 2030 and well below 50 &#8364;/t in 2050. STES will reduce renewable power curtailment by 10% in 2030 and 18% in 2050. This study investigated STES from an energy-system perspective, supporting the formulation of clean heating transition policies.</description>
      <author>Tianrun Yang, Wen Liu, Gert Jan Kramer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Review on Effects of Material Composition, Mix Design, and Mixing Regimes on Rheology of 3D-Printed Geopolymer Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/0118748368292859240313061706</link>
      <description>P. S. Barve, Alireza Bahrami, NULL AUTHOR_ID, &#152;The &#156;Open construction &amp; building technology journal. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400421748

                Recent years have witnessed a significant growth in the research and development of additive manufacturing methods involving concrete and cementitious materials, with technologies like three-dimensional (3D) printing becoming more widely used in the construction industry. Construction has the possibility to be revolutionized, not only in the context of cost savings but also in the context of increased sustainability and functionality. 3D printing of concrete is a cutting-edge technology that has the potential to speed up construction, reduce labor costs, give architects more creative freedom, improve precision, obviate requirements for formwork, and result in less construction wastes. In addition, 3D printing can be a long-term solution for both economy and environment. Even though 3D printing in concrete has made tremendous strides recently, developing an effective 3D-printable material that decreases material usage and enhances performance is critical for carbon dioxide reduction. Robust geopolymer formulations for 3D printing concrete technology in current construction applications have emerged as the subject of much research among scientists to find novel ways to circumvent this constraint. This study intends to highlight the current state of the art in developing 3D-Printed Geopolymer Concrete (3DPGC) with a comprehensive review related to the material composition, mix design, and mixing regimes on rheology of 3DPGC. The rheology of 3DPGC in terms of printability and buildability is discussed. The mixing regimes employed for the preparation of one-part and two-part 3DPGC are tabulated and commented on. Lastly, the research gaps are identified and summarized, and several research directions are also provided for future investigations to expedite the ubiquitous use of 3DPGC in versatile construction applications.</description>
      <author>P. S. Barve, Alireza Bahrami, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/0118748368292859240313061706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Performance Packages on Fuel Consumption and Exhaust Emissions of Passenger Cars and Commercial Vehicles under WLTP</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143356</link>
      <description>Luca Marchitto, Maria Antonietta Costagliola, Alessandra Berra, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400460455

                The transportation sector is responsible for about 16% of worldwide greenhouse gas emissions. Despite efforts for a sensible reduction by means of new technologies&#8217; development, the average age of a vehicle fleet is 12.3 years in the European Union. In light of this, actions aiming at improving the efficiency of circulating vehicles can prove effective in the short to mid-term. Introducing performance packages in standard fuels could allow a reduction in the CO2 emissions of whole vehicle fleets without any modification to powertrain. Such a kind of additive is generally used in premium fuels; deposit control additives can reduce or control the deposits at intake valves and at nozzle holes with benefits for the fuel efficiency and exhaust emissions. Further improvements in combustion phasing can be achieved with cetane/octane improver. This paper aims to assess the influence of two performance packages on the exhaust emissions and fuel consumption of five vehicles set to be as representative as possible of circulating Italian passenger cars and light commercial fleet vehicles (LCVs). Based on the literature datasets, three Euro 4 vehicles were selected with a mileage representative of each single vehicle class: two passenger cars (one spark ignition and one diesel) and an LCV. Further, two diesel Euro 6 vehicles, a passenger car and an LCV, were tested to investigate the effect of fuel additives on the combustion of vehicles compliant with current homologation regulation. Exhaust emissions and fuel consumption were experimentally estimated on a chassis dynamometer over a worldwide harmonized light vehicles test cycle (WLTC) in a climate-controlled laboratory. Each vehicle was preliminarily tested when running with base fuel, then a 3000 km clean-up stage was performed using the additive package. Finally, WLTC tests were repeated. Results demonstrated the efficiency of the performance packages with a reduction between 1.2% (diesel Euro 6 passenger car) and 8.1% (diesel Euro 4 passenger car) in fuel consumption. Similar trends were found for CO2 emissions. Further, a sensible reduction in THCs, CO and PM was found for each vehicle class.</description>
      <author>Luca Marchitto, Maria Antonietta Costagliola, Alessandra Berra</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An audit of corporate decarbonisation ambition against low-carbon futures.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3367979/v2</link>
      <description>Iain S. Weaver, Jesse F. Abrams, Jeffrey C. Oliver, Nikolaos Dimakis, Andrew Parry, Timothy M. Lenton, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400459950

                Abstract Atmospheric greenhouse gas concentration has been steadily increasing since the 19th century, causing global warming. Despite efforts to reduce emissions, current projections anticipate a significant increase in global mean temperature by the end of the century, which may push us beyond a safe and just operating space. We must develop emissions pathways that take into account renewable technology innovation, climate policy development and consumer behavior change. In this manuscript we assess corporate emissions reduction ambition in the context of reduction pathways, and in doing so show that company reporting has reached a scale and quality that it can be used to supplement global emissions forecasting. We find emissions disclosures of target-setting companies to account for roughly a fifth of global CO2 emissions and three-fifths of total market capitalisation. Of these, we find near-term targets to be consistent with the aggressive reduction requirements of the divergent net-zero scenario published by the Network for Greening the Financial System, but commitments to 2050 are lacking. There is a large disparity between the total market capitalisation of disclosing companies and the total emissions they cover, a disconnect which we emphasise must be addressed by future</description>
      <author>Iain S. Weaver, Jesse F. Abrams, Jeffrey C. Oliver, Nikolaos Dimakis, Andrew Parry, Timothy M. Lenton</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3367979/v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CRITICAL EXAMINATION OF THE CONSTRUCTION SECTOR IN TURKEY IN TERMS OF SUSTAINABILITY</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47933/ijeir.1491574</link>
      <description>P&#305;nar Usta, Kamertap Cirik, Elifnur &#350;akalak, Ali Ekber SEVER, International journal of engineering and innovative research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400496991

                The construction sector is of critical importance for economic growth and employment creation. However, it also has significant environmental impacts, including high energy consumption, extensive use of natural resources, and substantial waste production. Currently, the construction sector in Turkey accounts for 35% of the country&#8217;s total energy consumption, making it a significant energy consumer. Research conducted in European Union countries indicates that buildings are responsible for 40% of total energy consumption and 36% of total CO2 emissions. It is believed that a similar situation exists in Turkey. Furthermore, the long lifespan of structures built in the sector is of great importance for sustainability. The contribution of poor-quality and unhealthy structures to environmental stress further highlights the role of the construction sector in sustainability. The study addresses the impacts of strategic goals such as the design and construction of sustainable building models, the recyclability and reuse of building materials, energy efficiency, and the reduction of CO2 emissions on the construction sector. The findings indicate that the integration of energy efficiency and renewable energy technologies is crucial for the Turkish construction sector to move towards a sustainable future. In this context, it is recommended that the Turkish construction sector implement the necessary steps and engage in strategic planning in order to achieve its sustainability goals. The findings of the study emphasise the pivotal role and significance of the construction sector in this regard.</description>
      <author>P&#305;nar Usta, Kamertap Cirik, Elifnur &#350;akalak, Ali Ekber SEVER</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47933/ijeir.1491574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circular Economy Integration in 1G+2G Sugarcane Bioethanol Production: Application of Carbon Capture, Utilization and Storage, Closed-Loop Systems, and Waste Valorization for Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14416/j.asep.2024.07.005</link>
      <description>Rich Jhon Paul Latiza, Rugi Vicente C. Rubi, Applied Science and Engineering Progress. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400428585

                Bioethanol production is a vital player in the renewable energy landscape. However, it faces pressing issues regarding carbon emissions and resource management. Traditional open-loop systems generate substantial waste and pollution, exacerbating environmental concerns. Various emerging technologies offer promising solutions. Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage (CCUS) presents avenues for tackling carbon emissions. Utilization transforms CO2 emissions into valuable products, while Storage securely stores emissions to prevent atmospheric release. Closed-loop processes and waste valorization capitalize on material reuse, conserving natural resources, and minimizing waste. By promoting resource efficiency and waste minimization, circular economy principles align seamlessly with CCUS, closed-loop systems, and waste valorization. This study delves into utilizing Utilization technologies tailored to sugarcane 1G+2G bioethanol production, evaluates CO2 capture options, and presents applications. Storage strategies suitable for bioethanol production facilities are scrutinized, and deployment options are explored, highlighting the closed-loop system and waste valorization's role in waste reduction and environmental preservation. Through synergistic integration, these technologies pave the way for sustainable sugarcane bioethanol production, addressing economic and technological challenges while fostering innovation and collaboration. This comprehensive study will serve as a guide for transitioning to a circular economy model in bioethanol production.</description>
      <author>Rich Jhon Paul Latiza, Rugi Vicente C. Rubi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14416/j.asep.2024.07.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From forests to farming: identification of photosynthetic limitations in breadfruit across diverse environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.08.602079</link>
      <description>Graham J. Dow, Noa Kekuewa Lincoln, Dolly Autufuga, Robert E. Paull, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400488734

                Breadfruit (Artocarpus altilis) is a prolific tropical tree producing highly nutritious and voluminous carbohydrate-rich fruits. Already recognized as an underutilized crop, breadfruit could ameliorate food insecurity and protect against climate-related productivity shocks in undernourished equatorial regions. However, a lack of fundamental knowledge impedes widespread agricultural adoption, from modern agroforestry to plantation schemes. Here, we used a multi-environment breadfruit variety trial across the Hawaiian Islands to determine photosynthetic limitations, understand the role of site conditions or varietal features, and define their contributions to agronomic efficiency. Photosynthetic rates were dependent on location and variety, and strongly correlated with fruit yield (r2=0.80, p&lt;0.001). Photochemistry was suitable to full-sunlight conditions, with a saturation point of 1545 PAR, Vcmax of 151 umol m-2s-1, and Jmax of 128 umol m-2s-1, which are high-end compared to other tropical and temperate tree crops. However, limitations on CO2 assimilation were imposed by stomatal characteristics, including stomatal density (p&lt;0.05) and diurnal oscillations of stomatal conductance (&gt;50% reductions from daily maxima). These constraints on CO2 diffusion are likely to limit maximum productivity more than photochemistry. Our results comprise the first comprehensive analysis of breadfruit photosynthesis, successfully links ecophysiology with fruit yield, and identifies vital traits for future research and management optimization.</description>
      <author>Graham J. Dow, Noa Kekuewa Lincoln, Dolly Autufuga, Robert E. Paull</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.08.602079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ALPINE: An adaptive language-agnostic pruning method for language models
  for code</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.04147</link>
      <description>Mootez Saad, Jos&#233; Antonio Hern&#225;ndez L&#243;pez, Boqi Chen, D&#225;niel Varr&#243;, Tushar Sharma, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400434361

                Language models of code have demonstrated state-of-the-art performance across various software engineering and source code analysis tasks. However, their demanding computational resource requirements and consequential environmental footprint remain as significant challenges. This work introduces ALPINE, an adaptive programming language-agnostic pruning technique designed to substantially reduce these models' computational overhead. The proposed method offers a pluggable layer that can be integrated with all Transformer-based models. With ALPINE, input sequences undergo adaptive compression throughout the pipeline, reaching a size up to $\times 3$ less their initial size, resulting in significantly reduced computational load. Our experiments on two software engineering tasks, defect prediction and code clone detection across three language models CodeBERT, GraphCodeBERT and UniXCoder show that ALPINE achieves up to a 50% reduction in FLOPs, a 58.1% decrease in memory footprint, and a 28.1% improvement in throughput on average. This led to a reduction in CO2 by up to $44.85$%. Importantly, it achieves the reduction in computation resources while maintaining up to 98.1% of the original predictive performance. These findings highlight the potential of ALPINE in making language models of code more resource-efficient and accessible while preserving their performance, contributing to the overall sustainability of adopting language models in software development. Also, it sheds light on redundant and noisy information in source code analysis corpora, as shown by the substantial sequence compression achieved by ALPINE.</description>
      <author>Mootez Saad, Jos&#233; Antonio Hern&#225;ndez L&#243;pez, Boqi Chen, D&#225;niel Varr&#243;, Tushar Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.04147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Blast Furnace Ingredient Optimization Based on Improved Grey Wolf Optimization Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14070798</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qing Lv, Metals. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400407088

                Blast furnace ironmaking plays an important role in modern industry and the development of the economy. A reasonable ingredient scheme is crucial for energy efficiency and emission reduction in blast furnace production. Determining the right blast furnace ingredients is a complicated process; therefore, this study examines the optimization of the ingredient ratio. In this paper a model of the blast furnace ingredients is established by considering cost of per ton iron, CO2 emissions, and the theoretical coke ratio as the objective functions; ingredient parameters, process parameters, main and by-product parameters as variables; and the blast furnace smelting theory and equilibrium equation as constraints. Then, the model is solved by using an improved grey wolf optimization algorithm and an improved multi-objective grey wolf optimization algorithm. Using the data collected from the steel mill, the conclusion is that multi-objective optimization can consider the indexes of each target, so that the values of all the targets are excellent; we also compared the multi-objective solution results with the original production scheme of the steel mill, and we found that using the blast furnace ingredient scheme optimized in this study can reduce the cost of iron per ton, CO2 emissions per ton, and the theoretical coke ratio in blast furnace production by 350 CNY/t, 1000 kg/t, and 20 kg/t, respectively, compared with the original production plan. Thus, steel mill decision makers can choose the blast furnace ingredients according to different business strategies and the actual needs of steel mills can be better met.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qing Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14070798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for carbon farming schemes (Road4Schemes) : Deliverable D2.1-2, D2.4-5 : carbon farming schemes throughout Europe, an overall inventory and analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18174/654551</link>
      <description>Bert Smit, Martin Hvarregaard Thors&#248;e, J.W.H. van der Kolk, K. Nikolaus, Laura B. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Ennio Facq, Ilaria Falconi, &#220;lfet Erdal, Claudia Heidecke, Alessandra Martelli, Irene Criscuoli, Giovanni Dara Guccione, Morten Graversgaard, Jana Pol&#225;kov&#225;, S. G&#246;tzinger, A. Baumgarten, Suzanne Reynders, M. Nogu&#232;s, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400559880

                Carbon farming is considered as one of the mitigation options to reach the targets of the Paris Agreement and the European Green Deal.The purpose of this report is to assess which carbon farming schemes are available throughout Europe, how they can be characterised and to which extent they deal with principles like additionality, fairness and long-term carbon storage, besides the issues of a proper MRV(monitoring, reporting and verification)-system with acceptable costs and sufficient payments for the farmers.The way in which carbon farming is organised is very different depending on the type of scheme.In this report, a carbon farming scheme is defined as any voluntary agreement in which a farmer or a group of farmers commit themselves to apply carbon farming measures to get a positive balance between soil carbon accumulation and GHG emissions (possibly measured as CO2 equivalents) or reduction of GHG-emissions in return for a payment or compensation in any form.</description>
      <author>Bert Smit, Martin Hvarregaard Thors&#248;e, J.W.H. van der Kolk, K. Nikolaus, Laura B. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Ennio Facq, Ilaria Falconi, &#220;lfet Erdal, Claudia Heidecke, Alessandra Martelli, Irene Criscuoli, Giovanni Dara Guccione, Morten Graversgaard, Jana Pol&#225;kov&#225;, S. G&#246;tzinger, A. Baumgarten, Suzanne Reynders, M. Nogu&#232;s</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18174/654551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimising solar: A techno-economic assessment and government facility compensation framework power generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21741/9781644903216-45</link>
      <description>Navaid ALI, Materials research proceedings. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400454504

                Abstract. In light of the necessity to meet growing energy demands while minimising expenses, this article examines two solar power system designs, considering peak and average load situations. The peak system, designed to handle a peak load of 190 MW with 260,568 PV panels installed, generates a significant excess of approximately 49,911 MWh annually. On the other hand, the average load design suggests a little deficit in energy. The monetary analysis reveals considerable capital expenditures for the total installation costs, totalling $58.77 million for an average system and $66.71 million for the peak system. However, the Levelized Cost of Energy (LCOE) rates are relatively competitive, at 0.0835 USD/kWh and 0.0736 USD/kWh respectively. Notably, the study highlights that the environmental impact analysis demonstrates a significant decrease in CO2 emissions, with the peak system achieving a reduction of up to 3,601,588 tonnes per year. This research has explicitly validated the capabilities of centralised solar power systems in addressing the current and future energy difficulties faced by the Government of Sindh in a sustainable and economically viable manner.</description>
      <author>Navaid ALI</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21741/9781644903216-45</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of proposals from key suppliers of small-scale photovoltaic installations for single-family homes considering current regulations and environmental and economic criteria&#8212;A case study in Malaga, Spain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i6.5205</link>
      <description>Enrique Navarrete de G&#225;lvez, Luis Rodr&#237;guez-Passolas Cantal, Francisco Zamora, Shakir Mohamed, Laia Miravet Garret, Journal of infrastructure, policy and development. 8(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400516247

                The economic viability of a photovoltaic (PV) installation depends on regulations regarding administrative, technical and economic conditions associated with self-consumption and the sale of surplus production. Royal Decree (RD) 244/2019 is the Spanish legislation of reference for this case study, in which we analyse and compare PV installation offers by key suppliers. The proposals are not optimal in RD 244/2019 terms and appear not to fully contemplate power generation losses and seem to shift a representative percentage of consumption to the production period. In our case study of a residential dwelling, the best option corresponds to a 5 kWp installation with surplus sale to the market, with a payback period of 18 years and CO2 emission reductions of 1026 kg/year. Demand-side management offers a potential improvement of 6%&#8211;21.8%. Based on the increase in electricity prices since 2020, the best option offers savings of up to &#8364;1507.74 and amortization in 4.24 years. Considering costs and savings, sale to the market could be considered as the only feasible regulatory mechanism for managing surpluses, accompanied by measures to facilitate administrative procedures and guarantees for end users.</description>
      <author>Enrique Navarrete de G&#225;lvez, Luis Rodr&#237;guez-Passolas Cantal, Francisco Zamora, Shakir Mohamed, Laia Miravet Garret</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i6.5205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decomposition Analysis of Carbon Emission Drivers and Peaking Pathways for Key Sectors under China&#8217;s Dual Carbon Goals: A Case Study of Jiangxi Province, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16135811</link>
      <description>Xinjie Jiang, Fei Xie, Sustainability. 16(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400410302

                Clarifying the factors influencing CO2 emissions and their peaking pathways in major sectors holds significant practical importance for achieving regional dual-carbon goals. This paper takes Jiangxi, a less developed demonstration zone in central China, as an example. It pioneeringly combines the LMDI method, Tapio decoupling model, and LEAP model to multi-dimensionally analyze the driving mechanisms, evolution patterns, and dynamic relationships with the economic development of carbon emissions in Jiangxi&#8217;s key sectors from 2007 to 2021. It also explores the future carbon emission trends and peaking potentials of various sectors under different scenarios. Our results show that (1) Carbon emissions in various sectors in Jiangxi have continued to grow over the past fifteen years, and although some sectors have seen a slowdown in emission growth, most still rely on traditional fossil fuels; (2) Economic growth and industrial structure effects are the main drivers of carbon emission increases, with a general trend towards decoupling achieved across sectors, while agriculture, forestry, animal husbandry and fishery, and ferrous metal smelting have shown a decline in their decoupling status; (3) In the carbon reduction and low-carbon scenarios, the carbon emission peaks in Jiangxi are estimated to be 227.5 Mt and 216.4 Mt, respectively, and targeted strategies for high-emission industries will facilitate a phased peak across sectors and enhance emissions reduction benefits. This has significant reference value for the central region and even globally in formulating differentiated, phased, sector-specific carbon peaking plans, and exploring pathways for high-quality economic development in tandem with ecological civilization construction.</description>
      <author>Xinjie Jiang, Fei Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16135811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching Product Selectivity in CO2 Electroreduction via Cu&#8211;S Bond Length Variation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409206</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zijian Li, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Min Gyu Kim, Shangguo Liu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400420646

                Regulating competitive reaction pathways to direct the selectivity of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction toward a desired product is crucial but remains challenging. Herein, switching product from HCOOH to CO is achieved by incorporating Sb element into the CuS, in which the Cu&#8211;S ionic bond is coupled with S&#8211;Sb covalent bond through bridging S atoms that elongates the Cu&#8211;S bond from 2.24 &#197; to 2.30 &#197;. Consequently, CuS with a shorter Cu&#8211;S bond exhibited a high selectivity for producing HCOOH, with a maximum Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 72%. Conversely, Cu3SbS4 characterized by an elongated Cu&#8211;S bond exhibited the most pronounced production of CO with a maximum FE of 60%. In situ spectroscopy combined with density functional theory calculations revealed that the altered Cu&#8210;S bond length and local coordination environment make the *HCOO binding energy weaker on Cu3SbS4 compared to that on CuS. Notably, a volcano&#8208;shaped correlation between the Cu&#8211;S bond length and adsorption strength of *COOH indicates that Cu&#8211;S in Cu3SbS4 as double&#8208;active sites facilitates the adsorption of *COOH, and thus results in the high selectivity of Cu3SbS4 toward CO.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zijian Li, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Min Gyu Kim, Shangguo Liu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching Product Selectivity in CO2 Electroreduction via Cu&#8211;S Bond Length Variation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409206</link>
      <description>Xiaoqian Wei, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Haeseong Jang, Min Kim, Shangguo Liu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400420692

                Regulating competitive reaction pathways to direct the selectivity of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction toward a desired product is crucial but remains challenging. Herein, switching product from HCOOH to CO is achieved by incorporating Sb element into the CuS, in which the Cu&#8211;S ionic bond is coupled with S&#8211;Sb covalent bond through bridging S atoms that elongates the Cu&#8211;S bond from 2.24 &#197; to 2.30 &#197;. Consequently, CuS with a shorter Cu&#8211;S bond exhibited a high selectivity for producing HCOOH, with a maximum Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 72%. Conversely, Cu3SbS4 characterized by an elongated Cu&#8211;S bond exhibited the most pronounced production of CO with a maximum FE of 60%. In situ spectroscopy combined with density functional theory calculations revealed that the altered Cu&#8210;S bond length and local coordination environment make the *HCOO binding energy weaker on Cu3SbS4 compared to that on CuS. Notably, a volcano&#8208;shaped correlation between the Cu&#8211;S bond length and adsorption strength of *COOH indicates that Cu&#8211;S in Cu3SbS4 as double&#8208;active sites facilitates the adsorption of *COOH, and thus results in the high selectivity of Cu3SbS4 toward CO.</description>
      <author>Xiaoqian Wei, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Haeseong Jang, Min Kim, Shangguo Liu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu Regulating the Bifunctional Activity of Co-O Sites for the High-Performance Rechargeable Zinc-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04853</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dandan Yue, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qingyu Li, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400422879

                The rational design of cost-effective and highly active electrocatalysts becomes the crucial energy storage technology to boost the kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which hinders the large-scale application of metal-air batteries under the situation of increasingly pressing energy anxiety. Herein, the Co-based ZIF introduced the moderate amount of Cu2+-derived Cu/Co metal nanoparticles (NPs) embedded in carbon frameworks after high-temperature calcination. The Co-O bond on the surface of Co nanoparticles is modulated by adjacent Cu nanoparticles with the surface Cu-O bonds. The resulted increase of the Co2+/Co3+ ratio in 0.1CuCo-NC enhances the ORR/OER bifunctional catalytic kinetics along with the &#916;E of 0.639 V. In situ Raman spectra of the catalyst on the three-electrode system as well as in the driven zinc-air battery (ZAB) show that the Co-O active sites regulated by Cu nanoparticles with Cu-O bonds maintain a periodic lattice expansion and compression during discharging and charging. The zinc-air battery based on 0.1CuCo-NC has a peak power density of up to 198.3 mW cm&#8211;2, a mass-specific capacity of 798.2 mAh g&#8211;1, and a cycling stability of 923 h at room temperature. This work makes up the research gap of a Co-based metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF)-derived catalyst regulated by a transition metal.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dandan Yue, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qingyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidation of synergism in Ce-Zr/SBA-15 mesoporous catalysts and the effects on the activity in selective glycerol to lactic acid reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.powtec.2024.120048</link>
      <description>Salmiza Saleh, Muhammad Yusri Ahmad, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Ahmad Zuhairi Abdullah, Powder technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400392020

                The continued conversion of glycerol to value-added chemicals is essential in ensuring the sustainable development of the biodiesel industry. Selective catalytic oxidation of glycerol to lactic acid provides an alternative approach to valorizing glycerol. A mesoporous SBA-15 supported mixed-metallic oxide catalyst is deemed essential to selectively produce lactic acid in this mixed parallel and multi-step reaction. SBA-15-supported bimetallic Ce and Zr oxides were proved to be highly efficient catalysts for the selective glycerol oxidation into lactic acid in base-free media. The synergism between Ce and Zr in the bimetallic oxide compounds could enhance the creation of oxygen vacancies in the catalyst via the reduction of Ce4+ to Ce3+. The 2:1CeZr/SBA-15 catalyst exhibited prominent catalytic activity in selectively oxidizing glycerol to lactic acid, with a glycerol conversion of 91.8% and a lactic acid yield of 35.1%. This work achieved superior catalytic performance compared to previously conducted studies, primarily due to the significantly higher initial glycerol concentration employed in this study. To ascertain the intrinsic active sites of the catalyst, the physicochemical properties of the catalyst were thoroughly examined using BET, FTIR, XRD, FESEM, TEM, CO2-TPD, O2-TPD, and H2-TPR analysis. This work concluded that the synergistic interaction of the active sites, which led to the formation of active oxygen species, facilitated primary dehydrogenation of the terminal -OH bond in glycerol. Hence, in this work, a plausible glycerol conversion mechanism over the 2:1CeZr/SBA-15 catalyst was also proposed.</description>
      <author>Salmiza Saleh, Muhammad Yusri Ahmad, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Ahmad Zuhairi Abdullah</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.powtec.2024.120048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time LNG Buses Emissions Prediction Based on a Temporal Fusion Trans-Formers Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3808/jei.202400517</link>
      <description>Qing Liu, Fei Gao, Jun Zhao, Yafei Cai, Lei Chen, Cheng Lv, Journal of environmental informatics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400515183

                Emissions from transportation are one of the key factors preventing the achievement of carbon peaking and carbon neutrality by 2050, with particular attention to emissions from buses. Specifically, few research has been conducted on the exhaust emissions characteristics of liquified natural gas (LNG) buses under different driving scenarios. This study proposed a framework for predicting exhaust emissions of LNG buses based on the portable emission measurement system and GPS collaborative perception data. Firstly, the emission distribution characteristics of CO2, CO, HC, and NOx from LNG buses in real-world driving were analyzed by visualization methods. Then, the real-time exhaust emissions of LNG buses were predicted based on the temporal fusion transformers model for both urban and suburban sections of Zhenjiang City, and the model validity was verified. The current and past 10 s driving states were used for predicting the emission rate of LNG buses. The results showed that the proposed model outperforms other advanced algorithms in real-time exhaust emissions prediction of LNG buses, with an average R2 value higher than 0.94 and an average MAPE reduction of 14.19%. The error assessment revealed that the emission values and average emission rates are higher when driving in the urban section compared to the suburban section. Among the influencing factors, traffic conditions have the most significant impacts on the exhaust emissions of LNG buses, followed by road conditions and driving states, with relative feature importance of 48.9, 34.8, and 16.3%, respectively. Additionally, the current and past 10 s driving states also significantly influenced real-time predictions. This study provides an essential theoretical reference for reducing exhaust emissions for city buses.</description>
      <author>Qing Liu, Fei Gao, Jun Zhao, Yafei Cai, Lei Chen, Cheng Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3808/jei.202400517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights On Liquid Jet Breakup And Spray Formation Of An Air-Assisted Atomizer: Conventional And Alternative Jet Fuel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55037/lxlaser.21st.186</link>
      <description>In&#234;s Ferr&#227;o, Miguel A.A. Mendes, Ana Moita, Andr&#233; R. Silva, No host. 21(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400450791

                Presently, it is imperative to address global environmental challenges. The concerns are related to the depletion of non-renewable fossil fuels, greenhouse gases, and pollutant emissions. The transportation sector contributes significantly to these issues. In particular, the aviation industry primarily relies on jet fuel, a fossil fuel responsible for around 2% of anthropogenic CO2 emissions. As a result, to address contemporary society environmental concerns and energy requirements, promising renewable and green energy sources are being intensively investigated, especially in air transportation. Sustainable aviation fuels (SAF), particularly biofuels, have been explored and indicated as a short-term solution to address the energy transition in the aviation sector. Implementing alternative fuels requires a deeper investigation regarding the spray dynamics. Following this, the present study explores conventional (Jet A-1) and alternative jet fuel (HVO) atomization, and the breakup length is explored in a wide range of operating conditions. The normalized mean breakup length was measured, and a correlation was proposed based on the experimental data. Additionally, the droplets released by the jet breakup are compared for both fuels in terms of diameter. Observations reveal the occurrence of jet flapping and bag breakup, affected by the air flowrate. The results also show that regardless of the fuel, increasing the momentum flux leads to a reduction in the normalized mean breakup length. An increase in the air flowrate promotes a shorter breakup length, resulting in a secondary droplet with smaller secondary droplet diameters. An empirical correlation was developed based on the fitting of the experimental data. This correlation indicates that the normalized mean breakup length exhibits a power law relation with M, which is consistent with the literature. This experimental study is essential to research on biofuels and aids in the development of new injectors and the precision of theoretical models integrated into numerical algorithms.</description>
      <author>In&#234;s Ferr&#227;o, Miguel A.A. Mendes, Ana Moita, Andr&#233; R. Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55037/lxlaser.21st.186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Obesity on Respiratory Health: The Role of Sport and Physical Activity in Prevention and Management</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12775/qs.2024.15.52231</link>
      <description>RW Makuch, Amir N. Kucharski, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Alicja Chro&#347;cicka, Khushboo Gala, Andrzej Czajka, Pawe&#322; Lenard, Sara Michalska, Martyna Dewicka, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Quality in Sport. 15(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400425212

                Introduction and Objective: Obesity is a major social and economic problem. Since the 1980s, the number of overweight and obese people has doubled. Treatment of such patients is 30% more expensive than for people of normal weight. The main aim of the article is to present the impact of the occurrence of respiratory diseases and the deterioration of the system function. In addition, the article reviews the impact of physical activity and diet on weight loss and the prevention of further weight gain. Review and Methods: Review and summary of studies and meta-analysis of studies available in open-source format on Google Scholar and PubMed. Abbreviated Description of the State of Knowledge: One of the most common diseases in the population is bronchial asthma. People with excess body weight have a more severe course, and numerous studies have been carried out to explain the cause. The main mechanism that worsens respiratory function is mechanical compression by fatty tissue. It has also been observed that the inflammatory response, underlying the etiopathogenesis of asthma, may be caused by the secretion of inflammatory mediators by adipocytes. This is currently being investigated. Obstructive sleep apnea is a disorder that results in a fragmentation of sleep, which has serious health consequences and leads to a reduction in quality of life. Obesity is a major risk factor. The severity of the condition is strongly related to excess body weight. Obese hypoventilation syndrome is a condition in which obesity impairs alveolar ventilation and CO2 removal, resulting in hypercapnia, which can lead to respiratory failure. Summary: Weight loss and interventions to prevent weight gain in people with a baseline BMI &gt;25 kg/m2 are fundamental to good health. For best results, a calorie-restricted diet should be combined with physical activity. The WHO has created recommendations for the amount of physical activity needed each week.</description>
      <author>RW Makuch, Amir N. Kucharski, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Alicja Chro&#347;cicka, Khushboo Gala, Andrzej Czajka, Pawe&#322; Lenard, Sara Michalska, Martyna Dewicka, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12775/qs.2024.15.52231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Modeling of the Local Reaction Environment in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-t37bp-v2</link>
      <description>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400469170

                Electrocatalytic reactions, such as oxygen reduction/evolution reactions and CO2 reduction reaction that are pivotal for the energy transition, are multi-step processes that occur in a nanoscale electric double layer (EDL) at a solid-liquid interface. Conventional analyses based on the Sabatier principle, using binding energies or effective electronic structure properties such as the d-band center as descriptors, are able to grasp overall trends in catalytic activity in specific groups of catalysts. However, thermodynamic approaches often fail to account for a plethora of electrolyte effects that arise in the EDL, including pH, cation, and anion effects. These effects have been observed to exert strong impacts on electrocatalytic reactions. There is growing consensus that the local reaction environment (LRE) prevailing in the EDL is the key to deciphering these complex and hitherto perplexing electrolyte effects. Increasing attention is thus paid to designing appropriate electrolytes, positioning the LRE at center stage. To this end, unraveling the LRE is becoming essential for designing electrocatalysts with specifically tailored properties, which could enable much needed breakthroughs in electrochemical energy science. Theory and modeling are getting more and more important and powerful in addressing this multifaceted problem that involves physical phenomena at different scales and interacting in a multidimensional parametric space. Theoretical models developed for this purpose should treat intrinsic multistep kinetics of electrocatalytic reactions, EDL effects from sub-nm scale to the scale of 10 nm, and mass transport phenomena bridging scales from &lt; 0.1 to 100 &#956;m. Given the diverse physical phenomena and scales involved, it is evident that the challenge at hand surpasses the capabilities of any single theoretical or computational approach. In this Account, we present a hierarchical theoretical framework to address the above challenge. It seamlessly integrates several modules: (i) microkinetic modelling that accounts for various reaction pathways; (ii) an LRE model that describes the interfacial region extending from the nanometric EDL continuously to the solution bulk; (iii) first-principles calculations that provide parameters, e.g., adsorption energies, activation barriers and EDL parameters. The microkinetic model considers all elementary steps without designating an a priori rate-determining step. The kinetics of these elementary steps are expressed in terms of local concentrations, potential and electric field that are co-determined by EDL charging and mass transport in the LRE model. Vital insights on electrode kinetic phenomena, i.e., potential-dependent Tafel slopes, cation effects, and pH effects, obtained from this hierarchical framework are then reviewed. Finally, an outlook on further improvement of the model framework is presented, in view of recent developments in first-principles based simulation of electrocatalysis, observations of dynamic reconstruction of catalysts, and machine-learning assisted computational simulations.</description>
      <author>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-t37bp-v2</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
