<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 01:17:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Ionic Liquids Functionalized Copper Catalytic Systems for Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401049</link>
      <description>Zhengyi Fu, Jingfang Zhang, Haonan Wu, Yanan Gao, Hui Hu, Lijuan Shi, Qun Yi, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401366230

                The extensive combustion of fossil fuels results in excessive release of carbon dioxide (CO2), causing a global environmental crisis. It is imperative to develop sustainable methods for converting CO2 into renewable energy sources. Electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) offers the potential to generate valuable chemicals, including C1 products (e.g., carbon monoxide, methane, etc.) and C2+ products (e.g., ethene, ethanol, acetic acid, propyl alcohol, etc.). Copper&#8208;based (Cu&#8208;based) catalysts show promise for producing value&#8208;added C2+ products, but they face challenges like low selectivity and stability. The catalytic performances of Cu&#8208;based catalysts can be promoted through electronic structure adjustment, selective crystal face exposure, as well as molecular additive approaches. Ionic liquids (ILs), known for their strong CO2 adsorption capacity, adjustable hydrophobicity, and wide chemical window, hold significant promise for addressing the current challenges associated with Cu&#8208;based catalysts. This review provides a comprehensive overview of the structural characterization and catalytic mechanisms of ILs used in Cu&#8208;based CO2RR catalytic systems. Additionally, it offers suggestions for future research avenues regarding IL&#8208;functionalized Cu catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhengyi Fu, Jingfang Zhang, Haonan Wu, Yanan Gao, Hui Hu, Lijuan Shi, Qun Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Organic Frameworks for Photocatalytic Reduction of Carbon Dioxide: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06783</link>
      <description>Jinglun Yang, Zihao Chen, Lei Zhang, Qichun Zhang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401419317

                Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) are crystalline networks with extended backbones cross-linked by covalent bonds. Due to the semiconductive properties and variable metal coordinating sites, along with the rapid development in linkage chemistry, the utilization of COFs in photocatalytic CO</description>
      <author>Jinglun Yang, Zihao Chen, Lei Zhang, Qichun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling carbon dioxide emissions reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2024.08.004</link>
      <description>Andriy Matviychuk, Olena Zhytkevych, Natalia Osadcha, Energy Reports. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401448978

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andriy Matviychuk, Olena Zhytkevych, Natalia Osadcha</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2024.08.004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Synthesis of MOF&#8208;based Materials for Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400684</link>
      <description>Mitra Bagheri, Mirtha A. O. Louren&#231;o, Julien K. Dangbegnon, Nicol&#242; B. D. Monti, Lu&#237;s Mafra, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Juqin Zeng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401463455

                Porous ZIF&#8208;8 and ZIF&#8208;67 were synthesized via a green steam&#8208;assisted dry&#8208;gel technique and investigated as potential catalysts for CO2 electroreduction. The synthesis conditions are found to significantly influence the growth of these metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs). Notably, the water content employed during synthesis plays a crucial role in shaping the morphological properties of ZIF&#8208;8. Specifically, a moderate water content results in the formation of uniform ZIF&#8208;8 with a size distribution ranging from 240 to 440 nm. During CO2 electroreduction, these morphological properties exert substantial effects on the selectivity for CO formation, thereby facilitating the production of syngas with adjustable CO: H2 ratios. This feature holds promise for the widespread adoption of syngas as a clean alternative to fossil fuels, offering potential benefits for electricity generation and liquid fuel production. Despite sharing similar structural properties with ZIF&#8208;8, ZIF&#8208;67 exhibits distinct performance characterized by its limited selectivity for CO2 electroreduction. This discrepancy is attributed to the different metal centers of the two MOFs, resulting in the distinct activation of CO2 and H2O molecules and their further reduction. This finding highlights the critical role of metal centers in MOF&#8208;based materials for electrocatalysis application.</description>
      <author>Mitra Bagheri, Mirtha A. O. Louren&#231;o, Julien K. Dangbegnon, Nicol&#242; B. D. Monti, Lu&#237;s Mafra, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Juqin Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub&#8208;3 nm ultrafine Cu2O for electroreduction of carbon dioxide to ethane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129109</link>
      <description>Junhua You, Jun&#8208;Peng Chen, Sheng Wang, Jiali Ren, Hangzhou Zhang, Qi Zhang, Jian Tian, Haibo Liu, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401475192

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junhua You, Jun&#8208;Peng Chen, Sheng Wang, Jiali Ren, Hangzhou Zhang, Qi Zhang, Jian Tian, Haibo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic reduction of air pollutants and carbon dioxide emissions in Shanxi Province, China from 2013 to 2020</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175342</link>
      <description>Li&#8208;Ling Wu, Shida Sun, G. M. Zhang, Zimu Jia, Yuyun Liu, Chenxi Xu, Mengjie Guo, Luyao Zhang, C. Cai, Runcao Zhang, Jialin Zheng, Wenjie He, Jun Yu, Bo Yu, Kebin He, The Science of The Total Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351327

                Synergistic reduction of air pollutants and carbon dioxide (CO</description>
      <author>Li&#8208;Ling Wu, Shida Sun, G. M. Zhang, Zimu Jia, Yuyun Liu, Chenxi Xu, Mengjie Guo, Luyao Zhang, C. Cai, Runcao Zhang, Jialin Zheng, Wenjie He, Jun Yu, Bo Yu, Kebin He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysts for Urea Synthesis from CO2 and Nitrogenous Species: from CO2 and N2/NOx Reduction to urea synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401333</link>
      <description>Li Chun, Qiuji Zhu, Chaojie Song, Yimin Zeng, Ying Zheng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401452383

                The traditional industrial synthesis of urea relies on the energy&#8722;intensive and polluting process, namely the Haber&#8722;Bosch method for ammonia production, followed by the Bosch&#8722;Meiser process for urea synthesis. In contrast, electrocatalytic C&#8722;N coupling from carbon dioxide (CO2) and nitrogenous species presents a promising alternative for direct urea synthesis under ambient conditions, bypassing the need for ammonia production. This review provides an overview of recent progress in the electrocatalytic coupling of CO2 and nitrogen sources for urea synthesis. It focuses on the role of intermediate species and active site structures in promoting urea synthesis, drawing from insights into reactants&#8217; adsorption behavior and interactions with catalysts tailored for CO2 reduction, nitrogen reduction, and nitrate reduction. Advanced electrocatalyst design strategies for urea synthesis from CO2 and nitrogenous species under ambient conditions are explored, providing insights for efficient catalyst design. Key challenges and prospective directions are presented in the conclusion. Mechanistic studies elucidating the C&#8722;N coupling reaction and future development directions are discussed. The review aims to inspire further research and development in electrocatalysts for electrochemical urea synthesis.</description>
      <author>Li Chun, Qiuji Zhu, Chaojie Song, Yimin Zeng, Ying Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amino-Functionalization Enhanced CO2 Reduction Reaction in Pure Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01416b</link>
      <description>Junfeng Chen, Wenzhe Niu, Liangyao Xue, Kai Sun, Xiaolong Yang, Xinyue Zhang, Weihang Li, Shuanglong Huang, Wenjuan Shi, Shouxin Zhang, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401403770

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO 2 RR) to carbon monoxide 11 represents a cost-effective pathway towards realizing carbon neutrality. To suppress 12 the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the...</description>
      <author>Junfeng Chen, Wenzhe Niu, Liangyao Xue, Kai Sun, Xiaolong Yang, Xinyue Zhang, Weihang Li, Shuanglong Huang, Wenjuan Shi, Shouxin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01416b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Reduction Potential of Sustainable Stainless Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s38313-024-1954-9</link>
      <description>Stefan Lindner, MTZ worldwide. 85(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401408525

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stefan Lindner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s38313-024-1954-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k</link>
      <description>Sarah Desmons, Julien Bonin, Marc Robert, S&#233;bastien Bontemps, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337387

                The expansive and dynamic field of CO2 Reduction Reaction (CO2RR) seeks to harness CO2 as a sustainable carbon source or energy carrier. While significant progress has been made in two,...</description>
      <author>Sarah Desmons, Julien Bonin, Marc Robert, S&#233;bastien Bontemps</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte manipulation on Cu-based electrocatalysts for electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.055</link>
      <description>Hongyao Zhou, Wanlong Xi, Peng Yang, Huiting Huang, Jia Tian, Marina Ratova, Dan Wu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongyao Zhou, Wanlong Xi, Peng Yang, Huiting Huang, Jia Tian, Marina Ratova, Dan Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Non-CO2 Greenhouse Gas Emissions by Catalytic Processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-6431-0_49-4</link>
      <description>Gabriele Centi, Siglinda Perathoner, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401366802

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gabriele Centi, Siglinda Perathoner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-6431-0_49-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction performance of shape-controlled bismuth nanowires</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3037959</link>
      <description>Yue Guan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401389639

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3037959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature Promotes Selectivity During Electrochemical CO2 Reduction on NiO:SnO2 Nanofibers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04116j</link>
      <description>M. A. Rodriguez-Olguin, Raju Lipin, Eleazar Casta&#241;eda-Morales, Cristina Flox Donoso, Tanja Kallio, Matthias Vandichel, Arturo Susarrey&#8208;Arce, Milla Suominen, Francisco Ru&#237;z-Zepeda, A. Manzo&#8208;Robledo, Han Gardeniers, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401415802

                Electrolyzers operate over a range of temperatures; hence, it is crucial to design electrocatalysts that do not compromise the product distribution unless temperature can promote selectivity. This work reports a...</description>
      <author>M. A. Rodriguez-Olguin, Raju Lipin, Eleazar Casta&#241;eda-Morales, Cristina Flox Donoso, Tanja Kallio, Matthias Vandichel, Arturo Susarrey&#8208;Arce, Milla Suominen, Francisco Ru&#237;z-Zepeda, A. Manzo&#8208;Robledo, Han Gardeniers</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04116j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Reduction of lauric acid in coconut copra by supercritical carbon dioxide extraction: Process optimization and design of functional cookies using the lauric acid&#8208;lean copra meal&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jfpe.14700</link>
      <description>, Journal of Food Process Engineering. 47(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401346381

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jfpe.14700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Reaction: Comprehensive Strategic Approaches to Catalyst Design for Selective Liquid Products Formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402477</link>
      <description>Nivedita Sikdar, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401420173

                The escalating concern regarding the release of CO2 into the atmosphere poses a significant threat to the contemporary efforts in mitigating climate change. Amidst a multitude of strategies for curtailing CO2 emissions, the electrochemical CO2 reduction presents a promising avenue for transforming CO2 molecules into a diverse array of valuable gaseous and liquid products, such as CO, CH3OH, CH4, HCO2H, C2H4, C2H5OH, CH3CO2H, 1&#8208;C3H7OH and others. The mechanistic investigations of gaseous products (e.g. CO, CH4, C2H4, C2H6 and others) broadly covered in the literature. There is a noticeable gap in the literature when it comes to a comprehensive summary exclusively dedicated to coherent roadmap for the designing principles for a selective catalyst all possible liquid products (such as CH3OH, C2H5OH, 1&#8208;C3H7OH, 2&#8208;C3H7OH, 1&#8208;C4H9OH, as well as other C3&#8208;C4 products like methylglyoxal and 2,3&#8208;furandiol, in addition to HCO2H, AcOH, oxalic acid and others), selectively converted by CO2 reduction. This entails a meticulous analysis to justify these approaches and a thorough exploration of the correlation between materials and their electrocatalytic properties. Furthermore, these insightful discussions illuminate the future prospects for practical applications, a facet not exhaustively examined in prior reviews.</description>
      <author>Nivedita Sikdar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352454

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353277

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UI/UX Sustainable Design: Best Practices for Applications CO2 Emissions Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.23919/splitech61897.2024.10612495</link>
      <description>Athanasios Kiourtis, Argyro Mavrogiorgou, Nikolaos Zafeiropoulos, Konstantinos Mavrogiorgos, Andreas Karabetian, Dimosthenis Kyriazis, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401330038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Athanasios Kiourtis, Argyro Mavrogiorgou, Nikolaos Zafeiropoulos, Konstantinos Mavrogiorgos, Andreas Karabetian, Dimosthenis Kyriazis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.23919/splitech61897.2024.10612495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag/Cu Foam Catalyst for Selective Reduction of Co2 to Ch3oh at Low Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916909</link>
      <description>Xiaolong Deng, Renfeng Nie, H. Yang, Hongwei Chen, Jie Yang, Meijuan Lu, Kaiping Peng, Xiaoyu Zhou, Chen Yang, Juan Xie, Hu Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401378139

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaolong Deng, Renfeng Nie, H. Yang, Hongwei Chen, Jie Yang, Meijuan Lu, Kaiping Peng, Xiaoyu Zhou, Chen Yang, Juan Xie, Hu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916909</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352451

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353249

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353499

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-performance watermelon skin ion-solvating membrane for electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51139-6</link>
      <description>Qing-Lu Liu, Tang Tang, Zhimei Tian, Shiwen Ding, Linqin Wang, Dexin Chen, Zhiwei Wang, Wentao Zheng, Husileng Lee, Xingyu Lu, Xiaohe Miao, Lin Liu, Licheng Sun, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401389316

                Ion-solvating membranes have been gaining increasing attention as core components of electrochemical energy conversion and storage devices. However, the development of ion-solvating membranes with low ion resistance and high ion selectivity still poses challenges. In order to propose an effective strategy for high-performance ion-solvating membranes, this study conducted a comprehensive investigation on watermelon skin membranes through a combination of experimental research and molecular dynamics simulation. The micropores and continuous hydrogen-bonding networks constructed by the synergistic effect of cellulose fiber and pectin enable the hypodermis of watermelon skin membranes to have a high ion conductivity of 282.3 mS cm</description>
      <author>Qing-Lu Liu, Tang Tang, Zhimei Tian, Shiwen Ding, Linqin Wang, Dexin Chen, Zhiwei Wang, Wentao Zheng, Husileng Lee, Xingyu Lu, Xiaohe Miao, Lin Liu, Licheng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51139-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Hydrogen as Fuel in Decarbonizing US Clinker Manufacturing for Cement Production: Costs and CO2 Emissions Reduction Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.155078</link>
      <description>Ikenna J. Okeke, Sachin Nimbalkar, Kiran Thirumaran, Joe Cresko, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401459996

                As a low-carbon fuel, feedstock, and energy source, hydrogen is expected to play a vital role in the decarbonization of high-temperature process heat during the pyroprocessing steps of clinker production in cement manufacturing. However, to accurately assess its potential for reducing CO2 emissions and the associated costs in clinker production applications, a techno-economic analysis and a study of facility-level CO2 emissions are necessary. Assuming that up to 20% hydrogen can be blended in clinker fuel mix without significant changes in equipment configuration, this study evaluates the potential reduction in CO2 emissions (scopes 1 and 2) and cost implications when replacing current carbon-intensive fuels with hydrogen. Using the direct energy substitution method, we developed an Excel-based model of clinker production, considering different hydrogen&#65533;blend scenarios. Hydrogen from steam methane reformer (gray) and renewable-based electrolysis (green) are considered as sources of hydrogen fuel for blend scenarios of 5%&#65533;20%. Metrics such as the cost of cement production, facility-level CO2 emissions, and cost of CO2 avoided were computed. Results show that for hydrogen blends (gray or green) between 5% and 20%, the cost of cement increases by 0.6% to 16%, with only a 0.4% to 6% reduction in CO2 emissions. When the cost of CO2 avoided was computed, the extra cost required to reduce CO2 emissions is $229 to $358/ metric ton CO2. In summary, although green hydrogen shows promise as a low-carbon fuel, its adoption for decarbonizing clinker production is currently impeded by costs.</description>
      <author>Ikenna J. Okeke, Sachin Nimbalkar, Kiran Thirumaran, Joe Cresko</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.155078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352985

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-based metal-oxides and MOFs for efficient CO2 detection/reduction to chemical/fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100952</link>
      <description>Deepak Kumar, Pashupati Pratap Neelratan, Anshika Gupta, Neeru Sharma, Manisha Sharma, Sangeeta Shukla, Satendra Pal Singh, Jong&#8208;Sung Yu, Ajeet Kaushik, Sanjeev Kumar Sharma, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401361304

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deepak Kumar, Pashupati Pratap Neelratan, Anshika Gupta, Neeru Sharma, Manisha Sharma, Sangeeta Shukla, Satendra Pal Singh, Jong&#8208;Sung Yu, Ajeet Kaushik, Sanjeev Kumar Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353005

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Sarah Desmons, Julien Bonin, Marc Robert, S&#233;bastien Bontemps, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarah Desmons, Julien Bonin, Marc Robert, S&#233;bastien Bontemps</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insight into electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to formate by the iron(I) porphyrin complex: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114430</link>
      <description>Yaqing Wang, Wenzhen Lai, Molecular Catalysis. 566(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401386102

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaqing Wang, Wenzhen Lai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114430</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Dimension Reduction of Complex Three-dimensional CO2 Saturation using Deep Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2426378</link>
      <description>Hongsheng Wang, Seyyed A. Hosseini, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401437836

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongsheng Wang, Seyyed A. Hosseini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2426378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advancements in carbon/metal-based nano-catalysts for the reduction of CO2 to value-added products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143017</link>
      <description>Arunkumar Senthilkumar, Mohanraj Kumar, Melvin S. Samuel, Selvarajan Ethiraj, Mohd Anis, Jih-Hsing Chang, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401283836

                Due to the increased human activities in burning of fossil fuels and deforestation, the CO</description>
      <author>Arunkumar Senthilkumar, Mohanraj Kumar, Melvin S. Samuel, Selvarajan Ethiraj, Mohd Anis, Jih-Hsing Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b</link>
      <description>Jia Li, Jianning Lu, Shuai Li, Lu Dai, Kai Wang, Pengfei Li, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401377717

                2D conjugated MOFs (2D c-MOFs) have attracted significant interest in electrocatalysis due to their intrinsic electrical conductivity. Their catalytic performance heavily relied on the metal centers and structures of highly...</description>
      <author>Jia Li, Jianning Lu, Shuai Li, Lu Dai, Kai Wang, Pengfei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altering electronic states of Cu sites in Covalent organic frameworks for synthesis of formate via CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154636</link>
      <description>Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Qizheng An, Shuang Zheng, Guojuan Liu, Shuai Yang, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401437806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Qizheng An, Shuang Zheng, Guojuan Liu, Shuai Yang, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WATER SOFTENING PLANTS AND REDUCTION OF IRON AND MANGANESE BY MAGNETIC AND NANOBUBBLE CO2 TREATMENT: A TECHNICAL AND APPLICATIVE ANALYSIS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51865/jpgt.2024.01.09</link>
      <description>Dan Ovidiu C&#238;rjan, Maria Stoicescu, Romanian Journal of Petroleum &amp; Gas Technology. 5 (76)(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333969

                Human society and environment are based on water resources. Hard water with iron and manganese excess is spread across the world and softening of drinking water is widely applied for reasons of public health, client comfort, economic and environmental benefits. Also, from industrial or commercial point of view, using it produce scale deposits in water systems and equipment often result in ample technical and economic problems. Solutions of reducing its hardness and iron/manganese excess exists on the market, even with the substances presented in the work. The novelty this study brings comes from using high intensity permanent magnets arrangements and CO2 nanobubbles treatment that increased the speed, the volume of treatment, while decreasing the energy and complexity of the installation, also decreasing the pollution mark of the system. The detrimental contributions of softening, in particular the use of chemicals and energy, are taken into account in the carbon footprint of the drinking water companies. The beneficial contributions have not been included in the carbon footprint. For carbon capture in the crystallized calcite and dissolution of CO2 into the softened water, the carbon footprint is compensated by the net carbon benefit of softening.</description>
      <author>Dan Ovidiu C&#238;rjan, Maria Stoicescu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51865/jpgt.2024.01.09</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381913

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382002

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381984

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bismuth Oxide Nanoflakes Grown on Defective Microporous Carbon Endows High-Efficient Co2 Reduction at Ampere Level</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916693</link>
      <description>Minjun Zhou, Zhihao Guo, Mingwang Wang, Dewen Song, Rui Zhou, Quansheng Liu, Shuai Wang, Boshi Zheng, Xiaoshan Wang, Hui Ning, Mingbo Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401323189

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minjun Zhou, Zhihao Guo, Mingwang Wang, Dewen Song, Rui Zhou, Quansheng Liu, Shuai Wang, Boshi Zheng, Xiaoshan Wang, Hui Ning, Mingbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient solar-driven: Photothermal catalytic reduction of atmospheric CO2 at the gas-solid interface by CuTCPP/MXene/TiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.018</link>
      <description>Feng Yue, Meng Yang, Shuo Zhang, Cong Li, Mengke Shi, Xuhui Qian, Lan Wang, Yali Song, Jun Li, Yongpeng Ma, Hongzhong Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401327857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Yue, Meng Yang, Shuo Zhang, Cong Li, Mengke Shi, Xuhui Qian, Lan Wang, Yali Song, Jun Li, Yongpeng Ma, Hongzhong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the impact of energy efficiency and renewable energy on CO2 emissions reduction: empirical evidence from the power industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s13762-024-05865-5</link>
      <description>Sadegh Azizi, Reza Radfar, Ali Rajabzadeh Ghatari, Hanieh Nikoomaram, International Journal of Environmental Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401322533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sadegh Azizi, Reza Radfar, Ali Rajabzadeh Ghatari, Hanieh Nikoomaram</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s13762-024-05865-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381983

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of uncertainties in rice yield response to elevated CO2 by experiment-model integration: A case study in East China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cj.2024.06.012</link>
      <description>Zihao Wang, Zhang Yu, Xueni Wang, Yanfeng Ding, Songhan Wang, The Crop Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401314152

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihao Wang, Zhang Yu, Xueni Wang, Yanfeng Ding, Songhan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cj.2024.06.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381884

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Jia Li, Jianning Lv, Shuai Li, Lu Dai, Xiaogang Wang, Pengfei Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Li, Jianning Lv, Shuai Li, Lu Dai, Xiaogang Wang, Pengfei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381883

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing *CO coverage on Sm-Cu2O via 4f-3d orbital hybridization for highly efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction to C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.053</link>
      <description>Xiaojun Wang, Lan&#8208;Lan Shi, Wenkai Ren, Jingxian Li, Yuanming Liu, Weijie Fu, Shiyu Wang, Shuyun Yao, Yingjie Ji, Jian Kang, Shouxin Zhang, Zhiyu Yang, Jiangzhou Xie, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401305855

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojun Wang, Lan&#8208;Lan Shi, Wenkai Ren, Jingxian Li, Yuanming Liu, Weijie Fu, Shiyu Wang, Shuyun Yao, Yingjie Ji, Jian Kang, Shouxin Zhang, Zhiyu Yang, Jiangzhou Xie, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S&#8208;scheme MnO2/Co3O4 sugar&#8208;gourd nanohybrids with abundant oxygen vacancies for efficient visible&#8208;light&#8208;driven CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401057</link>
      <description>Linfeng Jin, Hao Yu, Chenhui Wang, Changfa Guo, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Yijun Zhong, Yong Hu, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401399360

                Converting CO2 to carbon&#8208;based fuels using solar energy via photocatalysis is a promising approach to boost carbon neutrality. However, the solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion efficiency is hampered by interconnected multiple factors including insufficient light absorption, low separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers as well as complex and sluggish surface reaction kinetics. Herein, we incorporate MnO2 nanowires and Co3O4 hollow polyhedrons with abundant oxygen vacancies (Vo) into MnO2/Co3O4 sugar&#8208;gourd nanohybrids for boosting CO2 photoreduction. The MnO2/Co3O4 nanohybrids not only display strong absorption in the visible&#8211;near infrared region, but also facilitate the separation of photogenerated carriers in terms of S&#8208;scheme transfer pathway, supplying abundant electrons for CO2 reduction reaction. Furthermore, the presence of VO enhances the separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers and promotes the chemical adsorption to CO2 molecules. In addition, the interfacial electronic interaction between MnO2 and Co3O4 also contributes to the chemical adsorption and activation to CO2. Owing to the synergy of S&#8208;scheme transfer pathway and VO, the MnO2/Co3O4 hybrids exhibit greatly enhanced photocatalytic activity towards CO2 reduction under the irradiation of visible light in comparison with bare MnO2 and Co3O4, delivering a CO evolution rate of 15.9 umol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 with a 100% selectivity.</description>
      <author>Linfeng Jin, Hao Yu, Chenhui Wang, Changfa Guo, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Yijun Zhong, Yong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;SEWGS integration in a direct reduction steelmaking process for CO2 mitigation&#8221; [International Journal of Greenhouse Gas Control, Volume 130 (2023), 103991]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104203</link>
      <description>Nicola Zecca, P.D. Cobden, Leonie L&#252;cking, Giampaolo Manzolini, International journal of greenhouse gas control. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354476

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicola Zecca, P.D. Cobden, Leonie L&#252;cking, Giampaolo Manzolini</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Study on the Impacts of CO2 and H2 Storage on Well Cement Integrity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221415-ms</link>
      <description>Abdalla Abdelfattah Abed, H. Galvis-Silva, Tarek Elsayed, Hamidreza Samouei, Kun Liu, E. R. Okoroafor, No host. 44(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401349144

                Abstract The interactions between hydrogen and carbon dioxide (CO2) with wellbore cement are not fully understood, raising concerns about cement degradation during carbon capture and storage (CCS) and underground hydrogen storage (UHS). This study examines the geochemical, petrophysical, and geomechanical properties of cement before and after exposure to hydrogen and CO2. Cement samples were saturated in brine of 30000 ppm and exposed to the gases at 500 psi and 50&#176;C for 30 days. Hydrogen exposure led to a 50% increase in brownmillerite, a 70% decrease in ettringite, and a reduction in porosity and permeability by 2% and 40%. Compressive strength and Young's modulus increased by 35% and 6%. CO2 exposure caused the formation of calcite (8.7% of the composition) and complete alite depletion, reducing porosity and permeability by 98% and 87%. Compressive strength and Young's modulus rose by 126% and 161%. This study is the first to comprehensively compare cement properties before and after hydrogen and CO2 exposure under the same conditions. The findings suggest hydrogen and CO2 do not weaken cement strength and can even heal fractures, reducing fluid losses.</description>
      <author>Abdalla Abdelfattah Abed, H. Galvis-Silva, Tarek Elsayed, Hamidreza Samouei, Kun Liu, E. R. Okoroafor</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221415-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Power Generation Systems With and Without Carbon Capture on Offshore Hydrocarbon Processing Facilities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-135750</link>
      <description>Jaime HuiChoo Tan, C. Lee, Ravi Kumar Mantry, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401458469

                Abstract There are very few offshore hydrocarbon processing facilities in operation that have implemented combined-cycle power generation systems, and this power scheme deserves more serious consideration and adoption due to its positive effect on carbon reduction. In this study, assessment is made of power generation schemes based on gas-driven power generation system, steam-driven power generation system and combined-cycle power generation system for an example floating production, storage and offloading (FPSO) platform design, to compare the engineering design, fuel gas consumption, equipment weights, and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions associated to each power generation system. It is found that the combined-cycle power generation system improves energy efficiency, reduces fuel gas consumption and in turn reduces CO2 emissions. Further, potential implementation of an offshore carbon capture system for separating CO2 from the gas turbine flue gases using a proprietary amine absorption technology, is presented. This paper recommends integrating combined-cycle power generation scheme and post-combustion carbon capture on the gas turbine exhausts for reducing the carbon footprint of the power generation system on the facility. Carbon capture of the process waste gas incinerator exhausts can further achieve the overall facility net-zero carbon emissions target, however this aspect is not in the scope of this paper.</description>
      <author>Jaime HuiChoo Tan, C. Lee, Ravi Kumar Mantry</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-135750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of Methanol Production using PyBOUND</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.194568</link>
      <description>Prapatsorn Borisut, Bianca Williams, Aroonsri Nuchitprasittichai, Selen Cremaschi, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401442238

                In this paper, we study the design optimization of methanol production with the goal of minimizing methanol production cost. One challenge of methanol production via carbon dioxide (CO2) hydrogenation is the reduction of operating costs. The simulation of methanol production is implemented within the Aspen HYSYS simulator. The feeds are pure hydrogen and captured CO2. The process simulation involves a single reactor and incorporates recycling at a ratio of 0.995. The methanol production cost is determined using an economic analysis. The cost includes capital and operating costs, which are determined through the equations and data from the capital equipment-costing program. The decision variables are the pressure and temperature of the reactor contents. The optimization problem is solved using a derivative-free algorithm, pyBOUND, a Python-based black-box model optimization algorithm that uses random forests (RFs) and multivariate adaptive regression splines (MARS). The predicted minimum methanol production cost by pyBOUND is $1396.56 per tonne of methanol, which corresponds to the pressure of 68.82 bar and temperature of 192.23&#65533;C while the actual cost is $1393.95 per tonne of methanol at these conditions. The cost breakdown of methanol production is 75% hydrogen price, 11% utility cost, 8% capital cost, 5% carbon dioxide price, and 1% operating cost.</description>
      <author>Prapatsorn Borisut, Bianca Williams, Aroonsri Nuchitprasittichai, Selen Cremaschi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.194568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Framework for Carbon-Capture and Storage (CCS) in Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221616-ms</link>
      <description>Akihiro Ibe, Adaobi Stephenie Nwosi-Anele, SPE Nigeria Annual International Conference and Exhibition. 143(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401349299

                Abstract Associated Carbon dioxide (CO2) gas flaring in Nigeria is but only a fraction of the amount of CO2 being released into the atmosphere daily. An increase in the concentration of CO2 in the atmosphere has led to an increase in greenhouse gas effects. Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS) is one of several solutions proposed to help combat the ever-continuous increase of greenhouse gases in our environment. However, it has been noted by several research papers that for CCS to affect the greenhouse gas effect, the source of the CO2 gas for the carbon capture and storage (sequestration) must be obtained from anthropogenic means. While most other nations haven't only begun this process but also have already established a solid legal framework and regulations for CCS, Nigeria currently has no legal framework for the regulation of CCS. This paper focuses on establishing a framework for CCS to be adapted in Nigeria as a measure to take the first step in the process of establishing a carbon capture and storage process in Nigeria. This process was done by analyzing other legal frameworks that have already been established and then taking into account the diversity and political nature of the Nigerian structure, censoring, and editing these regulations as seen fit, to make a legal framework that is suitable and acceptable to and for Nigerians. In the process of analysis, several key factors such as transportation (across borders and intra-trade), leakages, faults, levies, and taxes as well as tax reduction incentives for companies willing to use CCS were taken into consideration and then explored to find a common ground for both companies and government. The main objective of this work is to urge the Nigerian government and the petroleum industry of the need for the immediate reduction of greenhouse gasses and their effects and the first step begins with laying down the groundwork. The study concludes that adopting a robust legal framework tailored to Nigeria's unique socio-political environment is essential. It also recommends specific legislative actions and incentives to foster CCS adoption, emphasizing the importance of collaboration between government and industry stakeholders.</description>
      <author>Akihiro Ibe, Adaobi Stephenie Nwosi-Anele</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221616-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automation of Greenhouse Gas Emission Estimates Associated with Natural Gas Production in the Appalachian Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221400-ms</link>
      <description>Carlos Calad, T. Buckinham, Edwin Lee Mulligan, M. Annab, Pallav Sarma, Dayanara Betancourt, Carlo V. Caballero&#8208;Uribe, H. Solano, Javad Rafiee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401349617

                Abstract This study seeks to improve the quantification of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from unconventional natural gas production in the Appalachian Basin, covering Carbon Dioxide (CO2), Methane (CH4), and Nitrous Oxide (N2O). The goal is to automate the calculation process for compliance with the US Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), corporate sustainability reporting, and internal monitoring for emissions reduction targets. Traditionally, GHG emissions are manually computed once a year and are often calculated by third-party consultants, reducing transparency in calculation approaches. The development of an on-demand GHG emissions inventory enables real-time identification of emission-intensive processes, guiding strategic decisions for emissions mitigation and methane intensity reductions. In this project, we employed Python and SQL scripts to map activity data related to process and fugitive emissions, including pneumatic devices, drilling and completions combustion, equipment leaks, liquids unloading, dehydrators, and flaring, into US EPA Subpart W formulas. The result is an annualized carbon footprint calculated at the well pad level, providing comprehensive insights into component gasses (CO2, CH4, and N2O), production-based carbon and methane intensities, and emissions contributions by emission source. Automation improved the efficiency and accuracy of the emissions calculation workflow, generating an updated carbon footprint in a runtime under 5 minutes. Additionally, the inclusion of emissions-generating events overlooked due to human error substantially improved the quality of the emissions footprint. Lastly, the employment of data analytics on all calculation inputs and outputs aided in identifying outliers that required modification. The GHG calculation tool enhances accuracy, transparency, and consistency while minimizing the time invested in GHG estimations, allowing teams to redirect their efforts toward value-added activities. Next steps in the project include detailed emissions forecasting, which facilitates determining the most cost-effective emissions reduction strategy. The mapping of activity data into GHG estimation models was completed within six weeks, with additional time spent in result validation against previous manual calculations. After an initial configuration, data mappings do not require ongoing updates, establishing a fully automated GHG calculation process. This advancement enables efficiency and reliability in monitoring and reporting GHG emissions. Additionally, the development of a granular carbon footprint on an emission source basis enables detailed, source-level emissions forecasting to support future decisions around emission reduction projects.</description>
      <author>Carlos Calad, T. Buckinham, Edwin Lee Mulligan, M. Annab, Pallav Sarma, Dayanara Betancourt, Carlo V. Caballero&#8208;Uribe, H. Solano, Javad Rafiee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221400-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of the Mineral Manganese OXMN009 and OXMN009P in the Chemical Looping Combustion (CLC) Process Using Thermogravimetry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14156823</link>
      <description>Sandra Pe&#241;a Murillo, Carmen R. Forero, Francisco Velasco-Sarria, Eduardo Arango, Applied Sciences. 14(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401321925

                Indirect combustion with the chemical looping combustion (CLC) of solid oxygen carriers is one of the most promising technologies for capturing carbon dioxide (CO2) in energy production from fossil fuels since the separation of the generated CO2 is inherent to the process itself. Therefore, the cost associated with capturing this gas will be significantly reduced. This technology transfers oxygen from air to fuel through a metal oxide that acts as an oxygen carrier, avoiding direct contact between air and fuel. This oxygen carrier circulates in a fluidized bed reactor called a reduction reactor and an oxidation reactor. (1) This research work has focused on evaluating the behavior of oxygen carriers based on the original and improved manganese mineral (copper-impregnated mineral) named for this study, OXMN009 and OXMN009P, respectively. (2) Equilibrium experiments were carried out on a thermogravimetric balance (TGA) to evaluate the kinetic behavior of these oxygen transporters OXMN009 and OXMN009P, using the gases methane (CH4), carbon monoxide (CO), and hydrogen (H2). (3) The enhanced solid oxygen carrier OXMN009P exhibited good performance for the CLC process with gaseous fuels in terms of reactivity and combustion efficiency, having high reactivity and oxygen transfer properties due to copper impregnation. (4) The results show that OXMN009P has comparable reactivity to other manganese-based materials reported in the literature. It may be an effective option for carbon dioxide capture, as it uses metal oxides as the oxygen transporters (TO). (5) These oxygen transporters, OXMN009 and OXMN009P, are used in a cyclic process that prevents the formation of nitrogen oxides by keeping the air and fuel separate. (6) Thermogravimetric balance (TGA) experiments were conducted to evaluate the kinetic behavior of these copper-modified oxygen transporters. (7) It was found that OXMN009P improved the reactivity and oxygen transfer properties due to copper impregnation. The kinetic parameters obtained in the TGA indicate that the reaction is non-thermal and requires less energy to initiate. (8) The results show that OXMN009P has reactivity comparable to other manganese-based materials reported in the literature and can be an effective option for carbon dioxide capture.</description>
      <author>Sandra Pe&#241;a Murillo, Carmen R. Forero, Francisco Velasco-Sarria, Eduardo Arango</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14156823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameter Estimation of Breakthrough Curve Models in the Adsorption Process of H2S and CO2 Using the Markov Chain Monte Carlo Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14166956</link>
      <description>Haianny Beatriz Saraiva Lima, Ana Paula Souza de Sousa, Wellington Betencurte da Silva, Deibson Silva da Costa, Emerson Cardoso Rodrigues, Diego Cardoso Estumano, Applied Sciences. 14(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401410408

                The increase in emissions of toxic gasses such as hydrogen sulfide (H2S) and carbon dioxide (CO2), resulting from growing urbanization and industrialization, has caused environmental and public health problems, making the implementation of air purification techniques through adsorption important. Thus, modeling the gas adsorption process is fundamental for good agreement with experimental data, employing mathematical models that enable the prediction of adsorption capacity. In this way, the present work aimed to compare different analytical breakthrough curve models (Thomas, Yoon&#8211;Nelson, Adams&#8211;Bohart, and Yan) for the adsorption of H2S and CO2 in fixed-bed columns, using experimental data from the literature, estimating the curve parameters through the Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) method with the Metropolis&#8211;Hastings algorithm, and ranking using the determination coefficients (R2 and R2Adjusted) and the Bayesian Information Criterion (BIC). The models showed better agreement using the estimation of maximum adsorption capacity (qs, N0) and the constants of each model (kth, kyn, and kba). In the adsorption of H2S, the Yan model stood out for its precision in estimating qs. For the adsorption of CO2, the Adams&#8211;Bohart model achieved better results with the estimation of N0, along with the Yoon&#8211;Nelson model. Furthermore, the use of this method allows for a reduction in computational effort compared to models based on complex differential equations.</description>
      <author>Haianny Beatriz Saraiva Lima, Ana Paula Souza de Sousa, Wellington Betencurte da Silva, Deibson Silva da Costa, Emerson Cardoso Rodrigues, Diego Cardoso Estumano</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14166956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost-Benefit Analysis of a Policy that will Limit Carbon Dioxide Emissions of DieselPowered Generator.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56293/ijasr.2022.5543</link>
      <description>Toyin Amunigun, International Journal of Applied Science and Research. 06(04)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4401297225

                This paper presents a detailed economic analysis of a proposed regulation to limit carbon dioxide emissions from diesel generators in the United States. The analysis is conducted through a cost-benefit framework, with the objective of determining whether the societal benefits of reduced carbon dioxide emissions would outweigh the economic costs of the regulation. The study draws from previous research on the application of costbenefit analysis in the context of environmental policy, particularly climate change. It then estimates the potential benefits from avoided carbon dioxide emissions, and contrasts these with the costs that could arise from implementing carbon capture technologies, a reduction in the diesel generator sector's value, and a drop in diesel fuel demand. The results suggest that the economic costs of the proposed regulation outweigh the benefits, both in the short term and the long run. However, the paper concludes with a call for continued efforts in finding economically and environmentally balanced solutions to reduce carbon dioxide emissions, particularly in sectors with significant contributions like the electric power sector.</description>
      <author>Toyin Amunigun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56293/ijasr.2022.5543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular enhancement of Cu-based catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02619e</link>
      <description>Haiqiang Luo, Bo Li, Jian&#8208;Gong Ma, Peng Cheng, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401375322

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (eCO</description>
      <author>Haiqiang Luo, Bo Li, Jian&#8208;Gong Ma, Peng Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02619e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of Copper Enrichment on a Gold Electrocatalyst as a Method of Syngas Synthesis from CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47611/jsrhs.v13i1.6228</link>
      <description>Juliet Winiecki, Xu Guo, Journal of Student Research. 13(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401324089

                This literary review examines the work of a distinguished research team from the University of Berkeley and the University of Toronto. The work in question was a key paper in the global search within the scientific community to find a solution to the excess of fossil fuels within the atmosphere. Specifically, this research team&#8217;s focus was the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide to hydrogen gas and carbon monoxide. This review offers a fundamental standpoint, honing in on a specific technique that is cutting-edge in terms of technology, research, and methodology, while also being broadly applicable. The technique includes the use of a gold (Au) electrode precisely coated with a copper (Cu) monolayer, which (altogether) serves as the electrocatalyst powering the reaction. Techniques like Raman spectroscopy and cyclic voltammetry, coupled with concepts such as Molecular Orbital Theory, helped to explain the inner workings of the carbon dioxide reduction reaction. This study demonstrated that changing the amount of Cu deposited onto a Au surface affected the produced hydrogen gas (H2) to carbon monoxide (CO) ratio. This review also considered the appropriateness of Raman spectroscopy, and whether or not it was the best technical choice given the context of this experiment. Altogether, this review uses fundamental concepts in chemistry to analyze a new method of reducing carbon dioxide, an electrochemical process that is growing increasingly relevant in today&#8217;s efforts to reduce fossil fuel emissions.</description>
      <author>Juliet Winiecki, Xu Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47611/jsrhs.v13i1.6228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crude Oil Bulk Flow Strategy to Manage Emission Abatement and Gas Flaring &#8211; An Adafill Eastern Asset Success Story</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221710-ms</link>
      <description>Bayo Balogun, Idarasit Adigu, O.A. Adeleke, Oghenevwogaga Bosini, Emmanuel Wordu, Gloria Siwe Usiagu, Chinedu Onyeme, Victor Okahia Ewuzie, SPE Nigeria Annual International Conference and Exhibition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401349013

                Abstract Greenhouse gas emissions primarily result from releasing various gases into the Earth's atmosphere during oil and gas extraction, production, and distribution. These emissions significantly contribute to global warming and climate change. The main greenhouse gases emitted by this sector include carbon dioxide (CO2), methane (CH4), and nitrous oxide (N2O). These gases are released through leaks, venting, incomplete combustion, intentional releases, and notably, gas flaring from facilities lacking Associated Gas Gathering (AGG) solutions. Given the significant contribution of the oil and gas industry to greenhouse gas emissions, it is crucial to identify and implement effective management and reduction techniques. This paper focuses on identifying specific abatement technique tailored for the oil and gas sector, evaluating their effectiveness and feasibility, and identifying potential challenges in implementing them to combat climate change and ensure a sustainable future. The ADAFILL Eastern Asset is a pseudo-name for an existing major operator of a joint venture in Nigeria and has implemented bulk flow management strategies in the context of crude oil extraction and processing to manage and reduce emissions and gas flaring. This paper provides an overview of the assets, examining their current infrastructure, processes, and environmental performance. It also delves into the implementation of emission abatement measures, evaluates their results and impact, and provides recommendations for further improvements. This paper highlights the importance of addressing greenhouse gas emissions and reducing flare gas in the oil and gas industries. It presents the crude oil bulk flow approach as a proven solution, which effectively captures, recovers, and utilizes gases that would otherwise be flared or vented into the atmosphere. By implementing bulk flow systems, the Eastern Asset of ADAFILL has significantly reduced its environmental impact, conserved resources, and contributed to a more sustainable future by adopting this low-cost solution for facilities without Associated Gas Gathering infrastructure.</description>
      <author>Bayo Balogun, Idarasit Adigu, O.A. Adeleke, Oghenevwogaga Bosini, Emmanuel Wordu, Gloria Siwe Usiagu, Chinedu Onyeme, Victor Okahia Ewuzie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221710-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy and Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/hesc/9780198807506.003.0004</link>
      <description>Andrew Sturman, Herv&#233; Qu&#232;nol, Oxford University Press eBooks. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4401328597

                This chapter examines energy and infrastructure in the context of climate change. It notes that infrastructure is closely associated with energy production and use. The practical application of alternative energy sources relies on investigations undertaken at the local and regional scales. The chapter considers how transferring from the use of fossil fuels to renewable forms of energy can contribute to reduction of the enhanced greenhouse effect by reducing carbon dioxide emissions. It introduces hydropower, wind power, and solar power as renewable energy sources. Finally, the chapter shows that climate change is altering both supply capacity and energy demand and infrastructure use.</description>
      <author>Andrew Sturman, Herv&#233; Qu&#232;nol</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/hesc/9780198807506.003.0004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The synergistic effect of green innovation and governance in carbon neutrality: Insights from Japanese companies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bse.3922</link>
      <description>K. Keerthana, S. P. Wu, Thangavelu Kokulnathan, Mu&#8208;En Wu, Business Strategy and the Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401431553

                Abstract Japan is firmly committed to transitioning to a low&#8208;carbon economy to address climate change. This research focuses on the role of innovation and governance in achieving carbon neutrality among Japanese companies listed on the Tokyo Stock Exchange from 2017 to 2023, particularly in all carbon dioxide&#8208;contributing sectors. Through multivariate statistics, regression modeling, and quantitative literature analysis, we provide robust evidence of the relationship among innovation, governance, and carbon neutrality. The findings highlight the importance of fostering a sustainability&#8208;oriented culture to drive sustainable innovation and achieve carbon neutrality. We compared the environmental, social, and governance (ESG) and governance to expand our scope. Its results underscore the significance of strong corporate governance in facilitating sustainable initiatives. A robustness test is included to finalize that the samples have avoided endogeneity. These findings demonstrate a positive outlook for Japan's future emissions reduction.</description>
      <author>K. Keerthana, S. P. Wu, Thangavelu Kokulnathan, Mu&#8208;En Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bse.3922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental investigation of low temperature combustion in a diesel engine depending on injection advance and injection pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2298/tsci240105155g</link>
      <description>Onur Gezer, Orkun &#214;zener, Muammer &#214;zkan, Thermal Science. None(00)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401329618

                In this study, the performance parameters and emissions of a pre-mixed charge compression ignition were investigated under different injection pressures and injection advances. After the peak engine power was reached, reasonable decreases occurred in brake mean effective pressure at certain injection advances with the increase of injection advance, and dramatic decreases observed when interval was so exceeded. In addition to mean indicated pressure and peak in-cylinder pressure were investigated. Considering the emissions, dramatic increases were observed in carbon monoxide and total hydrocarbon, depending on the increase in the LTC regime. Nitrogen oxides started a rapid downward trend after a certain injection advance value in the experimental region, but this effect didn?t occur at the desired level for specific nitrogen oxides. It was observed that the nitrogen dioxide to nitrogen oxides ratio increased as the pre-mixed charge compression ignition became dominant and nitrogen dioxide production increased among the total nitrogen oxides. In the operating region where the LTC regime was dominant, the targeted reduction in NOx and PM emissions was observed, but the desired reduction in specific emissions did not occur. In the LTC region, the combustion process was prolonged, initially reasonable changes occurred at performance parameters, but unacceptable results were observed at high injection pressures with excessive injection advances.</description>
      <author>Onur Gezer, Orkun &#214;zener, Muammer &#214;zkan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2298/tsci240105155g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Conditions Empirical Optimization for Sustainability Manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18260/1-2--47816</link>
      <description>Hayder Zghair, Noah Bretz, Jeffrey Sumner, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401313494

                Abstract Clean and smart manufacturing is vital towards combating climate change. Manufacturing is one of the leading contributors to climate change, with the EPA saying that 24% of all greenhouse gas emissions come from manufacturing. While progress has been made in the industry, most technologies that reduce emissions are too cost prohibitive for most businesses to implement. The main roadblock to cleaner manufacturing is cost effectiveness. Cleaner processes can cost as much as five times the cost of the processes they are trying to replace. However, there is hope that as these new technologies are implemented, their overall cost will begin to decrease allowing more businesses to implement these new technologies. These new technologies can be assessed using a life cycle assessment to determine the environmental consequences of each individual machine and process through analysis of the material, energy, and emissions at each stage of the process. This assessment assumed to help determine which machine and / or process is more sustainable. Through many trials, it has been determined that machining in a controlled environment with higher cutting speeds and feed rates is the most economical and sustainable approach. There are a number of criteria that can be used to determine the sustainability of a manufacturing process. Some of them are carbon emissions, estimate of remaining tool life, estimation of total machining cost, and the surface quality of the machined product. Turning is a process commonly done on a lathe machine where the metal stock is rotated at a very fast speed and a cutting tool. This process can be wasteful in terms of material and can create carbon dioxide emissions. A set of designing and conducting experimentations to test the carbon emissions and power consumed in the turning process. The experimentation is by changing a number of parameters including the types of stock material (aluminum, steel, brass, etc.), the speed of turning the stock, as well as the speed of the cutting. The carbon dioxide contamination from the turning process is measured using two of atmospheric sensors. These the current temperature and humidity of an area in the atmosphere at that current point are measured to be with standard. The differences in the values between before and after the process determined the change in carbon dioxide levels and gives the indication which variables have the greatest effect on carbon emissions and how they can be optimized to be more sustainable. Using an energy consumption device, the consumed power calculated and the effect of the changes in parameters observed as well. Resulted data showed an interpretation determined on what set up of experimentation was the most energy efficient and contamination reduction for each parameter as well as determine the most effective way to conduct turning overall on the lathe machine.</description>
      <author>Hayder Zghair, Noah Bretz, Jeffrey Sumner</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18260/1-2--47816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Institutional Performance and Carbon Reduction Effect of High-Quality Development of New Energy: China&#8217;s Experience and Policy Implication</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166734</link>
      <description>L. Zhang, Dong Zheng-ai, Zhixiong Tan, Jiahui Luo, Dong Yan, Sustainability. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354919

                Based on the policy text from 1999 to 2022, this paper quantitatively analyzes photovoltaic power, wind power and new energy policies in mainland China by keyword capture and policy strength and establishes a spatial Durbin model to study the carbon reduction effects. The results show the following: (1) The development of new energy is primarily project-based and concentrated in rural areas. (2) Financial support is a double-edged sword. (3) After the implementation of the Renewable Energy Law in 2015, the change trend in policy quantity, total policy intensity, and average policy intensity is generally consistent. (4) The increase in the strength of new energy policies has effectively reduced the intensity of provincial carbon dioxide emissions. (5) New energy policies introduced in a single region are less effective in reducing carbon emissions than joint regional regulation. Therefore, it is necessary to improve the quality and coordination of new energy policies through the effective convergence of policies and regular evaluations to enhance the positive guidance of the policies. Policy measures for new energy are refined in three areas: improving the amount and quality of new energy policies, strengthening new energy policies and establishing cooperation mechanisms for the cross-regional consumption of new energy.</description>
      <author>L. Zhang, Dong Zheng-ai, Zhixiong Tan, Jiahui Luo, Dong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Clustered, Multi-modal CO2 Transport Considering Non-linear Costs &#65533; a Path-planning Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.150076</link>
      <description>Kang Qiu, Sigmund Eggen Holm, Julian Straus, Simon Roussanaly, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456022

                An important measure to achieve global reduction in CO2 emissions is CO2 capture, transport, and storage. The deployment of CO2 capture requires the development of a shared CO2 transport infrastructure, where CO2 can be transported with different transport modes. Furthermore, the cost of CO2 transport can be subject to significant economies of scale effects with respect to the amount of CO2 transported, also mentioned as clustering effects. Therefore, optimizing the shared infrastructure of multiple CO2 sources can lead to significant reductions in infrastructure costs. This paper presents a novel formulation of the clustered CO2 transport network. The Markov Decision Process formulation defined here allows for more detailed modeling of non-linear, discrete transport costs and increased geographical resolution. The clustering effects are modeled through cooperative multi-agent interactions. A multi-agent, reinforcement learning-based algorithm is proposed to optimize the shared transportation network, with examples illustrating the results of the method.</description>
      <author>Kang Qiu, Sigmund Eggen Holm, Julian Straus, Simon Roussanaly</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.150076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of hydrogen production potential of wastewater based on GRA-BiLSTM model under shared socioeconomic pathway in Guangdong</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2024.117988</link>
      <description>Bingchun Liu, Yawei Du, Mingzhao Lai, Desalination. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401361114

                With the deepening of the energy transition, hydrogen production from wastewater has attracted widespread attention as an energy production method that can realize resource recycling. To explore whether hydrogen production from wastewater can have a significant role in the energy transition, it is crucial to effectively assess the future potential of hydrogen production from municipal wastewater. Based on the Guangdong Province of China, this study proposed a prediction model combining grey relation analysis (GRA) and bi-directional long short term memory (BiLSTM). Combined with a common socio-economic pathway (SSP), wastewater production is predicted from 2023 to 2050, and the potential for hydrogen production from wastewater is further analyzed. The cost of hydrogen production and carbon reduction potential under different scenarios are explored on this basis. The results show that by 2050, the SSP4 (Inequality) scenario will produce the most hydrogen, which will reach 22.0 billion m3, and reduce 247.2 billion tons of carbon dioxide emissions. In contrast, the SSP1 (Sustainability) scenario will produce 7.5 billion m3 of hydrogen and reduce carbon emissions by 84.5 billion tons. From the perspective of energy production and environmental protection, future hydrogen production from wastewater will make a great contribution to the global energy transition and sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Bingchun Liu, Yawei Du, Mingzhao Lai</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2024.117988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of photoelectrochemical conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.03</link>
      <description>Xia Jiang, Rui Chen, Yanxin Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu, Chemical Synthesis. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401375495

                The reduction of CO2 to C2+ products using photoelectrochemistry (PEC) is significant and highly challenging. However, systematic summaries on PEC CO2 conversion into C2+ products are lacking. Therefore, this paper systematically reviews the current research status of the PEC CO2 conversion for the preparation of C2+ products, including the pathways of C2+ products, the usage of catalysts and reactors, and methods for improving C2+ product selectivity. Besides, the deficiencies in current research are analyzed, and future developments are discussed.</description>
      <author>Xia Jiang, Rui Chen, Yanxin Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.03</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering the Site Distance of Atomic Cu&#8208;Cu Pairs by First&#8208;Shell Halogen Coordination Boosts CO2&#8208;to&#8208;C2 Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412785</link>
      <description>Fengya Ma, Pengfang Zhang, Xiaoyan Zheng, Liang Chen, Yunrui Li, Zechao Zhuang, Yameng Fan, Peng Jiang, Hui Zhao, Jiawei Zhang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaojing Yao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401368251

                Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 into C2 products of high economic value provides a promising strategy to realize resourceful CO2 utilization. Rational design and construct dual sites to realize the CO protonation and C&#8208;C coupling to unravel their structure&#8208;performance correlation is of great significance in catalysing electrochemical CO2 reduction reactions. Herein, Cu&#8208;Cu dual sites with different site distance coordinated by halogen at the first&#8208;shell are constructed and shows a higher intramolecular electron redispersion and coordination symmetry configurations. The long&#8208;range Cu&#8208;Cu (Cu&#8208;I&#8208;Cu) dual sites show an enhanced Faraday efficiency of C2 products, up to 74.1%, and excellent stability. In addition, the linear relationships that the long&#8208;range Cu&#8208;Cu dual site is accelerated to C2H4 generation and short&#8208;range Cu&#8208;Cu (Cu&#8208;Cl&#8208;Cu) dual site is beneficial for C2H5OH formation are disclosed. In situ electrochemical attenuated total reflection surface enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy, in situ Raman and theoretical calculations manifest that long&#8208;range Cu&#8208;Cu dual sites can weaken reaction energy barriers of CO hydrogenation and C&#8208;C coupling, as well as accelerating deoxygenation of *CH2CHO. This study uncovers the exploitation of site&#8208;distance&#8208;dependent electrochemical property to steer the CO2 reduction pathway, as well as a potential generic tactic to target C2 synthesis by constructing the desired Cu&#8208;Cu dual sites.</description>
      <author>Fengya Ma, Pengfang Zhang, Xiaoyan Zheng, Liang Chen, Yunrui Li, Zechao Zhuang, Yameng Fan, Peng Jiang, Hui Zhao, Jiawei Zhang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaojing Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering the Site Distance of Atomic Cu&#8208;Cu Pairs by First&#8208;Shell Halogen Coordination Boosts CO2&#8208;to&#8208;C2 Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412785</link>
      <description>Fengya Ma, Pengfang Zhang, Xiaoyan Zheng, Liang Chen, Yunrui Li, Zechao Zhuang, Yameng Fan, Peng Jiang, Hui Zhao, Jiawei Zhang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaojing Yao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401368113

                Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 into C2 products of high economic value provides a promising strategy to realize resourceful CO2 utilization. Rational design and construct dual sites to realize the CO protonation and C-C coupling to unravel their structure-performance correlation is of great significance in catalysing electrochemical CO2 reduction reactions. Herein, Cu-Cu dual sites with different site distance coordinated by halogen at the first-shell are constructed and shows a higher intramolecular electron redispersion and coordination symmetry configurations. The long-range Cu-Cu (Cu-I-Cu) dual sites show an enhanced Faraday efficiency of C2 products, up to 74.1%, and excellent stability. In addition, the linear relationships that the long-range Cu-Cu dual site is accelerated to C2H4 generation and short-range Cu-Cu (Cu-Cl-Cu) dual site is beneficial for C2H5OH formation are disclosed. In situ electrochemical attenuated total reflection surface enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy, in situ Raman and theoretical calculations manifest that long-range Cu-Cu dual sites can weaken reaction energy barriers of CO hydrogenation and C-C coupling, as well as accelerating deoxygenation of *CH2CHO. This study uncovers the exploitation of site-distance-dependent electrochemical property to steer the CO2 reduction pathway, as well as a potential generic tactic to target C2 synthesis by constructing the desired Cu-Cu dual sites.</description>
      <author>Fengya Ma, Pengfang Zhang, Xiaoyan Zheng, Liang Chen, Yunrui Li, Zechao Zhuang, Yameng Fan, Peng Jiang, Hui Zhao, Jiawei Zhang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaojing Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative study of direct solid-gas carbonation and direct aqueous carbonation for carbon capture and storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2798/1/012006</link>
      <description>Jianguo Wang, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2798(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401344650

                Abstract Carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) is a significant contributor to global warming and environmental issues, necessitating the development of practical storage solutions. As an alternative to CO 2 storage in subsurface formations, mineral carbonation, which offers long-term CO 2 storage and advantages like thermodynamics and energy economy, is gaining popularity. Also, the possible repurposing of carbonated solid waste in the building and construction industry contributes to the reduction of CO 2 . However, large-scale implementation of natural mineral carbonation remains a challenge. This study investigates the comparative advantages and disadvantages of direct solid-gas and direct aqueous carbonation, two carbon capture and storage (CCS) methods for combating atmospheric CO 2 emissions. The research focuses on reaction kinetics, capture efficiency, recovery efficiency, leakage security, and cost-effectiveness. Both methods have the potential to capture CO 2 efficiently, but they differ in their effectiveness and feasibility. Direct solid-gas carbonation exhibits higher reaction rates and capture efficiency, while direct aqueous carbonation has lower energy requirements and is easier to implement at ambient temperature and pressure. Further research is essential to fully understand the comparative merits and drawbacks of direct solid-gas and aqueous carbonation and devise strategies to minimize their environmental impact. Furthermore, to ensure economic feasibility, future research should focus on lowering CO 2 sequestration costs, increasing the scale of captured CO 2 usage in industrial processes, and developing a circular economy by transforming captured CO 2 into valuable metal carbonates.</description>
      <author>Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2798/1/012006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Air Quality Indeks Using Long Short Term Memory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30871/jaic.v8i1.7402</link>
      <description>Irfan Wahyu Ramadhani, Filmada Ocky Saputra, Ricardus Anggi Pramunendar, Galuh Wilujeng Saraswati, Nurul Anisa Sri Winarsih, Muhammad Syaifur Rohman, Danny Oka Ratmana, Guruh Fajar Shidik, Journal of Applied Informatics and Computing. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401432188

                Exercise offers significant physical and mental health benefits. However, undetected air pollution can have a negative impact on individual health, especially lung health when doing physical activity in crowded sports venues. This study addresses the need for accurate air quality predictions in such environments. Using the Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) method or what is known as high performance time series prediction, this research focuses on forecasting the Air Quality Index (AQI) around crowded sports venues and its supporting parameters such as ozone gas, carbon dioxide, etc. -others as internal factors, without involving external factors causing the increase in AQI. Preprocessing of the data involves removing zero values &#8203;&#8203;and calculating correlations with AQI and the final step performs calculations with the LSTM model. The LSTM model which adds tuning parameters, namely with epoch 100, learning rate with a value of 0.001, and batch size with a value of 64, consistently shows a reduction in losses. The best results from the AQI, PM2.5, and PM10 features based on performance are MSE with the smallest value of 6.045, RMSE with the smallest value of 4.283, and MAE with a value of 2.757.</description>
      <author>Irfan Wahyu Ramadhani, Filmada Ocky Saputra, Ricardus Anggi Pramunendar, Galuh Wilujeng Saraswati, Nurul Anisa Sri Winarsih, Muhammad Syaifur Rohman, Danny Oka Ratmana, Guruh Fajar Shidik</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30871/jaic.v8i1.7402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Ionic Polymer Membrane Based on PVDF for Capacitor Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/0118722121313373240730072512</link>
      <description>Kamlesh Kukreti, Varij Panwar, Recent Patents on Engineering. 19(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401401742

                Objective: To address these issues, we propose the use of ionic polymer membranes. By reducing the demand for synthetic plastics, these membranes contribute to pollution reduction. Moreover, they offer economic and environmental benefits. Ionic polymers can also help limit carbon dioxide emissions. Method: In our study, we created a blend of polyvinylidene fluoride (PVDF), polyvinylpyrrolidone (PVP), and polyvinyl sulfonic acid (PVSA). This blend was used to fabricate an ionic membrane through the solvent casting method. The resulting membrane acts as a successful dielectric material, sandwiched between copper electrodes. We conducted extensive characterization, including microstructure analysis, crystal structure examination, identification of functional groups, and thermal behavior assessment. Results: Our findings demonstrate the potential of ionic polymer membranes for capacitor applications. By varying the composition of PVDF/PVP/PVSA, we explored different dielectric properties. Notably, the ionic polymer electrolyte can serve as an effective dielectric material, with copper electrodes providing a practical application. Conclusion: Our investigation included electrical current density measurements using cyclic voltammetry, elemental composition analysis, morphological studies, and material composition assessments.</description>
      <author>Kamlesh Kukreti, Varij Panwar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/0118722121313373240730072512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Hanwha Ocean Liquefied CO2 Carrier</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-126076</link>
      <description>Insoo Jun, Teuk-Jin Koh, Bruce S. Kang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456673

                Abstract The interest in carbon neutrality is growing around the world as human faces the climate crisis caused mainly by greenhouse gas emission. The methodologies for carbon reduction are being introduced in every industry and carbon reduction through Carbon Capture Utilization &amp; Storage (hereafter &#8220;CCUS&#8221;) is being recognized as one of the most feasible carbon reduction plan at the moment. CCUS is defined as a system of technologies that intergrates three stages: CO2 capture, transportation and utilization &amp; geological storage. The transportation sector is a major part in CCUS value chain to link the capture sector and utilization &amp; storage sector. Transportation methods of trucks, trains, pipelines, ships, etc. are being considered in the CCUS value chain and pipelines and ships are applicable in ocean transportation field. As the transportation distance of CCUS projects under development becomes longer and the total transportation volume is increased, ocean transportation using a dedicated liquefied CO2 (LCO2) carrier is expected to play a key role in carbon transportation of CCUS chain. In these market trends, Hanwha Ocean began developing a new vessel that can transfer liquid CO2 safely. This paper is to introduce the design development of Hanwha Ocean LCO2 carrier such as ship &amp; cargo tank design, tank material, CHS (Cargo Handling System) test facility, etc.</description>
      <author>Insoo Jun, Teuk-Jin Koh, Bruce S. Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-126076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerosol&#8208;Calibrated Matched Filter Method for Retrievals of Methane Point Source Emissions Over the Los Angeles Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024ea003519</link>
      <description>Chenxi Feng, Sihe Chen, Zhao&#8208;Cheng Zeng, Yangcheng Luo, Vijay Natraj, Yuk L. Yung, Earth and Space Science. 11(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401339971

                Abstract Methane, with a global warming potential roughly 86 times greater than carbon dioxide over a 20&#8208;year timeframe, plays a crucial role in global warming. Remote sensing retrieval is a pivotal methodology for identifying methane emission sources, with accuracy influenced largely by surface and atmospheric properties, including aerosols. In this study, we propose an Aerosol&#8208;Calibrated Matched Filter (ACMF) algorithm to improve the traditional Matched Filter (MF) method. Our new approach incorporates an aerosol scattering correction factor to reduce the aerosol&#8208;induced bias on methane retrievals. Validating our algorithm through simulated spectra, we demonstrate that considering the aerosol scattering effect significantly reduces retrieval errors compared to MF methods by an average of approximately 90%. We apply our newly developed algorithm to hyperspectral data obtained from the Airborne Visible/Infrared Imaging Spectrometer&#8212;Next Generation in the Los Angeles Basin and focus on 11 plumes identified through case studies. Our results reveal that ACMF estimates of emission rates and inversion uncertainties exhibit an average reduction of approximately 4% compared to corresponding MF results, with deviation increasing with aerosol optical depth (AOD).</description>
      <author>Chenxi Feng, Sihe Chen, Zhao&#8208;Cheng Zeng, Yangcheng Luo, Vijay Natraj, Yuk L. Yung</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024ea003519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Urban Transport and Land-Use Policies in Reducing CO2 Emissions and Energy Consumption: Case Study of a Medium-Sized City in Thailand</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/wevj15080349</link>
      <description>Prinya Chindaprasirt, Pongrid Klungboonkrong, Sittha Jaensirisak, Natthapoj Faiboun, Sina Long, Atit Tippichai, Michael A. P. Taylor, World Electric Vehicle Journal. 15(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326798

                In developing cities, transport activities have become one of the primary sources of CO2 emissions and energy consumption owing to rapid economic growth, urbanization, and motorization. Khon Kaen City, Thailand, was chosen as a representative mid-sized city of a developing country to investigate the potential influences of transit-oriented development (TOD), light rail transit (LRT), and electric vehicle (EV) policy integration scenarios on CO2 emission and energy consumption reductions in 2016, 2026, and 2046. The TOD did not significantly reduce CO2 emissions or energy consumption because it was only applied in one area of the city. The LRT development also had a small effect because of the small proportion of modal shifts to LRT. However, EV utilization offered the greatest potential for reducing both CO2 emissions and energy consumption. In addition, the integrated scenario combining the three policies had a promising effect, diminishing both CO2 emissions and energy consumption, because it gathered the potential merits and benefits of each individual policy.</description>
      <author>Prinya Chindaprasirt, Pongrid Klungboonkrong, Sittha Jaensirisak, Natthapoj Faiboun, Sina Long, Atit Tippichai, Michael A. P. Taylor</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/wevj15080349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Inter&#8208;Metal Interaction between Ni and Fe Atoms in Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts to Boost CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411543</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Jia Li, Xiaoli Pan, Ning Li, Zhounan Yu, Li Wang, Tianyi Ma, Sen Lin, Jian Lin, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401420908

                Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) are promising for applications in electrochemical CO2 reduction due to the enhanced flexibility of the catalytic sites and the synergistic effect between dual atoms. However, precisely controlling the atomic distance and identifying the dual&#8208;atom configuration of DACs to optimize the catalytic performance remains a challenge. Here, the Ni and Fe atomic pairs were constructed on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon support in three different configurations: NiFe&#8208;isolate, NiFe&#8208;N bridge, and NiFe bonding. It was found that the NiFe&#8208;N bridge catalyst with NiN4 and FeN4 sharing two N atoms exhibited superior CO2 reduction activity and promising stability when compared to the NiFe&#8208;isolate and NiFe&#8208;bonding catalysts. A series of characterizations and density functional theory calculations suggested that the N&#8208;bridged NiFe sites with an appropriate distance between Ni and Fe atoms can exert a more pronounced synergy. It not only regulated the suitable adsorption strength for the *COOH intermediate but also promoted the desorption of *CO, thus accelerating the CO2 electroreduction to CO. This work provides an important implication for the enhancement of catalysis by the tailoring of the coordination structure of DACs, with the identification of distance effect between neighboring dual atoms.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Jia Li, Xiaoli Pan, Ning Li, Zhounan Yu, Li Wang, Tianyi Ma, Sen Lin, Jian Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Inter&#8208;Metal Interaction between Ni and Fe Atoms in Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts to Boost CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411543</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Jia Li, Xiaoli Pan, Ning Li, Zhounan Yu, Li Wang, Tianyi Ma, Sen Lin, Jian Lin, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401421250

                Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) are promising for applications in electrochemical CO2 reduction due to the enhanced flexibility of the catalytic sites and the synergistic effect between dual atoms. However, precisely controlling the atomic distance and identifying the dual&#8208;atom configuration of DACs to optimize the catalytic performance remains a challenge. Here, the Ni and Fe atomic pairs were constructed on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon support in three different configurations: NiFe&#8208;isolate, NiFe&#8208;N bridge, and NiFe bonding. It was found that the NiFe&#8208;N bridge catalyst with NiN4 and FeN4 sharing two N atoms exhibited superior CO2 reduction activity and promising stability when compared to the NiFe&#8208;isolate and NiFe&#8208;bonding catalysts. A series of characterizations and density functional theory calculations suggested that the N&#8208;bridged NiFe sites with an appropriate distance between Ni and Fe atoms can exert a more pronounced synergy. It not only regulated the suitable adsorption strength for the *COOH intermediate but also promoted the desorption of *CO, thus accelerating the CO2 electroreduction to CO. This work provides an important implication for the enhancement of catalysis by the tailoring of the coordination structure of DACs, with the identification of distance effect between neighboring dual atoms.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Jia Li, Xiaoli Pan, Ning Li, Zhounan Yu, Li Wang, Tianyi Ma, Sen Lin, Jian Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Product Selectivity of Single-Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Beyond CO Formation by Orbital Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02650k</link>
      <description>Vasanthapandiyan Mari, Naiwrit Karmodak, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401461304

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction (CO2R) is one of the promising strategies for developing sustainable energy resources. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have emerged as efficient catalysts for CO2R. However, the efficiency of SACs...</description>
      <author>Vasanthapandiyan Mari, Naiwrit Karmodak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02650k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking CO2 emissions in East Asia Pacific-5 countries: Exploring the dynamics relationships among economic growth, foreign direct investment, trade openness, financial development and energy consumption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i8.5639</link>
      <description>Happy Febrina Hariyani, Dani Galih Prasetyo, Taemin Ha, Bich Ha Dam, Tran Thai Ha Nguyen, Journal of Infrastructure Policy and Development. 8(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401432095

                The increase in world carbon emissions is always in line with national economic growth programs, which create negative environmental externalities. To understand the effectiveness of related factors in mitigating CO2 emissions, this study investigates the intricate relationship among macro-pillars such as economic growth, foreign investment, trade and finance, energy, and renewable energy with CO2 emissions of the high gross domestic product economies in East Asia Pacific, such as China, Japan, Korea, Australia and Indonesia (EAP-5). Through the application of the Vector Error Correction Model (VECM), this research reveals the long-term equilibrium and short-term dynamics between CO2 emissions and selected factors from 1991 to 2020. The long-term cointegration vector test results show that economic growth and foreign investment contribute to carbon reduction. Meanwhile, the short-term Granger causality test shows that economic growth has a two-way causality towards carbon emissions, while energy consumption and renewable energy consumption have a one-way causality towards carbon emissions. In contrast, the variables trade, foreign direct investment, and domestic credit to the private sector do not have two-way causality towards CO2 emissions. The findings reveal that economic growth and foreign investment play significant roles in carbon reduction, which are observed in long-term causality relationships, while energy consumption and renewable energy are notable factors. Thus, the study offers implications for mitigating environmental concerns on national economic growth agendas by scrutinizing and examining the efficacy of related factors.</description>
      <author>Happy Febrina Hariyani, Dani Galih Prasetyo, Taemin Ha, Bich Ha Dam, Tran Thai Ha Nguyen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i8.5639</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antimicrobial activity of laser assisted endodontic therapy in disinfecting root canals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6026/973206300200610</link>
      <description>Shivam Patel, Harpreet Hundal, Geeta Nishad, Nityanand Shetty, Vinita Banjare, Jyotsna Sethumadhavan, Ramanpal Singh Makkad, Anushree Tiwari, Bioinformation. 20(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401366283

                Light Amplified Stimulated Emission of Radiation (LASER) is nowadays widely studied regarding their use in endodontics and restorative dentistry. Therefore, it is of interest to evaluate the antibacterial activity of three types of LASERs namely CO2 LASER.Er, Cr:YSGG LASER and Diode LASER in disinfection of root canals. 70 patients (105 single rooted teeth) were included in the study. There was application of 2% Sodium Hypochlorite (NaOCl), 2780 nm Er,Cr:YSGG LASER, 900 nm Diode LASER and CO2 LASER. Microbial samples were collected from root canals both before and after the interventions through paper points. These parameters were evaluated in microbiology laboratory to obtain Log10 Colony Forming Units (CFUs). There was significant reduction in CFUs of microorganisms inside root canal in all three LASERs evaluated and NaOCl. The reduction in CFUs in LASERs was comparable to NaOCl. Then secondly we applied each LASER in combination with NaOCl. It was observed that reduction in CFU was greater when combination of LASER with NaOCl was applied as compared when applied alone. It can be inferred that LASER when applied with NaOCl can have significant role in disinfection of root canals.</description>
      <author>Shivam Patel, Harpreet Hundal, Geeta Nishad, Nityanand Shetty, Vinita Banjare, Jyotsna Sethumadhavan, Ramanpal Singh Makkad, Anushree Tiwari</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6026/973206300200610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Geochemical Monitoring Technologies for CO2 Geological Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166784</link>
      <description>Jianhua Ma, Yongzhang Zhou, Yijun Zheng, Lixiang He, Hanyu Wang, L. L. Niu, Xinhui Yu, Wei Cao, Sustainability. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401418288

                CO2 geological storage, as a large-scale, low-cost, carbon reduction technology, has garnered widespread attention due to its safety. Monitoring potential leaks is critical to ensuring the safety of the carbon storage system. Geochemical monitoring employs methods such as gas monitoring, groundwater monitoring, tracer monitoring, and isotope monitoring to analyze the reservoir&#8217;s storage state and secondary changes after a CO2 injection. This paper summarizes the recent applications and limitations of geochemical monitoring technologies in CO2 geological storage. In gas monitoring, the combined monitoring of multiple surface gasses can analyze potential gas sources in the storage area. In water monitoring, pH and conductivity measurements are the most direct, while ion composition monitoring methods are emerging. In tracer monitoring, although artificial tracers are effective, the environmental compatibility of natural tracers provides them with greater development potential. In isotope monitoring, C and O isotopes can effectively reveal gas sources. Future CO2 geological storage project monitoring should integrate various monitoring methods to comprehensively assess the risk and sources of CO2 leakage. The incorporation of artificial intelligence, machine learning technologies, and IoT monitoring will significantly enhance the accuracy and intelligence of numerical simulations and baseline monitoring, ensuring the long-term safety and sustainability of CO2 geological storage projects.</description>
      <author>Jianhua Ma, Yongzhang Zhou, Yijun Zheng, Lixiang He, Hanyu Wang, L. L. Niu, Xinhui Yu, Wei Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Calibration and CO2 Plume Tracking at the Illinois Basin Decatur Project: A Dynamic Mode Decomposition and Data Assimilation Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221411-ms</link>
      <description>Omeke James, Kassem Alokla, Dimitrios Voulanas, Eduardo Gildin, No host. 175(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401349270

                Abstract Addressing climate change through carbon capture and storage (CCS) technologies necessitates advanced computational methodologies for subsurface CO2 storage monitoring. This study focuses on the Illinois Basin Decatur Project (IBDP), a CCS demonstration pilot aimed at CO2 injection into a deep saline reservoir. We introduce a novel framework combining Dynamic Mode Decomposition (DMD), a data-driven model reduction technique, with direct data assimilation to streamline the calibration of CO2 plume evolution models. This approach enhances rapid tracking and overcomes the computational challenges of traditional high-fidelity numerical reservoir simulations known as the full-order model (FOM). Using DMD, we analyzed five distinct FOM simulation cases of the IBDP with varied permeability in the Mt. Simon section to develop reduced-order models (ROMs). These ROMs utilize three state variables: reservoir pressure, CO2 plume saturation, and bottom-hole pressure (BHP) from a CO2 injection well alongside multi-level pressures from a monitoring well derived from the FOM and the actual field data respectively. Initial FOM simulation cases assessed the impact of permeability multipliers on pressure responses. We then transformed these into ROMs using DMD, preserving essential dynamics. Linear interpolation between permeabilities and DMD outputs&#8212;modes and eigenvalues&#8212;established relationships for rapid BHP prediction under different scenarios. Employing a Kalman filter, we optimized a global permeability multiplier, using the ROMs, to align measured and simulated BHP values, ensuring model calibration. The final calibrated FOM was further decomposed to a DMD-based ROM, enabling quick, accurate predictions, significantly reducing computational time from hours to minutes. Utilizing an ROM derived through DMD, we achieved an order of 160 reduction in computational time (from 8 hours to just 3 minutes) for a 3-year historical CO2 injection period modeled with 547,000 cells of the FOM. The ROM demonstrated remarkable fidelity, with a mean absolute error of 1.46 psi for pressure and 3.7e-05 for CO2 plume saturation, effectively capturing the dynamics of the full-order model. This substantial decrease in computational time illustrates an advantageous trade-off between speed and accuracy, optimizing the potential for long-term forecasting and monitoring of CO2 sequestration. Incorporating the IBDP as a case study, this research contributes a significant advancement to reservoir simulation practices, offering a potent, efficient tool for CCS monitoring. By integrating DMD for ROM construction with precise data assimilation-based calibration, the study provides a comprehensive solution for swift and accurate subsurface CO2 plume tracking, essential for the successful implementation of CCS projects and the broader effort to mitigate climate change impacts.</description>
      <author>Omeke James, Kassem Alokla, Dimitrios Voulanas, Eduardo Gildin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221411-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducerea impactului negativ al CO2 asupra mediului &#537;i promovarea unui model sustenabil de activitate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53486/sstc.v3.36</link>
      <description>M&#259;d&#259;lina Tonu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401313551

                In recent years, issues related to climate change and the negative impact of greenhouse gas emissions on the environment have become increasingly acute, attracting the attention of governments, non-governmental organizations, and the international community as a whole. Now more than ever, the development of sustainable models of activity is necessary to reduce the negative impact of CO2 on the environment and to promote sustainable development. Transport is one of the biggest polluters and We think that we can change it. Reducing transport emissions can significantly contribute to achieving greenhouse gas reduction targets. In this regard, public transportation is much more energy-efficient than individual cars and can significantly reduce CO2 emissions. Additionally, promoting the use of eco-friendly modes of transportation, such as bicycles or electric vehicles, can also contribute to reducing transport emissions. Promoting sustainable transport can be an effective solution to reducing the negative impact of CO2 on the environment and creating a sustainable model of activity. If we want a better life for us and our future generations, we must know and promote a policy that will reduce the emissions of CO2 and will transform our planet into a better place.</description>
      <author>M&#259;d&#259;lina Tonu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53486/sstc.v3.36</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Optimization of Aerobic Bacteria Inactivation in Tilapia (Oreochromis niloticus) Fillets using Micro-Nano Bubbles of Carbon Dioxide and Shelf-Life Extension</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14416/j.asep.2024.08.002</link>
      <description>Pattama Naewkanya, Anurak Petiraksakul, Applied Science and Engineering Progress. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401344184

                This study aims to examine the influence of NaOCl, NaCl and contact time on the inactivation of aerobic bacteria in tilapia fillets treated with micro-nano bubbles of CO2 (CO2 MNB) in a washing process of fish fillets, and compared to soaking with tap water and untreated fillets for their shelf-life extensions. Response surface methodology (RSM) with a central composite design was used to compare and predict of the inactivation effects. The fish fillets were soaked in a NaOCl solution before washing with a NaCl solution and CO2 MNB produced from an MNB generator system, maintaining the liquid temperature in the range of 4&#8211;7 &#176;C for all experiments. According to the regression analysis from the experimental design, aerobic bacteria inactivation was reduced by 1.509 log CFU/g at 100 mg/L NaOCl, 10%w/v NaCl, and a contact time of 32 min with CO2 MNB. The experimental value of the reduction of aerobic bacteria by 1.503 &#177; 0.009 log CFU/g (before washing 5.623 log CFU/g; after washing 4.120 log CFU/g) was found after treatment under the aforementioned condition. The number of aerobic bacteria counted on the tilapia fillets treated with the upper condition after being stored at 4 &#177; 2 &#176;C for 7 d was below the acceptable limits, but untreated and treated with tap water had bacteria counts exceeding the upper microbial limit (6 log CFU/g). The combined results showed that the NaOCl, NaCl solution and CO2 MNB treatment could extend the storage time by more than 7 d.</description>
      <author>Pattama Naewkanya, Anurak Petiraksakul</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14416/j.asep.2024.08.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Study on CO2 Flooding Characteristic in Low-Permeability Sandstone Considering the Influence of In-Situ Stress</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/223076-pa</link>
      <description>Tong Zhang, Mingcheng Zhu, Guoliang Zhou, Jun Wu, Xin Yang, Ruilong Li, SPE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401411447

                Summary The pore network controlled by in-situ stress significantly influences the CO2 flooding in low-permeability reservoirs. In this study, the CO2/oil distribution and response of pore structure were monitored online using low-field nuclear magnetic resonance (LF-NMR), and the in-situ stress dependence of oil recovery was analyzed. The results show that the pore structure consists of adsorption pore (AP &amp;lt; 1 millisecond), percolation pore (1 millisecond &amp;lt; PP &amp;lt; 10 milliseconds), and migration pore (10 milliseconds &amp;lt; MP). Oil recovery was primarily influenced by AP and MP at lower in-situ stress, while PP and MP are the main contributors at higher in-situ stress. The matrix experienced compression deformation, microfracture generation, and shrinkage of pore, combined with an increase and followed by a decrease in oil recovery, responding to the increase of in-situ stress from 5 MPa to 15 MPa and from 15 MPa to 20 MPa. The reduction in gas channels promotes a piston-like advancement of oil displacement, resulting in an initial increase in oil recovery, while subsequent decline is linked to heightened pore heterogeneity caused by high in-situ stress. Increased heterogeneity reduces gas displacement stability, hampers CO2 sweep efficiency, and results in a granular distribution of residual oil. The findings provide insight on CO2-enhanced oil recovery (EOR) in low-permeability reservoirs.</description>
      <author>Tong Zhang, Mingcheng Zhu, Guoliang Zhou, Jun Wu, Xin Yang, Ruilong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/223076-pa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Study on Optimization of Combustion Cycle Parameters and Exhaust Gas Emissions in Marine Dual-Fuel Engines by Adjusting Ammonia Injection Phases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12081340</link>
      <description>Martynas Drazdauskas, Serg&#279;jus Lebedevas, Journal of Marine Science and Engineering. 12(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401391371

                Decarbonizing maritime transport hinges on transitioning oil-fueled ships (98.4% of the fleet) to renewable and low-carbon fuel types. This shift is crucial for meeting the greenhouse gas (GHG) reduction targets set by the IMO and the EU, with the aim of achieving climate neutrality by 2050. Ammonia, which does not contain carbon atoms that generate CO2, is considered one of the effective solutions for decarbonization in the medium and long term. However, the concurrent increase in nitrogen oxide (NOx) emissions during the ammonia combustion cycle, subject to strict regulation by the MARPOL 73/78 convention, necessitates implementing solutions to reduce them through optimizing the combustion cycle. This publication presents a numerical study on the optimization of diesel and ammonia injection phases in a ship&#8217;s medium-speed engine, Wartsila 6L46. The study investigates the exhaust gas emissions and combustion cycle parameters through a high-pressure injection strategy. At an identified 7&#176; CAD injection phase distance between diesel and ammonia, along with an optimal dual-fuel start of injection 10&#176; CAD before TDC, a reduction of 47% in greenhouse gas emissions (GHG = CO2 + CH4 + N2O) was achieved compared to the diesel combustion cycle. This result aligns with the GHG reduction target set by both the IMO and the EU for 2030. Additionally, during the investigation of the thermodynamic combustion characteristics of the cycle, a comparative reduction in NOx of 4.6% was realized. This reduction is linked to the DeNOx process, where the decrease in NOx is offset by an increase in N2O. However, the optimized ammonia combustion cycle results in significant emissions of unburnt NH3, reaching 1.5 g/kWh. In summary, optimizing the combustion cycle of dual ammonia and diesel fuel is essential for achieving efficient and reliable engine performance. Balancing combustion efficiency with emission levels of greenhouse gases, unburned NH3, and NOx is crucial. For the Wartsila 6L46 marine diesel engine, the recommended injection phasing is A710/D717, with a 7&#176; CAD between injection phases.</description>
      <author>Martynas Drazdauskas, Serg&#279;jus Lebedevas</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12081340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of Compressibility and Other Thermodynamic Derivative Properties of CO2 Using Sonic Velocity for CCS and Enhanced Geothermal Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221413-ms</link>
      <description>Ram R. Ratnakar, No host. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401349083

                Abstract Reduction in Carbon-footprint has been gaining attention in variety of industries from manufacturing to energy due to the geopolitical pressures and climate related issues. Carbon capture and storage (CCS) and enhanced geothermal systems using CO2 as energy carrier are some of the possible decarbonization pathways. Process design for these options requires accurate estimation of thermochemical properties of CO2 at various temperature/pressure conditions, in both subcritical and supercritical regions. The objective of this work is to present coupled experimental- and equation-of-state (EOS) modeling based on general framework to estimate heat capacities, enthalpy, entropy, sonic velocity, density, Joule-Thomson coefficient, and compressibility of CO2 that is applicable to wide range of pressure and temperature conditions. The sonic velocity measurement is based on a pulse-echo technique while the density measurements were performed in a PVT cell. The subject measurements were conducted at two temperatures (300 and 311K), one below and the other one being above the critical temperature of CO2 (304K). The pressure points for the measurements range between 1 - 200 bar. Phase behavior is modeled using Peng and Robinson (1976, 1978) Equation of State (PR78-EOS) with Peneloux et al. (1982) volume-shift shift to accurately determine the CO2 density. First, the ideal part of the CO2 heat capacity is obtained from correlations available in literature and the residual part is obtained using the EOS. After evaluation of the heat capacities, enthalpy, entropy, speed of sound, Joule-Thomson coefficient and compressibility are directly obtained from EOS. This work presents experimental and modeling results on sonic velocity and density of CO2 at two different temperatures (300 and 311K) within the pressure range of 1- 200 bar. An EOS-based framework, utilizing PR78 with Peneloux et al. volume shift, is developed to determine the CO2 properties (such as phase boundary, density, heat capacities, enthalpy, entropy, sonic velocity and compressibility) at extended pressure and temperature conditions. The main results of this study are as follows: Experimental results on density and sonic velocity are aligned with the measured data found in the literature.Estimation of the CO2 properties from EOS-based framework agrees very well with the literature and newly presented data within, all within 1-3% relative error.Compressibility of the fluid is derived directly from the experimental measurements, bypassing the density-derivative-based approach and hence avoiding the significant errors associated with the discrete density data containing noise/fluctuations and as well as the nature of the compressibility being a derivative property.Most importantly, the framework is general, and applicable for the use of other EOS models, and can also be extended to other fluid systems. Novelty of this work lies in new experimental data on sonic velocity and density of CO2 (especially at high pressures) as well as development of an EOS-framework to determine thermodynamic properties of CO2 through sonic velocity. Proposed framework leads to more accurate estimation of compressibility, density, sonic velocity, heat capacities, enthalpy and entropy.</description>
      <author>Ram R. Ratnakar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221413-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most of the Long-Term Solar Radiation Forcing on the Climate Is Due to the Strong Feedback Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30564/jees.v6i3.6502</link>
      <description>H. I. Abdussamatov, Journal of Environmental &amp; Earth Sciences. 6(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401301309

                The main interactions of the Total Solar Irradiance (TSI) variations with the climatic system are considered. This research introduced new physically based indexes for 11-year cycles: the integral relative energetic power of the cycles solar activity (SA) and TSI, as well as the cycle-weighted mean value both of the TSI and sunspot number. The observed cycle-average TSI value in cycles XXII&#8211;XXIV has decreased by more than 0.5 W/m2, indicating its quasi-bicentennial decline. The onset of the Maunder-type Grand minimum phase of the SA and TSI of the quasi-bicentennial cycle (BCC) is expected in the 27th or 28th 11-year cycle in 2042 or 2053. The Earth's thermal inertia will cause a temperature reduction of around 0.25 K due to the deficit in TSI during the declining phase of the bicentennial cycle due to its negative impact on Earth's energy imbalance. As a result, the Bond's albedo will increase, and the abundance of atmospheric water vapor and carbon dioxide will decrease as a response to a direct solar forcing. BCC feedback mechanisms will also continue operating during both its minimum and maximum phases. The feedback mechanisms will continue further in short periods (about 30 years) at the beginning of BCC's growth and decline phases. These long-term self-reinforcing feedback effects will act as a response to the TSI, forcing in such a way as to trigger a strong amplification of the initial direct input to the corresponding temperature changes. They will lead to a significant increasing cooling in 2070 or 2080. Variations of the galactic cosmic rays and cloud cover practically do not affect the climate. The quasi-bicentennial cyclicity of the TSI also provides simultaneous climate variations on all Solar system planets.</description>
      <author>H. I. Abdussamatov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30564/jees.v6i3.6502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Design of Intensified Towers for CO2 Capture with Internal, Printed Heat Exchangers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.123118</link>
      <description>Stephen Summits, Paul Akula, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456246

                Solvent-based carbon capture processes typically suffer from the temperature rise of the solvent due to the heat of absorption of CO2. This increased temperature is not thermodynamically favorable and results in a significant reduction in performance in the absorber column. As opposed to interstage coolers, which only remove, cool, and return the solvent at discrete locations in the column, internal coolers that are integrated with the packing can cool the process inline, which can result in improved efficiency. This work presents the modeling of these internal coolers within an existing generic, equation-oriented absorber column model that can cool the process while allowing for simultaneous mass transfer. Optimization of this model is also performed, which is capable of optimally choosing the best locations to place these devices, such that heat removal and mass transfer area are balanced. Results of the optimization have shown that optimally placed cooling elements result in a significant increase in the capture efficiency of the process, compared to a similar column with no internal cooling, with a common trend being the cooling of the column in the temperature bulge region. It is observed that by optimally placing an internal cooler, the solvent flow rate can be decreased, and the CO2 lean loading can be increased while still maintaining the same efficiency. These process changes can lead to a substantial reduction in costs due to lower reboiler duty.</description>
      <author>Stephen Summits, Paul Akula, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.123118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioaugmentation by enriched hydrogenotrophic methanogens into trickle bed reactors for H2/CO2 conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131225</link>
      <description>Feng L&#252;, Thea Os Andersen, Live Heldal Hagen, Begum Bilgic, Svein Jarle Horn, Bioresource Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326300

                Biomethanation represents a promising approach for biomethane production, with biofilm-based processes like trickle bed reactors (TBRs) being among the most efficient solutions. However, maintaining stable performance can be challenging, and both pure and mixed culture approaches have been applied to address this. In this study, inocula enriched with hydrogenotrophic methanogens were introduced to to TBRs as bioaugmentation strategy to assess their impacts on the process performance and microbial community dynamics. Metagenomic analysis revealed a metagenome-assembled genome belonging to the hydrogenotrophic genus Methanobacterium, which became dominant during enrichment and successfully colonized the TBR biofilm after bioaugmentation. The TBRs achieved a biogas production with &gt; 96 % methane. The bioaugmented reactor consumed additional H2. This may be due to microbial species utilizing CO2 and H2 via various CO2 reduction pathways. Overall, implementing bioaugmentation in TBRs showed potential for establishing targeted species, although challenges remain in managing H2 consumption and optimizing microbial interactions.</description>
      <author>Feng L&#252;, Thea Os Andersen, Live Heldal Hagen, Begum Bilgic, Svein Jarle Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiphase fluid-rock interactions and flow behaviors in shale nanopores: A comprehensive review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.earscirev.2024.104884</link>
      <description>Wei Wei, Xiu Mei Jiao, Han Wang, Wei Xing Zheng, Yuxuan Xia, Earth-Science Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401305501

                The complicated flow behaviors of multiphase fluids in shale reservoirs are significantly influenced by fluid-fluid and fluid-rock interactions due to the non-negligible intermolecular forces at the nanoscale, which is crucial for the effective development and efficient extraction of shale oil. The complexity of multiphase fluid distribution and flow behaviors in shale reservoirs is further increased by low porosity, low permeability, poor connectivity, high inhomogeneity, and multi-component minerals, making the development process more challenging. Molecular dynamics simulation is widely to precisely capture the intermolecular forces and effectively explain the complex distribution and flow behaviors of these fluids under fluid-fluid and fluid-rock interaction forces. In this review, the characteristics of mineral composition, pore structure, porosity, permeability, and fluid types are first elaborated to illustrate the particularity of shale reservoirs and fluids compared to conventional scale reservoirs. The results show that shale minerals are composed of inorganic and organic matter with extremely low porosity and permeability, and nanoscale pore size, in which the complicated oil-water-CO2 multiphase fluid types are caused by the primary underground water, fracturing water and injected CO2. The research progress of molecular simulation on the fluid-fluid and fluid-rock interaction mechanisms and on multiphase shale fluids flow behaviors are then reviewed in detail. The strong intermolecular interaction forces can result in the different occurrence states of fluids, the fluid-fluid interfacial slip, the fluid-rock boundary slip and heterogeneous fluid viscosity/density, significantly exacerbating the complexity of fluids flow. Meanwhile, the injected CO2 in the formation becomes a supercritical state with high diffusivity and strong solubility, and causes oil expansion, density and viscosity reduction, interfacial tension reduction, wettability alteration and molecular diffusion, which effectively replaces adsorbed hydrocarbon components by competitive adsorption behaviors, and promotes oil flow. The challenges and outlook of molecular simulation research and upscaling applications are finally discussed. This review aims to provide a microscopic understanding of the distribution characteristics and flow behaviors of multiphase shale fluids in nanoconfined space for both unconventional oil and gas researchers and industry professionals.</description>
      <author>Wei Wei, Xiu Mei Jiao, Han Wang, Wei Xing Zheng, Yuxuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.earscirev.2024.104884</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Waste Management Performance in Pariaman City Using Life Cycle Assessment (LCA)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24036/cived.v10i3.326</link>
      <description>Dyah Paramita, Rizki Aziz, Shinta Indah, CIVED. 10(3)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4401373126

                Pariaman City's waste generation in 2022 is 38.26 tons/day. Waste management in Pariaman City is still not optimal, resulting in waste piling up in TPA South Tungkal. The waste reduction value at the research location after processing with BSF larvae can reduce 0.005 tons/day or 0.02% of the total waste generation in Pariaman City. The environmental impacts in waste management studied are Global Warming Potential (GWP), Acidification Potential (AP), and Eutrophication Potential (EP). Reducing the environmental impact of processing organic waste has been carried out, the smallest impact reduction results were obtained, namely in scenario 1, namely processing organic waste with BSF larvae in waste banks and TPS 3R. The results obtained were the impact characterization value from comparing several impact categories. GWP value 32,060,838.136 103 kg CO2-eq, AP 0.00246 x103 SO2-eq, and EP 0.00134 x103 kg PO4-3. So it can be concluded that scenario 1 has a smaller GWP, AP, and EP impact on the environment compared to scenario 0 and is used as the best alternative scenario for waste management in Pariaman City</description>
      <author>Dyah Paramita, Rizki Aziz, Shinta Indah</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24036/cived.v10i3.326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Assessment of End-Of-Life Wells and Fields for Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS) Suitability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/219642-ms</link>
      <description>Edward Hoskin, S. Mahyildin, M. Crookes, No host. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401407878

                Abstract In the coming decades many thousands of fields and tens of thousands of wells globally will reach the end of their commercial life due to dwindling production rates and will need to be decommissioned at a substantial cost. The scale of the task can be appreciated by considering that in Southeast Asia alone, it is forecast that approximately 1,500 platforms and over 7,000 wells are projected to need decommissioning by 2030 with costs estimated to range from $30 billion to as high as $100 billion (Evans, 2019). At the same time as the backlog for decommissioning grows, CO2 concentrations in the atmosphere continue to increase (www.co2.earth/daily-co2) without viable at-scale alternatives to eliminate fossil fuel use for the foreseeable future. Since governments world-wide (Carver, 2021) have committed to net zero targets or substantial reductions in CO2 emissions in the coming decades, there is a pressing need to address how to maintain use of fossils fuels (in countries and for activities for which there are no alternatives) while at the same time reducing or maintaining atmospheric CO2 concentrations at existing levels (12 countries have passed legislation on net zero targets and over 190 countries signed the Paris Agreement, a legally binding international treaty on climate change reached at COP21 in 2015, including all ASEAN nations). While the process of reducing or removing CO2 emissions from various sources is not straightforward for any country, there are a convergence of challenges faced by ASEAN nations. In the last two decades, a time of rapid economic development, renewable energy sources have not gained ground on fossil fuels in the overall total energy consumption of ASEAN nations (The World Bank, 2024) and data show a decrease in ratio of renewable energy generated compared to total energy consumed. Although the share of electricity generated from renewable sources increased from 2015 to 2020 it was insufficient to offset the increased fossil fuel use in transport and industry sectors (Lau, 2022). The slow increase in renewable energy generation can be partly attributed to sustainability concerns with both hydropower and bioenergy in ASEAN, for example, the over-damming of the Mekong River and the clearing of rainforest in Borneo (Lau, 2022). Furthermore, the deployment of other effective methods of renewable energy generation such as wind turbines and solar panels are less well suited to ASEAN countries. Minimum windspeeds across much of the region fall below the 4 m/s threshold level for efficient use of a wind turbine, except for coastal areas around Philippines and Vietnam where wind speeds are higher (Lau, 2022). Solar is rated as a moderate potential renewable source, with other parts of Asia rated higher, (Lau, 2022) but it requires a significant landmass to make a meaningful contribution, which is not available due to the dense population in ASEAN. Lau, 2022, assessed that it is unlikely that renewable energies will replace energy generated from fossil fuels within the 2030&#8211;2050 timeframe and fossil fuels will remain an important part of the energy mix requiring ASEAN countries to adopt strategies and technologies to mitigate CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Edward Hoskin, S. Mahyildin, M. Crookes</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/219642-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental impact assessment in the Caspian region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32454/0016-7762-2024-66-2-124-140</link>
      <description>Elnur Aliyev, V. Yu. Kerimov, Yu. &#1040;. Lobanov, Proceedings of higher educational establishments Geology and Exploration. 66(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401399031

                Background. The current state and pressures associated with the anthropogenic impact on the Caspian region environment are examined. Surrounded by five coastal countries, including the Republic of Azerbaijan, the Russian Federation, the Republic of Kazakhstan, Turkmenistan, and the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Caspian Sea is the world&#8217;s largest endorheic water body. The isolation of the Caspian Sea, which is characterized by special climatic conditions and salinity gradients, has led to the formation of a unique ecosystem. Aim. Environmental impact assessment of the Caspian region and the associated anthropogenetic load. Materials and methods. The anthropogenic processes affecting the environment of the Caspian Sea and the surrounding area were assessed using the DPSIR concept. This concept includes the components of driving forces, pressures, state, impacts, and response in order to inclusively determine the connections between human activities and the environment. This concept was used as by the European Environmental Agency as the basis for integrated environmental analysis. Results. The conducted study determined the scale and geography of greenhouse gas degassing, the volume of pollutant emissions into the atmosphere by components, the structure of greenhouse gas emissions, and the dynamics of emissions of carbon dioxide, methane, and nitrogen oxide generated from stationary sources in the Caspian region. Anthropogenic emissions of greenhouse gases that pollute the atmosphere and sea waters, generated from stationary sources, are formed as a result of the production activities of a number of industries: mining; electricity, gas, and steam generation; air conditioning; manufacturing; water supply; wastewater treatment; construction industry; agriculture and forestry; transport storage and communications; repair of vehicles and motorcycles; as well as other activities. Conclusion. The share of enterprises in the fuel and energy complex that emit greenhouse gases is about 60%. The structure of greenhouse gas emissions and the dynamics of CO 2 , CH 4 , and N 2 O emissions generated from stationary sources in the Caspian region are shown. The Caspian Sea is one of the most important endorheic basins in the world. Being surrounded by land on all sides, the Caspian Sea lacks flows that would maintain its self-purification. Pollutants that enter the Sea remain there due to the lack of mechanisms for their removal. Complete information about the level of pollutant inputs is crucial for selecting the most effective means of environmental compensation or pollution reduction. The largest polluting sectors are agriculture, industry, including oil and gas, and urbanization.</description>
      <author>Elnur Aliyev, V. Yu. Kerimov, Yu. &#1040;. Lobanov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32454/0016-7762-2024-66-2-124-140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LPG-Diesel Dual Fuel Emission Characteristics: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47611/jsr.v13i1.2368</link>
      <description>Turki Al-Amoodi, M. A. H. Khalafalla, Samer F. Ahmed, Journal of Student Research. 13(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401325880

                The global shift away from fossil fuels for energy, driven by concerns about emissions and energy security, has sparked significant interest in alternative fuels. One promising approach involves combining alternative fuels, like Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG), with traditional diesel engines. This strategy, known as the dual-fuel concept, aims to harness the strengths of each fuel type while reducing emissions and improving engine performance. This review focuses primarily on LPG as a dual fuel for diesel engines. LPG, a gaseous fuel primarily composed of propane and butane, offers substantial environmental benefits, including a 15% reduction in CO2 emissions, a 30% reduction in CO emissions, and a 50% reduction in NOx emissions compared to diesel. However, using pure LPG in diesel engines faces a challenge related to its ignition behavior. This challenge can be overcome by blending LPG with substances like Hydrotreated Vegetable Oil (HVO) or diesel fuel, which act as ignition enhancers. The main goal of this review is to provide a comprehensive overview of the potential advantages and applicability of the dual-fuel system combining diesel and LPG. It will explore various experimental setups, designs, and injection techniques, presenting diverse findings related to both engine performance and emissions. Additionally, the review will discuss additives that can further improve the combustion process. Overall, the research highlights the promising role of LPG as a dual fuel in reducing emissions and enhancing the efficiency of diesel engines, contributing to a more sustainable energy future.</description>
      <author>Turki Al-Amoodi, M. A. H. Khalafalla, Samer F. Ahmed</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47611/jsr.v13i1.2368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Study on the Stabilization of CO2 Oil-Based Foam by a Novel Compound Surfactant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-122352</link>
      <description>Zhoujie Wang, Kaiqiang Zhang, Shaopeng Li, Jia Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401458221

                Abstract The effectiveness of CO2 oil-based foam in conventional and unconventional oil and gas development, as well as CO2 storage, relies on its stability. This study delves into the gas-liquid surface properties and liquid film behavior of a compound surfactant FS oil-based foam system, with a focus on understanding the mechanisms influencing its stability. The investigation reveals that the viscoelastic modulus of the FS surfactant system initially rises and then stabilizes with increased concentration, reaching a peak of 15.43 mN/m at 1.5 wt%. In the FS oil-based foaming system, the inhibition of sliding between liquid molecules enhances resistance to external deformation, promoting stability. Observing the liquid film of FS oil-based foam, color transitions signify evolving film thickness. The film initially displays various colors, gradually shifting from cyan and purple to deep blue and brown. As the film stratifies, forming dark domains that expand and eventually lead to rupture, FS significantly prolongs thinning time and reduces film thickness. At 2 wt% FS concentration, the foam rupture time is maximized at 4550 s. The presence of surfactant molecules forming a molecular layer in the liquid film strengthens and toughens the film, enhancing durability against external forces. This research suggests that the FS oil-based foam system with a 2 wt% concentration exhibits superior stability. Insights gained from this study contribute to the strategic use of oil-based foam, offering potential benefits for enhancing oilfield development efficiency and supporting carbon reduction goals.</description>
      <author>Zhoujie Wang, Kaiqiang Zhang, Shaopeng Li, Jia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-122352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in Sustainable Aviation Fuels: Impact of Nano-Additives and Ammonia-Based Strategies On Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4066154</link>
      <description>Pasquale Di Gloria, Maria Grazia De Giorgi, Luciano Strafella, Giuseppe Ciccarella, Grazio Gregorio Castelluzzo, Francesca Baldassarre, Antonio Ficarella, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401338365

                Abstract Our study investigates the impact of ammonia- and water-based nano-particulate additives on the combustion characteristics of Jet-A1 aviation fuel, using a 300-kW liquid swirl combustor. Experiments were conducted at two global equivalence ratios (&#934; = 0.24 and &#934; = 0.40), focusing on laminar flame speed (LFS) and flame properties through chemiluminescence imaging and modal analysis techniques. The primary objective was to understand how these nano-additives modulate flame dynamics and internal chemical reactions, alongside evaluating the environmental implications of combustion alterations. Results showed that integrating urea and water additives into the fuel matrix affected LFS, enhancing it at the lower equivalence ratio but having detrimental effects at the higher ratio. Modal analysis revealed a notable stabilizing influence on flame behavior, especially under leaner fuel conditions. The addition of water and urea influenced combustion chemistry and spray patterns, leading to more uniform sprays and more complete combustion. Chemiluminescence imaging demonstrated higher emission intensity of NH2* radicals compared to NH* radicals, varying with the global equivalence ratio. The data indicated a significant reduction in NOx emissions, particularly at lower equivalence ratios, accompanied by a slight increase in CO2 and CO emissions. This study highlights the potential of ammonia- and water-based nano-additives to enhance the combustion performance and environmental outcomes of Jet-A1 aviation fuel, with the trade-off of increased CO2 and CO emissions requiring further consideration.</description>
      <author>Pasquale Di Gloria, Maria Grazia De Giorgi, Luciano Strafella, Giuseppe Ciccarella, Grazio Gregorio Castelluzzo, Francesca Baldassarre, Antonio Ficarella</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4066154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Versatile enhancement for anaerobic moving bed biofilm (AnMBBR) treating pretreated landfill leachate by hydrochar: Energy recovery, greenhouse gas emission reduction and underlying microbial mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175161</link>
      <description>Runfeng Liao, Zi Song, Xinbo Zhang, X. Xiong, Zumin Zhang, Jianning Zhang, Feiyun Sun, The Science of The Total Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401327106

                Hydrochars were prepared from fruit peels (HC-1) and vegetable waste (HC-2), and combined with fiber spheres, respectively, to form homogeneous biocompatible carriers, which were used for anaerobic moving bed biofilm reactor (AnMBBR) to enhance anaerobic digestion (AD) performance and energy recovery of landfill leachate treatment. Compared with the control AnMBBR with conventional fiber spheres as carriers, the chemical oxygen demand (COD) removal efficiency of the AnMBBR with HC-2 increased from 75 % to 88 %, methane yield increased from 77.7 mL/g-COD to 155.3 mL/g-COD, and achieved greenhouse gases (GHG) emission reductions of 1.74 t CO2 eq/a during long-term operation. HC-2-fiber sphere biocarriers provided more sites for attached-growth biomass (AGBS) and significantly enhanced the abundance of functional microbial community, with the relative abundance of methanogenic bacteria Methanothrix increased from 0.03 % to over 24.4 %. Moreover, the gene abundance of most the key enzymes encoding the hydrolysis, acidogenesis and methanogenesis pathways were up-regulated with the assistance of HC-2. Consequently, hydrochar-assisted AnMBBR were effective to enhance methanogenesis performance, energy recovery and carbon reduction for high-strength landfill leachate treatment.</description>
      <author>Runfeng Liao, Zi Song, Xinbo Zhang, X. Xiong, Zumin Zhang, Jianning Zhang, Feiyun Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combined solar and ground source heat pump (GSHP) heating system with a latent heat storage tank (LHST), as a sustainable system to replace an oilfield hot water station</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132726</link>
      <description>Dong Li, Zeyu Wang, Yangyang Wu, Nan Yu, Xuefeng Zhao, Lan Meng, M&#252;sl&#252;m Ar&#305;c&#305;, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401284251

                Present study focuses on a clean energy replacement for an oilfield hot water station and develops a combined solar and ground source heat pump (GSHP) heating system with a latent heat storage tank (LHST). The effects of LHST and heat replenishment on energy and coefficient of performance (COP) are quantitatively analyzed during short-term or long-term operation of the system. The suitability of three different phase change materials for the system is compared, and the optimal one is identified. Results show that the LHST with 70 &#176;C melting point can increase the collector efficiency to 53.91 % and reduce the total energy consumption of the system by 52344 kWh. Heat replenishment could effectively mitigate the ground temperature drop to 0.19 &#176;C/year, reducing the annual energy consumption of GSHP by more than 4230 kWh and providing an additional thermal energy of 72 GJ. Compared to the initial heating system, the novel system efficiency increases to 51.25 %. Gas consumption and total system energy consumption decreased by 81.7 % and 75.2 %, respectively. Annual reduction of CO2 emission is about 1150 tons, showing satisfactory performance. Outcomes of this study prove the application of clean energy in oil field industrial processes, and help in achieving the goals of emission reduction and carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Dong Li, Zeyu Wang, Yangyang Wu, Nan Yu, Xuefeng Zhao, Lan Meng, M&#252;sl&#252;m Ar&#305;c&#305;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging clean technologies: policy-driven cost reductions, implications and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4696747/v1</link>
      <description>Mohamed Atouife, Jesse D. Jenkins, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401437119

                Abstract Hydrogen production from water electrolysis, direct air capture (DAC), and synthetic kerosene derived from hydrogen and CO2 ('e-kerosene') are expected to play an important role in global decarbonization efforts. So far, the economics of these nascent technologies hamper their market diffusion. However, a wave of recent policy support in the United States, Europe, China, and elsewhere is anticipated to drive their commercial liftoff and bring their costs down. To this end, we evaluate the potential cost reductions driven by policy-induced scale-up of these emerging technologies through 2030 using an experience curves approach accounting for both local and global learning effects. We then analyze the consequences of projected cost declines on the competitiveness of these nascent technologies compared to conventional fossil alternatives, where applicable, and highlight some of the tradeoffs associated with their expansion. Our findings indicate that enacted policies could lead to substantial capital cost reductions for electrolyzers. Nevertheless, electrolytic hydrogen production at \$1-2/kg would still require some form of policy support. Given expected costs and experience curves, it is unlikely that liquid solvent DAC (L-DAC) scale-up will bring removal costs to stated targets of $100/tCO2, though a $200/tCO2 may eventually be within reach. We also underscore the importance of tackling methane leakage for natural gas-powered L-DAC: unmitigated leaks amplify net removal costs, exacerbate the investment requirements to reach targeted costs, and cast doubt on the technology's role in the clean energy transition. Lastly, despite reductions in electrolysis and L-DAC costs, e-kerosene remains considerably more expensive than fossil jet fuel. The economics of e-kerosene and the resources required for production raise questions about the fuel's ultimate viability as a decarbonization tool for aviation.</description>
      <author>Mohamed Atouife, Jesse D. Jenkins</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4696747/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing The Roadmap: Feasibility Studies on CCUS Implementation In Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221664-ms</link>
      <description>M. Bassey, Innocent O. Oboh, SPE Nigeria Annual International Conference and Exhibition. 6(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401349337

                Abstract The Paris agreement in 2015 saw nations agree to a global temperature limit below 2&#176;C above pre-industrial levels. This agreement over time has come under threat as the International Energy Agency reported an increase in global emissions by 0.9%, with Africa contributing only 4% per capita to global emissions, and Nigeria, contributing 0.64 tonnes per capita of the 4%. This explicitly illustrates the imbalance when African countries, who are among the least contributors, have to deal with climate change as they reap its adverse effects. Most African countries, do, however depend on the oil industry, for not just its nations&#8217; economy, but for energy supply. This is why, in ensuring that economies are protected and energy distribution is still held tantamount while protecting the earth, technologies such as CCUS are a necessary option to be considered and incorporated into the energy sector and other heavy industries. CCUS over the years has proven to be the most feasible options for oil producing nations, particularly those with high energy needs. In this paper, the feasibilities of CCUS implementation in Nigeria is explored, its economic and policy implications that follow, in relation to the Paris Agreement in 2015 and the just concluded COP 28. The cost implications for identified sequestration locations such as Port Harcourt and Lokoja and other possible sites in the country, currently hold storage capacities of 100-1000Mt CO2, and an average abatement cost of $42/tonne. This paper explores funding measures for CCUS in-country as well as policy adjustments, utilization of captured CO2 and what this means for multinational and indigenous companies in the country and on the continent, their roles and commitments in the international community and how their investments in emission reductions in Nigeria and other African countries can be a huge step towards achieving the Paris agreement and protecting the earth.</description>
      <author>M. Bassey, Innocent O. Oboh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221664-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Carbon Emissions via Production of Blue Hydrogen and Sustainable Fertilizer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221758-ms</link>
      <description>C.I. Okoh, G. I. Maduabuchi, Emmanuella Ebere, SPE Nigeria Annual International Conference and Exhibition. 7(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401349244

                Abstract The escalating threat of climate change necessitates innovative solutions to mitigate carbon emissions. This paper addresses the challenge by proposing a groundbreaking integrated system that combines Blue Hydrogen production through Steam Methane Reforming (SMR) with Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS) and the sustainable generation of fertilizer using Chlorella Algae. The synergistic approach not only reduces carbon emissions but also fosters sustainable agriculture. The study meticulously details the methodologies employed for Blue Hydrogen production and Chlorella Algae cultivation. It explicates the chosen SMR technologies, the intricacies of Chlorella Algae cultivation, and the orchestrated synergy between the two processes, emphasizing the utilization of waste heat and CO2 from SMR for algae cultivation. The findings from this study encompasses technical feasibility, economic viability, and scalability aspects of the integrated system. The results reveal the potential for significant greenhouse gas emission reduction, validated through life cycle assessments and comparisons with conventional methods. This research projects a promising pathway for sustainable energy and agriculture and fosters sustainable practice on a global scale.</description>
      <author>C.I. Okoh, G. I. Maduabuchi, Emmanuella Ebere</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221758-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Carbon Emissions and Influencing Factors of Residents&#8217; Lives in Hebei Province</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166770</link>
      <description>Cuiling Zhang, Yang Wei-hua, Ruyan Wang, Wen Zheng, Liying Guo, Sustainability. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401418326

                The standard of living has significantly risen along with ongoing economic progress, but CO2 emissions have also been rising. The reduction in CO2 resulting from the daily activities of residents has become a crucial priority for every province. A relevant study on the carbon emissions of Hebei Province residents was conducted for this publication, aiming to provide a theoretical basis for the sustainable development of Hebei Province. The first part of the article calculates the carbon emissions of Hebei Province people from 2005 to 2020 using the emission factor method and the Consumer Lifestyle Approach (CLA). Secondly, the Logarithmic Mean Divisia Index (LMDI) decomposition approach is used to assess the components that influence both direct and indirect carbon emissions. Finally, the scenario analysis approach is employed in conjunction with the LEAP model to establish baseline, low-carbon, and ultra-low-carbon scenarios to predict the trend of residents&#8217; carbon emissions in Hebei Province from 2021 to 2040. The results show that the total carbon emissions of residents in Hebei Province from 2005 to 2020 rose, from 77.45 million tons to 153.35 million tons. Income level, energy consumption intensity, and population scale are factors that contribute to the increase in direct carbon emissions, while consumption tendency factors have a mitigating effect on direct carbon emissions. Economic level, consumption structure, and population scale factors are factors that contribute to the increase in indirect carbon emissions, while energy consumption intensity and energy structure factors have a mitigating effect on indirect carbon emissions. The prediction results show that under the baseline scenario, the cumulative residents&#8217; carbon emissions in Hebei Province will not reach a zenith from 2021 to 2040. However, under the low-carbon situation, the carbon emissions of residents in Hebei Province will peak in 2029, with a peak of 174.69 million tons, whereas under the ultra-low-carbon scenario, it will peak in 2028, with a peak of 173.27 million tons.</description>
      <author>Cuiling Zhang, Yang Wei-hua, Ruyan Wang, Wen Zheng, Liying Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-carbon wastewater treatment and resource recovery of recirculating aquaculture system by immobilized chlorella vulgaris based on machine learning optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131208</link>
      <description>Shuqian Cheng, Xiaolei Liu, Carlo Pastore, Luigi di Bitonto, Anjie Li, Bioresource Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401305169

                Immobilized microalgae biotechnologies can conserve water and space by low-carbon wastewater treatment and resource recovery in a recirculating aquaculture system (RAS). However, technical process parameters have been unoptimized considering the mutual interaction between factors. In this study, machine learning optimized the parameters of alginate-immobilized Chlorella vulgaris (C. vulgaris), that is, 474 &#956;mol/(m2&#183;s) of light intensity, 23 &#215; 106 cells/mL for initial cell number, and 2.07 mm particle size. Importantly, under continuous illumination, the immobilized C. vulgaris and microalgal-bacterial consortium improved water purification and biomass reutilization. Transcriptomics of C. vulgaris showed enhanced nitrogen removal by increasing pyridine nucleotide and lipid accumulation via enhanced triacylglycerol synthesis. Symbiotic bacteria upregulated genes for nitrate reduction and organic matter degradation, which stimulated biomass accumulation through CO2 fixation and starch synthesis. The recoverable microalgae (1.94 g/L biomass, 47 % protein, 26.23 % lipids), struvite (64.79 % phosphorus), and alginate (79.52 %) every two weeks demonstrates a low-carbon resource recovery in RAS.</description>
      <author>Shuqian Cheng, Xiaolei Liu, Carlo Pastore, Luigi di Bitonto, Anjie Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373364

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non-magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core-shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores' local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells' surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen-containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm-2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376553

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core&#8208;shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores&#8217; local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells&#8217; surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling And Simulation Of Renewable Technologies For Economic And Environmental Analysis And Optimization Of Dairy Farms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34719/tcud9414</link>
      <description>Michael Breen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401392626

                The aim of this thesis was to develop a dairy optimisation platform to optimise investments in dairy farm technology and changes to on-farm management practices and electricity tariffs, in order to maximise profitability and minimise environmental impacts. Increased dairy herd sizes and milk production levels in Ireland as well as changing regulations concerning emissions, renewable penetration and energy efficiency have necessitated a means of financial decision support for farmers. Therefore this body of work focused on the creation of a comprehensive method for optimising dairy farm technology selection, management practices and electricity tariffs. The measures which could be implemented on dairy farms to improve economic performance and reduce environmental impacts were categorised in this study under the headings of efficiency through technology adoption, efficiency through management practices, and reduction in primary energy through renewable generation. To improve efficiency through technology adoption, technologies including plate heat exchangers, variable speed drives, solar thermal water heating and heat recovery systems were considered. To improve efficiency through management practices, load shifting measures were considered. To reduce primary energy through renewable generation, photovoltaic systems and wind turbines were considered. A comprehensive optimisation method was required which took into account all measures and the relationships between them, while the conflicting goals of improving profitability and environmental performance necessitated the use of multi-objective optimisation to assess trade-offs between these goals. Moreover, to facilitate the analysis of efficiency through technology adoption, efficiency through management practices, and reduction in primary energy through Abstract xxi renewable generation, validated scalable models of energy efficient and renewable technologies were created which enabled their effect on dairy farm profitability and environmental performance to be quantified. These models were employed when carrying out multi-objective optimisation to optimise dairy farm technology, management practices and electricity tariffs for maximisation of dairy farm net profit, minimisation of farm electricity related CO2 emissions, maximisation of farm renewable contribution and optimisation of milking start times for farmers. Trade-offs between these objectives were also assessed. A test case of a 195 cow farm was employed to demonstrate the applicability and usefulness of the optimisation platform, with results indicating that farm electricity related CO2 emissions could be reduced by 40%, 3% and 31% through technology adoption, management practices and renewable generation respectively. Furthermore, the use of a plate heat exchanger was the most economically feasible technology of the technologies examined. It is anticipated that the methods presented in this thesis will be used as a comprehensive means of decision support for farm advisors, policymakers and farmers. The outputs of the thesis will enable these key stakeholders to make prudent decisions pertaining to investments in technology and farm management changes, in order to increase farm profitability and contribute to national greenhouse gas mitigation.</description>
      <author>Michael Breen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34719/tcud9414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biofuels with Carbon Capture and Storage in the United States Transportation Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.167890</link>
      <description>Caleb H. Geissler, Christos T. Maravelias, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401461015

                There is a need to drastically reduce greenhouse gas emissions. While significant progress has been made in electrifying transport, heavy duty transportation and aviation are not likely to be capable of electrification in the near term, spurring significant research into biofuels. When coupled with carbon capture and storage, biofuels can achieve net-negative greenhouse gas emissions via many different conversion technologies such as fermentation, pyrolysis, or gasification to produce ethanol, gasoline, diesel, or jet fuel. However, each pathway has a different efficiency, capital and operating costs, and potential for carbon capture, making the optimal pathway dependent on policy and spatial factors. We use the Integrated Markal-EFOM System model applied to the USA, adding a rich suite of biofuel and carbon capture technologies, region-specific CO2 transportation and injection costs, and government incentives from the Inflation Reduction Act. We find that under current government incentives, biofuels and carbon capture from biorefineries are primarily focused in the Midwest and South of the USA, but play a relatively small role in the overall USA transportation sector even in 2055. However, increased government incentives, biomass availability, or oil price could lead to increased biofuel production and reduced transportation emissions.</description>
      <author>Caleb H. Geissler, Christos T. Maravelias</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.167890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Options and Costs for Mitigating GHG Emissions from the U.S. Dairy Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15080926</link>
      <description>Yuhong Lei, Muxi Cheng, Bruce A. McCarl, Jerry Cessna, Atmosphere. 15(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401323216

                The U.S. dairy sector is a significant emitter of methane and nitrous oxide, with the US EPA estimating it produced around 90 Tg CO2 eq. in 2021. This paper reviews the literature on and evaluates various mitigation actions for reducing GHG emissions in the U.S. dairy sector, focusing on both direct and indirect emission sources. We conducted a narrative literature review based on the cradle to gate life-cycle assessment method, covering the entire dairy supply chain up until milk enters retail establishments, including dairy and feed producing farm practices, processing, transportation, and their associated emissions/costs. The papers included were selected over a three year process depending on discussions with experts and issues mentioned in the emerging literature. We review significant opportunities for the U.S. dairy sector to reduce emissions, particularly through improved enteric fermentation and manure management practices. Additionally, we cover the potential for mitigating indirect emissions from feed production, processing, and transportation, areas less frequently covered in existing studies. This review also covers a gap in the literature by integrating economic findings including cost analysis and incentives to mitigate based on the social value of emissions reductions.</description>
      <author>Yuhong Lei, Muxi Cheng, Bruce A. McCarl, Jerry Cessna</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15080926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective electroreduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; products on cobalt decorated copper catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.11</link>
      <description>Sanaz Soodi, Junjun Zhang, Jie Zhang, Yuefeng Liu, Mohsen Lashgari, Spyridon Zafeiratos, Andreas Z&#252;ttel, Kun Zhao, Wen Luo, Chemical Synthesis. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373815

                Cu-catalyzed electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to multi-carbon (C2+) products is often plagued by low selectivity because the adsorption energies of different reaction intermediates are in a linear scaling relationship. Development of Cu-based bimetallic catalysts has been considered as an attractive strategy to address this issue; however, conventional bimetallic catalysts often avoid metals with strong CO adsorption energies to prevent surface poisoning. Herein, we demonstrated that limiting the amount of Co in CuCo bimetallic catalysts can enhance C2+ product selectivity. Specifically, we synthesized a series of CuCox catalysts with trace amounts of Co (0.07-1.8 at%) decorated on the surface of Cu nanowires using a simple dip coating method. Our results revealed a volcano-shaped correlation between Co loading and C2+ selectivity, with the CuCo0.4% catalyst exhibiting a 2-fold increase in C2+ selectivity compared to the Cu nanowire sample. In situ Raman and Infrared spectroscopies suggested that an optimal amount of Co could stabilize the Cu oxide/hydroxide species under the CO2RR condition and promote the adsorption of CO, thus enhancing the C2+ selectivity. This work expands the potential for developing Cu-based bimetallic catalysts for CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Sanaz Soodi, Junjun Zhang, Jie Zhang, Yuefeng Liu, Mohsen Lashgari, Spyridon Zafeiratos, Andreas Z&#252;ttel, Kun Zhao, Wen Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Fire Safety of Energy-Saving Foam by Self-Cleavage CO2 Pre-Combustion and Phosphorus Release Post-Combustion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29153708</link>
      <description>Fengyun Sun, Li Wang, Tingting Gao, Yuanyuan Zhong, Kefa Ren, Molecules. 29(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401323812

                Rigid polyurethane foam (RPUF) is widely utilized in construction and rail transportation due to its lightweight properties and low thermal conductivity, contributing to energy conservation and emission reduction. However, the inherent flammability of RPUF presents significant challenges. Delaying the time to ignition and preventing flame spread post-combustion is crucial for ensuring sufficient evacuation time in the event of a fire. Based on this principle, this study explores the efficacy of using potassium salts as a catalyst to promote the self-cleavage of RPUF, generating substantial amounts of CO2, thereby reducing the local oxygen concentration and delaying ignition. Additionally, the inclusion of a reactive flame retardant (DFD) facilitates the release of phosphorus-oxygen free radicals during combustion, disrupting the combustion chain reaction and thus mitigating flame propagation. Moreover, potassium salt-induced catalytic carbonization and phosphorus derivative cross-linking enhance the condensed phase flame retardancy. Consequently, the combined application of potassium salts and DFD increases the limiting oxygen index (LOI) and reduces both peak heat release rate (PHRR) and total heat release (THR). Importantly, the incorporation of these additives does not compromise the compressive strength or thermal insulation performance of RPUF. This integrated approach offers a new and effective strategy for the development of flame retardant RPUF.</description>
      <author>Fengyun Sun, Li Wang, Tingting Gao, Yuanyuan Zhong, Kefa Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29153708</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes in the Properties of Green Concrete Due to an Acidic Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18517/ijaseit.14.4.17495</link>
      <description>Irma Aswani Ahmad, Noor Fadilah Romadhani, Muhammad Idhil Maming, International Journal on Advanced Science Engineering and Information Technology. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401300351

                The problem in this research is the negative environmental impact of cement production and the decrease in concrete durability due to acid rain. This research aims to create an equation for the relationship between concrete's mechanical properties and the concrete's age in an acidic environment. This equation is used to predict the quality of green concrete produced according to the mix design and to measure the reduction in strength of green concrete in an acidic environment. The method used is experimental research with wet-dry acid rain simulations (a mixture of sulfuric acid and nitric acid solutions) in the laboratory using rice husk ash (RHA) as a cement substitute. This research uses 5% and 10% of RHA variations of cement weight and immersion in pH3 and pH4 acid solutions. The results showed that adding 5% RHA increased the compressive and flexural strength of concrete, both in normal and acidic environments, with a significant increase in concrete life up to 120 days. However, the addition of 10% RHA showed decreased performance in acidic environments, although it still provided benefits under normal conditions. The potential environmental and sustainability benefits of using RHA as a cement substitute are significant, as it can reduce CO2 emissions, overcome waste disposal problems, and increase the durability of green concrete in acidic environments. This finding provides an environmentally friendly and sustainable solution for the construction industry, especially in areas vulnerable to acidic environments (acid rain).</description>
      <author>Irma Aswani Ahmad, Noor Fadilah Romadhani, Muhammad Idhil Maming</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18517/ijaseit.14.4.17495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Role of Lithium Carbonate at Lithium Metal Anodes Through Study of Gas-Reacted Interphases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6d92</link>
      <description>Katherine Steinberg, Betar M. Gallant, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401447826

                Abstract A stable, ionically-conductive solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) is vital to lithium (Li) metal anodes, yet key properties of common SEI phases remain unknown. Among these, Li2CO3, central to foundational SEI models, has been difficult to probe given its metastability on Li. To address this, we adopted two approaches: (i) synthesis and study of model Li2CO3-based SEI and (ii) cycling and titration-based analysis of SEI from Li&#8211;Cu cells with or without additive CO2, with the aim of modulating Li2CO3 content natively. In (i), reductive instability of Li2CO3 led to co-formation of Li2O and Li2C2 in a multiphasic film with a Li+ conductivity (~8&#215;10-9 S cm-1) more than 4x higher than previously measured Li2O or LiF films. Li2CO3 content in native interphases from (ii) was found to correlate with decreased inactive Li0 accumulation and improved Coulombic efficiency (CE) across diverse electrolytes having moderate CE. In high CE electrolytes, however, capacity losses become dominated by SEI formation rather than inactive Li0, and Li2CO3 enrichment had negligible impact. This work updates understanding of Li2CO3 in modern electrolytes, reveals a leading mechanism by which Li2CO3 can boost CE despite its metastability, and indicates the potential and limitations of enriching this phase through electrolyte design.</description>
      <author>Katherine Steinberg, Betar M. Gallant</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6d92</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valorizing Polymeric Wastes and Biomass through Optimized Co-Pyrolysis for Upgraded Pyrolysis Oil: A study on TG-FTIR and Fixed bed reactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106686</link>
      <description>Gulzeb Rajput, Bin Liu, Minhui Pan, Akash Kumar, Lata Kumari, Muhammad Zohaib Farooq, Dan Li, Fawei Lin, Longlong Ma, Journal of Analytical and Applied Pyrolysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401362519

                The co-pyrolysis of biomass and polymeric wastes offers a promising approach for waste reduction and valuable product recovery while decreasing fossil fuel dependence. This study aimed to investigate the synergistic effects of blending waste tire (WT) or polystyrene (PS) with sawdust (SD) at varying effective hydrogen/carbon ratio (H/Ceff) on liquid product distribution. Thermal degradation behavior was analyzed using TGA-FTIR, followed by fixed-bed reactor pyrolysis experiments at different temperatures. The devolatilization of SD primarily occurred between 185 and 390&#176;C, while WT and PS decomposed between 250-500&#176;C and 350-460&#176;C, respectively. Results showed that SD addition to WT accelerated degradation at lower temperatures. Optimal H/Ceff ratios were 0.42 for WT/SD and 0.64 for PS/SD blends at 500&#176;C, maximizing valued hydrocarbons, reducing pollutants, and yielding the highest liquid fraction. TGA-FTIR analysis revealed the presence of various functional groups, including C-H, C=C, CO2, and O-H. The pyrolytic oil showed improved stability with significantly fewer undesired compounds. This research provides theoretical and practical insights into the control and application potential as well as the limitations of high-value energy products derived from the co-pyrolysis of SD, WT, and PS.</description>
      <author>Gulzeb Rajput, Bin Liu, Minhui Pan, Akash Kumar, Lata Kumari, Muhammad Zohaib Farooq, Dan Li, Fawei Lin, Longlong Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of modal integration for transit-access trips in motorcycle dependent cities&#8212;The case study of Hanoi, Vietnam</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i8.5351</link>
      <description>Khuat Viet Hung, An Minh Ngoc, Hoang Huu Thanh, Journal of Infrastructure Policy and Development. 8(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401317410

                Micro-mobility has the potential to address first -mile challenges, improving transit accessibility and encouraging public transit usage. However, users&#8217; acceptability of modal integration between various micro-mobility options and public transit remains largely unexplored in the literature. Our study investigates the user behavior for first-mile options, focusing on four alternatives: walking, bicycling, motorcycling, and bus, to access urban mass rapid transit (UMRT) in Hanoi, Vietnam. Based on data collected from 1380 individuals, a Nested Logit Model (NLM) was proposed to analyze the determinants of users&#8217; acceptability under each access mode option as well as evaluate further impacts of shifts in access mode choice on vehicle-kilometer traveled and emissions. The analysis shows that the availability of access modes might increase UMRT use by 47.83%. While this increase further generates additional vehicle-kilometer traveled due to the increase in park-and-ride users, this is offset overall by the large number of motorcycle users shifting to UMRT. Under the most optimistic scenario, modal integration for transit-access trips leads to an average reduction of 17.7% in net vehicle-kilometer traveled or 14.5% in net CO2 emissions or 10.9% in NOx from private vehicles. Our findings also imply that the introduction of parking fees for bicycling- or motorcycling-access trips, while impactful, does not significantly change UMRT choice. Therefore, the pricing schemes should be a focus of parking planning surrounding stations. Finally, a number of policy suggestions for parking planning and first-mile vehicles are presented.</description>
      <author>Khuat Viet Hung, An Minh Ngoc, Hoang Huu Thanh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i8.5351</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano Technolgy Application to Enhance the Emission Control by Using Activated Carbons Modified by Magnesium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52783/jes.4547</link>
      <description>Khalid Hussein Rahi, Deleted Journal. 20(9s)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401397413

                One of the fundamental processes for planet safety is the catalytic conversion of carbon monoxide (CO). CO has even been named one of the unseen toxins of this century. Inhaling CO can lead to hypoxic damage, neurological break, and even death. CO poisoning decays greenery life and accumulations in global warming and ozone layer depletion. CO is created in the atmosphere by the partial oxidation of carbon-containing mixtures. The primary origin of CO emissions is vehicles. Therefore, oxidizing contaminated CO to nonpoisonous CO2 under ambient conditions is essential for life protection in multiple applications. Additionally, low-temperature CO oxidation is crucial in reducing emissions at the cold start of an internal explosion in the engine. For controlling pollution, the available methods are pre-pollution control and post-pollution. This project depends on the post-pollution control method in Peugeot ROA automobiles using Activated Carbons Modified by Magnesium Oxide as a catalyst. An innovative catalytic converter design activated carbons modified by magnesium oxide nanoparticles as a catalyst to control pollution with different NPs lodgings and carbon structures. This proposed method aims for the reduction environmental pollution contributed by automobiles. It involves using more affordable materials than the existing rhodium nanoparticles, platinum, and palladium technique. The dispersion states of the grafted nanoparticles were examined with scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and X-ray diffraction analysis (XRD), confirming the correlation between high grafted ratio states and improved properties. The nanocomposites' desired properties were significantly enhanced when the graft density was high.</description>
      <author>Khalid Hussein Rahi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52783/jes.4547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GHG Policies in Maritime Transport: A Comparative Analysis using Cost-Effectiveness and Multi-Criteria Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4855186/v1</link>
      <description>R. Garcia, Cristiane Elia de Marsillac, Paula Carvalho Pereda, Andrea Lucchesi, Jean-David Caprace, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401407908

                Abstract Maritime transport accounts for approximately 3% of global greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions with the sector aiming to achieve net zero by or around i.e. close 2050. There has been intense debate on medium-term measures that combine regulatory frameworks with financial incentives or economic penalties. Among the main proposals under discussion are a GHG levy, two flexible mechanisms (FCMs) based on the GHG Fuel Intensity (GFI) and a feebate. Despite extensive discussions on carbon levies, there is a notable lack of studies comparing the cost-effectiveness of these different GHG reduction measures in the maritime sector. This study aims to fill this gap by developing a comprehensive methodology to evaluate and compare these GHG policies. Using cost-effectiveness and multi-criterion decision analysis (MCDA), the study assesses the technical feasibility, economic implications, and environmental benefits of the proposed measures. The main quantitative results reveal that a GHG levy starting at $100 per ton of CO2 doubles fuel costs, while new fuels become economically attractive only after 2040 under the feebate mechanism. Both original and revised FCM proposals show similar cost patterns, with the revised FCM leading to earlier adoption of new fuels. We find that the FCMs and the carbon levy are effective in achieving the IMO's final and intermediate targets. However, FCMs are the most cost-effective proposals, achieving targets with the lowest present value of costs and the cost per avoided GHG emissions. The proposed methodology provides a robust framework for facilitating objective and structured discussions with stakeholders, helping to balance economic and environmental goals in maritime policymaking.</description>
      <author>R. Garcia, Cristiane Elia de Marsillac, Paula Carvalho Pereda, Andrea Lucchesi, Jean-David Caprace</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4855186/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential For Ch4-enriched Biogas As A Transport Fuel In Ireland</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34719/vrkk7758</link>
      <description>Niamh Power, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401364246

                "Ireland needs a biofuel industry- to aid compliance with the Kyoto Protocol, the Biofuels Directive and to secure its energ&gt;' supply. The overall aim of this work is to assess the potential of CH4-enriched biogas as a transport fuel in Ireland. Biogas is produced during the anaerobic digestion of biomass. This work investigates biogas production from two different feedstocks; biodegradable municipal waste and agricultural crops. To assess the potential for biogas as a transport fuel the alternatives to biogas are investigated and compared. Thus digestion and composting of biodegradable municipal waste, and biogas and ethanol production from agricultural crops arc investigated on a technical, economic and environmental basis. Ireland is facing a waste crisis; municipal waste production has grown at a significant rate over the last number of years; to compound this problem the Landfill Directive requires a reduction in the quantity of biodegradable municipal waste consigned to landfill. This thesis compares composting to anaerobic digestion with biogas utilisation as a transport fuel. The composting model is based on two weeks in-vessel composting followed by eight to ten weeks aerated static pile composting. The anaerobic digestion model is based on a dry digestion process, followed by water absorption for biogas upgrading, and biogas compression. At present biogas is not subjected to excise duty; if this situation remains then biogas is economically preferable to composting when treating more than 18,000 t/a (which equates to the waste produced by 80,000 people). However, if excise duty were applied to biogas, then composting is economically preferable when treating less than 48,000 t/a. The area of land that is available for energy crops was examined. Crops for energy production can be grown on set-aside land and land previously under sugar beet without affecting food production. Currently there are three main crops in Ireland; wheat, barley and sugar beet. Biogas production from these crops is investigated for various rotations, however in addition to biogas these crops can also be used for ethanol production. Thus biogas from these crops is in direct competition with ethanol; consequently biogas and ethanol are compared. On a technical basis it was found that biogas produces more energy per hectare than ethanol. It was also found that a crop rotation of wheat, wheat and sugar beet is preferable in terms of energy production for both biogas and ethanol production. On an economic basis, biogas is preferable to ethanol when compared per unit of energy&#8217;. On an environmental basis ethanol saves more CO2 than biogas; this is due to present documented levels of leakage of methane at the biogas facilities. If biogas losses were reduced to between 3.4-4.4% then biogas saves more CO2 than ethanol. Overall this work shows that biogas from biodegradable municipal waste and agricultural crops on 48,000 ha of land previously under sugar beet and set aside can replace up to 3.3% of petroleum fuels in 2010. Biogas on its own will not enable Ireland to comply with the Biofuels Directive but can aid Ireland if used in a combined approach with other renew able fuels and biogas from different sources."</description>
      <author>Niamh Power</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34719/vrkk7758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beneficial Effects of Fruits and Vegetables on Kidney Disease Progression and Cardiovascular Disease Risk</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2024.07.029</link>
      <description>Claretha Lyas, The American Journal of Medicine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401305591

                Chronic kidney disease and cardiovascular disease are common causes of morbidity and mortality in the United States. In addition to pharmacologic therapy, dietary modification is an important strategy to mitigate disease progression. Diets rich in fruits and vegetable, such as the DASH (Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension) diet, the Mediterranean Diet, and vegan diets, have been shown to attenuate the risk of progressive chronic kidney disease and cardiovascular disease through a variety of mechanisms that are incompletely understood. Evidence suggests that these diets are high in potassium, which is an important dietary factor for blood pressure reduction, and high in magnesium which has been shown to lower the production of inflammatory and proatherogenic cytokines in endothelial cells2Morales-Alvarez M. et al.Effects of Reduced Dietary Sodium and the DASH Diet on GFR: The DASH-sodium trial.Kidney360. 2024; 5: 569-576Crossref Scopus (1) Google Scholar. Furthermore, diets high in fruits and vegetables have a reduced dietary acid load and provide a net alkalizing effect through its potassium, magnesium, and calcium content, which is in contrast to high acid diets, such as the typical Western diet or diets high in animal protein that have been shown to provide a net acidifying effect through its generation of hydrogen ions from phosphorus and protein3Noce A. et al.Nutritional Approaches for the Management of Metabolic Acidosis in Chronic Kidney Disease.Nutrients. 2021; 13: 2534Crossref PubMed Scopus (16) Google Scholar. High animal protein diets impose their adverse effects to the kidney through tubular toxicity from elevated ammonium concentration and activation of the renin-angiotensin system, and through the alternative complement pathway4Banerjee T. et al.High Dietary Acid Load Predicts ESRD among Adults with CKD.Journal of the American Association of Nephrology. 2015; 26: 1693-1700Crossref PubMed Scopus (0) Google Scholar. In this issue of AJM, Goraya and colleagues report the benefit of diets high in fruits and vegetables on chronic kidney disease progression, blood pressure control, and indices of cardiovascular disease risk in a primary hypertension patient population. They describe a randomized control trial of 153 ambulatory patients 18-70 years of age with macroalbuminuria defined as urine albumin-to-creatinine ratio &gt;200mg/g without diabetes, no known cardiovascular (CV) disease but at increased risk of developing CV disease due to having macroalbuminuria, normal plasma CO2 level, and normal kidney function to evaluate kidney disease progression and cardiovascular disease risk indices over five years. This patient population was selected as they had no known cardiovascular disease but were at increased risk and therefore had the greatest potential to benefit from dietary modification. The authors randomized ambulatory patients with hypertension in a 1:1:1 ratio to fruits and vegetables, sodium bicarbonate tablets to match the alkali content of the fruits and vegetables group, or to usual care with 51 patients in each of the three groups. All individuals received guideline-directed therapy of angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors (enalapril) and statin therapy (atorvastatin) as tolerated by patients. The investigators found that when compared to usual care both the fruit and vegetable group and oral sodium bicarbonate group resulted in a statistically significant reduction in albuminuria and slower decline in eGFR. These reductions occurred as early as year 2 in this five year study with the degree of albuminuria reduction as high as 33mg/g and the range of eGFR decline of 4.78-6.03ml/min/1.73m2 compared to 8.6-10.8ml/min/1.73m2 in the usual care group. The greatest reduction in CV disease risk indices of systolic blood pressure, LDL cholesterol, Lp(a) cholesterol, and BMI occurred in the fruits and vegetables group compared to both the usual care and the oral sodium bicarbonate groups. Clinically, these changes were equivalent to roughly 5mmHg reduction in systolic blood pressure, 6mg/dl reduction in LDL cholesterol, 3mg/dl reduction in Lp(a) cholesterol, and 1kg/m2 reduction in BMI when compared to enalapril and atorvastatin alone. The authors showed that median doses of antihypertensive medications and statins were lower in the fruits and vegetables group compared to the usual care group. Therefore, fruits and vegetables showed an added benefit to usual care. This study was a remarkable achievement in the way in which it was conducted, the limitation in resources available, and the diverse study population recruited. It took 10 years to enroll the necessary sample size of individuals that uniquely had hypertension, macroalbuminuria without diabetes, and normal kidney function with an estimated glomerular filtration rate &gt;90ml/min/1.73m2. Also, it enrolled a study population of 47% African American individuals which can be difficult to achieve in clinical trials. The large number of African Americans in the study cohort speaks to the trial's ability to generalize to a diverse patient population and speaks to the potential success of a dietary intervention in minority populations who are at risk of having limited resources and poor access to medical care. Furthermore, it provides a rationale for more dietary intervention studies in populations who would otherwise be skeptical of traditional pharmacologic care. This is the first interventional, randomized control trial that compared the alkali producing potential of fruits and vegetables against oral sodium bicarbonate therapy and its effect on kidney disease progression and cardiovascular disease risk in a patient population with normal kidney function. Furthermore, it shows that fruits and vegetables are an added benefit to usual care, and it provides the foundational support for routine assessment of albuminuria in a primary hypertension patient population. This study compliments a similar study by the authors that investigated similar parameters in a CKD Stage 3 population (eGFR 30-59ml/min/1.73m2), not a population with normal kidney function as this study, where similar results were reported, thus signifying an enduring benefit of fruit and vegetable consumption on kidney disease progression and cardiovascular disease risk5Goraya N. et al.Fruits and Vegetable Treatment of Chronic Kidney Disease-Related Metabolic Acidosis Reduces Cardiovascular Risk Better than Sodium Bicarbonate.American Journal of Nephrology. 2019; 49: 438-448Crossref PubMed Scopus (0) Google Scholar. Compared to the authors' previous study, this current study was conducted in a larger patient cohort but with similar numbers of African American and Hispanic individuals. Also, outcomes in the current study were investigated equally as compared to the previous study where outcomes were delineated as primary (eGFR change) versus secondary (urinary excretion of kidney injury parameters, body mass index, systolic blood pressure, and plasma levels of cholesterol), making the cardiovascular disease risk indices in this current study more robust. This study highlights the benefits of fruits and vegetables on cardiovascular and renal indices while also showcasing the continued limitations of delivering healthy foods and sustaining a dietary intervention, particularly in marginalized communities. The authors describe a significant investment of time and resources to retain this study cohort as this unique patient population makes up less than 1% of patients with primary hypertension and comprises a small number of individuals from which to recruit. Additionally, these patients were almost 50% African American, which undoubtedly made retention efforts different than what would be necessary for non-minority communities. As such, this study not only speaks to the willingness and engagement of minority communities in a dietary intervention but also further highlights the need for systemic change to make fruits and vegetables more widely available for all communities given that this study adds more evidence to support the need for fruit and vegetable intake in the management of chronic kidney disease and cardiovascular disease. Policy initiatives to include eliminating food deserts, creating subsidies or vouchers for fruits and vegetables, incentivizing community gardens, engaging community and civic organizations, and combining reductions in insurance premiums with increased consumption of fruits and vegetables are all areas to consider for practical implementation and for overcoming the barrier this dietary change would create. There are a few study limitations the authors cite. For example, the investigators describe a lack of specific data on adherence with sodium bicarbonate therapy as a major limitation of the study. Other limitations include a lack of data on differences in dietary sodium intake that could either contribute or attenuate the study results. Also, there is a lack of confirmation of the prespecified amount of fruits and vegetables consumed, although they did show that plasma total CO2 levels and plasma bicarbonate concentrations were higher in the sodium bicarbonate therapy and fruits and vegetable groups. Future studies could further test these findings in larger patient populations and further unravel the mechanisms of how high dietary fruit and vegetable intake attenuate the risk of kidney disease and cardiovascular disease progression. Furthermore, future studies with larger sample sizes and longer follow up periods could determine if high fruit and vegetable consumption decrease cardiovascular events and outcomes. 1Appel L. A Clinical Trial of the Effects of Dietary Patterns on Blood Pressure.NEJM. 1997; 336: 1117-1124Crossref PubMed Scopus (0) Google Scholar Claretha Lyas: Writing &#8211; original draft, Writing &#8211; review &amp; editing. I was a paid consultant in 2022 for Baxter Healthcare for my expertise in sepsis related acute kidney injury. This consulting work is not related to the current commentary.</description>
      <author>Claretha Lyas</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2024.07.029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphological and Physiological Response of Maize (Zea mays L.) to Drought Stress during Reproductive Stage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14081718</link>
      <description>Sitti Maryam Yasin, Francisco Zavala&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Guillermo Ni&#241;o&#8208;Medina, Pablo Al&#225;n Rodr&#237;guez-Salinas, Adriana Guti&#233;rrez-D&#237;ez, Sugey Ramona Sinagawa-Garc&#237;a, Eleazar Lugo-Cruz, Agronomy. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337615

                Maize is among the most significant crops in the world regarding production and yield, but it is highly sensitive to drought, which reduces the growth, photosynthetic efficiency, grain quality, and yield production of a plant. Quantum yield efficiency of photosystem II is a critical photosynthetic component that is susceptible to drought stress. This study intended to investigate the effects of drought stress on growth and morpho-physiological parameters using three maize hybrids (&#8216;P-3011w&#8217;, &#8216;P-3092&#8217; and &#8216;iku20&#8217;) with contrasting soil moisture contents (100%, 40%) at the pre-flowering stage. The stress treatment (40%) was initiated at stage V7, for a period of 15 days; the experimental units were established in a completely randomized design with split-plot arrangement along with three repetitions in 42 L pots using a substrate of peat moss, black soil and poultry manure (1:2:1). The morphological, growth-related and physiological parameters were assessed, including chlorophyll fluorescence (Fv/Fm), which was measured using a LiCor-6400-40 fluorometer. The results showed that all morphological, growth-related and physiological variables decreased under drought stress during the reproductive stage, with the exception of leaf temperature and intercellular CO2 concentration, which increased by 12% and 54%, respectively. Drought stress significantly reduced the photosynthetic chlorophyll fluorescence (43%), due to damage to photosystem II. The lowest percentage of damage to photosystem II (34%) was observed in the iku20 genotype. In contrast, P-3011w and P-3092 had the highest levels of significantly similar damage (49% and 46%, respectively). The correlation analysis showed a highly positive interaction of chlorophyll fluorescence (Fv/Fm) with net photosynthetic rate and stomatal conductance under drought conditions, and multiple regression analysis revealed that the maximum effect on net photosynthetic rate under drought was due to the damage it caused to photosystem II. Thus, iku20 might have a tendency to be able to withstand drought stress in the dry northeast region of Mexico. Overall, we concluded that the photosystem II was negatively impacted by drought stress thus causing a reduction in all physiological, morphological and growth-related variables.</description>
      <author>Sitti Maryam Yasin, Francisco Zavala&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Guillermo Ni&#241;o&#8208;Medina, Pablo Al&#225;n Rodr&#237;guez-Salinas, Adriana Guti&#233;rrez-D&#237;ez, Sugey Ramona Sinagawa-Garc&#237;a, Eleazar Lugo-Cruz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14081718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Company Valuation Before and After IPO Study Case PT Pertamina Geothermal Energy Tbk</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47191/ijcsrr/v7-i8-21</link>
      <description>Anita Nur Afidah, Ana Noveria, Subiakto Subiakto, International Journal of Current Science Research and Review. 07(08)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401400980

                Affordable energy resources of energy play a crucial role in economic and social development to support food production, availability of water supply and sustainable healty lifestyle. In order to avoid long-term scarcity resulting from the continuous use of non-renewable energy sources, we must explore all potential renewable energy source that align with concernes about climate change and other environmental issues. As a continuation of the Indonesian government&#8217;s efforts to generate clean and environmental friendly energy, PT Pertamina Geothermal Energy (PGE) was established in 2006. It has contributed 82% of the installed geothermal energy capacity in Indonesia. By leveraging Indonesia&#8217;s location within the Ring of Fire as one of the world&#8217;s geothermal energy hubs, PGE has been supplying electricity to more than 2 million households in Indonesia with a potential emission reduction of 9.7 million tons of CO2 per year. To achieve sustainable business growth, PGEO is optimizing production in its operational areas by expanding installed capacity. In the company consideration, IPO is an appropriate step to financing the expansion. The author compares the company&#8217;s value before and after the IPO to determine the short-term impact of the IPO, helping investors gauge their confidence in making investment decisions in PGEO. This study utilizes secondary data from prospectuses, financial statements, annual reports, sustainability reports, company-published documents, as well as data from IDX.co.id and IDN Financials.com. The data was collected and analyzed to understand evaluate financial performance, and assess the company&#8217;s value before and after the IPO. The calculation of the company&#8217;s intrinsic value is conducted using the Discounted Cash Flow Valuation method for the pre-IPO period against the company&#8217;s financial projections for the years 2019 to 2022 and for the post-IPO period against the company&#8217;s financial projections for the years 2024 to 2028, using discount rates of 8.25% and 8.65% for each. In resulting the intrinsic value pre-IPO is IDR 1.141,28 and the intrinsic value post-IPO is IDR 1.300,86. The stock price of PGEO at its IPO on February 23, 2023, was IDR 875, while the adjusted closing price on December 29, 2023, was IDR 1,170. This study founds that the market price of PGEO&#8217;s stock, both before and after the IPO, are overvalued.</description>
      <author>Anita Nur Afidah, Ana Noveria, Subiakto Subiakto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47191/ijcsrr/v7-i8-21</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of mediterranean diet promotion on environmental sustainability: a longitudinal analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32920/26528053</link>
      <description>Laura &#193;lvarez&#8208;&#193;lvarez, Facundo Vitelli&#8208;Storelli, Mar&#237;a Rub&#237;n&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Silvia Garc&#237;a, Cristina Bouzas, Miguel Ruiz&#8208;Canela, Dolores Corella, Jordi Salas&#8208;Salvad&#243;, Montserrat Fit&#243;, J. Alfredo Mart&#237;n&#233;z, Lucas Tojal&#8208;Sierra, Julia W&#228;rnberg, Jes&#250;s Vioque, Dora Romaguera, Jos&#233; L&#243;pez&#8208;Miranda, Ram&#243;n Estruch, Francisco J. Tinahones, Manuel Ortega&#8208;Calvo, Llu&#237;s Serra&#8208;Majem, Aurora Bueno&#8208;Cavanillas, Cristina Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Virginia Esteve-Luque, Miguel Delgado&#8208;Rodr&#237;guez, Macarena Torrego-Ellacur&#237;a, Josep Vidal, Lu&#237;s Prieto, Lidia Daimiel, Rosa Casas, Ana Garc&#237;a&#8208;Arellano, Sangeetha Shyam, Jos&#233; I. Gonz&#225;lez, Olga Casta&#241;er, Antonio Garc&#237;a&#8208;R&#237;os, Fran&#231;ois D&#237;az, Antonio Castro Fern&#225;ndez, Almudena S&#225;nchez&#8208;Villegas, Marga Morey, Naomi Cano&#8208;Ib&#225;&#241;ez, Carolina Sorto-S&#225;nchez, M. Rosa Bernal&#8208;L&#243;pez, Maira Bes&#8208;Rastrollo, Stephanie Nishi, &#211;scar Coltell, Mar&#237;a Dolores Zome&#241;o, Patricia J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Orihuela, D.V. Aparicio, M. &#193;ngeles Zulet, Zenaida V&#225;zquez&#8208;Ruiz, Nancy Babi&#243;, K.A. P&#233;rez, Josep A. Tur, Vicente Mart&#237;n, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401455005

                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This article aims to estimate the differences in environmental impact (greenhouse gas [GHG] emissions, land use, energy used, acidification and potential eutrophication) after one year of promoting a Mediterranean diet (MD).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Baseline and 1-year follow-up data from 5800 participants in the PREDIMED-Plus study were used. Each participant's food intake was estimated using validated semi-quantitative food frequency questionnaires, and the adherence to MD using the Dietary Score. The influence of diet on environmental impact was assessed through the EAT-Lancet Commission tables. The influence of diet on environmental impact was assessed through the EAT-Lancet Commission tables. The association between MD adherence and its environmental impact was calculated using adjusted multivariate linear regression models.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After one year of intervention, the kcal/day consumed was significantly reduced (&#8722;125,1 kcal/day), adherence to a MD pattern was improved (+0,9) and the environmental impact due to the diet was significantly reduced (GHG: &#8722;361 g/CO2-eq; Acidification:-11,5 g SO2-eq; Eutrophication:-4,7 g PO4-eq; Energy use:-842,7 kJ; and Land use:-2,2 m2). Higher adherence to MD (high vs. low) was significantly associated with lower environmental impact both at baseline and one year follow-up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meat products had the greatest environmental impact in all the factors analysed, both at baseline and at one-year follow-up, in spite of the reduction observed in their consumption.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A program promoting a MD, after one year of intervention, significantly reduced the environmental impact in all the factors analysed. Meat products had the greatest environmental impact in all the dimensions analysed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Laura &#193;lvarez&#8208;&#193;lvarez, Facundo Vitelli&#8208;Storelli, Mar&#237;a Rub&#237;n&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Silvia Garc&#237;a, Cristina Bouzas, Miguel Ruiz&#8208;Canela, Dolores Corella, Jordi Salas&#8208;Salvad&#243;, Montserrat Fit&#243;, J. Alfredo Mart&#237;n&#233;z, Lucas Tojal&#8208;Sierra, Julia W&#228;rnberg, Jes&#250;s Vioque, Dora Romaguera, Jos&#233; L&#243;pez&#8208;Miranda, Ram&#243;n Estruch, Francisco J. Tinahones, Manuel Ortega&#8208;Calvo, Llu&#237;s Serra&#8208;Majem, Aurora Bueno&#8208;Cavanillas, Cristina Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Virginia Esteve-Luque, Miguel Delgado&#8208;Rodr&#237;guez, Macarena Torrego-Ellacur&#237;a, Josep Vidal, Lu&#237;s Prieto, Lidia Daimiel, Rosa Casas, Ana Garc&#237;a&#8208;Arellano, Sangeetha Shyam, Jos&#233; I. Gonz&#225;lez, Olga Casta&#241;er, Antonio Garc&#237;a&#8208;R&#237;os, Fran&#231;ois D&#237;az, Antonio Castro Fern&#225;ndez, Almudena S&#225;nchez&#8208;Villegas, Marga Morey, Naomi Cano&#8208;Ib&#225;&#241;ez, Carolina Sorto-S&#225;nchez, M. Rosa Bernal&#8208;L&#243;pez, Maira Bes&#8208;Rastrollo, Stephanie Nishi, &#211;scar Coltell, Mar&#237;a Dolores Zome&#241;o, Patricia J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Orihuela, D.V. Aparicio, M. &#193;ngeles Zulet, Zenaida V&#225;zquez&#8208;Ruiz, Nancy Babi&#243;, K.A. P&#233;rez, Josep A. Tur, Vicente Mart&#237;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32920/26528053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of mediterranean diet promotion on environmental sustainability: a longitudinal analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32920/26528053.v1</link>
      <description>Laura &#193;lvarez&#8208;&#193;lvarez, Facundo Vitelli&#8208;Storelli, Mar&#237;a Rub&#237;n&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Silvia Garc&#237;a, Cristina Bouzas, Miguel Ruiz&#8208;Canela, Dolores Corella, Jordi Salas&#8208;Salvad&#243;, Montserrat Fit&#243;, J. Alfredo Mart&#237;n&#233;z, Lucas Tojal&#8208;Sierra, Julia W&#228;rnberg, Jes&#250;s Vioque, Dora Romaguera, Jos&#233; L&#243;pez&#8208;Miranda, Ram&#243;n Estruch, Francisco J. Tinahones, Manuel Ortega&#8208;Calvo, Llu&#237;s Serra&#8208;Majem, Aurora Bueno&#8208;Cavanillas, Cristina Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Virginia Esteve-Luque, Miguel Delgado&#8208;Rodr&#237;guez, Macarena Torrego-Ellacur&#237;a, Josep Vidal, Lu&#237;s Prieto, Lidia Daimiel, Rosa Casas, Ana Garc&#237;a&#8208;Arellano, Sangeetha Shyam, Jos&#233; I. Gonz&#225;lez, Olga Casta&#241;er, Antonio Garc&#237;a&#8208;R&#237;os, Fran&#231;ois D&#237;az, Antonio Castro Fern&#225;ndez, Almudena S&#225;nchez&#8208;Villegas, Marga Morey, Naomi Cano&#8208;Ib&#225;&#241;ez, Carolina Sorto-S&#225;nchez, M. Rosa Bernal&#8208;L&#243;pez, Maira Bes&#8208;Rastrollo, Stephanie Nishi, &#211;scar Coltell, Mar&#237;a Dolores Zome&#241;o, Patricia J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Orihuela, D.V. Aparicio, M. &#193;ngeles Zulet, Zenaida V&#225;zquez&#8208;Ruiz, Nancy Babi&#243;, K.A. P&#233;rez, Josep A. Tur, Vicente Mart&#237;n, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401476329

                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This article aims to estimate the differences in environmental impact (greenhouse gas [GHG] emissions, land use, energy used, acidification and potential eutrophication) after one year of promoting a Mediterranean diet (MD).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Baseline and 1-year follow-up data from 5800 participants in the PREDIMED-Plus study were used. Each participant's food intake was estimated using validated semi-quantitative food frequency questionnaires, and the adherence to MD using the Dietary Score. The influence of diet on environmental impact was assessed through the EAT-Lancet Commission tables. The influence of diet on environmental impact was assessed through the EAT-Lancet Commission tables. The association between MD adherence and its environmental impact was calculated using adjusted multivariate linear regression models.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After one year of intervention, the kcal/day consumed was significantly reduced (&#8722;125,1 kcal/day), adherence to a MD pattern was improved (+0,9) and the environmental impact due to the diet was significantly reduced (GHG: &#8722;361 g/CO2-eq; Acidification:-11,5 g SO2-eq; Eutrophication:-4,7 g PO4-eq; Energy use:-842,7 kJ; and Land use:-2,2 m2). Higher adherence to MD (high vs. low) was significantly associated with lower environmental impact both at baseline and one year follow-up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meat products had the greatest environmental impact in all the factors analysed, both at baseline and at one-year follow-up, in spite of the reduction observed in their consumption.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A program promoting a MD, after one year of intervention, significantly reduced the environmental impact in all the factors analysed. Meat products had the greatest environmental impact in all the dimensions analysed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Laura &#193;lvarez&#8208;&#193;lvarez, Facundo Vitelli&#8208;Storelli, Mar&#237;a Rub&#237;n&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Silvia Garc&#237;a, Cristina Bouzas, Miguel Ruiz&#8208;Canela, Dolores Corella, Jordi Salas&#8208;Salvad&#243;, Montserrat Fit&#243;, J. Alfredo Mart&#237;n&#233;z, Lucas Tojal&#8208;Sierra, Julia W&#228;rnberg, Jes&#250;s Vioque, Dora Romaguera, Jos&#233; L&#243;pez&#8208;Miranda, Ram&#243;n Estruch, Francisco J. Tinahones, Manuel Ortega&#8208;Calvo, Llu&#237;s Serra&#8208;Majem, Aurora Bueno&#8208;Cavanillas, Cristina Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Virginia Esteve-Luque, Miguel Delgado&#8208;Rodr&#237;guez, Macarena Torrego-Ellacur&#237;a, Josep Vidal, Lu&#237;s Prieto, Lidia Daimiel, Rosa Casas, Ana Garc&#237;a&#8208;Arellano, Sangeetha Shyam, Jos&#233; I. Gonz&#225;lez, Olga Casta&#241;er, Antonio Garc&#237;a&#8208;R&#237;os, Fran&#231;ois D&#237;az, Antonio Castro Fern&#225;ndez, Almudena S&#225;nchez&#8208;Villegas, Marga Morey, Naomi Cano&#8208;Ib&#225;&#241;ez, Carolina Sorto-S&#225;nchez, M. Rosa Bernal&#8208;L&#243;pez, Maira Bes&#8208;Rastrollo, Stephanie Nishi, &#211;scar Coltell, Mar&#237;a Dolores Zome&#241;o, Patricia J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Orihuela, D.V. Aparicio, M. &#193;ngeles Zulet, Zenaida V&#225;zquez&#8208;Ruiz, Nancy Babi&#243;, K.A. P&#233;rez, Josep A. Tur, Vicente Mart&#237;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32920/26528053.v1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
