<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:43:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging two-dimensional materials: Synthesis, physical properties, and application for catalysis in energy conversion and storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59717/j.xinn-mater.2024.100060</link>
      <description>Xu Li, Rashid Iqbal, Yijun Wang, Sana Taimoor, Leiduan Hao, Renhao Dong, Kaihui Liu, John Texter, Zhenyu Sun, The Innovation Materials. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392948629

                &lt;p&gt;Inorganic, organic, and hybrid two-dimensional (2D) materials are being developed for ever-expanding numbers of applications, though energy and catalysis remain the main drivers of their development. We present overviews of bottom-up and top-down synthetic strategies of such materials and examine manufacturing scalability issues. Mechanical, electrical, and thermal properties and their modulation are highlighted because they are fundamental to the above-mentioned drivers. The burgeoning importance of heterostructures in such materials, particularly for catalysis and electrode design and function is stressed. Detailed attention is given to applications of 2D materials to the electrocatalysis reactions: oxygen reduction, oxygen evolution, hydrogen evolution, carbon dioxide reduction, and nitrogen reduction. Water splitting, carbon dioxide reduction, and nitrogen reduction by photocatalysis are also examined. A perspective of expected advances in the expansion of applications and types of 2D materials, with a focus on heterostructure development, is presented in the conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Xu Li, Rashid Iqbal, Yijun Wang, Sana Taimoor, Leiduan Hao, Renhao Dong, Kaihui Liu, John Texter, Zhenyu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59717/j.xinn-mater.2024.100060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prospects for the Development of Nanocomposite Catalysts for the Oxidative Conversion of C1-C4 Alkanes with Carbon Dioxide to Produce Hydrogen/Synthesis Gas and Organic Compounds: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11237-024-09790-z</link>
      <description>Sergiy O. Soloviev, Theoretical and Experimental Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393011083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sergiy O. Soloviev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11237-024-09790-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digitalization and net-zero carbon: The role of industrial robots towards carbon dioxide emission reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141820</link>
      <description>Weizhi Yao, Liang Liu, Hidemichi Fujii, Lianshui Li, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393039058

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weizhi Yao, Liang Liu, Hidemichi Fujii, Lianshui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141820</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom anchored on curved boron nitride fullerene surface as efficient electrocatalyst for carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114040</link>
      <description>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Molecular Catalysis. 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393116736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium carbide sealed cadmium sulfide quantum dots on carbon, oxygen-doped boron nitride for enhanced and durable photochemical carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.139</link>
      <description>Zhangfeng Shen, Yang Yang, LI Yu-ji, Xiaohua Cheng, Huayang Zhang, Xuhui Zou, Ming Qiu, Hong Huang, Hongge Pan, Qineng Xia, Ge Zhang, Yongyong Cao, Jing Gao, Yangang Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393131989

                Despite great efforts that have been made, photocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction still faces enormous challenges due to the sluggish kinetics or disadvantageous thermodynamics. Herein, cadmium sulfide quantum dots (CdS QDs) were loaded onto carbon, oxygen-doped boron nitride (BN) and encapsulated by titanium carbide (Ti3C2, MXene) layers to construct a ternary composite. The uniform distribution of CdS QDs and the tight interfacial interaction among the three components could be achieved by adjusting the loading amounts of CdS QDs and MXene. The ternary 100MX/CQ/BN sample gave a productive rate of 2.45 and 0.44 &#956;mol g-1 h&#8722;1 for carbon monoxide (CO) and methane (CH4), respectively. This CO yield is 1.93 and 6.13 times higher than that of CdS QDs/BN and BN counterparts. The photocatalytic durability of the ternary composite is significantly improved compared with CdS QDs/BN because MXene can protect CdS from photocorrosion. The characterization results demonstrate that the excellent CO2 adsorption and activation capabilities of BN, the visible light absorption of CdS QDs, the good conductivity of MXene and the well-matched energy band alignment jointly promote the photocatalytic performance of the ternary catalyst.</description>
      <author>Zhangfeng Shen, Yang Yang, LI Yu-ji, Xiaohua Cheng, Huayang Zhang, Xuhui Zou, Ming Qiu, Hong Huang, Hongge Pan, Qineng Xia, Ge Zhang, Yongyong Cao, Jing Gao, Yangang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction via DNA-Directed Catalyst Immobilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.3c00823</link>
      <description>Gang Fan, Nathan Corbin, Minju Chung, Thomas M. Gill, Evan G. Moore, Amruta A. Karbelkar, Ariel L. Furst, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393150984

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gang Fan, Nathan Corbin, Minju Chung, Thomas M. Gill, Evan G. Moore, Amruta A. Karbelkar, Ariel L. Furst</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.3c00823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineered &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; Whole Cell-Mediated Electro-Biocatalysis for Carbon Dioxide to Formic Acid Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08129</link>
      <description>Hongbo Shi, Meng-Xi Fu, Shu Yuan, Yao Lu, Yang Zhuan, Chao Ye, Lunguang Yao, Chuang Xue, Cun-Duo Tang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393164149

                The conversion of CO2 into a valuable chemical fuel could help reduce its effect on global warming. However, the utilization of CO2 by biological transformations is challenging because of the lack of enzymes exhibiting high catalytic activity toward CO2 reduction. In this work, three NAD+/W-containing formate dehydrogenases (FDHs) were discovered, expressed, and characterized. In addition, we used PbFDH, which displays high catalytic activity toward CO2 reduction, as a biocatalyst to convert CO2 to formic acid through whole-cell biocatalysis and electro-biocatalysis. The specific activities of DaFDH, PbFDH, and CsFDH increased by 68.1, 100.0, and 18.7 times, respectively, compared with that of ClFDH reported with high catalytic efficiency. Furthermore, this paper presents a preliminary discussion of the catalytic mechanism of FDHs for CO2 reduction based on their structures. The yield of formic acid obtained from CO2 reduction using electro-biocatalysis under aerobic conditions reaches up to 4.1 mmol/L/h, without any cofactor NADH and hydrogen gas. This study also demonstrates and compares the performances of NAD+/W-containing and NAD+-dependent FDHs in whole-cell biocatalysis and electro-biocatalysis. The findings of this study provide a meaningful foundation for the conversion of CO2 into a value-added chemical fuel.</description>
      <author>Hongbo Shi, Meng-Xi Fu, Shu Yuan, Yao Lu, Yang Zhuan, Chao Ye, Lunguang Yao, Chuang Xue, Cun-Duo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas Diffusion Electrodes (GDEs) for Carbon Dioxide (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) Reduction in Microfluidic Cells: Towards a Fluid Dynamics Assisted Rational Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad377f</link>
      <description>Melanie Colet-Lagrille, Sergio Gonz&#225;lez-Poggini, Carol Salazar-Espinoza, Benito S&#225;nchez, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393164782

                Abstract The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) for the generation of multicarbon (C2+) products with high commercial value &#8211; e.g., ethanol and ethylene &#8211; is gaining growing interest due to the successful implementation of laboratory scale technologies that can reach high current densities (&gt;500 mA cm-2) and Faradaic efficiencies (&gt;60%), using a simplified approach in terms of configuration and cost. This is the case of microfluidic cells, low-temperature electrochemical flow systems which optimal operation sustains on the enhancement of the mass and charge transfer phenomena taking place at the gas diffusion electrode (GDE) | aqueous electrolyte interface where CO2 molecules are selectively transformed at the surface of the catalyst layer. &amp;#xD;This work presents an up-to-date overview of materials and operational conditions for microfluidic-type systems, providing significant enlightenment on the effects that the phenomena occurring at the GDE | electrolyte interface have over the CO2 reduction reaction kinetics towards the generation of C2+ products. It is shown that the integration of computational methods (particularly, density functional theory and computational fluid dynamics) to conventional experimental approaches is an effective strategy to elucidate the reactions mechanisms and mass/charge transfer trends determining the enhanced design of GDEs and the GDE | electrolyte interface.</description>
      <author>Melanie Colet-Lagrille, Sergio Gonz&#225;lez-Poggini, Carol Salazar-Espinoza, Benito S&#225;nchez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad377f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How informal environmental regulations constrain carbon dioxide emissions under pollution control and carbon reduction: Evidence from China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118732</link>
      <description>Po Kou, Ying Han, Baoling Jin, Tian Li, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392983203

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Po Kou, Ying Han, Baoling Jin, Tian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyzer and Catalyst Engineering for Acidic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393057305</link>
      <description>Alessandro Perazio, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393057305

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alessandro Perazio</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393057305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical Catalytic Co2 Reduction Enhanced by In-Doped Gan and Combined with Vibration Energy Harvester Driving Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4772115</link>
      <description>Mingxiang Zhang, Li Wen, Shanghao Gu, Weihan Xu, Zhouguang Lu, Fei Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393143337

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingxiang Zhang, Li Wen, Shanghao Gu, Weihan Xu, Zhouguang Lu, Fei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4772115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 catalyzed by a Cobalt molecular complex and a bimetallic Ni-Sn electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393024413</link>
      <description>Paul Rayess, No host. None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4393024413

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Paul Rayess</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393024413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient photoelectrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formate via Bi-Doped InOCl nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174220</link>
      <description>Yibo Jia, Huimin Yang, Rui Chen, Yi Zhang, Fanfan Gao, Nan Cheng, Jiaqi Yang, Xuemei Gao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392975989

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yibo Jia, Huimin Yang, Rui Chen, Yi Zhang, Fanfan Gao, Nan Cheng, Jiaqi Yang, Xuemei Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in Membrane Technologies for Enhanced Water Splitting and Co2 Reduction: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52783/jchr.v14.i2.3372</link>
      <description>, Journal of Chemical Health Risks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393005861

                The global pursuit of sustainable energy and environmental solutions has intensified the focus on water splitting and CO2 reduction as promising pathways towards a low-carbon future.Membrane technologies have emerged as crucial components in enhancing the efficiency and selectivity of these processes.This comprehensive review explores recent advancements in membrane technologies for water splitting and CO2 reduction, aiming to provide insights into their fundamental principles, current state-of-the-art developments, and prospects.Various techniques such as electrolysis, electrochemical and photocatalytic CO2 reduction are discussed, highlighting their respective principles and challenges.Subsequently, the role of membranes in facilitating these processes is examined.Different types of membranes are reviewed in terms of their structure, properties, and recent advancements aimed at improving performance.In the realm of water splitting, membranes play a pivotal role in separating reactants and products, enhancing reactions and enabling efficient utilization of resources.Recent developments in membrane have shown promising results in improving water splitting efficiency and durability.Similarly, in CO2 reduction processes, membranes are utilized for gas separation, concentration, and selective transport of species, enabling enhanced reaction and product selectivity.Integration of membrane technologies into water splitting and CO2 reduction systems is another area of focus, with the review examining the advantages and challenges associated with such integration.Integrated membrane systems are presented, showcasing their potential to achieve synergistic effects, and improved overall performance.Despite significant progress, including membrane fouling, stability, and cost-effectiveness, which necessitate further research and development efforts.In conclusion, this review underscores the critical role of membrane technologies in advancing water splitting and CO2 reduction for sustainable energy and environmental applications.By providing a comprehensive overview of recent advancements, challenges, and prospects, this review aims to stimulate further research and innovation in the field, ultimately contributing to the realization of a cleaner and more sustainable future.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52783/jchr.v14.i2.3372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Tuning of the Selectivity of Cu-Based Interface for Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction by Ligand Modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4760891</link>
      <description>Yonggao Yan, Tongxian Li, Manuel Oliva&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Yuguo Zhao, Shuo Wang, Xin Chen, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392973237

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Yonggao Yan, Tongxian Li, Manuel Oliva&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Yuguo Zhao, Shuo Wang, Xin Chen, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4760891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic reduction of simulated industrial CO2 and CO mixtures: Revising chronoamperometry to enable selective gas mixture reduction via cyclic voltammetry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150602</link>
      <description>Wen Qian Chen, Foo Jit Loong Cyrus, Li Ya Ge, Andrei Veksha, Wei Ping Chan, Yafei Shen, Grzegorz Lisak, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393088089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen Qian Chen, Foo Jit Loong Cyrus, Li Ya Ge, Andrei Veksha, Wei Ping Chan, Yafei Shen, Grzegorz Lisak</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond CO2 Reduction: Electrochemical C&#8210;N Coupling Reaction for Organonitrogen Compound Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101491</link>
      <description>Dohun Kim, Jungsu Eo, Siak Piang Lim, Dohun Kim, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393071276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dohun Kim, Jungsu Eo, Siak Piang Lim, Dohun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Engineered Catalyst Microenvironments using Conductive Polymers during Electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101490</link>
      <description>Suyun Lee, Jun-Hee Seo, Chanyeon Kim, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393084614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suyun Lee, Jun-Hee Seo, Chanyeon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101490</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO in flow cell device by a pristine Cu5tz6-cluster-based metal-organic framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00189c</link>
      <description>Zijing Li, Yingtong Lv, Haoliang Huang, Zijian Li, Tao Li, Linjuan Zhang, Jianqiang Wang, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393060748

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO is a powerful approach to achieve carbon neutrality. Herein, we report a five-nuclear copper cluster-based metal&#8211;azolate framework CuTz-1 as an electrocatalyst for the...</description>
      <author>Zijing Li, Yingtong Lv, Haoliang Huang, Zijian Li, Tao Li, Linjuan Zhang, Jianqiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00189c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulate the Adsorption of Oxygen-Containing Intermediates to Promote the Reduction of Co2 to Ch4 on Ni-Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4764056</link>
      <description>Hedan Yao, Liuyi Pan, Xi Yao, Wenhong Li, Yi Qin, Dong Li, Yingxia Wang, Wenjie Xue, Qianqian Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392955133

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Hedan Yao, Liuyi Pan, Xi Yao, Wenhong Li, Yi Qin, Dong Li, Yingxia Wang, Wenjie Xue, Qianqian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4764056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Metalated Porphyrin-Based MOFs Coupled with Anatase as Photocatalysts for CO2 Reduction: The Effect of Metalation Proportion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17061483</link>
      <description>Maria Anagnostopoulou, Val&#233;rie Keller, Konstantinos C. Christoforidis, Energies. 17(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393006588

                Converting carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable chemicals such as fossil resources via photocatalysis requires the development of advanced materials. Herein, we coupled zirconium-based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) containing porphyrin and Cu-porphyrin with anatase TiO2. The effect of the porphyrin metalation proportion was also investigated. Notably, while the use of free-base porphyrin as the organic linker resulted in the development of PCN-224, the presence of Cu-porphyrin provided mixed-phase MOF structures containing both PCN-224 and PCN-222. MOF/TiO2 composites bearing partial (50%) metalated porphyrin were proven more active and selective towards the production of CH4, at ambient conditions, in the gas phase and using water vapors without the use of hole scavengers. The optimized composite bearing 15 wt.% of the partial metalated MOF was three times more active than pure TiO2 towards CH4 production. This study provides insights on the effect of precise materials engineering at a molecular level on the development of advanced MOF-based photocatalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Maria Anagnostopoulou, Val&#233;rie Keller, Konstantinos C. Christoforidis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17061483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot two-step reduction of CO2 with amines and NaBH4 to N-substituted compounds at atmospheric pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102741</link>
      <description>Junhong Wang, B. P. Wang, Xuehong Wei, Zhiqiang Guo, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393124559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junhong Wang, B. P. Wang, Xuehong Wei, Zhiqiang Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-dopant and O-vacancy of mesoporous ZnO nanosheets induce high efficiency and selectivity of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coco.2024.101890</link>
      <description>Ying Wang, Youngeun Kang, Yuanxin Miao, Min Jia, S. Alice Long, Lipeng Diao, Lijie Zhang, Daohao Li, Guanglei Wu, Composites Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393166182

                Surface engineering can adjust the electronic properties of catalysts, thereby boosting their electrocatalytic performances. Herein, S-doped and O-vacant mesoporous ZnO nanosheets (ZnO-VO-S) were synthesized through the plasma-treatment method, exhibiting highly electrocatalytic selectivity and activity in the conversion of CO2 to CO. Synchrotron X-ray absorption fine structure (XAFS) investigations were used to further clarify the valence state and local coordination structure of Zn, concretely affirming the reduced electron density of Zn in ZnO-VO-S. Specifically, at &#8722;1.1 V vs. RHE, the as-prepared ZnO-VO-S demonstrated a high Faradaic efficiency of 90%. Experiments and density functional theory (DFT) suggest that the electron deficiency of Zn caused by the introduction of S dopant and O vacancy, reduces the energy barrier of CO2 to CO by improving the adsorption behavior of the intermediate *COOH.</description>
      <author>Ying Wang, Youngeun Kang, Yuanxin Miao, Min Jia, S. Alice Long, Lipeng Diao, Lijie Zhang, Daohao Li, Guanglei Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coco.2024.101890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faster Kinetics and High Selectivity for Electrolytic Reduction of CO2 with Zn0/Zn2+ Interface of ZnO/ZnAl2O4 Derived from Hydrotalcite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04648-4</link>
      <description>Ling Wang, Ya Gao, Shuxiu Yu, Yangying Sun, Yan Zheng, Yifan Liang, Liang Li, Catalysis Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393111610

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Wang, Ya Gao, Shuxiu Yu, Yangying Sun, Yan Zheng, Yifan Liang, Liang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04648-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0D/2D Bi2MoO6 quantum dots /rGO heterojunction boosting full solar spectrum-driven photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction to solar fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119079</link>
      <description>Rui Feng, Mingnv Guo, Zhongqing Yang, Jiaqi Qiu, Ziqi Wang, Yongliang Zhao, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393114428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Feng, Mingnv Guo, Zhongqing Yang, Jiaqi Qiu, Ziqi Wang, Yongliang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design a reducing CO2 emission system using nonfermentable substrates for carbon-economic biosynthesis of poly-2-hydrobutanedioic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150597</link>
      <description>Jishan He, Kangjia Zuo, Hongjing Chen, Xingran Xu, Xiang Zou, Chemical Engineering Journal. 487(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392975844

                Reducing carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions in the aerobic biorefinery system is becoming a crucial effort for achieving carbon-economic biosynthesis of biomaterials and chemicals. Poly-2-hydrobutanedioic acid (P2HBD), a long-carbon chain polyester produced by the fungus Aureobasidium pullulans, has garnered significant attention in the biomaterials and chemical industries. In this study, we designed a CO2 emission reduction system using nonfermentable substrates to enable efficient biosynthesis of P2HBD. Based on the genome-scale model iZX637 of A. pullulans, glycerol and ethanol were stimulated to show the potential advantages over glucose in terms of reduced CO2 emission. Additionally, we employed an NADH/NAD+ fluorescent probe called SoNar to dynamically monitor the reductive power ratio during CO2 emission. Subsequently, glycerol metabolism and rTCA carbon fixation pathway were engineered, while implementing a modular assembly strategy to achieve balanced integration between these two modules through precise promoter engineering regulation. The optimal strain ZX-LM03 showed the advantages of less carbon emission with glycerol and ethanol as the co-substrates, and achieved the higher P2HBD titer and yield of 15.07 &#177; 0.18 g/L and 0.54 &#177; 0.01 g/g, with the lower carbon emission of 31.08 % compared to glucose in the 5 L fermenter. In conclusion, this study provides novel insights into achieving carbon neutrality using renewable substrates for reducing carbon emission in aerobic fermentation systems.</description>
      <author>Jishan He, Kangjia Zuo, Hongjing Chen, Xingran Xu, Xiang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150597</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Each Component Ratio of Multiple Thermal Fluids in Extra-Heavy Oil Reservoir</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-0260-2_78</link>
      <description>Hua Ma, Bing Bo, Aiguo Xu, Lun Zhao, Wenqi Zhao, Fachao Shan, Chenggang Wang, Minghui Liu, Springer series in geomechanics and geoengineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393009781

                Under the goal of "carbon peaking and carbon neutrality", the technology of multiple thermal fluids is widely used to develop heavy oil reservoirs at home and abroad for its advantages of low carbon and environmental protection. The multicomponent thermal fluids mainly contain nitrogen, carbon dioxide and steam. In the formation, multi-components play an important role in the huff and puff effect. In order to improve the development effect of extra-heavy oil reservoir, the optimization of each component ratio must be further studied. Based on the single factor analysis method and orthogonal test method, this paper designs 40 groups of multi-component thermal fluids numerical simulation schemes with different component proportions. CMG software simulates the influence of steam injection rate, gas-steam ratio, CO2-N2 ratio and other injection parameters on the development effect of multi-component thermal fluids. The results show that the ratio of CO2 to N2 is the significant factor affecting the huff and puff effect, and the sensitivity order is CO2 to N2 ratio, gas-steam ratio and steam injection rate. The optimal injection parameter combination is as follows: the steam injection rate is 200 t/d, the gas-steam ratio is 300 m3/t, and the ratio of CO2 to N2 is 70%:30%. Viscosity deduction of muti-component thermal fluids has two regions: high temperature viscosity reduction and CO2 dissolution viscosity reduction region. The results of this study have theoretical guiding significance for the optimization of injection-production parameters of multiple thermal fluids huff and puff, and can be further applied to field practice.</description>
      <author>Hua Ma, Bing Bo, Aiguo Xu, Lun Zhao, Wenqi Zhao, Fachao Shan, Chenggang Wang, Minghui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-0260-2_78</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial-temporal Dynamics and Driving Forces of Provincial CO2 Emission Responsibilities in China from Multiple Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47260/amae/1447</link>
      <description>Tie Dai, Yazhou Zhao, Advances in Management and Applied Economics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393116592

                Abstract A comprehensive analysis of the carbon emission profile of Chinese provinces from multiple perspectives is required to develop equitable and effective policies to reduce carbon emissions. This study estimates the carbon dioxide (CO2) emission responsibilities of China&#8217;s 30 provinces and 22 sectors from production, consumption, and income-based perspectives from 2012 to 2017. Structural decomposition analysis (SDA) is used to determine the driving forces of changes in CO2 emissions in China from 2012 to 2017. The results indicate the following. (1) The dominant CO2 emission sectors are the Electric Power, Steam, and Hot Water industry and the Smelting and Pressing of Metals industry. (2) The scale effect of the initial input is the dominant factor affecting the growth of CO2 emissions, followed by the scale effect of the final demand from 2012 to 2017. (3) The structural effect of the production output is the primary carbon reduction factor, followed by the structural effect of the intermediate product input and the carbon intensity effect. Based on these results, recommendations are provided to reduce CO2 emissions, such as developing green and low-carbon technologies, revising and optimizing the energy composition, accelerating the green transition, and a science-based approach to investment. Keywords: Multiple perspectives, China&#8217;s Provinces, Spatial-temporal evolution, MRIO model, SDA model.</description>
      <author>Tie Dai, Yazhou Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47260/amae/1447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The use of algae as carbon dioxide absorber in heat production industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24425/aep.2024.149428</link>
      <description>Pawe&#322; Kupczak, Sylwester Kulig, Archives of Environmental Protection. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392959495

                There are approximately 15 million users of system heat in Poland, but unfortunately nearly 70% of the fuel used in heat production is fossil fuel. Therefore, the CO2 emission reduction in the heat production industry is becoming one of the key challenges. City Heat Distribution Enterprise Ltd. in Nowy S&#261;cz (Miejskie Przedsi&#281;biorstwo Energetyki Cieplnej sp. z o.o.) has been conducting a self-financed research and development project entitled The use of algae as carbon dioxide absorbers at MPEC Nowy S&#261;cz. The project deals with postcombustion CO2 capture using Chlorella vulgaris algae. As a result of tests conducted in a 1000 l hermetic container under optimal temperature and light conditions, the recovery of biomass can be performed in weekly cycles, yielding approximately 25 kilograms of biomass per year. Assuming that half of the dry mass of the algae is carbon, it can be said that 240 grams of carbon is bound in one cycle, which, converted to CO2, gives 880 grams of this gas. Our results showed that around 45.8 kilograms of CO2 per year was absorbed. Additionally, it is possible to use waste materials and by-products of technological processes as a nutrient medium for algae</description>
      <author>Pawe&#322; Kupczak, Sylwester Kulig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24425/aep.2024.149428</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
