<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 01:19:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous electrochemical upgrading of Polyethylene Terephthalate plastic and carbon dioxide into valuable chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124667</link>
      <description>Hongxia Liu, Ziqing Wang, Yanan He, Xin Hu, Lei Liu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403077498

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongxia Liu, Ziqing Wang, Yanan He, Xin Hu, Lei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover: Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Supported Low&#8208;Nuclearity Cluster Catalysts for Highly Selective Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction to Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416813</link>
      <description>Bing Shao, Du Shu Huang, Rui&#8208;Kang Huang, Xing&#8208;Lu He, Yan Luo, Yi&#8208;Lei Xiang, Linbin Jiang, Min Dong, Shixiong Li, Zhong Zhang, Jin Huang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082653

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Shao, Du Shu Huang, Rui&#8208;Kang Huang, Xing&#8208;Lu He, Yan Luo, Yi&#8208;Lei Xiang, Linbin Jiang, Min Dong, Shixiong Li, Zhong Zhang, Jin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover: Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Supported Low&#8208;Nuclearity Cluster Catalysts for Highly Selective Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction to Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416813</link>
      <description>Bing Shao, Du Shu Huang, Rui&#8208;Kang Huang, Xing&#8208;Lu He, Yan Luo, Yi&#8208;Lei Xiang, Linbin Jiang, Min Dong, Shixiong Li, Zhong Zhang, Jin Huang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082707

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Shao, Du Shu Huang, Rui&#8208;Kang Huang, Xing&#8208;Lu He, Yan Luo, Yi&#8208;Lei Xiang, Linbin Jiang, Min Dong, Shixiong Li, Zhong Zhang, Jin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Surfactant in Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction in the Absence of Metal Cations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00040</link>
      <description>Hansaem Jang, Adrian M. Gardner, Lucy Jayne Walters, Alex R. Neale, Laurence J. Hardwick, J.S. Roberts, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403084997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hansaem Jang, Adrian M. Gardner, Lucy Jayne Walters, Alex R. Neale, Laurence J. Hardwick, J.S. Roberts</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Conjugated Nickel(II)&#8208;Acetylide Framework for Efficient Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418269</link>
      <description>Yingying Qin, Yang Wang, Jian Lu, Linli Xu, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403129175

                The incorporation of transition&#8208;metal single atoms as molecular functional entities into the skeleton of graphdiyne (GDY) to construct novel two&#8208;dimensional (2D) metal&#8208;acetylide frameworks, known as metalated graphynes (MGYs), is a promising strategy for developing efficient catalysts, which can combine the tunable charge transfer of GDY frameworks, the catalytic activity of metal and the precise distribution of single metallic centers. Herein, four highly conjugated MGY photocatalysts based on NiII, PdII, PtII, and HgII were synthesized for the first time using the &#8216;bottom&#8208;up&#8217; strategy through the use of M&#8211;C bonds (&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;M&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;). Remarkably, the NiII&#8208;based graphyne (TEPY&#8208;Ni&#8208;GY) exhibited the highest CO generation rate of 18.3 mmol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1 and a selectivity of 98.8%. This superior performance is attributed to the synergistic effects of pyrenyl and &#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;Ni(PBu3)2&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211; moieties. The pyrenyl block functions as an intramolecular &#960;&#8208;conjugation channel, facilitating kinetically favorable electron transfer, while the &#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;Ni(PBu3)2&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211; moiety serves as the catalytic site that enhances CO2 adsorption and activation, thereby suppressing competitive hydrogen evolution. This study provides a new perspective on MGY&#8208;based photocatalysts for developing highly active and low&#8208;cost catalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Yingying Qin, Yang Wang, Jian Lu, Linli Xu, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide and Nitrate Reduction Reactions Tailoring Kinetics Over Cu2o with Mesoporous Carbon Channels for Boosting Electrocatalytic Urea Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4978955</link>
      <description>Jiamin Zhao, Ying Yuan, Meimei Kou, Jinsheng Zhao, Wei Lin, Jinsheng Zhao, Panagiotis Tsiakaras, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403183577

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiamin Zhao, Ying Yuan, Meimei Kou, Jinsheng Zhao, Wei Lin, Jinsheng Zhao, Panagiotis Tsiakaras</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4978955</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in MXene-based frameworks towards photocatalytic hydrogen production, carbon dioxide reduction and pollutant degradation: Current challenges and future prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216226</link>
      <description>Zeeshan Ajmal, Asif Hayat, Abdul Qadeer, Yuzeng Zhao, Essam H. Ibrahim, Mahmood Ul Haq, Kanwal Iqbal, Mohd Imran, Mohammed Kuku, Iftikhar Hussain, Hamid Ali, Yasin Orooji, John L. Zhou, Teng Ben, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 523(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403195408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeeshan Ajmal, Asif Hayat, Abdul Qadeer, Yuzeng Zhao, Essam H. Ibrahim, Mahmood Ul Haq, Kanwal Iqbal, Mohd Imran, Mohammed Kuku, Iftikhar Hussain, Hamid Ali, Yasin Orooji, John L. Zhou, Teng Ben</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel (II) Complexes Bearing Electron Donating OR/OH Groups on a Tetradentate Ligand Scaffold for Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-f9djd-v2</link>
      <description>Sonya Manafe, Gbolagade Olajide, Chance M. Boudreaux, Fengrui Qu, Logan M. Whitt, Patrick Pridemore, James Fletcher Hall, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, Elizabeth T. Papish, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403202205

                Nickel (II) complexes bearing tetradentate NCCN ligands comprised of optionally protic pyridine and N-heterocyclic carbene (NHC) donors have been synthesized and used as catalysts for carbon dioxide reduction. These complexes were synthesized bearing OMe, OBn, or OH substituents on the pyridine rings and were characterized by 1H NMR, 13C NMR, UV-Vis, IR, HR-MS, and single crystal X-ray diffraction. The OH substituent was partially deprotonated as shown by the crystal structure. Electrochemical studies show that these nickel complexes undergo two electron reduction events prior to CO2 reduction. Catalytic current enhancement under CO2 relative to N2 is not observed under dry conditions, but the addition of proton sources leads to modest current enhancement (icat/ip &lt; 2). Visible light driven photochemical CO2 reduction with a photosensitizer (Ir(ppy)3 where ppy = 2-phenylpyridine) and sacrificial electron and proton donors was studied, and formate is the major product with ~10:1 formate to CO production. Electron donor groups (OMe, OBn, OH) do not enhance formate production (relative to H analog), and CO production is only slightly enhanced. Overall with Ni(II), the tetradentate ligands are comparable to recently published pincer ligands for sensitized CO2 reduction, but pincer ligands offer a clear advantage in self-sensitized catalysis.</description>
      <author>Sonya Manafe, Gbolagade Olajide, Chance M. Boudreaux, Fengrui Qu, Logan M. Whitt, Patrick Pridemore, James Fletcher Hall, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, Elizabeth T. Papish</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-f9djd-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of urban vegetation cover on CO2 reduction in the city</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31705/cers.2024.28</link>
      <description>H.K.P. Chanika, Nilanka Harshani Weerasinghe, R.U. Halwatura, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140935

                Rising urban carbon dioxide levels have emerged as a critical issue due to their adverse effects on public health and the environment. Trees are a natural and sustainable solution to mitigate urban carbon dioxide (CO2) concentrations, as they absorb CO2 from the atmosphere through photosynthesis. However, the specific relationship between tree density and CO2 concentration within cities is unclear. The main objectives of this research are to determine the relationship between tree density and CO2 concentration reduction in cities and to identify the optimum tree density to reduce the CO2 level in the city to obtain the required CO2 level. For this study, data were collected in the densely urbanized city of Colombo and various urban areas within the Hambantota district. Tree densities and CO2 concentration reduction data were collected from 300 sample plots, each with a fixed size of 50m x 50m, near roads in selected urban areas. When calculating tree density, it is important to calculate canopy volumes of trees. It depends on canopy height, crown diameter and canopy shape. The tree density of the sample plot was calculated by dividing the total canopy volume by the area of the sample plot. A digital portable CO2 meter was used to measure the CO2 level. First the CO2 concentration was measured at the centre of the road and then the CO2 concentration was measured at the centre of the sample plot. The reduction in CO2 level was calculated by the difference between these two readings. By analysing tree densities and CO2 concentration data collected through field data studies, a linear relationship was obtained between tree density and CO2 concentration reduction in urban areas. The plotted line got a R2 value of 0.8806 indicating a well-fitting model. Therefore, this linear plotted line can be described as a reasonable fitted line representing all collected data. Also, the data was classified based on the CO2 concentration in the centre of the road and the behaviour of the CO2 concentration reduction Vs tree density relationship was studied in each range. A linear relationship was obtained in each of those ranges. When all the collected data were classified as residential and non-residential based on the usage of the sample plots, the R2 values obtained from those graphs were higher than the R2 value of the graph drawn without classification. The R2 value of the graph for non-residential areas has increased relative to the value of the graph for residential areas. Accordingly, classifying in this manner led to an increase in the accuracy of the relationship. Using these relationships, the optimum tree density required to obtain the required CO2 reduction in urban areas can be identified. The results of this study will be valuable for policymakers and urban planners looking for ways to improve air quality and create more sustainable urban environments.</description>
      <author>H.K.P. Chanika, Nilanka Harshani Weerasinghe, R.U. Halwatura</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31705/cers.2024.28</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction Mechanism of Lattice Tuning of Copper by Silver Single&#8208;Crystal Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400757</link>
      <description>Tao Zheng, Xia&#8208;Guang Zhang, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140632

                Intermolecular interactions and adsorbate coverage on a metal electrode's surface/interface play an important role in CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Herein, the activity and selectivity of CO2RR on bimetallic electrode, where a full monoatomic Cu layer covers on Ag surface (CuML/Ag) are investigated by using density functional theory calculations. The surface geometric and electronic structure results indicate that there is high electrocatalytic activity for CO2RR on the CuML/Ag electrode. Specifically, the CuML/Ag surface can accelerate the H2O and CO2 adsorption and hydrogenation while lowering the reaction energy of the rate&#8208;determining step. The structure parameters of chemisorbed CO2 with and without H2O demonstrate that activated H2O not only promotes the C&#8208;O dissociation but also provides the protons required for CO2RR on the CuML/Ag electrode surface. Furthermore, the various reaction mechanism diagrams indicate that the CuML/Ag electrode has high selectivity for CO2RR, and the efficiency of products can be regulated by modulating the reaction's electric potential.</description>
      <author>Tao Zheng, Xia&#8208;Guang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene-Based Photocatalysts for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-66260-7_29</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; M. Barrera&#8208;Andrade, Elim Albiter, Miguel A. Valenzuela, E. Rojas Garc&#237;a, Advanced structured materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403072741

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; M. Barrera&#8208;Andrade, Elim Albiter, Miguel A. Valenzuela, E. Rojas Garc&#237;a</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-66260-7_29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal trajectory of technological growth in Sub-Sahara Africa: new insights for achieving carbon dioxide emissions reduction and environmental sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10668-024-05467-8</link>
      <description>Seidu Abdulai Jamatutu, Kashif Abbass, Huaming Song, Sidique Gawusu, Kyei Emmanuel Yeboah, Environment Development and Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403209063

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seidu Abdulai Jamatutu, Kashif Abbass, Huaming Song, Sidique Gawusu, Kyei Emmanuel Yeboah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10668-024-05467-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Study of the Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 in Aprotic Ionic Liquid in Air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401832</link>
      <description>Go Iijima, Kazumitsu Sugiura, Kazuhiko Morishita, Hajime Shingai, Junichi Naruse, Atsushi Yamamoto, Yuki Fujita, Hiroaki Yoto, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140372

                The capture and electrochemical conversion of dilute CO2 in air is a promising approach to mitigate global warming. Aiming to increase the efficiency of the electrochemical reduction of CO2, we fabricated electrodes and developed a custom&#8208;designed sealed electrochemical reaction system to study the mechanism of this conversion. The performance of three metal electrodes, Ag, Cu, and SUS 316L, was compared in an aprotic ionic liquid as the electrolyte to monitor the CO2 concentration and chemical reactions using a CO2 sensor and diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy and Raman spectroscopy in CO2/N2 (400 ppm CO2 and 99.96% N2) or synthetic air (400 ppm CO2, 21% O2, and 79% N2). The CO2 concentration decreased at negative potentials and was more drastic in synthetic air than in CO2/N2. At negative potential in synthetic air, IR revealed carbon monoxide, carbonate, or peroxydicarbonate on the Ag, Cu, or SUS 316L electrodes, respectively. Reaction intermediates were identified using Raman spectroscopy. Superoxide (O2&#8226;&#8722;), produced by the reduction of O2 on each electrode, promotes the electrochemical reduction of CO2 whose reduction potential is higher on the negative side than that of O2. This research deepens our understanding of the electrochemical capture/release and conversion of dilute CO2.</description>
      <author>Go Iijima, Kazumitsu Sugiura, Kazuhiko Morishita, Hajime Shingai, Junichi Naruse, Atsushi Yamamoto, Yuki Fujita, Hiroaki Yoto</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction Over Materials Derived from Cu&#8208;Based Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401551</link>
      <description>Yining Li, Abhishek Dutta Chowdhury, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403195807

                The direct valorization of carbon dioxide (CO2) into value&#8208;added chemicals offers an efficient and attractive approach to promoting carbon neutrality. Among the available methods, the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) for producing multi&#8208;carbon products (C2+) is gaining attention due to its simplicity. However, achieving selective control over product formation remains a challenge. One key issue is the lack of a reliable correlation between the physicochemical properties of electrocatalytic materials and their activity and selectivity.To address this gap, we conducted a model study in which carbonized CuxZny@C materials, derived from metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs), were synthesized with varying Cu/Zn ratios. The pyrolyzed bimetallic MOFs retained key properties of the original MOFs while also developing new characteristics. These subtle changes in physicochemical properties influenced product selectivity. Our findings showed that higher Zn doping favors the formation of single&#8208;carbon (C1) products, while it is less favorable for multi&#8208;carbon (C2+) products. Optimizing the Cu/Zn ratio was emphasized through characterization techniques, which will help guide the design of improved electrocatalytic systems for the eCO2RR process.</description>
      <author>Yining Li, Abhishek Dutta Chowdhury</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COmbined suN-Driven Oxidation and CO2 Reduction for renewable energy storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101006839</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4403221851

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101006839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Modified Nb2o5 Photocatalysts for High Performance of Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4974364</link>
      <description>Junli Chen, Tao Wang, Ziqi Yang, Pan Gao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403069376

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junli Chen, Tao Wang, Ziqi Yang, Pan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4974364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Metallosalen&#8208;based Covalent Organic Frameworks for Artificial Photosynthetic Diluted CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414287</link>
      <description>Hong Dong, Liang Fang, Kexin Chen, Jianxin Wei, Jiaxin Li, Xiu Qiao, Ya Wang, Fengming Zhang, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403189900

                Directly converting CO2 in flue gas using artificial photosynthetic technology represents a promising green approach for CO2 resource utilization. However, it remains a great challenge to achieve efficient reduction of CO2 from flue gas due to the decreased activity of photocatalysts in diluted CO2 atmosphere. Herein, we designed and synthesized a series of dual metallosalen&#8208;based covalent organic frameworks (MM&#8208;Salen&#8208;COFs, M: Zn, Ni, Cu) for artificial photosynthetic diluted CO2 reduction and confirmed their advantage in comparison to that of single metal M&#8208;Salen&#8208;COFs. As a results, the ZnZn&#8208;Salen&#8208;COF with dual Zn sites exhibits a prominent visible&#8208;light&#8208;driven CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion rate of 150.9 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 under pure CO2 atmosphere, which is ~6 times higher than that of single metal Zn&#8208;Salen&#8208;COF. Notably, the dual metal ZnZn&#8208;Salen&#8208;COF still displays efficient CO2 conversion activity of 102.1 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 under diluted CO2 atmosphere from simulated flue gas conditions (15% CO2), which is a record high activity among COFs&#8208; and MOFs&#8208;based photocatalysts under the same reaction conditions. Further investigations and theoretical calculations suggest that the synergistic effect between the neighboring dual metal sites in the ZnZn&#8208;Salen&#8208;COF facilitates low concentration CO2 adsorption and activation, thereby lowering the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step.</description>
      <author>Hong Dong, Liang Fang, Kexin Chen, Jianxin Wei, Jiaxin Li, Xiu Qiao, Ya Wang, Fengming Zhang, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414287</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar light-assisted electrochemical CO2 reduction on Boron-doped Diamond cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00947a</link>
      <description>Goki Iwai, Andrea Fiorani, Chiaki Terashima, Yasuaki Einaga, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403192270

                In this study, photoelectrochemical water oxidation with a hematite (&#945;-Fe 2 O 3 ) photoanode and electrochemical CO 2 reduction with a boron-doped diamond (BDD) cathode were combined to convert CO 2 into formic acid under...</description>
      <author>Goki Iwai, Andrea Fiorani, Chiaki Terashima, Yasuaki Einaga</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00947a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT and microkinetic modeling study of pressure effects on electroreduction reduction of CO2 to ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161421</link>
      <description>Xiaowen Wang, Fei Ma, Haiqiao Wei, Jiaying Pan, Wenjia Li, Jun Zhao, Xiaotao Yang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403117340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaowen Wang, Fei Ma, Haiqiao Wei, Jiaying Pan, Wenjia Li, Jun Zhao, Xiaotao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Roles of Lattice Strain on Cu Doped Ag Nanosheet for Electrochemical Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4978806</link>
      <description>Mei Zhu, Ting Zhang, Xin Du, Jinlong Wu, Xiuli Wang, Jin Zhang, Feng Li, Jing Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403176482

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mei Zhu, Ting Zhang, Xin Du, Jinlong Wu, Xiuli Wang, Jin Zhang, Feng Li, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4978806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403224119

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403223487

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403224103

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air pollution mitigation and CO2 emission reduction effects of heterogeneous enterprises synergistic agglomeration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10668-024-05497-2</link>
      <description>Jiamin Liu, Xiaoyu Ma, Jiaoning Zhang, Chiqun Hu, Qiuqiu Guo, Environment Development and Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403170973

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiamin Liu, Xiaoyu Ma, Jiaoning Zhang, Chiqun Hu, Qiuqiu Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10668-024-05497-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co Cluster-Modified Ni Nanoparticles with Superior Light-Driven Thermocatalytic Co2 Reduction by Ch4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4976153</link>
      <description>Qian Zhang, Mei Li, Yuhua Zhang, Na Sun, Dan Cheng, Peng Sun, Shaowen Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403093962

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Zhang, Mei Li, Yuhua Zhang, Na Sun, Dan Cheng, Peng Sun, Shaowen Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4976153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited Cu2o@Cu Hierarchical Structures for Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction: Morphological Tuning and Copper Mediation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4979269</link>
      <description>Wang Zhen, Yanmin Zhao, Weirui Chen, Gaozu Liao, Laisheng Li, Jing Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403176058

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wang Zhen, Yanmin Zhao, Weirui Chen, Gaozu Liao, Laisheng Li, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4979269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403223846

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zirconium-doped ultrathin copper nanowires for C1 and C2+ products in electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114591</link>
      <description>Wuyang Lin, Matteo Palma, Devis Di Tommaso, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403077551

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wuyang Lin, Matteo Palma, Devis Di Tommaso</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplanar synergy of copper-based electrocatalyst favors reduction of CO2 into C2+ products"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403224106

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00141a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of mesoporous sulfated ZnO-modified g-C3N4 and TiO2 photocatalysts for CO2 reduction in gas phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115089</link>
      <description>L.A. Al-Hajji, Adel A. Ismail, M. Alsaidi, Ahmed Abdel Nazeer, Ahmed Mohamed El&#8208;Toni, S.F. Al-Ruwayeh, S.A. Ahmed, T. Al-Sharrah, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403157643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L.A. Al-Hajji, Adel A. Ismail, M. Alsaidi, Ahmed Abdel Nazeer, Ahmed Mohamed El&#8208;Toni, S.F. Al-Ruwayeh, S.A. Ahmed, T. Al-Sharrah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH4 and CO2 Reductions from Methanol Production Using Municipal Solid Waste Gasification with Hydrogen Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198649</link>
      <description>Mohammad Ostadi, D.R. Cohn, Guiyan Zang, L. Bromberg, Sustainability. 16(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403190063

                This study evaluates the greenhouse gas (GHG) impacts of converting municipal solid waste (MSW) into methanol, focusing on both landfill methane (CH&#8324;) emission avoidance and the provision of cleaner liquid fuels with lower carbon intensity. We conduct a life cycle assessment (LCA) to assess potential GHG reductions from MSW gasification to methanol, enhanced with hydrogen produced via natural gas pyrolysis or water electrolysis. Hydrogen enhancement effectively doubles the methanol yield from a given amount of MSW. Special attention is given to hydrogen production through natural gas pyrolysis due to its potential for lower-cost hydrogen and reduced reliance on renewable electricity compared to electrolytic hydrogen. Our analysis uses a case study of methanol production from an oxygen-fired entrained flow gasifier fed with refuse-derived fuel (RDF) simulated in Aspen HYSYS. The LCA incorporates the significant impact of landfill methane avoidance, particularly when considering the 20-year global warming potential (GWP). Based on the LCA, the process has illustrative net GHG emissions of 183 and 709 kgCO2e/t MeOH using renewable electricity for electrolytic hydrogen and pyrolytic hydrogen, respectively, for the 100-year GWP. The net GHG emissions using 20-year GWP are &#8722;1222 and &#8722;434 kgCO2e/t MeOH, respectively. Additionally, we analyze the sensitivity of net GHG emissions to varying levels of fugitive methane emissions.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Ostadi, D.R. Cohn, Guiyan Zang, L. Bromberg</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divergent Activity Shifts of Sn-Based Catalysts for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction: pH-Dependent Behavior of Single-Atom vs. Polyatomic Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-38nl4</link>
      <description>Yuhang Wang, Di Zhang, Bin Sun, Xue Jia, Linda Zhang, Hefeng Cheng, Jun Fan, Hao Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082874

                Tin (Sn)-based catalysts have been widely studied for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to produce formic acid, but the intricate influence of the structural sensitivity in single-atom Sn (e.g., Sn-N-C) and polyatomic Sn (e.g., SnOx and SnSx; x=1,2) on their pH-dependent performance remains enigmatic. Herein, we integrate large-scale data mining (with &gt;2,300 CO2RR catalysts from available experimental literature during the past decade), ab initio computations, machine learning force field accelerated molecular dynamic simulations, and pH-field coupled microkinetic modelling to unravel their pH dependence. We reveal a fascinating contrast: the electric field response of the binding strength of *OCHO on Sn-N4-C and polyatomic Sn exhibits opposite behaviors due to their differing dipole moment changes upon *OCHO formation. Such response leads to an intriguing opposite pH-dependent volcano evolution for Sn-N4-C and polyatomic Sn. Subsequent experimental validations of turnover frequency and current density under both neutral and alkaline conditions well aligned with our theoretical predictions. Most importantly, our analysis suggests the necessity of distinct optimization strategies for *OCHO binding energy on different types of Sn-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Wang, Di Zhang, Bin Sun, Xue Jia, Linda Zhang, Hefeng Cheng, Jun Fan, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-38nl4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Pre-sodium Hydroxide and Post-heat Treatments on Copper Oxide-Based Photocathode: A Perspective on Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting and CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11498-8</link>
      <description>Saowaluk Intarasiri, Surangkana Wannapop, Asanee Somdee, Journal of Electronic Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403187249

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saowaluk Intarasiri, Surangkana Wannapop, Asanee Somdee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11498-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important structural parameter for curvature effect of TM-N4 embeded C70 fullerenes as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction interpreted with machine learning and first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105233</link>
      <description>Aling Ma, Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403168428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aling Ma, Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Capture and Storage Via Electrochemical and Bioelectrochemical Techniques: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4314/cajost.v6i2.3</link>
      <description>John Tsado Mathew, Abel Inobeme, Yakubu Azeh, Musah Monday, Abdullahi Abdulkadir, Elijah Yanda Shaba, M. B. Etsuyankpa, Tanko S. Musa, A. I. Muhammad, Hina Ismail, Abubakar Mohammed Kanwa, Amos Mamman, Jonathan Hussaini, Caliphate Journal of Science and Technology. 6(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403103147

                The urgent need to mitigate climate change has spurred innovative research in carbon capture and storage (CCS) technologies. Electrochemical approaches utilize electrocatalysis and electrochemical reduction to capture carbon dioxide (CO2) from industrial emissions, demonstrating high selectivity and enabling the production of valuable chemicals and fuels from captured CO2. Bioelectrochemical techniques leverage microorganisms to convert CO2 into biomass or biofuels, enhancing carbon capture efficiency through biological and electrochemical synergy. Integrating bioelectrochemical systems with renewable energy sources provides a carbon-negative pathway, aiding industry decarbonization. This review underscores the transformative potential of these techniques in revolutionizing CCS strategies, emphasizing their role in addressing climate change while fostering a sustainable, circular economy.</description>
      <author>John Tsado Mathew, Abel Inobeme, Yakubu Azeh, Musah Monday, Abdullahi Abdulkadir, Elijah Yanda Shaba, M. B. Etsuyankpa, Tanko S. Musa, A. I. Muhammad, Hina Ismail, Abubakar Mohammed Kanwa, Amos Mamman, Jonathan Hussaini</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4314/cajost.v6i2.3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTEGRATED TECHNOLOGY OF BIOGAS UTILIZATION OF SOLID HOUSEHOLD WASTE LANDFILLS WITH THE PRODUCTION OF ELECTROCITY, HEAT AND CARBON DIOXIDE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33070/etars.3.2024.04</link>
      <description>Yu.V. Ivanov, Serhii Krushnevych, H.V. Zhuk, &#1051;.&#1056;. &#1054;&#1085;&#1086;&#1087;&#1072;, O.V. Verbovskyi, Dmitrii Komissarenko, Energy Technologies &amp; Resource Saving. 80(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403167145

                The presence of carbon dioxyl as a non-combustible admixture in the landfill biogas of solid household waste and the absorption of ambient air into the layer of landfill waste, and therefore its entry into the landfill gas, significantly reduces the concentration of methane in it, which affects the efficient operation of the gas piston engine of the power plant and the reduction of volumes electricity generation. With the use of computer modeling for the composition of biogas with an increased content of N2 and a reduced concentration of CH4 &#163; 32 %, calculations were made on the enrichment of biogas to concentrations of CH4 in it of 36&#8211;44 % due to the use of CO2 amine absorption technologies, in which the costs for the regeneration of the absorbent are compensated by the produced thermal energy of the gas piston engine of the power plant. The removal of carbon dioxide from biogas makes it possible to simultaneously increase the concentration of methane in it at the input to the heat engine, which contributes to the stable and efficient operation of the gas piston engine of the power plant and the increase in the amount of electricity generation as a result of energy utilization of landfill gas. The use of complex biogas utilization technology in the cogeneration mode allows obtaining not only electricity, but also heat, which can be used in absorption amine technologies for CO2 extraction from biogas and thus reducing carbon dioxide emissions into the atmosphere. Bibl. 17, Fig. 9, Tab. 3.</description>
      <author>Yu.V. Ivanov, Serhii Krushnevych, H.V. Zhuk, &#1051;.&#1056;. &#1054;&#1085;&#1086;&#1087;&#1072;, O.V. Verbovskyi, Dmitrii Komissarenko</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33070/etars.3.2024.04</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Reservoir Characteristics of Potential Carbon Dioxide Storage Sites in the Northern South Yellow Sea Basin, Offshore Eastern China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12101733</link>
      <description>Di Luo, Yong Yuan, Jianwen Chen, Qing Li, Jie Liang, Hualin Zhao, Journal of Marine Science and Engineering. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403074530

                The geological storage of carbon dioxide (CO2) in offshore saline aquifers stands as a primary option for reducing CO2 emissions in coastal regions. China&#8217;s coastal regions, particularly Shandong and Jiangsu provinces, face significant challenges in CO2 reduction. Therefore, evaluating the feasibility of CO2 geological storage in the adjacent seas is critical. To assess the suitability of a CO2 storage site, understanding its structural and reservoir characteristics is essential to mitigate injection and storage risks. In this study, we analyzed the structural characteristics and potential traps of the Yantai Depression in the South Yellow Sea Basin based on seismic data interpretation. We further conducted well logging analysis and post-stack seismic inversion to obtain lithological data, including acoustic impedance and sandstone content percentages from the Cenozoic Funing Formation, Dainan&#8211;Sanduo Formation, and Yancheng Formation. Our findings highlight that the Yantai Depression in the South Yellow Sea Basin exhibits diverse structural traps and favorable reservoir&#8211;caprock combinations, suggesting promising geological conditions for CO2 storage. This area emerges as a suitable candidate for implementing CO2 geological storage initiatives.</description>
      <author>Di Luo, Yong Yuan, Jianwen Chen, Qing Li, Jie Liang, Hualin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12101733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reduction in the Number of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Defects in the Process of Obtaining Breathing Air for Hyperbaric Oxygen Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2478/phr-2023-0001</link>
      <description>Arkadiusz Wo&#378;niak, Polish Hyperbaric Research. 82(1)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4403162272

                Abstract Maintaining a stable carbon dioxide content in the process of obtaining breathing air is essential for safe underwater operations and the reduction of the cost of losses resulting from a poor quality product. The paper addresses the modification of the hyperbaric breathing air production process in terms of eliminating harmful carbon dioxide contaminants. It presents the effects of the modifications made to the process in order to minimise the proportion of defects. A description is given of the status of the process before and after the correction in terms of the identified areas of improvement leading to the achievement of the defined critical requirements of the process. Achievement of the objective to rationalise the breathing air production process was confirmed by results of tests carried out at KTPP AMW 1 based on the compressed air supply system of the DGKN - 120 complex 2 .</description>
      <author>Arkadiusz Wo&#378;niak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2478/phr-2023-0001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomass Loss and Land Use Land Cover from Habitat Conversion in Kahe Forest Reserve, Northern Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i104500</link>
      <description>Adili Y. Zella, Luzabeth J. Kitali, International Journal of Environment and Climate Change. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403132622

                This paper offers a less known biomass depletion and atmospheric carbon emissions due to habitat alteration in the Kahe Forest Reserve (KFR), Northern Tanzania, during a two-decade span (2003&#8211;2023). The paper measures biomass depletion, carbon emissions, carbon dioxide emissions, and the consequent economic effects due to losses in carbon trading. The study used the NAFORMA methodology alongside geospatial analysis to evaluate the ecological and economic impacts of land-use and land-cover alterations inside the reserve. The findings indicate a significant biomass reduction of roughly 23,019.6 tonnes, with corresponding carbon emissions totaling 10,819.2 tonnes. The study quantifies carbon dioxide emissions at 39,706.46 tonnes and assesses a carbon trade loss amounting to US$ 158,825.83. The data underscore the considerable environmental issues confronting KFR, intensified by a 141.4% surge in the human population in the adjacent districts from 1967 to 2022. This demographic pressure has resulted in unlawful agricultural encroachment, although existing protective restrictions, undermining the forest's ecological integrity and carbon sequestration potential. The results highlight the immediate necessity for action to prevent additional habitat deterioration and biodiversity decline. The study concludes with multiple policy recommendations, such as strengthened enforcement of forest protection measures, enhanced community engagement and education, promotion of sustainable agricultural practices beyond the reserve, restoration initiatives, and the incorporation of KFR into global carbon markets. These measures are essential for preserving the ecological integrity of the reserve and guaranteeing the sustainable stewardship of the region's natural resources.</description>
      <author>Adili Y. Zella, Luzabeth J. Kitali</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i104500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Land Use and Land Cover Changes on Biomass and Carbon Sequestration in Coastal Kinondoni, Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i104498</link>
      <description>Luzabeth J. Kitali, Adili Y. Zella, International Journal of Environment and Climate Change. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403137310

                This study analyzes the impact of land use and land cover (LULC) alterations on biomass depletion and carbon sequestration in Kinondoni, Tanzania, over a 30-year period from 1993 to 2023. This study employs the National Forest Resources Monitoring and Assessment (NAFORMA) models and geospatial analysis to quantify the environmental and economic effects of urbanization, agricultural growth, and infrastructural development on local ecosystems. The deterioration of mangrove forests, essential for carbon sequestration, has resulted in an estimated biomass reduction of 65,600 tonnes, with mangroves representing 93.1% of the overall losses. This deterioration has markedly diminished the region's carbon storage capacity, leading to the emission of 30,830 tonnes of carbon, which is equivalent to 113,150 tonnes of carbon dioxide (CO&#8322;). The economic impact of this decrease in carbon sequestration capacity is estimated at around US$ 452,610, signifying a lost opportunity for carbon trading. The degradation of mangroves is recognized as the principal cause of these losses. The study highlights the critical necessity for conservation and restoration measures, specifically aimed at mangrove ecosystems, to alleviate additional environmental and economic deterioration. It promotes sustainable land use regulations and the incorporation of ecosystem services valuation in decision-making processes to improve resilience in coastal Tanzania.</description>
      <author>Luzabeth J. Kitali, Adili Y. Zella</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i104498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effects on Climate Change Due to Kitchen Waste Composting and Emissions of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.70436/nuijb.v3i02.198</link>
      <description>Nora&#8217;aini Ali, Riaz Husnain, Munir Baber Bakht, Iqbal Tasawar, No host. 03(ICCC(special))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403154375

                The emission of greenhouse gases into the atmosphere due to anthropogenic activities, including the disposal of large quantities of organic kitchen waste into the environment. There is currently no evidence suggesting the likelihood of a future reversal or pause in emissions. The process of carbon sequestration serves to mitigate the emission of greenhouse gases from kitchen organic waste through the creation of compost. Composting is proposed as a potentially effective and cost-efficient solution to address the issue production of kitchen organic waste, which is contributing to environmental pollution. The escalation in complete carbon dioxide and microbial biomass carbon emissions can be attributed to a concurrent reduction in the levels of dissolved organic carbon as the treatments experienced a noteworthy decrease in dissolved organic carbon concentrations. The application of banana and potato compost has been found to have a positive impact on the macro aggregates of soil, leading to an increase in soil stability due to the compost's ability to stabilize soil particles. The study indicate that composting represents the most effective approach for mitigating greenhouse gas emissions originating from kitchen organic waste, while also enhancing the biological and physicochemical characteristics of soil.</description>
      <author>Nora&#8217;aini Ali, Riaz Husnain, Munir Baber Bakht, Iqbal Tasawar</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.70436/nuijb.v3i02.198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Sustainable Goals Emissions Reduction Value to Measure Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-7230-2.ch007</link>
      <description>J. Bala Murugan, L. Priya Dharsini, C. Prabakaran, P. S. Ranjit, S. Menaka, R. Senthamil Selvan, Practice, progress, and proficiency in sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403122357

                The Sustainable Development Goals, or SDGs, goal indicators and the steps taken to slow down climate change have trade-offs and synergies. Although some research has evaluated these linkages, nothing is known about how much of an interaction there is. This section illustrates how reducing CO2 emissions relates to the SDGs. They created the &#8220;marginal SDG-emissions-reduction values (MSVs),&#8221; which show how a unit decrease in CO2 emissions affects certain SDG indicators on a marginal basis. This measure was utilised and may be used for national evaluations. They discovered significant correlations between rates of CO2 emission reduction and several SDG objectives. For example, a 1% reduction in CO2 may save 0.57% of premature deaths linked to air pollution (SDG3), whereas the same CO2 reduction can result in a 0.026% drop in mean species richness (SDG15) (excluding the effects of climate change). Our results help evaluate the implications of CO2 emissions reduction objectives for the SDGs, which will assist in informing national climate strategies.</description>
      <author>J. Bala Murugan, L. Priya Dharsini, C. Prabakaran, P. S. Ranjit, S. Menaka, R. Senthamil Selvan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-7230-2.ch007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrokinetic Analysis&#8208;Driven Promotion of Electrocatalytic CO Reduction to n&#8208;Propanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406345</link>
      <description>Yaqin Yan, Kunhao Liu, Chao Yang, Yangshen Chen, Ximeng Lv, Cejun Hu, Lijuan Zhang, Gengfeng Zheng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403109751

                Abstract The electrocatalytic carbon dioxide or carbon monoxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR or CORR) features a sustainable method for reducing carbon emissions and producing value&#8208;added chemicals. However, the generation of C 3 products with higher energy density and market values, such as n&#8208;propanol, remains highly challenging, which is attributed to the unclear formation mechanism of C 3+ versus C 2 products. In this work, by the Tafel slope analysis, electrolyte pH correlation exploration, and the kinetic analysis of CO partial pressure fitting, it is identified that both n&#8208;propanol and C 2 products share the same rate&#8208;determining step, which is the coupling of two C 1 intermediates via the derivation of the Butler&#8211;Volmer equation. In addition, inspired by the mechanistic study, it is proposed that a high OH &#9472; concentration and a water&#8208;limited environment are beneficial for promoting the subsequent *C 2 &#8211;*C 1 coupling to n&#8208;propanol. At 5.0 m [OH &#8722; ], the partial current density of producing n&#8208;propanol ( j n&#8208;propanol ) reached 45 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is 35 and 1.3 times higher than that at 0.01 m [OH &#8722; ] and 1.0 m [OH &#8722; ], respectively. This study provides a comprehensive kinetic analysis of n&#8208;propanol production and suggests opportunities for designing new catalytic systems for promoting the C 3 production.</description>
      <author>Yaqin Yan, Kunhao Liu, Chao Yang, Yangshen Chen, Ximeng Lv, Cejun Hu, Lijuan Zhang, Gengfeng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Inhibition Phenomena in Cu&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Pt Oxidation by CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02218</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Shyam Bharatkumar Patel, J. Anibal Boscoboinik, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, Guangwen Zhou, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403183740

                This study investigates the oxidation behavior of Cu3Pt(100) in CO2 using a combination of ambient-pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, mass spectroscopy, and density functional theory modeling. Our in situ measurements reveal the simultaneous oxidation and reduction of Cu2O due to the opposing effects of atomic oxygen and CO generated from dissociative CO2 adsorption, leading to a dynamic equilibrium state of simultaneously occurring redox reactions. Complementary atomistic calculations elucidate the inhibitory effects of subsurface Pt enrichment and the counteracting roles of CO2 and CO in surface oxidation and reduction. These results provide mechanistic insights into the dissociative pathway of CO2 molecules and dynamic evolution of surface composition and reactivity of Cu-based alloy catalysts in CO2-rich environments, with broader implications for tuning gas&#8211;surface reactions by manipulating gas reactants or solid surface composition.</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Shyam Bharatkumar Patel, J. Anibal Boscoboinik, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, Guangwen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Interactive Effects of Technological Innovation, Transportation Industry Development, and CO2 Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198672</link>
      <description>Kaige An, Li Wang, Zhenning Wang, Zisen He, Yao Zhong, Jia Shen, Xiaohong Ren, Sustainability. 16(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403216540

                This paper aims to clarify the intricate relationships between technological innovation, transportation industry development, and CO2 emissions to facilitate a positive synergy among technology, the economy, and climate, advancing the fulfillment of the &#8216;double carbon&#8217; goal. Utilizing panel data from 30 provinces in China from 2005 to 2020, we employ the panel vector autoregressive model using a generalized method of moments to empirically examine the dynamic interactive effects between these participants. The findings reveal that the transportation industry significantly promoted the inhibitory impact of technological innovation on CO2 emissions. However, such reductions cannot counterbalance the rise in emissions from the transportation industry. Moreover, its effects varied significantly across regions. Specifically, transportation industry development within eastern China contributed to a shift in the local carbon emission effects from positive to negative under the positive influence of technological innovation. In the northeast, the transportation industry enhanced the inhibitory effect of technological innovation on CO2 emissions. In contrast, across the western region, industrial development in transportation intensified the role of technological innovation in promoting CO2 emissions. Furthermore, this work found that CO2 emissions notably diminished the CO2 reduction performance of technological innovation in the eastern part and enhanced this performance in the northeastern region. These findings further revealed the complex interplay between technological innovation, the transportation industry, and CO2 emissions. They offer insights for policymakers to tailor region-specific technologies to bolster the &#8216;dual carbon&#8217; goal and sustainable transportation development strategies, thereby achieving CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Kaige An, Li Wang, Zhenning Wang, Zisen He, Yao Zhong, Jia Shen, Xiaohong Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamical channel coupling in strong-field ionization of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1364/oe.537980</link>
      <description>Yalei Zhu, Zeyu Jiang, Zhongxue Ren, Guangru Bai, Xiaowei Wang, Dongwen Zhang, Jinlei Liu, Jing Zhao, Zengxiu Zhao, Optics Express. 32(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403065622

                We present a theoretical study employing the time-dependent density functional theory (TDDFT) to explore the effects of angle-resolved channel coupling in strong field ionization of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) molecules. Our results reveal significant angular sensitivity of both the channel-resolved ionization probabilities and the effects of laser-induced channel couplings. By applying a linearly polarized two-color field scheme, we demonstrate the ability to significantly modify the strength of the laser-induced coupling, evidenced by the changes in the population distributions among the ionic states induced by the strong-field ionization. Importantly, the two-color field optimally modulates the coupling strength at the alignment angle where ionization of the highest occupied molecular orbital (HOMO) electrons is most efficient. This optimization is attributed to the reduction of the electron shielding effect. Our research provides valuable insights into the coherent manipulation of electron distribution within the cation, paving the way for the precise control of ultrafast electron dynamics during strong-field ionization processes.</description>
      <author>Yalei Zhu, Zeyu Jiang, Zhongxue Ren, Guangru Bai, Xiaowei Wang, Dongwen Zhang, Jinlei Liu, Jing Zhao, Zengxiu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1364/oe.537980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Energy Management System for Generator&#8211;Battery Hybrid Power System in Ships: A Novel Approach with Optimal Control Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12101755</link>
      <description>EunMi Choi, Heemoon Kim, Journal of Marine Science and Engineering. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403112671

                Advancements in the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions from ships are driving the development of more efficient onboard power systems. The proposed non-equivalent parallel running operation system is explored in this study, which improves the efficiency of the main power generation source compared with traditional equal load-sharing methods used in power management systems. However, the asymmetric method reduces the efficiency of the auxiliary power sources. To address this issue, we propose a control method that integrates a battery system with an efficiency-based algorithm to optimize the overall system performance. The proposed approach involves establishing operation command values based on the characteristics of the power generation source and adjusting these commands according to the battery&#8217;s state of charge (SOC). MATLAB/Simulink simulations confirmed the effectiveness of this method across various operating modes and revealed no operational issues. When applied to a ship&#8217;s operating profile over 222 h, the method reduced fuel consumption by approximately 2.98 tons (5.57%) compared with conventional systems. Over 38 annual voyages, this reduction equates to savings of 115.96 tons of fuel or approximately 96.47 million Korean won. This study demonstrates that integrating an optimal efficiency algorithm into the energy management system significantly enhances both the propulsion and overall energy efficiency of ships.</description>
      <author>EunMi Choi, Heemoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12101755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Dynamics Simulations for Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction: Bridging Macroscopic Experimental Observations and Microscopic Explanatory Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413703</link>
      <description>Yanzheng He, Mengfan Wang, Haoqing Ji, Qiyang Cheng, Sisi Liu, Yunfei Huan, Qian Tao, Chenglin Yan, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403202351

                Abstract Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) has been recognized as a promising route to convert carbon emissions to high&#8208;value chemicals and fuels. Significant breakthroughs are usually inseparable from deeper understanding of reaction mechanisms. To this end, molecular dynamics (MD) simulations have been invaluable in providing detailed insights into elucidation of complex reaction pathways and prediction of overall electrochemical performance, thus bridging macroscopic experimental observations and microscopic explanatory mechanisms. Directed by MD simulations, tremendous efforts have been devoted toward enhancing the CO 2 RR with rational design of electrocatalyst and efficient construction of electrode/electrolyte interface. Herein, a comprehensive review of applications of MD simulations in CO 2 RR is emerged. To begin with, specific fundamentals along with familiar methods such as algorithm and force fields of various MD simulations have been summed up. Followed, employment of MD simulations in optimization of CO 2 RR is introduced, encompassing interpretation of electrocatalyst activity, explanation of electrolyte effect, and investigation of electrode microenvironment. Definitively, imminent challenges and avenues for optimization in future MD simulations are contemplated, envisioning this review as a guiding beacon for future endeavors aimed at harnessing MD simulations to propel CO 2 RR toward a realm of heightened efficiency, economic viability, and practical utility.</description>
      <author>Yanzheng He, Mengfan Wang, Haoqing Ji, Qiyang Cheng, Sisi Liu, Yunfei Huan, Qian Tao, Chenglin Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Approach for Improving Flame Retardancy of Automotive Interior Upholstery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21605/cukurovaumfd.1559895</link>
      <description>&#214;zlem Erdem Y&#305;lmaz, Ali Can Y&#305;lmaz, Ahmet &#199;o&#351;gun, &#199;ukurova &#220;niversitesi M&#252;hendislik Fak&#252;ltesi Dergisi. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403074905

                This study presents the flame retardant (FR) performance of chemically treated automotive upholstery fabrics using two different impregnation methods of Resin Transfer Molding (RTM) and supercritical carbon dioxide (scCO2). Referring to the related standards, untreated seat fabric obtained from seat upholstery of a bus (neat fabric, NF) and treated fabric samples underwent burning rate (BR) and limiting oxygen index (LOI) tests to compare effect of treatment and impregnation methods on FR performance. Thermal analysis was also conducted on the samples considering onset degradation temperatures and char yields. The results showed that BR and LOI of all samples were in acceptable range and treatment provided enhancement in FR performance of NF. The treated sample using scCO2 method gave the highest LOI value of 32% and the lowest BR of 21 mm/min subtending to 18.5% increase in LOI and 30% reduction in BR compared to those of NF. The performance of treatment in RTM was worse than that of scCO2 and better than that of NF. The results confirm that both treatment and methods used in this study give promising results for safety against fire in transportation vehicles.</description>
      <author>&#214;zlem Erdem Y&#305;lmaz, Ali Can Y&#305;lmaz, Ahmet &#199;o&#351;gun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21605/cukurovaumfd.1559895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revitalizing subterranean spaces: a comprehensive study on enhancing air quality in underground shopping malls for sustainable urban living</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s42834-024-00231-z</link>
      <description>Kichul Kim, Jiwoong Kim, Yun Gyu Lee, Seunghwan Wi, Sumin Kim, Sustainable Environment Research. 34(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403197110

                Abstract Cities worldwide are increasingly turning to underground spaces to address the challenges posed by high population density. These subterranean areas are now utilized for various purposes such as offices, shopping malls, subway terminals, and underground sidewalks. However, the semi-closed nature of most underground spaces presents difficulties in ensuring a comfortable environment due to the lack of natural ventilation. This study focuses on a representative underground shopping mall in South Korea, utilizing preliminary surveys and long-term sensor monitoring to identify existing problems. The aging ventilation system was retrofitted to enhance and assess indoor air quality. As a result, concentrations of carbon dioxide, total volatile organic compounds, and radon were reduced by over 33, 74, and 98%, respectively, while particulate matter with a diameter of 2.5 &#956;m or less (PM 2.5 ) concentrations remained the same as before. This not only contributed to maintaining proper indoor air quality, but also led to a reduction in total energy consumption. The goal of this project is to improve air quality in facilities located in underground spaces, such as underground shopping malls, where indoor air quality management is challenging, thereby creating a safe and healthy environment for users and enhancing the overall functionality of the facility.</description>
      <author>Kichul Kim, Jiwoong Kim, Yun Gyu Lee, Seunghwan Wi, Sumin Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s42834-024-00231-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life cycle assessment of energy green transition goals in Slovenia and Serbia: Heat pump example</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2298/tsci240618222t</link>
      <description>Jelena Topi&#263; Bo&#382;i&#269;, Simon Muhi&#269;, Mirko Komatina, Milica Peri&#263;, Jo&#382;e Dimnik, Thermal Science. None(00)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403192692

                Heat pumps are a promising technology to reduce greenhouse gas emissions (GHGE). Their use benefits from decarbonization of the national electricity mixes across the EU, as running on cleaner electricity would reduce the emissions associated with the heat generated from heat pumps. The study aimed to perform a life cycle assessment (LCA) to compare the impact of using heat pumps as a heating source in Slovenia and Serbia under different electricity scenarios that align with measures presented in National Energy and Climate plans. The results show significant differences in the environmental profiles of Serbian and Slovenian electricity sectors and improvements from the current to the future mixes (2030) with a higher share of renewables such as photovoltaics. In the impact category of global warming, an 84.7 % higher value of 1 MJ of heat produced by ground source heat pump in Serbia (0.080 kg CO2 eq) was observed compared to Slovenia (0.033 kg CO2 eq) and 85.9 % higher value compared to Europe (0.032 kg CO2 eq). The reduction in the impact category global warming in NECP 2030 scenarios that model reduction in coal and increase solar PV was observed in both countries (-17.1% Serbia; -28.6 % Slovenia). On the other hand, an increase in the impact category of mineral resource scarcity was observed, with values higher in Slovenia than in Serbia due to a higher share of PV. The study demonstrates that LCA provides a powerful tool to consider GHGE reduction and other environmental impacts, such as land use and mineral resource scarcity, and it can be used to support decision-makers dealing with future national energy plans and decarbonization strategies.</description>
      <author>Jelena Topi&#263; Bo&#382;i&#269;, Simon Muhi&#269;, Mirko Komatina, Milica Peri&#263;, Jo&#382;e Dimnik</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2298/tsci240618222t</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Evaluation of CO2 + SiCl4 Binary Mixture in Recompression Brayton Cycle for Warm Climates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102155</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ehtisham Siddiqui, Khalid H. Almitani, Processes. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403106930

                This work demonstrates the potential of CO2 + SiCl4 binary mixture as a working fluid for power generation cycle. Recompression Brayton cycle configuration is considered due to its proven record of high performance for medium- to high-temperature sources. The objective of this study is to assess the thermodynamic performance of a recompression Brayton cycle using a CO2 + SiCl4 binary mixture as a working fluid, particularly under warm climate conditions. The cycle is simulated using the Peng&#8211;Robinson equation of state in Aspen Hysys (v11) software, and the model is validated by comparing VLE data against experimental data from the literature. The analysis involves the assessment of cycle&#8217;s thermal efficiency and exergy efficiency under warm climatic conditions, with a minimum cycle temperature of 40 &#176;C. The results demonstrate a notable improvement in the cycle&#8217;s thermodynamic performance with CO2 + SiCl4 binary mixture compared to pure CO2. A small concentration (5%) of SiCl4 in CO2 increases the thermal efficiency of the cycle from 41.7% to 43.4%. Moreover, irreversibility losses in the cooler and the heat recovery unit are significantly lower with the CO2 + SiCl4 binary mixture than with pure CO2. This improvement enhances the overall exergy efficiency of the cycle, increasing it from 62.1% to 70.2%. The primary reason for this enhancement is the substantial reduction in irreversibility losses in both the cooler and the HTR. This study reveals that when using a CO2 + SiCl4 mixture, the concentration must be optimized to avoid condensation in the compressor, which can cause physical damage to the compressor blades and other components, as well as increase power input. This issue arises from the higher glide temperature of the mixture at increased SiCl4 concentrations and the limited heat recovery from the cycle.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ehtisham Siddiqui, Khalid H. Almitani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous seismic interpolation and statics estimation of land data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1190/geo2023-0668.1</link>
      <description>Ali M. Alfaraj, D. J. Verschuur, Felix J. Herrmann, Geophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403185372

                Imaging and inversion of land seismic data affected by complex weathering layers near the surface are challenging. When the data are additionally subsampled for economical reasons such as monitoring of sequestrated carbon dioxide and hydrogen, the problem is further exacerbated due to the combined influence of subsampling and weathering layers. On the one hand, interpolation performs poorly since the weathering layers reduce the data's coherency. On the other hand, near-surface corrections require knowledge of the subsurface model, separation between primaries and multiples as well as subsurface velocity estimation, which are difficult to perform from subsampled data. To overcome these hurdles, we combine seismic interpolation and statics estimation into a joint single rank-reduction-based algorithm. To our knowledge, this is the first time that this has been done. The proposed method simultaneously accounts for the weathering and subsampling effects, which both contribute to the low-rank structure destruction typically associated with statics-free densely-sampled data, to provide accurate reconstruction. Since a low-rank approximation is used for statics estimation, we also use it in rank-minimization interpolation as a cost-free initial solution to the optimization problem. As both statics estimation and interpolation operate in the midpoint-offset domain, we avoid the cost of transformations back and forth from the source-receiver to midpoint-offset transform domain. Consequently, the proposed reconstruction, which shows its potential on synthetic and field data is also computationally efficient.</description>
      <author>Ali M. Alfaraj, D. J. Verschuur, Felix J. Herrmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1190/geo2023-0668.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Climate Change on Plant Parasitic Nematodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69860/nobel.9786053359449.12</link>
      <description>Bet&#252;l G&#220;RKAN, Tolga G&#220;RKAN, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403108794

                Climate change is defined as permanent changes in the Earth&#8217;s weather conditions, such as temperature, precipitation, and wind. The main impacts of climate change include global warming, increase in weather events, sea level rise, damage to ecosystems, melting of glaciers, negative impacts on agriculture, water resources and human health. The biology and physiology of plant parasitic nematodes are regulated by environmental factors, (such as temperature, humidity, precipitation, and soil CO2 levels). which is one of the indicators of climate change. Climate change weather extremes such as increased temperature due to global warming, drought, forest fires, high CO2 conditions, increased rainfall, humidity conditions and storms affect the biodiversity, distribution, reproduction, survival and parasitic potential of plant parasitic nematodes. Since changes in CO2, temperature and precipitation levels caused by climate change will increase the proliferation, distribution and damage potential of plant parasitic nematode populations, there is a need to develop appropriate strategies for the control of nematodes that will be effective in situations of global warming in order to prevent significant reductions in crop yields in the future.</description>
      <author>Bet&#252;l G&#220;RKAN, Tolga G&#220;RKAN</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69860/nobel.9786053359449.12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A-124 Sustainable Transport: Assessing Environmental Impact in Medical Sample Transit via Drones and Vehicles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.123</link>
      <description>Noel Rouven Stierlin, A Hemmerle, Martin Risch, Lorenz Risch, Clinical Chemistry. 70(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403071790

                Abstract Background This research explores the ecological implications associated with different methods of transporting medical samples, specifically focusing on drones, combustion cars, and electric cars within two laboratories in central European countries. With the primary goal of assessing and comparing CO2 consumption, delivery time, and overall environmental impact, the study aims to provide a basis for adopting sustainable practices in healthcare logistics. Methods The transportation of medical samples occurred between two laboratories in the Principality of Liechtenstein and Switzerland, utilizing authorized aerial and road routes. Various weather conditions and distances were considered for sample transports using different vehicles (8 combustion cars, two electric cars, and one drone model). Energy consumption was documented, and the CO2 footprint was calculated based on data from the Swiss Federal Office for the Environment (FOEN) for both imported and renewable electricity. Comparative analyses were conducted to quantify the environmental impact of each transportation method. Results In terms of CO2 footprint, combustion cars exhibited a CO2 release of 159.5 g/km, while electric cars showed 3.43g (2.15 to 4.08% of combustion cars). Drones demonstrated a minimal 0.09g CO2 emission per kilometer (0.066% of combustion car CO2 emission; 2.6% of electric car CO2 emission). The distance traveled by drones was significantly shorter (16.7% to 50%). Additionally, the efficiency of drone transport was emphasized by its ability to avoid traffic jams and associated detours, resulting in time savings ranging from 31.25 to 50% per delivery when comparing transport times during rush hour and regular hours in the selected setting. Conclusions The integration of drone technology emerges as a crucial strategy for establishing a &#8220;green laboratory.&#8221; The substantial reduction in CO2 emissions and enhanced delivery efficiency position drone transport as a sustainable and operationally effective solution for medical sample logistics, offering shorter delivery times. These findings highlight the potential for transformative change in healthcare logistics, aligning with the global shift towards sustainability and green practices.</description>
      <author>Noel Rouven Stierlin, A Hemmerle, Martin Risch, Lorenz Risch</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Synergistic Effect of the Carbon Emission Trading Scheme on Pollution and Carbon Reduction in China&#8217;s Power Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198681</link>
      <description>Xiling Zhang, Xiaoqian Liu, Zeyu Zhang, Ruiyi Tang, Ting Zhang, Junqiang Yao, Sustainability. 16(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403217171

                The synergistic effect of pollution and carbon reduction can alleviate the dual pressure of improving environmental quality and reducing greenhouse gas emissions in China. The carbon emission trading scheme (CETS) is a crucial market-based tool for carbon emission reduction, and understanding its synergistic impact on air pollution control is essential. Based on data from 30 provincial panels in China spanning from 2007 to 2021, we employ the difference-in-differences (DID) method to analyze the synergistic effects of the carbon emission trading plan in the power industry and its influence mechanisms are examined. We observe that the CETS significantly enhances both pollution and carbon reduction in China&#8217;s power sector, particularly demonstrating effective synergy in reducing CO2, SO2, and PM2.5 emissions. Furthermore, mechanism analysis reveals that the CETS achieves joint emission reductions by lowering energy consumption, influencing the power industry&#8217;s generation structure, promoting technological innovation among enterprises, and thereby realizing synergistic pollution and carbon reduction effects in China&#8217;s power sector. Heterogeneity analysis shows that regions with limited power facility, low electricity generation, and small economic scale exhibit the most pronounced synergistic benefits from pollution and carbon reduction efforts.</description>
      <author>Xiling Zhang, Xiaoqian Liu, Zeyu Zhang, Ruiyi Tang, Ting Zhang, Junqiang Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two&#8208;Dimensional Silver&#8211;Isocyanide Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417658</link>
      <description>Kaiyue Jiang, Pu Yan, Pengfei Shi, Jichao Zhang, Xinyu Chai, Li Wang, Chenhui Zhu, Chongqing Yang, Chenbao Lu, Yi Liu, Kecheng Cao, Xiaodong Zhuang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403080791

                Metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) have been widely studied due to their versatile applications and easily tunable structures. However, heteroatom&#8208;metal coordination dominates the MOFs community, and the rational synthesis of carbon&#8211;metal coordination&#8208;based MOFs remains a significant challenge. Herein, two&#8208;dimensional (2D) MOFs based on silver&#8211;carbon linkages are synthesized through the coordination between silver(I) salt and isocyanide&#8208;based monomers at ambient condition. The as&#8208;synthesized 2D MOFs possess well&#8208;defined crystalline structures and a staggered AB stacking mode. Most interestingly, these 2D MOFs, without &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking between layers, exhibit narrow bandgaps down to 1.42 eV. As electrochemical catalysts for converting CO2 to CO, such 2D MOFs demonstrate Faradaic efficiency over 92%. Surprisingly, the CO2 reduction catalyzed by these MOFs indicates favorable adsorption of CO2 and *COOH on the active carbon sites of the isocyanide groups rather than on silver sites. This is attributed to the critical &#963; donor role of isocyanides and the corresponding ligand&#8208;to&#8208;metal charge&#8211;transfer effect. This work not only paves the way toward a new family of MOFs based on metal&#8211;isocyanide coordination but also offers a rare platform for understanding the electrocatalysis processes on strongly polarized carbon species.</description>
      <author>Kaiyue Jiang, Pu Yan, Pengfei Shi, Jichao Zhang, Xinyu Chai, Li Wang, Chenhui Zhu, Chongqing Yang, Chenbao Lu, Yi Liu, Kecheng Cao, Xiaodong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visible-Light Photoredox-Catalyzed Direct Carboxylation of Tertiary C(sp&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#8211;H Bonds with CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Facile Synthesis of All-Carbon Quaternary Carboxylic Acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09558</link>
      <description>Yi Liu, Gi Xue, Zhen He, Jun&#8208;Ping Yue, Min Pan, Lei Song, Wei Zhang, Jian&#8208;Heng Ye, Da&#8208;Gang Yu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403172647

                Direct carboxylation of C&#8211;H bonds with CO2 represents an attractive strategy to synthesize valuable carboxylic acids with high atom, step, and redox economy. Although great progress has been achieved in this field, catalytic carboxylation of tertiary C(sp3)&#8211;H bonds still remains challenging due to their inherent inertness and significant steric hindrance. Herein, we report a direct carboxylation of tertiary benzylic C(sp3)&#8211;H bonds with CO2 via visible-light photoredox catalysis. Various all-carbon quaternary carboxylic acids, which are of significant importance in medicinal chemistry, are successfully obtained with high yields. This direct carboxylation is characterized by good functional group tolerance, broad substrate scope, and mild operational conditions. Furthermore, our methodology enables the efficient and rapid synthesis of key drug or bioactive molecules, such as carbetapentane, caramiphen, and PRE-084 (&#963;1 receptor agonist), and facilitates various functionalizations of C(sp2)&#8211;H bonds using the directing ability of target carboxylic acids, thus highlighting its practical applications. Mechanistic studies indicate that a carbanion, which serves as the key intermediate to react with CO2, is catalytically generated via a single electron reduction of a benzylic radical through a consecutive photoinduced electron transfer process.</description>
      <author>Yi Liu, Gi Xue, Zhen He, Jun&#8208;Ping Yue, Min Pan, Lei Song, Wei Zhang, Jian&#8208;Heng Ye, Da&#8208;Gang Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09558</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How teacher behaviors and perceptions, air change rates, and portable air purifiers affect indoor air quality in naturally ventilated schools</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2024.1427116</link>
      <description>Tian Xia, Julia Raneses, Brixon Schmiesing, Raquel Garc&#237;a&#8208;Esteban, Alison Walding, Richardo DeMajo, Amy J. Schulz, Stuart Batterman, Frontiers in Public Health. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403102704

                Introduction Many school buildings have inadequate ventilation, rudimentary if any air filtration, and aging and poorly maintained mechanical systems, all of which can lead to poor indoor air quality (IAQ). These issues are especially acute in environmental justice (EJ) communities where schools are located in polluted areas. This community-based participatory research examines how IAQ in naturally ventilated school buildings is affected by the use of air purifiers, air change rates, outdoor pollution levels, and teacher and staff behavior. Methods IAQ assessments were performed at two schools in Detroit, Michigan, which included building walk-through inspections and continuous indoor and outdoor measurements of black carbon (BC), particulate matter (PM 10 and PM 2.5 ), carbon dioxide (CO 2 ), air change rates (ACRs), temperature, humidity, and sound pressure levels. Air purifiers with usage monitors were then installed, and the IAQ assessments were repeated. Teachers were surveyed before and after purifier deployment. Results At baseline, classrooms had low ACRs (0.58&#8211;1.38 h &#8722;1 ), moderate PM 2.5 levels (2.8&#8211;8.9 &#956;g/m 3 ), highly variable PM 10 concentrations (4.7&#8211;37.5 &#956;g/m 3 ), and elevated BC levels (0.3&#8211;0.7 &#956;g/m 3 ), reflecting emissions from local traffic, industry and other sources. The installation and use of purifiers reduced pollutant levels and the overall performance matched the predictions of a single compartment model. However, daily reductions varied widely among classrooms, reflecting differences in teacher behavior regarding the frequency of opening windows and the operation of purifiers, including differences in purifier fan speed settings and whether purifiers were used at night. Survey responses indicated that many teachers were aware of IAQ problems. The higher rates reported for health symptoms and dissatisfaction at one school may have lowered the teachers&#8217; tolerance to noise and reduced purifier use. Discussion The study helps explain the variation reported in prior studies using purifiers, and it reinforces the need to monitor IAQ and purifier use, use enhanced filtration and increase ventilation, and engage with teachers and school staff to support and maintain IAQ programs in schools.</description>
      <author>Tian Xia, Julia Raneses, Brixon Schmiesing, Raquel Garc&#237;a&#8208;Esteban, Alison Walding, Richardo DeMajo, Amy J. Schulz, Stuart Batterman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2024.1427116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hemodynamic Disorders in Alcohol Withdrawal Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17816/pavlovj623055</link>
      <description>S.I. Utkin, &#1054;. &#1046;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1079;&#1080;&#1082;, I P Pavlov Russian Medical Biological Herald. 32(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403135275

                INTRODUCTION: The introduction of the study is determined by a high prevalence of alcoholism and a high incidence of complications from the cardiovascular system. AIM: To study the features of hemodynamics in patients with uncomplicated alcohol withdrawal syndrome (AWS) and in those with alcohol withdrawal delirium (delirium tremens). MATERIALS AND METHODS: The study enrolled 116 men, 58 of them with uncomplicated AWS, 78 with AWS and delirium. Basic hemodynamic parameters were studied: heart rate (HR), blood pressure (BP), and integral parameters &#8212; cardiac index (CI), total peripheral resistance (TPR), shock index (SI). Comparisons between the groups and correlation analysis were conducted to find relationships between hemodynamic parameters and clinical data. RESULTS: In patients with alcoholic delirium, hemodynamic parameters were statistically significantly higher than in patients with uncomplicated AWS: HR (&#1088; = 0.003), systolic BP (&#1088; = 0.02) and diastolic BP (&#1088; = 0.04), while no statistically significant differences in the integral parameters (CI, TPR, SI) were found between the groups. In patients of both groups, CI linearly decreased with age (p 0.0001). The same linearly CI decreased with increase in the duration of alcoholism (p = 0.02). With an increase in the amount of consumed alcohol during the binge period, a linear growth of CI was observed in withdrawal state (p = 0.001). The value of TPR increased with age (p = 0.005). Only in patients with delirium tremens, there was an inverse relationship between SI and partial tension of carbon dioxide in venous blood (r = -0.4; p = 0.014). Besides, only in patients with delirium tremens, by the 7th day of withdrawal, a direct relationship was established between the cardiac index and blood potassium level (r = 0.36; p = 0.03). CONCLUSIONS: There was no significant difference between hemodynamic parameters in uncomplicated AWS and in delirium tremens. CI in patients with uncomplicated AWS and in those with DT decreased with age and with increase in the alcohol load. The vessel tone was inversely proportional to CI throughout the entire period of observation. With the development of delirium, a correlation was noted between a decrease in the level of energy metabolism and the probability for decompensation of systemic circulation. At the stage of reduction of delirium tremens, a correlation was noted between CI and the blood potassium level that reflected the exhaustion of the cardiovascular system and reduction of its compensatory capacities.</description>
      <author>S.I. Utkin, &#1054;. &#1046;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1079;&#1080;&#1082;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17816/pavlovj623055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The use of opioids in late&#8208;stage &lt;scp&gt;COPD&lt;/scp&gt;&#8212;Where are we now?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/resp.14839</link>
      <description>Thomas J. Altree, David C. Currow, Respirology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403198556

                Chronic breathlessness is defined as breathlessness that persists on minimal or no exertion despite the optimal treatment of the underlying disease and other contributing factors.1 It is a cardinal and prevalent symptom of late-stage chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). Chronic breathlessness is present in about 40% of people with COPD in high-income countries, worsening with age and severity of disease. The majority of people with late-stage COPD experience such breathlessness. COPD is also associated with a high frequency of comorbidities.2 Common symptoms related to COPD and its systemic manifestations include, but are not limited to, long-term pain, sleep disturbance, fatigue and cough. This paper focuses on chronic breathlessness. In COPD at a population level, breathlessness is more strongly associated with mortality than the measurable degree of airway obstruction.3, 4 There is also a relatively poor correlation between pulmonary function tests and the subjective assessments of chronic breathlessness. Other population-level associations with chronic breathlessness include poorer quality of life (physical and mental components)5; greater anxiety and depression; poorer workforce participation in people of working age; greater disability measured on the World Health Organization Disability Assessment Schedule (WHO-DAS); poorer perceived health; less sexual activity; and a smaller Life-Space geographic footprint. In symptom management, the first step in managing chronic breathlessness requires clinicians to ensure that reversible causes are optimally treated. More than one underlying aetiology often contributes to chronic breathlessness and all need to be addressed in each person's management plan. Non-pharmacological interventions include pulmonary rehabilitation, activity pacing, and a handheld battery-operated fan.6 Despite these measures, many people still require pharmacotherapy for the symptom, especially in late-stage disease. Several medications have been assessed in adequately powered studies, yet the only class of medications, to date, which has an evidence base is opioids. There are two main sources to inform clinical considerations of effectiveness of opioids for the symptomatic reduction of chronic breathlessness: meta-analyses; and adequately powered studies. A sub-group analysis of people with COPD and breathlessness in a recent meta-analysis of opioids administered long enough to reach steady state (n = 91) found an overall benefit favouring morphine over placebo.7 This suggests that there is a cohort who likely derive meaningful symptomatic benefit. Since the publication of that study, three large randomized, placebo-controlled studies have been reported (n = 284; n = 156; n = 111).8-10 Each had differing primary endpoints at different times (intensity of worst breathlessness at 1 week,9 intensity of breathlessness now at 1 week),8 and COPD Assessment Test (CAT) scores and PaCO2 at 4 weeks.11 Breathlessness remained unchanged in all three studies, however, two of the three studies reported sub-group analyses that described sub-populations that derived significant benefit. The study by Verberkt et al. found two significant improvements in its secondary outcomes: worst breathlessness at 28 days after commencing the study; and a difference between the active and placebo arms for the CAT score. The study by Ferreira et al. identified that people with the most severe breathlessness (mMRC3, 4) and COPD achieved significant clinical benefit.12 Accurately identifying patient characteristics that predict a beneficial response to regular, low-dose, sustained-release morphine remains a challenge for researchers and clinicians. Basic clinico-demographic factors have been defined in two studies using data from double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized controlled trials.13, 14 In the study by Johnson et al. from four clinical studies of morphine for the symptomatic reduction of breathlessness (n = 213), baseline predictors of a greater likelihood of response included more intense breathlessness and younger age.14 Body mass index (BMI) was not available in this study. In the study by Verberkt et al., 21 participants in the active arm of their parallel arm clinical trial had a &#8805;1 point improvement on a 0&#8211;10 numerical rating scale.13 The two baseline predictors of response were higher baseline intensity of breathlessness and higher BMI. Age was not a predictor in this study. To date, exploring key single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) relating to opioid metabolism, transport or receptors has not found predictors of response.15 There appear to be a group of people (who are yet to be characterized from their pre-treatment characteristics) who have a marked benefit from regular, low-dose, sustained release morphine. The benefits are described by trial participants as 'life-changing' and persisted for at least 6 months with no increase in morphine dose.16 Although there are small numbers who describe benefits of this magnitude, the benefits were further reflected in improved actigraph-measured activity and increased Global Impression of Change scores. Opioids for pain have a wide therapeutic index. Morphine for the symptomatic reduction of chronic breathlessness may have a far narrower window for net benefit. Many people reflect that even mild adverse events negate any symptomatic reduction in chronic breathlessness.17 In a meta-analysis of 64 studies, of which five had data on safety measures, Verberkt et al. found no evidence of rising carbon dioxide partial pressures nor of any drop in oxygenation&#8212;two principal concerns when prescribing opioids for people with COPD.11 A pre-planned secondary analysis of the BEAMS study found that daytime drowsiness was no worse in the morphine arm than placebo and that, at 4 weeks, participants who reported reduced breathlessness with morphine also had improvement in Leeds Sleep Evaluation Questionnaire (LSEQ) domain scores including perceived sleep quality and daytime functioning.18 However, objective assessment of the effects of low-dose, slow-release morphine during sleep in people with COPD and chronic breathlessness has identified that although there is no negative effect on next-day alertness (including driving simulator performance), morphine causes lighter sleep depth, higher mean and peak transcutaneous CO2 and lower oxygen saturations.18, 19 The longer-term consequences of these changes are yet to be determined. Of note, any therapeutic benefit does not seem to have a whole-of-class effect for opioids. Studies utilizing oxycodone do not seem to have any signal of symptomatic benefit. Interestingly, it may also be that not all underlying aetiologies of chronic breathlessness derive the same benefits. One study in pulmonary artery hypertension saw no signal of benefit in the primary nor secondary outcomes and another in interstitial lung disease.20 At present, data from a meta-analysis and two large, randomized, controlled studies indicate that in people with severe chronic breathlessness secondary to COPD, a short trial of low dose, sustained release morphine is safe and potentially beneficial. When introduced at a low dose and titrated slowly (at least 1 week between commencing and titration), a sub-group of people derive significant, sometimes life-changing, benefit. Developing accurate methods to identify which patients derive benefit from regular, low-dose, sustained-release morphine is a critical goal for future research. T.J.A. had no disclosures. D.C.C. is an Advisory Board member and consultant for Helsinn Pharmaceuticals; consultant and receives payment for intellectual property with Mayne Pharma International Pty Ltd.; subcontractor to Nous Group Pty Ltd.; Board member for icare Dust Diseases Care NSW; Board member/Director NSW Health Pathology; Board member/Director for Chris O'Brien Lifehouse Cancer Centre.</description>
      <author>Thomas J. Altree, David C. Currow</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/resp.14839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative study of alternative fuels for sustainable IC engine operation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30574/wjarr.2021.12.1.0407</link>
      <description>BHASKARA, World Journal of Advanced Research and Reviews. 12(1)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4403079034

                The increasing environmental concerns, coupled with the rapid depletion of conventional fossil fuels, have prompted the automotive industry to explore alternative energy sources that can support the continued operation of internal combustion (IC) engines in a more sustainable manner. The need to mitigate greenhouse gas emissions, reduce dependence on finite fossil resources, and meet stringent environmental regulations has led to extensive research and development efforts in identifying viable alternative fuels. These fuels must not only align with the performance requirements of modern IC engines but also minimize their environmental footprint.This paper presents a comprehensive comparative analysis of various alternative fuels, including biodiesel, ethanol, hydrogen, natural gas, and synthetic fuels, each of which offers unique advantages and challenges. The study evaluates these fuels across key parameters, such as fuel availability, energy content, emissions profile, required engine modifications, and overall sustainability. The analysis takes into consideration the economic feasibility and infrastructure requirements for large-scale adoption of each fuel.Furthermore, the paper highlights the technological advancements and modifications necessary to optimize IC engines for these alternative fuels. This includes the impact of alternative fuels on engine efficiency, power output, fuel economy, and maintenance requirements. Special attention is given to emissions reduction strategies, with a focus on how each fuel contributes to lowering carbon dioxide (CO&#8322;), nitrogen oxides (NO&#8339;), and particulate matter (PM) emissions.In addition to evaluating the current state of alternative fuels, the paper addresses the challenges associated with their adoption, including production scalability, distribution infrastructure, and compatibility with existing vehicle technologies. Finally, the future prospects of integrating these fuels into automotive applications are explored, considering the rapid rise of electric vehicles and other emerging technologies that may further influence the role of IC engines in the transition to sustainable transportation.The findings of this study suggest that while no single alternative fuel is likely to fully replace conventional gasoline and diesel in the near future, a combination of fuels, along with continued innovation in fuel production, engine technology, and policy support, will be necessary to achieve sustainable IC engine operation. The paper concludes by outlining the critical research areas and policy initiatives needed to promote the wider adoption of alternative fuels in the automotive sector.</description>
      <author>BHASKARA</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30574/wjarr.2021.12.1.0407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Effect of Crystal Facets and Sulfur Defects on the Product Selectivity of Various CdS Configurations for CO2 Photoreduction: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100688</link>
      <description>Shuai Liu, Jing Wang, Yu Zhong, Leiping Wang, Ding&#8208;Ming Xue, Lei Tong, Honglei Zhang, Tao Wu, Guangsuo Yu, Hang Xiao, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403084362

                CO2 photoreduction into valuable hydrocarbons, such as CO, CH4, and C2H4, delivers a promising approach to address both environmental and energy challenges. Transition metal chalcogenides, particularly cadmium sulfide (CdS), have emerged as prominent candidates due to their tunable electronic properties and availability. This study delves into a comprehensive investigation of how CdS crystalline facets and sulfur-deficient surfaces modulate the product selectivity. Through employing density functional theory (DFT), we unravel the catalytic performance of various CdS crystal orientations and sulfur vacancy configurations. The results have shown that different CdS facets exhibit unique electronic characteristics and surface energetics, which influence the adsorption dynamics and reaction pathways. The introduction of sulfur vacancies further modulates the nature of active sites, leading to substantial shifts in product selectivity. A detailed investigation on the reaction mechanisms unveils that specific facets preferentially facilitate the formation of CO, while others are more conducive to the generation of hydrocarbons such as CH4 and C2H4, due to the variations in activation barriers and intermediate stabilities. These findings underscore the importance of crystal facet engineering and defect manipulation in tailoring catalyst performance thus providing valuable insights for the rational design of efficient and selective CO2 reduction metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shuai Liu, Jing Wang, Yu Zhong, Leiping Wang, Ding&#8208;Ming Xue, Lei Tong, Honglei Zhang, Tao Wu, Guangsuo Yu, Hang Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Synthetic Positive Energy District (PED) in &#304;stanbul: Balancing Cost, Mobility, and Environmental Impact</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14103153</link>
      <description>Mi&#775;ne Serts&#246;z, Buildings. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403107776

                The influence of mobility modes within Positive Energy Districts (PEDs) has gained limited attention, despite their crucial role in reducing energy consumption and greenhouse gas emissions. Buildings in the European Union (EU) account for 40% of energy consumption and 36% of greenhouse gas emissions. In comparison, transport contributes 28% of energy use and 25% of emissions, with road transport responsible for 72% of these emissions. This study aims to design and optimize a synthetic PED in Istanbul that integrates renewable energy sources and public mobility systems to address these challenges. The renewable energy sources integrated into the synthetic PED model include solar energy, hydrogen energy, and regenerative braking energy from a tram system. Solar panels provided a substantial portion of the energy, while hydrogen energy contributed to additional electricity generation. Regenerative braking energy from the tram system was also utilized to further optimize energy production within the district. This system powers a middle school, 10 houses, a supermarket, and the tram itself. Optimization techniques, including Linear Programming (LP) for economic purposes and the Weighted Sum Method (WSM) for environmental goals, were applied to balance cost and CO2 emissions. The LP method identified that the PED model can achieve cost competitiveness with conventional energy grids when hydrogen costs are below $93.16/MWh. Meanwhile, the WSM approach demonstrated that achieving a minimal CO2 emission level of 5.74 tons requires hydrogen costs to be $32.55/MWh or lower. Compared to a conventional grid producing 97 tons of CO2 annually, the PED model achieved reductions of up to 91.26 tons. This study contributes to the ongoing discourse on sustainable urban energy systems by addressing key research gaps related to the integration of mobility modes within PEDs and offering insights into the optimization of renewable energy sources for reducing emissions and energy consumption.</description>
      <author>Mi&#775;ne Serts&#246;z</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14103153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Conjugated Nickel(II)&#8208;Acetylide Framework for Efficient Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418269</link>
      <description>Yingying Qin, Yang Wang, Jian L&#252;, Linli Xu, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403129176

                The incorporation of transition&#8208;metal single atoms as molecular functional entities into the skeleton of graphdiyne (GDY) to construct novel two&#8208;dimensional (2D) metal&#8208;acetylide frameworks, known as metalated graphynes (MGYs), is a promising strategy for developing efficient catalysts, which can combine the tunable charge transfer of GDY frameworks, the catalytic activity of metal and the precise distribution of single metallic centers. Herein, four highly conjugated MGY photocatalysts based on NiII, PdII, PtII, and HgII were synthesized for the first time using the &#8216;bottom&#8208;up&#8217; strategy through the use of M&#8211;C bonds (&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;M&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;). Remarkably, the NiII&#8208;based graphyne (TEPY&#8208;Ni&#8208;GY) exhibited the highest CO generation rate of 18.3 mmol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1 and a selectivity of 98.8%. This superior performance is attributed to the synergistic effects of pyrenyl and &#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;Ni(PBu3)2&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211; moieties. The pyrenyl block functions as an intramolecular &#960;&#8208;conjugation channel, facilitating kinetically favorable electron transfer, while the &#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;Ni(PBu3)2&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211; moiety serves as the catalytic site that enhances CO2 adsorption and activation, thereby suppressing competitive hydrogen evolution. This study provides a new perspective on MGY&#8208;based photocatalysts for developing highly active and low&#8208;cost catalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Yingying Qin, Yang Wang, Jian L&#252;, Linli Xu, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewable Energy Credits Transforming Market Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198602</link>
      <description>Bankole I. Oladapo, Mattew A. Olawumi, Francis T. Omigbodun, Sustainability. 16(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403101705

                This research uses advanced statistical methods to examine climate change mitigation policies&#8217; economic and environmental impacts. The primary objective is to assess the effectiveness of carbon pricing, renewable energy subsidies, emission trading schemes, and regulatory standards in reducing CO2 emissions, fostering economic growth, and promoting employment. A mixed-methods approach was employed, combining regression analysis, cost&#8211;benefit analysis (CBA), and computable general equilibrium (CGE) models. Data were collected from national and global databases, and sensitivity analyses were conducted to ensure the robustness of the findings. Key findings revealed a statistically significant reduction in CO2 emissions by 0.45% for each unit increase in carbon pricing (p &lt; 0.01). Renewable energy subsidies were positively correlated with a 3.5% increase in employment in the green sector (p &lt; 0.05). Emission trading schemes were projected to increase GDP by 1.2% over a decade (p &lt; 0.05). However, chi-square tests indicated that carbon pricing disproportionately affects low-income households (p &lt; 0.05), highlighting the need for compensatory policies. The study concluded that a balanced policy mix, tailored to national contexts, can optimise economic and environmental outcomes while addressing social equity concerns. Error margins in GDP projections remained below &#177;0.3%, confirming the models&#8217; reliability.</description>
      <author>Bankole I. Oladapo, Mattew A. Olawumi, Francis T. Omigbodun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ionomer and Membrane Designs for Low&#8208;Temperature CO2 and CO Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401728</link>
      <description>Huihua Deng, Zhuo Chen, Li Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403146014

                Low&#8208;temperature electroreduction of CO2 and CO (CO(2)RR) into valuable chemicals and fuels offers a promising pathway to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and achieve carbon neutrality. Today's low&#8208;temperature CO(2)RR technology relies on the use of ionomers, polymers with ionized groups, primarily as catalyst layer (CL) additives. In the meantime, ionomers can assemble into ion&#8208;exchange membranes (IEMs), serving as important components of electrolyzers. According to the ion&#8208;exchange functions, ionomer additives are classified as cation&#8208;exchange ionomers (CEIs) and anion&#8208;exchange ionomers (AEIs); similarly, IEMs are divided into cation&#8208;exchange membranes (CEMs) and anion&#8208;exchange membranes (AEMs), as well as the multilayer polymer electrolytes (MPEs). Recent studies show that ionomer additives can regulate the catalytic microenvironment and thereby enhance performance towards desired products. This Review discusses the roles of ionomer additives and IEMs in CO2 and CO reduction reactions, highlighting the latest mechanistic insights and performance advances. It outlines challenges in designing ionomer additives and IEMs to improve product selectivity, energy efficiency (EE), and operational lifetime of CO(2)RR electrolyzers, while also providing perspectives on future research directions. The aim is to connect the current status of ionomer and membrane development with performance metrics analysis, offering insights for the advancement of commercially relevant low&#8208;temperature CO(2)RR electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Huihua Deng, Zhuo Chen, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Hydrogen on Flame Characteristics and Pollutant Emissions in Natural Gas Industrial Combustion Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17194959</link>
      <description>Yamei Lan, Li Wang, Jingxiang Xu, Yi Wang, Energies. 17(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140808

                To improve energy savings and emission reduction in industrial heating furnaces, this study investigated the impact of various molar fractions of hydrogen on natural gas combustion and compared the results of the Non-Premixed Combustion Model with the Eddy Dissipation Combustion Model. Initially, natural gas combustion in an industrial heating furnace was investigated experimentally, and these results were used as boundary conditions for CFD simulations. The diffusion flame and combustion characteristics of natural gas were simulated using both the non-premixed combustion model and the Eddy Dissipation Combustion Model. The results indicated that the Non-Premixed Combustion Model provided simulations more consistent with experimental data, within acceptable error margins, thus validating the accuracy of the numerical simulations. Additionally, to analyze the impact of hydrogen doping on the performance of an industrial gas heater, four gas mixtures with varying hydrogen contents (15% H2, 30% H2, 45% H2, and 60% H2) were studied while maintaining constant fuel inlet temperature and flow rate. The results demonstrate that the Non-Premixed Combustion Model more accurately simulates complex flue gas flow and chemical reactions during combustion. Moreover, hydrogen-doped natural gas significantly reduces CO and CO2 emissions compared to pure natural gas combustion. Specifically, at 60% hydrogen content, CO and CO2 levels decrease by 70% and 37.5%, respectively, while NO emissions increase proportionally; at this hydrogen content, NO concentration in the furnace chamber rises by 155%.</description>
      <author>Yamei Lan, Li Wang, Jingxiang Xu, Yi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17194959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study of The Energy, Economic, Environmental, and Thermal Comfort Impact of The Integration of Hemp Concrete and Hemp Plaster in a Residential Building Envelope in Morocco</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37934/arnht.23.1.127</link>
      <description>H. Kaddouri, Abderrahim Abidouche, Mohamed Saidi Hassani Alaoui, I. Driouch, Said Hamdaoui, Abdelouahad Ait Msaad, Journal of Advanced Research in Numerical Heat Transfer. 23(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403062885

                In the building sector, the majority of efforts are aimed at achieving greater energy efficiency, a low carbon footprint, and optimum thermal comfort to make buildings more efficient, more sustainable, and more pleasant to live in. In this context, this paper aims to assess the impact of integrating environmentally friendly and green materials (lime-hemp plaster and hemp concrete) into the envelope of an existing residential building. A numerical simulation study was carried out using TRNSYS 18, in four Moroccan climates: Mediterranean, cold semi-arid, hot semi-arid, and hot and dry desert, to study the energy, economic, and environmental impact, as well as that of the thermal comfort. The proposed construction scenarios are compared with the reference scenario in terms of heating and cooling requirements, electricity bills, carbon footprint, and percentage of annual thermal discomfort. The results show that energy savings are highest in the cold semi-arid climate (Oujda) at around 24%. Hemp concrete construction is more effective in reducing heating requirements, with a reduction of up to 39.4%. For cooling, the reduction is only 15.5%. The economic and environmental study shows that using materials such as hemp concrete in an optimal construction and climatic context can reduce electricity bills by 25% and CO2 emissions by around 23.7%. However, the reduction in terms of hours of discomfort is not yet significant enough. Hence the need to combine this technique with other strategies based on bioclimatic design. The use of hemp plaster and concrete for renovating existing buildings or constructing new ones represents a very promising alternative from several points of view: energy, economic, and environmental.</description>
      <author>H. Kaddouri, Abderrahim Abidouche, Mohamed Saidi Hassani Alaoui, I. Driouch, Said Hamdaoui, Abdelouahad Ait Msaad</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37934/arnht.23.1.127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phenotypic and Genomic Characterization of a Sulfate-Reducing Bacterium Pseudodesulfovibrio methanolicus sp. nov. Isolated from a Petroleum Reservoir in Russia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/biology13100800</link>
      <description>Salimat K. Bidzhieva, T. P. Tourova, Vitaly V. Kadnikov, Salima R. Samigullina, Alexander S. Shashkov, &#1040;. &#1041;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1083;&#1090;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1091;&#1089;, Alexander N. Avtukh, &#1042;. &#1052;. &#1058;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1096;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, Alexey V. Beletsky, Andrey V. Mardanov, Tamara N. Nazina, Biology. 13(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403190838

                The search for the microorganisms responsible for sulfide formation and corrosion of steel equipment in the oil fields of Tatarstan (Russia) resulted in the isolation of a new halotolerant strictly anaerobic sulfate-reducing bacterium, strain 5S69T. The cells were motile curved Gram-negative rods. Optimal growth was observed in the presence of 2.0&#8211;4.0% (w/v) NaCl, at pH 6.5, and at 23&#8211;28 &#176;C under sulfate-reducing conditions. The isolate was capable of chemoorganotrophic growth with sulfate and other sulfoxides as electron acceptors, resulting in sulfide formation; and of pyruvate fermentation resulting in formation of H2 and acetate. The strain utilized lactate, pyruvate, ethanol, methanol, fumarate, and fructose, as well as H2/CO2/acetate for sulfate reduction. The genome size of the type strain 5S69T was 4.16 Mb with a G + C content of 63.0 mol%. On the basis of unique physiological properties and results of the 16S rRNA gene-based phylogenetic analysis, phylogenomic analysis of the 120 conserved single copy proteins and genomic indexes (ANI, AAI, and dDDH), assigning the type strain 5S69T ((VKM B-3653T = KCTC 25499T) to a new species within the genus Pseudodesulfovibrio, is suggested, with the proposed name Pseudodesulfovibrio methanolicus sp. nov. Genome analysis of the new isolate showed several genes involved in sulfate reduction and its sulfide-producing potential in oil fields with high saline formation water.</description>
      <author>Salimat K. Bidzhieva, T. P. Tourova, Vitaly V. Kadnikov, Salima R. Samigullina, Alexander S. Shashkov, &#1040;. &#1041;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1083;&#1090;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1091;&#1089;, Alexander N. Avtukh, &#1042;. &#1052;. &#1058;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1096;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, Alexey V. Beletsky, Andrey V. Mardanov, Tamara N. Nazina</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/biology13100800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of Energy-saving Technologies in House construction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21822/2073-6185-2024-51-3-189-194</link>
      <description>E. I. Krupnov, Irina A. Zaytseva, Svetlana Andreyevna Loginova, Aleksandr Vladimirovich Simagin, Herald of Dagestan State Technical University Technical Sciences. 51(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403088596

                Objective. Over the past decades, heat pumps have gained great popularity due to their advantages in energy efficiency and environmental friendliness, becoming one of the most attractive alternatives to replace traditional heating systems running on fossil fuels. Heat pump efficiency is a decisive factor that should be taken into account when selecting and optimizing a heat pump system. The aim of the study was to evaluate the efficiency of air source heat pumps of the air-to-water system in the climatic conditions typical of the regions of the Central Federal District. Method . To evaluate the efficiency of air source heat pumps, a mathematical model is used that takes into account the multifactorial nature of the process under study. Result. To adequately compare the obtained research results with the passport performance indicators, the transformation coefficient (COP) was used, showing the ratio of the energy received to the expended work. As a result, the method of heating rooms with an air source heat pump with a combined operation mode was recognized as more preferable. Conclusion. Currently, the potential of heat pumps in the field of energy saving and CO2 emission reduction remains largely untapped, which sets the vector for further research.</description>
      <author>E. I. Krupnov, Irina A. Zaytseva, Svetlana Andreyevna Loginova, Aleksandr Vladimirovich Simagin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21822/2073-6185-2024-51-3-189-194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size&#8208;dependent Copper Nanoparticles Supported on Carbon Nanotubes with Balanced Cu+ and Cu0 Dual Sites for the Selective Hydrogenation of Ethylene Carbonate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402699</link>
      <description>Wanghua Chen, Dahye Ji, Yanfei Zhang, Yuanyuan Cui, Yinfeng Cheng, Songlin Wang, Wei&#8208;Lin Dai, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403081561

                Cyclic carbonate hydrogenation offers an alternative for the efficient indirect CO2 utilization. In this study, a series of carbon nanotubes (CNTs) supported xCu/CNTs catalysts with different Cu loadings were fabricated using a convenient impregnation method, and exhibited excellent catalytic activity for the hydrogenation of ethylene carbonate to methanol and ethylene glycol. The structural and physicochemical properties revealed that acid treatment of CNTs resulted in plentiful oxygen&#8208;containing functional groups, providing sufficient anchoring sites for copper species. The calcination process conducted under an inert atmosphere resulted in the formation of ternary CuO, Cu2O, and Cu composites, enhancing the metal&#8208;support interaction and facilitating the formation of balanced Cu0 and Cu+ dual sites as well as high active surface area after reduction. Contributed to the synergetic effect of balanced Cu+ and Cu0 species proved by density functional theory calculation and the electron&#8208;rich CNTs surface, the 40Cu/CNTs catalyst achieved strengthened catalytic performance with methanol yield of 83%, ethylene glycol yield of 99% at ethylene carbonate conversion of &gt;99%, and 150 h of long&#8208;term running stability. Consequently, CNTs supported Cu serve as efficient non&#8208;silica based catalyst for ester hydrogenation.</description>
      <author>Wanghua Chen, Dahye Ji, Yanfei Zhang, Yuanyuan Cui, Yinfeng Cheng, Songlin Wang, Wei&#8208;Lin Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402699</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of high&#8208;entropy oxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401663</link>
      <description>Qian Zhang, Xuexue Wang, Xiaomeng Lv, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403073360

                High&#8208;entropy oxides (HEOs), similar to high&#8208;entropy materials (HEMs), have "four&#8208;core effects", i.e., high&#8208;entropy effect, delayed diffusion effect, lattice distortion effect and cocktail effect, which have attracted more and more attention in the scientific field of renewable energy technology due to their unique structural characteristics, variable chemical composition and corresponding functional properties. HEOs have become potential candidates for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is a key half reaction for electrolytic CO2, nitrogen reduction, and water electrolysis. However, the precise synthesis of HEOs with a wide range of components and structures is challenging, not to mention their active and stable operation for OER. In this paper, we review the recent advancements in the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution facilitated by HEOs in water electrolysis. We analyze these developments from the perspectives of activity and stability in acid and alkaline conditions, respectively. Furthermore, we summarize the design from the aspect of element composition, structure, morphology, and catalyst&#8208;support interactions, along with related reaction mechanism of HEOs. Additionally, we discuss the current challenges faced by HEOs in the field of OER and suggest potential directions for the future development of HEOs beyond water electrolysis application.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhang, Xuexue Wang, Xiaomeng Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous Nanobelts for Efficient Electrocatalytic Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416878</link>
      <description>Ziming Su, Xiang&#8208;Yu Chen, Mingke Sun, Xiuyi Yang, Jianxin Kang, Zhi Cai, Lin Guo, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403141185

                One&#8208;dimensional (1D) amorphous nanomaterials combine the advantages of high active site concentration of amorphous structure, high specific surface area and efficient charge transfer and mass transport of 1D materials, so they present promising opportunities for catalysis. However, a significant challenge involves achieving a balance between the high orientation of 1D morphology and the isotropy of amorphous structure, which severely obstructs the controllable preparation of 1D amorphous materials. Guided by the hard&#8208;soft acids&#8208;bases theory, here we develop a general strategy for preparing 1D amorphous nanomaterials through the precise modulation of bond strength between metal ions and organic ligands for a moderated fastness. The soft base dodecanethiol (DT) is multifunctionally served as both structure&#8208;regulating agent and morphology&#8208;directing agent. Compared with the borderline acids (e.g. Fe2+, Co2+, Ni2+) to construct amorphous structure, soft acid of Cu+ which produced crystalline nanobelts can still be amorphized by reducing the hardness of Cu ions through redox reaction to weak Cu&#8208;SR bond. Due to the combined advantages of amorphous structure and one&#8208;dimensional morphology, amorphous CuDT nanobelts exhibited excellent electrocatalytic activity in electrochemical nitrate reduction, outperformed the most of the reported Cu&#8208;based catalysts. This work will effectively bridge the gap between traditional 1D crystalline nanomaterials and amorphization preparation.</description>
      <author>Ziming Su, Xiang&#8208;Yu Chen, Mingke Sun, Xiuyi Yang, Jianxin Kang, Zhi Cai, Lin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416878</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous Nanobelts for Efficient Electrocatalytic Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416878</link>
      <description>Ziming Su, Xiangyu Chen, Mingke Sun, Xiuyi Yang, Jianxin Kang, Zhi Cai, Xiaotian Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140466

                One&#8208;dimensional (1D) amorphous nanomaterials combine the advantages of high active site concentration of amorphous structure, high specific surface area and efficient charge transfer and mass transport of 1D materials, so they present promising opportunities for catalysis. However, a significant challenge involves achieving a balance between the high orientation of 1D morphology and the isotropy of amorphous structure, which severely obstructs the controllable preparation of 1D amorphous materials. Guided by the hard&#8208;soft acids&#8208;bases theory, here we develop a general strategy for preparing 1D amorphous nanomaterials through the precise modulation of bond strength between metal ions and organic ligands for a moderated fastness. The soft base dodecanethiol (DT) is multifunctionally served as both structure&#8208;regulating agent and morphology&#8208;directing agent. Compared with the borderline acids (e.g. Fe2+, Co2+, Ni2+) to construct amorphous structure, soft acid of Cu+ which produced crystalline nanobelts can still be amorphized by reducing the hardness of Cu ions through redox reaction to weak Cu&#8208;SR bond. Due to the combined advantages of amorphous structure and one&#8208;dimensional morphology, amorphous CuDT nanobelts exhibited excellent electrocatalytic activity in electrochemical nitrate reduction, outperformed the most of the reported Cu&#8208;based catalysts. This work will effectively bridge the gap between traditional 1D crystalline nanomaterials and amorphization preparation.</description>
      <author>Ziming Su, Xiangyu Chen, Mingke Sun, Xiuyi Yang, Jianxin Kang, Zhi Cai, Xiaotian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416878</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis, Characterization, and Shaping of UiO-67 Metal-Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33540/2439</link>
      <description>Christia Jabbour, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403222099

                This PhD thesis investigates the flexibility of metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) materials, particularly focusing on their adaptable synthesis and shaping techniques. MOFs, known for their dynamic framework structures and flexible linkers, allow researchers to design new and existing porous materials for specific applications, such as catalysis and environmental protection. The research covers a range of topics, including synthesis, characterization, shaping, and catalytic testing, with particular emphasis on the flexible properties of MOFs. Chapter 2 focuses on the application of MOFs in active coatings on surfaces and functionalized fabrics to deactivate biological and chemical toxins, a crucial topic in light of the global health crisis induced by the SARS-CoV-2 outbreak. The chapter discusses advancements in metal- and metal-oxide-based catalysts for inactivating chemical and biological threats. It also explores MOF applications in textiles, which are designed to capture and degrade chemical warfare agents. Despite progress, challenges remain, particularly in translating laboratory results to real-world conditions, such as creating multifunctional protective suits that are durable and capable of detoxifying toxins while remaining comfortable. The chapter highlights the promise of MOFs in addressing these challenges, but also the need for improved manipulation onto fibers and long-term stability. Chapters 3, 4, and 5 delve into the catalytic potential of MOFs and their manipulation for specific applications. In Chapter 3, the focus is on the catalytic activity of platinum nanoparticles (Pt-NPs) embedded within the UiO-67 MOF structure, specifically investigating their role in the CO2 hydrogenation reaction. The study examines the effects of reduction and pyrolysis treatments on Pt-NPs, finding that certain treatment processes improve the selectivity for methanol formation. This chapter emphasizes the importance of understanding the catalytic properties of MOFs and their potential for CO2 conversion. Chapter 4 investigates surface-mounted MOFs (SURMOFs), which offer promising in situ measurement capabilities. The chapter discusses the synthesis and characterization of three different SURMOF materials: UU-1, ZIF-8, and UiO-67. It explores how different anchor molecules, substrates, and synthetic conditions affect the growth and morphology of these SURMOFs. The chapter also addresses the limitations of current analytical techniques and proposes transmission-based characterization on transparent substrates. The findings highlight the importance of spectroscopic characterization in understanding the behavior of SURMOFs during various processes, offering insights for their application in fields like sensing, separation, and catalysis. Finally, Chapter 5 addresses the challenge of shaping MOFs via mechanical pressure by presenting a synthesis procedure that forms MOF beads through entanglement with chitosan (CS). This method eliminates the need for mechanical pressure, which can be detrimental to MOF structures. The study compares two synthesis procedures&#8212;one-pot synthesis (OPS) and post-synthetic functionalization (PSF)&#8212;and finds that OPS leads to better incorporation of MOFs into CS beads, resulting in higher thermal stability. Overall, this thesis demonstrates the versatility of MOFs in catalysis, environmental protection, and material science, while also addressing the challenges associated with shaping and long-term stability.</description>
      <author>Christia Jabbour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33540/2439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12201 Ketogenic-diet As A Trigger Of First Episode Diabetic Ketoacidosis In A Woman Living With Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1210/jendso/bvae163.826</link>
      <description>Margarida Cruz, Alex N Gonzalez Bossolo, Gabriel Jose Mora Osoria, Journal of the Endocrine Society. 8(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403153887

                Abstract Disclosure: M.E. Chacon Cruz: None. A.N. Gonzalez Bossolo: None. G.J. Mora Osoria: None. A number of dietary patterns have been proposed as an effective method for weight reduction. A keto diet is a strict low-carbohydrate and high-fat diet. The reduction in carbohydrates enables the body to rely on fat as a predominant energy source leading to a state of ketosis. However, a serious but rare complication of the ketogenic diet is ketoacidosis associated with low carbohydrate intake, which should be cautiously monitored in people with a predisposition to the condition, such patient with diabetes mellitus type 1. We report the case of a female patient living with type 1 diabetes mellitus female who developed her first episodes of diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA) as the following the course of ketogenic diet. A 53 y/o Female patient with past medical history diabetes mellitus type 1 and pernicious anemia went emergency department complaining pelvic pain associated with weakness, nausea and vomiting for about 1 day of evolution. Patient also refers that during the past 2 weeks she has been doing a detox and taking some herbal and tea. Other physical examinations were unremarkable except for moderate dehydration. The initial testing revealed patients meet criteria for severe diabetes ketoacidosis (DKA) with a pH: 7.04, CO2 15, serum central bicarbonate in 6 mmol/L and elevated blood glucose in 504 mg/dl and positive urine and serum ketones, C-Peptide less than 0.02 ng/ml. and glycosylated hemoglobin in 8.25%. She was admitted to the intensive care unit and treated with intravenous saline, intravenous insulin infusion, and electrolyte repletion. Blood glucose levels and metabolic acidosis improved. After DKA resolved patient refers that week started with Keto-diet and was restricting carbohydrates. Patient was discharge home with multiple injection insulin and followed by Endocrinologist services in the external clinic for a follow up. This case illustrates the challenges and the importance of dietary history providing clues to the diagnosis. If we had never asked her about her diet, we would not have found the reason that brought her to the DKA. This case demonstrates the development of DKA following ketogenic diet in a patient with type 1 diabetes. It is important for physicians to be aware of this rare potential complication of ketogenic diet which is infrequently reported in literature. Therefore, physicians should be cognizant of the complications and risks, and benefits of the ketogenic diet. Risks and benefits of the ketogenic diet should be discussed with patients before initiation of this diet. The patient was followed in an outpatient clinic with Endocrinologist service for evaluation for an insulin pump. Presentation: 6/1/2024</description>
      <author>Margarida Cruz, Alex N Gonzalez Bossolo, Gabriel Jose Mora Osoria</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1210/jendso/bvae163.826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Hybrid Physics/Data-Driven Model for Fractured Reservoir Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/219110-pa</link>
      <description>Billal Aslam, Bicheng Yan, Knut&#8211;Andreas Lie, Stein Krogstad, Olav M&#248;yner, Xupeng He, SPE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403091249

                Summary Fractured reservoir simulation plays a crucial role in understanding various subsurface geo-energy recovery and storage processes, including shale gas/oil extraction, enhanced geothermal systems, and CO2 sequestration in basaltic rocks. However, such simulations often entail significant computational expenses due to the high contrast in permeability and pore volume (PV) between matrix and fractures. To address this challenge, we introduce a reduced-order model (ROM) tailored for fractured reservoir simulation that offers flexible fracture representations by generating coarse matrix nodes based on reservoir outlines and adding extra diagonal connections between unconnected matrix nodes, whose corresponding volumes are intersected by fractures. This approach avoids the need for additional fracture nodes, effectively reducing computational costs. Dimensionality reduction methods, such as principal component analysis (PCA), are used to give quality priors for sampling matrix transmissibility and PV arrays. Tuning to well observation data, such as flow rates and bottomhole pressures (BHPs), is achieved through a gradient-based optimization method within a general automatic-differentiable simulator framework. Our results demonstrate robust calibration using synthetic well observation data from a fine-scale reference simulation model. Incorporating dominant flow physics, such as water breakthrough, from observation data improves history-matching (HM) convergence and prediction accuracy. Additionally, PCA for parameterization enhances the convergence rate of model calibration compared with random initialization. Calibrated transmissibilities align with high-connectivity regions from the fine-scale reference model, rendering the model interpretable in terms of reservoir connectivity or geology. This feature enables our method to be used effectively for reservoir HM and optimization using field observation data.</description>
      <author>Billal Aslam, Bicheng Yan, Knut&#8211;Andreas Lie, Stein Krogstad, Olav M&#248;yner, Xupeng He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/219110-pa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A-198 ESG Opportunities Harnessed During Pathology Transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.196</link>
      <description>T Ellison, Louise Hughes, R. F. G. Booth, Garry M. Walsh, David Dunn, Clinical Chemistry. 70(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403071086

                Abstract Background Synnovis (a SYNLAB business) is in the process of delivering one of the largest Pathology transformation programmes in the UK, moving to a seven-site hub and spoke model from 89 laboratories over a dispersed geography. This remit also presented an opportunity for SYNLAB to deliver on its Environmental Social Governance (ESG) ambitions, by embedding ESG principles into programme delivery. There are several examples within each ESG pillar that demonstrate the benefits to be leveraged during transformation. Methods SYNLAB&#8217;s vision is to deliver sustainable diagnostic services. The integration of ESG into both the decision-making process and transformation structure ties these ambitions into programme benefits realisation. As well as setting performance level targets, the delivery of ESG benefits provide measures of success throughout the transformation journey, motivating stakeholders and building confidence along the way. Results Environment: The efficient use of space and LEAN principle design has consolidated the fragmented laboratory services spanning 15,000m2 into a bespoke, cutting-edge Pathology Hub with 6 spokes (hospital based services). The new hub building was designed to achieve BREEAM Excellent standards which measure performance against criteria such as energy management and efficiency, sustainable design and materials. The hub&#8217;s energy is from renewable-backed sources, and we will achieve a 47% reduction in CO2 equivalent (CO2e) emissions by unifying a significant proportion of its legacy footprint in this way. Further energy savings will be achieved through the associated analytical equipment consolidation, including a decrease from 50 to 14 microtomes, a decrease of 29 to 15 ventilated benches and a reduction of over 200 fridges and freezers across the service. In addition, substantial CO2e emissions savings are also being delivered by moving to a greener logistics provider, utilising electric vehicles and bikes. 2023 saw such emissions fall by 60% across Synnovis, helping to keep London&#8217;s air cleaner. Social: The transformation programme enables the hand back of over 6,000m2 of real estate to Synnovis&#8217; NHS partners to use for critical hospital services (the equivalent of over 150 operating theatres). Governance Both internally and externally, ESG is integrated within the Synnovis organisational culture. For example, internally it applies mandatory sustainability metrics to its solution selection processes. These influenced the selection of Abbott&#8217;s Indexor solution to support the transformation of Blood Sciences, delivering a saving of over 2.8 million plastic sample bags every year. Externally, SYNLAB works with its partners to manage this substantial and complex transformation programme. Risk management is assured through transparency, securing confidence in the good use of public funds, ensuring responsiveness to customer and partner feedback, and ensuring accountability for and the delivery of targeted healthcare outcomes. Conclusions The integration of SYNLAB&#8217;s ESG strategy within the transformation programme is delivering tangible benefits across all ESG pillars. It has highlighted that in addition to the core outcome of services transformation, there are many more opportunities that can be realised as a result of making ESG an integral part of the pathology transformation programme.</description>
      <author>T Ellison, Louise Hughes, R. F. G. Booth, Garry M. Walsh, David Dunn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making of an Indigenous and Efficient Powertrains for EV, HEV &amp;amp; FCEV&#8217;s</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37285/ajmt.4.3.0</link>
      <description>S. S. Ramdasi, ARAI Journal of Mobility Technology. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403077243

                Rise in greenhouse gas emissions which is resulting into ozone layer depletion and global warming effect is alarming to control CO2 emissions by drastically reducing fossil fuel consumption from the vehicles. This need has already started trend towards extreme downsizing and down speeding of Internal Combustion Engines (ICE) for making them highly efficient. In addition to this use of after treatment devices viz. Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (DOC), Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF), Lean NOx Catalyst (LNT), Selective Catalytic Reduction (SCR) are helping to a great extent for meeting emission norms till Euro - VI for automotive sector, Tier&#8211;IV F and Stage V for Off Highway Power sector. However, to address present greenhouse effect along with exponential decay of fossil fuels, there is need to achieve CO2 emissions less than 100 g/km or to achieve practically zero carbon footprint using an alternate powertrain. Electrification is one of the promising solutions and which is three-fold in present situation. The first level of electrification comes in the form of Hybrid Electric Vehicle (HEV) technology followed by Battery Electric Vehicles and Fuel Cell Electric Vehicles as second and third level of electrification respectively. In all these technologies a common thread is running in the form of an efficient electric drive train. Several efforts have been taken to improve torque per unit ampere by use of efficient motor and motor control algorithms viz PMSM powered with FOC, by developing controls which take care of parametric variations and external force disturbances by use of back stepping techniques which are based on rotor resistance estimation by fuzzy logic, FOC techniques based on adaptive input-output feedback linearization, by shifting towards high voltage systems, by going for higher switching frequencies for inverters which uses silicon carbide based MOSFET switches, by exploring use of multilevel inverters for Total Harmonic Distortion (THD) control etc. Use of E Axle based powertrains in EV, HEV and FCEV offers additional complimentary benefits apart from technology options described above. E Axle based powertrains offers flexibility in generating three variants of vehicle using one electric drive train architecture viz. making EV, HEV &amp; FCEV. Compactness, modularity, scalability, flexibility along with efficient cooling system management and control over active current losses due to use of bus bars are the implicit advantages of E Axle based powertrains. These advantages further get multiplies if we go for 3 in 1 (gearbox + Stator housing + Inverter) architectures which are predominantly used in independent suspension-based vehicles. Lot of efforts are going on to inherit this technology for rigid axle suspension based commercial vehicles. Research in this area is getting further extended to make 5 in 1 E Axles where there will addition of DC - DC converter and On-Board Charger (OBC) apart from components present in 3 in 1 configuration. Two major challenges need to be addressed and to be resolved while designing E Axle based powertrains by doing concurrent vehicle engineering. This is mainly due to increased unsprang weight that need to be handled by suspension system and exposed electric drive components to excitation loads coming from roads. Fig: Indigenously Developed E Axle Based Powertrain for Small Commercial VehiclesBy proper lay outing for effective vehicle mass distribution and required CG location which is essential from overall vehicle dynamics, more space can be offered by E Axle based powertrains for increasing battery energy density for getting more electric range in case of BEV&#8217;s. This add on space benefit extend help in packaging of hydrogen fuel cell integrated with power cells in case of FCEV&#8217;s. Thus, E Axle based powertrains proves to be modern and most efficient way of making EV, HEV &amp; FCEV&#8217;s.</description>
      <author>S. S. Ramdasi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37285/ajmt.4.3.0</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
