<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 01:11:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Pd doped tin oxide nanostructured catalysts for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4621090/v1</link>
      <description>Shuting Tan, Zhuo Xiong, Zuwei Xu, Junying Zhang, Yongchun Zhao, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400678732

                Abstract Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 can convert CO2 into a variety of carbon-based fuels and achieve carbon neutrality. Tin oxide (SnO2) electrocatalytic materials have the advantages of low cost and low toxicity, and the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formic acid is highly selective. In this paper, Pd-doped SnO2 nanoparticle materials were synthesized by flame spray pyrolysis and their properties for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formic acid were explored in a gas diffusion electrolytic cell. The results showed that the Pd/SnO2 catalysts could improve the catalytic activity for the conversion of CO2 to formate, and the most superior 0.5 Pd/SnO2 showed a Faraday efficiency of 63% for formate at -1.20 V vs. RHE and a current density of 90.59 mA.cm&#8722; 2, which were 1.4 and 2.7 times higher than that of pure SnO2, respectively. The modified catalyst grains were refined, and the charge transfer resistance at the catalyst interface was reduced and the electrochemically active area was increased, generating more catalytically active sites and increasing the contact between CO2, electrolyte, and electrode-catalyst. Density-functional theory calculations showed that the doping of Pd element changed the local structure of SnO2, and the Pd/SnO2 surface was more favorable for the generation of the intermediate products *HCOO&#8722; and formate as well as the inhibition of hydrogen precipitation, which was consistent with the experimental results.</description>
      <author>Shuting Tan, Zhuo Xiong, Zuwei Xu, Junying Zhang, Yongchun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4621090/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide to Formate in the Acetylene-Black Gas-Diffusion Electrode with a Tin Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700149</link>
      <description>G. A. Kolyagin, &#1054;xana P. &#1058;aran, Russian journal of electrochemistry. 60(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400737610

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. A. Kolyagin, &#1054;xana P. &#1058;aran</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymerized Ionic Liquid Co-Catalysts Driving Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00194j</link>
      <description>Lisa Eisele, Blet&#235; Hulaj, Francesco Laudani, Maximilian Podsednik, Pablo Ayala, Alexey Cherevan, Annette Foelske, Andreas Limbeck, Dominik Eder, Katharina Bica, RSC sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400740450

                Photocatalytic production of CO from CO 2 has the potential for safe and atom-economic production of feedstock chemicals via in-situ carbonylation chemistry. We developed novel ionic liquid-based polymeric materials through radical...</description>
      <author>Lisa Eisele, Blet&#235; Hulaj, Francesco Laudani, Maximilian Podsednik, Pablo Ayala, Alexey Cherevan, Annette Foelske, Andreas Limbeck, Dominik Eder, Katharina Bica</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00194j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving co-electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction by optimizing the relative potentials of the redox mediator and catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01988a</link>
      <description>Amelia G. Reid, Ethan A. Zelenke, Megan E. Moberg, Diane A. Dickie, Charles W. Machan, Chemical communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400742285

                The effects of fixing the redox mediator (RM) reduction potential relative to a series of Cr-centered complexes capable of the reduction of CO</description>
      <author>Amelia G. Reid, Ethan A. Zelenke, Megan E. Moberg, Diane A. Dickie, Charles W. Machan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01988a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring vinegar residue-derived all-carbon electrodes for efficient electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction to formate through heteroatom doping and defect enrichment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.085</link>
      <description>Yun Kong, Bin Jiang, Yuchen Tian, Rong Liu, Firdoz Shaik, Journal of colloid and interface science. 676(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400768126

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (ECO</description>
      <author>Yun Kong, Bin Jiang, Yuchen Tian, Rong Liu, Firdoz Shaik</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-purity ethylene production via indirect carbon dioxide electrochemical reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50522-7</link>
      <description>Wenpeng Ni, Houjun Chen, Nujiang Tang, Ting Hu, Shiguo Zhang, Yan Zhang, Shiguo Zhang, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400834240

                Abstract High-purity ethylene production from CO 2 electroreduction (CO 2 RR) is a coveted, yet arduous feat because the product stream comprises a blend of unreacted CO 2 , H 2, and other off-target CO 2 reduction products. Here we present an indirect reduction strategy for CO 2 -to-ethylene conversion, one that employs 2-bromoethanol (Br-EO) as a mediator. Br-EO is initially generated from CO 2 RR and subsequently undergoes reduction to ethylene without the need for energy-intensive separation steps. The optimized AC-Ag/C catalyst with Cl incorporation reduces the energy barrier of the debromination step during Br-EO reduction, and accelerates the mass-transfer process, delivering a 4-fold decrease of the relaxation time constant. Resultantly, AC-Ag/C achieved a FE ethylene of over 95.0 &#177; 0.36% at a low potential of &#8722;0.08 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) in an H-type cell with 0.5 M KCl electrolyte, alongside a near 100% selectivity within the range of &#8722;0.38 to &#8722;0.58 V versus RHE. Through this indirect strategy, the average ethylene purity within 6-hour electrolysis was 98.00 &#177; 1.45 wt%, at &#8722;0.48 V (vs RHE) from the neutralized electrolyte after CO 2 reduction over the Cu/Cu 2 O catalyst in a flow-cell.</description>
      <author>Wenpeng Ni, Houjun Chen, Nujiang Tang, Ting Hu, Shiguo Zhang, Yan Zhang, Shiguo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50522-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural crystal engineering for energy: Unleashing the potential of metal-organic frameworks for photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102197</link>
      <description>Sirisha Subbareddy, Santhosh Arehalli Shivamurthy, Srujan Basavapura Ravikumar, M.K. Hema, Sandeep Shadakshari, Manickam Selvaraj, Sanjay Basumatary, Materials Today Chemistry. 40(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400851293

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sirisha Subbareddy, Santhosh Arehalli Shivamurthy, Srujan Basavapura Ravikumar, M.K. Hema, Sandeep Shadakshari, Manickam Selvaraj, Sanjay Basumatary</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Roughness of Copper Working Electrode through Electroless Deposition for Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113013</link>
      <description>Watsananan T. Thienprasert, N. Manjula, Ninie Suhana Abdul Manan, Yu&#8208;Hsu Chang, Materials Research Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400880028

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Watsananan T. Thienprasert, N. Manjula, Ninie Suhana Abdul Manan, Yu&#8208;Hsu Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the energy efficiency and carbon dioxide reduction of a long-haul bus through aerodynamic design optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06173</link>
      <description>, Global NEST Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741600

                &lt;p&gt;Exhaustion of fossil fuel resources, inconsistent fuel costs and the difficulty of adopting electric vehicle technology in commercial vehicles support the idea that there is an opportunity for research in public transit regarding the correlation between energy efficiency and aerodynamic drag. The turbulent external airflow over a bus at high speeds impacts acceleration, speed, and fuel economy. The fundamental bus's design is intended to carry enough passengers for a reasonable run. Envisaging the factors influencing aerodynamic drag is defiant due to the convoluted relationship between the moving bus and the air. Consequently, a comprehensive numerical and experimental exploration is executed on the bodywork of a bus to improve its aerodynamic efficiency. The aerodynamic drag is directly proportional to the variations in the air density, frontal area, freestream velocity and the drag coefficient. Minimal design reforms are performed on a distinctive long-haul bus. The exertion aims to minimize the drag coefficient, thereby improving the flow characteristics of the bus's bodywork. Through the shape optimization of the bus's bodywork, the modified design has attained a forty-five percent reduction in the drag coefficient. This substantial reduction in drag coefficient directly impacts the reduction of drag force, energy efficiency improvement, and carbon emissions reduction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of organic ligands for metal-organic frameworks as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02635g</link>
      <description>Ya Zhang, Wei&#8208;Yin Sun, Chemical communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400722259

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction to valuable chemical compounds is a sustainable technology with enormous potential to facilitate carbon neutrality by transforming intermittent energy sources into stable fuels. Among various...</description>
      <author>Ya Zhang, Wei&#8208;Yin Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02635g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping engineering of Cu-based catalysts for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to multi-carbon products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee01325e</link>
      <description>Shixue You, Jiewen Xiao, Shuyu Liang, Wenfu Xie, Tianyu Zhang, Min Li, Ziyi Zhong, Qiang Wang, Hong He, Energy &amp; environmental science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400782748

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (CO2RR) is a promising technology that uses renewable energy sources to convert excess atmospheric CO2 into high-value multi-carbon (C2+) products. In the CO2RR mechanism, adsorbed *CO...</description>
      <author>Shixue You, Jiewen Xiao, Shuyu Liang, Wenfu Xie, Tianyu Zhang, Min Li, Ziyi Zhong, Qiang Wang, Hong He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee01325e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cleaner separation and recovery of valuable metals from spent ternary cathode via carbon dioxide synergetic thermite reduction strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121853</link>
      <description>Cheng Yang, Qiong Wang, Liang Xu, Yongpan Tian, Zhuo Zhao, Journal of environmental management. 366(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400673266

                The low-carbon recycling of spent lithium-ion batteries has become crucial due to the increasing need to address resource shortages and environmental concerns. Herein, a low-carbon, facile, and efficient method was developed to separate and recover Li, Al, and transition metals from spent ternary cathodes. Initially, the cathode materials post-discharge and disassembly do not require pre-sorting. Instead of using carbonaceous materials, the Al foil in the cathode serves as the reducing agent during reduction roasting. The impact of different roasting atmospheres (air, N</description>
      <author>Cheng Yang, Qiong Wang, Liang Xu, Yongpan Tian, Zhuo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging intramolecular electrostatics to boost electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101053</link>
      <description>David S. Tresp, Demyan E. Prokopchuk, Chem catalysis. 4(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400770264

                No abstract</description>
      <author>David S. Tresp, Demyan E. Prokopchuk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enzymatic CO2 reduction catalyzed by natural and artificial Metalloenzymes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2024.112669</link>
      <description>Yunling Deng, Jingxiang Wang, Barindra Kumar Ghosh, Yi Lu, Journal of inorganic biochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400799664

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunling Deng, Jingxiang Wang, Barindra Kumar Ghosh, Yi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2024.112669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on plasmonic enhancement of activity and selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-024-0950-8</link>
      <description>Jing Xue, Zhenlin Chen, Yuchao Zhang, Jincai Zhao, Frontiers in Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400798034

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Xue, Zhenlin Chen, Yuchao Zhang, Jincai Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-024-0950-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoredox coupling of carbon dioxide reduction with tetracycline oxidation using excited-state bismuth and cobalt dual sites over cobalt-tailored bismuth oxychloride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.124</link>
      <description>Xinyue Li, Haili Lin, Xuemei Jia, Haoyu Sun, Shifu Chen, Jing Cao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 676(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400786546

                Photocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO</description>
      <author>Xinyue Li, Haili Lin, Xuemei Jia, Haoyu Sun, Shifu Chen, Jing Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Spin Polarization via Axial Nitrogen Traction at Fe&#8208;N5 Sites Enhanced Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction for Zn&#8208;CO2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406030</link>
      <description>Yongzhong Bao, Jiayong Xiao, Yongkang Huang, Youzhi Li, Siyu Yao, Ming Qiu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Lecheng Lei, Zhongjian Li, Jing Wang, Gang Wu, Bin Yang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400797651

                Single Fe sites have been explored as promising catalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction to value&#8208;added CO. Herein, we introduce a novel molten salt synthesis strategy for developing axial nitrogen&#8208;coordinated Fe&#8208;N5 sites on ultrathin defect&#8208;rich carbon nanosheets, aiming to modulate the reaction pathway precisely. This distinctive architecture weakens the spin polarization at the Fe sites, promoting a dynamic equilibrium of activated intermediates and facilitating the balance between *COOH formation and *CO desorption at the active Fe site. Notably, the synthesized FeN5, supported on defect&#8208;rich in nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (FeN5@DNC), exhibits superior performance in CO2RR, achieving a Faraday efficiency of 99% for CO production (&#8208;0.4 V vs. RHE) in an H&#8208;cell, and maintaining a Faraday efficiency of 98% at a current density of 270 mA cm&#8208;2 (&#8208;1.0 V vs. RHE) in the flow cell. Furthermore, the FeN5@DNC catalyst is assembled as a reversible Zn&#8208;CO2 battery with a cycle durability of 24 hours. In&#8208;situ IR spectroscopy and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the axial N coordination traction induces a transformation in the crystal field and local symmetry, therefore weakening the spin polarization of the central Fe atom and lowering the energy barrier for *CO desorption.</description>
      <author>Yongzhong Bao, Jiayong Xiao, Yongkang Huang, Youzhi Li, Siyu Yao, Ming Qiu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Lecheng Lei, Zhongjian Li, Jing Wang, Gang Wu, Bin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Spin Polarization via Axial Nitrogen Traction at Fe&#8208;N5 Sites Enhanced Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction for Zn&#8208;CO2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406030</link>
      <description>Yongzhong Bao, Jiayong Xiao, Yongkang Huang, Youzhi Li, Siyu Yao, Ming Qiu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Lecheng Lei, Zhongjian Li, Jing Wang, Gang Wu, Jing Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400797890

                Single Fe sites have been explored as promising catalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction to value&#8208;added CO. Herein, we introduce a novel molten salt synthesis strategy for developing axial nitrogen&#8208;coordinated Fe&#8208;N5 sites on ultrathin defect&#8208;rich carbon nanosheets, aiming to modulate the reaction pathway precisely. This distinctive architecture weakens the spin polarization at the Fe sites, promoting a dynamic equilibrium of activated intermediates and facilitating the balance between *COOH formation and *CO desorption at the active Fe site. Notably, the synthesized FeN5, supported on defect&#8208;rich in nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (FeN5@DNC), exhibits superior performance in CO2RR, achieving a Faraday efficiency of 99% for CO production (&#8208;0.4 V vs. RHE) in an H&#8208;cell, and maintaining a Faraday efficiency of 98% at a current density of 270 mA cm&#8208;2 (&#8208;1.0 V vs. RHE) in the flow cell. Furthermore, the FeN5@DNC catalyst is assembled as a reversible Zn&#8208;CO2 battery with a cycle durability of 24 hours. In&#8208;situ IR spectroscopy and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the axial N coordination traction induces a transformation in the crystal field and local symmetry, therefore weakening the spin polarization of the central Fe atom and lowering the energy barrier for *CO desorption.</description>
      <author>Yongzhong Bao, Jiayong Xiao, Yongkang Huang, Youzhi Li, Siyu Yao, Ming Qiu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Lecheng Lei, Zhongjian Li, Jing Wang, Gang Wu, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances of the catalysts for photoelectrocatalytic oxygen evolution and CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60053-7</link>
      <description>Hongrui Zhu, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Zhijie Zhang, Qi&#8208;Ni Zhan, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Gao&#8208;Ren Li, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806504

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongrui Zhu, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Zhijie Zhang, Qi&#8208;Ni Zhan, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Gao&#8208;Ren Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60053-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale Modeling of CO2 Electrochemical Reduction on Copper Electrocatalysts: A Review of Advancements, Challenges, and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400898</link>
      <description>Reza Gholizadeh, Matic Pavlin, Matej Hu&#353;, Bla&#382; Likozar, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400777654

                Although CO2 contributes to global warming, it also offers potential as a raw material for the production of hydrocarbons (CH4, C2H4 and CH3OH). Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) is an emerging technology that utilizes renewable energy to convert CO2 into valuable fuels, solving environmental and energy problems simultaneously. Insights gained at any individual scale can only provide a limited view of that specific scale. Multiscale modeling, which involves coupling atomistic&#8208;level insights (DFT) and (MD), with mesoscale (KMC and MK) and macroscale (CFD) simulations, has received significant attention recently. While multiscale modeling of eCO2RR on electrocatalysts across all scales is limited due to its complexity, this review offers an overview of recent works on single scales and the coupling of two and three scales, such as "DFT+MD", "DFT+KMC", "DFT+MK", "KMC/MK+CFD" and "DFT+MK/KMC+CFD", focusing particularly on Cu&#8208;based electrocatalysts. This sets it apart from other reviews that solely focus exclusively on a single scale or only on a combination of DFT and MK/KMC scales. Furthermore, this review offers a concise overview of machine learning (ML) applications for eCO2RR, an emerging approach that has not yet been reviewed. Finally, this review highlights the key challenges, research gaps and perspectives of multiscale modeling for eCO2RR.</description>
      <author>Reza Gholizadeh, Matic Pavlin, Matej Hu&#353;, Bla&#382; Likozar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First-Principles Study on the Reaction Mechanisms of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction to C1 and C2 Products on Cu(110)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070468</link>
      <description>Yangyang Xu, Lixin Zhang, Catalysts. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400873071

                The mechanism of the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction on a Cu(110) surface has yet to be fully revealed. In this work, based on first-principles calculations, we investigate the mechanisms of the CO2 reduction reaction to produce C1 (including one C atom) and C2 (including two C atoms) products on a Cu(110) surface. The results show that CH4 and C2H5OH are the main C1 and C2 products on the Cu(110) surface, respectively. CH4 is produced along the pathway CO2 &#8594; COOH* &#8594; CO* &#8594; CHO* &#8594; CH2O* &#8594; CH3O* &#8594; CH4. C2H5OH is produced via the C-C coupling pathway between CO* and CH2O* intermediates, which is the key reaction step. This is because CO* and CH2O* coupling to CO-CH2O* has the lowest barrier among the CHxO* (x = 0&#8211;2) coupling pathways. Therefore, it is the most likely C-C coupling pathway. Further, CO-CH2O* is gradually hydrogenated to C2H5OH along the following pathway: CO-CH2O* &#8594; CHO-CH2O* &#8594; CHOH-CH2* &#8594; CH2OH-CH2* &#8594; CH2OH-CH3* &#8594; C2H5OH.</description>
      <author>Yangyang Xu, Lixin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu into Cu2O/RuAl intermetallic heterojunction for lowering the thermodynamic energy barrier of the CO2 reduction and evolution reactions in Li&#8211;CO2 battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.016</link>
      <description>Wenqing Ma, Jiagang Hou, Siyu Liu, Tianzhen Jian, Jianping Ma, Caixia Xu, Hong Liu, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400673212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenqing Ma, Jiagang Hou, Siyu Liu, Tianzhen Jian, Jianping Ma, Caixia Xu, Hong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Layered Double Hydroxides and Metal-Organic Frameworks for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2024.100384</link>
      <description>Mahider Tekalgne, Ha Huu, Gyeong Ho Han, Sung Hyun Hong, Jin Hyuk Cho, Sang Hyun Ahn, Soo Young Kim, Carbon Trends. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400882601

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mahider Tekalgne, Ha Huu, Gyeong Ho Han, Sung Hyun Hong, Jin Hyuk Cho, Sang Hyun Ahn, Soo Young Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2024.100384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile fabrication of CdIn2S4/TiO2 heterojunction for enhanced solar light efficient CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11705-024-2456-7</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Ma, Longlong Wang, Houde She, Yingwu Zhou, Li Wang, Jingwei Huang, Qizhao Wang, Frontiers of Chemical Science and Engineering. 18(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400797656

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Ma, Longlong Wang, Houde She, Yingwu Zhou, Li Wang, Jingwei Huang, Qizhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11705-024-2456-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pincer Shaped N-Mesoionic Pyridylidene Amide (PYA) for Palladium Catalyzed CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.139347</link>
      <description>Afshan Khurshid, Muhammad Nawaz Tahir, Faroha Liaqat, Maqsood Ahmed, Ehsan Ullah Mughal, M.N. Zafar, Journal of molecular structure. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400855941

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Afshan Khurshid, Muhammad Nawaz Tahir, Faroha Liaqat, Maqsood Ahmed, Ehsan Ullah Mughal, M.N. Zafar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.139347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling and quantifying the mass transfer resistance of the gas diffusion electrode for CO2 electrochemical reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154124</link>
      <description>Qiqi Wan, Bang Li, L.Q. Li, Yingying Liu, Lixia Yuan, Endao Zhang, Xiaodong Zhuang, Yongyi Jiang, Junliang Zhang, Changchun Ke, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400839759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiqi Wan, Bang Li, L.Q. Li, Yingying Liu, Lixia Yuan, Endao Zhang, Xiaodong Zhuang, Yongyi Jiang, Junliang Zhang, Changchun Ke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Dual Single Atom Ni/Cu Catalyst for Highly Selective CO2-to-Ethanol Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124420</link>
      <description>Soressa Abera Chala, Keseven Lakshmanan, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Amaha Woldu Kahsay, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Fikiru Temesgen Angerasa, Yen&#8208;Fa Liao, Jyh&#8208;Fu Lee, Hongjie Dai, Meng&#8208;Che Tsai, Wei&#8722;Nien Su, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400766652

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soressa Abera Chala, Keseven Lakshmanan, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Amaha Woldu Kahsay, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Fikiru Temesgen Angerasa, Yen&#8208;Fa Liao, Jyh&#8208;Fu Lee, Hongjie Dai, Meng&#8208;Che Tsai, Wei&#8722;Nien Su, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124420</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO using molecule-regulated Ag nanoparticle in ionic liquids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.07.005</link>
      <description>Fangfang Li, Kuilin Peng, Chongyang Jiang, Shaojuan Zeng, Shaojuan Zeng, Xiaoyan Ji, Green energy &amp; environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400785845

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fangfang Li, Kuilin Peng, Chongyang Jiang, Shaojuan Zeng, Shaojuan Zeng, Xiaoyan Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.07.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction to syngas on copper mesh electrode: Alloying strategy for tuning syngas composition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100254</link>
      <description>Yangna Luo, Xianglin Chen, Yuping Wu, Yafei Guo, Yuxuan Gao, Guoyang Zhao, Chuanwen Zhao, Carbon capture science &amp; technology. 13(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400867292

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yangna Luo, Xianglin Chen, Yuping Wu, Yafei Guo, Yuxuan Gao, Guoyang Zhao, Chuanwen Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 and CO reduction using Au/TiO2 model catalysts for syngas and Fischer-Tropsch chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.184</link>
      <description>So Young Kim, Seon Young Hwang, Gak-Won Yun, Yunji Gwon, Sooyeon Bae, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400720613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>So Young Kim, Seon Young Hwang, Gak-Won Yun, Yunji Gwon, Sooyeon Bae, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in tracking electrochemical CO2 reduction intermediates over single-atom catalysts using operando ATR-SEIRAS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60068-9</link>
      <description>Jing Yan, Jiaqi Ni, Hongli Sun, Chenliang Su, Bin Liu, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806569

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Yan, Jiaqi Ni, Hongli Sun, Chenliang Su, Bin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60068-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 transformed into highly active catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction via low-temperature molten salt electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107781</link>
      <description>Anna-Liis Remmel, Sander Ratso, Kerli T&#245;nurist, Mati Danilson, Valdek Mikli, Ivar Kruusenberg, Electrochemistry communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400858753

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anna-Liis Remmel, Sander Ratso, Kerli T&#245;nurist, Mati Danilson, Valdek Mikli, Ivar Kruusenberg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical co-reduction of N2 and CO2 to urea using In2S3 anchored on S-doped reduced graphene oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118516</link>
      <description>Xinyi Chen, Pingxing Xing, Shenqi Wei, Hualan Luo, Liyi Dai, Yuanyuan Wang, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400866323

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyi Chen, Pingxing Xing, Shenqi Wei, Hualan Luo, Liyi Dai, Yuanyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The performance of CO2 reduction by dielectric barrier discharge plasma coupled Cu-Ni binary silicon-based composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113617</link>
      <description>Xue&#8208;Qian Wu, Jinlong Zhao, Jing Tao, Jiawen Chi, Xin Min, Songjian Zhao, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400767886

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue&#8208;Qian Wu, Jinlong Zhao, Jing Tao, Jiawen Chi, Xin Min, Songjian Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Systems Engineering Approach to Decarbonizing Mining: Analyzing Electrification and CO2 Emission Reduction Scenarios for Copper Mining Haulage Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146232</link>
      <description>Kemalcan Aydogdu, &#350;ebnem D&#252;zg&#252;n, Evren Deniz Yaylac&#305;, Fatih Aranoglu, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400873606

                Due to climate change risks, the public, regulators, and investors require solid actions to minimize the greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions of mineral extraction and metals production. The mining sector considers alternatives to reduce its carbon footprint by transforming the business and adopting new technologies into operations. Given the capital intensity, technical characteristics, and business structure involved, a shift in the mining industry necessitates impartial insights into the trade-offs and risks. Considering the low-carbon transition trade-offs and risks in mining, this study presents the application of system dynamics modeling (SDM) in mining projects to analyze the impact of decarbonization alternatives with respect to carbon footprint and costs. A system dynamics model of an open-pit copper mine is developed to quantify greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, as well as capital and operational costs, during the project life cycle. The change in GHG emissions in the business-as-usual scenario with diesel equipment haulage versus the alternative scenario with electric overland conveyor haulage is compared concerning GHG emissions and associated costs. The results unequivocally demonstrated that electrifying material mobility offers significant decarbonization in open-pit mining if the on-site electricity has a low emission factor. The findings also indicate that the substantial cost difference between electrification and diesel alternatives is another major obstacle to implementing electrification in an open-pit copper mine. This research proves that implementing SDM in the mining industry can offer impartial insights into decision-making and enable a thorough evaluation of options using quantitative criteria. It effectively assesses and communicates the trade-offs and risks of transitioning to low-carbon alternatives because it analyzes project variables quantitatively and holistically and is easy to run.</description>
      <author>Kemalcan Aydogdu, &#350;ebnem D&#252;zg&#252;n, Evren Deniz Yaylac&#305;, Fatih Aranoglu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electro-synthesis of valuable products by coupling energy-saving anodic alcohol oxidation reaction with cathodic CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.223</link>
      <description>Faiza Zulfiqar, Farhan Arshad, Tanveer ul Haq, Falak Sher, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400863957

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faiza Zulfiqar, Farhan Arshad, Tanveer ul Haq, Falak Sher</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective reduction of CO2 to ethanol over Si/Cu(1 1 1) surface: An insights from the first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114781</link>
      <description>Chang Liu, Dan Wang, Boting Yang, Song Jiang, Gang Sun, Yong&#8208;Qing Qiu, Chun&#8208;Guang Liu, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400867054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang Liu, Dan Wang, Boting Yang, Song Jiang, Gang Sun, Yong&#8208;Qing Qiu, Chun&#8208;Guang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Financial Efficiency and Renewable Energy Consumption on CO2 Emission Reduction in GCC Economies: A Panel Data Quantile Regression Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146242</link>
      <description>Lena Bedawi Elfadli Elmonshid, Omer Ahmed Sayed, Ghadda Mohamed Awad Yousif, Kamal Eldin Hassan Ibrahim Eldaw, Muawya Ahmed Hussein, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400873485

                As prominent oil producers, Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) countries have played a significant role in the global energy market. However, as the world&#8217;s attention increasingly shifts towards environmental sustainability, understanding the implications of the GCC&#8217;s economic activities on CO2 emissions becomes indispensable. This research paper investigates the relationship between specific economic indicators and their impact on CO2 emissions in the GCC from 2001 to 2021. This study employs quantile regression, a robust statistical method that estimates the conditional quantiles of a response variable given a set of predictor variables. The findings reveal several essential insights: Financial institution efficiency is significant and negative at a 1% level at the lower (10th, &#8722;83,537.3) and higher quantiles (90th, &#8722;549,002.3). The relationship between the GDP per capita and CO2 emissions varies across quantiles, highlighting the complexity of the growth&#8211;environment nexus. Total patents exhibit a positive and significant relationship with emissions, underscoring the importance of directing innovation towards environmentally sustainable solutions. Renewable energy consumption displays a nuanced relationship with CO2 emissions, with a more substantial negative impact observed at higher consumption levels. This underscores the potential of renewable energy to mitigate emissions when integrated at scale. This study&#8217;s outcomes hold crucial policy implications for GCC countries as they seek to align economic growth with environmental sustainability. The findings emphasize the importance of fostering financial institution efficiency, promoting green innovation, and expanding renewable energy sources to reduce emissions.</description>
      <author>Lena Bedawi Elfadli Elmonshid, Omer Ahmed Sayed, Ghadda Mohamed Awad Yousif, Kamal Eldin Hassan Ibrahim Eldaw, Muawya Ahmed Hussein</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 on a CoTPP/MWCNT Composite: Investigation of Operation Parameters Influence on CH3OH Production by Differential Electrochemical Mass Spectrometry (DEMS)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144748</link>
      <description>Mongur Hossain, Milla Suominen, Tanja Kallio, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400865895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mongur Hossain, Milla Suominen, Tanja Kallio</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of electrochemical active surface area of Cu on electrochemical CO2 reduction in acidic electrolyte using Cu nanoparticles on surfactant-treated carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115662</link>
      <description>H.-J. Noh, Yoonsun Park, Ashutosh Bhadouria, Brian M. Tackett, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400859814

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H.-J. Noh, Yoonsun Park, Ashutosh Bhadouria, Brian M. Tackett</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115662</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT and machine learning studies on a multi-functional single-atom catalyst for enhanced oxygen and hydrogen evolution as well as CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.244</link>
      <description>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806168

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing CO2 reduction efficiency: surface&#8208;regulated highly porous Ag&#8208;Cu alloy aerogel inserted with multi&#8208;wall carbon nanotube achieving nearly complete CO selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400959</link>
      <description>Junyan Wang, J.S. Park, Iman A. Mahdy, Zixin Yu, Zehao Fang, Meissam Noroozifar, Heinz-Bernhard Kraatz, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400878137

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (eCO2RR) holds promise in mitigating atmospheric greenhouse gas levels but is hindered by low reaction kinetics, high energy barriers, and poor selectivity. To address these challenges, we developed a novel series of cost&#8208;effective AgCu&#8208;containing metal&#8208;aerogel catalysts with high electrochemical surface areas (ECSA) using a top&#8208;down reduction approach. The Ag85Cu15 aerogel, with an ECSA of 27.41 cm&#178;, achieved a Faraday efficiency (FE%) of 89.3% for CO production at &#8208;0.9 V vs. RHE. Increasing the Cu content to over 50% in the aerogel matrix produced small amounts of C2H4, with a maximum FE% of 12.9% at &#8208;1.0 V vs. RHE. To further enhance CO2 reduction efficiency, multi&#8208;walled carbon nanotubes (CNT) were incorporated into the Ag85Cu15 alloy aerogel via a hydrothermal treatment. The highly dispersed CNTs within the aerogel matrix increased the ECSA to 57.00 cm&#178; by forming a well&#8208;defined porous structure through van&#8208;der Waals interactions, improving CO selectivity, and achieving a FE% of 98.6% at &#8208;0.7 V vs. RHE and a partial current density of 9.6 mA/cm&#178; in an H&#8208;cell. 86% of the initial FECO% was maintained during an 18 h test with continuous electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Junyan Wang, J.S. Park, Iman A. Mahdy, Zixin Yu, Zehao Fang, Meissam Noroozifar, Heinz-Bernhard Kraatz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pronounced reduction in the regeneration energy of potassium sarcosinate CO2 capture solvent using TiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128850</link>
      <description>Dhruba J. Deka, Gyoung Gug Jang, Radu Custelcean, Di&#257;na Stamberga, Jong K. Keum, Radu Custelcean, Costas Tsouris, Separation and Purification Technology. 354(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4400888913

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dhruba J. Deka, Gyoung Gug Jang, Radu Custelcean, Di&#257;na Stamberga, Jong K. Keum, Radu Custelcean, Costas Tsouris</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of carbon dioxide disposal methods to reduce greenhouse gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37878/2708-0080/2024-2.16</link>
      <description>Bolatbek Khussain, A. Kenessary, E. Narimanov, Jamilyam Ismailova, Dinara Delikesheva, Neft&#697; i gaz. 140(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400739758

                The practice of capturing, storing and utilizing CO2 is becoming key to developing sustainable energy and industrial solutions. The technology promotes the use of fossil fuels, which remain the predominant source of energy worldwide. The effectiveness of the technology is evident in the reduction of CO2 levels in the atmosphere, a significant contribution to the reduction of global greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions and the fight against climate change. However, a notable concern in the realm of geological storage revolves around the potential leakage of CO2 from storage reservoirs. Carbon dioxide has the capability to migrate from the storage site, reaching both the surface and underground formations. Surface leakage presents health risks to humans, animals, and plants. The solution to this problem requires a detailed approach and should be solved through an inverse problem, in which pressure measurements in monitoring wells will be performed frequently to obtain information about the reservoir and possible leaks. Additionally, there are a number of issues with carbon dioxide leakage during oil and gas extraction, as well as various operations at fields. Emphasizing the monitoring of CO2 leakage, this paper underscores the importance of developing an algorithm designed to proactively prevent CO2 leakage in aquifers and depleted reservoirs. Such an initiative is pivotal in the broader context of mitigating greenhouse gas emissions. The paper offers an overview of methodologies for effective monitoring, management and modeling of CO2 leakage and practical approaches to calculation and assessment, contributing to a more complete understanding of the challenges associated with CO2 storage.</description>
      <author>Bolatbek Khussain, A. Kenessary, E. Narimanov, Jamilyam Ismailova, Dinara Delikesheva</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37878/2708-0080/2024-2.16</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic incentives to reduce Carbon Dioxide emissions from vehicles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34925/eip.2021.135.10.045</link>
      <description>&#1052;.&#1060;. &#1040;&#1075;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1079;&#1086;&#1077;&#1074;, &#200;konomika i predprinimatel&#697;stvo. None(10(135))] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4400852626

                &#1040;&#1082;&#1090;&#1091;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1100; &#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074; &#1090;&#1086;&#1084;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1085;&#1077;&#1086;&#1073;&#1093;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1084;&#1086; &#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1080;&#1090;&#1100; &#1074;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1085;&#1086;&#1077; &#1074;&#1083;&#1080;&#1103;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1074;&#1099;&#1073;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074; &#1072;&#1074;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084;&#1086;&#1073;&#1080;&#1083;&#1077;&#1081;, &#1090;&#1072;&#1082; &#1082;&#1072;&#1082; &#1089; &#1082;&#1072;&#1078;&#1076;&#1099;&#1084; &#1075;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1084; &#1079;&#1072;&#1075;&#1088;&#1103;&#1079;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1074;&#1086;&#1079;&#1076;&#1091;&#1093;&#1072; &#1091;&#1074;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1080;&#1074;&#1072;&#1077;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103;. &#1062;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1102; &#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1103;&#1074;&#1083;&#1103;&#1077;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1082;&#1072; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074; &#1101;&#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1084;&#1091;&#1083;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1089;&#1086;&#1082;&#1088;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074;&#1099;&#1073;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074; &#1057;&#1054;2 &#1072;&#1074;&#1090;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084;. &#1044;&#1083;&#1103; &#1076;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1081; &#1094;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1099; &#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1091;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1079;&#1072;&#1076;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080;: 1. &#1055;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1072;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1079; &#1074;&#1083;&#1080;&#1103;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074;&#1099;&#1073;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074; &#1085;&#1072; &#1086;&#1082;&#1088;&#1091;&#1078;&#1072;&#1102;&#1097;&#1091;&#1102; &#1089;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1091;. 2. &#1056;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1084;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1090;&#1100; &#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1099; &#1101;&#1084;&#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1080; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1075;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;. 3. &#1056;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072;&#1090;&#1100; &#1084;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1103;&#1090;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1086; &#1089;&#1086;&#1082;&#1088;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1074;&#1099;&#1073;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074; &#1057;02 &#1072;&#1074;&#1090;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084;. 4. &#1055;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1083;&#1086;&#1078;&#1080;&#1090;&#1100; &#1084;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1103;&#1090;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1086; &#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1084;&#1091;&#1083;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1089;&#1086;&#1082;&#1088;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074;&#1099;&#1073;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074; &#1057;O2 &#1072;&#1074;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084;&#1086;&#1073;&#1080;&#1083;&#1103;&#1084;&#1080;. &#1054;&#1073;&#1098;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090; &#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; -&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1084;&#1091;&#1083;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1089;&#1086;&#1082;&#1088;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1084;&#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1080; &#1057;02 &#1072;&#1074;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084;&#1086;&#1073;&#1080;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084; &#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084;. &#1055;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090; &#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; -&#1101;&#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1086;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;, &#1074;&#1086;&#1079;&#1085;&#1080;&#1082;&#1072;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1084;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1103;&#1090;&#1080;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086; &#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1101;&#1084;&#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1080; &#1057;02 &#1072;&#1074;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084;&#1086;&#1073;&#1080;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084; &#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084;. The relevance of this study is that it is necessary to reduce the harmful effect of car emissions, since air pollution is increasing every year. The purpose of this study is to develop methods of economic incentives to reduce CO2 emissions from vehicles. To achieve the goals, the following tasks have been set: 1. Conductan analysis of the impact of emissions on the environment. 2. Consider aspects of carbon dioxide emissions. 3.Develop measures to reduce CO2 emissions from vehicles. 4. Propose measures to stimulate the reduction ofCO2 emissions from vehicles. The object of the study is to stimulate the reduction of CO2 emissions by roadtransport. The subject of the research is economic relations arising in the process of carrying out measures toreduce CO2 emissions by road transport.</description>
      <author>&#1052;.&#1060;. &#1040;&#1075;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1079;&#1086;&#1077;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34925/eip.2021.135.10.045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Propiolic and Butynedioic Acids via Carboxylation of CaC2 by CO2 under Mild Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070467</link>
      <description>Xiaomin Zhao, Xiaoteng Zang, Yingzhou Lu, Hong Meng, Chunxi Li, Catalysts. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400875276

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) is a greenhouse gas, and its resource use is vital for carbon reduction and neutrality. Herein, the nucleophilic addition reaction of calcium carbide (CaC2) to CO2 was studied for the first time to synthesize propiolic and butynedioic acids by using CuI or AgNO3 as catalyst, Na2CO3 as additive, and triphenylphosphine as ligand in the presence/absence of a hydrogen donor. The effects of the experimental conditions and intensification approach on the reaction were investigated. The reactivity of CaC2 is closely associated with its synergistic activation by the catalysts, solvent, and external intensification, such as the ultrasound and mechanical force. Ultrasound helps to promote the reaction by enhancing the interfacial mass transfer of CaC2 particulates. Mechanochemistry can effectively promote the reaction, yielding 29.8% of butynedioic acid and 74.8% of propiolic acid after 2 h ball milling at 150 rpm, arising from the effective micronization and interfacial renewal of calcium carbide. The present study sheds a light on the high-value uses of CO2 and CaC2 and is of reference significance for the nucleophilic reaction of CaC2 with other carbonyl compounds.</description>
      <author>Xiaomin Zhao, Xiaoteng Zang, Yingzhou Lu, Hong Meng, Chunxi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear relationship between technological innovation and carbon emission: evidence from maximal information coefficient approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ijlct/ctae111</link>
      <description>Yi Zhu, Shuning Liu, &#152;The &#156;international journal of low carbon technologies. 19(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400843404

                Abstract Carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions reduction has emerged as a paramount priority, aiming to achieve &#8216;peak emissions and carbon neutrality&#8217;, wherein green innovation assumes a critical role. The existing literature has extensively examined the impact of green innovations on carbon emissions. However, there has been comparatively less emphasis on the nonlinear relationship between technological innovations and carbon emission. This research employs the panel data from 16 districts in Shanghai spanning from 2010 to 2019 to investigate the nonlinear relationship between technological innovation and carbon emissions. The primary objective of our research is to examine the applicability of the maximum information coefficient method within an environmental context. Furthermore, our analysis indicates that patent applications, patent citations, and patent grants exhibit feature importance scores of 0.55, 0.53, and 0.52, respectively, according to the random forest regression results. These findings offer valuable insights for policymakers committed to achieving carbon neutrality of China.</description>
      <author>Yi Zhu, Shuning Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ijlct/ctae111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Online Endoscopy Education Video Platform Reduces Carbon Footprint Associated with Endoscopy Related Patient Travel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47829/jjgh.2024.101002</link>
      <description>Yuming Ding, Gonzalo Chinchilla, Ann Vandeleur, Kimberley Littlemore, Tony Rahman, Japanese Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology. 10(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400896914

                1.1. Aims Endoscopy units are resource intensive and contribute to a significant part of healthcare&#8217;s carbon footprint and greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Sustainability measures is at the forefront of shifting towards carbon neutral endoscopy practices. In 2019, our department introduced an online endoscopy education video series to replace in person pre-procedural education, minimising patient travel associated emission. This study aims to quantify the reduction in pre-procedural travel-associated carbon dioxide emission using a digital health education intervention. 1.2. Methods Outpatient procedural activity between January 2019 to May 2022 at a single tertiary endoscopy unit was collated. Total distance of patient travel (kilometres) to hospital was calculated using postcode geodata coordinates between home postcodes to the hospital. The primary outcome was tonnes of CO2 emission averted from avoided travel.</description>
      <author>Yuming Ding, Gonzalo Chinchilla, Ann Vandeleur, Kimberley Littlemore, Tony Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47829/jjgh.2024.101002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conjugated polyimides modified self-supported carbon electrodes for electrochemical conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2024.35</link>
      <description>Daming Feng, Zuo Li, Huifang Guo, Xiaodong Sun, Peng Huang, Ying Sun, Hui Li, Tianyi Ma, Energy materials. 4(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400787503

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2RR) offers a promising approach to address the dual challenges of energy scarcity and environmental degradation. This study presents a new, cost-effective, and scalable electrocatalyst: self-supporting carbon paper modified with porous conjugated polyimides. This innovative material facilitates efficient CO2 conversion in aqueous media, eliminating the need for a pyrolysis step. The electrocatalyst&#8217;s design utilizes a non-metallic organic polymer with a high density of nitrogen atoms, serving as active sites for catalysis. Its unique mesoporous microsphere structure comprises randomly stacked nanosheets that are generated in situ and aligned along the carbon fibers of carbon paper substrate. This architecture enhances both CO2 adsorption and ensures proper electron transportation, facilitated by the conjugated structure of the polymer. Additionally, the inherent hydrophobicity of conjugated polyimides contributes to its robust catalytic performance in selectively reducing CO2, yielding CO as the primary gaseous product with up to 88.7% Faradaic efficiency and 82.0 mmol g-1 h-1 yield rate. Therefore, the proposed electrocatalyst provides a sustainable solution for electrochemical CO2RR catalyzed by non-metal organic materials, combining high efficiency with the advantages of a simple preparation process and the absence of costly materials or steps. This research contributes to the advancement of CO2RR technologies, potentially leading to more environmentally friendly and energy-efficient solutions.</description>
      <author>Daming Feng, Zuo Li, Huifang Guo, Xiaodong Sun, Peng Huang, Ying Sun, Hui Li, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2024.35</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biochar Co-Compost: A Promising Soil Amendment to Restrain Greenhouse Gases and Improve Rice Productivity and Soil Fertility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071583</link>
      <description>Muhammad Umair Hassan, Huang Guo-qin, Rizwan Munir, Tahir Abbas Khan, Mehmood Ali Noor, Agronomy. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400885594

                Agriculture is a major source of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Biochar has been recommended as a potential strategy to mitigate GHG emissions and improve soil fertility and crop productivity. However, few studies have investigated the potential of biochar co-compost (BCC) in relation to soil properties, rice productivity, and GHG emissions. Therefore, we examined the potential of BC, compost (CP), and BCC in terms of environmental and agronomic benefits. The study comprised four different treatments: control, biochar, compost, and biochar co-compost. The application of all of the treatments increased the soil pH; however, BC and BCC remained the top performers. The addition of BC and BBC also limited the ammonium nitrogen (NH4+-N) availability and increased soil organic carbon (SOC), which limited the GHG emissions. Biochar co-compost resulted in fewer carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions, while BC resulted in fewer methane (CH4) emissions, which was comparable with BCC. Moreover, BC caused a marked reduction in nitrous oxide (N2O) emissions that was comparable to BCC. This reduction was attributed to increased soil pH, nosZ, and nirK abundance and a reduction in ammonia-oxidizing archaea (AOA) and ammonia-oxidizing bacteria (AOB) abundance. The application of different amendments, particularly BCC, favored rice growth and productivity by increasing nutrient availability, soil carbon, and enzymatic activities. Lastly, BCC and BC also increased the abundance and diversity of soil bacteria, which favored plant growth and caused a reduction in GHG emissions. Our results suggest that BCC could be an important practice to recycle organic sources while optimizing climate change and crop productivity.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Umair Hassan, Huang Guo-qin, Rizwan Munir, Tahir Abbas Khan, Mehmood Ali Noor</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide Oil Repulsion in the Sandstone Reservoirs of Lunnan Oilfield, Tarim Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143503</link>
      <description>Zangyuan Wu, Qihong Feng, Liming Lian, Xiangjuan Meng, Daiyu Zhou, Min Luo, Hanlie Cheng, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400728892

                The Lunnan oilfield, nestled within the Tarim Basin, represents a prototypical extra-low-permeability sandstone reservoir, distinguished by high-quality crude oil characterised by a low viscosity, density, and gel content. The effective exploitation of such reservoirs hinges on the implementation of carbon dioxide (CO2) flooding techniques. This study, focusing on the sandstone reservoirs of Lunnan, delves into the mechanisms of CO2-assisted oil displacement under diverse operational parameters: injection pressures, CO2 concentration levels, and variations in crude oil properties. It integrates analyses on the high-pressure, high-temperature behaviour of CO2, the dynamics of CO2 injection and expansion, prolonged core flood characteristics, and the governing principles of minimum miscible pressure transitions. The findings reveal a nuanced interplay between variables: CO2&#8217;s density and viscosity initially surge with escalating injection pressures before stabilising, whereas they experience a gradual decline with increasing temperature. Enhanced CO2 injection correlates with a heightened expansion coefficient, yet the density increment of degassed crude oil remains marginal. Notably, CO2 viscosity undergoes a substantial reduction under stratigraphic pressures. The sequential application of water alternating gas (WAG) followed by continuous CO2 flooding attains oil recovery efficiency surpassing 90%, emphasising the superiority of uninterrupted CO2 injection over processes lacking profiling. The presence of non-miscible hydrocarbon gases in segmented plug drives impedes the oil displacement efficiency, underscoring the importance of CO2 purity in the displacement medium. Furthermore, a marked trend emerges in crude oil recovery rates as the replacement pressure escalates, exhibiting an initial rapid enhancement succeeded by a gradual rise. Collectively, these insights offer a robust theoretical foundation endorsing the deployment of CO2 flooding strategies for enhancing oil recovery from sandstone reservoirs, thereby contributing valuable data to the advancement of enhanced oil recovery (EOR) technologies in challenging, low-permeability environments.</description>
      <author>Zangyuan Wu, Qihong Feng, Liming Lian, Xiangjuan Meng, Daiyu Zhou, Min Luo, Hanlie Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N&#228;chster Halt Kohlendioxid-Entnahme? Die deutsche Klimapolitik als riskanter Weg zu negativen Emissionstechnologien</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41358-024-00379-5</link>
      <description>Tobias Haas, Dorothea Elena Schoppek, Zeitschrift f&#252;r Politikwissenschaft. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400879033

                Abstract Both the global and the German climate targets are ambitious given recent emission reduction rates. In addition to emission reduction measures, carbon dioxide removal has been increasingly discussed recently and initial measures have been developed to potentially scale-up carbon removals in order to meet net zero targets. In this article, we undertake a political economy-based analysis of the historical development and structural conditions of German climate policy measures and their enabling role for the emergence and strengthening of carbon dioxide removal policy options. We refer to regulation theory and the Modell Deutschland approach and argue that within this model the concept of ecological modernization has been established as the dominant approach to regulate society-nature relations. In light of the ambitious climate policy goals, such as net zero by 2045, ecological modernization reaches its current limits and must be recalibrated. Against this background, we conclude by discussing the risk of mitigation deterrence associated with carbon dioxide removals and considering alternative pathways, such as degrowth, to social ecological transformation.</description>
      <author>Tobias Haas, Dorothea Elena Schoppek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41358-024-00379-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of the digital economy on carbon dioxide emissions in resource-based cities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-66005-0</link>
      <description>Yang Kuang, Yaojun Fan, Jie Bin, Min Fan, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400738479

                With the rapid development of the digital economy, its environmental impact, particularly on carbon dioxide emissions in resource-based cities, has emerged as a vital research topic. Resource-based cities, often central to traditional industries, are confronted with the dual challenges of environmental pollution and economic transformation. This study employs empirical analysis to examine the influence of the digital economy on carbon dioxide emissions in these cities. The findings reveal that the digital economy significantly reduces carbon dioxide emissions, with this impact being more pronounced in the early stages of digital economic development and gradually diminishing thereafter. In the mechanism analysis, we found that the digital economy can reduce carbon dioxide emissions in resource-based cities by raising public concern about the environment. Moreover, the study highlights significant variations in carbon reduction effects among different types of resource-based cities, noting that stronger environmental regulations further enhance these effects. These insights not only provide a new theoretical perspective but also offer practical guidance for policymakers in promoting sustainable development within the digital economy.</description>
      <author>Yang Kuang, Yaojun Fan, Jie Bin, Min Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-66005-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental impact assessment of rapeseed production using the LCA method: Part two: Life cycle impact assessment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5937/selsem2401035k</link>
      <description>Ferenc Kiss, Nata&#353;a &#272;uri&#353;i&#263;&#8208;Mladenovi&#263;, Ana Marjanovi&#263;&#8208;Jeromela, Selekcija i semenarstvo. 30(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400808072

                This constitutes the second segment of an environmental life cycle assessment (LCA) study on oilseed rape cultivation in the prevalent conditions of Vojvodina, Serbia. The paper presents the results of the life cycle impact assessment (LCIA) phase of the LCA. The functional unit (FU) is one hectare of agricultural land used for winter rapeseed cultivation, with a reference flow of 3,000 kg of seeds, representing the average yield per hectare. The assessment is focused on the rapeseed production chain, concluding with the transportation of oilseeds to regional silos. The environmental impact assessment employed the ReCiPe 2016 (H) LCIA method, using the OpenLCA software. The study found that the total damage to human health was estimated at 0.0048 DALY, while damage due to biodiversity loss was calculated as 0.0001 species per year. Additionally, the damage resulting from the exploitation of geological mineral reserves was determined to be 167 USD per FU. Notably, land occupation was identified as the primary contributor to biodiversity loss, accounting for 90% of the associated damage within the rapeseed production chain. Meanwhile, the life cycle of diesel fuel, the mineral fertilizer production chain, and nitrogen compound emissions from agricultural land collectively accounted for 74% of the damage to human health and 91% of the damage attributed to mineral resource consumption. On the midpoint level, the ReCiPe 2016 (H) LCIA method calculates results within 18 impact categories, including the impact on global warming and fossil fuel depletion. The cumulative impact of greenhouse gases (GHG) emitted in the rapeseed production chain is equivalent to the impact of 1,970 kg of carbon dioxide. The carbon footprint of rapeseed was estimated at 0.65 kg CO2 eq. per kg of rapeseed. In the production chain of 3,000 kg of rapeseed, 454 kg of oil equivalent is consumed, which means that approximately 6.93 MJ of energy from fossil sources is required to produce 1 kg of rapeseed under the prevalent conditions in Vojvodina. The ReCiPe 2016 method identified and assessed the impact of approximately 750 different emissions with adverse effects on the environment, as well as the impact of around 250 different forms of natural resources consumed or used in the rapeseed production chain. However, the results of the LCIA analysis show that only about ten elementary flows are responsible for over 90% of the total damage in specific protection areas. These primarily include air emissions (carbon dioxide, ammonia, nitrogen oxides, nitrous oxide, sulphur dioxide, and suspended particles), emissions of certain heavy metals into water and soil (hexavalent chromium and zinc), as well as the exploitation of some natural resources, notably arable land, natural gas, and crude oil. The results of the LCIA analysis can be utilized to identify processes and emissions where rationalization or improved control can yield the greatest environmental benefits. The most substantial environmental improvements are expected through the reduction of mineral fertilizer consumption per unit yield and the decrease in diesel fuel usage for field and transportation activities. Furthermore, enhanced control over emissions that contribute significantly to the adverse impacts of the rapeseed production chain can also lead to substantial environmental enhancements.</description>
      <author>Ferenc Kiss, Nata&#353;a &#272;uri&#353;i&#263;&#8208;Mladenovi&#263;, Ana Marjanovi&#263;&#8208;Jeromela</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5937/selsem2401035k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a satellite-based monitoring system for urban CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions in support of global collective climate mitigation actions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad6017</link>
      <description>Taylor Y. Wilmot, John C. Lin, Dien Wu, Tomohiro Oda, E. A. Kort, Environmental research letters. 19(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400831246

                Abstract Over the past decade, 1000s of cities have pledged reductions in carbon dioxide emissions. However, tracking progress toward these pledges has largely relied exclusively on activity-based, self-reported emissions inventories, which often underestimate emissions due to incomplete accounting. Furthermore, the lack of a consistent framework that may be deployed broadly, across political boundaries, hampers understanding of changes in both city-scale emissions and the global summation of urban emissions mitigation actions, with insight being particularly limited for cities within the global south. Given the pressing need for rapid decarbonization, development of a consistent framework that tracks progress toward city-scale emissions reduction targets, while providing actionable information for policy makers, will be critical. Here, we combine satellite-based observations of atmospheric carbon dioxide and an atmospheric model to present an atmospherically-based framework for monitoring changes in urban emissions and related intensity metrics. Application of this framework to 77 cities captures &#8764;16% of global carbon dioxide emissions, similar in magnitude to the total direct emissions of the United States or Europe, and demonstrates the framework&#8217;s ability to track changes in emissions via satellite-observation. COVID-19 lockdowns correspond to an average &#8764;21% reduction in emissions across urban systems over March&#8211;May of 2020 relative to non-lockdown years. Urban scaling analyses suggest that per capita energy savings drive decreases in emissions per capita as population density increases, while local affluence and economic development correspond to increasing emissions. Results highlight the potential for a global atmospherically-based monitoring framework to complement activity-based inventories and provide actionable information regarding interactions between city-scale emissions and local policy actions.</description>
      <author>Taylor Y. Wilmot, John C. Lin, Dien Wu, Tomohiro Oda, E. A. Kort</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad6017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observed kinetics for the production of diethyl carbonate from CO2 and ethanol catalyzed by CuNi nanoparticles supported on activated carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-59070-y</link>
      <description>Oscar Arbel&#225;ez, Felipe Bustamante, A&#237;da Luz Villa, Alba Nelly Ardila Arias, Gustavo A. Fuentes, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400833256

                Monometallic and bimetallic Cu:Ni catalysts with different Cu:Ni molar ratios (3:1, 2:1, 1:1, 1:2, 1:3) were synthesized by wetness impregnation on activated carbon and characterized by TPR (temperature programmed reduction), XRD (X-ray diffraction) and XPS (X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy). The synthesized catalysts were evaluated in the gas phase production of diethyl carbonate from ethanol and carbon dioxide. The largest catalytic activity was obtained over the bimetallic catalyst with a Cu:Ni molar ratio of 3:1. Its improved activity was attributed to the formation of a Cu-Ni alloy on the surface of the catalyst, evidenced by XPS and in agreement with a previous assignment based on Vegard law and TPR analysis. During the reaction rate experiments, it observed the presence of a maximum of the reaction rate as a function of temperature, a tendency also reported for other carbon dioxide-alcohol reactions. It showed that the reaction rate-temperature data can be adjusted with a reversible rate equation. The initial rate as a function of reactant partial pressure data was satisfactorily adjusted using the forward power law rate equation and it was found that the reaction rate is first order in CO</description>
      <author>Oscar Arbel&#225;ez, Felipe Bustamante, A&#237;da Luz Villa, Alba Nelly Ardila Arias, Gustavo A. Fuentes</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-59070-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Energy Efficient Technology and Carbon Trading for Reducing Carbon Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/acri/2024/v24i6779</link>
      <description>Satinder Kaur Khattra, D. Singh, Ritu Dogra, Archives of Current Research International. 24(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400854773

                This review addresses the energy efficient technology and carbon trading for reducing carbon emissions. Energy-efficient technologies (EET) and carbon trading are mechanisms for mitigating climate change. EET offers direct ways to reduce emissions by improving the efficiency of energy use in various sectors. The use of technologies such as Variable Frequency Drives (VFD) in compressors, enhanced thermal performance in buildings, and smart lighting systems demonstrate significant potential in cutting energy consumption and thereby emissions The roles of carbon credits in international emission trading schemes, emphasizing their dual purpose of environmental protection and revenue generation for developing nations. The study explores into various types of carbon credit projects, including the Clean Development Mechanism (CDM) and the Verified Carbon Standard (VCS), highlighting their distribution and impact across different regions. The importance of forests in carbon dioxide absorption and the challenges of ensuring permanence and accounting for carbon sequestration are also discussed. Additionally, the document examines policy recommendations, such as carbon pricing and emission reduction targets set by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC).</description>
      <author>Satinder Kaur Khattra, D. Singh, Ritu Dogra</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.9734/acri/2024/v24i6779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real&#8208;Time Product Detection during CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction on SCILL&#8208;Modified Cu Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400305</link>
      <description>Walter A. Parada, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Pavlo Nikolaienko, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400884351

                Abstract Modifying the chemical environment of active surfaces with ionic liquids (IL) is an emerging strategy for tailoring novel electrocatalytic systems, including carbon dioxide reduction (CO 2 RR). Although copper (Cu) catalysts have recently gained more attention in this field, their modification with ILs is yet to be investigated. This work tested a range of common hydrophobic ILs impregnated into carbon&#8208;supported Cu catalysts, following the &#8220;solid catalyst with ionic liquid layer&#8221; (SCILL) approach. The latter was used to showcase the applicability of real&#8208;time product detection for CO 2 RR employing electrochemical mass spectrometry. The observed patterns of C 1 to C 3 product selectivity offered valuable insights into the intricate reaction mechanism. In addition, increasing the size of the IL cation showed an opposite and significant effect on the reaction selectivity. The obtained qualitative results were partially compared with conventional long&#8208;term experiments.</description>
      <author>Walter A. Parada, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Pavlo Nikolaienko</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental emission characteristics of diesel engine performance using biodiesel by cotton and pumpkin seed</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06066</link>
      <description>, Global NEST Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741908

                &lt;p&gt;The hunt for alternative fuels that may be utilized in place of conventional fuels is intensifying quickly since the availability of fossil fuels is dwindling daily. In this work, biodiesel derived from pumpkin and cotton seed oils is presented for use as diesel engine fuel. Related to diesel, the calorific value of this precise biodiesel is low. In a 4-stroke diesel engine, four mixes (B0, B25, B50, B75 and B100) of biodiesel were evaluated. The engine's emissions and combustion results were contrasted with the diesels. When all blended fuels are related to diesel fuel, the test repercussions illustrate a small increase in the thermal efficiency of the brakes and a decrease in the consumption of fuel specifically for the brake. Emissions of Carbon monoxide and the usage of biodiesel subsequent in a reduction in hydrocarbon emissions and an upsurge in carbon dioxide and nitrogen oxide emissions. The experiment's results showed that biodiesel, which is derived from these seed oils, maybe a useful diesel replacement for compression ignition engines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Entity Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00723</link>
      <description>Thomas B. Clarke, Lynn E. Krushinski, Kathryn J. Vannoy, Guillermo S. Col&#243;n-Quintana, Kingshuk Roy, Jeffrey E. Dick, Christophe Renault, Myrtle Hill, Jeffrey E. Dick, Chemical reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400729701

                Making a measurement over millions of nanoparticles or exposed crystal facets seldom reports on reactivity of a single nanoparticle or facet, which may depart drastically from ensemble measurements. Within the past 30 years, science has moved toward studying the reactivity of single atoms, molecules, and nanoparticles, one at a time. This shift has been fueled by the realization that everything changes at the nanoscale, especially important industrially relevant properties like those important to electrocatalysis. Studying single nanoscale entities, however, is not trivial and has required the development of new measurement tools. This review explores a tale of the clever use of old and new measurement tools to study electrocatalysis at the single entity level. We explore in detail the complex interrelationship between measurement method, electrocatalytic material, and reaction of interest (e.g., carbon dioxide reduction, oxygen reduction, hydrazine oxidation, etc.). We end with our perspective on the future of single entity electrocatalysis with a key focus on what types of measurements present the greatest opportunity for fundamental discovery.</description>
      <author>Thomas B. Clarke, Lynn E. Krushinski, Kathryn J. Vannoy, Guillermo S. Col&#243;n-Quintana, Kingshuk Roy, Jeffrey E. Dick, Christophe Renault, Myrtle Hill, Jeffrey E. Dick</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Hydrogen Embrittlement in Pipeline Steels for Natural Gas-Hydrogen Blends: Implications for Existing Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/solids5030025</link>
      <description>Hesamedin Ghadiani, Zoheir Farhat, Tahrim Alam, Md. Aminul Islam, Solids. 5(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400674742

                Governments worldwide are actively committed to achieving their carbon emission reduction targets, and one avenue under exploration is harnessing the potential of hydrogen. Blending hydrogen with natural gas is emerging as a promising strategy to reduce carbon emissions, as it burns cleanly without emitting carbon dioxide. This blending could significantly contribute to emissions reduction in both residential and commercial settings. However, a critical challenge associated with this approach is the potential for Hydrogen Embrittlement (HE), a phenomenon wherein the mechanical properties of pipe steels degrade due to the infiltration of hydrogen atoms into the metal lattice structure. This can result in sudden and sever failures when the steel is subjected to mechanical stress. To effectively implement hydrogen-natural gas blending, it is imperative to gain a comprehensive understanding of how hydrogen affects the integrity of pipe steel. This necessitates the development of robust experimental methodologies capable of monitoring the presence and impact of hydrogen within the microstructures of steel. Key techniques employed for this assessment include microscopic observation, hydrogen permeation tests, and tensile and fatigue testing. In this study, samples from two distinct types of pipeline steels used in the natural gas distribution network underwent rigorous examination. The findings from this research indicate that charged samples exhibit a discernible decline in fatigue and tensile properties. This deterioration is attributed to embrittlement and reduced ductility stemming from the infiltration of hydrogen into the steel matrix. The extent of degradation in fatigue properties is correlated not only to the hydrogen content but also to the hydrogen permeability and diffusion rate influenced by steel&#8217;s microstructural features, with higher charging current densities indicating a more significant presence of hydrogen in the natural gas pipeline blend.</description>
      <author>Hesamedin Ghadiani, Zoheir Farhat, Tahrim Alam, Md. Aminul Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/solids5030025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion with over 10% efficiency using earth abundant system in a single&#8208;compartment reactor with oxygen tolerant Mn complex catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401082</link>
      <description>Shunsuke Sato, Teppei Nishi, Naonari Sakamoto, Keita Sekizawa, Takeshi Morikawa, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400789469

                The direct conversion of CO2 in flue gas to value&#8208;added chemicals is a potentially important cost&#8208;effective solar&#8208;driven CO2 reduction technology. The present work demonstrates the solar&#8208;powered conversion of CO2 to CO with greater than 10% efficiency using a Mn complex cathode and an Fe&#8208;Ni anode in a single&#8208;compartment reactor without an ion exchange membrane in conjunction with a Si solar cell. Reactors separated by ion exchange membranes are typically used to prevent any effects of oxygen generated by the counter electrode. However, the present Mn complex catalyst maintained its activity even in the presence of 15% O2. Operando surface&#8208;enhanced Raman spectroscopy established that the present Mn catalyst preferentially reacted with CO2 without adsorbing O2. This unique characteristic enabled solar&#8208;driven CO2 reduction using a single&#8208;compartment reactor. In contrast, catalytic metals such as Ag tend to lose activity in such systems as a consequence of reaction with oxygen produced at the anode.</description>
      <author>Shunsuke Sato, Teppei Nishi, Naonari Sakamoto, Keita Sekizawa, Takeshi Morikawa</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The combined effect of the oxidizing agent and its concentration on the oxidative coupling of methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400877</link>
      <description>Wei Zhou, Pedro S. F. Mendes, Parviz Yazdani, Christophe Detavernier, Joris Thybaut, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400681384

                The combined use of O2 and CO2 as oxidizing agents in the oxidative coupling of methane (OCM) has been assessed over two representative OCM catalysts, i.e., La&#8208;Sr/CaO and NaMnW/SiO2, under a wide range of inlet O2 and CO2 concentrations. The overall impact of CO2 was found to depend on the operating conditions and the catalyst used. At O2&#8208;rich conditions, a negative effect of CO2 was observed on C2 selectivity. At O2&#8208;lean conditions, a positive effect of CO2 on both catalysts was observed, likely originating from an enhanced dehydrogenation of C2H6 to C2H4 and limited deep oxidation of the involving hydrocarbons and reaction intermediates. The behavior induced by CO2 is attributed to its mild oxidizing ability and interactions with the catalysts. The enhanced dehydrogenation of C2H6 was observed and confirmed by specific tests with a CO2 and C2H6 feed. Well&#8208;controlled CO2 addition improved the value of the OCM product mixture, mainly due to a 9% increase in C2H4 and a 19% increase in CO selectivity, resulting in a 25% reduction of CO2 at the outlet over the La&#8208;Sr/CaO catalyst. These findings provide new insight into the CO2 effect on OCM and the data to translate this research into OCM process alternatives.</description>
      <author>Wei Zhou, Pedro S. F. Mendes, Parviz Yazdani, Christophe Detavernier, Joris Thybaut</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clumped Isotope Signatures of Abiotic Methane: The Role of the Combinatorial Isotope Effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2023jb028194</link>
      <description>Jabrane Labidi, T. M. McCollom, Thomas Giunta, Barbara Sherwood Lollar, William D. Leavitt, Edward Young, Journal of geophysical research. Solid earth. 129(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400735353

                Abstract Methane clumped isotope signatures of abiogenesis may be diagnostic of the origin of methane on Earth and other planetary bodies. We performed synthesis of abiogenic methane in hydrothermal conditions between 130 and 300&#176;C and determined &#948; 13 C, &#948;D, &#916; 13 CH 3 D, and &#916; 12 CH 2 D 2 . The experiments were performed by heating water in the presence of Fe 0 powder and CO. The reduction of water on metallic iron led to the formation of H 2 . CO was reacted with both H 2 and H 2 O, generating both CH 4 and CO 2 . Methane &#948; 13 C values are isotopically depleted by &#8764;25&#8240; relative to the CO starting material. This is consistent with carbon isotopic equilibrium between methane, carbon monoxide and carbon dioxide in our experiments. In contrast, D/H ratios are inconsistent with equilibrium isotopic fractionation, as illustrated by &#948;D values of methane fractionated by &#8764;500&#8240; relative to starting H 2 O. This suggests that under our experimental conditions, hydrogen additions to carbon may be governed by kinetics. &#916; 13 CH 3 D values track experimental temperature, with values between +1.5&#8240; and +5.0&#8240; for most samples. In contrast, &#916; 12 CH 2 D 2 values are displaced from equilibrium. We find exclusively negative &#916; 12 CH 2 D 2 values, showing deficits down to 40&#8240; relative to thermodynamic equilibrium. We interpret the data as evidence for distinct, kinetically induced D/H pools contributing to methane assembly, that is, a combinatorial effect. The cumulative D/H fractionations associated with CO hydrogenation explain the direction and magnitude of &#916; 12 CH 2 D 2 values during abiotic methane formation. We suggest that near equilibrium &#916; 13 CH 3 D with negative &#916; 12 CH 2 D 2 signatures will help identify methane formed abiotically in nature.</description>
      <author>Jabrane Labidi, T. M. McCollom, Thomas Giunta, Barbara Sherwood Lollar, William D. Leavitt, Edward Young</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2023jb028194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density-Driven CO2 Dissolution in Depleted Gas Reservoirs with Bottom Aquifers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143491</link>
      <description>Xiaocong Lyu, Fang Cen, Rui Wang, Huiqing Liu, Sheng Wang, Jin&#8208;Xin Xiao, Xudong Shen, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400677287

                Depleted gas reservoirs with bottom water show significant potential for long-term CO2 storage. The residual gas influences mass-transfer dynamics, further affecting CO2 dissolution and convection in porous media. In this study, we conducted a series of numerical simulations to explore how residual-gas mixtures impact CO2 dissolution trapping. Moreover, we analyzed the CO2 dissolution rate at various stages and delineated the initiation and decline of convection in relation to gas composition, thereby quantifying the influence of residual-gas mixtures. The findings elucidate that the temporal evolution of the Sherwood number observed in the synthetic model incorporating CTZ closely parallels that of the single-phase model, but the order of magnitude is markedly higher. The introduction of CTZ serves to augment gravity-induced convection and expedites the dissolution of CO2, whereas the presence of residual-gas mixtures exerts a deleterious impact on mass transfer. The escalation of residual gas content concomitantly diminishes the partial pressure and solubility of CO2. Consequently, there is an alleviation of the concentration and density differentials between saturated water and fresh water, resulting in the attenuation of the driving force governing CO2 diffusion and convection. This leads to a substantial reduction in the rate of CO2 dissolution, primarily governed by gravity-induced fingering, thereby manifesting as a delay in the onset and decay time of convection, accompanied by a pronounced decrement in the maximum Sherwood number. In the field-scale simulation, the injected CO2 improves the reservoir pressure, further pushing more gas to the producers. However, due to the presence of CH4 in the post-injection process, the capacity for CO2 dissolution is reduced.</description>
      <author>Xiaocong Lyu, Fang Cen, Rui Wang, Huiqing Liu, Sheng Wang, Jin&#8208;Xin Xiao, Xudong Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Smart Home Technologies on Energy Efficiency, Cost Savings, and Environmental Benefits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55529/jeet.44.21.32</link>
      <description>C. Ukpene Patience, Tessy N. Apaokueze, Journal of energy engineering and thermodynamics. None(44)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400688412

                The results of this study addressed the effectiveness of smart home technologies in terms of energy consumption, cost reduction, and environmental advantages in Nigerian homes. Given the growing energy requirements and concern for the environment, assessing the efficiency of such technologies is critical for socioeconomic development. We collected data using a combination of surveys and statistical analysis in five major Nigerian cities: Lagos, Abuja, Kano, Port Harcourt, and Enugu. We evaluated smart home technologies such as smart thermostats, lighting systems, appliances, plugs, and energy monitoring systems based on their energy savings (%), monthly cost savings (NGN), kilogram of CO2 emissions cut, and percent adoption. We used descriptive analysis and regression modeling to analyze the data collected from the respondents. The introduction of smart technologies reduced general energy use by fifteen to twenty-five percent, with smart appliances recording the highest reduction of up to 25%. This feature demonstrated how monthly cost savings varied depending on the technology and geographical location, resulting in significant increases of up to 4000 NGN per household, each household saw a reduction in CO2 emissions by 500 kg to 700 kg annually, resulting in significant environmental benefits. According to the studies, smart home technologies can help promote energy conservation and therefore reduce CO2 emissions in Nigerian households. However, there are still widely recognized obstacles, like high initial costs and a low level of awareness. offering financial incentives, improving Information Promotion of existing policies and overhauling the distribution systems to increase the pace of uptake and impact returns.</description>
      <author>C. Ukpene Patience, Tessy N. Apaokueze</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55529/jeet.44.21.32</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing stomatal density by expression of a synthetic Epidermal Patterning Factor increases leaf intrinsic water use efficiency and reduces plant water use in a C4 crop</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jxb/erae289</link>
      <description>John N. Ferguson, Peter Schmuker, Anna Dmitrieva, Truyen Quach, Tieling Zhang, Zhengxiang Ge, Natalya Nersesian, Shirley Sato, Thomas E. Clemente, Andrew D. B. Leakey, Journal of experimental botany. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400785850

                Abstract Enhancing crop water use efficiency (WUE) is a key target trait for climatic resilience and expanding cultivation on marginal lands. Engineering lower stomatal density to reduce stomatal conductance (gs) has improved WUE in multiple C3 crop species. However, reducing gs in C3 species often reduces photosynthetic carbon gain. A different response is expected in C4 plants because they possess specialized anatomy and biochemistry which concentrates CO2 at the site of fixation. This modifies the photosynthesis (AN) relationship with intracellular CO2 concentration (ci) so that photosynthesis is CO2-saturated and reductions in gs are unlikely to limit AN. To test this hypothesis, genetic strategies were investigated to reduce stomatal density in the C4 crop sorghum. Constitutive expression of a synthetic epidermal patterning factor (EPF) transgenic allele in sorghum, led to reduced stomatal densities, reduced gs, reduced plant water use and avoidance of stress during a period of water deprivation. In addition, moderate reduction in stomatal density did not increase stomatal limitation to AN. However, these positive outcomes were associated with negative pleiotropic effects on reproductive development and photosynthetic capacity. Avoiding pleiotropy by targeting expression of the transgene to specific tissues could provide a pathway to improved agronomic outcomes.</description>
      <author>John N. Ferguson, Peter Schmuker, Anna Dmitrieva, Truyen Quach, Tieling Zhang, Zhengxiang Ge, Natalya Nersesian, Shirley Sato, Thomas E. Clemente, Andrew D. B. Leakey</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jxb/erae289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate-dependent oxidative inactivation of a W-dependent formate dehydrogenase involving selenocysteine displacement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02394c</link>
      <description>Guilherme Vilela-Alves, Rita Rebelo Manuel, Aldino Viegas, Philippe Carpentier, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Biaso, Bruno Guigliarelli, In&#234;s A. C. Pereira, Maria Jo&#227;o Rom&#227;o, Cristiano Mota, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400681578

                Metal-dependent formate dehydrogenases are very promising targets for enzyme optimization and design of bio-inspired catalysts for CO2 reduction, towards innovative strategies for climate change mitigation. For effective application of these...</description>
      <author>Guilherme Vilela-Alves, Rita Rebelo Manuel, Aldino Viegas, Philippe Carpentier, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Biaso, Bruno Guigliarelli, In&#234;s A. C. Pereira, Maria Jo&#227;o Rom&#227;o, Cristiano Mota</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02394c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of solar thermal in district heating systems &#8211; the case of parabolic trough collectors in a high-latitude region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00607k</link>
      <description>Nguyen Le Truong, Itai Danielski, Benjamin Ahlgren, Gireesh Nair, Sustainable energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400700929

                This study investigates primary energy use and CO2 emission reduction potential resulted by the integration of solar thermal heating in biomass-based district heating systems in high-latitude regions. A newly commissioned...</description>
      <author>Nguyen Le Truong, Itai Danielski, Benjamin Ahlgren, Gireesh Nair</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00607k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Policies and Countermeasures for Phase-Out of Ozone-Depleting Substances (ODS) over the Last 30 Years: Case Study in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202407.1142.v1</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Tien Tsai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400686943

                It is well established that the reaction cycles involving some halogenated alkanes (so-called ozone-depleting substances, ODS) contribute to the depletion of ozone in the stratosphere, thus causing the Montreal Protocol (initially signed in 1987) and later amendments. The Protocol called for the scheduled phase-out of ODS, including chlorofluorocarbons (CFC), hydrochloro-fluorocarbons (HCFC), carbon tetrachloride (CCl4), halon, methyl chloroform (CH3CCl3), me-thyl chloride (CH3Cl), and even hydrofluorocarbons (HFCs). In view of the urgent importance of ozone layer protection to the globally ecological environment, the Taiwan government took regulatory actions on reducing ODS consumption since 1993 by the joint-venture of the central competent authorities. Under the regulatory requirements and the industry&#8217;s efforts by adopt-ing the alternatives to ODS and abatement technologies, the phase-out of some ODS (i.e., CFC, CCl4, halon, and CH3CCl3) have been achieved prior to 2010. The consumptions of HCFCs and methyl chloride have been significantly declined over the past three decades (1993-2022). However, HFC emission indicated a V-type variation during the period. Due to the local pro-duction and extensive use of HFC in Taiwan, its emissions increased from 663 kilotons of carbon dioxide equivalents (CO2eq) in 1993 to 2,330 kilotons of CO2eq in 2001, and then decreased to 373 kilotons of CO2eq in 2011. Since then, the emissions of HFC largely used as the alternatives to ODS showed an upward trend, increasing to 1,555 kilotons of CO2eq in 2022. To be in compliance with the Kigali Amendment (KA-2015) to the Montreal Protocol for mitigating global warming, the Taiwan government has taken regulatory actions in reducing the consumption of some HFC substances with high global warming potential (GWP) under the authorization of the Climate Change Response Act in 2023, aiming at the baseline consumption in 2024 by 80 % reduction by 2045.</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Tien Tsai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202407.1142.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the single-basket mindset: A multi-gas approach to better constrain overshoot in near term warming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad6461</link>
      <description>Julie Miller, G. Dreyfus, John Daniel, Stephen G. Willis, Yangyang Xu, Environmental research letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400720502

                Abstract The remaining carbon budget framework tracks progress towards the Paris Agreement&#8217;s goal to limit longer-term warming to well below 2 &#186;C, but no analogous framework exists for constraining mid-century warming. Established single-basket methods of combining gases into CO2-equivalents using Global Warming Potentials (GWPs) lead to ambiguity over what combination of short- and long-lived emissions reductions are needed because they obscure the distinct warming impacts of each. We investigate to what extent a multi-basket approach that separates short-lived and long-lived pollutants can better estimate the likelihood for emission pathways to meet a near-term warming goal. We develop logistic regression models to categorize IPCC emission pathways (AR6) based on whether they exceed a mid-century temperature threshold. We focus on two baskets, using CO2 for long-lived and methane (CH4) for short-lived gases. For comparison, we consider several single-basket approaches (e.g., GWP100, GWP20, GWP*). We further apply our framework to a synthetic dataset covering a broader emissions space. Across both datasets, the two-basket outperforms all single-baskets. Using an illustrative near-term goal (1.7&#186;C), the two-basket approach reduces the magnitude of overshoot by a factor of 7 compared with the traditional single-basket. The two-basket&#8217;s advantage is smaller with the AR6 pathways, which we attribute to the high correlation between CO2 and CH4 emissions and confounding effects from other pollutants. Our results indicate that the two-basket approach better constrains overshoot magnitude, particularly if future emissions deviate from the AR6 assumption of correlated CO2 and CH4 reductions. Our approach allows the determination of a metric value and reduction target in the context of a chosen set of scenarios and temperature threshold; the outcome is a near-term methane-specific emissions budget that can be adopted by decisionmakers in a way that is analogous and complementary to the carbon budget. Future work could consider a third basket for very short-lived pollutants.</description>
      <author>Julie Miller, G. Dreyfus, John Daniel, Stephen G. Willis, Yangyang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad6461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Capture and Utilization Projects Run by Oil and Gas Companies: A Case Study from Russia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146221</link>
      <description>Alina Cherepovitsyna, Ekaterina Kuznetsova, A. Yu. Popov, Dmitry Skobelev, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400873174

                As oil and gas companies are one of the major greenhouse gas emitters, they face increasing responsibility to address climate challenges. This highlights the necessity of integrating decarbonization options into their operations to meet global climate objectives. While progress in technologies for capturing, utilizing, and storing CO2 (CCUS technologies) is often attributed to oil and gas companies, CCUS projects in the sector predominantly focus on carbon storage, namely CO2 injection for enhanced oil recovery, which presents limited possibilities. Meanwhile, carbon capture and utilization (CCU) technologies offer a promising avenue for producing valuable products from CO2, a potential that has been underexplored in theory and practice within the oil and gas sector. This study analyzes the development of the full CCU cycle by oil and gas companies, assessing the economic viability of such projects. It includes a content analysis of research materials on CCU deployment and a case study modeling the economic viability of producing methanol from CO2 in Russia. The findings indicate that the estimated minimum price for CO2-based methanol to achieve project payback is USD 1128 per ton, compared to approximately USD 400 per ton for traditional methanol. This price gap underscores the need to foster the development of low-carbon technologies, markets, and measures to support these projects. In the domain of CCU projects, cost-reduction measures could be more applicable, while regulatory measures, such as carbon taxes, currently have a limited impact on the economic viability of these projects.</description>
      <author>Alina Cherepovitsyna, Ekaterina Kuznetsova, A. Yu. Popov, Dmitry Skobelev</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of the industrial emissions impact on the quality of atmospheric air in the Burlin district of West Kazakhstan region DEVELOPMENT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37878/2708-0080/2024-2.14</link>
      <description>&#1057;.&#1054;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1078;&#1072;&#1075;&#1091;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, Vitaliy Salnikov, Neft&#697; i gaz. 140(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741889

                The article is devoted to the study of air pollution in the Burlin district of the West Kazakhstan region, where one of the main sources of air pollution is the Karachagan oil and gas condensate field, the main feature of which is the high content of hydrogen sulfide in natural gas from 4 to 4.3%. The analysis showed that the atmospheric air state in the specified area is determined by the characteristics of harmful emissions sources, composition, volumes of pollutant emissions and climatic characteristics of the territory, which determine the conditions for the polluting components dispersion. The qualitative and quantitative characteristics of the chemical composition of the atmospheric air in the study area, as well as the features of their changes over the years end climatic seasons, are largely determined by emissions of nitrogen oxides, carbon, sulfur dioxide, hydrogen sulfide, volatile organic compounds and inorganic dust into the atmosphere by oil and gas facilities. The anthropogenic influence of industry in this area is also evidenced by the calculated value of the integral coefficient of air pollution. At the same time, industrial enterprises, having increased the anthropogenic impact on the environment, have the ability to prevent negative environmental consequences. The system of industrial environmental control of the chemical composition of industrial emissions at the Karachagnak field facilities is carried out on an ongoing basis. The analysis showed that a reduction in emissions and, accordingly, a reduction in ground-level concentrations of air pollutants at the Karachagnak field facilities is ensured by a whole range of technological and organizational measures, among which the technology of high-pressure gas reinjection deserves special attention. It necessitates the need to carry out systematic work to study the ecological state of the territory of the Karachagnak field, using not only ground-based research methods, but also modern geoinformation and aerospace technologies that make it possible to dynamically assess the changes taking place, conduct a geo-ecological assessment and make a forecast for the development of the environmental situation in this area. territories. The work carried out contributes to further analysis of the regional assessment of the environmental state of the atmosphere of large industrial centers.</description>
      <author>&#1057;.&#1054;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1078;&#1072;&#1075;&#1091;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, Vitaliy Salnikov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37878/2708-0080/2024-2.14</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pathways Towards Improving the Energy Efficiency of Residential Air &amp;amp;#x96; Conditioning Systems in Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4065973</link>
      <description>Abdulaziz M. Alotaibi, Taha K. Makhdoom, Awad B. S. Alquaity, Journal of solar energy engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400683596

                Abstract In Saudi Arabia, the residential electricity consumption approaches 50%, primarily driven by air conditioners (AC). This study explores the potential energy savings and CO2 emission reductions up to 2030 through three scenarios: Business as Usual (BAU), Continuous Improvement Scenario (CIS), and Accelerated Improvement Scenario (AIS). BAU scenario assumes that the current Energy Efficiency Ratio (EER) of 11.8 BTU/Wh is maintained until 2030. CIS considers a 5% EER improvement in new AC stock every 2 or 5 years, while AIS assumes a 10% improvement in EER at the same intervals. Additionally, energy savings and emission reductions possible from varying adoption levels of a new refrigerant (R32) are estimated for three scenarios. Lastly, the CO2 emission reduction under each scenario is computed for two extreme cases of grid emission factor. BAU scenario predicts energy savings of up to 17.7 TWh in 2030 compared to 2020 energy consumption figures. AIS with 2 year intervals results in additional energy savings of 10.1 TWh in 2030 and cumulative energy savings of 37.1 TWh over a decade compared to the BAU scenario. Even CIS with 5 year intervals yields additional energy savings of 1.69 TWh in 2030 and 5.1 TWh cumulatively compared to the BAU scenario. In comparison, the introduction of the new refrigerant results in cumulative energy savings of 10.2 TWh in the best-case scenario. These findings emphasize the importance of enhancing the EER of residential AC systems as a priority in energy efficiency policy.</description>
      <author>Abdulaziz M. Alotaibi, Taha K. Makhdoom, Awad B. S. Alquaity</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4065973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition to Low-Carbon Vehicle Market: Characterization, System Dynamics Modeling, and Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143525</link>
      <description>Mohammad Pourmatin, Moein Moeini&#8208;Aghtaie, Erfan Hassannayebi, Elizabeth Hewitt, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400768766

                Rapid growth in vehicle ownership in the developing world and the evolution of transportation technologies have spurred a number of new challenges for policymakers. To address these challenges, this study develops a system dynamics (SD) model to project the future composition of Iran&#8217;s vehicle fleet, and to forecast fuel consumption and CO2 emissions through 2040. The model facilitates the exploration of system behaviors and the formulation of effective policies by equipping decision-makers with predictive insights. Under various scenarios, this study simulates the penetration of five distinct vehicle types, highlighting that an increase in fuel prices does not constitute a sustainable long-term intervention for reducing fuel consumption. Additionally, the model demonstrates that investments aimed at the rapid adoption of electric transportation technologies yield limited short-term reductions in CO2 emissions from transportation. The projections indicate that the number of vehicles in Iran is expected to surpass 30 million by 2040, with plug-in and hybrid electric vehicles (EVs and PHEVs) comprising up to approximately 2.2 million units in the base scenario. It is anticipated that annual gasoline consumption and CO2 emissions from passenger cars will escalate to 30,000 million liters and 77 million tons, respectively, over the next two decades. These findings highlight the need for a strategic approach in policy development to effectively manage the transition towards a lower-carbon vehicle fleet.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Pourmatin, Moein Moeini&#8208;Aghtaie, Erfan Hassannayebi, Elizabeth Hewitt</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co2(CO)8 as a CO-source for Pd-catalyzed Carbonylations: An Update</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/0115701794302069240624045929</link>
      <description>Debarati Das, Bhalchandra M. Bhanage, Current Organic Synthesis. 21(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400894681

                Abstract: Palladium-catalyzed carbonylative cross-coupling reactions with various carbon monoxide (CO) sources cultivate competent routes for the synthesis of bulk and value-added chemicals. However, the practical use of this odorless, inflammable, lethal gas has always raised a concern for chemists. The attention and advancement of various CO-surrogates is surely wel-comed as a green alternative to CO-gas. However, the main concern lies in the suitability and scalability of these CO-surrogate-driven reactions. Literature showed the progress of various ways to make in-situ CO from these CO surrogates. One of the most convenient sources is using metal carbonyls which are already known to lose CO easily. Among all the kinds, Mo(CO)6 gained much popularity but its toxic nature and demand for high temperatures restricted its use. However, Co2(CO)8 is popular as a catalyst but as an in-situ CO-source reports are scarce. This low-melting CO-releaser was found effective in flourishing aminocarbonylation, alkoxycar-bonylation, and reductive carbonylation under mild conditions. This mini-review portrays the recent developments of palladium-catalyzed carbonylation reactions using Co2(CO)8 as a CO source.</description>
      <author>Debarati Das, Bhalchandra M. Bhanage</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/0115701794302069240624045929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biochar as an Alternative Litter Additive to Mitigate Gaseous Emissions from Broiler Housing and Subsequent Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071595</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Pereira, Filipa M. S. Martins, Gabriel Bonif&#225;cio, Ana Carla Garcia, Jos&#233; Teixeira, Henrique Trindade, Agronomy. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400882585

                Broiler farming is a significant source of gaseous emissions. The aim of this study was to assess the effects of different litter additives on the emission of NH3, N2O, CO2, and CH4 during broiler housing and subsequent manure storage. The gaseous emissions from the housing facilities were evaluated during one fattening cycle in environmentally controlled rooms with three different additives applied to the litter material (10% w/w aluminum sulphate or biochar and 2.50 mg m&#8722;2 urease inhibitor), as well as a control. A storage experiment was conducted under laboratory conditions for 90 days to evaluate the influence of these three additives on gaseous losses. During broiler housing, the results indicated that NH3 emissions were reduced significantly (40&#8211;60%) by litter additives, while global warming potential (GWP) emissions were reduced significantly (31%) by Alum. The addition of Biochar (a 58% reduction) had the same significant effect as Alum (a 60% reduction) to mitigate these losses. The re-application of Urease (a 41% reduction) may be required to reach an equal or higher reduction. During storage, NH3 and GWP emissions were not significantly affected by the litter additives. During broiler housing and subsequent manure storage, NH3 emissions were reduced significantly (22&#8211;41%) by litter additives, whereas GWP emissions did not decrease significantly. Globally, it can be concluded that Biochar appears to be a good alternative to Alum due to its equal effectiveness in mitigating NH3 losses, without increasing the GWP potential in the housing and avoiding pollution swapping.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Pereira, Filipa M. S. Martins, Gabriel Bonif&#225;cio, Ana Carla Garcia, Jos&#233; Teixeira, Henrique Trindade</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14071595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greater aperture counteracts effects of reduced stomatal density on WUE: a case study on sugarcane and meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jxb/erae271</link>
      <description>Daniel Lunn, Baskaran Kannan, Amandine Germon, Alistair Leverett, Thomas E. Clemente, Fredy Altpeter, Andrew D. B. Leakey, Journal of experimental botany. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400800828

                Stomata regulate CO2 and water vapor exchange between leaves and the atmosphere. Stomata are a target for engineering to improve crop intrinsic water use efficiency (iWUE). One example is by expressing genes that lower stomatal density (SD) and reduce stomatal conductance (gsw). However, the quantitative relationship between reduced SD, gsw, and the mechanisms underlying it is poorly understood. We addressed this knowledge gap using low-SD sugarcane (Saccharum spp. hybrid) as a case study alongside a meta-analysis of data from 10 species. Transgenic expression of EPIDERMAL PATTERNING FACTOR 2 from Sorghum bicolor (SbEFP2) in sugarcane reduced SD by 26-38% but did not affect gsw compared to wildtype. Further, no changes occurred in stomatal complex size or proxies for photosynthetic capacity. Measurements of gas exchange at low CO2 concentrations that promote complete stomatal opening to normalize aperture size between genotypes were combined with modeling of maximum gsw from anatomical data. These data suggest that increased stomatal aperture is the only possible explanation for maintaining gsw when SD is reduced. Meta-analysis across C3 dicots, C3 monocots, and C4 monocots revealed engineered reductions in SD are strongly correlated with lower gsw (r2=0.60-0.98), but this response is damped relative to the change in anatomy.</description>
      <author>Daniel Lunn, Baskaran Kannan, Amandine Germon, Alistair Leverett, Thomas E. Clemente, Fredy Altpeter, Andrew D. B. Leakey</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jxb/erae271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Biomass Transformation to Hydrocarbons under Supercritical Conditions over Nickel Supported on Schungite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12071503</link>
      <description>Elena O. Schipanskaya, &#1040;ntonina &#1040;. Stepacheva, Mariia E. Markova, Alexey V. Bykov, &#1040;. &#1048;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Valentina G. Matveeva, Mikhail G. Sulman, Lioubov Kiwi&#8208;Minsker, Processes. 12(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400723682

                Liquid fuel production from biomass-derived molecules has received great attention due to the diminished fossil fuel reserves, growing energy demand, and the necessity of CO2 emission reduction. The deoxygenation of oils and fatty acids is a promising process to obtain &#8220;green&#8221; diesel. Herein, we report the results of the study of the deoxygenation of stearic acid to alkanes as a model reaction. Series of Ni-supported on schungite were obtained by precipitation in subcritical water (hydrothermal deposition) and for comparison via wetness impregnation followed, in both cases, by calcination at 500 &#176;C and a reduction in H2 at 300 &#176;C. The catalyst obtained via hydrothermal synthesis showed a three-fold higher specific surface area with a four-fold higher active phase dispersion compared to the catalysts synthesized via conventional impregnation. The catalysts were tested in stearic acid deoxygenation in supercritical n-hexane as the solvent. Under optimized process conditions (temperature of 280 &#176;C, hydrogen partial pressure of 1.5 MPa, and 13.2 mol of stearic acid per mol of Ni), a close to 100% yield of C10&#8211;C18 alkanes, containing over 70 wt.% of targeted n-heptadecane, was obtained after 60 min of reaction.</description>
      <author>Elena O. Schipanskaya, &#1040;ntonina &#1040;. Stepacheva, Mariia E. Markova, Alexey V. Bykov, &#1040;. &#1048;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Valentina G. Matveeva, Mikhail G. Sulman, Lioubov Kiwi&#8208;Minsker</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12071503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Building Morphology on Energy Use Intensity of High-Rise Residential Clusters: A Case Study of Hangzhou, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14072245</link>
      <description>Weijia Feng, Jintao Chen, Jing Wang, Weijun Gao, Qinfeng Zhao, Haowei Xing, Shuai Yu, Buildings. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400885293

                Building operations account for a large amount of energy use and CO2 emissions, and the morphology of buildings in residential clusters strongly impacts energy efficiency performance. However, little research has focused on the morphology and energy electricity usage of high-rise residential clusters in hot summer and cold winter (HSCW) regions. We investigated 96 residential clusters in Hangzhou, China, and established a corresponding morphology database. Additionally, we obtained annual electricity consumption for 16 of these residential clusters. With this database, we performed optimization of morphological parameters upon energy use intensity (EUI) using a genetic algorithm (GA). Specifically, the cooling, heating, and lighting EUIs of high-rise residential clusters were studied. After implementing the optimized morphological parameters, there was a reduction of up to 7.73% in EUI. According to regression analysis, the average aspect ratio was the most significant factor influencing EUI (r = &#8722;0.907), followed by floor area ratio (r = &#8722;0.755), average orientation (r = 0.502), and average number of floors (r = &#8722;0.453). These results indicate that a higher intensity of land development with a greater floor area ratio, average aspect ratio, and average number of floors can reduce total energy consumption. Additionally, we found that an average building orientation of southwest 15&#176; (with respect to south) is optimal. The findings of this study can assist urban planners and designers in developing more sustainable residential clusters, leading to decreased energy costs and CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Weijia Feng, Jintao Chen, Jing Wang, Weijun Gao, Qinfeng Zhao, Haowei Xing, Shuai Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14072245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Experience With a New Miniaturized Pump-Driven Venovenous Extracorporeal CO2 Removal System (iLA Activve): A Retrospective Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003543480-43</link>
      <description>Alexander Hermann, Thomas Staudinger, Andja Bojic, Katharina Riss, Philipp Wohlfarth, Oliver Robak, Wolfgang R. Sperr, Peter Schellongowski, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400685349

                iLA Activve is a new minimally invasive device for extracorporeal CO2 removal (ECCO2-R) using a miniaturized pump, a special gas exchange membrane, and a double-lumen cannula. We retrospectively analyzed our experiences in 12 patients with hypercapnic respiratory failure undergoing ECCO2-R. Indication for ECCO2-R was hypercapnia due to terminal lung failure during bridging to lung transplantation, pneumonia, and chronic obstructive lung disease or asthma. The median duration of ECCO2-R was 8 days (range 2&#8211;30). Seven patients were successfully weaned and five died. Patients with primarily hypoxic lung failure were significantly longer ventilated before ECCO2-R and had a higher mortality rate. Complications were retroperitoneal hematoma after cannulation in one patient and repeated system changes because of clotting in two patients. We observed effective CO2 removal in all patients, with significant reduction in ventilation pressures and minute volumes at median blood flow rates of 1.2&#8211;1.4 L/ min. The iLA Activve system using venous double-lumen cannulas proved to be an effective method for ECCO2-R. Invasiveness of ventilation could be reduced. Additional severe impairment of oxygenation and prolonged mechanical ventilation before ECCO2-R are factors of adverse prognosis. The use of ECCO2-R should be thoroughly reconsidered in these cases. ASAIO Journal 2014; 60:342&#8211;347. ECCO2-R, iLA Activve, hypercapnia, decarboxylation, extracorporeal</description>
      <author>Alexander Hermann, Thomas Staudinger, Andja Bojic, Katharina Riss, Philipp Wohlfarth, Oliver Robak, Wolfgang R. Sperr, Peter Schellongowski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003543480-43</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultivating, harvesting and processing microalgae for biodiesel production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24084/eqj24.225</link>
      <description>Donald P. Campbell, Christian Schr&#246;der, John Sherman, E. Sitzer, B. Uhler, A. Pourmovahed, No host. 2(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400849182

                In recent years, sustainable aviation fuels (SAF) have been gaining popularity as an alternative to conventional jet fuel due to their smaller carbon footprint. It has been estimated that their use will result in a 65% reduction in CO2 emissions. SAF can be produced by using waste oil, animal fat, plant-based oil or municipal waste. One promising feedstock for SAF production is alga as it grows quickly under the right conditions and may contain 50% oil. In this student project, algae species were reviewed, and one was chosen based on its growth speed and lipid-producing characteristics. A photobioreactor was designed and built. The algae grown were monitored and harvested. Due to the short duration of this project and difficulties in extracting the algae and a malfunctioning ultrasonic bath, the oil extracted was not sufficient for conversion into biodiesel. The heat of combustion of the produced fuel from used cooking oil was measured. The lessons learned are discussed. Key words. Photobioreactor, Biodiesel, Microalgae</description>
      <author>Donald P. Campbell, Christian Schr&#246;der, John Sherman, E. Sitzer, B. Uhler, A. Pourmovahed</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24084/eqj24.225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Optimization of Natural Gas Injection Timing in a Dual-Fuel Marine Engine to Minimize GHG Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/gases4030011</link>
      <description>Luigi De Simio, Luca Marchitto, Sabato Iannaccone, Vincenzo Pennino, Nunzio Altieri, Gases. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400679400

                Phased injection of natural gas into internal combustion marine engines is a promising solution for optimizing performance and reducing harmful emissions, particularly unburned methane, a potent greenhouse gas. This innovative practice distinguishes itself from continuous injection because it allows for more precise control of the combustion process with only a slight increase in system complexity. By synchronizing the injection of natural gas with the intake and exhaust valve opening and closing times while also considering the gas path in the manifolds, methane release into the atmosphere is significantly reduced, making a substantial contribution to efforts to address climate change. Moreover, phased injection improves the efficiency of marine engines, resulting in reduced overall fuel consumption, lower fuel costs, and increased ship autonomy. This technology was tested on a single-cylinder, large-bore, four-stroke research engine designed for marine applications, operating in dual-fuel mode with diesel and natural gas. Performance was compared with that of the conventional continuous feeding method. Evaluation of the effect on equivalent CO2 emissions indicates a potential reduction of up to approximately 20%. This reduction effectively brings greenhouse gas emissions below those of the diesel baseline case, especially when injection control is combined with supercharging control to optimize the air&#8211;fuel ratio. In this context, the boost pressure in DF was reduced from 3 to 1.5 bar compared with the FD case.</description>
      <author>Luigi De Simio, Luca Marchitto, Sabato Iannaccone, Vincenzo Pennino, Nunzio Altieri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/gases4030011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution global geopositioning system for last-mile delivery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17533/udea.redin.20240731</link>
      <description>Luis Felipe Quirama-Londo&#241;o, Michael Giraldo, Juan Camilo Mej&#237;a Hern&#225;ndez, Juan Esteban Tibaquir&#225;-Giraldo, Revista Facultad de Ingenier&#237;a Universidad de Antioquia. 113(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400876250

                High-resolution monitoring systems are commonly used to calculate mechanical and energy performance, as well as environmental impact resulting from the operation of a fleet of vehicles in a region. These systems require recording operational or vehicle position data, energy consumption in the case of electric or electric-assisted vehicles, and buttons for specific signals in the operation, such as the start of operation, end of operation, or package delivery. Some vehicle tracking devices available on the market do not allow speed and energy consumption data to be recorded and accessed at the required sampling frequency. This study presents the development and validation of a remote sensing device to record energy consumption and operational variables of a vehicle under real operating conditions with a frequency of 1 Hz. The functioning of the device, the integrated elements in its development, and the data analysis process are detailed. Finally, using the monitoring equipment data, a comparison was made between the operation of electric vehicles and internal combustion vehicles, achieving savings of up to 83% in operating costs and a 79% reduction in CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Luis Felipe Quirama-Londo&#241;o, Michael Giraldo, Juan Camilo Mej&#237;a Hern&#225;ndez, Juan Esteban Tibaquir&#225;-Giraldo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17533/udea.redin.20240731</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Mitigation Through AI Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-2845-3.ch014</link>
      <description>R. Selvapriya, M. Gopinath, D. Velmurugan, P. Tamilchelvan, Advances in environmental engineering and green technologies book series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400879795

                Climate change is a serious hazard that has already harmed urban and natural systems and resulted in over $500 billion in economic losses worldwide.These problems could be partially resolved by artificial intelligence,which incorporates internet resources to provide quick recommendations based on precise climate change projections.Our research revealed that raising energy efficiency can greatly lessen the effects of climate change.Smart manufacturing, in instance, can reduce energy consumption in buildings by 30 to 50 percent.It can also reduce waste and carbon emissions by 30 to 50 percent.Artificial intelligence technologies are used by almost 70% of the world's natural gas industry to improve the precision and dependability of weather forecasts. Artificial intelligence and smart grids can be used to maximise power system efficiency and cut electricity costs by 10&#8211;20%.Intelligent transport systems have a 60% reduction in CO2 emissions potential. Furthermore,artificial intelligence may be used to manage natural resources and build resilient cities, further advancing sustainability.</description>
      <author>R. Selvapriya, M. Gopinath, D. Velmurugan, P. Tamilchelvan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-2845-3.ch014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formate&#8208;Mediated Electroenzymatic Synthesis via Biological Cofactor NADH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408756</link>
      <description>Chuanjun Wang, Wenjin Dong, Pengye Zhang, Yaya Ma, Zhiwei Han, Yutai Zou, Wenshuo Wang, Hao Li, Frank Hollmann, Jian Liu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400894254

                Synthetic biohybrid systems by coupling artificial system with nature&#8217;s machinery may offer a disruptive solution to address the global energy crisis. We developed a versatile electroenzymatic pathway for the continuous synthesis of valuable chemicals, facilitated by formate&#8208;driven NADH regeneration. Utilising a bismuth electrocatalyst, we achieved stable CO2 reduction to formate with approximately 90% Faraday efficiency at a current density of 150 mA cm&#8722;2. The generated formate acts as a mediator to regenerate NADH, which is then coupled with immobilised redox enzymes&#8212;alcohol dehydrogenase (ADH), L&#8208;lactate dehydrogenase (LDH), and L&#8208;glutamate dehydrogenase (GDH)&#8212;to produce targeted chemicals at significant rates and exceptionally high turnover numbers (1.8&#215;106 to 3.1&#215;106). These achievements not only underscore the efficiency of the system but also its practical applicability in industrial settings. By leveraging in situ generated formate, this innovative approach demonstrates the potential of integrating electrocatalysis with enzymatic reactions for sustainable and efficient chemical production on a practical scale.</description>
      <author>Chuanjun Wang, Wenjin Dong, Pengye Zhang, Yaya Ma, Zhiwei Han, Yutai Zou, Wenshuo Wang, Hao Li, Frank Hollmann, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formate&#8208;Mediated Electroenzymatic Synthesis via Biological Cofactor NADH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408756</link>
      <description>Chuanjun Wang, Wenjin Dong, Pengye Zhang, Yaya Ma, Zhiwei Han, Yutai Zou, Wenshuo Wang, Hao Li, Frank Hollmann, Jian Liu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400894769

                Synthetic biohybrid systems by coupling artificial system with nature's machinery may offer a disruptive solution to address the global energy crisis. We developed a versatile electroenzymatic pathway for the continuous synthesis of valuable chemicals, facilitated by formate-driven NADH regeneration. Utilising a bismuth electrocatalyst, we achieved stable CO2 reduction to formate with approximately 90% Faraday efficiency at a current density of 150 mA cm-2. The generated formate acts as a mediator to regenerate NADH, which is then coupled with immobilised redox enzymes-alcohol dehydrogenase (ADH), L-lactate dehydrogenase (LDH), and L-glutamate dehydrogenase (GDH)-to produce targeted chemicals at significant rates and exceptionally high turnover numbers (1.8&#215;106 to 3.1&#215;106). These achievements not only underscore the efficiency of the system but also its practical applicability in industrial settings. By leveraging in situ generated formate, this innovative approach demonstrates the potential of integrating electrocatalysis with enzymatic reactions for sustainable and efficient chemical production on a practical scale.</description>
      <author>Chuanjun Wang, Wenjin Dong, Pengye Zhang, Yaya Ma, Zhiwei Han, Yutai Zou, Wenshuo Wang, Hao Li, Frank Hollmann, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Retrospective Audit with Subsequent Cost and Environmental Analysis of a Denosumab Self Injection Programme</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jbmrpl/ziae092</link>
      <description>Jack Boylan, Jane F. Turton, Zita R. Hicks, Julia Cottam, Michael D. Stone, JBMR plus. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400728745

                Abstract The Metabolic Bone Health Department, Cardiff and Vale University Health Board, serves a local population of approximately 445 000 people. A retrospective audit of attendance data regarding the Denosumab treatment clinic (the traditional treatment pathway) and the Denosumab Self Injection Programme (SIP) was conducted to determine whether the Self Injection Programme is both cost effective and environmentally beneficial, compared to the traditional treatment pathway. Cost analysis was then conducted by the Finance Department. The audit was conducted over 3 years following the implementation of the service development; 233 patients had enrolled in the program at the time of the audit and 69 had completed 3 years of self- injected treatment. A control group of 497 patients were identified by the service. This group remained on the historical pathway and had consistent attendance activity over the three-year period from 2017 to 2019. Pre and post period activity of all patients on the program was compared, together with the activity for the independent control group. The SIP resulted in a reduction in clinical contacts, with financial analysis showing a total opportunity cost saving per patient of &#163;420 per annum. There were obvious benefits to the patient of a reduced number of visits to a clinical site, which also resulted in an estimated carbon footprint reduction of 59 KG CO2 per patient per annum. The cost analysis is based on our organisation&#8217;s 2022 charges. The SIP demonstrates that through focusing on care &#8220;closer to home&#8221;, it is possible to maximise resources, improve the patient experience through reduced travel and reduce the environmental impact of healthcare.</description>
      <author>Jack Boylan, Jane F. Turton, Zita R. Hicks, Julia Cottam, Michael D. Stone</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jbmrpl/ziae092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy and Environmental Analyses of a Solar&#8211;Gas Turbine Combined Cycle with Inlet Air Cooling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146229</link>
      <description>Ahmad M. Abubaker, Adnan Darwish Ahmad, Binit B. Singh, Yaman Manaserh, Loiy Al&#8208;Ghussain, Nelson K. Akafuah, Kozo Saito, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400873430

                Sensitivity to ambient air temperatures, consuming a large amount of fuel, and wasting a significant amount of heat dumped into the ambient atmosphere are three major challenges facing gas turbine power plants. This study was conducted to simultaneously solve all three aforementioned GT problems using solar energy and introducing a new configuration that consists of solar preheating and inlet-air-cooling systems. In this study, air was preheated at a combustion chamber inlet using parabolic trough collectors. Then, inlet air to the compressor was cooled by these collectors by operating an absorption cooling cycle. At the design point conditions, this novel proposed integration resulted in a 6.87% relative increase in generated power and a 10.53% relative decrement in fuel consumption, achieving a 19.45% relative increment in the plant&#8217;s thermal efficiency. This was accompanied by a reduction of 0.026 kg/s, 4.2 kg/s, and 0.278 kg/s in CO2, CO, and NOx emissions, respectively. Finally, spider diagrams were employed to assess the impact of the operating parameters on the overall system&#8217;s performance and its associated environmental implications.</description>
      <author>Ahmad M. Abubaker, Adnan Darwish Ahmad, Binit B. Singh, Yaman Manaserh, Loiy Al&#8208;Ghussain, Nelson K. Akafuah, Kozo Saito</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flammability, Toxicity, and Microbiological Properties of Polyurethane Flexible Foams</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17143517</link>
      <description>A. Glowacki, Przemys&#322;aw Rybi&#324;ski, Grzegorz Czerwonka, Witold &#379;ukowski, Ulugbek Zakirovich Mirkhodjaev, Monika &#379;elezik, Materials. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400683024

                The aim of the research was to investigate the influence of calcium phosphinate (HPCA) and aluminum phosphinate (HPAL) in synergistic systems with organophosphorus compounds, i.e., diphenylcresyl phosphate (CDP) and trichloropropyl phosphate (TCPP), on the thermal stability, flammability, smoke density, and emission of toxic gases during the thermal decomposition of polyurethane (PUR) foams. Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA), along with cone calorimetry and microcalorimetry, were used to assess the influence of fillers on the thermal stability and flammability of PUR foams. The analysis of toxic gas products was performed with the use of a coupled TG&#8211;gas analyzer system. The optical density of gases was measured with the use of a smoke density chamber (SDC). The obtained results showed an increase in thermal stability and a decrease in the flammability of the PUR composites. However, the results regarding smoke and gas emissions, as well as toxic combustion by-products, present ambiguity. On one hand, the applied flame retardant systems in the form of PUR-HPCA-CDP and PUR-HPCA-TCPP led to a reduction in the concentration of CO and HCN in the gas by-products. On the other hand, they clearly increased the concentration of CO2, NOx, and smoke emissions. Microbiological studies indicated that the obtained foam material is completely safe for use and does not exhibit biocidal properties.</description>
      <author>A. Glowacki, Przemys&#322;aw Rybi&#324;ski, Grzegorz Czerwonka, Witold &#379;ukowski, Ulugbek Zakirovich Mirkhodjaev, Monika &#379;elezik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17143517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Dry Mix Alkali Activated Slag Binder Composite Properties Cured in Ambient Condition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.05746</link>
      <description>, Global NEST Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400727261

                &lt;p&gt;A dry mix (solution-free) alkali-activated slag (a primary cementitious material) and/or fly ash based binder composition is developed that can be cast in-site and consequently cured at ambient temperature. Mortar specimens were cast by mixing slag and or fly ash, river sand, powder form alkaline activators (NaOH 14M, varying solids percentage of Na2SiO3) and water were thoroughly mixed in fabricated equipment. The dry density (28 days) of all specimens showed greater than 2200 kg/m3. The compressive strength (28 days) of all mixes was resulted in higher than 40 N/mm2. Among all the four mixes, a mix F103 with 90% slag, 10% fly ash, 30% Na2SiO3 and 14M NaOH at 3, 7 and 28 days curing showed overall higher compressive strength. It is due to fewer solids content of Na2SiO3. The experimental results indicated that solution free studied binder composite can be developed under ambient conditions eliminating other curing types without compromising in the strength. The studied sustainable mixes require only 12-15 percent water which is less compared to regular used mixes. Thus reduced water quantities can be achieved thereby protects the reduction in volume of water bodies, environment hazards, reduces CO2 emissions due to use of industrial by-products as main binders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.05746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADDITIVE MANUFACTURING FOR FAST PROTOTYPING OF A VELOCITY COMPOUNDED RADIAL RE-ENTRY TURBINE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12795/9788447227457_3</link>
      <description>Dominik St&#252;mpfl, Karel R&#225;&#382;, Philipp Streit, Andreas Wei&#223;, Editorial Universidad de Sevilla eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400888181

                In order to achieve a drastic reduction in CO2 emissions to limit global warming, it must be possible to globally cover the electricity demand from renewable sources. However, the fluctuating availability of solar and wind energy will nevertheless make it necessary to complement the renewables by thermal power plants. Additionally using e.g., the potentials of waste, biomass or waste heat from industrial processes locally in Organic Rankine Cycle (ORC) power plants is a promising approach to finally achieve a stable and sustainable electricity supply. In the present work, therefore, different variants of a radial, velocity compounded re-entry cantilever turbine (Elektra turbine) are investigated regarding their potential for such applications. The paper concentrates on the fast prototyping of an existing 5 kW air turbine demonstrator, recently developed by the authors, by using the possibilities of additive manufacturing with plastic materials to substitute essential parts of the flow geometry. In this context the approach to implement the plastic parts in the turbine is explained. Experimentally determined efficiency parameters of various 3D-printed deflection channel modifications and a printed plastic wheel made of PA12GB are presented, discussed, and compared to the fully milled metal turbine. This results in a quantification of the additional losses due to the higher inaccuracies and roughness of the printed parts, which can be taken into account in further investigations. Furthermore, the various problems and hurdles that must be observed when using 3D-printed plastic parts in high-speed turbomachines are highlighted. With regard to the rotor wheel, the authors conclude that the use of additively manufactured plastic wheels is only feasible with increased preliminary testing. The time required for this is usually not in proportion to the manufacturing time and costs saved. For the stator parts however, 3D-printing turned out to be a reasonable approach.</description>
      <author>Dominik St&#252;mpfl, Karel R&#225;&#382;, Philipp Streit, Andreas Wei&#223;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12795/9788447227457_3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Interactions between Flooding Dynamics and Agricultural Productivity in a Changing Climate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146141</link>
      <description>Thidarat Rupngam, Aim&#233; J. Messiga, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400768498

                Extreme precipitation and flooding frequency associated with global climate change are expected to increase worldwide, with major consequences in floodplains and areas susceptible to flooding. The purpose of this review was to examine the effects of flooding events on changes in soil properties and their consequences on agricultural production. Flooding is caused by natural and anthropogenic factors, and their effects can be amplified by interactions between rainfall and catchments. Flooding impacts soil structure and aggregation by altering the resistance of soil to slaking, which occurs when aggregates are not strong enough to withstand internal stresses caused by rapid water uptake. The disruption of soil aggregates can enhance soil erosion and sediment transport during flooding events and contribute to the sedimentation of water bodies and the degradation of aquatic ecosystems. Total precipitation, flood discharge, and total water are the main factors controlling suspended mineral-associated organic matter, dissolved organic matter, and particulate organic matter loads. Studies conducted in paddy rice cultivation show that flooded and reduced conditions neutralize soil pH but changes in pH are reversible upon draining the soil. In flooded soil, changes in nitrogen cycling are linked to decreases in oxygen, the accumulation of ammonium, and the volatilization of ammonia. Ammonium is the primary form of dissolved inorganic nitrogen in sediment porewaters. In floodplains, nitrate removal can be enhanced by high denitrification when intermittent flooding provides the necessary anaerobic conditions. In flooded soils, the reductive dissolution of minerals can release phosphorus (P) into the soil solution. Phosphorus can be mobilized during flood events, leading to increased availability during the first weeks of waterlogging, but this availability generally decreases with time. Rainstorms can promote the subsurface transport of P-enriched soil particles, and colloidal P can account for up to 64% of total P in tile drainage water. Anaerobic microorganisms prevailing in flooded soil utilize alternate electron acceptors, such as nitrate, sulfate, and carbon dioxide, for energy production and organic matter decomposition. Anaerobic metabolism leads to the production of fermentation by-products, such as organic acids, methane, and hydrogen sulfide, influencing soil pH, redox potential, and nutrient availability. Soil enzyme activity and the presence of various microbial groups, including Gram+ and Gram&#8722; bacteria and mycorrhizal fungi, are affected by flooding. Waterlogging decreases the activity of &#946;-glucosidase and acid phosphomonoesterase but increases N-acetyl-&#946;-glucosaminidase in soil. Since these enzymes control the hydrolysis of cellulose, phosphomonoesters, and chitin, soil moisture content can impact the direction and magnitude of nutrient release and availability. The supply of oxygen to submerged plants is limited because its diffusion in water is extremely low, and this impacts mitochondrial respiration in flooded plant tissues. Fermentation is the only viable pathway for energy production in flooded plants, which, under prolonged waterlogging conditions, is inefficient and results in plant death. Seed germination is also impaired under flooding stress due to decreased sugar and phytohormone biosynthesis. The sensitivity of different crops to waterlogging varies significantly across growth stages. Mitigation and adaptation strategies, essential to the management of flooding impacts on agriculture, enhance resilience to climate change through improved drainage and water management practices, soil amendments and rehabilitation techniques, best management practices, such as zero tillage and cover crops, and the development of flood-tolerant crop varieties. Technological advances play a crucial role in assessing flooding dynamics and impacts on crop production in agricultural landscapes. This review embarks on a comprehensive journey through existing research to unravel the intricate interplay between flooding events, agricultural soil, crop production, and the environment. We also synthesize available knowledge to address critical gaps in understanding, identify methodological challenges, and propose future research directions.</description>
      <author>Thidarat Rupngam, Aim&#233; J. Messiga</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY OF ADHESION OF PHYSICAL VAPOR DEPOSITION COATINGS ON FUNCTIONAL TEXTILE WITH LASER POST-PROCESSING</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17770/etr2024vol3.8178</link>
      <description>Silvija Me&#382;inska, Antons Pacejs, Imants Adij&#257;ns, Edgars Zaicevs, Lyubomir Lazov, Vide. Tehnolog&#807;ija. Resursi/Environment. Technology. Resources. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400836675

                Functional textile are one of the most critical fields in the textile industry and textile materials science. In recent years, advanced technologies in textile processing have become relevant in order to improve its usability. In the production of various types of functional textile, one of the methods is the modification of textile surfaces. To improve the properties of the textile surface, magnetron vacuum sputtering and laser post-processing technologies can be used, which in general gives the material new or improved properties and functionalities. In this study, mixed fiber fabrics containing polyester, protal and cotton fibers are used to determine how laser post-treatment of the metalized fabrics impact the adhesive properties between fabric and deposited metal. The following materials were used for magnetron vacuum sputtering for functional textile coatings: Cu, Al, Ti, Ag. Individually or by combining these metals, it is possible to assign the textile such properties as: electromagnetic, UV and IR radiation shielding; antistatic, antibacterial, hydrophilic and hydrophobic properties, as well as increasing wear resistance. In this study a 100 W continuous wave CO2 laser with a wavelength of 10.6 &#181;m is used for post-treatment of magnetron vacuum sputtered modified textile surfaces. The study's conclusions point towards a tailored approach in determining linear energy densities that bolster adhesion for each metal-textile combination, which is essential for the development of durable and functional advanced textile. The patterns noted in the adhesion strengths, influenced by different energy densities and metal types, highlight the intricate relationship between the thermal impact of laser treatment and the inherent characteristics of the metals deposited. Some metals demonstrated improved adhesion at lower energy densities. However, a general trend emerged showing a reduction in the strength of adhesion as the energy density increased, especially when surpassing certain energy levels.</description>
      <author>Silvija Me&#382;inska, Antons Pacejs, Imants Adij&#257;ns, Edgars Zaicevs, Lyubomir Lazov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17770/etr2024vol3.8178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Engine Performance and Emissions with Eucalyptus Oil and Diesel Blends</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143528</link>
      <description>Robert M&#259;d&#259;lin Chivu, Jorge Martins, Florin Gabriel Popescu, Margarida Gon&#231;alves, Krisztina Uzuneanu, Michael Fr&#259;ti&#355;a, F. P. Brito, Energies. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400768743

                This research evaluates the feasibility of using eucalyptus oil blended with conventional diesel fuel in diesel engines. Eucalyptus globulus is one of the main tree species cultivated for paper pulp in western European countries such as Portugal, and eucalyptus oil is one of the byproducts that so far has not been sufficiently evaluated as a biofuel. This study assesses the impact of using this additive on engine performance parameters and emissions as a means to contribute to reducing fossil fuel consumption and pollutant and greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. The analysis revealed that the addition of eucalyptus oil had a positive effect on torque, a critical performance parameter, with biofuel blends showing consistent torque increases at lower engine speeds. However, torque tended to decrease towards the higher range of engine speed for eucalyptus oil&#8211;diesel blends. Several blends showed lower brake specific fuel consumption compared to regular diesel at high engine loads and low engine speeds. Brake thermal efficiency did not vary substantially at lower engine speeds and loads but decreased at higher speeds and loads. Pollutant emissions, particularly unburned hydrocarbons and nitrogen oxides, were influenced by fuel composition, with biofuel blends showing both increases and decreases compared to diesel. It is noteworthy that eucalyptus oil blends exhibited up to a 60% reduction in smoke opacity under specific operating conditions at low speed and high load for 10% incorporation (10EU90D), suggesting that in addition to the already positive effects of cutting down fossil CO2 emissions in proportion to the substitution of fossil diesel with nearly carbon-neutral eucalyptus oil, more environmental benefits may be expected from the incorporation of this product. Although the present economic viability of using eucalyptus oil as a biofuel is still not guaranteed, the present study seems to reinforce its technical viability. Future prospects for the improvement of oil yield through biotechnology, the economic interest of this product for several countries, and the updating and upscaling industrial processes may allow the viability of this biofuel to remain a possibility in the future</description>
      <author>Robert M&#259;d&#259;lin Chivu, Jorge Martins, Florin Gabriel Popescu, Margarida Gon&#231;alves, Krisztina Uzuneanu, Michael Fr&#259;ti&#355;a, F. P. Brito</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17143528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal impact of screening colonoscopy on greenhouse gas emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0307133</link>
      <description>Hasiya Yusuf, Vinita Gupta, Ikponmwosa Osaghae, Abhishek Kumar, PLoS ONE. 19(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400811722

                Background and aim Colonoscopy is the gold-standard screening test for colorectal cancer. However, it has come under scrutiny for its carbon footprint and contribution to greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions compared to other medical procedures. Notwithstanding, screening colonoscopies may have a positive effect on GHG emissions that is unknown. This study estimated the carbon emissions prevented by screening colonoscopies in the U.S. Methods Using the reported number of screening colonoscopies performed annually in the U.S. and the absolute risk reduction (ARR) reported in the NorDICC trial, we calculated the expected minimum number of cancer treatment and surveillance visits prevented through screening based on the cancer stage. The average carbon emission averted per mile traveled was computed using the Environmental Protection Agency&#8217;s (EPA) GHG equivalencies calculator. The final estimate of carbon emissions averted over a decade by screening colonoscopies performed in one year was determined. Result 6.3 million screening colonoscopies performed in one year prevent 1,134,000 colorectal cancers over a ten-year period. Of these, 38&#8729;3% (434,254) are localized, 38&#8729;8% (440,281) are regional, and 22&#8729;9% (259,465) are metastatic disease. The minimum number of post-diagnosis visits prevented is 11 for stage I, &#8805; 21 for stage II, &#8805;25 for stage III, and &#8805; 20 for stage IV disease, comprised of diagnostic, surgical evaluation, chemotherapy, and surveillance visits. The total number of visits prevented by screening is 2,388,397 for stage I, 5,254,421 for stage II, 13,120,369 for stage III, and 9,210,972 for stage IV disease. Approximately 395 million miles of travel and 158,263 metric tons of CO2, equivalent to 177 million pounds of coal burned, 19 billion smartphones charged, or 18 million gallons of gasoline consumed, were saved over ten years through screening. Conclusion Colorectal cancer screening decreases cancer-related GHG emissions and minimizes the environmental impact of cancer treatment.</description>
      <author>Hasiya Yusuf, Vinita Gupta, Ikponmwosa Osaghae, Abhishek Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0307133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Effect of Fly Ash on Mechanical Properties and Seawater Freeze&#8211;Thaw Resistance of Seawater Sea Sand Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14072191</link>
      <description>Jingjing He, Chuanwu Sun, Xuezhi Wang, Buildings. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400676666

                When using seawater and sea sand as mixes, the mechanical properties and durability of concrete are adversely affected because the raw materials themselves contain harmful ions. Fly ash is the tailings formed in the process of industrial production, the use of which does not require the burning of clinker, reducing CO2 emissions. Moreover, it belongs to a new type of cementitious materials with low emissions and high environmental protection. Fly ash enhances the properties of concrete and reduces the effect of harmful ions on concrete. Based on the above considerations, the corresponding specimens were prepared and subjected to cubic compressive strength, flexural strength, and seawater freezing and thawing resistance tests by using fly ash admixture as the main variable. A combination of macro-analysis and micro-analysis was used to investigate the effect of fly ash on the performance of seawater sea sand concrete. The results showed that fly ash significantly enhanced the mechanical properties and resistance to seawater freezing and thawing of seawater sea sand concrete. The best improvement in compressive strength and resistance to seawater freezing and thawing was achieved at a substitution rate of 20%. The maximum increase in compressive strength was 13.22%. The maximum reduction in mass loss rate was 57.26% and the strength loss rate was 43.14% after the specimens were subjected to seawater freezing and thawing 75 times. The maximum enhancement in flexural strength was 17.06% for a substitution rate of 10%. Through microanalysis, it can be seen that the incorporation of coal ash can enhance the compactness of concrete through the microaggregate effect as well as the volcanic ash reaction to promote the secondary hydration reaction, so as to strengthen the seawater freeze&#8211;thaw resistance of seawater sea sand concrete. Finally, the damage prediction model established using the mean GM (1, 1) model of gray system theory meets the requirements of the first level of prediction accuracy and can accurately predict the damage of seawater sea sand concrete under seawater freezing and thawing.</description>
      <author>Jingjing He, Chuanwu Sun, Xuezhi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14072191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight on Secondary Metabolites Produced by an Early-Flowering Apulian Artichoke Ecotype Sanitized from Virus Infection by Meristem-Tip-Culture and Thermotherapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox13070852</link>
      <description>Roberta Span&#242;, Patrizia Gena, Vito Linsalata, Valeria Sini, Isabella D&#8217;Antuono, Angela Cardinali, Pietro Cotugno, Giuseppe Calamita, Tiziana Mascia, Antioxidants. 13(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400682113

                Globe artichoke (Cynara cardunculus L. subsp. scolymus) is an important crop of the Mediterranean basin characterized by many properties, like hepatoprotective, anticarcinogenic, antioxidant, antibacterial, and beneficial to human health. The high bioactive compounds (BACs) content, as polyphenols, has attracted the research interest in artichoke extracts. We analysed the changes in polyphenol transcriptome profile between sanitized (S) virus-free and non-sanitized (NS) artichoke plants, focusing on genes involved in phenylpropanoid metabolic pathway and flavonoid biosynthesis. A total of 2458 upregulated and 2154 downregulated differentially expressed genes (DEGs) were functionally characterized. Among them, 31 and 35 KEGG orthology entries characterized by upregulated and downregulated DEGs, respectively, were involved in the biosynthesis of other secondary metabolites. A downregulation of PAL, C4H, 4CL, HST/HQT, C3&#8242;H, CCoAMT, CCR1, and F5H, was observed in S artichoke compared to NS one, whereas the CSE, CHS, and CHI genes were upregulated in S samples. Transcriptome results were compared to the polyphenols accumulation in S and NS artichoke leaves. A higher content of total polyphenols was observed in older leaves of NS samples, compared to extracts obtained from young leaves or from S plants, and this result was associated with the presence of viral infections in NS plants. In all the conditions tested, the most represented compound was chlorogenic acid, followed by luteolin-7-O-glucoside. The different composition of each extract was evaluated by a polyphenol dose&#8211;response treatment on the rodent hepatoma FaO cell line to the accumulation of reactive oxygen species (ROS). A significant reduction in ROS content ranging between &#8722;40% and &#8722;48% was observed when 10&#8211;20 mg/L of polyphenols from NS or S plants were used, characterized by a specific profile of compounds. To reduce MetOH residues in polyphenol extracts, a supercritical fluid CO2 extraction was evaluated to propose a sustainable green extraction.</description>
      <author>Roberta Span&#242;, Patrizia Gena, Vito Linsalata, Valeria Sini, Isabella D&#8217;Antuono, Angela Cardinali, Pietro Cotugno, Giuseppe Calamita, Tiziana Mascia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox13070852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using historical temperature to constrain the climate sensitivity, the transient climate response, and aerosol-induced cooling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-8105-2024</link>
      <description>Olaf Morgenstern, Atmospheric chemistry and physics. 24(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400782529

                Abstract. The most recent generation of climate models that has informed the Sixth Assessment Report (AR6) of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) is characterized by the presence of several models with larger equilibrium climate sensitivities (ECSs) and transient climate responses (TCRs) than exhibited by the previous generation. Partly as a result, AR6 did not use any direct quantifications of ECSs and TCRs based on the 4&#215;CO2 and 1pctCO2 simulations and relied on other evidence when assessing the Earth's actual ECS and TCR. Here I use historical observed global-mean temperature and simulations produced under the Detection and Attribution Model Intercomparison Project to constrain the ECS, TCR, and historical aerosol-related cooling. I introduce additivity criteria that disqualify 8 of the participating 16 models from consideration in multi-model averaging calculations. Based on the remaining eight models, I obtain an average adjusted ECS of 3.5 &#177; 0.4 K and a TCR of 1.8 &#177; 0.3 K (both at 68 % confidence). Both are consistent with the AR6 estimates but with substantially reduced uncertainties. Furthermore, importantly I find that the optimal cooling due to short-lived climate forcers consistent with the observed temperature record should, on average, be about 47 % &#177; 39 % of what these models simulate in their aerosol-only simulations, yielding a multi-model mean, global-mean, and annual-mean cooling due to near-term climate forcers for 2000&#8211;2014, relative to 1850&#8211;1899, of 0.24 &#177; 0.11 K (at 68 % confidence). This is consistent with but at the lower end of the very likely uncertainty range of the IPCC's AR6. There is a correlation between the models' ECSs and their aerosol-related cooling, whereby large-ECS models tend to be associated also with strong aerosol-related cooling. The results imply that a reduction in the aerosol-related cooling, along with a more moderate adjustment of the greenhouse-gas-related warming for most models, would bring the historical global-mean temperature simulated by these models into better agreement with observations.</description>
      <author>Olaf Morgenstern</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-8105-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Municipal Solid Waste Management Scenarios in Metro Manila Using the Long-Range Energy Alternatives Planning-Integrated Benefit Calculator (LEAP-IBC) System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146246</link>
      <description>Jazzie Jao, Maryfe Toyokan, Edgar Vallar, Liz Silva, Maria Cecilia Galvez, Sustainability. 16(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400873424

                Short-lived climate pollutants (SLCPs) and municipal solid wastes (MSWs) have been found to be viable sources of clean energy. This study integrates the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) guidelines for methane flow rate estimation in the software Long-Range Energy Alternatives Planning-Integrated Benefit Calculator (LEAP-IBC) system to estimate and project the methane emissions coming from the waste generated by Metro Manila, disposed in sanitary landfills. It aims to analyze the environmental impacts of the emissions coming from the non-energy sector using the IBC feature of LEAP and by developing two scenarios with 2010 and 2050 as the base and end years: the baseline and methane recovery scenario, where the latter represents the solid waste management undertaken to counter the emissions. Under the baseline, 97.30 million metric tonnes of methane emissions are expected to be produced and are predicted to continuously increase. In the same scenario, the cities of Quezon, Manila, and Caloocan account for the biggest methane emissions. On the other hand, in the methane recovery scenario, the methane emissions are expected to have a decline of 36% from 127.036 to 81.303 million metric tonnes by 2025, 52% from 135.358 to 64.972 million metric tonnes by 2030, and 54% from 150.554 to 69.254 million metric tonnes by 2040. For the 40-year projection of the study under the 100-year global warming potential analysis, a total of 10,249 million metric tonnes of CO2 equivalent is avoided in the methane recovery compared to the BAU, and a maximum of 0.019 &#176;C temperature increase can also be avoided. Moreover, electricity costs without LFG technology increase from 2.21 trillion to 8.75 trillion, while costs with LFG technology also rise but remain consistently lower, ranging from 2.20 trillion to 8.74 trillion. This consistent reduction in electricity costs underscores the long-term value and importance of adopting LFG technology, even as its relative savings impact diminishes over time. Finally, the fixed effects and random effects panel data regression analysis reinforces and asserts that the solid waste management is really improved by means of the methane recovery technology, leading the methane emissions to decrease.</description>
      <author>Jazzie Jao, Maryfe Toyokan, Edgar Vallar, Liz Silva, Maria Cecilia Galvez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16146246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resilient incremental social housing design: Mexico City, Mexico</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5821/dissertation-2117-412157</link>
      <description>Jani F. Vel&#225;zquez Robles, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400896769

                (English) The rapid growth of Mexico&#8217;s urban population and the highly exposed vulnerability of the country to natural hazards and climate risk are aspects that need to be considered for the actual adaptation of the infrastructure to ensure the safety of all the residents. Last decade, private construction companies and the public administration in Mexico built different large-scale social housing projects for low-income occupants to provide a house to the most vulnerable population considering natural hazards and climate risk. The quality of the buildings is getting worse with time causing health problems, non-inclusive spaces, poor architectural flexibility, expensive maintenance, and poor environmental performance, among others. Having said that, the leading question of this study is: How to design a more sustainable and resilient incremental social house in Mexico City considering social, environmental, and economic aspects? The main limitation of this proposal is to respect the budget from the Mexican public administration designated to social housing projects. To deal with economic restrictions of Mexican public administration, the incremental housing concept proposed in this study could be used to answer (1) current housing needs for most low-income families in Mexico City, (2) provide an affordable initial core housing with spatial flexibility for future housing expansion, (3) provide a more environmentally sustainable social housing design in terms of the entire life cycle of the construction considering energy consumption and water consumption and CO2 emissions. Therefore, this research study presents a methodology, which is a combination of BIM (Building Information Modelling) and MIVES (Integrated Value Model for Sustainability Assessment), to assess the three main pillars of sustainability in incremental social housing design. To validate the methodology, first it is applied to three existing incremental housing cases, which are scenario A in Mexico, scenario B in Puerto Rico and scenario C in Indonesia, sharing similar characteristics such as construction area, construction cost per m2 and high-risk flooding location in developing economies. As well as, the same methodology is applied to elaborate a design elaborated by the author called MICASA, to find the best architectural solutions for an incremental social housing in Mexico City. The results show that the BIM-MIVES methodology is a useful tool for decision-making to improve the sustainability of social housing design in Mexico City. In this study, the proposal design, MICASA, shows 45% less CO2 emissions, 38% less energy consumption and 68% less solid waste than scenario A. MICASA is 2.5 times more expensive per m2 than scenario A, however, MICASA respects the cost limit assigned by the public administration for a low-income housing construction in Mexico City with a construction cost of 546.45 euros/m2. Considering social and environmental requirements, MICASA is the most sustainable case study compared to scenario A, B and C. The findings of this study suggest that it is feasible to design more sustainable social housing developments in Mexico City considering the environmental impact reduction, life-cycle cost and social acceptance respecting construction budget limitations. (Espa&#241;ol) El r&#225;pido crecimiento de la poblaci&#243;n urbana de M&#233;xico y la vulnerabilidad altamente expuesta del pa&#237;s a los peligros naturales y el riesgo clim&#225;tico son aspectos que deben considerarse para la adaptaci&#243;n de la infraestructura y garantizar la seguridad y el bienestar de todos los residentes. La d&#233;cada pasada, empresas constructoras privadas y la administraci&#243;n p&#250;blica en M&#233;xico construyeron diferentes proyectos de vivienda social de gran escala para ocupantes de bajos ingresos y en algunos consideraron en el dise&#241;o los peligros naturales de las diferentes zonas. La calidad de estas edificaciones va empeorando con el tiempo provocando problemas de salubridad, espacios no inclusivos, poca flexibilidad arquitect&#243;nica, mantenimiento constante debido a la precaria calidad de los materiales, un pobre desempe&#241;o ambiental, entre otros. Dicho esto, la pregunta principal de este estudio es: &#191;C&#243;mo dise&#241;ar una vivienda social incremental m&#225;s sostenible y resiliente en la Ciudad de M&#233;xico considerando aspectos sociales, ambientales y econ&#243;micos? La principal limitaci&#243;n de esta propuesta es respetar el presupuesto de la administraci&#243;n p&#250;blica mexicana destinado a este tipo de desarrollos de vivienda. Para hacer frente a las restricciones econ&#243;micas de la administraci&#243;n p&#250;blica mexicana, la estrategia de vivienda incremental, es propuesta en este estudio. Esta estrategia podr&#237;a usarse para: (1) responder a las necesidades actuales de vivienda para la mayor&#237;a de las familias de ingresos bajos en la Ciudad de M&#233;xico, (2) proporcionar una vivienda b&#225;sica inicial asequible con flexibilidad espacial para la futura expansi&#243;n, (3) proporcionar un dise&#241;o de vivienda social m&#225;s sostenible ambientalmente en todo su ciclo de vida considerando el consumo de energ&#237;a y agua, y las emisiones de CO2 . Dicho esto, esta investigaci&#243;n presenta una metodolog&#237;a, que en combinaci&#243;n de BIM (Building Information Modelling) y MIVES (Modelo Integrado de Valor para una Evaluaci&#243;n Sostenible), eval&#250;a los tres pilares principales de la sostenibilidad en el dise&#241;o de vivienda social incremental. Para validar esta metodolog&#237;a, est&#225; se aplica a tres casos de vivienda incremental existentes, que son los casos de estudio A, B y C, y que comparten caracter&#237;sticas similares como &#225;rea de construcci&#243;n, costo de construcci&#243;n por m2 y localizaci&#243;n en una zona de alto riesgo de inundaci&#243;n en econom&#237;as en desarrollo, entre otras. Asimismo, esta metodolog&#237;a es aplicada a un dise&#241;o elaborado por el autor, para encontrar las mejores soluciones arquitect&#243;nicas para la vivienda social incremental en la Ciudad de M&#233;xico. Los resultados muestran que la nueva metodolog&#237;a propuesta de BIM-MIVES es &#250;til para la toma de decisiones para mejorar la sustentabilidad del dise&#241;o de vivienda social en la Ciudad de M&#233;xico. En este estudio, el dise&#241;o de la propuesta (MICASA) muestra un 45% menos de emisiones de CO2 , un 38% menos de consumo de energ&#237;a y un 68% menos de residuos s&#243;lidos que el escenario A. MICASA es 2,5 veces m&#225;s caro por m2 que el escenario A, sin embargo, MICASA respeta el l&#237;mite de costo asignado por la administraci&#243;n p&#250;blica para la construcci&#243;n de una vivienda de inter&#233;s social en la Ciudad de M&#233;xico con un costo de construcci&#243;n de 546,45 euros/m2 . Teniendo en cuenta los requisitos sociales y ambientales, MICASA es el estudio de caso m&#225;s sostenible en comparaci&#243;n con los escenarios A, B y C. Finalmente, este estudio sugiere que es factible dise&#241;ar desarrollos de vivienda social m&#225;s sostenibles en la Ciudad de M&#233;xico considerando la reducci&#243;n del impacto ambiental, el costo del ciclo de vida y la aceptaci&#243;n social respetando las limitaciones del presupuesto de construcci&#243;n.</description>
      <author>Jani F. Vel&#225;zquez Robles</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5821/dissertation-2117-412157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International convergence towards a climate-neutral economy: modeling the agricultural sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51599/are.2024.10.02.03</link>
      <description>Andriy Krysovatyy, Iryna Maksymova, Vitalina Kuryliak, Michael A. Radin, Maksym Kurilyak, Agricultural and resource economics. 10(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400700094

                Purpose. This article aims to construct a comprehensive convergent model for assessing the global and EU&#8217;s progress, degree of consolidation and symmetry of agricultural economies towards climate neutrality in the context of key international green initiatives. Methodology / approach. This research employs both qualitative and quantitative analyses to assess convergence measures in the agricultural sector&#8217;s carbon emissions. The quantitative component relies on the sigma and beta convergence models to evaluate international convergence in carbon emissions CO2 dynamics. The dimensions of modeling are as follows: global sample within 194 countries with reliable emissions data; European Union, focusing on convergence within the EU27 member states, the United Kingdom, and Ukraine. The time period covers open data from 1972&#8211;2022. The dynamics of sigma and beta convergence is determined for the points, namely UN Stockholm Conference (1972), UN Rio Conference (1992), Kyoto Protocol (entry into force in 2005), Paris Agreement (2015). Additionally, statistical indicators of variation, skewness, Gini and Theil indices were calculated for delineating global smoothness and the concentration of agricultural emissions. Results. The results of the study reveal an inertial and divergent trend of the agricultural economy towards decarbonisation, which slows down the overall movement towards &#8220;net zero&#8221; due to the presence of clubs of lagging agricultural countries that increase emissions in violation of international agreements. The reduction in emissions skewness in recent years shows that more countries are &#8220;pulling&#8221; decarbonisation due to their high capacity to move towards net zero, but this is not enough. The EU is the most prominent example of accelerated climate convergence, but markers of its weakening in recent years are identified due to the inability of economies to maintain the pace of decarbonisation caused by economic constraints, technological barriers, policy and regulatory issues, and misunderstandings of climate neutrality goals. It is shown that the long-term decarbonisation capacity of the agricultural sector is the key trigger for a country to make a positive contribution to the global convergence towards climate neutrality. At the current stage, the pace of decarbonisation plays a much greater role for consolidating efforts in the agricultural economy and achieving climate neutrality than the initial level of emissions in the sector. Factors in this process include proactive compliance with global climate agreements, technology sharing and cooperation, digitalisation and smart agriculture, and green financing and investment. Its implementation requires a three-way integration of stakeholder actions, strategy selection and results evaluation. Originality / scientific novelty. The study&#8217;s originality lies in its large-scale analysis of over 50 years of emissions dynamics and the context of five key green agreements that provided support for the green transition. It allows studying international convergence in agricultural sectors globally and within the EU. The novelty implies the integrated use of sigma and beta convergence models that identifies predictors of convergent and divergent processes and separates countries into leaders and laggards of agricultural decarbonisation. This approach provides a comprehensive view of modern climate policy, the impact of international green initiatives, and the position of individual towards climate neutrality in agriculture. Practical value / implications. The practical value lies in the ability to adjust climate policies for the agricultural economy&#8217;s decarbonisation, facilitating the determination of prospective outcomes for achieving climate neutrality. The aforementioned factors facilitate the process of governmental decision-making. The assessment of international programmatic agreements' effectiveness is enhanced through these models. The study offers a framework for global convergence towards climate neutrality in agriculture, highlighting the importance of digital technologies and smart agriculture as significant factors in global convergence.</description>
      <author>Andriy Krysovatyy, Iryna Maksymova, Vitalina Kuryliak, Michael A. Radin, Maksym Kurilyak</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51599/are.2024.10.02.03</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ship emissions assessment in short sea shipping: application on weather ship routing, slow steaming and maritime education and training</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5821/dissertation-2117-412171</link>
      <description>Clara Bor&#233;n Alt&#233;s, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400896802

                (English) A significant proportion of global carbon dioxide emissions are attributed to ocean-sailing ships. These shipping emissions are predicted to double in less than 30 years. In this sense, it is mandatory to develop tools and methods for a proper assessment of the air contaminants emitted by vessels as the basis for developing efficient policies also enhancing best practices on board. From an academic point of view, the training of seafarers is the backbone of success in emissions abatement as their actions and knowledge have a direct impact on ships operation. From a theoretical point of view, the objective of this thesis is to analyse the effects on emissions abatement of the two operational techniques, i. e. weather ship routing and slow steaming, used in the shipping industry to reduce fuel consumption taking also into consideration future seafarers&#8217; education on the mentioned techniques. Firstly, this thesis merges the estimation of shipping pollutants and their mitigation through weather routing optimisation; two lines of research widely analysed separately but seldom discussed together. An open software of weather ship routing is used to obtain the minimum cost (i.e. optimised route) in terms of sailing time, using high-resolution wave forecasting analysing several scenarios for a Ro-Pax vessel sailing in the Mediterranean Sea. The assessment of fuel consumption and ship emissions calculations have been inspired by a bottom-up methodology, in conjunction with the estimation of the power increase needed to overcome speed decrement due to waves. The ship routing optimisation reveals a reduction up to 30% of ship emissions during severe storms on longer routes. Nevertheless, all the cases studied show emissions mitigation when ship routing optimisation is used. The expected increase of extreme weather events, in terms of frequency, intensity and duration due to climate change, suggests a gradual gain of implementing weather ship routing optimisation in all types of routes, regardless of the distance. Secondly, this contribution also investigates the effect on fuel consumption and emissions when vessels are sailing below the design speed (i.e. slow steaming), as a strategy to minimize fuel consumption. The estimation of fuel consumption is commonly based on the cubic speed- power relation as a bottom-up approach. Nevertheless, the cubic relation could overestimate the impact of slow steaming on fuel consumption reduction and the emissions assessment. Container ships real fuel consumption data is compared with the results of assessing these parameters from a bottom-up approach. The exponential values obtained for the speed- power relation show an overrating over 20%. Moreover, this section shows the results of the additional emissions savings in the framework of ship-specific measures when weather ship routing and slow steaming are applied simultaneously. Based on the results obtained, the present thesis proposes a weather ship routing software developed at the Barcelona School of Nautical Studies (UPC-Tech) as a new teaching tool for distance and face-to-face education, which has the aim to assess some knowledge of several competences of the Standards of Training, Certification and Watchkeeping (STCW) code on weather routing and emissions abatement. The results of a teaching trial carried out alternatively at sea (distance education) and onshore (face-to-face education) are compared in terms of competences acquisition in the Maritime Education and Training framework. Results indicate that, in the context of maritime training, there are no significant differences between students enrolled in a face-to-face or in a distance environment and results also demonstrate that the proposed software represents an innovative teaching tool that can be used by all Maritime Education and Traning Institutions. (Catal&#224;) Una part important de les emissions mundials de di&#242;xid de carboni s'atribueix als vaixells mercants i es preveu que les emissions del transport mar&#237;tim es dupliquin en menys de 30 anys. En aquest sentit, &#233;s d&#8217;una import&#224;ncia cabdal desenvolupar eines i m&#232;todes per a una avaluaci&#243; correcta de contaminants atmosf&#232;rics emesos pels vaixells per tal que sigui la base del desenvolupament de pol&#237;tiques eficients i de l&#8217;&#250;s de les millors pr&#224;ctiques a bord. Des del punt de vista acad&#232;mic, la formaci&#243; i conscienciaci&#243; de la gent de mar &#233;s l&#8217;eix vertebrador de l&#8217;&#232;xit en la reducci&#243; d&#8217;emissions, ja que les seves accions i coneixements tenen un impacte directe en l&#8217;explotaci&#243; dels vaixells. Des d&#8217;un punt de vista te&#242;ric, l&#8217;objectiu d&#8217;aquesta tesi &#233;s analitzar l&#8217;impacte en les emissions de l&#8217;aplicaci&#243; de dues t&#232;cniques operatives, com s&#243;n l&#8217;optimitzaci&#243; meteorol&#242;gica de rutes i la reducci&#243; de velocitat de navegaci&#243;, utilitzades en la ind&#250;stria naviliera per reduir les emissions, tenint en compte tamb&#233; la formaci&#243; de la futura gent de mar sobre les esmentades t&#232;cniques. Conseq&#252;entment, aquesta tesi contribueix a l&#8217;Objectiu de Desenvolupament Sostenible n&#250;mero 13 de les Nacions Unides d&#8217;Acci&#243; pel clima. D'una banda, la present contribuci&#243; combina l'estimaci&#243; dels contaminants del transport mar&#237;tim i la seva mitigaci&#243; mitjan&#231;ant l'optimitzaci&#243; rutes. S'utilitza un programari obert d&#8217;optimitzaci&#243; de rutes de vaixells mitjan&#231;ant la meteorologia que ha estat desenvolupat a la Facultat de N&#224;utica de Barcelona per obtenir el cost m&#237;nim (&#233;s a dir, una ruta optimitzada) en termes de temps de navegaci&#243;, utilitzant previsions d'onatge d'alta resoluci&#243; per a un vaixell Ro-Pax navegant pel Mar Mediterrani. L'optimitzaci&#243; de rutes revela una reducci&#243; de fins a un 30% de les emissions dels vaixells durant les tempestes severes en les rutes m&#233;s llargues. No obstant aix&#242;, tots els casos estudiats mostren una mitigaci&#243; d'emissions quan s'utilitza l'optimitzaci&#243; de rutes. L'augment esperat d'esdeveniments meteorol&#242;gics extrems, en termes de freq&#252;&#232;ncia, intensitat i durada a causa del canvi clim&#224;tic, suggereix un guany gradual d'implementar l'optimitzaci&#243; de rutes mitjan&#231;ant la meteorologia en tot tipus de rutes, independentment de la dist&#224;ncia. D'altra banda, aquesta contribuci&#243; tamb&#233; investiga l'efecte sobre el consum de combustible i les emissions quan els vaixells naveguen per sota de la velocitat de disseny (&#233;s a dir, en condici&#243; de navegaci&#243; lenta o &#8221;slow steaming&#8221;, SS), com a estrat&#232;gia per minimitzar el consum de combustible. L'estimaci&#243; del consum de combustible es basa habitualment en la relaci&#243; c&#250;bica velocitat-pot&#232;ncia. No obstant aix&#242;, la relaci&#243; c&#250;bica podria sobreestimar l'impacte de l&#8217;&#8221;slow steaming&#8221; en la reducci&#243; del consum de combustible i l'avaluaci&#243; d'emissions. Es comparen les dades de consum de combustible real de vaixells portacontenidors amb els resultats de l'avaluaci&#243; d'aquests par&#224;metres des d'un enfocament ascendent mostrant una sobreestimaci&#243; dels beneficis de l&#8217;SS superior al 20%. En funci&#243; dels resultats obtinguts, aquesta contribuci&#243; proposa un programari d&#8217;optimitzaci&#243; de rutes mar&#237;times segons la meteorologia com a eina docent per a l'ensenyament a dist&#224;ncia i presencial, que t&#233; com a objectiu avaluar alguns coneixements de diverses compet&#232;ncies del codi Est&#224;ndards de Formaci&#243;, Certificaci&#243; i Vigil&#224;ncia de la gent de mar (STCW) sobre l&#8217;optimitzaci&#243; de rutes i la reducci&#243; d'emissions. Es comparen els resultats d'un assaig docent realitzat alternativament al mar (educaci&#243; a dist&#224;ncia) i a terra (ensenyament presencial) pel que fa a l'adquisici&#243; de compet&#232;ncies en el marc d'Educaci&#243; i Formaci&#243; Mar&#237;times. Els resultats indiquen que, en el context de la formaci&#243; mar&#237;tima, no hi ha difer&#232;ncies significatives entre els estudiants matriculats en un entorn presencial o a distancia i tamb&#233; demostren que el software proposat &#233;s una eina did&#224;ctica innovadora que pot ser utilitzada per qualsevol Instituci&#243; d'Educaci&#243; Mar&#237;tima Superior. (Espa&#241;ol) Una parte importante de las emisiones globales de di&#243;xido de carbono se atribuyen a buques mercantes y se prev&#233; que las emisiones del transporte mar&#237;timo se dupliquen en menos de 30 a&#241;os. En este sentido, es de vital importancia desarrollar herramientas y metodolog&#237;as para una correcta evaluaci&#243;n de contaminantes atmosf&#233;ricos emitidos por los buques para que sirva de base para el desarrollo de pol&#237;ticas eficientes y para el uso de buenas pr&#225;cticas abordo. Desde el punto de vista acad&#233;mico, la formaci&#243;n y concienciaci&#243;n de la gente de mar es el eje vertebrador del &#233;xito en la reducci&#243;n de emisiones, puesto que sus acciones y conocimientos tienen un impacto directo en la explotaci&#243;n de los buques. Desde un punto de vista te&#243;rico, el objetivo de esta tesis es analizar el impacto sobre las emisiones de dos t&#233;cnicas operativas, como son la optimizaci&#243;n meteorol&#243;gica de rutas y la reducci&#243;n de la velocidad de navegaci&#243;n, utilizadas en la industria naviera para reducir emisiones, teniendo en cuenta tambi&#233;n la formaci&#243;n de los futuros marinos sobre las citadas t&#233;cnicas. En primer lugar, la presente contribuci&#243;n fusiona la estimaci&#243;n de los contaminantes del transporte mar&#237;timo y su mitigaci&#243;n a trav&#233;s de la optimizaci&#243;n de las rutas seg&#250;n las condiciones meteo-oceanogr&#225;ficas encontradas. Para tal efecto, se utiliza un software de optimizaci&#243;n de rutas de navegaci&#243;n de acceso abierto desarrollado en la Facultad de N&#225;utica de Barcelona (UPC-Tech) para obtener el costo m&#237;nimo (es decir, la ruta optimizada) en t&#233;rminos de tiempo de navegaci&#243;n, utilizando pron&#243;sticos de oleaje de alta resoluci&#243;n para un buque Ro-Pax navegando en el Mar Mediterraneo. La optimizaci&#243;n de las rutas estudiadas revela una reducci&#243;n de hasta el 30% de las emisiones durante tormentas severas. Sin embargo, todos los casos estudiados muestran mitigaci&#243;n de emisiones cuando se utiliza la optimizaci&#243;n de rutas. El esperado aumento de eventos clim&#225;ticos extremos, en t&#233;rminos de frecuencia, intensidad y duraci&#243;n debido al cambio clim&#225;tico, sugiere una ganancia gradual en la implementaci&#243;n de la optimizaci&#243;n de rutas de buques en todo tipo de rutas, independientemente de la distancia. En segundo lugar, esta contribuci&#243;n tambi&#233;n investiga el efecto sobre el consumo de combustible y las emisiones cuando los buques navegan por debajo de la velocidad de dise&#241;o (i.e. slow steaming, SS), como estrategia para minimizar el consumo de combustible. La estimaci&#243;n del consumo de combustible se basa com&#250;nmente en la relaci&#243;n c&#250;bica velocidad-potencia. Sin embargo, la relaci&#243;n c&#250;bica aplicada a cualquier velocidad de navegaci&#243;n podr&#237;a sobrestimar el beneficio del slow steaming en la reducci&#243;n del consumo de combustible y la evaluaci&#243;n de emisiones derivadas de dicho consumo. En esta contribuci&#243;n, se comparan los datos de consumo real de combustible de varios buques portacontenedores con los resultados de la evaluaci&#243;n te&#243;rica de estos par&#225;metros desde un enfoque ascendente mostrando una sobrevaloraci&#243;n de los beneficios del SS superior al 20%. En base a los resultados obtenidos, esta contribuci&#243;n propone un software de optimizaci&#243;n de rutas como herramienta did&#225;ctica para la educaci&#243;n a distancia y presencial, que tiene como objetivo evaluar parte del conocimiento de algunas competencias del c&#243;digo Est&#225;ndares de Formaci&#243;n, Certificaci&#243;n y Vigilancia de la gente de mar (STCW) sobre optimizaci&#243;n de rutas y mitigaci&#243;n de emisiones. Se comparan los resultados de la ense&#241;anza realizada alternativamente a distancia (en la mar) y presencial (en tierra) en t&#233;rminos de adquisici&#243;n de competencias en el marco de la Educaci&#243;n y Formaci&#243;n Mar&#237;timas. Los resultados indican que, en el contexto de la formaci&#243;n mar&#237;tima, no existen diferencias significativas entre los alumnos matriculados en un entorno presencial o a distancia y tambi&#233;n demuestran que el software propuesto es una herramienta de ense&#241;anza innovadora que puede ser utilizada por cualquier Instituci&#243;n de Educaci&#243;n Mar&#237;tima Superior.</description>
      <author>Clara Bor&#233;n Alt&#233;s</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5821/dissertation-2117-412171</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
