<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 01:24:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Selective Electroreduction of Carbon Dioxide Using Defect-Driven Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18267</link>
      <description>Tania Akter, Christian J. Kuster, Quinn A. Padovan, Samuel O. Odoh, Christopher J. Barile, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404615966

                The production of methanol from the electrochemical reduction of CO</description>
      <author>Tania Akter, Christian J. Kuster, Quinn A. Padovan, Samuel O. Odoh, Christopher J. Barile</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesopore&#8208;Augmented Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Nitrogen&#8208;Doped Carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406883</link>
      <description>Xu Han, Ting Zhang, Mart&#237; Biset&#8208;Peir&#243;, Alberto Rold&#225;n, Mads Folkj&#230;r, Nina Lock, Steen Uttrup Pedersen, J.R. Morante, Jordi Arbiol, Emil Tveden Bjerglund, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404617967

                Abstract The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (eCO 2 RR) using nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (N&#8211;C) materials offers a promising and cost&#8208;effective approach to global carbon neutrality. Regulating the porosity of N&#8211;C materials can potentially increase the catalytic performance by suppressing the concurrence of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, the augmentation of porosity usually alters the active sites or the chemical composition of catalysts, resulting in intertwined influences of various structural factors and catalytic performance. In this study, incorporating secondary carbon sources into the metal&#8208;organic framework (MOF) precursor through nanocasting aimed to selectively enhance the mesoporous structure, allowing for deciphering this effect from other changes in the catalyst composition. Consequently, the developed N&#8211;C catalyst exhibited a significant surface area with abundant mesopores, leading to a maximum Faradaic efficiency (FE) for carbon monoxide (CO) of 95% at &#8722;0.50 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (vs. RHE). Furthermore, the FE for CO is enhanced across a wide potential range, surpassing previously reported metal&#8208;free N&#8211;C eCO 2 RR catalysts. The investigation reveals that constructing mesoporous structures can induce excellent CO 2 catalysis by enhancing the accessibility of active sites while establishing an elevated local pH at these sites.</description>
      <author>Xu Han, Ting Zhang, Mart&#237; Biset&#8208;Peir&#243;, Alberto Rold&#225;n, Mads Folkj&#230;r, Nina Lock, Steen Uttrup Pedersen, J.R. Morante, Jordi Arbiol, Emil Tveden Bjerglund</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of the electrolyte solution in the activity of non-noble metal electrocatalysts in the carbon dioxide reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47749/t/unicamp.2024.1403387</link>
      <description>Maria Rodrigues Pinto, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404627816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maria Rodrigues Pinto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47749/t/unicamp.2024.1403387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag2O-supported FePO4 heterojunctions: Facile fabrication and fast visible-light carbon dioxide photoreduction into methanol with superb recyclability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109160</link>
      <description>G. H. Sewify, Soliman I. El-Hout, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 187(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404659708

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. H. Sewify, Soliman I. El-Hout</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lattice Mismatch-Driven Photochemical Self-Assembly of Supported Heterostructures for Stable and Enhanced Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235560</link>
      <description>Yidan Liu, Xu Ren, Yali Ji, Ting Li, Rongrong Jia, Liyi Shi, Wenlong Zhou, Xiran Qiao, Lei Huang, Molecules. 29(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404696234

                Metallic heterostructural nanocrystals (HNCs) hold immense potential in electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) owing to their abundant active sites and high intrinsic activity. However, a significant challenge still remains in achieving controlled nucleation and growth sites for HNCs on supports and comprehending the influence of the structure&#8211;activity relationship on electrocatalytic CO2RR performance. This work presents a photochemical self-assembly technique without the necessity for reducing agents or facet-specific capping agents. By controlling lattice mismatch and manipulating transfer paths of photo-generated carriers, we can precisely direct the growth sites and nucleation of nanocrystals, enabling the self-assembly of supported core&#8211;shell and Janus nanostructures. Compared to Pd(T)@Au core&#8211;shell HNCs with the same loading, Pd cube&#8211;Au Janus HNCs exhibit significantly enhanced selectivity and stability toward carbon monoxide (CO) production in CO2RR at less negative potentials. The Pd cube&#8211;Au Janus HNC electrocatalyst achieved a Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 92.6 &#177; 3.5% for CO electroreduction, accompanied by a current density of 72.3 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;0.58 V. This work provides an effective strategy for designing advanced supported tandem electrocatalysts to boost the selectivity and durability test of CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Yidan Liu, Xu Ren, Yali Ji, Ting Li, Rongrong Jia, Liyi Shi, Wenlong Zhou, Xiran Qiao, Lei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bulk Layering Effects of Ag and Cu for Tandem CO2 Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401769</link>
      <description>Mark Sassenburg, Hugo&#8208;Pieter Iglesias van Montfort, Nikita Kolobov, Wilson A. Smith, Thomas Burdyny, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404706959

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) presents an opportunity to close the carbon cycle and obtain sustainably sourced carbon compounds. In recent years, copper has received widespread attention as the only catalyst capable of meaningfully producing multi&#8208;carbon (C2+) species. Notably carbon monoxide (CO) can also be reduced to C2+ compounds on copper, motivating tandem systems that combine copper and CO&#8208;producing species, like silver, to enhance overall C2+ selectivities. In this work, we examine the impact of layered&#8208;combinations of bulk Cu and Ag by varying the location and proportion of the CO&#8208;producing Ag layer. We report an effective increase in the C2+ oxygenate selectivity from 23% with a 100 nm Cu to 38% for a 100:15 nm Cu:Ag layer. Notably, however, for all co&#8208;catalyst cases there is an overproduction of CO vs Cu alone, even for 5 nm Ag layers. Lastly, due to restructuring and interlayer mobility of the copper layer it is clear that the stability of copper limits the locational advantages of such tandem solutions.</description>
      <author>Mark Sassenburg, Hugo&#8208;Pieter Iglesias van Montfort, Nikita Kolobov, Wilson A. Smith, Thomas Burdyny</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Electrochemical Conversion of Carbon Dioxide into Methanol in Water with High Faradaic Efficiency by Mo-Functionalized Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-2c12c</link>
      <description>Carlo Nervi, Alice Barbero, Federico Pezzano, Federico Calderaro, Roberto Gobetto, Chiara Reviglio, Asia Porceddu, Victoria A. Nikitina, Jianfeng Li, Shouxin Zhang, Zhuo Huang, Jia Liu, Artem R. Oganov, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404779291

                We developed a new electrocatalysts for hybrid homogeneous / heterogeneous conversion of CO2 in water. A Molybdenum-based organometallic compound has been linked by covalent C-C bond to a carbon-cloth electrode surface. This technique allows using the Mo catalyst in water, a solvent in which the catalyst is not soluble, for the direct electrocatalytic conversion of CO2 to methanol. Although the system displays moderate current density (1&#247;4 mA/cm2), the very high faradaic efficiency of the CO2-to-methanol conversion (65%), the good selectivity (H2 is the only other reduction product), the simply experimental setup and the potential industrial scale-up of the technique makes this approach of great interest. Chronoamperometric measurement carried in water for 21 hours show a stable and constant catalytic performance with no other carbon-reduced products. Spectroelectrochemistry and detailed DFT calculations shed light on the catalytic process, which consists of six protons coupled electron transfer (PCET) steps. We propose the catalytic cycle that converts CO to methanol in which the first step is a PCET localized on the CO coordinated to the metal.</description>
      <author>Carlo Nervi, Alice Barbero, Federico Pezzano, Federico Calderaro, Roberto Gobetto, Chiara Reviglio, Asia Porceddu, Victoria A. Nikitina, Jianfeng Li, Shouxin Zhang, Zhuo Huang, Jia Liu, Artem R. Oganov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-2c12c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide and nitrate reduction reactions tailoring kinetics over Cu2O with mesoporous carbon channels for boosting electrocatalytic urea synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114959</link>
      <description>Jiamin Zhao, Ying Yuan, Meimei Kou, Fanpeng Meng, Wei Lin, Jinsheng Zhao, Panagiotis Tsiakaras, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404802445

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiamin Zhao, Ying Yuan, Meimei Kou, Fanpeng Meng, Wei Lin, Jinsheng Zhao, Panagiotis Tsiakaras</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radiation-assisted electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00484a</link>
      <description>Ryan P. Morco, L. D&#305;&#769;az, Maria Magdalena Ramirez Corredores, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404627200

                Carbon monoxide (CO) is a versatile intermediate feedstock for many applications, which can be produced from the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2). However, current electrochemical CO production is associated...</description>
      <author>Ryan P. Morco, L. D&#305;&#769;az, Maria Magdalena Ramirez Corredores</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00484a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the performance of electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction towards C1 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.63028/10067/2101340151162165141</link>
      <description>J&#228;ri Van den Hoek, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404724057

                The Industrial Revolution led to significant socio-economic growth and population expansion, yet its environmental consequences have been profound, notably through the increase in anthropogenic greenhouse gases like carbon dioxide (CO2). This imbalance in the carbon cycle contributes to global warming, melting ice caps, biodiversity loss, and extreme weather events. To combat this, international and European authorities aim for carbon neutrality by 2050. Achieving this requires innovative technologies to limit global temperature rise to below 2C above pre-industrial levels. One promising solution is the electrochemical reduction of CO2 (eCO2R), a carbon dioxide utilization technology that reduces atmospheric CO2 and closes the carbon cycle by converting it into valuable chemicals using renewable energy sources such as wind, solar, and geothermal power. Two key products of eCO2R, carbon monoxide and formate, are of particular interest due to their industrial relevance, high market value, and low energy requirements. This dissertation explores the electroreduction of CO2 as a critical solution to mitigate climate change. It delves into the interplay between electrocatalyst performance and interface properties to improve the selectivity, activity, and stability of electrocatalysts used for producing C1 products. The research highlights the challenges faced by current electrocatalysts and suggests ways to enhance their performance. In the context of CO production, the dissertation investigates the limitations of silver (Ag) nanoparticle stability, addressing issues of agglomeration and detachment. The study proposes a nanoparticle confinement strategy to stabilize Ag nanoparticles within nitrogen-doped ordered mesoporous carbon (NOMC). This method significantly reduces instability and improves Faradaic efficiency (FE) towards CO production (&gt;80% at 100 mA cm-2). For formate production, the research focuses on chalcogenide-based electrocatalysts, specifically SnS2 thin films fabricated using atomic layer deposition (ALD) techniques. The study examines the impact of morphology on the electrocatalytic interface and its role in the triple-phase boundary (TPB). Although these SnS2 electrocatalysts exhibit high formate FE (~80%), their long-term stability is limited by the reduction of SnS2 to Sn and morphological degradation. Further investigation into the effect of substrate modifications via ALD reveals that thermal deposition of In2S3 electrocatalysts leads to superior formate selectivity (&gt;90%) and stability compared to plasma-enhanced versions. These findings emphasize the importance of interface properties, such as roughness and wettability, in enhancing electrocatalyst performance. The research provides valuable insights for optimizing electrocatalysts for industrial applications, improving their stability, activity, and selectivity.</description>
      <author>J&#228;ri Van den Hoek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.63028/10067/2101340151162165141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Pathways for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction into Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-zmdtq</link>
      <description>Peshala Jayamaha, Lichang Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404779659

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) offers a promising route to storing chemical energy and producing valuable chemicals, while also contributing to carbon cycle closure. Despite significant advances in electrocatalytic CO2RR for multi-carbon products, challenges remain in optimizing catalysts for high selectivity and efficiency. Cu-based heterogeneous catalysts are among the most promising options; however, enhancing their catalytic efficiency and product selectivity remains complex due to several factors. One key challenge is that product selectivity heavily depends on the catalyst&#8217;s surface morphology, which impacts both Faradaic efficiency and overpotential requirements for target product formation. Additionally, the reaction pathways and intermediates for multi-carbon products are not yet fully understood, complicating efforts to achieve consistent multi-carbon yields. Variability introduced by the electrolyte environment, applied potential, and operating conditions further impacts selectivity and efficiency. This review aims to address these challenges by exploring the interplay between the surface structure of Cu-based catalysts and system parameters that shape reaction pathways for ethanol formation. Notably, we explore alternative pathways beyond the conventional mechanisms involving CHO, COH, and CO dimers.</description>
      <author>Peshala Jayamaha, Lichang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-zmdtq</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learning-accelerated density functional theory screening of Cu-based high-entropy alloys for carbon dioxide reduction to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161919</link>
      <description>Meena Rittiruam, Pisit Khamloet, Sirapat Tiwtusthada, Annop Ektarawong, Tinnakorn Saelee, Chayanon Atthapak, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404724512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meena Rittiruam, Pisit Khamloet, Sirapat Tiwtusthada, Annop Ektarawong, Tinnakorn Saelee, Chayanon Atthapak, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161919</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anode engineering for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110665</link>
      <description>Mingming Zhang, Ting Xu, Ruonan Yin, Xueqiu Chen, Zhengjun Wang, Jun Li, Xin Wang, Huile Jin, Haibo Ke, Shun Wang, Jing-Jing Lv, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404649205

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingming Zhang, Ting Xu, Ruonan Yin, Xueqiu Chen, Zhengjun Wang, Jun Li, Xin Wang, Huile Jin, Haibo Ke, Shun Wang, Jing-Jing Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress of mechanistic pathways involved in electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.032</link>
      <description>Jing-Wen DuanMu, Xiaopeng Yang, Fei&#8208;Yue Gao, Masoud Atapour, Min&#8208;Rui Gao, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404801239

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing-Wen DuanMu, Xiaopeng Yang, Fei&#8208;Yue Gao, Masoud Atapour, Min&#8208;Rui Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic Molecule Functionalization Enables Selective Electrochemical Reduction of Dilute CO2 Feedstock</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417196</link>
      <description>B.X. Wang, Xingyu Wang, Bo Wu, Peize Li, Shenghua Chen, Ruihu Lu, Wenjie Lai, Yan Shen, Zechao Zhuang, Jiexin Zhu, Ziyun Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Yanwei Lum, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404729304

                The electrochemical conversion of low&#8208;concentration CO2 feedstock to value&#8208;added chemicals and fuels is a promising pathway for achieving direct valorization of waste gas streams. However, this is challenging due to significant competition from the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and lowered CO2 reduction (CO2R) kinetics as compared to systems that employ pure CO2. Here we show that terephthalic acid (TPA) functionalization can boost selectivity towards CO2R and suppress HER over a range of catalysts including Bi, Cu and Zn. For instance, TPA functionalized Bi attained a formate Faradaic efficiency (FEHCOO&#8208;) of 96.3% at 300 mA cm&#8208;2 with pure CO2 feedstock. Density functional theory simulations indicate that this is because TPA functionalization modulates the binding energies of the key reaction intermediates *OCHO and *H. With low&#8208;concentration feedstock (15% CO2) at 100 mA cm&#8208;2, we achieved a high FEHCOO&#8208; of 85.8%, which was double that of an unmodified Bi catalyst. Using an electrolyzer with a porous solid electrolyte layer, we successfully showcase 30 h of continuous high&#8208;purity formic acid production from dilute CO2. Taken together, our findings demonstrate that molecular tuning of a catalyst can be an effective strategy for enabling selective CO2R using low&#8208;concentration feedstock.</description>
      <author>B.X. Wang, Xingyu Wang, Bo Wu, Peize Li, Shenghua Chen, Ruihu Lu, Wenjie Lai, Yan Shen, Zechao Zhuang, Jiexin Zhu, Ziyun Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Yanwei Lum</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic Molecule Functionalization Enables Selective Electrochemical Reduction of Dilute CO2 Feedstock</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417196</link>
      <description>Bingqing Wang, Xingyu Wang, Bo Wu, Peize Li, Shenghua Chen, Ruihu Lu, Wei-Chi Lai, Yan Shen, Zechao Zhuang, Jiexin Zhu, Ziyun Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Yanwei Lum, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404729303

                The electrochemical conversion of low&#8208;concentration CO2 feedstock to value&#8208;added chemicals and fuels is a promising pathway for achieving direct valorization of waste gas streams. However, this is challenging due to significant competition from the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and lowered CO2 reduction (CO2R) kinetics as compared to systems that employ pure CO2. Here we show that terephthalic acid (TPA) functionalization can boost selectivity towards CO2R and suppress HER over a range of catalysts including Bi, Cu and Zn. For instance, TPA functionalized Bi attained a formate Faradaic efficiency (FEHCOO&#8208;) of 96.3% at 300 mA cm&#8208;2 with pure CO2 feedstock. Density functional theory simulations indicate that this is because TPA functionalization modulates the binding energies of the key reaction intermediates *OCHO and *H. With low&#8208;concentration feedstock (15% CO2) at 100 mA cm&#8208;2, we achieved a high FEHCOO&#8208; of 85.8%, which was double that of an unmodified Bi catalyst. Using an electrolyzer with a porous solid electrolyte layer, we successfully showcase 30 h of continuous high&#8208;purity formic acid production from dilute CO2. Taken together, our findings demonstrate that molecular tuning of a catalyst can be an effective strategy for enabling selective CO2R using low&#8208;concentration feedstock.</description>
      <author>Bingqing Wang, Xingyu Wang, Bo Wu, Peize Li, Shenghua Chen, Ruihu Lu, Wei-Chi Lai, Yan Shen, Zechao Zhuang, Jiexin Zhu, Ziyun Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Yanwei Lum</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Triple-Atom sites for H2O Participated electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157813</link>
      <description>Zhaojun Min, Chunfeng Shao, Bing Chang, Nan Wang, Yang Zhao, Shuaiqi Gao, Xia&#8208;Guang Zhang, Maohong Fan, Suojiang Zhang, Jianji Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404634479

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaojun Min, Chunfeng Shao, Bing Chang, Nan Wang, Yang Zhao, Shuaiqi Gao, Xia&#8208;Guang Zhang, Maohong Fan, Suojiang Zhang, Jianji Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional electrode material for (photo)electrochemical reduction of CO2: An overview</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijoes.2024.100874</link>
      <description>Paulsamy Raja, Tse&#8208;Wei Chen, Shen&#8208;Ming Chen, Palraj Kalimuthu, Ganesan Anushya, Rasu Ramachandran, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Vinitha Mariyappan, Saranvignesh Alargarsamy, Mohammed Mujahid Alam, Ajith Velraj, S Selvapriya, Ramanujam Kannan, International Journal of Electrochemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404625470

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Paulsamy Raja, Tse&#8208;Wei Chen, Shen&#8208;Ming Chen, Palraj Kalimuthu, Ganesan Anushya, Rasu Ramachandran, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Vinitha Mariyappan, Saranvignesh Alargarsamy, Mohammed Mujahid Alam, Ajith Velraj, S Selvapriya, Ramanujam Kannan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijoes.2024.100874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-synthetic modification of Covalent Organic Frameworks with active Manganese centers for the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction in water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02807d</link>
      <description>Elena Gala, Geyla Caridad, Mattia Vettori, Sergio Royuela, Marcos Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Jos&#233; I. Mart&#237;nez, Elena Salagre, E. G. Michel, F&#233;lix Zamora, J.L. Fillol, Jos&#233; L. Segura, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404738867

                The development of effective catalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is essential for transforming atmospheric CO2 into valuable chemical scaffolds.. The development of appropriate CO2RR catalysts is challenging but,...</description>
      <author>Elena Gala, Geyla Caridad, Mattia Vettori, Sergio Royuela, Marcos Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Jos&#233; I. Mart&#237;nez, Elena Salagre, E. G. Michel, F&#233;lix Zamora, J.L. Fillol, Jos&#233; L. Segura</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02807d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in electrolytic cells for synchrotron radiation characterization of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-024-0968-y</link>
      <description>Zhaojun Wu, Weidong Cheng, Xin Wang, Huanyan Liu, Xiang Chen, Z. T. Sui, Zhonghua Wu, Frontiers in Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404764238

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaojun Wu, Weidong Cheng, Xin Wang, Huanyan Liu, Xiang Chen, Z. T. Sui, Zhonghua Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-024-0968-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective urea electrosynthesis via nitrate and CO2 reduction on uncoordinated Zn nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05599c</link>
      <description>Xiaomiao Wang, Fengyu Zhang, Haixin Zhang, Jingxuan Wang, Wenhuan Qu, Xiangdong Li, Ke Chu, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404777966

                Electroreduction of NO3- and CO2 to urea (ENCU) represents a fascinating strategy to enable waste NO3-/CO2 removal and sustainable urea production. Herein, uncoordinated Zn nanosheets (U-Zn) are developed as a...</description>
      <author>Xiaomiao Wang, Fengyu Zhang, Haixin Zhang, Jingxuan Wang, Wenhuan Qu, Xiangdong Li, Ke Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05599c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in mechanistic insights into cation effects on electrochemical CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101614</link>
      <description>Xueping Qin, Renata Sechi, Heine Anton Hansen, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404651771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xueping Qin, Renata Sechi, Heine Anton Hansen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101614</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Systematic Review of CO2 Reduction Technologies in China&#8217;s Iron and Steel Industry: Advancing Towards Carbon Neutrality</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235975</link>
      <description>Tianshu Hou, Yuxing Yuan, Hongming Na, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404757249

                The iron and steel industry, a major energy consumer, faces significant pressure to reduce CO2 emissions. As the world&#8217;s largest steel producer, China must prioritize this sector to meet its carbon neutrality goals. This study provides a comprehensive review of various carbon reduction technologies to drive decarbonization in the steel industry. China&#8217;s iron and steel sector, which accounted for approximately 15% of the country&#8217;s total CO2 emissions in 2022, predominantly relies on coke and coal combustion. This study provides a comprehensive review of a variety of carbon reduction technologies to advance decarbonization in the iron and steel industry. This study categorizes carbon reduction technologies in the steel sector into low-carbon, zero-carbon, and negative-carbon technologies. Low-carbon technologies, which are the most widely implemented, are further divided into energy structure adjustment, material structure adjustment, energy efficiency improvement technologies, etc. This study specifically reviews dry quenching technology, high-scale pellet technology for blast furnace, and top pressure recovery turbine power generation technology. As a zero-carbon technology, hydrometallurgy is a central focus of this study and a key area of research within China&#8217;s iron and steel industry. While negative-carbon technologies are primarily centered around carbon capture, utilization technologies are still in early stages. By presenting the latest advancements, this study offers valuable insights and guidance to facilitate the iron and steel industry&#8217;s transition to a low-carbon future, crucial for mitigating global climate change.</description>
      <author>Tianshu Hou, Yuxing Yuan, Hongming Na</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving China's CO2 reduction targets: Insights from a hybrid PPA-PPR forecasting model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123409</link>
      <description>YU Xiao-hong, Haiyan Xu, Jun Yin, Qiancheng Ma, Farina Khan, Journal of Environmental Management. 372(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631099

                No abstract</description>
      <author>YU Xiao-hong, Haiyan Xu, Jun Yin, Qiancheng Ma, Farina Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing MILD Combustion of Natural Gas with Additives: A Taguchi Method Approach for CO2 Emission Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-024-09794-w</link>
      <description>Neda Firooznia, Cyrus Aghanajafi, Arabian Journal for Science and Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404814147

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Neda Firooznia, Cyrus Aghanajafi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-024-09794-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Bi2WO6/MXene(Ti3C2Tx) Composite Material and Its Photothermal Catalytic Reduction of CO2 in Air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120859</link>
      <description>Lingji Zhang, Mengke Shi, Shuo Zhang, Feng Yue, Cai&#8208;Rong Yang, Yang Meng, Wen Li, Cong Li, Mario Berrettoni, Silvia Zamponi, Yongpeng Ma, Hongzhong Zhang, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404721152

                In response to growing concerns about the greenhouse effect, the direct conversion of atmospheric CO2 has become a pivotal research focus. This research utilizes hydrothermal synthesis to develop Bi2WO6/MXene(Ti3C2Tx), which efficiently reduces CO2 directly at the gas&#8211;solid interface through photothermal synergy, without requiring additional sacrificial agents or alkaline absorption solutions. The results indicate that the CO formation rate is about 216.9 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1h&#8722;1. Notably, this system demonstrates exceptional selectivity for reducing CO2 to CO. The outstanding photothermal catalytic efficiency is attributed to the introduction of MXene, which serves as an efficient and economical co-catalyst. The integration of MXene improves the composite material&#8217;s specific surface area and pore structure, enhances its CO2 adsorption capacity, and results in the Bi2WO6/MXene hybrid having a shorter charge transfer distance and a larger interface contact area. This ensures superior charge transfer capabilities, ultimately leading to a significant enhancement in the catalytic efficiency of the composite. This study presents a straightforward and highly selective method for capturing and converting atmospheric CO2, offering fresh insights for developing efficient photothermal catalytic materials.</description>
      <author>Lingji Zhang, Mengke Shi, Shuo Zhang, Feng Yue, Cai&#8208;Rong Yang, Yang Meng, Wen Li, Cong Li, Mario Berrettoni, Silvia Zamponi, Yongpeng Ma, Hongzhong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing CO2 Reduction Effects Through Decarbonization Scenarios in the Residential and Transportation Sectors: Challenges and Solutions for Japan&#8217;s Hilly and Mountainous Areas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310342</link>
      <description>Xiying Hao, Chuyue Yan, Daisuke NARUMI, Sustainability. 16(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404716793

                Depopulation, aging, and regional decline are becoming increasingly serious issues in Japan&#8217;s hilly and mountainous areas. Focusing on mitigating environmental damage and envisioning a sustainable future for these regions, this study examines the potential for reducing CO2 emissions in the residential and transportation sectors by 2050. Bottom-up simulations were used to estimate CO2 emissions. Subsequently, six decarbonization scenarios were formulated, considering various measures from the perspectives of population distribution and technological progress. Based on these scenarios, this study analyzes changes in future population, energy consumption, and CO2 emissions by 2050. The results of this study show the following. (1) Depopulation and aging problems in these regions are expected to become more severe in the future. It is necessary to take action to promote sustainable regional development. (2) Pursuing decarbonization has a positive impact on enhancing regional sustainability; however, maintaining the intensity of measures at the current level could lead to a reduction of only 40% in CO2 emissions per capita by 2050 compared with 2020. (3) Scenarios that strengthen decarbonization measures could achieve a reduction of over 95% by 2050, indicating that carbon neutrality is attainable. However, this will require implementing measures at a higher intensity, especially in the transportation sector.</description>
      <author>Xiying Hao, Chuyue Yan, Daisuke NARUMI</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethanol Electrosynthesis with Co2 Reduction Via Synergistic Reactions Over Copc/Cu2-Xse Tandem Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5034929</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Jun Cheng, Hongkun Lv, Kang Zhang, Liwei Ding, Rencheng Jin, Yang Xu, Yuxiang Mao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404741964

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Jun Cheng, Hongkun Lv, Kang Zhang, Liwei Ding, Rencheng Jin, Yang Xu, Yuxiang Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5034929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Synthesis of Nano-Ceo2 by the Hydrothermal Route and its Effect on the Activity of Co2 Non-Reductive Transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5035885</link>
      <description>Yuying Yang, Junjie Ma, Liu Na, Xueli Huang, Lijun Jin, He Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404765350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuying Yang, Junjie Ma, Liu Na, Xueli Huang, Lijun Jin, He Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5035885</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigations of transition metal atom-doped MoSi2N4 monolayers as catalysts for electrochemical CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03493g</link>
      <description>Guoqiang Ding, Yiwen Gao, Hetong Zhang, Na Yang, Xiaobin Niu, Jianwei Wang, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404768068

                Following the principle of single-atom catalysts (SACs), the fourth-period transition metals (TM) were designed as active sites on a MoSi2N4 monolayer surface with N vacancy, and the catalytic mechanisms of...</description>
      <author>Guoqiang Ding, Yiwen Gao, Hetong Zhang, Na Yang, Xiaobin Niu, Jianwei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03493g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating C-C coupling pathway in electrochemical CO2 reduction for selective ethylene and ethanol production over single-atom alloy catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54636-w</link>
      <description>Shifu Wang, Fuhua Li, Jian Zhao, Yaqiong Zeng, Yifan Li, Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Tsung-Ju Lee, Shu-Hui Liu, Xinyi Ren, Weijue Wang, Yusen Chen, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yi Cui, Xiaofeng Yang, Xuning Li, Yanqiang Huang, Bin Liu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404709191

                Manipulation C-C coupling pathway is of great importance for selective CO2 electroreduction but remain challenging. Herein, two model Cu-based catalysts, by modifying Cu nanowires with Ag nanoparticles (AgCu NW) and Ag single atoms (Ag1Cu NW), respectively, are rationally designed for exploring the C-C coupling mechanisms in electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Compared to AgCu NW, the Ag1Cu NW exhibits a more than 10-fold increase of C2 selectivity in CO2 reduction to ethanol, with ethanol-to-ethylene ratio increased from 0.41 over AgCu NW to 4.26 over Ag1Cu NW. Via a variety of operando/in-situ techniques and theoretical calculation, the enhanced ethanol selectivity over Ag1Cu NW is attributed to the promoted H2O dissociation over the atomically dispersed Ag sites, which effectively accelerated *CO hydrogenation to form *CHO intermediate and facilitated asymmetric *CO-*CHO coupling over paired Cu atoms adjacent to single Ag atoms. Results of this work provide deep insight into the C-C coupling pathways towards target C2+ product and shed light on the rational design of efficient CO2RR catalysts with paired active sites. Manipulating the carbon-carbon coupling pathway in CO2 electroreduction is vital yet challenging. Here, by studying two model copper-based catalysts with distinct ethylene and ethanol selectivity, authors investigate the mechanistic origins for symmetric and asymmetric carbon-carbon coupling.</description>
      <author>Shifu Wang, Fuhua Li, Jian Zhao, Yaqiong Zeng, Yifan Li, Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Tsung-Ju Lee, Shu-Hui Liu, Xinyi Ren, Weijue Wang, Yusen Chen, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yi Cui, Xiaofeng Yang, Xuning Li, Yanqiang Huang, Bin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54636-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Catalytic Activity of i-MXenes for CO2 Reduction Reaction by Ordered Metal Atomic Vacancies: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105535</link>
      <description>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404804106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subtle Modifications in Interface Configurations of Iron/Cobalt Phthalocyanine&#8208;based Electrocatalysts Determine Molecular CO2 Reduction Activities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420286</link>
      <description>Yinger Xin, Charles B. Musgrave, Jianjun Su, Jiangtong Li, Pei Xiong, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Yun Mi Song, Qianfeng Gu, Qiang Zhang, Yong Liu, Weihua Guo, Le Cheng, Xuefeng Tan, Qiu Jiang, Chuan Xia, Ben Zhong Tang, William A. Goddard, Ruquan Ye, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404691550

                Strain engineering has emerged as a powerful approach in steering the material properties. However, the improved catalytic activity remains poorly understood. Here we report that subtle changes in molecular configurations can profoundly affect, conducively or adversely, the catalytic selectivity and product turnover frequencies (TOFs) of CO2RR. Specifically, introducing molecular curvature in cobalt tetraaminophthalocyanine improves the multielectron CO2RR activity by favorable *CO hydrogenation, attaining methanol Faradaic efficiency up to 52%. In stark contrast, strained iron phthalocyanine exacerbates *CO poisoning, leading to a decreased TOFCO by over 50% at &#8208;0.5 VRHE and a rapid current decay. The uniform dispersion is crucial for optimizing electron transfer, while activity is distinctly sensitive to local atomic environment around the active sites. Specifically, local strain either enhances binding to intermediates or poisons the catalytic sites. Our comprehensive analysis elucidates the intricate relationship between molecular structure and CO2RR activities, offering insights into designing efficient heterogeneous molecular interfaces.</description>
      <author>Yinger Xin, Charles B. Musgrave, Jianjun Su, Jiangtong Li, Pei Xiong, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Yun Mi Song, Qianfeng Gu, Qiang Zhang, Yong Liu, Weihua Guo, Le Cheng, Xuefeng Tan, Qiu Jiang, Chuan Xia, Ben Zhong Tang, William A. Goddard, Ruquan Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subtle Modifications in Interface Configurations of Iron/Cobalt Phthalocyanine&#8208;based Electrocatalysts Determine Molecular CO2 Reduction Activities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420286</link>
      <description>Yinger Xin, Charles B. Musgrave, Jianjun Su, Jiangtong Li, Pei Xiong, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Yun Mi Song, Qianfeng Gu, Qiang Zhang, Yong Liu, Weihua Guo, Le Cheng, Xuefeng Tan, Jiang Qiu, Chuan Xia, Ben Zhong Tang, William A. Goddard, Ruquan Ye, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404691182

                Strain engineering has emerged as a powerful approach in steering the material properties. However, the improved catalytic activity remains poorly understood. Here we report that subtle changes in molecular configurations can profoundly affect, conducively or adversely, the catalytic selectivity and product turnover frequencies (TOFs) of CO2RR. Specifically, introducing molecular curvature in cobalt tetraaminophthalocyanine improves the multielectron CO2RR activity by favorable *CO hydrogenation, attaining methanol Faradaic efficiency up to 52%. In stark contrast, strained iron phthalocyanine exacerbates *CO poisoning, leading to a decreased TOFCO by over 50% at &#8208;0.5 VRHE and a rapid current decay. The uniform dispersion is crucial for optimizing electron transfer, while activity is distinctly sensitive to local atomic environment around the active sites. Specifically, local strain either enhances binding to intermediates or poisons the catalytic sites. Our comprehensive analysis elucidates the intricate relationship between molecular structure and CO2RR activities, offering insights into designing efficient heterogeneous molecular interfaces.</description>
      <author>Yinger Xin, Charles B. Musgrave, Jianjun Su, Jiangtong Li, Pei Xiong, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Yun Mi Song, Qianfeng Gu, Qiang Zhang, Yong Liu, Weihua Guo, Le Cheng, Xuefeng Tan, Jiang Qiu, Chuan Xia, Ben Zhong Tang, William A. Goddard, Ruquan Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divergent Activity Shifts of Sn-Based Catalysts for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction: pH-Dependent Behavior of Single-Atom vs. Polyatomic Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-38nl4-v2</link>
      <description>Yuhang Wang, Di Zhang, Bin Sun, Xue Jia, Linda Zhang, Hefeng Cheng, Jun Fan, Hao Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404704203

                Tin (Sn)-based catalysts have been widely studied for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to produce formic acid, but the intricate influence of the structural sensitivity in single-atom Sn (e.g., Sn-N-C) and polyatomic Sn (e.g., SnOx and SnSx; x=1,2) on their pH-dependent performance remains enigmatic. Herein, we integrate large-scale data mining (with &gt;2,300 CO2RR catalysts from available experimental literature during the past decade), ab initio computations, machine learning force field accelerated molecular dynamic simulations, and pH-field coupled microkinetic modelling to unravel their pH dependence. We reveal a fascinating contrast: the electric field response of the binding strength of *OCHO on Sn-N4-C and polyatomic Sn exhibits opposite behaviors due to their differing dipole moment changes upon *OCHO formation. Such response leads to an intriguing opposite pH-dependent volcano evolution for Sn-N4-C and polyatomic Sn. Subsequent experimental validations of turnover frequency and current density under both neutral and alkaline conditions well aligned with our theoretical predictions. Most importantly, our analysis suggests the necessity of distinct optimization strategies for *OCHO binding energy on different types of Sn-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Wang, Di Zhang, Bin Sun, Xue Jia, Linda Zhang, Hefeng Cheng, Jun Fan, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-38nl4-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure-Activity Relationship Of Small Organic Molecule Functionalized Bi-Based Heterogeneous Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Reduction of Co2 to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5036499</link>
      <description>Yan Li, Lei Zhu, Junping Niu, Yijia Bai, Jianlel Qi, Limin Han, Nianyong Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404789977

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Li, Lei Zhu, Junping Niu, Yijia Bai, Jianlel Qi, Limin Han, Nianyong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5036499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper electrocatalyst modified with pyridinium-based ionic liquids for the efficient synthesis of ethylene through electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158067</link>
      <description>Ruining He, Kelei Huang, Xiantao Yang, Jing Xu, Zhangfa Tong, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404710371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruining He, Kelei Huang, Xiantao Yang, Jing Xu, Zhangfa Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal Synergistic Effect and Categorized Management Policy of CO2 and Air Pollutant Reduction and Economic Growth Under China&#8217;s Interregional Trade</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/systems12120520</link>
      <description>Li Bai, Long Lei Dong, Qian Li, Zhiguang Qu, Fei Li, Systems. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404694750

                In this study, we utilized multi-regional input&#8211;output (MRIO) tables from 2012 to 2017 to determine the spatiotemporal characteristics of CO2 emissions, air pollutant emissions, and value added associated with trade in different regions and industries, as well as the level of coupling coordination among them. Secondly, structural decomposition analysis (SDA) was used to identify the drivers of changes in the above indicators at the regional level. The results show that consumption-based emissions exceeded those based on production in developed regions such as Jing-Jin and the eastern coastal regions, while the opposite occurred in energy hubs such as the northern coastal and central regions; the results of the value added show higher levels in production areas than in consumption areas in the eastern coastal regions, while the opposite trend was observed in the northwestern regions. In different industries, energy production and heavy manufacturing contributed significantly to CO2, PM2.5, and SO2 emissions, while the service industry contributed more to NOx and VOC emissions and value added. The relationships among the changes in the three consumption-based indicators were divided into four categories: positive synergies, negative synergies, trade-offs A, and trade-offs B. Recommendations for targeted collaborative management strategies were delineated based on a regional resource-driven classification.</description>
      <author>Li Bai, Long Lei Dong, Qian Li, Zhiguang Qu, Fei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/systems12120520</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the performance of g-C3N4 loaded silver nanoparticles (Ag4, Ag8, Ag13) catalysts and their electrocatalytic reduction mechanism of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114705</link>
      <description>Xin-Long Zhang, Ya-Yuan Shi, Xiao&#8208;Min Liang, Laicai Li, Molecular Catalysis. 571(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404678818

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin-Long Zhang, Ya-Yuan Shi, Xiao&#8208;Min Liang, Laicai Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C2 Product Selectivity by 2D&#8208;Nanosheet of Layered Zn&#8208;doped Cu2(OH)3(NO3)&#8208; A Pre&#8208;Catalyst for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400566</link>
      <description>Pankaj Kumar Singh, Jyotika Thakur, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, A. K. Gautam, Shyam Kumar Masakapalli, Sudhanshu Sharma, Aditi Halder, ChemPlusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404805678

                The natural carbon cycle cannot mitigate and recycle the excess CO2 in the atmosphere, leading to a continuous rise in the global temperature. Electrochemical conversion of CO2 is one of the useful methods to utilise this anthropogenic CO2 and convert it into value&#8208;added chemicals. However, this process suffers the challenges of product selectivity and good Faradaic efficiency. In our current work, we report the role of Zn&#8208;doping in the 2D&#8208;Nanosheet of Cu2(OH)3(NO3)&#8208; a pre&#8208;catalyst that undergoes the in situ transformation into metallic state along with surface reconstruction. Our studies show, in the aqueous medium, the optimum amount of Zn plays a crucial role in the production of ethanol with the Faradaic efficiency of &#8764;45.2% though C&#8208;C coupling. Temperature&#8208;programmed desorption studies conclude that Zn increases the product selectivity for CO adsorption on Cu2(OH)3(NO3) nanosheets, further facilitating the C&#8208;C coupling at higher negative potential. The detailed XPS studies also reveal that the in&#8208;situ conversion of Cu2+ to Cu0 and Cu+ at negative potential contributes to the production of C2 products. The post&#8208;catalytic microstructural and spectroscopic studies converge to this point that cumulative effect of oxidation state, surface reconstruction, as well as the presence of Zn modulates overall Faradaic efficiency for ethanol formation.</description>
      <author>Pankaj Kumar Singh, Jyotika Thakur, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, A. K. Gautam, Shyam Kumar Masakapalli, Sudhanshu Sharma, Aditi Halder</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Forecast and Optimization of Geological Co2 Storage in Deep Saline Aquifers: A Data-Driven Dynamic Mode Decomposition Model Order Reduction Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5034410</link>
      <description>Dimitrios Voulanas, Eduardo Gildin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404720996

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dimitrios Voulanas, Eduardo Gildin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5034410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Path to Energy Savings and CO2 Emission Reductions in China's Industrial Sector from the Perspective of Factor Price Distortions Correction - Based on an Extended Capital Vintage Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.134004</link>
      <description>Jiangchuan Xu, En&#8208;Ze Wang, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404799648

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiangchuan Xu, En&#8208;Ze Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.134004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public demand for carbon capture and storage varies with information, development magnitude and prior familiarity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01900-y</link>
      <description>Jiwon Kim, Jacob Ladenburg, Communications Earth &amp; Environment. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404672587

                Carbon capture and storage is vital to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, albeit research on the public willingness to pay for it remains limited. Here we address this gap by considering information effects, development magnitude effects and prior familiarity relations on willingness to pay towards carbon capture and storage. Based on national-wide online survey targeting Danish public, conducted from June to August 2022, the contingent valuation method is employed. The study reveals that, irrespective of CO2 reduction goals, enhancing familiarity with carbon capture storage can influence public support. Additionally, we estimate willingness to pay elasticities related to development magnitude using a scope test, ensuring economic significance and validity of our findings. Ultimately, this study provides valuable insights for policymakers and stakeholders, supporting and enabling the design of effective strategies to promote public support for carbon capture and storage, and contribute to global climate change mitigation efforts. Regardless of Denmark's carbon dioxide emission reduction goal, knowledge and familiarity influence public support and willingness to pay for carbon capture and storage, according to an online survey and econometric model analysis.</description>
      <author>Jiwon Kim, Jacob Ladenburg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01900-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting CO2 Electroreduction over ion&#8208;exchange resin&#8208;derived Ni&#8208;N&#8208;C catalyst with sulfur doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401250</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Qiyu Zhang, Chenxu Wang, Ayeza Ayeza, Yating Zhang, Chao Hu, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404772547

                The utilization of renewable energy for electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) represents a pivotal technology in sustainable carbon conversion. Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) featuring transition metal&#8208;nitrogen&#8208;carbon (M&#8208;N&#8208;C) structures have demonstrated exceptional electrocatalytic efficacy in CO2RR by maximizing atom efficiency. Nevertheless, further investigation is warranted to optimize the catalytic performance of SACs through the selection of suitable carbon sources and supports, as well as the modulation of the microenvironment surrounding individual metal atoms. In this study, a sulfur&#8208;doped Ni&#8208;N&#8208;C catalyst was prepared using a two&#8208;step strategy involving metal ion adsorption and thermal decomposition, with porous ion exchange resin serving as the carbon source. Due to the uniform distribution of single atom active centers on the resin&#8208;based carbon support and sulfur doping, this catalyst efficiently converts CO2 into CO with a Faradaic efficiency exceeding 90% within the range of &#8722;0.79 ~ &#8722;1.29 V (vs. RHE), reaching a maximum value of 97.7% (&#8722;0.79 V vs. RHE). Theoretical calculations indicate that second&#8208;shell sulfur doping effectively promotes coupled transfer of protons and electrons, leading to a significant reduction in Gibbs free energy barriers for CO2RR intermediate products.</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Qiyu Zhang, Chenxu Wang, Ayeza Ayeza, Yating Zhang, Chao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategies for Minimizing Greenhouse Gas Emissions in Agriculture through Sustainable Practices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/jabb/2024/v27i111700</link>
      <description>Sahil Raj, Yumkhaibam Ambika Devi, Munish Kaundal, Journal of Advances in Biology &amp; Biotechnology. 27(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404640898

                The growing global population has resulted in an increased demand for agricultural products. The second-largest source of releases of greenhouse gases is agriculture, which includes land use, agricultural production, and animal husbandry. Consequently, there has been a rise in GHG emissions. The three main greenhouse pollutants (often referred to as GHGs) that are contributing to the phenomenon of global warming and its many catastrophic effects are carbon dioxide (CO2), nitrous oxide (N2O), and methane (CH4). Despite being generated in lesser amounts than the greenhouse gas carbon dioxide (CO2), methane (CH4), and the gases nitrous oxide (N2O) have a higher potential to contribute to global warming. This paper presents an extensive review on the factors affecting greenhouse gas emissions, including organic (crop species, animal dung, composted manure, and biosolids) and inorganic (such as fertilizers containing phosphate, nitrogen, and potassium) variables. Major sources of agricultural GHG emissions include agricultural soils, field burning of agricultural wastes, enteric fermentation, manure management, and liming. Strategies to mitigate GHG emissions from agriculture encompass improving crop residue management, enhancing nitrogen use efficiency in plants, optimizing nutrient management, implementing sustainable livestock production and feeding practices, adopting climate-smart agriculture, and reducing methane emissions. This paper deals with the future trends in carbon reduction.</description>
      <author>Sahil Raj, Yumkhaibam Ambika Devi, Munish Kaundal</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.9734/jabb/2024/v27i111700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating direct air capture of carbon dioxide using alkali dosed biochar-based adsorbent</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2631-8695/ad97a1</link>
      <description>Thananat Lungkadee, Sanphawat Phromphithak, Tossapon Katongtung, Suparit Tangparitkul, Chatchawan Chaichana, Nakorn Tippayawong, Engineering Research Express. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404734662

                Abstract As a response to the urgent need for global climate change mitigation, negative emissions technologies have gained widespread recognition as essential tools for achieving climate goals. Among these technologies, direct air capture (DAC) and biochar are considered promising methods for carbon capture, contributing to the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions into the atmosphere. Biochar stands out as an environmentally friendly and cost-effective adsorbent for DAC. While both DAC and biochar technologies have undergone extensive research, limited attention has been given to the potential of using alkali-dosed biochar as a sorbent for DAC, with most validation conducted at laboratory level. This study focuses on the DAC of CO2 using a KOH-dosed biochar-based adsorbent and introduces a mobile prototype designed to accommodate a portable biochar filter. Our research explores the viability of this innovative approach for carbon capture, offering a possible solution for sectors with limited financial resources and the public.</description>
      <author>Thananat Lungkadee, Sanphawat Phromphithak, Tossapon Katongtung, Suparit Tangparitkul, Chatchawan Chaichana, Nakorn Tippayawong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2631-8695/ad97a1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of CO2, CS2, and COS by &#945;&#8208;Diimine&#8208;stabilized Gallylenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403652</link>
      <description>Meng Guo, Ben Dong, Yao Qu, Zhen-Zhou Sun, Li Yang, Yanchao Wang, Xiao&#8208;Juan Yang, Igor L. Fedushkin, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404644302

                Several gallylenes [LPhGaM(THF)n] stabilized by an &#945;&#8208;diimine ligand (LPh = [(2,6&#8208;iPr2C6H3)NC(Ph)]2; M = Li, n = 3, 3&#8208;Li; M = Na, n = 4, 3&#8208;Na; M = K, n = 1, 3&#8208;K) were prepared, which display diverse reactivities toward carbon dioxide and its sulfurized analogues. The reaction of 3 with CO2 yielded a trimeric carbonate complex [{LPhGa(CO3)2}3{&#956;&#8208;K9(THF)6}] (4) and a dinuclear oxo&#8208;carbonate complex {K2(THF)6}[LPhGa(&#956;&#8208;CO3)(&#956;&#8208;O)GaLPh] (5) in one pot through reductive disproportionation of CO2. For CS2, two ethenetetrathiolate gallium complexes, [M2(Solv)4][LPhGa(&#956;&#8208;C2S4)GaLPh] (M = Na, Solv = THF, 6; M = K, Solv = DME, 7), were obtained via reductive coupling of CS2. In the case of COS, disproportionation gave a disulfide&#8208;bridged complex [K2(THF)5] [LPhGa(&#956;&#8208;S)2GaLPh] (8) at room temperature, but a dithiocarbonate [Na2(THF)6][LPhGa(S2CO)]2 (9) at low temperature, the latter being the first example of dithiocarbonates of p&#8208;block elements.</description>
      <author>Meng Guo, Ben Dong, Yao Qu, Zhen-Zhou Sun, Li Yang, Yanchao Wang, Xiao&#8208;Juan Yang, Igor L. Fedushkin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403652</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility Assessment for the Application of Carbon Capture Systems Onboard Cargo Ships in Response to the EU ETS Regulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3233/pmst240009</link>
      <description>Valentina Bortuzzo, Serena Bertagna, Alberto Marin&#243;, Vittorio Bucci, Progress in marine science and technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404769134

                The role of the maritime industry in reducing greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions to mitigate the effects of global warming is significant. The International Maritime Organization (IMO) has set a specific target for the industry, but the challenge is to implement emission-reducing technologies at scale. The use of fossil fuels is still dominant in the shipping sector, also due to the significant barriers that hinder the full adoption of carbon-neutral alternative fuels. The transition to a low-carbon economy presents an opportunity for the industry to lead the way towards a sustainable innovation and demonstrate a commitment to reducing its environmental impact. In this context, Carbon Capture System (CCS) technologies have been identified as a promising solution, but their implementation on ships comes with its own set of challenges. In this paper, the authors aims at exploring the technical requirements and consequences of the installation of a CCS based on the use of Calcium Hydroxide (Ca(OH)2) onboard a container ship. To validate their assumptions, the authors set up a simulation tool able to evaluate the potential reduction in Carbon Dioxide (CO2) emissions from the ship along a selected route. On the basis of the tool outcomes, the authors were able to provide a comprehensive analysis of the proposed system&#8217;s costs and benefits, emphasizing the considerable savings that could be attained through the implementation of this technology on board cargo ships with a specific consideration to the future implementation of carbon emission taxes and a focus on the European Union Emission Trading System (EU ETS) regulation. The findings of this research offer valuable perspectives on creating more effective and environmentally friendly approaches to mitigate GHG in the maritime sector.</description>
      <author>Valentina Bortuzzo, Serena Bertagna, Alberto Marin&#243;, Vittorio Bucci</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3233/pmst240009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Double Layer Dynamics for CO2 Electroreduction over Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-pzpd0</link>
      <description>Daniel Sinausia, Noam Zisser, Thierry K. Slot, David Eisenberg, Florian Meirer, Charlotte Vogt, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404760756

                Understanding of the nature and role of the electric double layer (EDL) at electrocatalytic interfaces, and its dynamic evolution, is critical to optimizing electrochemical processes such as the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). Despite its postulated significant influence on CO2RR activity, direct spectroscopic evidence of the complex interplay between EDL structure and reaction kinetics has remained elusive. Here, we introduce Dynamic Response Spectroscopy (DRS), a novel approach that isolates spectroscopic signatures of key physicochemical features of the EDL, including the compact (interfacial) layer and the diffuse double layer based on their time-variance profiles. By analyzing multi dimensional time-variance within a matrix of time-resolved infrared spectral data recorded during sequential potential steps, we reveal that EDL equilibration is not continuous but involves discrete restructuring events. We correlate these sudden EDL reorganizations with the rapid adsorption and conversion of CO2 to CO, providing - to the best of our knowledge - the first direct spectroscopic evidence of such a phenomenon. Furthermore, we show that saturation of aqueous NaHCO3 electrolytes with CO2, as opposed to Ar, induces more frequent and pronounced water reorientation in the diffuse double layer, characterized by less ice-like ordering and increased randomness. These findings provide novel insights into the dynamic nature of the EDL and its synergistic role in electrocatalysis, establishing a paradigm to better understand, and thus optimize electrochemical systems.</description>
      <author>Daniel Sinausia, Noam Zisser, Thierry K. Slot, David Eisenberg, Florian Meirer, Charlotte Vogt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-pzpd0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Microbubbles in Silicone Oil (Part II: Henry&#8217;s Constant and Anomalous Diffusion)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02020</link>
      <description>A. D&#8217;Onofrio, V. M. Freytes, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404640014

                This work demonstrates the utility of microfluidic devices for characterizing diffusion mechanisms. We determined Henry's constant and characterized the diffusion process of gaseous CO2 in silicone oil. Using microfluidic techniques, we analyzed the evolution of the CO2 bubble size in a solvent flowing through a microchannel system. The reduction in bubble size due to the mass transfer of gaseous CO2 into the solvent fluid primarily affects their length. A microfluidic device was used to produce bubbles, consisting of a pressure-driven injection system for the gas and a flow-driven system for the liquid. Additionally, an optical device was coupled for tracking and studying the bubbles in the microchannels, enabling us to study their spatial and temporal evolution using image analysis. From this study, we found two diffusion regimes. The first is a superdiffusive process for short times. In this regime, due to the high concentration gradient values at the gas&#8211;liquid interface, we observed a higher rate of carbon dioxide transfer to the silicone oil. At longer times, we see that the gas transfer rate significantly decreases compared to the previous regime, leading to a subdiffusive process. In this latter regime, it was found that if we increase the gas pressure, the system approaches a normal diffusive process that coincides with previously conducted studies by other researchers. It is suggested that the subdiffusion could be due to the high degree of confinement of the bubbles within the microchannel, similar to what occurs in porous media, the high viscosity of the fluid, and the low gas pressure used in the tests. The microfluidic device proved to be a very efficient method for determining the diffusion process and Henry's constant in this case. Its easy fabrication and low cost make this type of device appropriate for substance characterization.</description>
      <author>A. D&#8217;Onofrio, V. M. Freytes</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A hybrid modelling approach to compare chemical separation technologies in terms of energy consumption and carbon dioxide emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01668-7</link>
      <description>Gerg&#337; Ign&#225;cz, Aron K. Beke, Viktor T&#243;th, Gy&#246;rgy Sz&#233;kely, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404764703

                Abstract Accurate energy system modelling of chemical separations is a critical component of technology selection to minimize operating costs, energy consumption and emissions. Here we report a hybrid modelling approach based on data-driven and mechanistic models to holistically compare chemical separation performance. Our model can be used to select the most suitable technology for a given chemical separation, such as membrane separation, evaporation, extraction or hybrid configurations, by training a machine learning model to predict solute rejection using an open-access membrane dataset. We estimated an average 40% reduction in energy consumption and carbon dioxide emissions for industrially relevant separations using our methodology. We predicted and analysed 7.1 million solute rejections across several industrial sectors. Pharmaceutical purification could realize carbon dioxide emissions reductions of up to 90% by selecting the most efficient technology. We mapped the reduction in carbon dioxide emissions and the reduction in operating costs globally, establishing parameter thresholds to facilitate corporate and governmental decision-making.</description>
      <author>Gerg&#337; Ign&#225;cz, Aron K. Beke, Viktor T&#243;th, Gy&#246;rgy Sz&#233;kely</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01668-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Synergistic Effect of Pore Architect and Reducibility in Ceria-Promoted Ni Molecular Sieve for Methane Dry Reforming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120852</link>
      <description>Norah Alwadai, Abdulaziz A.M. Abahussain, Vijay Shrivastava, Salma A. Al&#8208;Zahrani, Anis H. Fakeeha, Naif Alarifi, Mohammed O. Bayazed, Khaled M. Banabdwin, Rawesh Kumar, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404690765

                Methane and carbon dioxide, the primary contributors to global warming, are now at critical levels, threatening the extinction of numerous organisms on our planet. In this regard, dry reforming of methane reactions have gained considerable attention because of the conversion capacity of CH4 and CO2 into synthetic/energy-important syngas (H2 and CO). Herein, a molecular sieve (CBV3024E; SiO2/Al2O3 = 30) with ZSM-8-type pore architect, is utilized as the support for the active site of Ni and Ce promoters. Catalysts are characterized by surface area and porosity, X-ray diffraction study, Raman and infrared spectroscopy, thermogravimetry analysis, and temperature-programmed reduction/desorption techniques. A total of 2 wt.% ceria is added over 5Ni/CBV3024E to induce the optimum connectivity of aluminum in the silicate framework. NiO residing in these porous cages are mostly under &#8220;prominent interaction with support&#8221; which is reduced easily into metallic Ni as the active sites for DRM reactions. The active sites over 5Ni2Ce/CBV3024E remain stable during the DRM reaction and achieve ~58% H2 yield after 300 min TOS at 42,000 mL/(gcat.h) GHSV and ~70% H2 yield after 20 h at 26,000 mL/(gcat.h) GHSV. The high activity after a longer time stream justifies using CBV3024E molecular sieves as the support and ceria as the promoter for Ni-based catalyst towards the DRM reaction.</description>
      <author>Norah Alwadai, Abdulaziz A.M. Abahussain, Vijay Shrivastava, Salma A. Al&#8208;Zahrani, Anis H. Fakeeha, Naif Alarifi, Mohammed O. Bayazed, Khaled M. Banabdwin, Rawesh Kumar, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Real-Time Accounting Method for Carbon Dioxide Emissions in High-Energy-Consuming Industrial Parks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12122657</link>
      <description>Hongli Liu, Lianfang Xie, Wei Yang, Yumin Chen, Xueyuan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Deming Liu, Q. X. Li, Processes. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404695716

                Industrial parks play a crucial role in carbon control and reduction. With energy-intensive enterprises at their core, such parks feature highly concentrated carbon emission sources and a significant demand for carbon trading. Nonetheless, the absence of precise and real-time carbon accounting methods makes it difficult for them to effectively manage and regulate carbon emissions. The real-time accounting methods for carbon dioxide emissions in high-energy-consuming industrial parks urgently need further study. Therefore, this paper initially examines three areas&#8212;fuel combustion, industrial engineering, and electricity usage&#8212;and proposes a real-time framework to account for carbon dioxide emissions in high-energy industrial parks. Secondly, it extracts real-time elements from each part and proposes a real-time carbon dioxide emission accounting method tailored to the actual needs of high-energy-consuming industrial parks. Finally, an empirical analysis is carried out on an aluminum production park as an example to verify the feasibility and effectiveness of the real-time accounting method for carbon dioxide emissions in high-energy-consuming industrial parks.</description>
      <author>Hongli Liu, Lianfang Xie, Wei Yang, Yumin Chen, Xueyuan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Deming Liu, Q. X. Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12122657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoters of Carbon Dioxide Hydrate Formation Derived from Citric and Amino Acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26907/2542-064x.2024.4.640-657</link>
      <description>Shamil E. Gainullin, P. Yu. Kazakova, Roman S. Pavelyev, V. M. Tavochkin, Mikhail A. Varfolomeev, U&#269;&#235;nye zapiski Kazanskogo universiteta. Seri&#226;  Estestvennye nauki/U&#269;&#235;nye zapiski Kazanskogo universiteta. Seri&#226; Estestvennye nauki/U&#269;enye zapiski Kazanskogo gosudarstvennogo universiteta. Seri&#226; Estestvennye nauki. 166(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404767392

                Novel amides of some amino and citric acids were synthesized and studied for their ability to improve the kinetics of carbon dioxide hydrate formation. It was demonstrated that these compounds can be effective promoters of hydrate formation, even at low concentrations. The addition of citric acid and norleucine amide (CTR+Nle) increased the water-to-hydrate conversion and significantly reduced the induction time. At a concentration of 0.05 wt. %, the conversion rate reached 57 &#177; 3 %, which is 21 and 3.1 % higher than in water without additives and sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS) solution, respectively. In the presence of CTR+Nle, the induction time decreased to 35 min, which is an 8.1-fold reduction compared to water without additives, as well as 5.8-fold less than with tryptophan solution known as a promoter of carbon dioxide hydrate formation.</description>
      <author>Shamil E. Gainullin, P. Yu. Kazakova, Roman S. Pavelyev, V. M. Tavochkin, Mikhail A. Varfolomeev</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26907/2542-064x.2024.4.640-657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protection Materials on III&#8211;V Semiconductors for Photoelectrochemical CO Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04782</link>
      <description>K.&#8208;H. Naumann, Tim Tichter, Rasmus Nielsen, Brian Seger, Ole Hansen, Ib Chorkendorff, Peter C. K. Vesborg, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404697380

                Tantalum oxide (TaOx) and amorphous titanium dioxide (TiO2) are employed as protection materials for commercial GaInP/GaAs/Ge triple-junction solar cells to facilitate the unbiased photoelectrochemical reduction of carbon monoxide on nanostructured copper particles. It has been found that a photoelectrode protected by a 150 nm-thick layer of TiO2, capped with 8 nm TaOx, and decorated with copper nanocubes in the size of 150 nm can successfully drive the photoelectrochemical conversion of carbon monoxide to ethylene. Implemented into a photoelectrochemical flow reactor, which continuously supplies the active interface with CO-saturated electrolyte, the device achieves a faradaic efficiency of 24% under AM1.5G conditions. Direct attachment of the copper nanocubes to a protection layer of TiO2 in the absence of TaOx results in a strong hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and no CO reduction products are found. This unexpected loss in selectivity is studied via post-operando X-ray photoemission spectroscopy and ion-scattering spectroscopy. No modifications in the redox state of TiO2 or signs of H intercalation are found, while the preferential redeposition of small Cu nanoparticles is considered possible. This increase in HER appears specific for TiO2, as additional, purely electroanalytical experiments using tantalum oxide or carbon as a support layer for Cu nanocubes can produce ethylene effectively.</description>
      <author>K.&#8208;H. Naumann, Tim Tichter, Rasmus Nielsen, Brian Seger, Ole Hansen, Ib Chorkendorff, Peter C. K. Vesborg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04782</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Empirical Analysis on the Use of Sustainable Fuels in the Aviation Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.23890/ijast.vm05is02.0202</link>
      <description>Ya&#351;ar K&#214;SE, Emre O&#287;uzhan Polat, International Journal of Aviation Science and Technology. vm05(is02)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404756904

                This study aims to analyze and evaluate different types of alternative fuels for aviation from a life cycle and cost perspective. It aims to analyze different alternative fuels and their use in aircraft for this purpose in the aviation sector in relation to their potential to be a suitable transition solution towards sustainable transformation. Using the GREET (Greenhouse gases, Regulated Emissions, and Energy use in Technologies) aviation module developed by the US National Research Laboratory (Argonne), the life cycles of petroleum and six different sustainable aviation fuel production methods were calculated, and the environmental impact of kerosene and sustainable aviation fuels in terms of cost and carbon dioxide emissions on long, medium and short-haul flights were analyzed. The life cycle values of carbon dioxide formed as a result of the production of corn, soybean and canola products, which are the most preferred to produce biofuel in the aviation industry, with hydro-processed esters and fatty acids (HEFA), alcohol-to-jet (ATJ), ethanol-to-jet (ETJ) methods, were calculated. As a result of the study, it was determined that the cost of the sustainable aviation fuels examined was higher than fossil fuel. The key to greater acceptance and deployment of sustainable aviation fuel is cost reduction. In the long term, this will require investment in advanced technologies to process feedstocks more efficiently on a larger scale and in the development of sustainable and scalable feedstock options. However, in the short term, temporary support from governments and other stakeholders through policy incentives is needed.</description>
      <author>Ya&#351;ar K&#214;SE, Emre O&#287;uzhan Polat</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.23890/ijast.vm05is02.0202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Oltu Stone (Turbostratic Carbon) from the Olur-Tortum Area: A Natural Composite Carbonaceous Material (Erzurum, T&#252;rkiye)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25288/tjb.1491493</link>
      <description>Cahit Helvac&#305;, Murat Hatipo&#287;lu, Daniele Passeri, Ne&#351;at Konak, Eyy&#252;p Hikmet K&#305;nac&#305;, T&#252;rkiye Jeoloji B&#252;lteni / Geological Bulletin of Turkey. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404738441

                This study focuses on geological, microstructural, oxygen isotopic, and thermogravimetric investigations of Oltu stone, which is the most important turbostratic carbonaceous material in Turkey. The results of our investigations indicate that the carbonaceous Oltu stone material (specific gravity of 1.317) is not an organic material, such as jet, derived from fossilized wood. Rather, it is composed of a carbonaceous phase intermediate between amorphous carbon and crystallized graphite (termed turbostratic carbon), that is intercalated with flysch and formed by the reduction of seeping magmatic carbon dioxide during the diagenesis of Upper Jurassic-Lower Cretaceous marine sediments. Oxygen isotope analyses (SMOW) (using EA-IRMS) of both Oltu stone (&#948;18O = +37.2&#8240;to +40.8&#8240;) and the enclosing flysches (&#948;18O = +10.3&#8240; to +12.3&#8240;) suggest that the nodules formed during diagenesis at a temperature of around 50 &#8451;. However, they are enclosed in flysches whose grains are derived from rocks that formed at significantly higher temperatures, perhaps above 100 &#8451;. The main industrial use of Oltu stone is as host material for diamond coating, as the sp3 bonds in the material can provide nucleation sites for diamond crystals and improve the nucleation rate at the early stage of diamond deposition on turbostratic carbon.</description>
      <author>Cahit Helvac&#305;, Murat Hatipo&#287;lu, Daniele Passeri, Ne&#351;at Konak, Eyy&#252;p Hikmet K&#305;nac&#305;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25288/tjb.1491493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved estimates of net ecosystem exchanges in mega-countries using GOSAT and OCO-2 observations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01910-w</link>
      <description>Lingyu Zhang, Fei Jiang, Wei He, Mousong Wu, Jun Wang, Weimin Ju, Hengmao Wang, Yongguang Zhang, Stephen Sitch, Jing M. Chen, Communications Earth &amp; Environment. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404665124

                Accurate national terrestrial net ecosystem exchange estimates are crucial for the global stocktake. Net ecosystem exchange estimates from different inversion models vary greatly at national scale, and the relative impacts of prior fluxes and observations on these inversions remain unclear. Here we estimate the net ecosystem exchange of 51 land regions for the 2017-2019 period, focusing on the 10 largest countries, using prior fluxes from 12 terrestrial biosphere models and XCO2 retrievals from GOSAT and OCO-2 satellites as constraints. The average uncertainty reduction for the 10 countries increases from 37% with GOSAT and 45% with OCO-2 to 50% with combined observations, indicating a trend towards robust estimates. At finer spatial scales, even with combined observations, the uncertainty reduction is only 33%, i.e., the prior flux dominates the estimates. This finding underscores the critical importance of integrating multi-source observations and refining prior fluxes to improve the accuracy of carbon flux estimates. Choice of ecosystem model and input satellite data has a significant impact on modelled carbon dioxide flux and its associated uncertainty for large countries, according to atmospheric inversions using GOSAT and OCO-2 data.</description>
      <author>Lingyu Zhang, Fei Jiang, Wei He, Mousong Wu, Jun Wang, Weimin Ju, Hengmao Wang, Yongguang Zhang, Stephen Sitch, Jing M. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01910-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of the Art of Residential Building Energy Retrofits in Libya and Neighbouring Mediterranean Countries: A Systematic Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202411.1864.v1</link>
      <description>Salwa Albarssi, Shan Shan Hou, Eshrar Latif, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404685526

                With the increasing concern about global warming and future climate change, attention has been drawn to the need to reduce building energy use through improving buildings&#8217; energy efficiency. Existing residential buildings constitute the largest percentage of energy demand and carbon dioxide emissions, and hence offer significant potential for energy savings and reductions in greenhouse gas emissions. The review aims to determine the most widely considered energy-efficiency measures for retrofitting existing residential buildings in Mediterranean countries and to determine the research methods and tools adopted in current research work for retrofitting existing residential buildings. This will help to identify potential areas of intervention to improve the energy efficiency of existing residential stock in Libya. This study systematically reviews the literature focusing on energy retrofit in residential buildings in Mediterranean countries, with a particular focus on the Libyan context. Forty- four publications of high relevance to the subject area are analysed under identified themes. The results reveal that while energy retrofitting is a research area of interest in the region considered, studies in a Libyan context are limited. There is also limited attention to achieving net zero energy and embodied carbon reductions, including in the Libyan context. Moreover, some weaknesses are identified for most of the studies reviewed, including those in the Libyan context, related to the credibility and reliability of the energy models.</description>
      <author>Salwa Albarssi, Shan Shan Hou, Eshrar Latif</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202411.1864.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenhouse gas emission driving factors and reduction strategies for operational phase of urban rail transit in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.14528</link>
      <description>Hao Guo, Environmental Progress &amp; Sustainable Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404696628

                Abstract To promote the sustainable development of urban rail transit (URT) in China, it is necessary to quantitatively analyze the greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions and its internal driving factors. Based on the LMDI algorithm, this research constructs an assessment model and makes a quantitative analysis of internal driving factors for GHG emissions in the operational phase of the URT system in China. According to the official investigated data, the GHG emission of URT in the operational phase is between 600 &#215; 10 4 and 2000 &#215; 10 4 tons of carbon dioxide equivalent (CO 2 e) per year from 2012 to 2023. The results of the driving factors decomposition showed that the passenger demand intensity was the key and positive factor affecting carbon emissions in the operational phase and the contribution rate was 12.93%&#8211;60.81% from 2013 to 2023. Therefore, it is necessary to formulate targeted policies in terms of management and technical means to reduce the average traveling distance demanded by passengers and reasonably control the scale of the line network for GHG reduction in the Chinese URT system.</description>
      <author>Hao Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.14528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Tourists&#8217; Summer Vacations Save Energy and Reduce CO2 Emissions? Evidence from China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15121414</link>
      <description>Puwei Zhang, Xiujiang Li, Meixuan Ren, Rui Li, Xin Gao, Atmosphere. 15(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404692561

                This study develops a methodological framework for measuring energy conservation and CO2 emission reductions that considers both origins and destinations. The framework encompasses four key aspects: transportation, accommodation, cooking, and housing rehabilitation. Data were collected through a literature review, questionnaire surveys, and field measurement tracking. Compared to living in the origin, senior tourists from Nanchang visiting Zhongyuan Township in China for summer tourism can save 5.747 MJ of energy and reduce CO2 emissions by 3.303 kg per capita per day. An in-depth analysis indicated that the research site could further enhance energy conservation and reduce CO2 emissions by improving public transportation services, optimizing the energy structure of the destination, and diversifying the available recreational offerings. Depending on the characteristics of the destination and the primary origin, summer or winter tourism in various countries or regions can employ the methodological framework to evaluate energy conservation and CO2 emission reductions after identifying specific parameters. The improved pathways identified through this research can serve as a checklist for other countries or regions aiming to explore energy conservation and CO2-emission-reduction pathways for summer or winter tourism. Enhancing climate-driven tourism development may offer a new avenue for the tourism industry to contribute to carbon reduction targets.</description>
      <author>Puwei Zhang, Xiujiang Li, Meixuan Ren, Rui Li, Xin Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15121414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Asymmetric Cu Catalytic Sites for CO2 Electroreduction with Higher Selectivity to C2 Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402120</link>
      <description>Fanfei Meng, Xiaohui Yao, Jingting He, Jianxia Gu, Wei Li, Chunyi Sun, Sheng Wang, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404728889

                The design of catalytic sites with tunable properties is considered a promising approach to advance the reduction of CO2 into valuable fuels and chemicals, as well as to achieve carbon neutrality. However, significant challenges remain in precisely constructing catalytic sites to adjust target reduction products. In this study, catalysts were derived from metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) with different coordination environments during the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR), referred to as Cu&#8208;N2O2 and Cu&#8208;N2O3, respectively. Higher selectivity towards the production of C2 products was exhibited by the Cu&#8208;N2O2&#8208;derived catalysts, characterized by asymmetric catalytic centers of Cu0 and Cu+, compared to the Cu&#8208;N2O3&#8208;derived catalysts, which contained only symmetric catalytic centers of Cu0 sites. This enhanced selectivity is attributed to the synergistic interaction between the Cu0 and Cu+ sites, facilitating the multi&#8208;electron transfer process and improving the activation of CO2. This study explores how the coordination environment affects the catalytic performance of catalysts derived from MOFs, providing valuable insights for the development of more effective catalysts aimed at CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Fanfei Meng, Xiaohui Yao, Jingting He, Jianxia Gu, Wei Li, Chunyi Sun, Sheng Wang, Zhong&#8208;Min Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Nanocomposites in Covalent Organic Framework-Based Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14231907</link>
      <description>Haiping Zhou, Kechang Li, Qingqing Pan, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Rui Wang, Nanomaterials. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404756219

                In recent years, the development of high-performance electrocatalysts for energy conversion and environmental remediation has become a topic of great interest. Covalent organic frameworks (COFs), linked by covalent bonds, have emerged as promising materials in the field of electrocatalysis due to their well-defined structures, high specific surface areas, tunable pore structures, and excellent acid&#8211;base stability. However, the low conductivity of COF materials often limits their intrinsic electrocatalytic activity. To enhance the catalytic performance of COF-based catalysts, various nanomaterials are integrated into COFs to form composite catalysts. The stable and tunable porous structure of COFs provides an ideal platform for these nanomaterials, leading to improved electrocatalytic activity. Through rational design, COF-based composite electrocatalysts can achieve synergistic effects between nanomaterials and the COF carrier, enabling efficient targeted electrocatalysis. This review summarizes the applications of nanomaterial-incorporated COF-based catalysts in hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, oxygen reduction, carbon dioxide reduction, and nitrogen reduction. Additionally, it outlines design principles for COF-based composite electrocatalysis, focusing on structure&#8211;activity relationships and synergistic effects in COF composite nanomaterial electrocatalysts, as well as challenges and future perspectives for next-generation composite electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Haiping Zhou, Kechang Li, Qingqing Pan, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Rui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14231907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Interlayered Single-Atom Active Sites on Bipyridine-Based 2D Conjugated Covalent-Organic Frameworks for Boosting the C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Products of Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16371</link>
      <description>Lu Dai, Jianning Lv, Shuo Xu, Jiawen Zong, Lisha Liang, Bo Wang, Pengfei Li, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404742203

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction (eCO2RR) shows great potential in the realization of carbon neutrality, which requires a dedicated catalyst design. To develop electrocatalysts that favor C2 products, herein, the synthetic protocol for engineering interlayered single-atom metal active sites on the bipyridine-linked 2D conjugated covalent-organic framework (2D c-COF) has been developed by utilizing the interlayer &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking. The resultant M@BTT-BPy-COF (where M = Cu, Ni, and Fe) provides fully exposed single-atom active sites with a suitable interdistance for catalyzing the key C&#8211;C coupling in the eCO2RR process. The Faradaic efficiency of ethanol (FEethanol) exceeds 40% with M@BTT-BPy-COF at &#8722;0.8 V vs RHE, outperforming most reported COF-based electrocatalysts. Density functional calculations suggest that the proximal active sites in the pore channel of COFs are the key active sites for promoting the C&#8211;C coupling to generate ethanol product. This investigation presents a novel way to engineer single-atom catalytic centers on 2D c-COFs, displaying the great potential of 2D c-COFs in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Lu Dai, Jianning Lv, Shuo Xu, Jiawen Zong, Lisha Liang, Bo Wang, Pengfei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce3+/Ce4+ Ion Redox Shuttle Stabilized Cu&#948;+ for Efficient CO2 Electroreduction to C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419796</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Ting Liu, Ting Ouyang, Jiguang Deng, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404749084

                The CO2 electroreduction reaction has advantages in clean and pollution&#8208;free carbon conversion, but it still faces challenges in carbon utilization efficiency and improving the selectivity of C2+ products. Although the dynamic Cu&#948;+ state is known to favor the C&#8208;C coupling process, the Cu&#948;+ species suitable for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 are difficult to maintain under the conditions of strong reduction and large current. Herein, we propose a Ce doping strategy (Ce/CuOx) to protect the Cu&#948;+ state in the CO2RR process, which enables a high Faradaic efficiency of 60% for multi&#8208;carbon products (40% for C2H4, 14% for CH3CH2OH, and 6% for CH3COOH), and 25 h stability at &#8208;1.2 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode. In&#8208;situ infrared spectroscopy, in&#8208;situ XPS combined with density functional theory calculations reveal that the Cu&#948;+ is stabilized by the redox ion pairs of Ce, which reduces the energy barrier of *CO coupling, and improves the Faraday efficiency of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction of C2H4. This work provides an idea to make full use of lanthanide variable value metals to maintain the stability of dynamic Cu&#948;+ state and improve the performance of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to C2H4.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Ting Liu, Ting Ouyang, Jiguang Deng, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419796</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental and Theoretical Insights into Single Atoms, Dual Atoms, and Sub&#8208;Nanocluster Catalysts for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR) to High&#8208;Value Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414169</link>
      <description>Abebe Reda Woldu, Asfaw G. Yohannes, Zanling Huang, Pierre Kennepohl, Didier Astruc, Liangsheng Hu, Xiao&#8208;Chun Huang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404777680

                Abstract Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) conversion into valuable chemicals paves the way for the realization of carbon recycling. Downsizing catalysts to single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs), dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs), and sub&#8208;nanocluster catalysts (SNCCs) has generated highly active and selective CO 2 transformation into highly reduced products. This is due to the introduction of numerous active sites, highly unsaturated coordination environments, efficient atom utilization, and confinement effect compared to their nanoparticle counterparts. Herein, recent Cu&#8208;based SACs are first reviewed and the newly emerged DACs and SNCCs expanding the catalysis of SACs to electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction (CO 2 RR) to high&#8208;value products are discussed. Tandem Cu&#8208;based SAC&#8211;nanocatalysts (NCs) (SAC&#8211;NCs) are also discussed for the CO 2 RR to high&#8208;value products. Then, the non&#8208;Cu&#8208;based SACs, DACs, SAC&#8211;NCs, and SNCCs and theoretical calculations of various transition&#8208;metal catalysts for CO 2 RR to high&#8208;value products are summarized. Compared to previous achievements of less&#8208;reduced products, this review focuses on the double objective of achieving full CO 2 reduction and increasing the selectivity and formation rate toward C&#8211;C coupled products with additional emphasis on the stability of the catalysts. Finally, through combined theoretical and experimental research, future outlooks are offered to further develop the CO 2 RR into high&#8208;value products over isolated atoms and sub&#8208;nanometal clusters.</description>
      <author>Abebe Reda Woldu, Asfaw G. Yohannes, Zanling Huang, Pierre Kennepohl, Didier Astruc, Liangsheng Hu, Xiao&#8208;Chun Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce3+/Ce4+ Ion Redox Shuttle Stabilized Cu&#948;+ for Efficient CO2 Electroreduction to C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419796</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Ting Liu, Ting Ouyang, Jiguang Deng, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404749444

                The CO2 electroreduction reaction has advantages in clean and pollution&#8208;free carbon conversion, but it still faces challenges in carbon utilization efficiency and improving the selectivity of C2+ products. Although the dynamic Cu&#948;+ state is known to favor the C&#8208;C coupling process, the Cu&#948;+ species suitable for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 are difficult to maintain under the conditions of strong reduction and large current. Herein, we propose a Ce doping strategy (Ce/CuOx) to protect the Cu&#948;+ state in the CO2RR process, which enables a high Faradaic efficiency of 60% for multi&#8208;carbon products (40% for C2H4, 14% for CH3CH2OH, and 6% for CH3COOH), and 25 h stability at &#8208;1.2 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode. In&#8208;situ infrared spectroscopy, in&#8208;situ XPS combined with density functional theory calculations reveal that the Cu&#948;+ is stabilized by the redox ion pairs of Ce, which reduces the energy barrier of *CO coupling, and improves the Faraday efficiency of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction of C2H4. This work provides an idea to make full use of lanthanide variable value metals to maintain the stability of dynamic Cu&#948;+ state and improve the performance of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to C2H4.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Ting Liu, Ting Ouyang, Jiguang Deng, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419796</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anionic Surfactant-Tuned Interfacial Water Reactivity Promoting Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05541</link>
      <description>Wangxin Ge, Yihua Zhu, Haiyan Wang, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404646427

                The effects of the electrical double layer (EDL), which pertain to the compositions and interactions among electrolyte species, significantly impact the catalytic process. There is a pressing need to investigate the role of electrolyte components and to deepen our understanding of EDL effects. In this study, we tune the water activity within a range of anionic surfactants featuring different functional groups to adjust H2 evolution activity and CO2 reduction selectivity. We demonstrate that these anionic surfactants are active in the local reaction environment under a cathodic potential. The enhanced selectivity of CO2 to CO can be attributed to the robust interfacial hydrogen-bonding network reformed by the anionic surfactants. This network diminishes the water dissociation activity and promotes the hydrogenation step in CO2 reduction. Notably, the electrolyte incorporating anionic surfactants improves the CO2 reduction performance, registering CO Faradaic efficiencies of 89.7% (RSO3&#8211;, SDS), 97.5% (RSO4&#8211;, SLS), 98.4% (RPO42&#8211;, SMP), and 98.9% (RCOO&#8211;, SL) at &#8722;1.2 V versus RHE, thereby outperforming the blank KHCO3 electrolyte (53.1%). This research underscores the crucial influence of anionic additives in the CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Wangxin Ge, Yihua Zhu, Haiyan Wang, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Evaluation of a Recrosslinkable CO2-Resistant Micro-Sized Preformed Particle Gel for CO2 Sweep Efficiency Improvement in Reservoirs with Super-K Channels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/gels10120765</link>
      <description>Adel Alotibi, Tao Song, Ali Al Brahim, Baojun Bai, Thomas Schuman, Gels. 10(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404691615

                A recrosslinkable CO2-resistant branched preformed particle gel (CO2-BRPPG) was developed for controlling CO2 injection conformance, particularly in reservoirs with super-permeable channels. Previous work focused on a millimeter-sized CO2-BRPPG in open fractures, but its performance in high-permeability channels with pore throat networks remained unexplored. This study used a sandpack model to evaluate a micro-sized CO2-BRPPG under varying conditions of salinity, gel concentration, and pH. At ambient conditions, the equilibrium swelling ratio (ESR) of the gel reached 76 times its original size. This ratio decreased with increasing salinity but remained stable at low pH values, demonstrating the gel&#8217;s resilience in acidic environments. Rheological tests revealed shear-thinning behavior, with gel strength improving as salinity increased (the storage modulus rose from 113 Pa in 1% NaCl to 145 Pa in 10% NaCl). Injectivity tests showed that lower gel concentrations reduced the injection pressure, offering flexibility in deep injection treatments. Gels with higher swelling ratios had lower injection pressures due to increased strength and reduced deformability. The gel maintained stable plugging performance during two water-alternating-CO2 cycles, but a decline was observed in the third cycle. It also demonstrated a high CO2 breakthrough pressure of 177 psi in high salinity conditions (10% NaCl). The permeability reduction for water and CO2 was influenced by gel concentration and salinity, with higher salinity increasing the permeability reduction and higher gel concentrations decreasing it. These findings underscore the effectiveness of the CO2-BRPPG in improving CO2 sweep efficiency and managing CO2 sequestration in reservoirs with high permeability.</description>
      <author>Adel Alotibi, Tao Song, Ali Al Brahim, Baojun Bai, Thomas Schuman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/gels10120765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All-in-One CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture and Transformation: Lessons from Formylmethanofuran Dehydrogenases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00623</link>
      <description>Olivier N. Lemaire, Tristan Wagner, Accounts of Chemical Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404668607

                ConspectusCarbon-one-unit (C1) feedstocks are generally used in the chemical synthesis of organic molecules, such as solvents, drugs, polymers, and fuels. Contrary to the dangerous and polluting carbon monoxide mostly coming from fossil fuels, formate and formamide are attractive alternative feedstocks for chemical synthesis. As these are currently mainly obtained from the oil industry, novel synthetic routes have been developed based on the transformation of the greenhouse gas CO2. Such developments are motivated by the urgent need for carbon chemical recycling, leading to a sustainable future. The inert nature of CO2 represents a challenge for chemists to activate and specifically convert the molecule through an affordable and efficient process. The chemical transformation could be inspired by biological CO2 activation, in which highly specialized enzymes perform atmospheric CO2 fixation through relatively abundant metal catalysts. In this Account, we describe and discuss the potential of one of the most efficient biological CO2-converting systems: the formylmethanofuran dehydrogenase (abbreviated as FMD).FMDs are multienzymatic complexes found in archaea that capture CO2 as a formyl group branched on the amine moiety of the methanofuran (MFR) cofactor. This overall reaction leading to formyl&#8722;MFR production does not require ATP hydrolysis as compared to the CO2-fixing microbes relying on the reductive Wood&#8211;Ljungdahl pathway, highlighting a different operative mode that saves cellular energy. FMD reaction represents the entry point in hydrogenotrophic methanogenesis (H2 and CO2 dependent or formate dependent) and operates in reverse in other methanogenic pathways and microbial metabolisms. Therefore, FMD is a key enzyme in the planetary carbon cycle. After decades of investigations, recent studies have provided a description of the FMD structure, reaction mechanism, and potential for the electroreduction of CO2, to which our laboratory has been actively contributing.FMD is an "all-in-one" enzyme catalyzing a redox-active transformation coupled to a redox-neutral transformation at two very different metal cofactors where new C&#8211;H and C&#8211;N bonds are made. First, the principle of the overall reaction consisting of an exergonic CO2 reduction coupled with an endergonic formate condensation on MFR is resumed. Then, this Account exposes the molecular details of the active sites and provides an overview of each catalytic mechanism. It also describes the natural versatility of electron-delivery modules fueling CO2 reduction and extends it to the possibilities of using artificial systems such as electrodes.A perspective concludes on how the mechanistic of FMD could be applied to produce CO2-based chemical intermediates to synthesize organic molecules. Indeed, through its biochemical properties, the enzyme opens opportunities for CO2 electroreduction to generate molecules such as formate and formamide derivatives, which are all intermediates for synthesizing organic compounds. Transferring the chemical knowledge acquired from these biological systems would provide coherent models that can lead to further development in the field of synthetic biology and bio-inspired synthetic chemistry to perform large-scale CO2 conversion into building blocks for chemical synthesis.</description>
      <author>Olivier N. Lemaire, Tristan Wagner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient Tri&#8208;Conductive Electrode for Ethane Direct Electrochemical Dehydrogenation on Proton Ceramic Electrolysis Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409452</link>
      <description>Shixian Zhang, Wang Sun, Chunming Xu, Rongzheng Ren, Jinshuo Qiao, Zhenhua Wang, Kening Sun, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718327

                Abstract The preparation of ethylene from ethane, a main component of shale gas, has become an important process of the petrochemical industry, using ethane steam cracking at high temperatures (&gt;900 &#176;C), which is a highly energy intensive industry. Here, direct dehydrogenation of ethane is engineered electrochemically to produce ethylene and hydrogen in a proton&#8208;conducting electrolysis cell, achieving over 50% ethane conversion and 90.42% ethylene selectivity at 700 &#176;C. On the basis of constructing NiCu bimetallic alloy nano&#8208;catalyst on the surface of perovskite Sr 3 Fe 2 O 7 , Hafnium (Hf) element is doped in the bulk phase to improve proton conductivity, establish triple conductivity, and achieve efficient directional conversion of ethane. The carbon dioxide reduction reaction at the cathode is further coupled, resulting in a higher conversion of ethane on the anode side and the production of syngas on the cathode side. This electrochemical reaction process provides a choice for the clean production of high value&#8208;added small molecule chemical products.</description>
      <author>Shixian Zhang, Wang Sun, Chunming Xu, Rongzheng Ren, Jinshuo Qiao, Zhenhua Wang, Kening Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unusual Hydrogen-mediated Oxidation in Doped Ceria Systems: Operando Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-m46zg</link>
      <description>Vipin Kamboj, Soham Raychowdhury, Chinmoy Ranjan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404704760

                Ceria and doped-ceria are well-known material in heterogeneous catalysis due to their ability to catalyse are large number of redox reactions. They are a promising choice for solid oxide-based CO2 electrolysis cathodes due to their mixed ionic-electronic conducting nature. Gd and Pr doping is known to significantly improve both electrochemical and thermochemical reactions involving CO2 reduction. H2 in the feed stream was found to play a critical and unusual role in these reactions. This study systematically investigates the hydrogen&#8217;s impact on CO2 reduction within CeOx, Ce{Pr}Ox, and Ce{Gd}Ox. Operando Raman spectroscopy, combined with online mass spectrometry and optical imaging, revealed that CO production is linked to the reduction of Ce&#8308;&#8314; to Ce&#179;&#8314; sites under bias. While dopants typically enhanced oxygen defect formation, Ce{Pr}O&#8339; eliminated oxygen defects and tends to oxidize in H&#8322;. First-principles calculations showed that hydrogen incorporation could stabilize or destabilize oxygen vacancies in the catalyst. It promotes reduction in CeO&#8339; and Ce{Gd}O&#8339;, but counterintuitively stabilizes oxygen sites in Ce{Pr}O&#8339;, leading to its oxidation. This study reports the first ever system which oxidized upon exposure to H2.</description>
      <author>Vipin Kamboj, Soham Raychowdhury, Chinmoy Ranjan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-m46zg</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variation of Modified Combustion Efficiency and Its Impact on Biomass Burning Emission Estimation in Africa</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024jd041808</link>
      <description>Xiaosheng Fang, Zilin Wang, Xin Huang, Lian Xue, Wenxuan Hua, Sijia Lou, K. Y. Ding, Aijun Ding, Journal of Geophysical Research Atmospheres. 129(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404687542

                Abstract Biomass burning (BB) is one of the largest sources of trace gases and primary carbonaceous particles in the global troposphere, posing great impacts on air quality and regional climate. Accurate quantification of BB emissions is vital for assessing its environmental and climate impacts. However, there are still large uncertainties in current BB emission inventories due to poorly characterized emission rates under different combustion states. The fixed emission factor (EF) instead of varying EF associated with different combustion efficiencies may be the reason for the bias. Here, based on satellite&#8208;retrieved carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) and carbon monoxide (CO), the modified combustion efficiency (MCE) is derived for fire&#8208;prone regions in Africa. The monthly and inter&#8208;annual variability of MCE shows a good correlation with meteorological variables such as relative humidity. Therefore, variable EF was established based on its statistical relationship with MCE for different fire&#8208;emitted species. Application of such MCE&#8208;dependent EF in the global climate&#8208;chemistry model can greatly improve the performance of wildfire smoke pollution during the fire season, indicated by an increase of 31% in aerosol optical depth (AOD) and a 50% reduction in normalized mean bias compared with AOD observations. The study elucidates the critical role of meteorology in BB emission estimates and highlights the importance of implementing a dynamic fire emission inventory in response to meteorological conditions.</description>
      <author>Xiaosheng Fang, Zilin Wang, Xin Huang, Lian Xue, Wenxuan Hua, Sijia Lou, K. Y. Ding, Aijun Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024jd041808</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relationships between the Surface Hydrophilicity of a Bismuth Electrode and the Product Selectivity of Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c09642</link>
      <description>Yujing Ji, Jichuang Wu, Ha Eun Lee, Yongsu An, Duk&#8208;Young Jung, Chan Woo Lee, Young Dok Kim, Hyun Ook Seo, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404735652

                Two types of bismuth films (micro-Bi and nano-Bi) were prepared, and their electrocatalytic behavior was studied in terms of reduction current and product selectivity in a potential range of &#8722;0.776 to &#8722;1.376 V vs RHE. CO2 and H2O molecules competed with each other for reduction on the surfaces of both types of films, and formate and H2 were the respective major products of reductive reactions. Under the same conditions, nano-Bi exhibited lower selectivity for formate and higher selectivity for H2 compared to the respective micro-Bi cases with bismuth films of similar thickness. This can be attributed to the higher hydrophilicity of bismuth film surfaces of nano-Bi due to surface nanoscale roughness and lower surface-carbon content compared with those of micro-Bi. Our results suggest a new strategy for controlling the selectivity of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction under aqueous electrolytes through the use of surface engineering.</description>
      <author>Yujing Ji, Jichuang Wu, Ha Eun Lee, Yongsu An, Duk&#8208;Young Jung, Chan Woo Lee, Young Dok Kim, Hyun Ook Seo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c09642</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Influence of Transportation Infrastructure on Socio-Environmental Efficiency: Countries Case Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/03611981241284625</link>
      <description>H&#233;lio da Silva Queiroz J&#250;nior, Marcos Ara&#250;jo de Souza Celestino, Viviane Adriano Falc&#227;o, Francisco Gildemir Ferreira da Silva, Maur&#237;cio de Oliveira Andrade, An&#237;sio Brasileiro, Transportation Research Record Journal of the Transportation Research Board. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404616566

                The literature suggests that a country&#8217;s economic development is directly related to the efficiency of its transportation system. While the importance of a well-functioning transport system for economic growth and poverty reduction is widely acknowledged, there is limited quantitative research demonstrating this relationship. Many studies have separately applied data envelopment analysis (DEA) to analyze highways, airports, railways, and harbors. However, they have yet to analyze all modes and their relationship with economic development comprehensively. Consequently, this paper seeks to address this gap in the existing literature. The objective of this study is to demonstrate that transportation system. To this end, we employ DEA and consider a range of operational variables, including airports, railways, highways, and harbors. Furthermore, we examine the relationship between transportation efficiency and several economic and social indicators, including gross domestic product (GDP), human development index (HDI), and carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) emissions from the transportation system. Our findings reveal that Brazil exhibits the lowest relative efficiency when compared with the G-7 countries and South America. Additionally, it demonstrates medium efficiency within the BRICS group (Brazil, Russia, India, China, and South Africa).</description>
      <author>H&#233;lio da Silva Queiroz J&#250;nior, Marcos Ara&#250;jo de Souza Celestino, Viviane Adriano Falc&#227;o, Francisco Gildemir Ferreira da Silva, Maur&#237;cio de Oliveira Andrade, An&#237;sio Brasileiro</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/03611981241284625</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Front Cover: Quantitative Analysis and Manipulation of Alkali Metal Cations at the Cathode Surface in Membrane Electrode Assembly Electrolyzers for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reactions (ChemSusChem 22/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202482201</link>
      <description>Shintaro Kato, Shotaro Ito, Shoko Nakahata, Ryo Kurihara, Takashi Harada, Shuji Nakanishi, Kazuhide Kamiya, ChemSusChem. 17(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404670263

                The Front Cover depicts an MEA electrolyzer as an ice wall, with penguins carrying CO2 through it, where it is reduced to C2+. The flow of K+ is represented by rain, and its variation is illustrated by the relationship between clouds and the sun. This illustration conveys a strong desire to address environmental issues by depicting penguins in Antarctica, which are severely affected by global warming, desperately reductions in the greenhouse gas CO2. More information can be found in the Research Article by S. Nakanishi, K. Kamiya and co-workers.</description>
      <author>Shintaro Kato, Shotaro Ito, Shoko Nakahata, Ryo Kurihara, Takashi Harada, Shuji Nakanishi, Kazuhide Kamiya</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202482201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Valorisation of Biochar Produced from Black Liquor Pyrolysis for the Development of CO2 Adsorbents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235613</link>
      <description>Anca Zaharioiu, Violeta&#8208;Carolina Niculescu, Claudia &#350;andru, Stefan Ionu&#539; Spiridon, Amalia Soare, Simona Oancea, Florian Marin, Molecules. 29(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404757943

                The paper manufacturing process produces liquid and gaseous alternative fuels, as well as solid wastes. These can be subsequently treated through chemical processing, oxidation, and thermal activation, resulting in adsorbent materials with CO2 adsorption capacities. The valorisation of black liquor waste resulting from paper manufacturing was achieved through a catalytic pyrolysis process using two catalysts previously prepared in house (Cu-Zn-MCM-41 and Ni-SBA-16). The HCl-treated adsorbent material, resulting from Ni-SBA-16-catalysed pyrolysis, was selected for use in CO2 adsorption tests as it had the highest specific surface area (224.06 m2/g) and pore volume (0.28 cm3/g). The adsorption experimental setup was linked to a gas chromatograph in order to evaluate CO2 adsorption efficiency using a binary gas mixture consisting of 81% CO2 and 19% N2. With a CO2 adsorption capacity of 1.61 mmol/g, a separation efficiency of 99.78%, and a CO2 recovery yield of 90.02%, it can be concluded that the developed adsorbent material resulting from Ni-SBA16-catalysed pyrolysis and HCl treatment represents a viable solution for black liquor pyrolytic solid waste removal and reduction in greenhouse gases.</description>
      <author>Anca Zaharioiu, Violeta&#8208;Carolina Niculescu, Claudia &#350;andru, Stefan Ionu&#539; Spiridon, Amalia Soare, Simona Oancea, Florian Marin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost&#8211;Benefit Analysis of the China&#8217;s Household Coal-to-Electricity Transition: A Case Study on the Beijing Mentougou Area</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235933</link>
      <description>Yanran Pan, Lei Jiang, Hui Wang, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404712107

                Since 2013, China has implemented clean heating projects such as the coal-to-electricity project to reduce emissions and improve air quality in northern China, but it still requires significant investment from governments, businesses, and households. However, the benefits of coal-to-electricity to improve the rural family environment have received less attention. In this study, we conducted a cost&#8211;benefit analysis of the coal-to-electricity transition in Beijing&#8217;s Mentougou District from 2013 to 2017, distinguishing private costs and benefits, government costs and public benefits, and social costs and benefits. The results show that for all coal-to-electricity households, the private benefits far outweigh the private costs, with a benefit&#8211;cost ratio of 15.9. The government costs outweigh the benefit of air pollutants and carbon dioxide emission reduction, with a benefit&#8211;cost ratio of 0.4. Overall, the social benefits outweigh the social costs: the benefit&#8211;cost ratio for society was 2.2. The environmental benefits of the coal-to-electricity policies did not offset the large amount of investment of the government, but society received a positive net benefit owing to the large benefits gained by rural households. This also proves that the investment by the government is efficient and verifies the government&#8217;s next step to continue to promote the coal-to-electricity transition.</description>
      <author>Yanran Pan, Lei Jiang, Hui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Spatial Spillover Effect and Mechanism of Carbon Emission Trading Policy on Pollution Reduction and Carbon Reduction: Evidence from the Pearl River&#8211;West River Economic Belt in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310279</link>
      <description>Zhigao Liao, Yufeng Bai, Kerong Jian, Wongvanichtawee Chalermkiat, Sustainability. 16(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404702360

                Abstract: China faces issues such as air pollution and global climate change, and the Carbon Emission Trading Policy (CETP) has attracted considerable attention as a core policy tool for achieving the "dual carbon" goals. Based on panel data from the Pearl River&#8211;West River Economic Belt (PRWREB) from 2008 to 2021, we use the Synthetic Control Method (SCM) and Spatial Difference-in-Differences (S-DID) models to explore the pollution reduction and carbon reduction effects of the CETP and its spatial heterogeneity. Our analysis reveals several interesting insights. First, the CETP has promoted a 34.1% overall reduction in pollution and carbon levels in the pilot areas, with sustained effects. Moreover, spatial spillover effects can reduce the pollution and carbon levels in the economic belt by 29.9%. Second, the pollution and carbon reduction effects of the CETP are more significant in regions with better economic development and active carbon trading. It has the best synergistic reduction effects on CO2 and SO2 but is less effective in reducing PM2.5. Third, the spillover effects of the CETP on technological innovation are greater than the direct effects, with the most noticeable pollution and carbon reduction outcomes. The overall negative effect on industrial structure is that it fails to promote pollution and carbon reduction. The emission reduction mechanisms vary for different targets: CO2 and PM2.5 are related to energy efficiency, SO2 to advancing industrial structure, and smoke and dust to technological innovation. Based on the research conclusions, we propose to improve the coordinated governance system for carbon and pollution, advance pollution and carbon reduction according to local conditions, and implement targeted emission reduction and efficiency enhancement.</description>
      <author>Zhigao Liao, Yufeng Bai, Kerong Jian, Wongvanichtawee Chalermkiat</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly graphitized nitrogen-doped ordered mesoporous carbon supported Ni nanocrystals for efficient hydrazine-assisted CO2 splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06503d</link>
      <description>Kang Lian, Junyang Ding, Jin Zhang, Quan Zhang, Yifan Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Jia He, Xijun Liu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404681757

                As the size of atomic nickel increased to nanoscale particles, the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) was subjected to intense hydrogen evolution side reactions and significant *CO adsorption, which markedly...</description>
      <author>Kang Lian, Junyang Ding, Jin Zhang, Quan Zhang, Yifan Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Jia He, Xijun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06503d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of the CO2 Flooding Front for CO2-EOR in Unconventional Reservoirs: Considering the Different Miscibilities of CO2-Crude Oil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/223225-ms</link>
      <description>Xiliang Liu, Hao Chen, Weiming Cheng, Chenghao Xu, Mingsheng Zuo, Shuaiqiang Gao, Yi Wu, Haipeng Liu, Xinyu Qi, Mahaman Sidi Brahim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404784636

                Abstract Both laboratory tests and pilot wells have demonstrated the significant potential of CO2 as an enhanced oil recovery (EOR) medium. Due to the weak pressure conduction and mass transfer of the CO2-oil system, multiple zones are generated between the injection well and production well in ultra-low permeability reservoirs. This work aims to explore the characteristics of these multiple zones and the mechanisms of CO2-EOR by combining experimental results, core-scale analysis, and field-scale simulation. Long-core CO2 displacement experiments were conducted under different miscibility pressures, with production gas assayed using gas chromatography. The core-scale simulation was aligned with the experimental results, defining four CO2 fronts to distinguish different zones based on pressure, interfacial tension, and CO2 concentration along the long core. The distribution of five zones was upscaled to the field-scale model after pilot well history matching. The final step involved evaluating the miscible zone range value, CO2 injection utilization factor, oil recovery, and CO2 storage efficiency during the CO2 injection process. Results show that the boundary between the original oil zone and the oil transition zone exists at the CO2 component front, where the CO2 concentration is zero. Additionally, the location of the CO2 component front does not overlap with the contact interface of CO2-crude oil, meaning that the dissolution effect of CO2 in the oil transition zone results in the CO2 component front moving farther. Besides, when the formation pressure is higher than the minimum miscibility pressure (MMP), the distance between the CO2-effective phase front and the CO2-effective component front further expands as the pressure increases, enlarging the miscible zone range. The pressure accumulates around the injection well because of slow pressure conduction. When the average formation pressure reaches 1.1 MMP, the miscible zone range is enlarged by 2.7% higher than that of the near miscible flooding (0.92 MMP), leading to a higher rate of oil recovery by 8.6% and a utilization factor of CO2 by 0.14t/t. It is for the first time that the range of five zones and the characteristics of four CO2 fronts migration is assessed, furnishing an in-depth understanding of the complicated mechanisms and phase behavior in CO2 EOR in the ultra-low permeability oil reservoir. This work contributes to providing significant information for designing an economic and environmental CO2 flooding strategy and is significant in the improvement of oil recovery and the reduction of CO2 emission.</description>
      <author>Xiliang Liu, Hao Chen, Weiming Cheng, Chenghao Xu, Mingsheng Zuo, Shuaiqiang Gao, Yi Wu, Haipeng Liu, Xinyu Qi, Mahaman Sidi Brahim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/223225-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A geospatial approach for dynamic on-road emission through open-access floating car data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad984d</link>
      <description>Pak Lun Fung, Omar Al-Jaghbeer, Jia Chen, Ville-Veikko Paunu, Shaghayegh Vosough, Claudio Roncoli, Leena J&#228;rvi, Environmental Research Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404801485

                Abstract This paper presents a geospatial approach for quantifying street-level on-road emissions of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ), nitrogen oxides (NO x ), and carbon monoxide (CO). By leveraging an existing open-access database of real-time congestion information derived from floating car data, we tested three methods to map high-resolution dynamic traffic emissions. To demonstrate the robustness and accuracy of the methods, we showcased results for summer workdays and winter weekends in the Helsinki Metropolitan Area (HMA). The three methods employed include (1) a physics-based relation known as the macroscopic fundamental diagram (MFD), (2) a data-driven input-adaptive generalized linear model (GLM), and (3) their ensemble (ENS). These methods estimated traffic density with satisfactory accuracy (R 2 = 0.60&#8211;0.88, sMAPE = 31&#8211;68%). Utilizing speed-dependent emission factors retrieved from a European database, the results compared favorably against the downscaled national emission inventory, particularly for CO 2 (R 2 = 0.70&#8211;0.77). Among the three methods, GLM exhibited the best overall performance in the HMA, while ENS provided a robust upscaling solution. The modeled emissions exhibited dynamic diurnal and spatial behavior, influenced by different functional road classes, fleet compositions and congestion patterns. Congestion-induced emissions were calculated to account for up to 10% of the total vehicular emissions. Furthermore, to anticipate the forthcoming transportation transformation, we calculated emission changes under scenarios with various penetration rates of connected and autonomous vehicles (CAVs) using this geospatial approach. The introduction of CAVs could result in emission reductions of 3&#8211;14% owing to congestion improvements.</description>
      <author>Pak Lun Fung, Omar Al-Jaghbeer, Jia Chen, Ville-Veikko Paunu, Shaghayegh Vosough, Claudio Roncoli, Leena J&#228;rvi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad984d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of CO2 Capture Using a New Aqueous Hybrid Solvent (MDEA-[TBPA][TFA]) with a Low Heat Capacity: Integration of COSMO-RS and RSM Approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12122626</link>
      <description>Fairuz Liyana Mohd Rasdi, Revathi Jeyaseelan, Mohd Faisal Taha, Mohamad Amirul Ashraf Mohd Razip, Processes. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404613417

                This study aims to evaluate the performance of a new hybrid solvent, comprising aqueous MDEA and tetrabutylphosphonium trifluoroacetate ([TBP][TFA]), for CO2 capture and to optimize its CO2 absorption efficiency. First, this study focused on predicting the thermodynamic properties of aqueous MDEAs and [TBP][TFA] and their interaction energy with CO2 using COSMO-RS. Based on the prediction, it aligns with the principle that CO2 solubility in the MDEA-[TBP][TFA] hybrid solvent decreases as the Henry&#8217;s Law constant increases, with the interactions primarily governed by van der Waals forces and hydrogen bonding. The aqueous MDEA-[TBP][TFA] hybrid solvent was prepared in two steps: synthesizing and blending [TBP][TFA] with aqueous MDEAs. The formation and purity of [TBP][TFA] were confirmed through NMR, FT-IR, and Karl Fischer. The heat capacity of the hybrid solvents was lower than their aqueous MDEA solutions. The performance and optimization of CO2 capture were studied using RSM-FC-CCD design, with the optimal value obtained at 50 wt.% MDEA, 20 wt.% [TBP][TFA], 30 &#176;C, and 30 bar (12.14 mol/kg), aligning with COSMO-RS predictions. A 26% reduction in the heat capacity was achieved with the optimal ratio (wt.%) of the hybrid solvent. These findings suggest that the aqueous MDEA-[TBP][TFA] hybrid solvent is a promising alternative for CO2 capture, providing a high removal capacity and lower heat capacity for more efficient regeneration compared to commercial aqueous MDEA solutions.</description>
      <author>Fairuz Liyana Mohd Rasdi, Revathi Jeyaseelan, Mohd Faisal Taha, Mohamad Amirul Ashraf Mohd Razip</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12122626</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modest Method for Estimating CO2 Emissions from Container Handling Equipment at Ports</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310293</link>
      <description>Muhammad Arif Budiyanto, Faril Ichfari, Takeshi Shinoda, Sustainability. 16(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404700483

                The maritime industry is under increasing pressure to reduce CO2 emissions, with the International Maritime Organization (IMO) setting a target to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, including emissions from the port sector, by 40% by 2030. However, accurate and reliable methods for estimating CO2 emissions at container ports, which are significant contributors to maritime emissions, are still lacking. This study aims to address this by evaluating a novel method for estimating CO2 emissions at container ports. The proposed method utilizes the cargo handling equipment movement theory, quantifying both vertical and horizontal movements based on the amount of container handling equipment at the port. The emissions for each piece of equipment are estimated by multiplying the movement quantity by the respective emission factor. To validate the model, a robustness test compares the estimated CO2 emissions with actual energy consumption data from the port. A case study was conducted at a container port with an annual capacity of over 500,000 TEUs and a parallel layout type. The estimated CO2 emissions were approximately 8183 tons per year, with container cranes contributing 56%, rubber-tire gantry cranes contributing 27%, terminal trucks contributing 14%, and reach stackers contributing 3%. The method demonstrated accuracy, with a deviation of less than 1%. This method offers a fast and reliable approach for estimating baseline CO2 emissions at container ports, providing valuable insights for port authorities and policymakers to develop more effective emission-reduction strategies.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Arif Budiyanto, Faril Ichfari, Takeshi Shinoda</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance analysis of multi-energy sharing prosumers considering different load profiles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1470769</link>
      <description>Jincan Zeng, Peng Wang, Qin Wang, Minwei Liu, Xi Liu, Guori Huang, Gengsheng He, Shangheng Yao, Longxi Li, Frontiers in Energy Research. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404622467

                With the advancement of distributed energy systems, energy sharing has emerged as a crucial trading mechanism on the demand-side, enabling participants to share self-generated energy with their neighbors through contractual agreements. Nevertheless, a comprehensive analysis is needed to balance the benefits among energy prosumers, given their distinct characteristics. This paper proposes a multi-energy sharing framework with flexible demand-side management based on full cooperation. We evaluate the economic and environmental performance of sharing participants, considering the impacts of different operation modes and diverse demand profiles. Cooperative game theory is employed to maximize the social welfare of all participants, with the different allocation schemes are used to distribute the cooperative surplus among stakeholders. The fairness of these schemes is assessed to ensure the feasibility and equity of the proposed framework. The results indicate that the centralized multi-energy sharing framework yields win-win outcomes for both individual and collective interests. Specifically, the total cost and carbon dioxide emissions of prosumers in the shared scenario are reduced by 13% and 16%, respectively, compared to individual operation scenarios. Moreover, thermal energy management is critically important for energy sharing. Furthermore, varying combinations of building types significantly affect cost savings and emission reductions, influencing energy sharing patterns and quantities.</description>
      <author>Jincan Zeng, Peng Wang, Qin Wang, Minwei Liu, Xi Liu, Guori Huang, Gengsheng He, Shangheng Yao, Longxi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1470769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Management of Adult Hypopharyngeal Vascular Anomalies&#8212;A Descriptive Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/01455613241302548</link>
      <description>Xiufa Wu, Jing Zhang, Chunsheng Wei, Ear Nose &amp; Throat Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404702321

                Objective: Given the rarity of adult hypopharyngeal vascular anomalies (AHVAs), no systematic studies are currently available. The aim of this study is to explore therapeutic strategies for AHVAs and determine the optimal timing for surgery in their treatment. Methods: We conducted a retrospective analysis of the data from patients diagnosed with AHVAs who underwent treatment using either bleomycin injection or excision methods in our department between September 2013 and November 2022. The study evaluated the curative efficacy, factors influencing efficacy, the size of AHVAs, and the selection of surgical methods. Results: A total of 23 adult patients underwent 30 distinct procedures. The study revealed that the choice of surgical methods significantly impacted therapeutic outcomes, with potassium-titanyl-phosphate laser, carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) lasers, low-temperature plasma, and Holmium laser proving effective in treating AHVAs. The therapeutic effect was found to be worse for AHVAs involving multiple subzones compared to those with single subzone invasion. Notably, 3 patients underwent 2 surgeries: the first involved a bleomycin injection, followed by a complete surgical excision. Conclusions: The findings of our study emphasize the superior outcomes achieved through surgical excision when AHVAs are clearly delineated. Furthermore, we recommend opting for surgical excision after a reduction of AHVAs induced by bleomycin injection.</description>
      <author>Xiufa Wu, Jing Zhang, Chunsheng Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/01455613241302548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roughing Nitrogen-Doped Carbon Nanosheets for Loading of Monatomic Fe and Electroreduction of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235561</link>
      <description>Yuxuan Liu, Yong Bo Tan, Keyi Zhang, Tianqi Guo, Yao Zhu, Ting Cao, Haiyang Lv, Junpeng Zhu, Ze Gao, Su Zhang, Zheng Liu, Juzhe Liu, Molecules. 29(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404696438

                The catalyst is the pivotal component in CO2 electroreduction systems for converting CO2 into valuable products. Carbon-based single-atom materials (CSAMs) have emerged as promising catalyst candidates due to their low cost and high atomic utilization efficiency. The rational design of the morphology and microstructure of such materials is desirable but poses a challenge. Here, we employed different Mg(OH)2 templates to guide the fabrication of two kinds of amorphous nitrogen-doped carbon nanosheet-supported Fe single atoms (FeSNC) with rough and flat surface structures. In comparison to flat FeSNC with saturated FeN4 sites, the rough FeSNC (R-FeSNC) exhibited unsaturated FeN4&#8722;x sites and contracted Fe-N bond length. The featured structure endowed R-FeSNC with superior capacity of catalyzing CO2 reduction reaction, achieving an exceptional CO selectivity with Faradaic efficiency of 93% at a potential of &#8722;0.66 V vs. RHE. This study offers valuable insights into the design of CSAMs and provides a perspective for gaining a deeper understanding of their activity origins.</description>
      <author>Yuxuan Liu, Yong Bo Tan, Keyi Zhang, Tianqi Guo, Yao Zhu, Ting Cao, Haiyang Lv, Junpeng Zhu, Ze Gao, Su Zhang, Zheng Liu, Juzhe Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial and temporal variation in water availability across high mountain gravelly pavement herbfields affects the distribution of hydrophilic plant species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10750-024-05763-4</link>
      <description>Alexandra Blackburn-Smith, Ewen Silvester, Zac C. Walker, John W. Morgan, Hydrobiologia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404742590

                Gravelly pavement herbfields are a groundwater-dependant vegetation type; water composition and supply are hypothesised to be a crucial factor affecting the distribution of plant species in the community. We described the relationship between plant species distribution in pavements and the spatial and temporal availability and composition of water. Water flows into pavements varied through the growing season, as did lateral spread of water, and its permanency. Furthermore, the distribution of dominant pavement plant species was associated with moisture. Oreobolus pumilio (Cyperaceae) was significantly negatively associated, whilst Psychrophila introloba (Ranunculaceae) was significantly positively associated, with persistent moisture. The chemical composition of water changed whilst transiting through pavements, with loss of dissolved CO2 and an increase in pH likely due to strong CO2 evasion. When compared with other hydrologic units across the landscape, the chemical composition of pavement waters was between that of groundwater and peatlands, corresponding to their physical position in the landscape. These results have implications for the conservation of the gravelly pavement herbfield community. With climate change, reductions in water availability threatens the persistence of key hydrophilic species given their strong association with moisture. Reductions in areal extent, as well as re-organisation of the plant community, could be expected.</description>
      <author>Alexandra Blackburn-Smith, Ewen Silvester, Zac C. Walker, John W. Morgan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10750-024-05763-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satellite Data and Machine Learning for Benchmarking Methane Concentrations in the Canadian Dairy Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310400</link>
      <description>Hanqing Bi, Suresh Neethirajan, Sustainability. 16(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404757044

                Amid escalating climate change concerns, methane&#8212;a greenhouse gas with a global warming potential far exceeding that of carbon dioxide&#8212;demands urgent attention. The Canadian dairy industry significantly contributes to methane emissions through cattle enteric fermentation and manure management practices. Precise benchmarking of these emissions is critical for developing effective mitigation strategies. This study ingeniously integrates eight years of Sentinel-5P satellite data with advanced machine learning techniques to establish a methane concentration benchmark and predict future emission trends in the Canadian dairy sector. By meticulously analyzing weekly methane concentration data from 575 dairy farms and 384 dairy processors, we uncovered intriguing patterns: methane levels peak during autumn, and Ontario exhibits the highest concentrations among all provinces. The COVID-19 pandemic introduced unexpected shifts in methane emissions due to altered production methods and disrupted supply chains. Our Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) neural network model adeptly captures methane concentration trends, providing a powerful tool for planning and reducing emissions from dairy operations. This pioneering approach not only demonstrates the untapped potential of combining satellite data with machine learning for environmental monitoring but also paves the way for informed emission reduction strategies in the dairy industry. Future endeavors will focus on enhancing satellite data accuracy, integrating more granular farm and processor variables, and refining machine learning models to bolster prediction precision.</description>
      <author>Hanqing Bi, Suresh Neethirajan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effect of Copper and Indium Species for Highly Selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c08258</link>
      <description>Shangzhi Xie, Xintian Luo, Jialong Zhao, Minjie Xu, Haoxiang Chen, Minghui Zhu, Jing Xu, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404625683

                CO2 hydrogenation to methanol over Cu-based catalysts faces challenges such as low methanol selectivity and poor stability. Here, we report a series of CuIn bimetallic catalysts with different Cu/In ratios prepared by the coprecipitation method. Among them, the methanol selectivity of Cu25In75 reaches as high as 92.5% at 200 &#176;C and 64.5% at 260 &#176;C, which is 1.3 times and 1.9 times higher than that of the commercial catalyst at 200 and 260 &#176;C, respectively. Moreover, Cu25In75 exhibits high stability for 200 h time-on-stream at 260 &#176;C. The high selectivity originates from a strong interaction between Cu species and In2O3&#8211;x with oxygen vacancies. On the interface between Cu and In2O3&#8211;x, dispersed Cu is the main contributor to the activation and dissociation of H2, while the oxygen vacancies in In2O3 adsorb and activate CO2. During the reaction, the abundance of hydrogen facilitates the reduction of the In2O3 surface, promoting the generation of surface oxygen vacancies and providing the necessary hydrogen for the hydrogenation reaction. Our research unveils a promising synergistic strategy for the rational design and application of Cu-based catalysts in CO2 hydrogenation, offering avenues for further exploration and advancement in this field.</description>
      <author>Shangzhi Xie, Xintian Luo, Jialong Zhao, Minjie Xu, Haoxiang Chen, Minghui Zhu, Jing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c08258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Conversion of Sulfate Oxygen for High-Precision Triple Oxygen Isotope Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c03683</link>
      <description>Yu Wei, Hao Yan, Yongbo Peng, Huiming Bao, Analytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404708220

                Triple oxygen isotope composition (&#916;&#8242;17O) of sulfate carries information on the sulfur cycle as well as signatures of atmospheric O2, O3, and surface water of the geological past. However, existing analytical techniques can only achieve a partial oxygen yield during the conversion from sulfate to the analyte O2, which results in isotope fractionation and impedes the &#916;&#8242;17O comparison with other oxygen-bearing compounds (e.g., H2O) on the VSMOW-SLAP scale. Here, we present an analytical method involving high-temperature graphite reduction, CO discharge, and Pt-catalyzed CO2&#8211;O2 isotope exchange, the R&#8211;D&#8211;E method, that achieves &#8764;100% conversion of sulfate oxygen to CO2. Compared with the widely used CO2-laser-fluorination technique, our R&#8211;D&#8211;E method has a better &#916;&#8242;17O precision (9 per meg) and requires a smaller sample amount, as low as 4 &#956;mol of sulfate (equivalent to 1 mg BaSO4), with both &#916;&#8242;17O and &#948;18O being determined simultaneously. Using this method, we report the triple oxygen isotope compositions of three international reference materials (NBS-127, IAEA-SO-5, and IAEA-SO-6) and three in-house references on the VSMOW-SLAP scale. We found that the sulfate &#916;&#8242;17O values measured on the partially yielded O2 from the fluorination technique are 10&#8211;200 per meg higher than those obtained by our R&#8211;D&#8211;E method, depending on the oxidant used (e.g., F2 or BrF5). Incomplete conversion of sulfate oxygen during the high-temperature graphite reduction would result in lower &#948;18O and higher &#916;&#8242;17O values. This work highlights the needs for recalibration and reinterpretation of the published sulfate &#916;&#8242;17O data when sulfate &#916;&#8242;17O values of interest are small.</description>
      <author>Yu Wei, Hao Yan, Yongbo Peng, Huiming Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c03683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The association between ozone exposure and blood pressure in a general Chinese middle-aged and older population: a large-scale repeated-measurement study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916-024-03783-4</link>
      <description>Chen Tang, Yiqin Zhang, Jennifer Wang Yi, Zhonghua Lu, Xianfa Xuan, Hanxiang Jiang, Dongbei Guo, Hanyu Xiang, Ting Wu, Jianhua Yan, Siyu Zhang, Yuxin Wang, Jie Zhang, BMC Medicine. 22(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404709155

                The relationship between ozone (O3) exposure and blood pressure (BP) remains inconclusive. Given the scarcity of Chinese epidemiological data, more research on this association is of paramount importance, particularly among middle-aged and older Chinese populations. This study involved 10,875 participants (median age: 60.0 years) in Xiamen, China, from 2013 to 2019, with 34,939 repeated BP measurements. Air pollutant exposure data, including O3, particulate matter, nitrogen dioxide, sulfur dioxide, and carbon monoxide were derived from China High Air Pollutants and High-resolution Air Quality Reanalysis datasets using a k-nearest neighbor algorithm. The relationship between mixed air pollutant exposure and BP was evaluated using Bayesian kernel machine regression model. The effects of daily-specific O3 exposure on BP were assessed by distributed lag models integrated into a linear mixed-effects framework. The mediating role of total cholesterol (TC), serum total bilirubin (STB), triglyceride (TG), and low-density lipoprotein (LDL) were examined using multilevel mediation analysis with a fully adjusted model. Mixed air pollutant exposure was positively correlated with BP, with O3 being a predominant contributor exhibiting an inverse effect. O3 exposure had immediate effects on pulse pressure (PP), while systolic blood pressure (SBP), diastolic blood pressure (DBP), and mean arterial pressure (MAP) showed delayed responses, with 3-, 14-, and 8-day lags, respectively. During the study period of up to 30 days, each 10 &#956;g/m3 increase in maximum daily 8-h average O3 concentration was associated with reductions in SBP (&#946; = &#8722; 1.176 mm Hg), DBP (&#8722; 0.237 mm Hg), PP (&#946; = &#8722; 0.973 mm Hg), and MAP (&#946; = &#8722; 0.544 mm Hg). Stronger correlations were observed in the older participants (aged &#8805; 65 years), overweight/obese individuals, smokers and alcohol consumers, and those with hypertension or type 2 diabetes mellitus. STB and LDL mediated these effects, while TC and TG played mitigating roles. Short-term O3 exposure is negatively associated with BP in middle-aged and older Chinese individuals. The findings provide preliminary evidence for the impact of O3 exposure on BP regulation and underscore the urgent need to reassess public health policies in response to O3 pollution.</description>
      <author>Chen Tang, Yiqin Zhang, Jennifer Wang Yi, Zhonghua Lu, Xianfa Xuan, Hanxiang Jiang, Dongbei Guo, Hanyu Xiang, Ting Wu, Jianhua Yan, Siyu Zhang, Yuxin Wang, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916-024-03783-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneity Analysis of Regional Greenhouse Gas Driving Effects: An Empirical Study from Southeast Asian Countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235951</link>
      <description>Wei Deng, Qingquan Liang, Yan Shuai, Xiaodan Shen, Lan Yi, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404760739

                Southeast Asia is suffering from extreme weather, and its carbon emissions are increasing rapidly. For efficient emission reduction, clarifying the complex sources behind is necessary. This study takes a new perspective of incorporating multiple GHGs (greenhouse gases) into the same analysis framework, employing the STIRPAT model to dissect the contributions of various socio-economic factors to the emissions of CO2, CH4, and F-gases based on panel data. The analysis reveals that the driving coefficients of total population and urbanization rate are several to 10 times higher than those of other factors and can reach up to 2.98 and 4.715 and are the most significant drivers of GHG emissions in the region. Quadratic per capita GDP shows a significant positive driving effect, indicating that most Southeast Asian countries are unlikely to reach the Kuznets point in current development trajectories. The driving coefficients of F-gases in industrialized countries are significantly higher than those of other GHGs, indicating that their growth rate of F-gases will outpace that of CO2 and CH4. In countries with a similar industrial structure, the driving coefficient of CO2 from the secondary industry is up to 0.183 and down to 0.057, shows the influence of specific sector composition in the secondary industry on emissions. These findings provide critical insights for Southeast Asian policymakers aiming to develop effective climate policies.</description>
      <author>Wei Deng, Qingquan Liang, Yan Shuai, Xiaodan Shen, Lan Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235951</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Histological Analysis of the Effect of a Vector Potential Generator on the Femur of a Hindlimb-Suspended Rat</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/anatomia3040023</link>
      <description>Wataru Minamizono, Nao Yashima, Hiroya Matsunaga, Kaoru Fujikawa, Hirai Suito, Takumi Okunuki, Masafumi Ohsako, Anatomia. 3(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404717922

                Disuse osteoporosis occurs due to rest and reduced mechanical stimulation. Under these conditions, bone resorption exceeds bone formation, leading to a decrease in bone density. Vector potential (VP) generators have been developed, and their ability to maintain cartilage thickness has been reported. However, their effects on bone tissue remain unstudied. In this study, experiments were conducted to test the effects of VP on bones that had undergone weight reduction due to hindlimb suspension as a model of disuse osteoporosis. Methods: In this study, 7-week-old male Wistar rats (N = 6 each) were classified into control (CO), hindlimb suspension (HS), and VP energization intervention groups. The tail was used to suspend the HS and VP to remove the load applied to the hindlimbs. The VP conditions were as follows: voltage, 67 mV; frequency, 20 kHz, 0.12 mA; experimental intervention, 30 min/day, 5 days/week, for 3 weeks. At the end of the experimental period, the rats were euthanized with carbon dioxide gas, and histological specimens were fixed in 4% paraformaldehyde (PFA) in the femur and analyzed by electron microscopy, bone morphometry, immunohistology, bone fracture testing, and gene expression analysis. Results: HS decreased trabecular bone density and strength. However, VP maintained a significantly higher bone mass than HS, and VP did not differ from CO in bone strength; more osteoclasts were observed on the bone surface in HS, but they were suppressed in VP, and gene expression of CTSK and MMP-9 was decreased. Conclusions: VP suppressed bone resorption by osteoclasts, suggesting that VP is useful in the treatment of disuse osteoporosis.</description>
      <author>Wataru Minamizono, Nao Yashima, Hiroya Matsunaga, Kaoru Fujikawa, Hirai Suito, Takumi Okunuki, Masafumi Ohsako</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/anatomia3040023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clean Energy and Carbon Emissions in Mexico&#8217;s Electric Power Sector: Past Performance and Current Trend</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235859</link>
      <description>Oliver Probst, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404640673

                The concept of clean energy was introduced by the Mexican authorities as part of the wholesale electricity market with the objectives of both measuring the progress in decarbonization and fostering emission-free and low-emission technologies. In the present work, the evolution of clean energy production for the period 2017&#8211;2023, corresponding to seven full years of operation of the electricity market, was analyzed and compared to official targets. Emission of greenhouse gases (GHGs) was calculated from fuel consumption statistics. The consistency between electricity generation and fuel consumption data has been assessed. The projected short-term evolution of electricity generation and GHG emissions through 2026, locked in by decisions in the recent past, was modeled and discussed. A reduction in carbon intensity from 0.56 gCO2,eq to 0.46 g CO2,eq was found for the 2017&#8211;2022 period, in qualitative agreement with official figures, mainly due to the large-scale introduction of wind and solar, as well as some displacement of coal- and fuel oil-fired generation. Total GHG emissions reached a minimum of about 150 Gt CO2,eq/a in 2020&#8211;2021; emissions are projected to rise to 190 Gt CO2,eq in 2026, due to a strong rise in natural gas-fired generation from combined-cycle plants and the largely stalled development of wind and solar plants. Clean energy figures were found to decouple from emissions and can therefore not be considered a good proxy for decarbonization. A recent roadmap presented by the incoming federal government does, however, indicate a change in policies which might bring Mexico back on track towards the decarbonization of the electric power sector.</description>
      <author>Oliver Probst</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Waste-Derived Fuels in Cement Kilns</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003539322-33</link>
      <description>M.P. Heap, Warren D. Owens, D.W. Pershing, Adel F. Sarofim, G.D. Silcox, Eric R. Hansen, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404615586

                Cement kilns offer an attractive method of utilizing certain wastes as substitutes for fossil fuel, thus providing an alternative to landfilling and incineration. The use of waste-derived fuel (WDF) in cement kilns not only provides a safe and cost-effective disposal method for combustible wastes, it also provides a net reduction in CO2 emissions since the WDF is replacing fossil fuel rather than being incinerated. This paper considers the fate of both metals and hydrocarbons present in WDF, and uses a simple process model to evaluate the thermal impact of injecting solid WDF into the calcining zone.</description>
      <author>M.P. Heap, Warren D. Owens, D.W. Pershing, Adel F. Sarofim, G.D. Silcox, Eric R. Hansen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003539322-33</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Elaborate for the early public insight of Master Plan of Belgrade 2041 in the context of climate mitigation planning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5937/lspupn24365i</link>
      <description>Bojana Ivanovi&#263;, Tijana Dabovi&#263;, Bojana Pjanovi&#263;, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404666042

                The intensification of human activities is the chief cause of increasing concentrations of greenhouse gases (GHG) in the atmosphere, accelerating climate change. This results in rising air and ocean temperatures and leads to prolonged droughts, devastating floods, and storms, which pose global risks with local implications. International institutions are urging countries to reduce GHG emissions through various agreements, like the Paris Agreement which Serbia has ratified, committing to a 13.2% reduction in GHG emissions by 2030. Similarly, Belgrade, under the Covenant of Mayors for Climate and Energy, aims to reduce carbon dioxide emissions by 40% in specific sectors by 2030. Spatial and urban planning should address questions regarding which activities, where and when to implement to achieve this. In this context, the Elaborate for early public insight of the Master Plan of Belgrade 2041 was analysed through document analysis and comparison methods, to determine whether and how climate mitigation was addressed. The project Climate Action for Belgrade, completed at the Faculty of Geography in Belgrade during the fall semester of 2023/2024, served as a reference point. It was one of the local projects within the Global Climate Geodesign Challenge, which is being implemented since 2022 by International Geodesign Collaboration and Liechtenstein Institute for Strategic Development (LISD) with the companies Esri and Geodesign Hub. All local projects follow the predefined geodesign methodological framework and digital technology, as well as LISD's domains and climate actions directory. The comparative analysis of the Elaborate and the project revealed that many planning measures in the Elaborate, although initially addressing other issues, could also contribute to climate mitigation. However, the potential to contribute to this goal has not been fully utilized in many areas, leaving opportunities for further enhancement through innovative and proactive approaches, not only in climate mitigation but also sustainable urban development context.</description>
      <author>Bojana Ivanovi&#263;, Tijana Dabovi&#263;, Bojana Pjanovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5937/lspupn24365i</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance analysis and engineering application of waste rubber crumbs in concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2053-1591/ad988f</link>
      <description>Li Liu, Materials Research Express. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404797604

                Abstract With the increasing number of waste tires, rubberized concrete, as a sustainable building material, has garnered widespread attention for its performance and environmental benefits. This study utilized KH-570 modified rubber particles to replace ordinary sand in the preparation of concrete, assessing the workability, shrinkage performance, and axial compression characteristics of rubberized concrete, and establishing a stress-strain constitutive model. The research indicates that the introduction of rubber particles enhances the irregularity and roughness of particles within the concrete matrix, leading to increased inter-particle friction and a reduction in workability. Pre-treatment with KH-570 effectively improves workability, particularly when the rubber content is 15%. Rubberized concrete exhibits higher ductility and slower crack propagation rates, with a decrease in elastic modulus and peak stress as rubber content increases, indicating an enhancement in the deformability and toughness of the concrete. The KH-570 pre-treatment partially counteracts this trend and significantly improves the energy absorption capacity of the concrete. The addition of unmodified rubber particles leads to an increased shrinkage rate in concrete, while the surface pre-treatment with KH-570 enhances the adhesion of rubber to the cementitious matrix, mitigating concrete shrinkage. The proposed axial stress-strain constitutive model for rubberized concrete accurately predicts the mechanical characteristics during the transition from elastic to plastic behavior. Rubberized concrete significantly reduces carbon dioxide emissions per unit volume, especially in untreated rubberized concrete, and offers better cost-effectiveness. In the construction of airport patrol roads, rubberized concrete demonstrates excellent durability and lower maintenance costs. In summary, rubberized concrete not only improves the ductility and toughness of concrete but also offers significant environmental and economic benefits, making it a promising sustainable building material.&amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Li Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2053-1591/ad988f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The sustainability impacts of a web&#8208;based outpatient booking application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1754-9485.13815</link>
      <description>Melissa Yeo, Kane M Nicholls, Pey Ling Shum, Hamed Asadi, Natalie Yang, Journal of Medical Imaging and Radiation Oncology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404764995

                Abstract Background Climate change is a critical global issue, impacting ecosystems, economies and communities worldwide. The shift from paper&#8208;based to digital systems is becoming increasingly prevalent across industries, with downstream positive impacts on sustainability. In 2020, Austin Health, a public tertiary hospital in Victoria, Australia, adopted a web&#8208;based outpatient booking application, which succeeded the prior paper&#8208;based system. The application served as an integrated platform for administrative staff to access various Austin Information Technology platforms and replaced previous mail&#8208;based outpatient appointment notifications with Short Message Service&#8208;based notifications. This study aimed to assess the environmental impact and organisation&#8208;wide economic cost of a web&#8208;based outpatient booking application compared to the prior paper&#8208;based system across the same time period. Methods A retrospective environmental and economic assessment was conducted for both the web&#8208;based booking application and the paper&#8208;based system. The evaluation covered 36,925 outpatient diagnostic imaging studies &#8211; including CT, MRI, ultrasound and mammography &#8211; performed at Austin Health from 1st July 2023 until 30th June 2024. The environmental impact was assessed by calculating the expected carbon dioxide equivalent (CO 2 e) emissions produced by each system. The economic cost analysis was conducted from the perspective of the hospital and included the direct costs of labour and materials/consumables. Results CO 2 e emissions were significantly reduced using the web&#8208;based outpatient booking application compared to the prior paper&#8208;based system (38.5 tonnes compared to 0.002 tonnes), predominantly attributable to the elimination of postage&#8208;related fuel emissions (27.7 tonnes). The estimated net operating cost savings across the year was at least AUD 175,000 (in 2024 Australian Dollars, adjusted for inflation). This was primarily due to labour savings from the elimination of workflow inefficiencies (at least 2342 h saved) amounting to at least AUD 85,272 in salary, followed by savings from eliminated pathology tests (AUD 57,422) and postage costs (AUD 55,193). Conclusion The adoption of the web&#8208;based outpatient booking application led to a substantial reduction in carbon emissions and operating costs, alongside enhanced operational efficiency and productivity. These benefits are anticipated to be enduring, especially in the face of an ever&#8208;increasing demand for medical imaging services.</description>
      <author>Melissa Yeo, Kane M Nicholls, Pey Ling Shum, Hamed Asadi, Natalie Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1754-9485.13815</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO Oxidation over Cu/Ce Binary Oxide Prepared via the Solvothermal Method: Effects of Cerium Precursors on Properties and Catalytic Behavior</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120856</link>
      <description>Wen Jin, Yanmin Liu, Hongyan Xue, Jun Yu, Dongsen Mao, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404690767

                Cu/Ce binary oxides were prepared via the one-pot solvothermal method, and the effects of different cerium precursors (cerium nitrate and cerium ammonium nitrate) on the catalytic activity and resistance to water vapor or CO2 of the prepared samples for low-temperature CO oxidation reaction were investigated. The physicochemical characteristics of the catalysts were characterized via thermal analyses (TG-DSC), X-ray diffraction (XRD), Raman spectroscopy, N2 adsorption/desorption, inductively coupled plasma-atomic emission spectrometry (ICP-AES), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), in situ diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (in situ DRIFTs), and temperature-programmed reduction with H2 (H2-TPR). The results indicated that the CuO/CeO2 catalyst (CC-N) prepared with cerium nitrate showed higher activity for low-temperature CO oxidation, which can be ascribed to its larger specific surface area and pore volume, higher amounts of highly dispersed CuO species with strong interaction with CeO2, Cu+ species, and more active surface oxygen species, compared with the counterpart prepared with cerium ammonium nitrate (CC-NH). Furthermore, the CC-N catalyst also exhibited better resistance to CO2 poisoning than CC-NH.</description>
      <author>Wen Jin, Yanmin Liu, Hongyan Xue, Jun Yu, Dongsen Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-conserving Bioproduction of Malate in an E. coli-based Cell-Free System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.26.623433</link>
      <description>Ryan Cardiff, Shaafique Chowdhury, Widianti Sugianto, Benjamin I. Tickman, Diego Alba Burbano, Pimphan Aye Meyer, Michael I. Cook, Ben King, David Garenne, Anton Y. Beliaev, Vincent Noireaux, Pamela Peralta&#8208;Yahya, James M. Carothers, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404730386

                Formate, a biologically accessible form of CO2, has attracted interest as a renewable feedstock for bioproduction. However, its use in microorganisms suffers from toxicity and limited utilization. Approaches are needed to investigate efficient routes for biological formate assimilation. Cell-free systems hold promise due to their potential for efficient use of carbon and energy sources and compatibility with diverse feedstocks. However, bioproduction using purified cell-free systems is limited by costly enzyme purification, whereas lysate-based systems must overcome loss of flux to background reactions in the cell extract. Here, we engineer an E. coli-based system for an eight-enzyme pathway from DNA and incorporate strategies to regenerate cofactors and minimize background reactions. We produce the industrial di-acid malate from glycine, bicarbonate, and formate by engineering the carbon-conserving reductive TCA and formate assimilation pathways. We demonstrate that in situ regeneration of NADH drives metabolic flux towards malate, improving titer by 15-fold. Background reactions can also be reduced 6-fold by diluting the lysate following expression and introducing chemical inhibitors of competing reactions. Together, these results establish a carbon-conserving, lysate-based cell-free platform for malate production, producing 64 &#956;M malate after 8 hours. This system conserves 43% of carbon otherwise lost as CO2 and incorporates 0.13 mol CO2 equivalents/mol glycine fed. Finally, techno-economic analysis of cell-free malate production from formate revealed that the high cost of lysate is a key challenge to the economic feasibility of the process, even assuming efficient cofactor recycling. This work demonstrates the capabilities of cell-free expression systems for both the prototyping of carbon-conserving pathways and the sustainable bioproduction of platform chemicals.</description>
      <author>Ryan Cardiff, Shaafique Chowdhury, Widianti Sugianto, Benjamin I. Tickman, Diego Alba Burbano, Pimphan Aye Meyer, Michael I. Cook, Ben King, David Garenne, Anton Y. Beliaev, Vincent Noireaux, Pamela Peralta&#8208;Yahya, James M. Carothers</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.26.623433</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caffeine reduces cerebrovascular reactivity in addition to lowering basal perfusion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/4881</link>
      <description>Dinil Sasi Sankaralayam, Zeqing Hu, Cuimei Xu, Dengrong Jiang, Peiying Liu, Abhay Moghekar, Hanzhang Lu, Proceedings on CD-ROM - International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine. Scientific Meeting and Exhibition/Proceedings of the International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, Scientific Meeting and Exhibition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404745469

                Motivation: Caffeine, one of the widely used psychoactive substances is known to reduce basal cerebral blood flow (CBF). However, its effect on vasodilatory capacity has not been characterizedGoal(s): To evaluate the impact of Caffein on cerebrovascular reactivity (CVR)Approach: 8 healthy caffeine-na&amp;iuml;ve volunteers were scanned for baseline (pre-caffeine) and post-Caffeine CVR measurements using BOLD MRI and phase-contrast MRI (PC)-MRI during normal air breathing and hypercapnia using 5% CO2 enriched gas mixtureResults: There was a significant reduction in blood-flux (BF) during room-air (p=0.002) and hypercapnia (p=0.0015) post caffeine administration (variation=33.7% and 41.3% respectively). PC-CVR and BOLD-CVR were reduced by 32.7%(p=0.006) and 22.5%(p=0.006) respectivelyImpact: This study's findings provide valuable insights into the impact of caffeine on cerebrovascular reactivity (CVR), revealing a significant reduction after caffeine intake. Findings would be beneficial in reducing the inter-subject variability of CVR by improving the sensitivity in detecting abnormalities.</description>
      <author>Dinil Sasi Sankaralayam, Zeqing Hu, Cuimei Xu, Dengrong Jiang, Peiying Liu, Abhay Moghekar, Hanzhang Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/4881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-centennial climate change in a warming world beyond 2100</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3377</link>
      <description>Sun&#8208;Seon Lee, Sahil Sharma, Nan Rosenbloom, Keith B. Rodgers, Ji&#8208;Eun Kim, Eun Young Kwon, Christian Franzke, In&#8208;Won Kim, Mohanan Geethalekshmi Sreeush, Karl Stein, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404775362

                Abstract. Sustained anthropogenic perturbations are anticipated to influence Earth's climate system well beyond the 21st century. Despite growing interest in climate change after 2100 and improved computational resources, multi-century climate projections remain limited in number. Here, we examine a set of 10 ensemble simulations extending the Community Earth System Model 2 large ensemble (CESM2-LE) from 2101 to 2500 under the shared socio-economic pathway (SSP)3-7.0 scenario, which involves the reduction of fossil and industrial CO2 emissions to zero by 2250. By the year 2500, substantial forced changes are projected in both the spatial and temporal characteristics of variability and mean states. Post-2100, El Ni&#241;o-Southern Oscillation variability is expected to diminish, while the tropical intraseasonal variability will notably strengthen. The mean state changes include a global mean temperature rise of 12 &#176;C and a 23.5 % increase in global precipitation compared with historical observations. Additionally, substantial soil carbon release from permafrost thawing is projected over Siberia and Canada, resulting in a shift of land from a carbon sink to a carbon source after the 22nd century. The ocean experiences a rapidly diminished capacity to absorb anthropogenic CO2 after the 21st century, while nevertheless continuing to act as a carbon sink, with an increased contribution from the Southern Ocean to total carbon uptake. The model also projects a considerable decline in low-latitude marine primary production, which is linked to a considerable depletion of PO4 in the local mesopelagic domain. At urban scales, the extended simulations reveal substantial projected changes in the amplitude and phasing of precipitation seasonality, with the same holding for the partial pressure of CO2 in seawater at regional scales, demonstrating that post-2100 changes are not simply amplifications of projected 21st century changes. Taken together, these new simulations highlight the far-reaching impacts of multi-centennial climate change on both human societies and global ecosystems.</description>
      <author>Sun&#8208;Seon Lee, Sahil Sharma, Nan Rosenbloom, Keith B. Rodgers, Ji&#8208;Eun Kim, Eun Young Kwon, Christian Franzke, In&#8208;Won Kim, Mohanan Geethalekshmi Sreeush, Karl Stein</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying Information Gap Decision Theory for Uncertainty Management in Building Lifecycle Assessment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14123729</link>
      <description>Tris Kee, Frankie Fu, Buildings. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404668695

                This study applies Info-Gap Decision Theory (IGDT) to manage uncertainties in early-stage lifecycle assessment (LCA) in the building sector, focusing on carbon emissions and cost optimization. The building industry significantly contributes to global carbon emissions, making robust LCA models crucial for achieving environmental improvements. Traditional LCA methods often overlook deep uncertainties, leading to unreliable outcomes. To address this, this research integrates IGDT, providing a non-probabilistic approach that enhances decision-making under uncertainty. The study develops an optimization model that considers uncertainties in material choices, supplier selection, and transportation logistics, demonstrated through a case study of a Science and Technology Expo Pavilion in Chongqing, China. The results show that manufacturing processes are the main source of carbon emissions, with transportation having a smaller but notable impact. Significant emission reductions can be achieved by using alternative materials like fly ash and volcanic ash in cement production. Strategic supplier selection, based on the cost per ton of CO2 reduction, balances environmental impact with economic feasibility. IGDT provides a robust framework for managing uncertainty, helping building projects to achieve sustainability targets even under deep uncertainty, thereby supporting the industry&#8217;s efforts towards net-zero emissions.</description>
      <author>Tris Kee, Frankie Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14123729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Ga, Sr, and Ce on Ni/DSZ95 Catalyst for Methane Partial Oxidation in Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120851</link>
      <description>Salma A. Al&#8208;Zahrani, Omer Bellahwel, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Mohammed F. Alotibi, Najat Masood, Sahar Y. Rajeh, Ahmed Al Otaibi, Hessah Difallah A. Al-Enazy, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404691554

                The greenhouse gas CH4 is more potent than CO2, although both these gases are solely responsible for global warming. The efficient catalytic conversion of CH4 into hydrogen-rich syngas, which also demonstrates economic viability, can deplete the concentration of CH4. This study examines the partial oxidation of methane (POM) prepared by the wetness impregnation process using 5% Ni supported over DSZ95 (93.3% ZrO2 + 6.7% Sc2O3) and promoted with 1% Ga (gallium), 1% Sr (strontium), and 1% Ce (cerium). These catalysts are characterized by surface area porosity, X-ray diffraction, FT-Infrared spectroscopy, Raman infrared spectroscopy, temperature programmed reduction, CO2 temperature-programmed techniques, desorption techniques, thermogravimetry, and transmission electron microscopy. The characterization results demonstrate that Ni is appropriate for the POM because of its crystalline structure, improved metal support contact, and increased thermal stability with Sr, Ce, and Ga promoters. The synthesized catalyst 5Ni+1Ga-DSZ95 maintained stability for 240 min on stream during the POM at 700 &#176;C. Adding a 1% Ga promoter and active metal Ni to the DSZ95 improved the CH4 conversion from 70.00% to 75.90% and raised the H2 yield from 69.21% to 74.80%, while maintaining the reactants&#8217; stoichiometric ratio of (CH4:O2 = 2:1). The 5Ni+1Ga-DSZ95 catalyst is superior to the other catalysts, given its rich catalyst surface, strong metal support interaction, high surface area and low amount of carbon deposit. The high H2/CO ratio (&gt;2.6) and H2 yield close to 75% indicate that 5Ni+1Ga-DSZ95 is a potent industrial catalyst for hydrogen-rich syngas production through partial oxidation of methane.</description>
      <author>Salma A. Al&#8208;Zahrani, Omer Bellahwel, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Mohammed F. Alotibi, Najat Masood, Sahar Y. Rajeh, Ahmed Al Otaibi, Hessah Difallah A. Al-Enazy, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triple Validation of Calibrated Building Energy Models with Different Air Infiltration Values</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app142310828</link>
      <description>Gabriela Bastos Porsani, Juan Bautista Echeverr&#237;a Trueba, Carlos Fern&#225;ndez Bandera, Applied Sciences. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635567

                Model calibration refines design-stage inputs to align with real-world building performance. Accurate parameter selection, especially for highly sensitive variables like air leakage, is crucial. This study compared two building energy model calibration methods. The &#8220;classic&#8221; method adjusted indoor air capacitance, internal mass, and air infiltration, while a novel method focused on capacitance and internal mass, using empirical data for infiltration. The infiltration values were calculated using the decay equation and the EnergyPlus equations with site-specific coefficients. A triple validation assessed model performance in terms of temperature (CIBSE TM63), energy consumption (minimization), and indoor air quality (represented by CO2 levels in accordance with the ASTM D5157 Standard). Results demonstrated the novel method&#8217;s superiority across all three performance metrics. All calibrated models met the CIBSE TM63 criteria even during the validation period, which was five times longer than the training period. Compared to the classic method, models incorporating dynamic empirical infiltration showed a 29% and 26% improvement in MAE and RMSE, respectively, in temperature prediction. In energy consumption results, the novel method models presented a 31% reduction, and for CO2 level agreement, these models achieved a 130% higher R&#178; value than the classic model. In addition, the classic method&#8217;s infiltration values failed to meet ASTM D5157 requirements, suggesting reliance on unrealistic parameter values for accurate temperature representation. The incorporation of calculated air leakage data into the BEM allowed a more realistic estimation of capacitance and internal mass values, emphasizing the importance of accurate air infiltration modeling for overall model reliability.</description>
      <author>Gabriela Bastos Porsani, Juan Bautista Echeverr&#237;a Trueba, Carlos Fern&#225;ndez Bandera</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app142310828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Cold Thermal Energy Storage for Air Conditioning Demand in a CO2 Refrigeration System at a Supermarket</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235923</link>
      <description>Davide Tommasini, H&#229;kon Selvnes, Armin Hafner, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404721627

                A common configuration for transcritical CO2 booster systems in supermarkets involves air conditioning (AC) supplied by cooling a water-glycol circuit. The design capacity of the refrigeration unit must handle all refrigeration loads and the AC load during the hottest summer day, leading to overcapacity and part-load operation for most of the year. A proposed design for implementing cold thermal energy storage (CTES) dedicated to AC demand in a supermarket located in the Oslo region is modeled in the object-oriented language Modelica. Simulation results demonstrate an electricity peak power reduction of up to 32.33%. Even though energy savings are not the primary objective of this project, they are achieved by producing and storing energy when the outdoor temperature is lower, and the coefficient of performance (COP) of the system is higher. The energy savings can reach up to 11.8%. Finally, the economic benefits of the system are assessed under the spot pricing system, revealing potential electricity cost savings of up to 12.56%.</description>
      <author>Davide Tommasini, H&#229;kon Selvnes, Armin Hafner</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17235923</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PR015-23206-R01 Centrifugal Compressor Station Efficiency Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55274/r0000102</link>
      <description>Kelsi Katcher, Abhay Patil, Reese Roddy, Subhra Shankha Koley, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404633359

                The Compressor and Pump Station Technical Committee of Pipeline Research Council International (PRCI) has identified a need to reduce fuel and energy consumption at centrifugal compressor stations by improving the operating efficiency of centrifugal compressors at off-design conditions. It is commonplace for centrifugal compressors to operate well away from their original design point (and best efficiency point); this is generally due to (1) compressor stations needing to operate over an increasingly wide range of conditions and (2) economics favoring the installation of 1 or 2 large compressors as opposed to multiple smaller units. The objective of this project was to identify effective and impactful modifications that can be applied at centrifugal compressor sta-tions to improve operating efficiency and reduce the fuel/energy consumption. Case studies were evaluated for select technologies using historical operator data to demonstrate the performance improvement potential. For the top performing case studies, the net present value and emissions reduction were evaluated using the PRCI CO2 Economic Analysis Tool.</description>
      <author>Kelsi Katcher, Abhay Patil, Reese Roddy, Subhra Shankha Koley</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55274/r0000102</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Blast-Pile Image Analysis in a Mine-to-Crusher Model to Minimize Overall Costs in a Large-Scale Open-Pit Mine in Brazil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/mining4040055</link>
      <description>Vidal F&#233;lix Navarro Torres, Fabiano Veloso Ferreira, Victor Albuquerque de Carvalho, Eltton Veras, Felipe Fran&#231;a Sit&#244;nio, Mining. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404638228

                Amazon rainforests have many hidden treasures; thus, a balance between mine activities and the environment must be maintained. In the northern region of Brazil, there is a large diversity of metal ore deposits, the exploitation of which requires innovative and sustainable mining operations. Historically, mining operations have caused various environmental issues, such as landscape deterioration, damage to natural structures due to detonations, and soil and water pollution, and have also contributed to CO2 emissions from diesel trucks. Here, to estimate and minimize the operating expenses of a large-scale open-pit iron mine, a mine-to-crusher model was developed. The calibration of the mine-to-crusher model was based on rock fragmentation from the blasting phase through the primary crushing phase from an analysis of pictures of the fragmented pile. A reduction in cost was determined for an optimum 90% passing size (P90). The calibration was performed with technical and economic parameters from 2 years before. For the studied iron ore mine site, an optimum P90 value between 0.29 and 0.31 m was determined.</description>
      <author>Vidal F&#233;lix Navarro Torres, Fabiano Veloso Ferreira, Victor Albuquerque de Carvalho, Eltton Veras, Felipe Fran&#231;a Sit&#244;nio</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/mining4040055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High vulnerability of the endemic Southern Ocean snail Neobuccinum eatoni (Buccinidae) to critical projected oceanographic changes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-80353-x</link>
      <description>Rosvita Gonz&#225;lez, Luis R. Pertierra, Pablo Guerrero, Angie D&#237;az, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404659606

                Climate change is projected to substantially alter the Southern Ocean's physical and chemical properties, thereby impacting its marine ecosystems and species, particularly those in Antarctic and sub-Antarctic regions. This study focuses on Neobuccinum eatoni, a polar marine 'true whelk' endemic to these regions, utilizing 166 spatially independent occurrence data records to model potential distribution shifts under future climate scenarios. Employing Species Distribution Models (SDMs) on spatially cross-validated occurrences, we achieved high predictive accuracy, identifying "sea water salinity range" at mean bottom depth as the most significant predictor of habitat preferences. Additionally, dissolved iron (minimum), ocean temperature (range), and pH (long-term maximum) emerged as critical factors influencing the species' modeled distribution. By 2050, future projections under the SSP2-4.5 scenario predict an eastward expansion, particularly in the Antarctic Peninsula, the Scotia Arc and the Weddell Sea, with an expansion in the latter region also predicted under the SSP5-8.5 scenario. However, in both scenarios, a reduction in habitat suitability is expected in certain sectors around the Antarctic continent and the Kerguelen Archipelago. By 2100, under the moderate emissions scenario (SSP2-4.5), the species is projected to move to deeper areas and lower latitudes, with notable expansions in the Weddell Sea and in the Southern Ocean surrounding the Kerguelen Archipelago. However, under the SSP5-8.5 scenario, expansion is projected in the Weddell Sea and reductions in Antarctic and subantarctic regions. This study highlights the critical influence of changing salinity on N. eatoni's distribution, predicting a significant habitat reduction under high CO2 emissions scenarios (SSP5-8.5). The findings underscore the urgent need for focused research on the vulnerability of endemic marine invertebrates to develop effective conservation strategies in the face of rapid climatic changes.</description>
      <author>Rosvita Gonz&#225;lez, Luis R. Pertierra, Pablo Guerrero, Angie D&#237;az</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-80353-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolated High-Gain DC-DC Converter with Nanocrystalline-Core Transformer: Achieving 1:16 Voltage Boost for Renewable Energy Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/technologies12120246</link>
      <description>Tania Elizabeth Sandoval Valencia, Dante Ruiz-Robles, Jorge Ort&#237;z-Mar&#237;n, Jesus Alejandro Franco, Quetzalc&#243;atl Hern&#225;ndez-Escobedo, Edgar L. Moreno&#8208;Goytia, Technologies. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404759042

                This paper presents an isolated DC-DC converter with high voltage gain that features an advanced inter-built nanocrystalline-core medium-frequency transformer (NC-MFT). The isolated DC-DC converter with an NC-MFT is specifically designed for applications such as interconnect photovoltaic (PV) systems, DC microgrids, DC loads, and DC buses, where voltage gain is one of the essential issues to consider. The NC-MFT inside the DC-DC converter is designed with a new approach that not only provides isolation but also contributes to achieving high efficiency and a higher step-up ratio. The high efficiency of the converters contributes to the integration of PV systems into DC microgrids. The converter yields a high voltage conversion ratio of 16.17. The experimental results obtained at 41.8 V/676 V and 275 W for the prototype revealed high efficiency (95.63% at full load). The experimental results validate the theoretical analysis and simulation, confirming that the converter achieves the main objective of high voltage conversion and high efficiency. These results will contribute to the interest in the use of this type of energy and its impact on the reduction in CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Tania Elizabeth Sandoval Valencia, Dante Ruiz-Robles, Jorge Ort&#237;z-Mar&#237;n, Jesus Alejandro Franco, Quetzalc&#243;atl Hern&#225;ndez-Escobedo, Edgar L. Moreno&#8208;Goytia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/technologies12120246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Forecasting Framework Based on Advanced Machine Learning Algorithms for Greenhouse Gas Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/systems12120528</link>
      <description>Seval ENE YAL&#199;IN, Systems. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404757860

                The reduction of greenhouse gas emissions, in order to effectively address the issue of climate change, has critical importance worldwide. To achieve this aim and implement the necessary strategies and policies, the projection of greenhouse gas emissions is essential. This paper presents a forecasting framework for greenhouse gas emissions based on advanced machine learning algorithms: multivariable linear regression, random forest, k-nearest neighbor, extreme gradient boosting, support vector, and multilayer perceptron regression algorithms. The algorithms employ several input variables associated with greenhouse gas emission outputs. In order to evaluate the applicability and performance of the developed framework, nationwide statistical data from Turkey are employed as a case study. The dataset of the case study includes six input variables and annual sectoral and total greenhouse gas emissions in CO2 eq. as output variables. This paper provides a scenario-based approach for future forecasts of greenhouse gas emissions and a sector-based analysis of greenhouse gas emissions in the case country considering multiple input variables. The present study indicates that the stated machine learning algorithms can be successfully applied to the forecasting of greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
      <author>Seval ENE YAL&#199;IN</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/systems12120528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of nonmetal F&#8208;doped Co3O4 as catalyst for N2O catalytic decomposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401659</link>
      <description>Ruifang Wu, Qian Wang, Ruirui Wang, Xianqing Lin, Hui Dang, Linmao Li, S. H. Hu, Mingxia Yang, Ke Zheng, Liang&#8208;Liang Zhang, Yongzhao Wang, Yongxiang Zhao, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404700147

                An effective nonmetal F&#8208;doped Co3O4 ( F&#8208;Co3O4) catalyst was prepared using co&#8208;precipitation method, and its catalytic performance was investigated for N2O decomposition comparing with pure Co3O4 catalyst. The catalytic activity test indicates that F&#8208;Co3O4 catalyst exhibits better activity with 100% N2O conversion at a reaction temperature of 380 &#8451;, which is 80 &#8451; lower than that of pure Co3O4. The characterization results show that F is successfully doped into the lattice of Co3O4 and replaces part of O sites, which enlarges the surface area, enhances the surface basicity and leads to higher basic sites density on the surface of Co3O4. Moreover, F doping promotes the electron donation capacity of Co2+, weakening of Co&#8208;O bond and generation of more oxygen vacancies. The synergy of the above factors results in reduction of activation energy over F&#8208;Co3O4 catalyst, thus F&#8208;Co3O4 catalyst exhibits better catalytic performance than pure Co3O4 for N2O decomposition, even in the existence of O2 or H2O as impurity gas. Meanwhile, F&#8208;Co3O4 catalyst also exhibits better stability than pure Co3O4. This work will provide practical reference for constructing efficient nonmetal&#8208;doped Co3O4 catalysts for N2O decomposition.</description>
      <author>Ruifang Wu, Qian Wang, Ruirui Wang, Xianqing Lin, Hui Dang, Linmao Li, S. H. Hu, Mingxia Yang, Ke Zheng, Liang&#8208;Liang Zhang, Yongzhao Wang, Yongxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Javeriana Cali&#8217; Strategic Plan for the Sustainable Management: An Example of How to Implement, Disseminate and Evaluate Sustainability Policies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14710/jsp.2024.25044</link>
      <description>Isabella Tello, Jos&#233; Aguilar, Journal of Sustainability Perspectives. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404767123

                In order to organize the multiple actions the Universidad Javeriana had been developing for the sustainable management of its campus, a strategic plan was structured. The plan is structured in five major programs: water resources, energy, biodiversity, recycling and reduction of CO2 emissions. For the definition of these five programs we were inspired by the contributions of the thematic structure of Green Metrics, the recommendations of the Encyclical Laudato Si and the SDGs. In turn, each program is broken down into sub-programs, projects and sub-projects. Each program also includes cross-cutting strategies articulated in sub-programs which are broken down into research projects, semester projects, graduate work and theses. Also, sub-programs for disseminating initiatives and entrepreneurship are considered. The planning instrument is taken to the detail of operational planning, using the Gantt Chart. A team coordinates the coordination of the different programs and meets weekly to review its progress. The plan was presented and approved to the University's Steering Committee, and the document has been incorporated into the University's Strategic Plan. It is also being used to link professors from civil engineering, electronics and architecture careers who invite students to carry out semester or degree work on topics that strengthen campus execution.</description>
      <author>Isabella Tello, Jos&#233; Aguilar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14710/jsp.2024.25044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divergent effects of 3-nitrooxypropanol on enteric methane emissions in Holstein and Brown Swiss cows, and its lack of synergy with Acacia mearnsii tannin extract</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.24.625036</link>
      <description>Z. Islam, S.E. R&#228;is&#228;nen, Tengfei He, Carmen Kunz, Yang Li, Xiaowen Ma, Aira Maye Serviento, Kai Wang, Meiqing Wang, Zhibo Zeng, Mutian Niu, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404663640

                The objectives of this study were to investigate the combined effects of 3-nitrooxypropanol (3-NOP) and Acacia mearnsii tannin extract (TAN), and their interactions with dairy cattle breed [Brown Swiss (BS) vs. Holstein Friesian (HF)], on lactational performance, and enteric methane (CH4) emissions. Sixteen multiparous mid-lactation cows, including 8 BS and 8 HF cows were used in a split-plot design, with breed as the main plot. Cows within each subplot were arranged in a replicated 4 x 4 Latin Square design with a 2 x 2 factorial arrangement of treatments across four 24-d periods. The experimental diets were: 1) CON (basal total mixed ration), 2) 3-NOP (60 mg/kg DM), 3) TAN (3% of DM), and 4) 3-NOP + TAN. Spot samples of urine, feces, and gas emissions (via GreenFeed) were collected at the end of each period 8 times over 3 days. No 3-NOP x TAN x Breed interactions were observed for DM intake (DMI), milk production, or enteric gas emissions, except for CH4 yield (g/kg DMI) and CO2 production. Breed influenced DMI, milk production, and component yields, with HF cows consuming 3.7 kg/d more DMI, producing 9.3 kg/d more milk, and achieving greater feed efficiency and higher milk component yields than BS cows. Milk yield and energy-corrected milk (ECM) tended to increase in HF but tended to decrease in BS cows by 3-NOP. Cows fed TAN had 1 kg/d lower DMI with the tendency for 3-NOP x TAN showed greater reduction when TAN was fed alone, but milk yield, ECM, and feed efficiency remained unchanged. Cows fed TAN exhibited 18% lower milk urea nitrogen (N) concentration and 23.0% lower urinary N but 36.7% greater fecal N excretions as a percentage of daily N intake. A 3-NOP x Breed interaction was observed in CH4 production (g/d), with a 21.7% reduction in HF, and a 13.0% reduction in BS. Similarly, there were 3-NOP x Breed tendencies in CH4 yield and intensity (g/kg ECM), with reductions in HF cows of 21.8% and 23.4%, respectively, compared to 11.0% and 10.8% in BS cows. In conclusion, there were no synergistic or additive effects between 3-NOP and TAN on enteric CH4 mitigation. The enteric CH4 emission mitigating effect of 3-NOP was more pronounced in HF cows than in BS cows. Further research is needed to understand breed-specific responses and to optimize CH4 mitigation strategies for inclusion in national greenhouse gas inventories.</description>
      <author>Z. Islam, S.E. R&#228;is&#228;nen, Tengfei He, Carmen Kunz, Yang Li, Xiaowen Ma, Aira Maye Serviento, Kai Wang, Meiqing Wang, Zhibo Zeng, Mutian Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.24.625036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupled Design and Operation Optimization for Decarbonization of Industrial Energy Systems Using an Open-Source In-House Tool</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/eng5040158</link>
      <description>Rushit Kansara, Mar&#237;a Isabel Rold&#225;n Serrano, Eng&#8212;Advances in Engineering. 5(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404638424

                The decarbonization of industrial energy systems which comprise different networks (such as steam, water, electric power, fuel sources) is crucial for mitigating climate change and achieving sustainability goals. This paper presents a comprehensive methodology integrated in an open-source in-house tool for the coupled design and operation optimization of energy systems in industrial settings. The proposed approach integrates advanced optimization techniques with modeling of energy systems including properties like mass flow and temperature to simultaneously optimize both design parameters and operational strategies. The methodology encompasses the optimized integration of various energy technologies, such as renewable energy technologies, energy storage, and power-to-heat technologies while considering changing operational conditions and variable energy demand and supply. A multi-objective optimization framework is employed to balance conflicting targets, such as minimizing greenhouse gas emissions, operational costs, and ensuring system reliability. The in-house tool application considering a case study based on a food industry process demonstrates the effectiveness of the proposed approach in significantly reducing carbon footprints as well as operational and investment costs compared to traditional low-fidelity methods incorporated in commercial tools. The optimized concept achieved through the in-house tool has shown 8.5% less emission (EMI) compared to the optimized designs of the commercial tool. It shows 36% reduction in CO2 emissions compared to the existing facility of the case study. The optimized energy concept can be implemented in the existing facility with a payback period of 4.6 years. The outcomes of the selected use-case highlight the importance of coordinated design and operation decisions in achieving optimal performance and sustainability in industrial energy systems. It also shows an ideal workflow for making optimized design decisions to decarbonize industry with novel energy concepts. Thus, this work provides a robust foundation for future research and practical applications aimed at accelerating the transition towards low-carbon industrial processes.</description>
      <author>Rushit Kansara, Mar&#237;a Isabel Rold&#225;n Serrano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/eng5040158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of Electric Vehicle Charging Stations on the Quality of Power Supply to the Consumer in Novosibirsk 10/0.4 KV Electrical Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25729/esr.2023.02.0007</link>
      <description>Moises Carlos Tanca-Villanueva, LU Ya, Atamanova O.S., Yurkov S.A., M. A., Energy Systems Research. 6(2(22))] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4404610557

                Currently, there is a massive use of electric vehicles in the world. This is due to the ever-increasing importance and severity of the environmental safety issue. Now, there is no more convenient, affordable, popular and at the same time less harmful alternative to road transport. The annual global emissions are more than 25 million tons of pollutants of various origins, which are extremely dangerous for nature in general. On average, they increase by 3% every year. The transport sector accounts for 23% of all greenhouse gas emissions in the world. Electric vehicles can contribute enormously to the reduction in greenhouse gas emissions. In 2025, sales of electric vehicles are expected to increase to 100 000 units. By 2030, the number of electric vehicles will reach 1.5 million units. However, widespread adoption of electric vehicles will cause an increase in electricity consumption. In addition, an appropriate charging infrastructure is required to power electric vehicles. It is worth noting that the market for electric vehicles and charging stations is developing dynamically with an annual growth rate up to 80%. The main barriers to the development of electric vehicles in Russia are their high cost and underdeveloped network of charging stations. The relevance of the problem is confirmed by an order signed by Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin in March 2022 to allocate about 1.37 billion rubles for the creation of charging infrastructure for electric vehicles in Russia. As for incentives, there are many of them. This is the need to solve the environmental problem in large cities, achieve the goal of reducing CO2 emissions and pursue industrial policy, including the policy of innovative development of the country. Another way of increasing the payback of charging stations is the employment of smart services, which can reduce the cost of technological connection through dynamic power distribution between the main facility and the charging station. There are other, more advanced solutions, which are currently being piloted, such as optimization of investment in network infrastructure, including an operator of a regional public charging infrastructure. This study focuses on the development of a power supply system to connect an electric vehicle charging station to a substation in Novosibirsk. The connected electric vehicle charger, being a non-linear load, can not only increase the load on the power grid infrastructure, but also cause a deterioration in the power quality due to the generation of harmonic distortions. Therefore, special attention is paid to the analysis of the power supply quality during the operation of the charging station by using the model developed in the MATLAB Simulink software for the analysis of harmonics.</description>
      <author>Moises Carlos Tanca-Villanueva, LU Ya, Atamanova O.S., Yurkov S.A., M. A.</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25729/esr.2023.02.0007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editorial for the Special Issue: Research at the SKKU Institute of Energy Science and Technology (SIEST), Sungkyunkwan University</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404864</link>
      <description>Nam&#8208;Gyu Park, Won&#8208;Sub Yoon, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404656974

                We are delighted to present this special issue of Advanced Energy Materials, which brings together research and progress on future energy conversion, next-generation batteries, and advanced green energy. This issue includes studies on solar cells, lithium batteries, display technologies, microenergy harvesting, and hydrogen production, all performed at the SKKU Institute of Energy Science and Technology (SIEST), Sungkyunkwan University. SIEST was established on March 1, 2022, to support advanced energy science and technology through collective efforts in energy conversion, storage, and harvesting. Leading-edge scientists in these fields have joined forces to enhance research collaboration and address global energy challenges. As we navigate the complex landscape of energy materials and devices, these studies and review articles offer transformative insights and solutions that push the boundaries of current technology. This issue is a testament to the innovative spirit driving the field forward, showcasing a diverse range of topics from perovskite solar cells to the development of next-generation batteries. To improve the efficiency and stability of solar cells, particularly perovskite solar cells, optimizing interface chemistry is crucial. Three topics are presented for this purpose, dealing with the interfacial reaction in perovskite solar cells by introducing novel dopants into the hole-transporting molecular layer (article number 2402144), the cation disorder engineering in chalcogenide-based absorber for improving the deposition method (article number 2402099), and carbazole-treated waterproof perovskite films to provide a solution to the perennial problem of moisture sensitivity in perovskites for better durability (article number 2401965). Cutting-edge lithium battery research is also discussed as part of the special issue. The article entitled "Navigating the carbon maze: A roadmap to effective carbon conductive networks for lithium-ion batteries" (article number 2400499) provides a comprehensive guide to optimizing carbon networks in lithium-ion batteries. The article on dual flame-retardant mechanism is helpful in suppression of thermal runaway in lithium metal batteries (article number 2304366), which can tackle the critical issue of safety, proposing mechanisms to prevent thermal runaway in lithium metal batteries. Strategies to enhance battery performance under constrained electrolyte conditions are discussed in the article entitled "Advancing post-secondary batteries under lean electrolyte conditions through interfacial modification strategies" (article number 2400035). Advances in blue energy and triboelectric energy harvesting highlight exciting developments in energy harvesting technologies. The article entitled "Advances in blue energy fuels: harvesting energy from ocean for self-powered electrolysis" introduces new methods to harness energy from ocean waves, providing a sustainable approach to hydrogen production (article number 2400563). An integrated system that combines triboelectric energy harvesting with modern communication technologies is discussed to offer potential applications in low-power devices (article number 2400481). Perovskite quantum dot technologies see rising importance in energy conversion and display-related research fields. Superfluorescence is discussed with metal halide perovskites to offer insights that could lead to highly efficient optoelectronic devices (article number 2400322). The cross-correlation between crystallinity and optoelectronic properties of perovskite thin films is discussed via multiple time-resolved spectroscopy to provide insights into optimizing device performance (article number 2400225). The question how to achieve near-perfect quantum yield in quantum dots can be answered from the article entitled "Unlocking invisible defects of ZnSe alloy shells in giant quantum dots with near unity quantum yield" (article number 2400148). Research on hydrogen production and electrochemical cells is also prominently featured by two articles. "Interface engineering to operate reversible protonic ceramic electrochemical cells below 500 &#176;C" (article number 2400124) presents strategies to improve the operation of protonic ceramic electrochemical cells at lower temperatures, and "Computational design of optimized modular photovoltaic electrochemical reactor for energy efficient CO2-to-Cn reduction reaction with band gap tunable perovskite tandem cells" highlighting the potential of computational design in creating efficient reactors for CO2 reduction, integrating photovoltaic and electrochemical technologies (article number 2304492). This is but a small selection of the topics covered and the diverse array of studies in this special issue underscores the importance of interdisciplinary approaches and technological integration in advancing energy materials and devices. From the exploration of new materials and processes to the development of innovative energy conversion systems, the contributions in this special issue pave the way for future research and applications in sustainable energy. We extend our deepest gratitude to the authors for their invaluable contributions and to the reviewers for their critical insights and rigorous evaluations. We hope this special issue inspires continued innovation and collaboration in the field of advanced energy materials. Nam-Gyu Park and Won-Sub Yoon Guest Editors Advanced Energy Materials</description>
      <author>Nam&#8208;Gyu Park, Won&#8208;Sub Yoon</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fossil Fuel Fa&#231;ade</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5204/mcj.3120</link>
      <description>Robyn Gulliver, M/C Journal. 27(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404730894

                Introduction Our era of urgent climate action is underpinned by a perplexing paradox: a continued reliance on fossil fuels is presented as a solution to the very crisis it perpetuates. We live in a world where this logical inconsistency is normalised and accepted; an artificial fantasy realm where we can have our fossil fuel cake and eat it as well. In this realm, society, business, and government acknowledge the reality of climate change and its cause, yet do little to alleviate it. Instead, they express bi-partisan support for zero emissions targets while expanding fossil fuel projects, and promote corporate decarbonisation pledges while advocating against legislation reducing greenhouse gas emissions. They celebrate manipulated emissions reduction data while pushing aside the reality of rapidly breaking heat records (UN News) and decades of locked-in continuous emissions increases (Bhatia) through unabated approvals of coal and gas mines (Roe and Lowrey). Our ability to construct and sustain artificial worlds is nothing new, having long featured in philosophical discourse. From Plato's Allegory of the Cave&#8212;where prisoners mistake shadows for reality&#8212;to modern conspiracy theories, people have long explored and exploited the notion that our understanding of the world has flexible epistemological foundations which can be easily manipulated. Modern scholars have expanded this analysis to a societal scale. For example, Jean Baudrillard explored how media and symbols can create a 'hyperreality' that obscures or replaces objective truth (Wolny), while Noam Chomsky and Edward Herman analysed the mechanisms of 'manufacturing consent', whereby public opinion is carefully curated to align with specific interests (Chomsky and Herman). Through our growing immersion in online communities, networks of power work to create epistemic bubbles and echo chambers. Information is curated to reinforce existing beliefs and exclude contradictory evidence, leveraging our tendency to reject information that does not align with our beliefs. These blurred lines of the fossil-fuelled artificial reality can be difficult to discern given the entrenched role these resources play in our society. Australia is one of the world&#8217;s largest fossil fuel exporters, with one of the highest carbon emissions per capita (Grant and Hare). Fossil fuels hold a central place in the Australian economy, community, and psyche (Botrel et al.). The pervasive grip of the fossil fuel industry compels our continued consumption regardless of climate concerns while offering few pathways for escape. This creates a profound cognitive dissonance: we must simultaneously acknowledge climate change while participating in the very systems that accelerate it. Not only that: in managing this psychological tension, we acquiesce to the industry&#8217;s preferred narrative of an ongoing fossil-fuelled future (Wright et al.). In this mythical future, fossil fuel expansion will bring unbridled collective goods so long as we sweep away any inconvenient concerns about climate change from our thoughts. In doing so, the direct link between fossil fuel production and carbon emissions is severed: rendered trivial, eclipsed by the carefully constructed myth of fossil fuel dependence. And thus a new world comes into existence, one where the use of fossil fuels becomes both necessary and inevitable. In this article, I explore the many channels by which the fossil fuel industry has constructed this artificial reality. I draw on parallels between the tactics employed by the fossil fuel industry and those previously used by other health- and planet-harming industries, particularly the tobacco industry (Lacy-Nichols et al.). Using data compiled from a comprehensive longitudinal database of state and federal lobbying registers, combined with online and archival sources, the following sections explore how the industry and its enablers wield these strategies to perpetuate this artificial reality. The Construction of the Artificial Fossil-Fuelled World Strategy 1: Constructing and Controlling the Narrative Sustaining this artificial reality requires narratives that mask fossil fuels' climate destruction. A veneer of plausibility justifies acceptance of this reality, making it crucial for the industry to control the narrative of its societal role. Accordingly, industry-favoured solutions&#8212;such as carbon capture and storage&#8212;are framed as 'common sense' (Parkin). Mirroring Gramsci&#8217;s concept of "cultural hegemony", this pro-fossil fuel ideology is perpetuated through the extensive material, organisational, and communicative power of the industry, allowing it to be accepted as natural and inevitable (Blondeel). These resources fuel the small army of PR firms, lobbyists, think tanks, and 'junk scientists', who all play various roles in customising narratives for different audiences in a way that is most likely to maintain this artificial reality, as described below (Hoggan and Littlemore). Promoting gas as a transition fuel. The idea of a &#8216;transition&#8217; fuel has been highly effective in neutralising threats to fossil fuel extraction as well as renewable energy challenges (Heras 49). Through dedicated websites and industry reports like "Gas Vision 2050" the industry reframes gas as a climate solution while avoiding direct discussion of its climate impacts. This extends to misleading claims; the Australian Petroleum Production and Exploration Association (APPEA) framed gas as 50% cleaner than an unspecified alternative fuel, in claims subsequently found to have breached environmental advertising codes (Ad Standards Community Panel). Sowing doubt from denial to delay. Despite knowing about climate change since the 1960s, companies like Exxon Mobile promoted scepticism for decades (Bennett). Today, this narrative has now shifted from denial to delay (Hoggan and Littlemore). The industry acknowledges climate change while claiming its fossil fuel expansion serves the public good. Net zero targets are one particularly prominent narrative of delay: companies promote targets to postpone meaningful action while maintaining an appearance of progress (e.g., APPEA's rebranding to Australian Energy Producers). Another example is natural gas company Tamboran Resources, which mirrors this narrative in front-page claims about their net zero vision, despite its role in the controversial Beetaloo fracking project set to emit more greenhouse gases than all Pacific Island nations combined (Ogge, Emissions). Emphasising economic benefits. The fossil fuel industry maintains legitimacy by emphasising economic benefits and jobs (Bryson). Both major political parties adhere to this framing, enabling fossil fuel expansion to continue unabated while the role of other industries in providing jobs&#8212;such as renewable energy and tourism in the Great Barrier Reef&#8212;gains little space in the narrative (Bryson). Companies like Origin Energy promote direct benefits to landowners as &#8220;a valuable addition to farm income&#8221; (Origin Energy), aligning themselves with economic growth, stability, and the broader national interest while downplaying their role in climate-related disasters (Wright et al.). Capturing the media. Media outlets play a crucial role in reinforcing fossil fuel narratives. Some, like the West Australian, openly support the industry and attack climate initiatives (Dumas). More broadly, media outlets perpetuate the connection between fossil fuels and economic wellbeing, while overstating the industry's employment significance relative to environmental concerns (Nyberg and Wright). Strategy 2: Camouflaging and Greenwashing The second strategy used to maintain this artificial reality is camouflaging and greenwashing. These mechanisms actively work to disguise the industry's harmful impacts and present a deceptively eco-friendly image. They construct a picture of corporate virtue, allow destructive companies to deflect criticism, position themselves as solution providers, and act as mouthpieces for industry (Lacy-Nichols et al.). Fossil fuel companies seek to promote their public role through partnerships in the public sector, while sponsorship and advertising help deflect attention from emissions and minimise criticism (Nyberg and Wright; Plec and Pettenger). Three examples of camouflaging and greenwashing are presented below. Promoting front groups. The Climate Leaders Coalition has 47 members each paying around $3000 a year to join and claim their title as a climate leader (Fernyhough; Climate Leaders Coalition, "About"). Members of the group include major gas producers Santos and Woodside, who ostensibly agree with the statement "We take climate change seriously in our business" (Climate Leaders Coalition, "About"). This group is used as a way to overlay a fake climate lens to climate emissions, with Santos even earning its own climate case study in the 2020 Roadmap to Zero report (Climate Leaders Coalition, Roadmap). Fostering public-private partnerships. The Queensland Resources Council highlighted partnerships between Arrow Energy, Moranbah State High School, and Simply Sunshine Day Care (Queensland Resources Council), while Santos provided funding to Queensland police, regional councils, health committees, and government departments (Santos). Similarly, the Australian Earth Science Education Group is supported by Woodside, Santos, and Chevron, and promotes gas-positive education to children in Years 4-10 (AusEarthEd). Sponsorship and advertising. The Australian Institute of Marine Science, despite its goal of supporting sustainable use and protection of oceans, is sponsored by BHP, Santos, Shell, and Woodside (Australian Institute of Marine Science, "World&#8217;s"; Australian Institute of Marine Science, "Industry"). Fossil fuel companies advertise and sponsor sporting venues like the Canberra Tennis Arena (Rimmer), while hundreds of health, community, and education organisations receive sponsorship from energy companies. Major initiatives like Bright-r invest $750 million in community projects (Bright-r), while partnerships with state governments, like Western Australia&#8217;s Resources Community Investment Initiative, further legitimise the industry. Collectively they create a discourse of community wellbeing, supported by actors across industry, politics, and the media (Wright et al.). Strategy 3: Influencing Public Policy and Research Narrative control alone does not maintain fossil fuel dominance. Instead, "petro-hegemony" describes how companies gain deeper political and economic control through lobbying, undermining science, and funding climate denial (LeQuesne 19; Parkin). Fossil fuel interests are crafted to appear synonymous with democratic governance (LeQuesne), enabling them to counter climate policies that threaten their business model (B&#246;hler et al.). In this "carbon democracy" (LeQuesne), historical links between coal and politics give lobbyists significant policy influence, turning modest economic gains into remarkable political power (Baer 199). As demonstrated below, the industry's extensive financial resources allow for persistent lobbying that climate advocates cannot match (Botrel et al.) often resulting in business-friendly policy outcomes (Meng and Rode). Lobbying. Major gas companies have been shown to engage in "predatory lobbying" to secure investments and influence policy (ACCR). This lobbying also involves developing alternatives to public policy, usually promoting options such as fast-tracking projects, tax breaks, self-regulation, or voluntary commitments. Industry bodies promote self-regulation and reduced climate reporting (EY; Minerals Council of Australia). The revolving door between politics and industry has been demonstrated to have influenced major projects (Lucas) and sought preferential treatment for certain companies such as Beach Energy, Sibelco, and Linc Energy (Aulby and Ogge). These lobbying efforts often emphasise decarbonisation risks to communities and employment, while highlighting the industry's economic contributions (Wright et al.; Minerals Council of Australia). Undermining legitimate science. The distortion of evidence and exaggeration of uncertainty is a well-established tactic to neutralise threats to business models (Lacy-Nichols et al.). The Gas Industry Social and Environmental Research Alliance (GISERA) exemplifies this approach: funded 75% by gas companies and overseen by industry executives (Ogge, GISERA; Australia Institute, &#8220;CSIRO&#8221;; Bambrick et al.), GISERA has been accused of publishing biased reports, such as claiming fracking was environmentally safe based on a limited sample of just six out of Queensland's 19,000 coal seam gas wells, and conducting surveys that inflate apparent support for coal seam gas projects (Australia Institute, &#8220;CSIRO&#8221;; Lock the Gate). Meanwhile, a 2010 Australian Research Council project on CSG health risks was reportedly not undertaken due to the industry partner, Santos, withdrawing funding (McCarron). Strategy 4: Leveraging State Power The alliance between state power and fossil fuel interests combines financial support with dissent suppression, protecting industry interests while maintaining the narrative that fossil fuels are essential for national prosperity. State support for expansion alongside suppression of protection as described below, makes it increasingly difficult for sustainable energy alternatives to gain public traction. Providing government support. State power actively supports fossil fuel expansion (e.g., see Nyberg and Wright), such as Queensland's backing of the Carmichael coal mine despite market doubts (Bryson). State support can be linked to political donations, as suggested by donations to the Western Australia Labor Party by Mineral Resources and Woodside during consideration of increasing gas export allowances (Readfearn). Financial support to the sector is also provided through the estimated A$14.5b annual cost to the state for various fossil fuel subsidies (Australia Institute, "Fossil"). Criminalising protest. Governments and corporations leverage state power to suppress, protest, and convert political communication practices into offences (Gulliver et al., "Criminalisation"). These include new anti-protest laws, expanded applications of existing discretionary powers, and portraying protesters as extremists (Brock et al.; Irwin et al.). Companies also use private security, strategic lawsuits, and surveillance, as well as attempting to remove environmental organisations' charitable status (Al-Azzawi et al.; Hoggan and Littlemore; Kirkwood). Our Shared Duplicity: Moral Disengagement and Identity Capture While personal choices offer accessible forms of dissent, a focus on individual responsibility to reduce individual emissions serves industry interests by deflecting attention from their role in perpetuating fossil fuel dependence. Two key psychological responses emerge to maintain fossil fuel control: moral disengagement and identity capture, both of which may help individuals cope with but ultimately reinforce the status quo. Moral disengagement. The ubiquitous influence wielded by the fossil fuel industry only succeeds because of societal acceptance of fossil fuel norms (Blondeel). These norms are often at their most visible amongst those who work in environmentally destructive industries where employees justify carbon impacts through various strategies: by emphasising the positive outcomes as opposed to the negative influence of their efforts, through promoting gradual change or relying on future solutions, and by dismissing carbon data (Torres-Delgado et al. 1). Identity capture. Simultaneously, climate change beliefs have become deeply tied to personal identity, with stronger identity attachments increasing resistance to change (Marquart-Pyatt et al.). Climate change beliefs are also substantially linked to, and constrained by, political affiliation (Hornsey et al.; Fielding et al.). This identity capture extends to professional spheres, as evidenced by Arctic tourism operators who morally disengage from their environmental impacts while portraying activities as sustainable (Vespestad et al.). Dismantling the Artificial World The industry gains popular consent by normalising the entrenched role of fossil fuels in our lives and rigorously challenging threats that question the assumptions, beliefs, and patterns that maintain these prevailing norms (Blondeel). However, history demonstrates that social movements offer a powerful mechanism for effectively challenging the status quo. Environmental movements constitute a counter-hegemonic force, mobilising resources, establishing alternative institutions, and developing organisational capacity to challenge the dominant power structure (Heras). In Australia, evidence suggests these efforts can be effective (Gulliver et al., "Understanding"; Gulliver et al., "Civil"). Advocacy groups across the country challenge the processes that enable fossil fuel companies and their enablers to perpetuate this artificial world by demanding greater action on climate change and transparency on climate-harming activities. Legal challenges focussing on climate accountability and greenwashing are proving to be effective avenues to shatter the industry's narrative veneer. Yet, despite increasing awareness of these strategies used to maintain this artificial world, emissions continue to rise. Dismantling this artificial world, therefore, requires more: a multifaceted approach that dismantles the industry's narrative control, economic influence, and societal embeddedness. By shifting focus from individual actions to the systemic forces that lock in fossil fuel use, we can more effectively confront the power structures that underpin the fossil fuel industry&#8217;s power. This involves not only challenging the industry directly but also addressing the broader societal and economic structures that enable its continued dominance. Only through coordinated collective action, grounded in a thorough understanding of industry tactics, can society break free of this artificial reality and forge a new world free from its destructive constraints. References 350.org. "Fossil Free Sponsorships." 25 Sep. 2024. &lt;https://cutallties.350.org.au/&gt;. ACCR. "BHP, Origin Energy, Santos &amp; Woodside Aiming to Destroy the Clean Energy Finance Corporation." 28 Aug. 2020. Ad Standards Community Panel. Case Report 0119-23. 2023. &lt;https://adstandards.com.au/sites/default/files/reports/0119-23.pdf&gt;. Al-Azzawi, Yusur, et al. Global Warning: The Threat to Climate Defenders in Australia. Human Rights Law Centre, Greenpeace, Environmental Defenders Office, 2020. Aulby, Hannah, and Mark Ogge. Greasing the Wheels: The Systemic Weaknesses That Allow Undue Influence by Mining Companies on Government: A QLD Case Study. Australian Conservation Foundation and The Australia Institute. AusEarthEd. 2022. &lt;https://web.archive.org/web/20220311201637/https:/ausearthed.com.au/wa/#&gt;. Australia Institute. "CSIRO Report Misleads on Fracking Risks." 14 July 2020. &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;. "Fossil Fuel Subsidies in Australia 2024." 2024. Australian Institute of Marine Science. "Industry Partnerships." 27 Sep. 2024. &lt;https://www.aims.gov.au/partnerships/industry-partnerships&gt;. &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;. "World&#8217;s Brightest in Marine Science Meet in Perth to Mark Major Milestone." 28 Feb. 2019. Baer, Hans A. &#8220;The Nexus of the Coal Industry and the State in Australia: Historical Dimensions and Contemporary Challenges.&#8221; Energy Policy 99 (2016): 194&#8211;202. Bambrick, Hilary, et al. Kicking the Gas Habit: How Gas Is Harming Our Health. The Climate Council, 2021. Bennett, Briony. &#8220;Big Oil, Big Liability: Fossil Fuel Companies and Liability for Climate Change Harm.&#8221; NZJ Environmental Law 23 (2019): 153. Bhatia, Aatish. Carbon Dioxide Levels Have Passed a New Milestone. 20 Apr. 2024. Blondeel, Mathieu. &#8220;Taking Away a &#8216;Social Licence&#8217;: Neo-Gramscian Perspectives on an International Fossil Fuel Divestment Norm.&#8221; Global Transitions 1 (2019): 200&#8211;09. B&#246;hler, Heike, et al. &#8220;Does Climate Advocacy Matter? The Importance of Competing Interest Groups for National Climate Policies.&#8221; Climate Policy 22.8 (2022): 961&#8211;75 Botrel, Clara Almeida, et al. &#8220;Understanding the Lobbying Actions Taken by the Australian Renewable Energy Industry.&#8221; Journal of Cleaner Production 434 (2024): 139674. Brock, Andrea, et al. &#8220;&#8216;Go Home, Get a Job, and Pay Some Taxes to Replace a Bit of What You&#8217;ve Wasted&#8217;: Stigma Power and Solidarity in Response to Anti-Open-Cast Mining Activism in the Coalfields of Rural County Durham, UK.&#8221; Sociological Research Online (2022): 1&#8211;22. Bryson, Finn. &#8220;The Rise of Fossil Fuel Authoritarianism in Australia.&#8221; Journal of Australian Political Economy 88 (2021): 52&#8211;76. Chomsky, Noam, and Edward S. Herman. Manufacturing Consent. Penguin. Climate Leaders Coalition. "About: Purpose and Vision." 25 Sep. 2024. &lt;https://www.climateleaders.org.au/about/&gt;. &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;. "Roadmap to 2030: Shifting to a Low Carbon Future by CEOs for CEOs." 2021. Dumas, Daisy. &#8220;Enemy at the Gate? The West Australian Turns Its Guns on Labor to Back the Mining Giants.&#8221; The Guardian, 13 Sep. 2024. EY. Australia&#8217;s Oil and Gas Industry: Kickstarting Recovery from COVID-19. APPEA, 2020. Fernyhough, James. Top CEOs Form Exclusive Climate Change Club. 25 Nov. 2020. Fielding, Kelly S., et al. &#8220;Using Ingroup Messengers and Ingroup Values to Promote Climate Change Policy.&#8221; Climatic Change 158 (2020): 181&#8211;99. Grant, Hannah, and Bill Hare. Australia&#8217;s Global Fossil Fuel Carbon Footprint. Climate Analytics. Gulliver, Robyn E., Kelly S. Fielding, et al. "Civil Resistance against Climate Change." International Center on Nonviolent Conflict, 2021. Gulliver, Robyn E., Robin Banks, et al. &#8220;The Criminalization of Climate Change Protest.&#8221; Contention: A Multidisciplinary Journal of Social Protest 11.4 (2023): 24&#8211;54. Gulliver, Robyn E., Kelly S. Fielding, et al. &#8220;Understanding the Outcomes of Climate Change Campaigns in the Australian Environmental Movement.&#8221; Case Studies in the Environment 3.1 (2019): 1&#8211;9. Heras, Augusto. &#8220;Supply-Side Climate Policy and Fossil Fuels in Developing Countries: A Neo-Gramscian Perspective.&#8221; International Environmental Agreements: Politics, Law and Economics 24.1 (2024): 49&#8211;74. Hoggan, James, and Richard Littlemore. Climate Cover-up: The Crusade to Deny Global Warming. Greystone Books, 2009. Hornsey, Matthew J., et al. &#8220;Meta-Analyses of the Determinants and Outcomes of Belief in Climate Change.&#8221; Nature Climate Change 6.6 (2016): 622&#8211;26. Irwin, Randi, et al. &#8220;Making Green Extreme: Defending Fossil Fuel Hegemony through Citizen Exclusion.&#8221; Citizenship Studies 26.1 (2022): 73&#8211;89. Kirkwood, Ian. "Climate Group 350.org Investigated over 2016 Newcastle Harbour Coal Protest." Bendigo Advertiser, 2017. Lacy-Nichols, Jennifer, et al. &#8220;The Public Health Playbook: Ideas for Challenging the Corporate Playbook.&#8221; The Lancet Global Health 10.7 (2022): e1067&#8211;72. LeQuesne, Theo. &#8220;From Carbon Democracy to Carbon Rebellion: Countering Petro-Hegemony on the Frontlines of Climate Justice.&#8221; Journal of World-Systems Research 25.1 (2019): 15&#8211;27. Lock the Gate. "Gas Company-Funded GISERA at It Again with Unreliable Report." 20 Apr. 2020. Lucas, Adam. &#8220;Revealed: The Extent of Job-Swapping between Public Servants and Fossil Fuel Lobbyists.&#8221; The Conversation, 5 Mar. 2018. Marquart-Pyatt, Sandra T., et al. &#8220;Understanding Public Opinion on Climate Change: A Call for Research.&#8221; Environment: Science and Policy for Sustainable Development 53.4 (2011): 38&#8211;42. McCarron, Geralyn. &#8220;Air Pollution and Human Health Hazards: A Compilation of Air Toxins Acknowledged by the Gas Industry in Queensland&#8217;s Darling Downs.&#8221; International Journal of Environmental Studies 75.1 (2018): 171&#8211;85. Meng, Kyle C., and Ashwin Rode. &#8220;The Social Cost of Lobbying over Climate Policy.&#8221; Nature Climate Change 9.6 (2019): 472&#8211;76. Minerals Council of Australia. Immediate Reform Priorities to Accelerate Economic Recovery. May 2020. Nyberg, Daniel, and Christopher Wright. &#8220;Defending Hegemony: From Climate Change Mitigation to Adaptation on the Great Barrier Reef.&#8221; Organization 31.2 (2024): 247&#8211;68. Ogge, Mark. "Emissions from the Tamboran NT LNG Facility." The Australia Institute, August 2023. &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;. "GISERA and Conflict of Interest." The Australia Institute, 2018, Origin Energy. Submission to the Senate Select Committee on Unconventional Gas Mining. 14 Mar. 2016. Parkin, Scott. &#8220;Climate Hegemony: Now Is the Time of Monsters.&#8221; CounterPunch, 2022. Plec, Emily, and Mary Pettenger. &#8220;Greenwashing Consumption: The Didactic Framing of ExxonMobil&#8217;s Energy Solutions.&#8221; Environmental Communication 6.4 (2012): 459&#8211;76. Queensland Resources Council. Submission to the Senate Select Committee on Unconventional Gas Mining. 2016. Readfearn, Graham. &#8220;Mineral Resources and Woodside Donated to WA Labor While It Mulled Gas Policy Changes.&#8221; The Guardian, 21 Sep. 2024. Rimmer, Matthew. &#8220;A Submission on the Environment Protection (Fossil Fuel Company Advertising) Amendment Bill 2024 (ACT).&#8221; Standing Committee on Environment, Climate Change and Biodiversity, ACT Legislative Assembly, 2024. Roe, Isobel, and Tom Lowrey. &#8220;Government Green-Lights Three NSW Coal Mine Extensions, Angering Environmental Groups.&#8221; ABC News, 24 Sep. 2024. Santos. Submission to the Select Committee on Unconventional Gas Mining. Mar. 2016. Torres-Delgado, Anna, et al. &#8220;Self-Defence against Carbon Footprint Evidence: How Employees of Destination Management and Marketing Organisations Cope with Conflicting Environmental and Economic Data.&#8221; Annals of Tourism Research 104 (2024): 103722. UN News. Another Month, Another Heat Record Broken: UN Weather Agency. 7 Aug. 2024. Vespestad, May-Kristin, et al. &#8220;How Moral Disengagement Links to Destination Marketing Organisations&#8217; Moral Muteness in Their Sustainability Communications.&#8221; Journal of Sustainable Tourism (2023): 1&#8211;17. Wolny, Ryszard W. &#8220;Hyperreality and Simulacrum: Jean Baudrillard and European Postmodernism.&#8221; European Journal of Interdisciplinary Studies 3.3 (2017): 75&#8211;79. Wright, Christopher, Daniel Nyberg, et al. &#8220;Beyond the Discourse of Denial: The Reproduction of Fossil Fuel Hegemony in Australia.&#8221; Energy Research &amp; Social Science 77 (2021): 102094. Wright, Christopher, Randi Irwin, et al. &#8220;&#8216;We&#8217;re in the Coal Business&#8217;: Maintaining Fossil Fuel Hegemony in the Face of Climate Change.&#8221; Journal of Industrial Relations 64.4 (2022): 544&#8211;63.</description>
      <author>Robyn Gulliver</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5204/mcj.3120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metagenomic analysis sheds light on the mixotrophic lifestyle of bacterial phylum &lt;i&gt;Zhuqueibacterota&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/imt2.249</link>
      <description>Zheng&#8208;Han Lian, Nimaichand Salam, Sha Tan, Yang Yuan, Meng&#8208;Meng Li, Yu&#8208;Xian Li, Ze&#8208;Tao Liu, Chao&#8208;Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yu&#8208;Ting OuYang, Caiyu Lu, Jingyi Zhang, Ying Chen, Le&#8208;Bin Chen, Zhen&#8208;Hao Luo, Bin Ma, Zheng&#8208;Shuang Hua, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Wen&#8208;Jun Li, Lan Liu, iMeta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404650498

                Zhuqueibacterota is a novel bacterial phylum proposed based on hot spring metagenomes and public metagenome-assembled genomes, classified within the Fibrobacterota-Chlorobiota-Bacteroidota superphylum. This globally distributed phylum consists of one class and five orders, with the majority of its members being facultative anaerobes. Notably, the order Zhuqueibacterales utilizes hydrogen as an electron donor for carbon fixation through the Calvin Benson Bassham cycle. Phylogenetic and metabolic analyses reveal the phylum's key role in the carbon cycle, with frequent horizontal gene transfer events influencing its evolutionary trajectory. To the editor, The candidate phylum KSB1 has been identified as anaerobic heterotrophic bacterium and detected in various environments. However, little known about its diversity, ecology, and evolutionary history. In this study, we analyzed 30 new metagenome-assembled genomes (MAGs) from the Tengchong hot spring and 45 public MAGs. Phylogenetic analyses based on the draft genome and 16S rRNA gene indicate they form a distinct group within the Fibrobacterota-Chlorobiota-Bacteroidota (FCB) superphylum, and thus we propose their classification as a new phylum, herein Zhuqueibacterota, which contain five orders and one class. Members of Zhuqueibacterota are globally distributed and likely facultative anaerobes, with one order exhibiting autotrophy via the Calvin Benson Bassham (CBB) cycle by using hydrogen as an electron donor. Metabolic predictions at the community level suggest that Zhuqueibacterota play a significant role in the carbon fixation of hot spring. Ancestral state reconstruction points to frequent horizontal gene transfer (HGT) events throughout Zhuqueibacterota evolution. Facultative anaerobic traits appear to be ancestral, with some lineage losing hydrogen oxidation capabilities while acquiring carbon fixation capabilities through HGT in Zhuqueibacterales. These results shed light on diversity, ecological roles, and evolutionary history of Zhuqueibacterota, highlighting their significance in the carbon cycle. The earth harbors a huge biodiversity of eukaryotic and prokaryotic microorganisms. However, only a small portion of bacteria is culturable under laboratory conditions and most bacterial phyla have no cultured members. The candidate bacterial phylum KSB1, as one of the uncultured phyla, was first identified in sulfur-rich marine sediments, and now was recognized for its broad ecological adaptability [1]. In estuary sediments, genome studies revealed its capacity for carbohydrate metabolism and &#946;-oxidation [2]. KSB1 members from hydrothermal sediment possess genes encoding benzylsuccinate synthase and alkylsuccinate synthase, suggesting a role in anaerobic hydrocarbon degradation [3]. In wetland sediments, KSB1 MAGs encode enzymes such as isopropanol dehydrogenase, phosphotransbutyrylase, and butyrate kinase, further highlighting their ecological versatility. Notably, KSB1 was also recovered from metagenomic data of hot spring, indicating KSB1 may harbor new functional niches that allow it to grow in the extreme environment. In addition, although nearly 100 MAGs of KSB1 have been reconstructed from various environments, the limited number of high-quality genomes hinders the ability to understand the ecological roles and metabolism of KSB1. Thus, more comprehensive research is needed to explore their metabolic pathways and evolutionary history. To address this, we collected available KSB1 genomes from public database and extracted new MAGs from hot spring samples. Our study significantly expands the genomic diversity of KSB1, clarify the phylogenetic relationships, and revealing its facultative anaerobic lifestyle and carbon fixation potential via the CBB cycle. We hereby designate this phylum as Zhuqueibacterota. Continuous sampling of hot springs in Tengchong County, Yunnan province, China, has been conducted for metagenomic studies since 2016, and 30 high-quality MAGs (Table S1) assigned to KSB1 were reconstructed from 16 metagenomes of hot springs. In total, 75 high-quality KSB1 MAGs were used to construct phylogenetic trees, including 45 genomes (Table S2) downloaded from GenBank. A maximum-likelihood tree, employing Bac120 marker sets from genome taxonomy database (GTDB), revealed that KSB1 forms a monophyletic clade within the FCB superphylum [4], and clearly separated from other phyla (Figure S1A). Phylogenetic tree based on 16S rRNA gene further supports the classification of KSB1 as a distinct phylum taxon in the domain Bacteria under the kingdom Psuedomonadati [5] (Figure S1B). To resolve the phylogenetic affiliations within phylum Zhuqueibacterota, we constructed a maximum likelihood tree with a concatenated set of single-copy marker genes. Previous analyses identified four clades within KSB1 [1]; however, our phylogenetic analysis revealed five distinct groups, corresponding to five orders of the undescribed phylum KSB1 in GTDB r214 (Figure 1A) and clarified that clade II (GTDB taxonomy: p__JdFR-76) is not part of KSB1 but a sister phylum. Average amino acid identity (AAI, 95%&#8211;100% for same species) [6], and average nucleotide identity (ANI, 95%&#8211;100% for same species) (Table S3, Figure S2) were used to classify the novel lineage on the species, which were consistent with the GTDB classification. In addition, phylogenomic tree and GTDB toolkit (GTDB-Tk) (Tables S1 and S2) based analyses were performed to classify the novel lineage on genus levels and higher taxonomic ranks. Finally, we identified 1 class, 5 orders, 14 families, 27 genera, and 40 species from the 75 MAGs (Table S4), including 9 novel species from our own 30 MAGs. Following the recommendations for defining species and higher ranks of not-yet-cultured bacteria using MAGs as type material [6, 7], we proposed the name Zhuqueibacterota phyl. nov. for the KSB1 with five orders: Zhuqueibacterales (O1), Residuimicrobiales (O2), Oleimicrobiales (O3), Thermofontimicrobiales (O4), and Oceanimicrobiales (O5). Using 16S rRNA gene sequences as queries in the IMNGS platform, Zhuqueibacterota was detected across six biotopes: aquatic, sediment, soil, hydrothermal vents, animal- and plant-associated environments (Figure 1B). The phylum is particularly prevalent in soil and biofilm samples, where it constitutes 3%&#8211;10% of biofilm-associated communities (Table S5), suggesting that biofilms may serve as a protective niche for these bacteria. Zhuqueibacterales (O1), the most widely distributed order (Figure 1C), was found in diverse environments. Residuimicrobiales (O2) and Oleimicrobiales (O3) were predominantly detected in hydrothermal vents and sediment, and Thermofontimicrobiales (O4) was enriched in marine environments. Despite limited data for Oceanimicrobiales (O5), Zhuqueibacterota's broad ecological presence (Figure 1C) highlights its adaptability across various habitats, emphasizing its ecological significance. Previous studies suggested that Zhuqueibacterota is enriched in anoxic environments [1], leading to the hypothesis of an anaerobic lifestyle. In our study, genes associated with anaerobic metabolism, such as acetyl-CoA synthetase (acs), phosphate acetyltransferase (pta), acetate kinase (ack), aldehyde dehydrogenase (aldh), and alcohol dehydrogenase (adh), were detected across all clades of Zhuqueibacterota (Table S6), suggesting they may have the ability to produce ethanol through fermentation [8]. Additionally, we identified the Rnf complexes [9] were widely distributed among Residuimicrobiales (O2), Oleimicrobiales (O3), and Thermofontimicrobiales (O4). Phylogenetic analysis of the rnfABCDEG operon indicated that they clustered with anaerobic microorganisms (Figure S3), further suggesting the potential anaerobic lifestyle of Residuimicrobiales (O2), Oleimicrobiales (O3), and Thermofontimicrobiales (O4). Remarkably, Zhuqueibacterota harbored cydAB genes, encoding the cytochrome bd ubiquinol oxidase, which provides an O2-directed respiratory chain under low-oxygen conditions. The coxABC genes [10] were identified in all MAGs of the Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5), as well as in three MAGs of the Residuimicrobiales (O2) and two MAGs of the Thermofontimicrobiales (O4). Additionally, we observed that several MAGs from Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) encoded the aerobic aa3-type cytochrome c oxidase [10]. However, the genes of complete pathways for oxidative phosphorylation were just widely distributed in Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5). These findings suggest that members of Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) may have the ability to utilize oxygen as a terminal electron acceptor. Considering these observations, we propose that members of Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) are more likely facultative anaerobes, rather than being obligate anaerobes. Through metabolic reconstruction, all Zhuqueibacterota orders contain complete genes for glycolysis, gluconeogenesis, and pentose phosphate pathways (Figure 1D). MAGs assigned to the Zhuqueibacterales (O1), Thermofontimicrobiales (O4), and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) harbor the complete gene sets for the TCA cycle. We also identified a diverse array of carbohydrate-active enzymes (CAZymes) among the 75 MAGs, including 79 glycoside hydrolases (GHs), 10 glycosyl transferases (GTs), 10 carbohydrate esterases (CEs), 8 polysaccharide lyases (PLs), and 10 carbohydrate-binding modules (CBMs) (Table S7). Interestingly, the gene encoding the large subunit of ribulose-1,5-bisphosphate carboxylase/oxygenase (RuBisCO) was identified in 35 MAGs of Zhuqueibacterales (O1). Phylogenetic analysis revealed that the RuBisCO large subunit (rbcL) gene belongs to form I group (Figure 2A), which plays a crucial role in carbon fixation via the CBB cycle [11]. Moreover, genes encoding RuBisCO small subunit (rbcS), phosphoribulokinase (PRK), transketolase (TKT), fructose-1,6-bisphosphate aldolase (FBPA), fructose-1,6-bisphosphatase (FBPase), and ribulose-5-phosphate 3-epimerase (RuPE) were found near the rbcL gene cluster (Figure 2B). Based on these observations, we hypothesize that members of Zhuqueibacterota possess the capability for carbon fixation via the CBB cycle. Notably, the absence of sedoheptulose-1,7-bisphosphatase (SBPase) and the presence of transaldolase (TAL) suggest that Zhuqueibacterota uses the transaldolase-variant of the CBB cycle [12, 13]. Carbon fixation via the CBB cycle requires significant energy and reducing equivalents, and hydrogen is a critical energy source in terrestrial hot springs [14] and hydrothermal vents [15]. Numerous prokaryotes can utilize H2 and CO2 as their energy and carbon source [16]. In our study, genes annotated to encode hydrogenases were present in Zhuqueibacterota, and the phylogenetic analyses of hydrogenases revealed five different clades ([Ni&#8211;Fe] group 1d, 3b-3d, and [Fe&#8211;Fe] group) (Figure S4). In Zhuqueibacterales (O1) MAGs, especially those containing CBB gene cluster, we identified two types of hydrogenases (Figure 2C). The [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 1d hydrogenase, a membrane-bound hydrogenase, transfers electrons from H2 to the respiratory chain via membrane-connected cytochromes [17] (Figure S4). Additionally, the cytosolic [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 3b hydrogenase transfers electrons generated by H2 oxidation to NAD+ [18], which serves as a reducing equivalent, for carbon fixation or for ATP production through the respiratory chain [17]. The biosynthesis and maturation of [Ni&#8211;Fe] hydrogenase are catalyzed by six Hyp proteins (hypABCDEF) [19]. The co-localization of hydrogenase maturation proteins, [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 1 d and 3b hydrogenases (Figure 2C) indicate that Zhuqueibacterales (O1) likely utilizes hydrogen as an energy source for carbon fixation. The CBB cycle operates aerobically [20], and both the [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 1d and 3b hydrogenases exhibit O2 tolerance, maintaining hydrogen oxidation even in the presence of oxygen. This further supports the hypothesis that Zhuqueibacterota is facultative anaerobic mixotrophy. Utilizing METABOLIC v4.0, we constructed a community metabolic network comprising with 186 medium/high-quality MAGs (completeness &gt;50% and contamination &lt;6%) derived from JZ2 hot spring (JZ2_202007). Despite being represented by only two MAGs, Zhuqueibacterota exhibited the highest relative abundance (15.48%). It contributed to 24 metabolic processes, with a relative contribution exceeding 25% (Figure S5, Table S8). Notably, Zhuqueibacterota dominated carbon fixation via the CBB cycle, with the highest contribution (57.9%) among all microbial taxa (Table S8). These findings suggest that Zhuqueibacterota, with its chemolithoautotrophic capabilities, plays a vital role in this ecosystem. To decipher the evolutionary histories of the Zhuqueibacterota, we predicted gene gain and loss events mapping onto a Bayesian tree showed that contemporary Zhuqueibacterota harbor more gene families over time (Figure 2D, Figure S6), with 71% of HGT events occurred within Zhuqueibacterales (O1), mostly from hot spring-associated MAGs. HGT played a major role in genome diversity, despite the common trend of genome reduction in hot spring environments. The ancestral Zhuqueibacterota likely possessed hydrogenase, with later loss events leading to the loss of this hydrogen utilization capability in some lineages. The cydAB gene (Figure 2E, Table S9) for high oxygen stress response was acquired early, while the coxABC gene was independently acquired by different lineages (Figure 2E, Table S9). Anaerobic fermentation-related genes were lost at multiple evolutionary nodes, potentially contributing to metabolic diversity, indicating that the ancestors of Zhuqueibacterota were facultative anaerobic bacteria. Genes related to the CBB cycle, such as rbcL, rbcS, and PRK, were acquired gradually. Over time, Zhuqueibacterota inhabiting thermal environments gained the ability for carbon fixation via the CBB cycle. In this study, we have expanded our understanding of the uncultured phylum KSB1, herein Zhuqueibacterota, by utilizing high-quality genomes to explore its diversity and function. Our analysis indicated that Zhuqueibacterota has clear functional differentiation, and distinct environmental preferences among its clades. Notably, this phylum represents a group of facultative anaerobic chemoautotrophs, which play a pivotal role in sustaining microbial communities in hot springs. Ancestral state reconstructions suggest the facultative anaerobic lifestyle of their ancestor, while carbon fixation capabilities probably evolved through HGT. Overall, this study provides new insights into the ecological functions of Zhuqueibacterota and open avenues for further research. Moreover, the findings indicate the possibility of isolating and purifying members of this phylum using the hydrogen-oxidizing autotrophic enrichment system. Zheng-Han Lian: Writing&#8212;review and editing; writing&#8212;original draft; software. Nimaichand Salam: Writing&#8212;review and editing; formal analysis; data curation; investigation. Sha Tan: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; visualization. Yang Yuan: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; visualization. Meng-Meng Li: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; resources. Yu-Xian Li: Writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization; software. Ze-Tao Liu: Writing&#8212;review and editing; data curation. Chao-Jian Hu: Writing&#8212;review and editing; methodology. Ai-Ping Lv: Writing&#8212;review and editing; formal analysis. Yu-Ting OuYang: Writing&#8212;review and editing; validation. Cai-Yu Lu: Writing&#8212;review and editing; formal analysis. Jing-Yi Zhang: Writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization. Ying Chen: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; data curation. Le-Bin Chen: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; resources. Zhen-Hao Luo: Writing&#8212;review and editing; resources; validation. Bin Ma: Writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization; software. Zheng-Shuang Hua: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software. Jian-Yu Jiao: Supervision; writing&#8212;review and editing; writing&#8212;original draft; software; funding acquisition. Wen-Jun Li: Supervision; writing&#8212;review and editing; funding acquisition; project administration; resources. Lan Liu: Supervision; writing&#8212;original draft; writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization; software; validation; funding acquisition; project administration; data curation; resources. This research received financial support from the Key R&amp;D Program of Zhejiang Province (2023C02004, 2023C020015), the Key-Area Research and Development Program of Guangdong Province (2022B0202110001), the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grants No. 92251302, 32200010, 32300001, 32200007, and 32370011), the National Science and Technology Fundamental Resources Investigation Program of China (2021FY100900), and the Fundamental Research Funds for the Universities (Nos. 23ptpy11, 23ptpy136, and 23ptpy137). We extend our sincere appreciation to the staff at Yunnan Tengchong Volcano for their invaluable assistance and gracious permission granted for sample collection. Special thanks are due to Dr. Chih-Min Chang from Guangdong Magigene Biotechnology Co., Ltd., China, for his expert guidance and support throughout the data analysis process. The authors declare no conflicts of interest. No animals or humans were involved in this study. The MAGs discussed in this research have been archived in the GenBank database under the BioProject ID PRJNA895542 (https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/bioproject/PRJNA895542/). Accession numbers for each individual MAG are detailed in Table S1. The data and scripts used are saved in GitHub https://github.com/lianzhh-pub/Code_for_iMeta2024. Supplementary materials (methods, figures, tables, graphical abstract, slides, videos, Chinese translated version, and updated materials) may be found in the online DOI or iMeta Science http://www.imeta.science/. The data that supports the findings of this study are available in the supplementary material of this article. Figure S1. Phylogeny of Zhuqueibacterota. Figure S2. The ANI/AAI heatmap of all pairwise comparisons. Figure S3. The phylogenetic tree based on concatenated alignment of Rnf complex genes. Figure S4. Phylogenetic trees and classification of hydrogenases and metabolic model of hydrogen-oxidizing bacteria. Figure S5. Microbial contribution to carbon, nitrogen, and sulfur cycling in hot spring. Figure S6. Ancestral genome content reconstruction using COUNT software. Figure S7. Phylogenetic tree of nosZ gene. Figure S8. Variation and correlation of genome size and GC content across orders of Zhuqueibacterota. Figure S9. Plot of Principal Coordinates Analysis (PCoA) based on functional traits of Zhuqueibacterota MAGs. Table S1. General genomic features of Candidate Division KSB1 genomes from hot spring. Table S2. Genomic overview of Candidate Division KSB1 reference genome. Table S3. ANI/AAI values for each genome pair. Table S4. Brief nomenclature of Zhuqueibacterota MAGs. Table S5. Global distribution and relative abundances of the Zhuqueibacterota. Table S6. List of genes in the metabolic model of Zhuqueibacterota. Table S7. CAZyme statistics for Zhuqueibacterota MAGs. Table S8. The MW-score for JZ2 hot spring metagenomic dataset. Table S9. Gene gain and loss events detected at key nodes. Please note: The publisher is not responsible for the content or functionality of any supporting information supplied by the authors. Any queries (other than missing content) should be directed to the corresponding author for the article.</description>
      <author>Zheng&#8208;Han Lian, Nimaichand Salam, Sha Tan, Yang Yuan, Meng&#8208;Meng Li, Yu&#8208;Xian Li, Ze&#8208;Tao Liu, Chao&#8208;Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yu&#8208;Ting OuYang, Caiyu Lu, Jingyi Zhang, Ying Chen, Le&#8208;Bin Chen, Zhen&#8208;Hao Luo, Bin Ma, Zheng&#8208;Shuang Hua, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Wen&#8208;Jun Li, Lan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/imt2.249</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
