<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 01:22:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Accelerated screening of gas diffusion electrodes for carbon dioxide reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00061g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402934411

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00061g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Accelerated screening of gas diffusion electrodes for carbon dioxide reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00061g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402935014

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00061g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Accelerated screening of gas diffusion electrodes for carbon dioxide reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00061g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402934444

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00061g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Accelerated screening of gas diffusion electrodes for carbon dioxide reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00061g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402934858

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00061g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction on TM-C3N5 for C1 products: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj02934h</link>
      <description>Huijun Cao, Li Sheng, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402724209

                In the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), transition metal atoms embedded in carbon and nitrogen materials are widely seen as highly efficient catalysts because of their excellent catalytic activity and...</description>
      <author>Huijun Cao, Li Sheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj02934h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water-induced Switching in Selectivity and Steric Control of Activity in Photochemical CO2 Reduction Catalyzed by RhCp*(bpy) Derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-t3ltd-v3</link>
      <description>Dongseb Lee, Kosei Yamauchi, Ken Sakai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402852228

                Photocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formic acid (HCOOH) was investigated in either organic or aqueous/organic media by employing three water-soluble [RhIIICp*(LH2)Cl]+ (LH2 = n,n&#8217;-dihydroxy-2,2&#8217;-bipyridine; n = 4, 5, or 6) in the presence of [Ru(bpy)3]2+, 1,3-dimethyl-2-phenyl-2,3-dihydro-1H-benzo[d]imidazole (BIH) and triethanolamine (TEOA). Through studying the electron-donating effects of two hydroxyl groups introduced to the bipyridyl ligand, we found that the substituent positions greatly affect both the catalytic efficiency and selectivity in CO2 reduction. More importantly, the HCOOH selectivity shows a dramatic increase from 14% to 83% upon switching the solvent media from pure organic to aqueous/organic mixture, where the H2 selectivity shows a reverse phenomenon. The enhanced HCOOH selectivity and the drastic decrease in the H2 yield are well rationalized by the fact that the catalytic CO2 hydrogenation is not only driven photochemically via the attack of RhIII(H)Cp*(LH2-&#8226;) on CO2 but also partly bypassed by a dark H2 addition reaction yielding [RhIII(H)Cp*(L)]- from [RhIIICp*(L)Cl]+, which was also separately investigated under the dark conditions. Combination of experimental and theoretical approaches were made to clarify the pKa values of catalyst intermediates together with the abundant species responsible for the major catalytic processes. Our DFT studies unveil that the exceptionally large structural strain given by the steric contacts between the 6,6&#8217;-dihydroxyl groups and the Cp* moiety plays a significant role in bringing about an outstanding catalytic performance of the 6,6&#8217;-subsituted derivative. The intrinsic reaction coordinate calculations were carried out to clarify the mechanism of hydride transfer steps leading to generate formate together the heterolytic H2 cleavage steps leading to afford the key hydridorhodium intermediates. This study represents the first report on the water-induced high selectivity in CO2-to-HCOOH conversion, shedding a new light on the strategy to control the efficiency and selectivity in the catalysis of CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Dongseb Lee, Kosei Yamauchi, Ken Sakai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-t3ltd-v3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pengaruh Modifikasi Permukaan Piston terhadap Emisi Gas Buang Motor Bakar Kapasitas 100 cc</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55606/jtmei.v3i3.4108</link>
      <description>Gennarki Dini Setyawan Putra, Khambali Khambali, JURNAL TEKNIK MESIN INDUSTRI ELEKTRO DAN INFORMATIKA. 3(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402788974

                Technological advances in motorized transportation are progressing rapidly, making motorized vehicles the main mode of transportation. The increasing number of motorized vehicles in society results in a significant increase in exhaust emissions. Combustion in vehicle engines is not always perfect, producing exhaust gases containing compounds harmful to human health, such as carbon monoxide (CO), hydrocarbons (HC), carbon dioxide (CO2), and nitrogen oxides (NOx). This study investigates the effect of variations in piston dome shape on exhaust emissions in a 100cc internal combustion engine using RON 90 fuel. The goal is to find the optimal compression ratio to produce cleaner exhaust emissions. The research data are presented in tabular form and analyzed using one-way ANOVA and graphs. The results showed a significant reduction in CO and HC emissions at all engine speeds (1000, 2000, 4000, and 5000 rpm) with variations in piston dome shape. The reduction in CO emissions ranged from 55.07% to 85.73%, while the reduction in HC emissions ranged from 54.14% to 86.10%. These results suggest that variations in piston dome shape can be an effective solution to minimize harmful exhaust emissions in internal combustion engines.</description>
      <author>Gennarki Dini Setyawan Putra, Khambali Khambali</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55606/jtmei.v3i3.4108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Geochemical imaging Technique for CO2 Monitoring in the Saline Aquifer of Krechba Field Algeria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5122014/v1</link>
      <description>Zeboudj Fay&#231;al, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402752359

                Abstract As part of the reduction and elimination of anthropogenic emissions, carbon capture, and storage (CCS) has been applied in recent decades. One option for reducing greenhouse gas emissions GHG is to store carbon dioxide CO2 in deep saline aquifers. Due to their abundance and large capacity, deep saline aquifers make excellent storage sites due to their potential for long-term sequestration. In early 2006, in Salah Gas Krechba field in Algeria became the world's first onshore saline aquifer to begin sequestration. This paper will focus on new insights into surface CO2 monitoring. We will discuss the introduction of geochemical imaging as an emerging surface technique to monitor CO2, recently adopted to investigate and detect tracer gases leaks injected in 2007 from neighboring wells and the cap rock. In the following few pages, we will summarize the geochemical imaging survey process from the implementation design, samples signature measurement to chemical analysis using the sophisticated statistical geo-chemical methods in the final interpretation stage. As a conclusion, the comprehensive analysis of the geochemical data has allowed the Krechba team to investigate the CO2 leakage areas in the field and demonstrates to be an efficient valuable, and accurate method for CO2 monitoring</description>
      <author>Zeboudj Fay&#231;al</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5122014/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Economic Factors on Changing Carbon Emission Landscape in ASEAN With ARDL Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24002/kinerja.v28i2.8583</link>
      <description>Hasbi Hasbi, KINERJA. 28(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402849537

                This study aims to analyze the factors influencing carbon emissions in the member countries of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN). The data used in this study covers the period from 1990 to 2021, utilizing the Autoregressive Distributed Lag (ARDL) analysis method. All independent variables show a significant impact on carbon emissions in both the short and long term. This research provides evidence that factors such as urbanization, foreign direct investment, population, and economic growth significantly contribute to the increase in carbon emissions in ASEAN countries. The findings also validate the Environmental Kuznets Curve hypothesis for carbon emissions in ASEAN countries. In other words, economic growth leads to a reduction in carbon emissions. The ASEAN region has experienced substantial economic growth over the past few decades. However, carbon dioxide (CO2) remains a socio-economic issue in the ASEAN region. The results of this study can be highly beneficial for policymakers in the region regarding sustainability and economic development.</description>
      <author>Hasbi Hasbi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24002/kinerja.v28i2.8583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental investigation of emissions from a single-cylinder diesel engine using methanol&#8211;diesel blends</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1449652</link>
      <description>Mohammed Qays Kadhim, P. P. Oshchepkov, Frontiers in Energy Research. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402722556

                This study examines the effects of methanol&#8211;diesel blends on the emissions of a diesel engine, concentrating on carbon monoxide (CO), carbon dioxide (CO 2 ), nitrogen oxides (NOx), hydrocarbons (HCs), and particulate matter (PM). Using a single-cylinder four-stroke diesel engine at varying torque settings (2 N m&#8211;6 N m), significant reductions in CO, CO 2 , HC, and PM emissions were observed with increasing methanol content. CO emissions reduced by up to 81.8%, CO 2 by up to 64.2%, HC by up to 80.4%, and PM by up to 23.5% with the MD11 blend. NOx emissions initially increased but decreased by up to 20% at higher torques with the same blend. These results highlight the environmental benefits of methanol&#8211;diesel blends and the need for effective NOx reduction strategies.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Qays Kadhim, P. P. Oshchepkov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1449652</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Relationship between Energy Consumption and Environmental Degradation with the Moderating Influence of Technological Innovation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jrfm17090419</link>
      <description>Suzan Sameer Issa, Mosab I. Tabash, Adel Ahmed, Hosam Alden Riyadh, Mohammed Alnahhal&#8236;&#8207;, Manishkumar Varma, Journal of risk and financial management. 17(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402760981

                Energy consumption (ECON) in BRICS countries is fueled by fossil fuels, mainly coal. Increased environmental degradation (ED) in BRICS countries is mostly driven by coal consumption. This study utilizes quantile regression for the analysis, enabling the development of targeted energy reorganization and emission reduction policies in BRICS countries. This study uses data spanning from 1990 to 2022 to explore the impact of ECON on ED. Additionally, technological innovation was used to create a moderating role in the nexus between ECON and ED. The model focuses on CO2 emissions and the ecological footprint across ten BRICS countries. Among the nations included in the panel, the results indicate a significant dependence on cross-sectional factors. The study shows that ECON has a detrimental impact on ED across all quantiles. However, technological innovation reduces ED. In terms of a moderating role, technological innovation mitigates the negative influence of ECON on ED. Therefore, it is necessary to implement distinct policies in order to accomplish carbon emission reduction goals in various countries.</description>
      <author>Suzan Sameer Issa, Mosab I. Tabash, Adel Ahmed, Hosam Alden Riyadh, Mohammed Alnahhal&#8236;&#8207;, Manishkumar Varma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jrfm17090419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of the National Cooling Action Plan of the Philippines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1755-1315/1395/1/012042</link>
      <description>A. Calder&#243;n, IOP Conference Series Earth and Environmental Science. 1395(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402732280

                Abstract The Philippines NCAP was developed to account for the environmental impacts of energy consumption (indirect impacts) and use of high-GWP refrigerants (direct impacts) from the RAC Sector that can be mitigated by transitioning to more climate-friendly and higher-efficiency refrigerants. Utilizing the NCAP Methodology developed by the UNEP-led Cool Coalition, UN ESCAP in collaboration with Alliance for an Energy Efficient Economy (AEEE) together with and built on the expertise of the Cool Coalition&#8217;s NCAP Working Group facilitated by The Kigali Cooling Efficiency Programme (K-CEP), the Philippines NCAP was launched by the Philippines Department of Energy &#8211; Energy Utilization and Management Bureau, Department of Environment and Natural Resources, and United Nations Development Programme (Philippines Country Office). This paper presented the Reference Cooling Scenario (RCS) and the Sustainable Cooling Scenario (SCS) adopted from the business-as-usual (BAU) and Clean Energy Scenario (CES) of the Philippine Energy Outlook. With these assumptions on RCS and SCS, the domestic refrigeration sector will save 4.41 TWh while the residential cooling sector will save 12.15 TWh. There is a net effect in total emission reduction estimates of 10.68 MT CO2 equivalent which is close to 12 % of the unconditional target submitted to UNFCCC.</description>
      <author>A. Calder&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1755-1315/1395/1/012042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Green Building Materials in Reducing Environmental and Human Health Impacts Using VIKOR Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46632/tfe/2/3/1</link>
      <description>, Trends in Finance and Economics. 2(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402788835

                Green Building Materials (GBMs) are construction materials Green building materials (GBMs), sustainable building practices, resource conservation, energy efficiency, indoor air quality, environmental impact reduction, and renewable and recyclable materials. The drive to adopt GBMs is fueled by the need to reduce energy consumption, cut greenhouse gas emissions, and preserve natural resources. By incorporating renewable, recyclable, and non-toxic elements, GBMs are integral to sustainable building practices, ensuring a balance between development and environmental responsibility. Growing awareness of environmental challenges and the emphasis on sustainable development have made green building materials a central focus in contemporary construction. Environmental Impact Reduction: GBMs help decrease the environmental footprint of construction by cutting waste, cutting greenhouse gas emissions, and using less energy. These minerals are essential for maintaining ecosystems and halting climate change. Health &amp; Well-Being: Research on GBMs makes it easier to create materials that improve indoor air quality and reduce exposure to dangerous pollutants, which benefits building occupants' comfort and health. Resource Conservation: This study promotes the use of recyclable and renewable materials, helping to preserve the planet's finite natural resources and encouraging the building sector to implement circular economy principles. Alternatives taken as Bamboo, Recycled Steel, Cork, Rammed Earth, Hempcrete, Straw Bale. Evaluation Parameters taken as Thermal Insulation (Benefit), Sustainability Score (Benefit), Cost per Square Meter (Non-Benefit), CO2 Emissions during Production (Non-Benefit). The results indicate that Recycled Steel achieved the highest rank, while Straw Bale had the lowest rank being attained. &#8220;The value of the dataset for Green Building Materials, according to the VIKOR, Recycled Steel achieves the highest ranking.&#8221;</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46632/tfe/2/3/1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decarbonizing Commercial Vehicles: Life Cycle Assessment of Diesel, Petrol and Electric Trucks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1755-1315/1395/1/012016</link>
      <description>Siti Indati Mustapa, Vigna K. Ramachandaramurthy, Norsyahida Mohammad, Faheemullah Shaikh, IOP Conference Series Earth and Environmental Science. 1395(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402732046

                Abstract The electric vehicle (EV) landscape in Malaysia is still trailing behind the more established internal combustion engine industry. However, the promotion of EVs has become an increasing priority for the government, especially after committing to achieving net-zero emissions by 2050 at the earliest, as outlined in the 12th Malaysia Plan. Malaysia has set a target of having 1.5 million EVs by 2040, with a notable portion consisting of commercial EVs like buses and trucks. Developing the EV ecosystem and sustainable trucks in Malaysia faces challenges such as high costs and insufficient supporting infrastructure. This study aims to assess the Well-to-wheel life cycle of CO 2 emissions and total cost of ownership (TCO) of diesel trucks (DTs), petrol trucks (PTs), and electric trucks (ETs). The study employs IPCC 2006 guidelines to estimate CO 2 emissions and a TCO assessment method. The results indicate that the average CO2 emissions of ET are 38% lower than those of DT, and 33% lower than PT. Furthermore, the TCO of ET is 30% and 15% higher than that of DT and PT, respectively. Despite the higher cost, the study concludes that ETs display superior performance in terms of CO 2 emission reduction. These findings contribute significantly to the development of policies and knowledge aimed at promoting sustainable trucks, aligning with the country&#8217;s net-zero goals.</description>
      <author>Siti Indati Mustapa, Vigna K. Ramachandaramurthy, Norsyahida Mohammad, Faheemullah Shaikh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1755-1315/1395/1/012016</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
