<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 01:17:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Design of the Electrocatalytic Urea Synthesis from Carbon Dioxide and Nitric Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03785</link>
      <description>Jun Long, Dong Luan, Xiaoyan Fu, Huan Li, Jianping Xiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402591482

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Long, Dong Luan, Xiaoyan Fu, Huan Li, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaf-like MSX/TiN heterojunction photocathodes mimicking plant cell &#8211; An effective strategy to enhance photoelectrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction and systematic mechanism investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.105</link>
      <description>Wei Yan, Chenpu He, Noushad Ullah, Youzhi Cao, Changwan Zhuang, Bing Wang, Jianhua Wang, Zhe Hu, Di Ma, Weichun Ye, Jinyuan Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402471165

                Semiconductors, such as metal oxides and metal sulfides (MS</description>
      <author>Wei Yan, Chenpu He, Noushad Ullah, Youzhi Cao, Changwan Zhuang, Bing Wang, Jianhua Wang, Zhe Hu, Di Ma, Weichun Ye, Jinyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of Heat Treatment on the Photoactivity of Amine-Modified Titanium Dioxide in the Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29184348</link>
      <description>Iwona Pe&#322;ech, Piotr Staciwa, Daniel Sibera, Konrad S. Sobczuk, Wiktoria Majewska, Ewelina Kusiak&#8208;Nejman, Antoni W. Morawski, Kaiying Wang, Urszula Narkiewicz, Molecules. 29(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402524757

                Modification of titanium dioxide using ethylenediamine (EDA), diethylamine (DEA), and triethylamine (TEA) has been studied. As the reference material, titanium dioxide prepared by the sol&#8211;gel method using titanium(IV) isopropoxide as a precursor was applied. The preparation procedure involved heat treatment in the microwave reactor or in the high-temperature furnace. The obtained samples have been characterized in detail. The phase composition was determined through the X-ray diffraction method, and the average crystallite size was calculated based on it. Values for specific surface areas and the total pore volumes were calculated based on the isotherms obtained through the low-temperature nitrogen adsorption method. The bang gap energy was estimated based on Tauc&#8217;s plots. The influence of the type and content of amine, as well as heat treatment on the photocatalytic activity of modified titanium dioxide in the photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide, was determined and discussed. It was clear that, regardless of the amount and content of amine introduced, the higher photoactivity characterized the samples prepared in the microwave reactor. The highest amounts of hydrogen, carbon monoxide, and methane have been achieved using triethylamine-modified titanium dioxide.</description>
      <author>Iwona Pe&#322;ech, Piotr Staciwa, Daniel Sibera, Konrad S. Sobczuk, Wiktoria Majewska, Ewelina Kusiak&#8208;Nejman, Antoni W. Morawski, Kaiying Wang, Urszula Narkiewicz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29184348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction to methane via a novel copper-based conductive metal organic framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.124</link>
      <description>Zhongyu Jing, Wenli Su, Yu Fan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402550001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongyu Jing, Wenli Su, Yu Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances of in situ insights into CO2 reduction toward fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401388</link>
      <description>Liang Chen, Chengbin Zhang, Hao Chen, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402497787

                The conversion of CO2 into valuable chemical fuels addresses both environmental pollution and energy scarcity. However, understanding reaction mechanisms and the dynamic catalyst evolution during CO2 reduction remains a challenge to data. In this review, we present a detailed description of recent advanced in situ characterization techniques, which provide a reliable means of monitoring the intermediate evolution during CO2 reduction and the dynamic evolution of the catalyst, respectively. Finally, we provide an outlook on the development of in situ characterization techniques.</description>
      <author>Liang Chen, Chengbin Zhang, Hao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#945;-Amino Acids by Reductive Carboxylation of Imines Using Formate and CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0043-1775082</link>
      <description>, Synfacts. 20(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402503388

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0043-1775082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size and Morphology Dependent Activity of Cu Clusters for CO2 Activation and Reduction: A First Principles Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400442</link>
      <description>Shahid Amin, Sa&#239;laja Krishnamurty, Manzoor Ahmad Dar, Krati Joshi, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402499862

                Various Cu&#8208;based materials in diverse forms have been investigated as efficient catalysts for electrochemical reduction of CO2; however, they suffer from issues such as higher over potential and poor selectivity. The activity and selectivity of CO2 electro reduction have been shown to change significantly when the surface morphology (steps, kinks, and edges) of these catalysts is altered. In light of this, size and morphology dependent activity of selected copper clusters, Cun (n=2&#8208;20) have been evaluated for the activation and reduction of CO2 molecule. The phase&#8208;space of these copper clusters is rich in conformations of distinct morphologies starting from planar, 2D geometries to prolate&#8208;shaped geometries and also high&#8208;symmetry structures. The binding efficiency and the activation of CO2 are highest for medium sized clusters (n=9&#8208;17) with prolate&#8208;morphologies as compared to small or larger sized CunCO2 clusters that are existing mainly as planar (triangular, tetragonal etc.) or highly&#8208;symmetric geometries (icosahedron, capped&#8208;icosahedron etc.), respectively. The best performing (prolate&#8208;shaped) CunCO2 conformations are quite fluxional and also they are thermally stable, as demonstrated by the molecular dynamics simulations. Furthermore, on these CunCO2 conformations, the step&#8208;by&#8208;step hydrogenation pathways of CO2 to produce value&#8208;added products like methanol, formic acid, and methane are exceptionally favorable and energy&#8208;efficient.</description>
      <author>Shahid Amin, Sa&#239;laja Krishnamurty, Manzoor Ahmad Dar, Krati Joshi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction Polymerization of CO2 with Phenylene Silanes Cata&#8208;lyzed by Single Component B(C6F5)3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415626</link>
      <description>Wenhao He, Bingwen Li, Yuxuan Li, Xinli Liu, Dongmei Cui, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402489449

                CO2 is an abundant C1 resource but a green&#8208;house gas and chemically inert. Thus, its utilization has been a promising but challenging project. Herein, we report the unprecedented polymerization of CO2 and C6H4(SiMe2H)2 using B(C6F5)3 alone under mild conditions to give poly(silphenylene siloxane) accompanied by releasing CH4. The copolymerization can be extended to comonomers of phenylene silanes bearing functional groups. Moreover, it combines with Piers&#8208;Rubinsztajn reaction to establish a tandem polymerization system to achieve super thermal resistant poly(siloxane&#8208;co&#8208;silphenylene siloxane)s. Density functional theory reveals that B(C6F5)3 is activated by silanes to form free HB(C6F5)2, which is the true active species for CO2 reducing to borylformate, the rate controlling step of the polymerization procedure. The subsequent multiple reductions of borylformate to CH4 and the step&#8208;growth to poly(silphenylene siloxane)s can be fulfilled by both B(C6F5)3 and HB(C6F5)2, and the former shows a slightly higher activity. This work opens a new avenue of utilizing CO2 to fabricate polysiloxanes that is unable to access using current manners.</description>
      <author>Wenhao He, Bingwen Li, Yuxuan Li, Xinli Liu, Dongmei Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415626</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction Polymerization of CO2 with Phenylene Silanes Cata&#8208;lyzed by Single Component B(C6F5)3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415626</link>
      <description>Wenhao He, Bingwen Li, Yuxuan Li, Xinli Liu, Dongmei Cui, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402489599

                CO2 is an abundant C1 resource but a green&#8208;house gas and chemically inert. Thus, its utilization has been a promising but challenging project. Herein, we report the unprecedented polymerization of CO2 and C6H4(SiMe2H)2 using B(C6F5)3 alone under mild conditions to give poly(silphenylene siloxane) accompanied by releasing CH4. The copolymerization can be extended to comonomers of phenylene silanes bearing functional groups. Moreover, it combines with Piers&#8208;Rubinsztajn reaction to establish a tandem polymerization system to achieve super thermal resistant poly(siloxane&#8208;co&#8208;silphenylene siloxane)s. Density functional theory reveals that B(C6F5)3 is activated by silanes to form free HB(C6F5)2, which is the true active species for CO2 reducing to borylformate, the rate controlling step of the polymerization procedure. The subsequent multiple reductions of borylformate to CH4 and the step&#8208;growth to poly(silphenylene siloxane)s can be fulfilled by both B(C6F5)3 and HB(C6F5)2, and the former shows a slightly higher activity. This work opens a new avenue of utilizing CO2 to fabricate polysiloxanes that is unable to access using current manners.</description>
      <author>Wenhao He, Bingwen Li, Yuxuan Li, Xinli Liu, Dongmei Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415626</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ exsolved Ni nanoparticles for boosting CO2 reduction in solid oxide electrolysis cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235456</link>
      <description>Tao Chen, Fei Shan, Lingting Ye, Kui Xie, Journal of Power Sources. 623(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402507664

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Chen, Fei Shan, Lingting Ye, Kui Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu(I)&#8208;Induced &#8216;Click Reaction&#8217; Involving Coordination and Covalent Assembly of Hybrid Borates for the Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412073</link>
      <description>Jianbing Chen, Yinghua Yu, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Jian Zhang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402531561

                The design and synthesis of hybrid borates by the organic ligand modification method are urgent and undeveloped areas of research. It is difficult to directly integrate organoboronic acids within inorganic borate chemistry by adopting the traditional preparation approaches. This work reports a facile synthetic method to synthesize a large family of pyrazole molecule&#8208;protected borates in a rapid and precise manner under mild conditions. A unique cyclic eight&#8208;membered B4O4&#8208;ring has been identified as the cluster core for all these hybrid borates with two different conformations (boat and crown). This strategy can be applied to a system of pyrazolyl molecules to generate such hybrid borates in two independent routes from organoboronic or inorganic boric acids. Furtherly, the mechanism of &#8216;click reaction&#8217; between boric acid and pyrazole induced by copper ions has been proposed based on the synthetic conditions and the structure of intermediate. Due to the bimetallic Cu sites and the functional surfaces, these materials can be used as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction reaction and efficiently enhance the selectivity of HCOOH and C2H4. Our strategy can be regarded as a typical template technique for organic molecule&#8208;protected borates.</description>
      <author>Jianbing Chen, Yinghua Yu, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu(I)&#8208;Induced &#8216;Click Reaction&#8217; Involving Coordination and Covalent Assembly of Hybrid Borates for the Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412073</link>
      <description>Jianbing Chen, Yinghua Yu, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Jian Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402531493

                The design and synthesis of hybrid borates by the organic ligand modification method are urgent and undeveloped areas of research. It is difficult to directly integrate organoboronic acids within inorganic borate chemistry by adopting the traditional preparation approaches. This work reports a facile synthetic method to synthesize a large family of pyrazole molecule&#8208;protected borates in a rapid and precise manner under mild conditions. A unique cyclic eight&#8208;membered B4O4&#8208;ring has been identified as the cluster core for all these hybrid borates with two different conformations (boat and crown). This strategy can be applied to a system of pyrazolyl molecules to generate such hybrid borates in two independent routes from organoboronic or inorganic boric acids. Furtherly, the mechanism of &#8216;click reaction&#8217; between boric acid and pyrazole induced by copper ions has been proposed based on the synthetic conditions and the structure of intermediate. Due to the bimetallic Cu sites and the functional surfaces, these materials can be used as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction reaction and efficiently enhance the selectivity of HCOOH and C2H4. Our strategy can be regarded as a typical template technique for organic molecule&#8208;protected borates.</description>
      <author>Jianbing Chen, Yinghua Yu, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplification of clean development mechanism to measure CO2 emission reductions from shifting private transportation to mass rapid transit: a case study of MRT Jakarta Phase 1</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.155406.1</link>
      <description>Nunuj Nurdjanah, Tri Edhi Budhi Soesilo, K. Mizuno, Raldi Hendro Koestoer, F1000Research. 13(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402579361

                Background The Indonesian government built the Mass Rapid Transit (MRT) in Jakarta to reduce traffic congestion and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions. The objective of this study is to estimate the CO2 emissions reductions from switching from private transport to MRT by using a methodology proposed by the United Nations Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) for developing countries, namely the Clean Development Mechanism (CDM) methodology, which generates Certified Emission Reductions (CERs). This methodology is more comprehensive than other available methodologies. However, this method has not been widely used to calculate greenhouse gas (GHG) emission reductions in mass transit projects because it is complex enough to require a lot of data based on primary surveys. Therefore, this research simplifies the CDM formula to make it easier and applicable in Indonesia. Methods The primary data were collected using a questionnaire distributed to 480 MRT Jakarta Phase 1 user respondents in September 2019 (baseline); the secondary data were obtained from The MRT Jakarta. The data were processed using IBM SPSS Statistics 27. The simplified Clean Development Mechanism Approved Consolidated Methodology 0016 (CDM ACM 0016) was the analysis method used. Result The results of this study indicate that 53.75% of MRT Jakarta Phase 1 users are shifting from private transportation, which has reduced CO2 emissions by 2,732.7 tons in 2019 and 6,043.9 tons in 2023. Increasing the number of MRT passengers who switch from private transportation will further reduce CO2 emissions. Conclusion and implications The simplified CDM ACM 0016 formula may be suitable for use in Indonesia. This would enable the measurement of CO2 emission reductions through mitigation actions through MRT development to be certified by the UNFCCC. Applying this method in calculating CO2 emission reductions, implementing strategies to increase MRT passengers, and using renewable energy electricity sources would increase CO2 emission reductions.</description>
      <author>Nunuj Nurdjanah, Tri Edhi Budhi Soesilo, K. Mizuno, Raldi Hendro Koestoer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.155406.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective reduction of CO2 to CO over alumina-supported catalysts of group 5 transition metal carbides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119963</link>
      <description>Arturo Pajares, Pilar Ram&#305;&#769;rez de la Piscina, Narc&#305;&#769;s Homs, Applied Catalysis A General. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402468312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arturo Pajares, Pilar Ram&#305;&#769;rez de la Piscina, Narc&#305;&#769;s Homs</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An empirical approach-based analysis for the exploration of ternary metal sulfide as an active and selective CO2 reduction electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2024.100832</link>
      <description>An Niza El Aisnada, Yuhki Yui, Ji&#8208;Eun Lee, Norio Kitadai, Ryuhei Nakamura, Masaya Ibe, Masahiro Miyauchi, Akira Yamaguchi, Materials Science and Engineering R Reports. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402532296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>An Niza El Aisnada, Yuhki Yui, Ji&#8208;Eun Lee, Norio Kitadai, Ryuhei Nakamura, Masaya Ibe, Masahiro Miyauchi, Akira Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2024.100832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Photoelectrocatalytic Co2 Reduction to Co Via Structure-Induced Carrier Separation in Coral-Like Cubi2o4-Bi2o3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4955477</link>
      <description>Guorui Liu, Wei Wang, Jing Li, Haiqiang Mu, Min Zhu, J. Zhang, Feng Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402516821

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guorui Liu, Wei Wang, Jing Li, Haiqiang Mu, Min Zhu, J. Zhang, Feng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4955477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving green synthesis of high-value-added chemicals via N-integrated CO2 co-reduction: a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02954-9</link>
      <description>Zhichao Wang, Sisi Liu, Yanzheng He, Yuzhuo Jiang, Yunfei Huan, Qiyang Cheng, Cheng-Tao Yang, Mengfan Wang, Chenglin Yan, Tao Qian, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402545956

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhichao Wang, Sisi Liu, Yanzheng He, Yuzhuo Jiang, Yunfei Huan, Qiyang Cheng, Cheng-Tao Yang, Mengfan Wang, Chenglin Yan, Tao Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02954-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bismuth oxide nanoflakes grown on defective microporous carbon endows high-efficient CO2 reduction at ampere level</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.116</link>
      <description>Minjun Zhou, Zhihao Guo, Mingwang Wang, Dewen Song, Rui Zhou, Quansheng Liu, Shuai Wang, Boshi Zheng, Xiaoshan Wang, Hui Ning, Mingbo Wu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402537824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minjun Zhou, Zhihao Guo, Mingwang Wang, Dewen Song, Rui Zhou, Quansheng Liu, Shuai Wang, Boshi Zheng, Xiaoshan Wang, Hui Ning, Mingbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum Saving and CO2 Emission reduction from waste recycling of China&#8217;s Rooftop Photovoltaics under Carbon Neutrality Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2024.110669</link>
      <description>Bin Zhang, Y. Zhang, Yuantao Yang, Zhaohua Wang, iScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402493855

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Zhang, Y. Zhang, Yuantao Yang, Zhaohua Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2024.110669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating p-orbital electronic configuration of In2O3 by thickness-controlled carbon layer for efficient electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to HCOOH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124596</link>
      <description>Jian Meng, Manfen Liang, Jinglin Mu, Zhichao Miao, Hong Huang, Ruirui Qi, Lechen Diao, Shuping Zhuo, Jin Zhou, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402494696

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Meng, Manfen Liang, Jinglin Mu, Zhichao Miao, Hong Huang, Ruirui Qi, Lechen Diao, Shuping Zhuo, Jin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sn-modified Cu nanosheets catalyze CO2 reduction to C2H4 efficiently by stabilizing CO intermediates and promoting C C coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.117</link>
      <description>Hongfei Wang, Fusen Zhang, Yang Li, Yingping Pang, Xiqiang Zhao, Zhanlong Song, Wenlong Wang, Jing Sun, Yanpeng Mao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402550081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongfei Wang, Fusen Zhang, Yang Li, Yingping Pang, Xiqiang Zhao, Zhanlong Song, Wenlong Wang, Jing Sun, Yanpeng Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Ethylene Yield via Synergistic 2D/0D Nanostructured VCu Layered Double Hydroxide/TiO2 Catalyst in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00417e</link>
      <description>Sneha Lavate, Rohit Srivastava, Energy Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402578037

                The electrochemical conversion of CO2 into C1 to C2 hydrocarbon such as Methane and ethylene is a promising pathway towards to achieve net zero however due to high activation barrier...</description>
      <author>Sneha Lavate, Rohit Srivastava</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00417e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Prediction of the Reaction Mechanism Underlying the Active Phase of Bn (N=3-5) and Cu-Doped Electron Deficient Bn-1 Clusters: Reduction of Co2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4955180</link>
      <description>Hongxia Liu, Ling Fu, Chaozheng He, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402530045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongxia Liu, Ling Fu, Chaozheng He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4955180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of Methylamine by Co-Reduction of Co2 and No3&#8722; with a Series Catalyst Based on O-Doped Metal Phthalocyanine-Porphyrin Two-Dimensional Carbon-Rich Conjugated Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4958584</link>
      <description>Fengling Luo, Li Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402583930

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengling Luo, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4958584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini-Review on Recent Developments and Improvements in CO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; Catalytic Conversion to Methanol: Prospects for the Cement Plant Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0961.v1</link>
      <description>Lu&#237;sa Marques, Maria Clara Vieira, Jos&#233; Conde&#231;o, Carlos Henriques, Maria Margarida Mateus, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402532128

                The cement industry has significant environmental impacts, stemming from natural resources extraction and fossil fuels combustion. Notably, carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions are a major concern associated with cement production. The cement industry emits 0.6 tons of CO2 per ton of cement production, which is around 8 % of the total CO2 emissions in the world. Meeting the 13th United Nations Sustainable Goals, cement plants aim to achieve carbon neutrality by 2050, resulting from reduction in CO2 emissions (change in the composition of cementitious materials) and the adoption of carbon capture and utilisation (CCU) technologies. A promising approach involves converting CO&#8322; into valuable chemicals and fuels, such as methanol (MeOH) through the power-to-liquid (PtL) technologies. In this process, CO2 captured from cement industry flue gas with hydrogen generated from renewable sources through electrolysis of water, catalytically transformed into renewable methanol (e-MeOH), offering a sustainable solution. To achieve this, it is crucial to advance the development of novel, highly efficient catalysts specifically designed for direct CO2 hydrogenation. In this sense, this review discusses recent developments and improvements in CO2 catalytic conversion, emphasizing catalyst performance, selectivity, and stability.</description>
      <author>Lu&#237;sa Marques, Maria Clara Vieira, Jos&#233; Conde&#231;o, Carlos Henriques, Maria Margarida Mateus</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0961.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of an informed choice of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-equivalence metrics for contrail avoidance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-9401-2024</link>
      <description>Audran Borella, Olivi&#233;r Boucher, Keith P. Shine, Marc Stettler, Katsumasa Tanaka, Roger Teoh, Nicolas Bellouin, Atmospheric chemistry and physics. 24(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402552629

                Abstract. One of the proposed ways to reduce the climate impact of civil aviation is rerouting aircraft to minimise the formation of warming contrails. As this strategy may increase fuel consumption, it would only be beneficial if the climate impact reduction from the avoided contrails exceeds the negative impact of any additional carbon dioxide (CO2) emitted by the rerouted flight. In this study, we calculate the surface temperature response of almost half a million flights that crossed the North Atlantic sector in 2019 and compare it to the temperature response of hypothetical rerouted flights. The climate impacts of contrails and CO2 are assessed through the perspective of CO2-equivalence metrics, represented here as nine combinations of different definitions and time horizons. We estimate that the total emitted CO2 and the persistent contrails formed will have warmed the climate by 17.2 &#181;K in 2039, 13.7 &#181;K in 2069, and 14.1 &#181;K in 2119. Under an idealised scenario where 1 % additional carbon dioxide is enough to reroute all contrail-forming flights and avoid contrail formation completely, total warming would decrease by 4.9 (&#8722;28 %), 2.6 (&#8722;19 %), and 1.9 (&#8722;13 %) &#181;K in 2039, 2069, and 2119, respectively. In most rerouting cases, the results based on the nine different CO2-equivalence metrics agree that rerouting leads to a climate benefit, assuming that contrails are avoided as predicted. But the size of that benefit is very dependent on the choice of CO2-equivalence metrics, contrail efficacy and CO2 penalty. Sources of uncertainty not considered here could also heavily influence the perceived benefit. In about 10 % of rerouting cases, the climate damage resulting from contrail avoidance indicated by CO2-equivalence metrics integrated over a 100-year time horizon is not predicted by metrics integrated over a 20-year time horizon. This study highlights, using North Atlantic flights as a case study, the implications of the choice of CO2-equivalence metrics for contrail avoidance, but the choice of metric implies a focus on a specific climate objective, which is ultimately a political decision.</description>
      <author>Audran Borella, Olivi&#233;r Boucher, Keith P. Shine, Marc Stettler, Katsumasa Tanaka, Roger Teoh, Nicolas Bellouin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-9401-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic-Induced Variability of Greenhouse Gases and Aerosols at the WMO/GAW Coastal Site of Lamezia Terme (Calabria, Southern Italy): Towards a New Method to Assess the Weekly Distribution of Gathered Data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0884.v1</link>
      <description>Francesco D&#8217;Amico, Ivano Ammoscato, Daniel Gull&#236;, Elenio Avolio, Teresa Lo Feudo, Mariafrancesca De Pino, Paolo Cristofanelli, Luana Malacaria, Domenico Parise, Salvatore Sinopoli, Giorgia De Benedetto, Claudia Roberta Calidonna, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402531837

                The key towards a sustainable future is the reduction of mankind&amp;rsquo;s impact on natural systems via the development of new technologies and the improvement of source apportionment. Though days, years and seasons are arbitrarily set, their mechanisms are based on natural cycles driven by Earth&amp;rsquo;s orbital periods. This is not the case for weeks, which are a pure anthropic category and are known from literature to influence emission cycles. For the first time since it started data gathering operations, CO (carbon monoxide), CO2 (carbon dioxide), CH4 (methane) and eBC (equivalent black carbon) values detected by the Lamezia Terme WMO/GAW station in Calabria, Southern Italy have been evaluated via a two-pronged approach accounting for weekly variations in absolute concentrations, as well as the number of hourly averages exceeding select thresholds. The analyses were performed on seven continuous years of measurements, from 2016 to 2022. Moreso, the two results have been combined into a new parameter: the hereby defined WDWO (Weighed Distribution of Weekly Outbreaks) normalizes weekly trends of CO, CO2, CH4 and eBC on an absolute scale as percentages, with the scope of providing regulators and researchers alike with a new tool meant to better evaluate anthropogenic pollution and mitigate its effects.</description>
      <author>Francesco D&#8217;Amico, Ivano Ammoscato, Daniel Gull&#236;, Elenio Avolio, Teresa Lo Feudo, Mariafrancesca De Pino, Paolo Cristofanelli, Luana Malacaria, Domenico Parise, Salvatore Sinopoli, Giorgia De Benedetto, Claudia Roberta Calidonna</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0884.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide sequestration in brackish water: Principles, techniques and environmental benefits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61173/1njx1r03</link>
      <description>Zuhong Gong, Science and Technology of Engineering Chemistry and Environmental Protection. 1(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402576747

                Carbon dioxide storage is a technology to separate carbon dioxide gas from the atmosphere and inject it into the brackish water layer to achieve the purpose of carbon dioxide emission reduction. In this way, carbon dioxide is dissolved in salt water and then sequestered in deep underground water layers, preventing it from being released into the atmosphere and causing a greenhouse effect. This technology can effectively reduce carbon dioxide emissions, but also can use geological structures for storage, has great potential application prospects. It is important to note that further research and practice is needed to address possible environmental risks and costs.</description>
      <author>Zuhong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61173/1njx1r03</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSV-14 The effects of calcium cyanamide on greenhouse gases, ammonia emissions, and the microbiome of dairy cattle lagoon water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.585</link>
      <description>Alice S. Rocha, Bryan Morales, Hamed M. El&#8208;Mashad, Yuee Pan, Yongjing Zhao, Frank M. Mitloehner, Journal of Animal Science. 102(Supplement_3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402533394

                Abstract Dairy manure management is responsible for a significant amount of greenhouse gas emissions (GHG) in California. Aside from redesigning infrastructure to adopt alternative manure management systems, there are few options available to farmers to mitigate emissions without substantial financial investment. Calcium cyanamide, a new manure additive, showed significant reductions in GHG emissions when applied to fresh dairy cow slurry, but has not been tested on dairy lagoon water. The aim of the present study was to investigate the effects of calcium cyanamide on GHG and NH3 emissions and the microbiome of dairy lagoon water. Lagoon water was collected from a commercial dairy, and distributed into 12 stainless steel barrels. Three treatments (n = 4/treatment) of different doses of calcium cyanamide were tested: high (LW-HD; 1 kg/m3 lagoon water), low (LW-LD; 0.5 kg/m3 lagoon water), and control with no calcium cyanamide (LW-CONT; n = 4). Each barrel was sampled over two, 14-d periods, staggered to four barrels at a time, using OdoFlux chambers to monitor emissions for carbon dioxide (CO2,), methane (CH4), nitrous oxide (N2O), and ammonia (NH3). Treatments LW-LD and LW-HD contained significantly more total solids, total nitrogen and total carbon compared with LW-CONT. There was also a significantly greater concentration of acetic acid in LW-LD and LW-HD treatments compared with LW-CONT. CO2 emissions in LW-LD and LW-HD were 2.96% and 12.03% less than LW-CONT. CH4 emissions in LW-LD and LW-HD were 80.9% and 85.13% less compared with LW-CONT. N2O emissions in LW-LD and LW-HD were 81.1% and 82.66% less than LW-CONT. However, NH3 fluxes were greater in LW-LD and LW-HD compared with LW-CONT by 65.26% and 65.73%, respectively. The microbiome of the lagoon water was also affected, with reductions in relative abundance of the Proteobacteria phylum responsible for nitrification in LW-LD and LW-HD and increases in the Firmicutes phylum containing acetogenic bacteria. Calcium cyanamide could inhibit methanogenesis by increasing acetogenic bacteria that compete with methanogens for fermentation substrates. Further research is needed to investigate the efficacy of calcium cyanamide in a commercial lagoon setting.</description>
      <author>Alice S. Rocha, Bryan Morales, Hamed M. El&#8208;Mashad, Yuee Pan, Yongjing Zhao, Frank M. Mitloehner</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Solar-Powered Cooling Systems Using Concentrating Photovoltaic/Thermal Systems for Residential Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17184558</link>
      <description>Fadi A. Ghaith, Taabish Siddiqui, Mutasim Nour, Energies. 17(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402495785

                This paper addresses the potential of integrating a concentrating photovoltaic thermal (CPV/T) system with an absorption chiller for the purpose of space cooling in residential buildings in the United Arab Emirates (UAE). The proposed system consists of a low concentrating photovoltaic thermal (CPV/T) collector that utilizes mono-crystalline silicon photovoltaic (PV) cells integrated with a single-effect absorption chiller. The integrated system was modeled using the Transient System Simulation (TRNSYS v17) software. The obtained model was implemented in a case study represented by a villa situated in Abu Dhabi having a peak cooling load of 366 kW. The hybrid system was proposed to have a contribution of 60% renewable energy and 40% conventional nonrenewable energy. A feasibility study was carried out that demonstrated that the system could save approximately 670,700 kWh annually and reduce carbon dioxide emissions by 461 tons per year. The reduction in carbon dioxide emissions is equivalent of removing approximately 98 cars off the road. The payback period for the system was estimated to be 3.12 years.</description>
      <author>Fadi A. Ghaith, Taabish Siddiqui, Mutasim Nour</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17184558</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The interaction between China&#8217;s economic recovery and environmental governance: a comprehensive analysis of energy consumption, CO2 emissions, and resource management</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenvs.2024.1459483</link>
      <description>Yuting Duan, Frontiers in Environmental Science. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402529246

                To gain a deeper understanding of the intrinsic dynamic relationship between energy consumption and economic growth in China. This study employs panel cointegration and causality models, utilizing the SYS-GMM technique to assess the factors influencing economic growth in China&#8217;s green finance sector from 2002 to 2022. The research explores the interactions among multiple variables related to the Chinese economic context, including economic growth, carbon dioxide emissions, total natural resource rents, energy consumption, and environmental impact. While considering key factors that may cause structural disturbances in the time series analysis. The findings indicate the existence of long-term cointegration relationships among these variables, with positive correlations between economic growth and total natural resource rents, energy consumption, energy quantity, and ecological footprint. Results also show a bidirectional causal relationship between carbon dioxide emissions and energy consumption and a unidirectional correlation between energy consumption and GDP growth. Additionally, energy intensity (EI) improvements supported by green finance are linked to a significant reduction in CO 2 emissions, with a coefficient of &#8722;1.933 ( p &amp;lt; 0.05), underscoring the role of technological innovation. Further evaluations suggest that investments in renewable energy can promote economic growth, create job opportunities, and reduce greenhouse gas emissions. Energy-saving measures and green finance-supported technological innovations play crucial roles in improving energy intensity and reducing CO 2 emissions. The study also underscores the importance of economic diversification to reduce dependence on natural resources and enhance economic stability. Future research should further explore the economic feasibility and environmental benefits of emerging technologies such as Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS), providing deeper insights into sustainable energy practices.</description>
      <author>Yuting Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenvs.2024.1459483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applicability of Hydrazine Alternatives to Water Treatment in Power Plants: Effects of Hydrazine Alternatives and Decomposition Products on Water Properties and Corrosion of Carbon Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5006/4621</link>
      <description>Noriyuki Ida, Junichi Tani, Hirotaka Kawamura, CORROSION. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402517306

                ABSTRACT The applicability of carbohydrazide (CHZ) and diethylhydroxilamine (DEHA) as hydrazine alternatives to the water treatment of water-steam circuits of power plants was investigated by assessing their effects on the corrosion of carbon steel and water properties, including the conductivity, conductivity after cation exchange (cation conductivity), dissolved-oxygen concentration (DO), and oxidation&#8211;reduction potential (ORP) of high-temperature water under simulated conditions of boiler feed water of power plants. Hydrazine and carbon dioxide were generated by CHZ decomposition, resulting in a decrease in DO and increases in both conductivity and cation conductivity. Various substances including diethylamine, ethylamine, and acetaldehyde were generated by DEHA decomposition, and the amines increased conductivity. Under the oxygen-containing condition, acetate was also formed, and cation conductivity was increased by DEHA injection. Measurements of DO and ORP suggested that high CHZ and DEHA concentrations or temperatures were required for them to exert their oxygen-scavenging effect and decrease the electrode potential of metals like hydrazine. Irrespective of the decomposition products of CHZ or DEHA, neither of these hydrazine alternatives accelerated the corrosion of carbon steel. In this study, various characteristics of CHZ and DEHA were clarified, and results suggest that CHZ is a safe choice, as long as hydrazine generation by CHZ decomposition does not conflict with hydrazine restriction.</description>
      <author>Noriyuki Ida, Junichi Tani, Hirotaka Kawamura</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5006/4621</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon footprint and techno-economic analysis to decarbonize the production of linerboard via fuel switching in the lime kiln and boiler: Development of a marginal abatement cost curve</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15376/biores.19.4.7806-7823</link>
      <description>Rodrigo Buitrago-Tello, Richard A. Venditti, Hasan Jameel, PETER W. HART, Ashok Ghosh, BioResources. 19(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402475136

                The US Pulp and Paper (P&amp;P) industry heavily relies on fossil sources, with lime kiln operations posing a significant challenge for achieving zero on-site fossil emissions. This study assesses the greenhouse gas (GHG) reduction potential and costs associated with alternative fuels in lime kiln operations for linerboard production. Various options, including bio-based fuels including pulverized biomass, gasification of biomass, crude tall oil, bio-methanol, and traditional fuels such as fuel oil and petcoke, were analyzed through detailed process simulations and Life Cycle Assessment. Results indicate that per ton of product, 2,789 kg of CO2-eq is emitted, with 69% being biogenic CO2 and 31% fossil CO2-eq. Notably, replacing the natural gas boiler with a biomass boiler reduces Global Warming Potential (GWP) by 41%, while switching lime kiln fuel to biofuels achieves a 5.5% reduction. Combining a biomass boiler with pulverized biomass fuel use in the lime kiln yields a substantial 93.1% reduction in Scope 1 and 2 emissions, at a cost of $76/ton of CO2-eq avoided.</description>
      <author>Rodrigo Buitrago-Tello, Richard A. Venditti, Hasan Jameel, PETER W. HART, Ashok Ghosh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15376/biores.19.4.7806-7823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the carbon footprint for a 30-bed haemodialysis unit by changing the delivery of acid concentrate supplied by individual 5 L containers to a central delivery system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40620-024-02073-9</link>
      <description>Gareth Murcutt, Rosie Hillson, Cate Goodlad, Andrew Davenport, Journal of Nephrology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402599258

                Abstract Background Haemodialysis treatments generate greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions mainly as a result of the equipment, consumables and pharmaceuticals required. An internal audit demonstrated a 33% wastage of acid concentrate when using individual 5.0 L containers at a 1:44 dilution ratio. We therefore investigated whether changing the delivery system for acid concentrate would reduce wastage and any associated greenhouse gas emissions. Methods We calculated the difference for a 30-bed dialysis unit between receiving acid concentrate in single-use 5.0 L plastic containers versus bulk delivery for a central acid delivery system connected to the dialysis machines. Estimates of carbon dioxide equivalent (CO 2 e) emissions were made using the United Kingdom government database and other sources. Results A 30-station dialysis unit functioning at maximum capacity (3 shifts and 6 days/week), switching to bulk delivery and central acid delivery could realise an approximate total reduction of 33,841 kgCO 2 e/year; in reduced product wastage, saving 6192 kgCO 2 e, 5205 kgCO 2 e from fewer deliveries, and 22,444 kgCO 2 e saving from a reduction in packaging and waste generated, which equates approximately to a one tonne reduction in CO 2 e emissions per dialysis station/year. Conclusions Switching from delivering acid concentrate in individual 5.0 L containers to a central acid delivery system can result in substantial reductions in CO 2 e emissions within a dialysis clinic. The emission savings from reducing the single-use plastic packaging greatly outweigh any gains from eliminating wastage of acid concentrate. Dialysis companies and clinicians should consider reviewing the design of current and future dialysis facilities and policies to determine whether reductions in CO 2 e emissions can be made. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Gareth Murcutt, Rosie Hillson, Cate Goodlad, Andrew Davenport</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40620-024-02073-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Assessment of Crude Oil-Contaminated Soil Treated by Low-Temperature Thermal Desorption and Its Beneficial Reuse for Soil Amendment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0872.v1</link>
      <description>Young Rim Song, Geon Yong Kim, Da Yeon Kim, Yong Woo Hwang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402500415

                The LTTD process for highly concentrated crude oil-contaminated soil was studied to evaluate the remediation efficiency. In addition, the environmental impact difference between HTTD and LTTD was studied. OpenLCA software obtained from PE International was used to perform the analyses. The total ADP environmental impact of the HTTD process was 1.63E-04 MJ, whereas the total GWP impact was 4.14E+02 kg CO2-eq. In contrast, the LTTD process exhibits total ADP and GWP environmental impacts of 1.29E-04 MJ and 2.78E+02 kg CO2 eq, respectively. Analysis of the overall environmental impact reduction revealed that replacing the HTTD process with the LTTD process resulted in a total ADP reduction of 3.40E-05 MJ (20.5%) and a GWP reduction of 1.36E+02 kg CO2 -eq (32.9%). It is inferred that the LTTD treatment of contaminated soil can significantly reduce the environmental impact compared with conventional incineration and HTTD processes. Additionally, the LTTD-treated soil with coke or carbonized residue could act like biochar as a soil amendment. Approximately 50% of organic hydrocarbon contaminants are sequestered into coke or carbonized residues on the soil surface. With additional analyses of various oil-contaminated soils, the potential utility of LTTD-treated soils is expected to be maximized.</description>
      <author>Young Rim Song, Geon Yong Kim, Da Yeon Kim, Yong Woo Hwang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0872.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High electrolysis performance of the SOEC cathode by creating oxygen vacancies to regulate the adsorption energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04915b</link>
      <description>Yongqian Du, Longyan Zhao, Yanzhi Xiao, Jiangrong Kong, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Xianfeng Yang, Tao Zhou, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402499758

                Solid oxide electrolysis cell (SOEC), as an attractive means of CO2 emission reduction, possesses the advantages of high efficiency, greenness and flexibility. However, the catalytic performance of cathode materials currently...</description>
      <author>Yongqian Du, Longyan Zhao, Yanzhi Xiao, Jiangrong Kong, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Xianfeng Yang, Tao Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04915b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Fabrication of Plasmonic Bi@Bi2O2CO3 Core-Shell Heterostructure for Photocatalytic CO2 Reduction: Structural Insights into Selectivity Modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02203c</link>
      <description>Yannan Zhou, Jingyun Jiang, Hang Yin, Shouren Zhang, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402542556

                The precise design of active sites and light absorbers is essential in developing highly efficient photocatalysts for CO2 reduction. Core-shell heterostructures constructed based on large-sized plasmonic Bi metals are ideal...</description>
      <author>Yannan Zhou, Jingyun Jiang, Hang Yin, Shouren Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02203c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance of Zeolite-Based Soil&#8211;Geopolymer Mixtures for Geostructures under Eccentric Loading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/infrastructures9090160</link>
      <description>Alaa H. J. Al-Rkaby, Infrastructures. 9(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402484636

                Although soil stabilization with cement and lime is widely used to overcome the low shear strength of soft clay, which can cause severe damage to the infrastructures founded on such soils, such binders have severe impacts on the environment in terms of increasing emissions of carbon dioxide and the consumption of energy. Therefore, it is necessary to investigate soil improvement using sustainable materials such as byproducts or natural resources as alternatives to conventional binders&#8212;cement and lime. In this study, the combination of cement kiln dust as a byproduct and zeolite was used to produce an alkali-activated matrix. The results showed that the strength increased from 124 kPa for the untreated clay to 572 kPa for clay treated with 30% activated stabilizer agent (activated cement kiln dust). Moreover, incorporating zeolite as a partial replacement of the activated cement kiln dust increased the strength drastically to 960 and 2530 kPa for zeolite ratios of 0.1 and 0.6, respectively, which then decreased sharply to 1167 and 800 kPa with further increasing zeolite/pr to 0.8 and 1.0, respectively. The soil that was improved with the activated stabilizer agents was tested under footings subjected to eccentric loading. The results of large-scale loading tests showed clear improvements in terms of increasing the bearing capacity and decreasing the tilt of the footings. Also, a reduction occurred due to the eccentricity decreasing as a result of increasing the thickness of the treated soil layer beneath the footing.</description>
      <author>Alaa H. J. Al-Rkaby</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/infrastructures9090160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of metal oxides doping on the surface stability of In2O3 for CO2 hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0224256</link>
      <description>Xingtang Xu, Yanwei Li, Zhenhua Tao, Jianliang Cao, Yan Wang, Xu-Long Qin, AIP Advances. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402513197

                The significance of maintaining the surface stability of the In2O3 catalyst in the conversion of CO2 to methanol through hydrogenation cannot be overstated. To improve surface stability, doping with metal oxides is usually employed. To explore high-efficiency In2O3 based catalysts, density functional theory calculations were utilized to explore the effects of doping CuO, Co2O3, NiO, TiO2, HfO2, Nb2O3, Ta2O5, and CeO2 on the stability of the In2O3(110) surface. It was found that in a CO atmosphere, the crucial step in determining the creation of oxygen vacancies on the In2O3 plane occurred during the desorption of CO2 from the vacancy location. The results indicate that doping CuO, Co2O3, NiO, Nb2O3, Ta2O5, and CeO2 on the In2O3(110) surface promotes the reduction process through the reaction of CO with the O atoms on the surface, resulting in reduced surface stability. Conversely, the doping of Ti and Hf can raise the reaction energy barriers for CO reacting with the O atoms on the surface and enhance CO2 molecule adsorption on vacant sites, thereby suggesting the potential of TiO2 and HfO2 as effective modifiers to improve the efficiency and durability of the In2O3 catalyst. Furthermore, it is crucial to enhance its stability by modifying the density of the electron cloud or Fermi level of the In2O3 catalyst.</description>
      <author>Xingtang Xu, Yanwei Li, Zhenhua Tao, Jianliang Cao, Yan Wang, Xu-Long Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0224256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSV-10 Vaccination of beef cattle to reduce enteric methane emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.581</link>
      <description>Musah Muntari, Brigid R Arciero, Christa K&#252;hn, Kate Mulcock, Damon Smith, Brette Poliakiwski, Keara O&#8217;Reilly, Odile Polanco Jim&#233;nez, Jeff Bickmeier, Sara Kimler, John Sullivan, &#381;eljko Radulovi&#263;, Laura Z Holland, Taylor A Falk, Chris Allen, Lauren E Fitch, James Spoonamore, Kristin J. Adolfsen, G. E. Carstens, Ky G Pohler, Cliff C Lamb, Matthew R. Dunn, Journal of Animal Science. 102(Supplement_3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402541590

                Abstract Livestock methane (CH4) emissions total over 3 billion tonnes per year of carbon dioxide equivalents (CO2e) and are responsible for approximately 6% of total annual greenhouse gas emissions. The contribution of livestock CH4 emissions are only to be exacerbated as the global demand for meat and dairy products increases. Greater than 75% of livestock CH4 emissions are generated in dispersed production environments (e.g., cow-calf and stocker segments), which are not addressable by methane mitigation strategies requiring constant inputs. Thus, strategies that fit into standard agronomic practices, in particular dispersed production environments, are urgently needed to address the increasing carbon footprint associated with livestock production. Methane-reducing vaccines are a promising solution for addressing this need, due to their longevity of action, low cost, and ease of integration into standard agronomic practices, which could lower the barrier for adoption. Thus, this study aimed to assess the effects of a prototype vaccine on total and antigen-specific immune response, CH4 yield, and average daily gain (ADG) in cattle. Angus crossbred steers [n = 20; initial body weight (BW) = 537 &#177; 15 kg) fed on a high-forage diet were randomly assigned to either placebo- or vaccine-treated groups blocked by BW, breed, and feed intake. Steers were subcutaneously inoculated (2 mL dose) in the anterior region of the neck. Blood and saliva samples were collected, and total sera and salivary immunoglobulin (Ig) G and IgA were quantified using ELISA (Bethyl laboratories, Montgomery, TX). Antigen-specific sera IgG was measured using ELISA. Daily CH4 emissions and dry matter intake (DMI) were measured using GreenFeed systems (C-Lock Inc. Rapid City, SD) and GrowSafe feed bunks (Vytelle, Lenexa, KS), respectively. Body weights were recorded bi-weekly. Total sera IgA and IgG did not differ between the placebo-treated and vaccinated steers (P = 0.584 and P = 0.425, respectively), nor did total salivary IgA and IgG (P = 0.577 and P = 0.548, respectively). However, antigen-specific sera IgG did significantly increase following booster vaccination in the vaccinated steers, as compared with placebo-treated steers (d 0 vs. d 28; P &amp;lt; 0.001). CH4 yield was significantly reduced in vaccinated steers following booster vaccination despite significantly increasing in placebo-treated steers over the same period (P = 0.002). This reduction in CH4 yield was not associated with a reduction in DMI nor ADG (P = 0.181 and P = 0.314, respectively), suggesting that vaccination did not negatively affect treated animals. These findings underscore the potential of vaccine-based solutions to mitigate the environmental impact of livestock CH4 emissions, especially from dispersed production environments where current options for mitigation strategies are limited.</description>
      <author>Musah Muntari, Brigid R Arciero, Christa K&#252;hn, Kate Mulcock, Damon Smith, Brette Poliakiwski, Keara O&#8217;Reilly, Odile Polanco Jim&#233;nez, Jeff Bickmeier, Sara Kimler, John Sullivan, &#381;eljko Radulovi&#263;, Laura Z Holland, Taylor A Falk, Chris Allen, Lauren E Fitch, James Spoonamore, Kristin J. Adolfsen, G. E. Carstens, Ky G Pohler, Cliff C Lamb, Matthew R. Dunn</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.581</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Stable Propane Dehydrogenation on a Self&#8208;supporting Single&#8208;component Zn2SiO4 Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413297</link>
      <description>Zhaohui Liu, Min Mao, Tie Shu, Qingpeng Cheng, Dong Liu, Jianjian Wang, Yun Zhao, Lingmei Liu, Yu Han, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402513873

                Current industrial propane dehydrogenation (PDH) processes predominantly use either toxic Cr&#8208;based or expensive Pt&#8208;based catalysts, necessitating urgent exploration for alternatives. Herein, we present Zn2SiO4, an easily prepared, cost&#8208;effective material, as a highly efficient and stable catalyst for PDH. Uniquely, Zn2SiO4 nanocrystals do not require dispersion on support materials, commonly needed for catalytic active oxide clusters, but function as a self&#8208;supporting catalyst instead. During the reaction's induction period, surface Zn species on the Zn2SiO4 crystal reduce to coordinately unsaturated ZnOx single sites, serving as highly active catalytic centers. The Zn2SiO4 catalyst demonstrates a stable performance over 200 hours of PDH operation at 550 &#176;C. We further find that introducing a minuscule amount of CO2 into the propane feed significantly extends the catalyst lifespan to over 2000 hours. This enhancement arises from the special role of CO2 in facilitating the removal of strongly adsorbed H*, preventing the complete reduction of ZnOx. After prolonged reaction, the activity of Zn2SiO4 can be fully restored by etching the surface layer to expose fresh Zn species, available throughout the crystals. The combination of CO2 introduction and catalytic site regeneration strategies is expected to enable a year&#8208;long PDH operation using a single batch of Zn2SiO4 catalyst.</description>
      <author>Zhaohui Liu, Min Mao, Tie Shu, Qingpeng Cheng, Dong Liu, Jianjian Wang, Yun Zhao, Lingmei Liu, Yu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and production of a mini-turbo reactor and study of its dual-fuel (gas-hydrogen) operation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46932/sfjdv5n9-019</link>
      <description>Adel Miles, A. Bouchoucha, Driss Bendjaballah, South Florida Journal of Development. 5(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402542223

                The objective of this research was to investigate the effects of hydrogen injection on the performance of a mini turbo reactor. To achieve this, an experimental test bench was constructed, incorporating a specially designed mini turbo reactor capable of operating on various fuel mixtures and a dry cell electrolyzer for on-site hydrogen production. A comprehensive testing campaign was conducted, comparing the mini turbo reactor performance when fueled with pure propane and a propane-hydrogen blend at varying concentrations. Parameters evaluated included power output, thermal efficiency, fuel mass flow rate, flame temperatures, and pollutant emissions (CO, CO2, NOx). The experimental results unequivocally demonstrated that the addition of hydrogen to propane significantly enhances the mini turbo reactor specific power while concurrently reducing CO and CO2 emissions. Furthermore, data analysis revealed an improvement in the thermal efficiency of the cycle, suggesting potential reductions in specific fuel consumption. These findings highlight the promising potential of hydrogen injection as a strategy to enhance the performance and environmental impact of mini turbo reactor.</description>
      <author>Adel Miles, A. Bouchoucha, Driss Bendjaballah</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46932/sfjdv5n9-019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Stable Propane Dehydrogenation on a Self&#8208;supporting Single&#8208;component Zn2SiO4 Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413297</link>
      <description>Zhaohui Liu, Min Mao, Tie Shu, Qingpeng Cheng, Dong Liu, Jianjian Wang, Yun Zhao, Lingmei Liu, Yu Han, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402514472

                Current industrial propane dehydrogenation (PDH) processes predominantly use either toxic Cr&#8208;based or expensive Pt&#8208;based catalysts, necessitating urgent exploration for alternatives. Herein, we present Zn2SiO4, an easily prepared, cost&#8208;effective material, as a highly efficient and stable catalyst for PDH. Uniquely, Zn2SiO4 nanocrystals do not require dispersion on support materials, commonly needed for catalytic active oxide clusters, but function as a self&#8208;supporting catalyst instead. During the reaction's induction period, surface Zn species on the Zn2SiO4 crystal reduce to coordinately unsaturated ZnOx single sites, serving as highly active catalytic centers. The Zn2SiO4 catalyst demonstrates a stable performance over 200 hours of PDH operation at 550 &#176;C. We further find that introducing a minuscule amount of CO2 into the propane feed significantly extends the catalyst lifespan to over 2000 hours. This enhancement arises from the special role of CO2 in facilitating the removal of strongly adsorbed H*, preventing the complete reduction of ZnOx. After prolonged reaction, the activity of Zn2SiO4 can be fully restored by etching the surface layer to expose fresh Zn species, available throughout the crystals. The combination of CO2 introduction and catalytic site regeneration strategies is expected to enable a year&#8208;long PDH operation using a single batch of Zn2SiO4 catalyst.</description>
      <author>Zhaohui Liu, Min Mao, Tie Shu, Qingpeng Cheng, Dong Liu, Jianjian Wang, Yun Zhao, Lingmei Liu, Yu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ink And Influence: The Role of Media on Climate Policy Understanding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5195/cinej.2024.645</link>
      <description>&#304;brahim Dalk&#305;l&#305;&#231;, Nezahat Do&#287;an, CINEJ Cinema Journal. 12(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402474174

                The main purpose of this study is to investigate the role of media (including cinema) on the CO2 emission levels of The United States of America (USA). Employing three co-integration methods, namely Canonical Co-Integrating Regression (CCR), Dynamic Least Squares (DOLS), and Fully Modified Least Squares (FMOLS), within the framework of Environmental Kuznet Curves (EKC) theory, we unravel the impact of media coverage on the USA&#8217;s carbon footprint. Utilizing Climate Policy Uncertainty index (CPU), extracted from prominent USA newspapers as a main concern, the analysis reveals a noteworthy outcome indicating media coverage pertaining to environmental issues, pollution, and climate changes emerges as a contributing factor in the reduction of CO2 emissions. The study also uses income per capita, renewable energy consumption and foreign direct investment as additional metrics of air pollution. The findings not only shed light on the influential role of media in shaping environmental outcomes but also offer valuable insights to policy makers and governors.</description>
      <author>&#304;brahim Dalk&#305;l&#305;&#231;, Nezahat Do&#287;an</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5195/cinej.2024.645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pore-Scale Simulation of the Effect of Wettability Alteration on Flow Transport Kinetics in 3D Natural Porous Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/223106-pa</link>
      <description>Yongfei Yang, H.Y. Li, Chuan Tong, Lei Zhang, Hai Sun, Junjie Zhong, Kai Zhang, Jun Yao, SPE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402468078

                Summary Wettability alteration commonly occurs in subsurface two-phase displacements, such as enhanced hydrocarbon recovery, hydrogen storage, and carbon dioxide sequestration. A comprehensive understanding of two-phase flow transport kinetics during wettability alteration in natural rocks is essential for optimizing these processes. To address this, a wettability alteration model induced by low-salinity waterflooding (LSWF) was implemented based on the volume of fluid (VOF) method and the compressive continuous species transfer (C-CST) method in the OpenFOAM platform, which integrates the pore-scale two-phase fluid flow and the advection-diffusion of species. Following validation against experimental data from existing literature, extensive direct numerical simulations (DNSs) were conducted in an actual 3D sandstone sample obtained by microcomputed tomography (micro-CT) images. The effects of the wettability alteration degree, wettability alteration model, and capillary number on dynamic salt dispersion and fluid redistribution are considered in simulation works. The findings indicate that a higher wettability alteration degree facilitates the release of more oil trapped in smaller pores toward the outlet, while the mobilized oil might become trapped again due to snap-off in larger downstream pores. Moreover, due to the presence of alternative flow pathways in the system, the backflowed oil induced by heterogeneous salinity distribution might not be effectively recovered. A faster wettability alteration rate enhances the performance of LSWF because of the rapid reduction of entry capillary pressure and the delayed negative effect of salt dispersion. In terms of the capillary number, a higher capillary number accelerates the diffusion of species to the three-phase contact line and reduces the occurrence of snap-off retrapping, thereby increasing ultimate oil recovery. This study contributes to a deeper understanding of the microscopic displacement mechanism during the wettability alteration processes, especially for LSWF, in 3D heterogeneous porous media.</description>
      <author>Yongfei Yang, H.Y. Li, Chuan Tong, Lei Zhang, Hai Sun, Junjie Zhong, Kai Zhang, Jun Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/223106-pa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-Precipitation Synthesized Ag-Doped Ceria Redox Material (ACRM) for the Thermochemical Conversion of CO2 into Solar Fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14188272</link>
      <description>Gorakshnath Takalkar, Sayma Akhter, Rahul R. Bhosale, Applied Sciences. 14(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402515786

                In this investigation, an effort was made to introduce Ag into the CeO2 fluorite crystal lattice to form Ce0.99Ag0.01O2-&#948; (ACRM) using an ammonium hydroxide-assisted co-precipitation method. The resulting powder obtained after the co-precipitation reaction, filtration, and drying was annealed at 800 &#176;C in a muffle furnace to obtain crystalline ACRM. The phase composition and microstructure of the synthesized ACRM were analyzed using a powder X-ray diffractometer (PXRD) and a scanning electron microscope (SEM). The characterized ACRM powder was then subjected to multiple thermochemical thermal reduction (TR) and CO2 splitting (CDS) cycles using a high-temperature thermogravimetric analyzer (TGA). The TR step was conducted using Ar gas as an inert atmosphere, maintaining the temperature at 1400 &#176;C for 60 min. Subsequently, the same powder was subjected to the CDS step by treating it with a gaseous mixture of 50% CO2 and Ar gas at 1000 &#176;C for 30 min. ACRM displayed stable redox reactivity towards thermochemical CDS cycles by generating an average of 50.9 &#956;mol of O2/g&#183;cycle and 101.6 &#956;mol of CO/g&#183;cycle, respectively, over 10 thermochemical cycles.</description>
      <author>Gorakshnath Takalkar, Sayma Akhter, Rahul R. Bhosale</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14188272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDUCATIONAL BUILDING RENOVATION USING GREEN ROOF TOWARDS ENERGY SAVINGS AND DECARBONIZATION OF CITIES</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46793/ieep24.397g</link>
      <description>J. P. Gli&#353;i&#263;, Tamara Bajc, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402473828

                This paper presents an analysis of the possible application of green roof on an existing educational building with a flat roof, through an analysis of the degree of energy efficiency improvement and CO2 emission reduction. The goal of the paper is to show, through the preparation of the energy efficiency report and Energy passport, the green roof as an exceptional tool for ensuring sustainable development, decarbonization and improving the quality of life of people in urban areas. This is important because urban areas have limited space for green infrastructure and high level of pollution. The research also clearly defines the impact of green roof installations on energy savings with the share for heating of 15% and air quality contributing to the about 6% lower CO2 emission, with attached methodological explanations for their application. Economic analysis and profitability of the proposed project are also provided as an additional indication of the relevance of this type of practice. In the economic analysis, the key indicators of the profitability of the investment are studied, in this investigation, the net present value (NPV) and the payback period (PBP) of the green roof project. PBP of 22 years was obtained, but it should not be considered separately of the other benefits of green roofs, which are not measurable in money, such as lower pollution in cities, habitats for pollinators, additional green areas for people, prevention of floods, etc.</description>
      <author>J. P. Gli&#353;i&#263;, Tamara Bajc</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46793/ieep24.397g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends in CO, CO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;, CH&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;4&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;, BC, and NO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;x &amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;during the first 2020 COVID-19 lockdown: source insights from the WMO/GAW station of Lamezia Terme (Calabria, Southern Italy)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0915.v2</link>
      <description>Francesco D&#8217;Amico, Ivano Ammoscato, Daniel Gull&#236;, Elenio Avolio, Teresa Lo Feudo, Mariafrancesca De Pino, Paolo Cristofanelli, Luana Malacaria, Domenico Parise, Salvatore Sinopoli, Giorgia De Benedetto, Claudia Roberta Calidonna, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402559566

                In 2020, the Covid-19 outbreak led many countries across the globe to introduce lockdowns (LDs) that effectively caused most anthropic activities to either stop completely or be significantly reduced. In Europe, Italy played a pioneeristic role via the early introduction of a strict nationwide LD on March 9th. This study is aimed at evaluating, using both chemical and meteorological data, the environmental response to that occurrence as observed by the Lamezia Terme (LMT) GAW/WMO station in Calabria, Southern Italy. The first 2020 lockdown has therefore been used as a &amp;ldquo;proving ground&amp;rdquo; to assess CO, CO2, CH4, BC, and NOx concentrations in a rather unique context by exploiting the location of LMT in the context of the Mediterranean Basin. In fact, its location on the Tyrrhenian coast of Calabria and local wind circulation both lead to daily cycles where western-seaside winds depleted in anthropogenic pollutants can be easily differentiated from northeastern-continental winds, enriched in anthropogenic outputs. In addition to that, the first Italian LD occurred during the seasonal transition from Winter to Spring and, consequently, Summer, thus providing new insights on emission outputs correlated with seasons. Findings have clearly indicated BC and, in particular, CO as strongly correlated with average daily temperatures, and possibly domestic heating. CO2&amp;rsquo;s reduction during the lockdown and consequent increase in the post-lockdown period, combined with wind data, has allowed to constrain local source of emissions located northeast from LMT. NOx reductions during specific circumstances are consistent with hypotheses from previous research which linked them to rush hour traffic and other forms of transportation emissions. CH4&amp;rsquo;s stable patterns are consistent with livestock, landfills, and other sources assumed to be nearly constant during LD periods.</description>
      <author>Francesco D&#8217;Amico, Ivano Ammoscato, Daniel Gull&#236;, Elenio Avolio, Teresa Lo Feudo, Mariafrancesca De Pino, Paolo Cristofanelli, Luana Malacaria, Domenico Parise, Salvatore Sinopoli, Giorgia De Benedetto, Claudia Roberta Calidonna</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0915.v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic Feasibility of Chemical Looping CO Production from Blast Furnace Gas Based on Fe-Ca-Based Carriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091965</link>
      <description>Yang Gao, Huaqing Xie, Chao Sun, Mengxin Qin, Kun Wang, Zhushan Shao, Processes. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402480085

                In this paper, a novel process for synergistic carbon in situ capture and the utilization of blast furnace gas is proposed to produce CO via chemical looping. Through thermodynamic analysis, this process was studied in terms of the carbon fixation rate, CO yield, in situ CO2 utilization rate, CH4 conversion rate and energy consumption. It provides valuable insights for achieving efficient CO2 capture and in situ conversion. FeO and CaO are used as the oxygen carrier and the carbon carrier, respectively. Under the conditions of reaction temperature of 400 &#176;C, pressure of 1 bar and FeO/CO ratio of 1, the carbon capture rate of blast furnace gas can reach more than 99%. In the carbon release reactor, the CO yield is lower than that in the original blast furnace gas (BFG) if no reduction gas is involved. Therefore, methane is introduced as a reducing gas to increase CO yield. When the reaction temperature is increased to 1000 &#176;C, the pressure level is reduced to 0.01 bar and the CH4/C ratio is 1:1 (methane to carbon), the CO yield is four times that of the initial blast furnace gas. Under the optimal conditions, the energy consumption of the system is 0.2 MJ/kg, which is much lower than that of the traditional process. This paper verifies the feasibility of the new process from the perspective of thermodynamics.</description>
      <author>Yang Gao, Huaqing Xie, Chao Sun, Mengxin Qin, Kun Wang, Zhushan Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of tetrandrine tablets on cytokines, immune function, blood gas and respiratory function in patients with stage II pneumoconiosis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4314/tjpr.v23i6.10</link>
      <description>Chongjian Wang, Hongliang Li, Jintao Wang, Xiuwu Liu, Tropical Journal of Pharmaceutical Research. 23(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402487904

                Purpose: To investigate the impact of tetrandrine tablets on cytokines, immune function, blood gas and respiratory function in patients with stage II pneumoconiosis. Methods: 136 subjects with stage II pneumoconiosis diagnosed and treated in People's Hospital of Linyi City, Linyi City, China were divided into control and study cohorts, each with 68 individuals. Patients in control cohort received conventional symptomatic treatment, while study cohort additionally received tetrandrine tablets orally 3 times per day, for 4 weeks. Lung function, serum indicators and blood gas indicators were determined before and after treatment. Results: After treatment, the levels of forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1) and FEV1/FVC in both groups were significantly increased in both cohorts, with significantly higher values in study cohort. In both cohorts, there were higher post-treatment numbers of CD4+ and CD8+ cells and CD4+/CD8+ ratio than before treatment, but with significantly higher values in study cohort (p &lt; 0.05). After treatment, there were significantly raised levels of peripheral capillary oxygen saturation (SpO2), minute ventilation (VE) and tidal volume (VT) in the two cohorts, with higher values in the study group cohort (p &lt; 0.05). Moreover, treatment resulted in a significant reduction in partial pressure of end-tidal carbon dioxide (PETCO2), with significantly lower levels in study cohort (p &lt; 0.05). After treatment, concentrations of interleukin-1 beta (IL-1&#946;), matrix metalloproteinase-7 (MMP-7), and tumor necrosis factor beta-1 (TNF-&#946;1) in study cohort were significantly reduced, relative to pre-treatment. Conclusion: Tetrandrine tablets are efficacious in stage II pneumoconiosis patients. The drug is beneficial in improving immune function, reducing levels of inflammatory mediators, and improving lung function and blood gas indicators in patients. Future studies incorporating additional parameters and a larger number of patients will be required to provide a more comprehensive understanding of the efficacy and safety of this treatment protocol.</description>
      <author>Chongjian Wang, Hongliang Li, Jintao Wang, Xiuwu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4314/tjpr.v23i6.10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Engine Performance, Emissions, Noise, and Vibration: A Comparative Study of Diesel and Biodiesel Fuel Mixture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30939/ijastech..1495167</link>
      <description>Mahmut &#304;nce, Samet &#199;elebi, &#220;same Demir, Can HA&#350;&#304;MO&#286;LU, International Journal of Automotive Science And Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402501667

                This study investigates the performance, emissions, noise, and vibration characteristics of a single-cylinder, air-cooled, four-stroke diesel engine running on pure diesel (D100) and biodiesel blends (B10: 90% diesel, 10% biodiesel; B20: 80% diesel, 20% biodiesel) at 1800 rpm, where the engine delivers maximum torque. Key metrics such as torque, power, brake specific fuel consumption (BSFC), exhaust gas temperature, noise, vibration, and emissions (CO, CO2, HC, O2, NOx, and smoke opacity) were analyzed. The findings indicate that B10 enhances torque, power output, and overall fuel efficiency, especially at low to medium loads, with a significant 17.54% reduction in BSFC compared to D100 at 40% engine load. Vibration levels generally increased with biodiesel addition, while B10 and B20 both reduced smoke opacity, with B20 having a more substantial effect. HC emissions decreased at idle with B10 but increased at higher loads, suggesting more complete combustion with potential thermal stress on engine components. Noise and vibration results were mixed; B20 reduced noise at higher loads but increased vibration. At 100% load, B20 decreased noise by 1.42% compared to D100. Despite benefits such as improved torque and reduced particulate emissions, biodiesel blends, particularly B20, led to increased NOx and CO2 emissions, emphasizing the need for further op-timization of blend formulations and emission control strategies. This study provides valuable insights into the tradeoffs and potential of biodiesel blends as sustainable diesel alternatives.</description>
      <author>Mahmut &#304;nce, Samet &#199;elebi, &#220;same Demir, Can HA&#350;&#304;MO&#286;LU</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30939/ijastech..1495167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>178 Programing the rumen microbiome to optimize microbial efficiency in high forage diets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.452</link>
      <description>Tim A. McAllister, Robert J. Gruninger, Stephanie A. Terry, Ajay Badhan, Yan Wang, Leluo Guan, Journal of Animal Science. 102(Supplement_3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402533540

                Abstract As the majority of energy and protein supplied to cattle arises as a result of ruminal fermentation, the rumen microbiome has an integral role in determining host feed efficiency. Counterintuitively, current evidence suggests that a less diverse rumen microbiome is associated with improved feed efficiency, possibly as a result of greater metabolic precision and avoidance of energy spilling fermentative pathways. The composition of the rumen microbiome is mainly determined by diet, but host traits such as rumen volume, rate of passage, rumination and immunity also have influence. Although less microbial diversity may improve feed efficiency in cattle fed a specific diet, reduced diversity may impair the ability of cattle to adapt to frequent changes in diet and the environment. Hydrogen exchange and capture is the energetic foundation of the rumen microbiome and considerable capital has been invested to develop additives that redirect hydrogen flow away from the reduction of CO2 to CH4 towards alternative sinks. These additives have been shown to reduce enteric CH4 emissions by 30 to 80%, but improvements in feed efficiency have been less than stoichiometric predictions. Approaches to improve the feed efficiency of cattle need to be multifaceted with consideration for host genetics, functional efficiency of the rumen microbiome, and the structure and composition of feed. Likewise, reductions in carbon emissions need to be broader than just CH4, with an appreciation of the role that cattle have within a circular bioeconomy to promote upcycling of nutrients and reductions in emissions from farming systems. Strategies to improve the efficiency of cattle production are a prerequisite for the sustainable intensification needed to ensure that the social license for milk and meat production from cattle is retained.</description>
      <author>Tim A. McAllister, Robert J. Gruninger, Stephanie A. Terry, Ajay Badhan, Yan Wang, Leluo Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>301 Leveraging genomics to advance the breeding of Canadian livestock</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.208</link>
      <description>Emily M. Leishman, Ricarda E Jahnel, Alexandra Harlander, Owen W Willems, Benjamin J. Wood, Shai Barbut, Fl&#225;vio S. Schenkel, F. Miglior, R. Gervais, Paul Stothard, Christine F. Baes, Journal of Animal Science. 102(Supplement_3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402541296

                Abstract Implementing breeding strategies for a more sustainable food system is one of the most pressing topics for livestock industries. Although different species face different challenges, large-scale research projects can pave the way for future opportunities in these key sectors. Herein, we present two examples (dairy and poultry) of how research projects can result in meaningful changes to commercial breeding programs. The first example is an international large-scale dairy project, which will deliver a roadmap for greenhouse gas (GHG) management using genomics and nutrition. The project aims to facilitate a 55% reduction in GHG emissions from Canadian dairy at an estimated value of $338M CAD. This systems-level approach will leverage resources developed through previous and current large-scale projects to produce accurate multi-level emission estimates and identify opportunities to mitigate enteric GHG emissions. The results of this project will provide accurate, reliable, and robust data for industry stakeholders, national policy, and GHG inventories. The second example is a research collaboration with a commercial turkey breeding company that will enable breeding strategies for long-term and sustainable genetic improvement in health traits. This project aims to reduce preslaughter mortality by 5% and condemnations due to myopathies and health issues. This reduction alone is expected to result in 7.5M kg more turkey meat at a value of $19.8M CAD. Furthermore, there is also an expected reduction of 2.3M kg of CO2 equivalent per year for each 1% livability improvement due to production efficiencies and reduced inputs wasted for more sustainable and ethical meat production. Overall, ongoing and future research initiatives will continue to deliver solutions for key Canadian livestock sectors to improve animal health and welfare as well as efficiency and sustainability. The strides made in these ongoing collaborative projects are imperative for enhancing the sustainability of animal agriculture to feed the growing population.</description>
      <author>Emily M. Leishman, Ricarda E Jahnel, Alexandra Harlander, Owen W Willems, Benjamin J. Wood, Shai Barbut, Fl&#225;vio S. Schenkel, F. Miglior, R. Gervais, Paul Stothard, Christine F. Baes</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The environmental impact of a malaria clinical trial in Mali: Life cycle assessment reveals high emissions due to international travel and local electricity use and identifies opportunities for sustainable improvement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31223/x5sh8r</link>
      <description>Merel Smit, Almahamoudou Mahamar, E. Kooistra, Kjerstin Lanke, Koualy Sanogo, Patrick Wilikpan Okedy, Mohamed Yehia, Chris Drakeley, Hugo Touw, William J. Stone, Alassane Dicko, Teun Bousema, Tim Stobernack, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402503927

                Climate change may be the single largest threat facing humanity and ecosystems, necessitating decarbonization across all sectors, including healthcare and academia. With the aim of informing and supporting sustainable research practices, we performed a life cycle assessment of a clinical trial conducted in Mali. The trial involved 80 malaria-infected participants in Ou&#233;less&#233;bougou who were treated with antimalarials and followed for 28 days to determine their clinical and transmission-blocking efficacy. Data on consumables, transportation, travel, and electricity use were collected in Mali and the Netherlands, where additional laboratory analyses and sample storage occurred. Data were analysed using the ReCiPe 2016 method for midpoint impact assessment. The trial involved 3 intercontinental shipments of materials and samples, 59,900 km of travel by research staff, and ~55 kg of plastics. Trial conduct and reporting resulted in 20.5 metric tonnes of CO2-equivalent (CO2e) emissions. Major contributors were international travel (50%), electricity in Mali (28%), and air-transportation (14%). Laboratory consumables, while contributing up to 22% of the trial&#8217;s impact on land and water use, were less important sources of emissions (2% of CO2e). Whereas the electricity mix in Mali, ~60% fossil-fuel-based, was disadvantageous for the carbon footprint, laboratory analyses in the Netherlands benefited from 100% wind energy, resulting in a minor overall contribution to emissions (&amp;lt;1%). We observed no loss in stability of parasite genetic material (mRNA) in protective buffers when stored for 12 months at -20&#176;C, compared to conventional -70&#176;C. These results form a foundation for improving the environmental sustainability of clinical trials in Africa. Switching to energy-efficient equipment settings could reduce electricity consumption by over 30%. Implementing solar panels in the Mali laboratory would reduce CO2e emissions by 28%. Immediate CO2e reductions can be achieved through online conference attendance and alternative sample transportation, which would contribute an additional 10% CO2e reduction.</description>
      <author>Merel Smit, Almahamoudou Mahamar, E. Kooistra, Kjerstin Lanke, Koualy Sanogo, Patrick Wilikpan Okedy, Mohamed Yehia, Chris Drakeley, Hugo Touw, William J. Stone, Alassane Dicko, Teun Bousema, Tim Stobernack</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31223/x5sh8r</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Plug-In Hybrid Light Duty Commercial Vehicle in Real-World Conditions by Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-24-0016</link>
      <description>Ezio Mancaruso, Giovanni Meccariello, Simona Rossetti, SAE technical papers on CD-ROM/SAE technical paper series. 1(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402588401

                &lt;div class="section abstract"&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;Light commercial vehicles are an indispensable element for the transport of people and the delivery of goods, especially on extra-urban and long-distance routes. With a view to sustainable mobility, it is necessary to think about hybridizing these vehicles to reduce the fuel consumption as well as greenhouse gas emissions and particulate matter. These types of vehicles are generally powered by diesel and travel many kilometers a day. On the other hand, the use of light commercial vehicles in battery electric vehicle (BEV) configuration has already been started but is not receiving widespread recognition. In this panorama, starting from a study already developed for the hybridization of a plug-in light commercial vehicle in Worldwide harmonized Light vehicles Test Cycle (WLTC) condition, the simulation analysis has been extended to the plug-in hybrid vehicle (PHEV) operating in real driving emission conditions (RDE). In particular, using Advisor software, a vehicle has been simulated in different plug-in hybrid configurations. The software has been validated with real operation data of a euro 6 diesel engine. The general hypothesis underlying the research consists in the possibility of using these vehicles in totally electric mode in the city and in hybrid mode outside urban centers; with the aim of reducing polluting emissions in populated city but completing the delivery mission during all phases of vehicle operation. The PHEV simulations have been performed on both WLTC and RDE condition. In the latter mode, particular attention has been devoted to the interpretation of data from GPS sensor: like the slope of the route or the presence of tunnels. The success of the simulation depends on a correct and careful reconstruction of the GPS data. Three vehicles with different hybridization factors have been simulated: 0.44, 0.56, and 0.67, respectively, with power equal to that of the base vehicle. The battery packs have been sized for the three hybrid vehicles and simulations were carried out in both Charge Depleting and Charge Sustaining configuration. In charge depleting for the highest hybrid configuration (HF=0.66), the results demonstrate that a reduction of up to 80% and 76% in fuel can be saved While a reduction up to 75% and 45% in NOx emissions can be achieved on WLTC and RDE cycle, respectively. On the other hand, when the battery is discharged, for HF=0.67, although consumption can be reduced by up to 45%, NOx emissions also increase by 183% even if ICE operation mode has to be better optimize for hybrid operation. Finally, even if the hybrid solutions is really convenient if compared to the conventional vehicle in terms of fuel savings and NOx pollutant emissions, about a realistic estimation of the CO2 reduction that can be achieved the use of electrical energy must be take into account.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <author>Ezio Mancaruso, Giovanni Meccariello, Simona Rossetti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-24-0016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the bioactive constituents and some pharmacological activities of the ethanol extracts of &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Acanthospermum hispidum&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Moringa oleifera&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4314/tjpr.v23i6.5</link>
      <description>F. O. Ojo, Erkay &#214;zg&#246;r, Tropical Journal of Pharmaceutical Research. 23(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402487962

                Purpose: To determine the bioactive compounds in Moringa oleifera (MO) and Acanthospermum hispidum (AH) with antioxidant, anticancer, antifungal and antibacterial potentials. Methods: Fresh leaves of these plants were collected from Akinmoorin and Awe, Oyo State, Nigeria. Particle-induced x-ray emission (PIXE) technique was performed using a 2.5MeV proton beam (a non-destructive elemental analysis). Phytochemicals were qualitatively analyzed using High-performance liquid chromatography (HPLC), gas chromatographic-mass spectrophotometer (GC-MS) and standard procedures. Disc diffusion method was used to determine the minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) for fungi and bacteria. Antioxidant properties were carried out by DPPH radical scavenging activity. Cancer cells (MDAMB 231 and HTC 15) were cultivated in the presence of the extracts at body temperature with 5 % CO2 and 95 % air in 100 % relative humidity. Thereafter, adherent cells were seeded and treated with increasing concentrations of the plant extracts for 48 &#8211; 72 h. Results: Phytochemical analysis showed that both plants contain alkaloids, flavonoids, anthraquinones, steroids and terpenoids, saponins, tannins, phenols and glycosides. The MIC for MO on fungi was 21.0 and 12.0 mg/mL for AH. Furthermore, MO MIC for bacteria was 25.25 mg/mL and 9.75 mg/mL for AH. Antioxidant properties revealed MO having 80.02 % and AH, 76 % at 32.00 &#181;L. The ethanolic extracts showed a 50 % reduction in cancer cell viability at 24.5 &#956;g/mL for MO and 16.0 &#956;g/mL for AH, respectively, on MDAMB 231 and HTC 15 cells. Conclusion: Moringa oleifera (MO) and Acanthospermum hispidum (AH) extracts exhibit significant antioxidant, antitumor, antifungal and antibacterial activities. Further studies will require that the active constituents be isolated and formulated into suitable dosage forms.</description>
      <author>F. O. Ojo, Erkay &#214;zg&#246;r</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4314/tjpr.v23i6.5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>379 Application of an energy and nutrient matrix to a diet supplemented with a novel phytase achieved a production and sustainability benefit in pigs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.284</link>
      <description>Deepak Velayudhan, Janet C Remus, Yueming Dersjant-Li, Ester Vinyeta, Journal of Animal Science. 102(Supplement_3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402541986

                Abstract The capacity of a novel consensus bacterial 6-phytase variant (PhyG) to maintain growth performance and production benefits of pigs when added to an energy and nutrient-reduced mixed cereal diet was assessed. Two experiments were conducted. In Exp. 1 (wean to finish), weaned pigs [n = 192; initial body weight (BW) 7.18 &#177; 0.38 kg] were randomized to 4 treatments from weaning until market weight. Diets were provided in 5 phases. Treatments included: 1) a nutritionally sufficient positive control (PC); 2) a negative control (NC1) without added inorganic phosphate, reduced (based on specific PhyG dose) in net energy (NE), calcium (Ca), digestible amino acids (AA) and sodium (Na) vs. PC, supplemented with PhyG at 1,000, 1,000, 750, 500 and 500 FTU/kg in each phase, respectively (NC1+low PhyG); 3) a negative control (NC2) as NC1 supplemented with PhyG at 2,000, 2,000, 1,000, 750 and 750 FTU/kg in each phase and further reduced in energy and nutrient based on specific PhyG dose (NC2+high PhyG), and; 4) a negative control (NC3) as 2) and supplemented with xylanase&#8211;&#946;-glucanase (XB) to provide 2,400 U/kg xylanase and 304 U/kg &#946;-glucanase, with additional reduction in NE and digestible AA based on the contribution of XB (NC3+low PhyG + XB). In Exp. 2 (nursery), weaned pigs (n = 360; initial BW 8.40 &#177; 0.78 kg) were assigned to 3 dietary treatments from weaning up to 35 d. Diets were offered in 2 phases. Treatments included a nutritionally adequate positive control (PC) and 2 PhyG-supplemented diets, reduced in digestible phosphorus, Ca, Na, NE and digestible AA vs. PC, according to the expected contribution of PhyG added at 1,000 FTU/kg (NC1) or 2,000 FTU/kg (NC2), respectively. Data were analyzed by ANOVA. Means separation was by Tukey&#8217;s HSD test. In Exp. 1, overall growth performance (114 d) in all enzyme-supplemented diets was maintained or improved compared with PC. Compared with PC, feed cost per kg BW gain was significantly reduced by 7.3% and total carbon footprint (CFP; CO2 eq. g/kg BW gain) was reduced by 6.8% with PhyG + XB combination. In Exp.2, overall growth performance (35 d), in all PhyG-supplemented, nutrient-reduced, treatments, were either not different from, or were improved, vs. PC. Total feed costs and estimated CFP per kg BW gain were reduced in all PhyG-supplemented, nutrient- and NE-reduced treatments vs. PC. In conclusion, the application of a full energy and nutrient matrix maintained the overall growth of pigs in both 114- and 35-d studies with the novel phytase. The addition of XB further improved the overall growth of market pigs. Moreover, full matrix application with PhyG achieved reductions in total feed cost and carbon footprint in both studies.</description>
      <author>Deepak Velayudhan, Janet C Remus, Yueming Dersjant-Li, Ester Vinyeta</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.284</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>358 The effect of increasing dietary limestone concentration on growth performance, gas flux, and carcass characteristics in finishing beef cattle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.427</link>
      <description>Nathan S Long, Jarret A Proctor, Ryan C Foster, Vin&#237;cius N Gouv&#234;a, Matthew R Beck, Jason K. Smith, Journal of Animal Science. 102(Supplement_3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402541624

                Abstract Reducing methane (CH4) emissions from beef cattle is desirable as CH4 is a greenhouse gas that represents an energetic loss from the production system. Limestone is commonly fed to cattle as a source of calcium but may also act as a rumen buffer and decrease CH4 emissions by limiting hydrogen availability for methanogenesis. The objective of this experiment was to determine if diet limestone concentration influences growth performance, gas flux, and carcass characteristics in finishing beef cattle. Yearling steers [n = 16; initial body weight (BW) 619 &#177; 34 kg] were stratified by BW and randomly assigned to 1 of 2 isocaloric and isonitrogenous dietary treatments in a completely randomized design where limestone was included at 1.3% (1X) or 2.6% (2X) of diet dry matter (DM). Finishing diets were formulated to contain 0.43 or 0.96% DM as Ca and were fed ad libitum using automated cattle feeders (SmartFeed Pro; C-Lock Inc.; Rapid City, SD) in a single pen for the final 37 d of finishing. Body weights were measured on d -1, 0, 36, and 37. An automated head chamber system (GreenFeed; C-Lock Inc.) was used to measure gas flux. Analysis of variance was conducted using JMP Pro 17 to determine the fixed effect of treatment with individual animal as the experimental unit. Statistical significance was defined as P &#8804; 0.05 with a tendency defined as 0.05 &amp;lt; P &#8804; 0.10. Increasing the dietary limestone concentration from 1.3 to 2.6% of DM did not influence DM intake, but numerically increased final shrunk BW (P = 0.68) and hot carcass weight (P = 0.75) and increased average daily gain (ADG; P = 0.02) and gain to feed ratio (G:F) by approximately 12%. Cattle fed the 2X diet tended to have 6.5% greater ribeye area (P = 0.09), but similar USDA yield grade, backfat thickness, and dressing percentage (P &#8805; 0.34) when compared with cattle fed the 1X diet. Daily CO2 and CH4 emissions, daily O2 consumption, CH4 yield, and respiratory quotient were unaffected by treatment (P &#8805; 0.47). The improvement in ADG resulted in a tendency for CH4 emission intensity to be decreased by 9.1% (P = 0.09) when the concentration of limestone was 2.6% of dietary DM. While increasing dietary limestone concentration from 1.3 to 2.6% of diet DM did not influence absolute daily CH4 emissions, it increased ADG through an improvement in feed efficiency, which translated to a tendency for a reduction in CH4 emission intensity. These preliminary data suggest that there may be a benefit to feeding limestone or calcium at levels greater than currently recommended by the NASEM (2016). Future research should focus on determining optimum dietary limestone or calcium levels for finishing cattle.</description>
      <author>Nathan S Long, Jarret A Proctor, Ryan C Foster, Vin&#237;cius N Gouv&#234;a, Matthew R Beck, Jason K. Smith</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skae234.427</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
