<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 01:24:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active and Stable Cu&#8208;Cd Bimetallic Oxides for Enhanced Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403261</link>
      <description>Guoliang Mei, Yanling Zhai, Weiwei Guo, Doudou Liu, Zijian Fang, Guixian Xie, Zongxia Duan, Xianzhen Lang, Zhijun Zhu, Xiaoquan Lu, Jianguo Tang, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404366530

                Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) can produce value&#8208;added chemicals such as carbon monoxide (CO) and multicarbon (C2+). However, the complex reaction pathways of CO2 electro&#8208;reduction reaction (CO2RR) greatly limit the product selectivity and conversion efficiency. Herein, the Cu&#8208;Cd bimetallic oxides catalyst was designed and applied for the CO2RR. The optimized 4.73%Cd&#8208;CuO exhibits remarkable electrocatalytic CO2RR activity for selective CO production in H&#8208;cell using 0.5 M 1&#8208;butyl&#8208;3&#8208;methylimidazolium hexafluorophosphate ([Bmim]PF6)/MeCN as electrolyte. The Faradaic efficiency of CO (FE(CO)) can be maintained above 90% over a wide potential range of &#8722;2.0 to &#8722;2.4 V vs. Ag/Ag+. Particularly, the catalyst achieves an impressive FE(CO) of 96.3% with a current density of 60.7 mA cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;2.2 V vs. Ag/Ag+. Furthermore, scaling up the 4.73%Cd&#8208;CuO catalyst into a flow cell can reach 56.64% FE of C2+ products (ethylene, ethanol and n&#8208;propanol) with a current density as high as 600 mA cm&#8722;2 steadily. The excellent CO2RR performance of the as&#8208;synthesized 4.73%Cd&#8208;CuO can be mainly attributed to the introduction of CdO to improve the ability of CuO to activate CO2, the electronic interactions between Cu and Cd can boost activation and conversion key intermediates of CO2RR and ensure the continuous stability of 4.73%Cd&#8208;CuO in electrolysis process.</description>
      <author>Guoliang Mei, Yanling Zhai, Weiwei Guo, Doudou Liu, Zijian Fang, Guixian Xie, Zongxia Duan, Xianzhen Lang, Zhijun Zhu, Xiaoquan Lu, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metals Doped into g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; via N,O Coordination as Efficient Electrocatalysts for the Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03938</link>
      <description>Haoyang Qiu, Huohai Yang, Li Wang, Manxi Leng, Xingbo Ge, Yang Xu, Xin Chen, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404376052

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO</description>
      <author>Haoyang Qiu, Huohai Yang, Li Wang, Manxi Leng, Xingbo Ge, Yang Xu, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03938</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Nanowire-Supported Catalysts for the Photocatalytic Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/engproc2024076081</link>
      <description>Feysal M. Ali, D. D. Perovi&#263;, Geoffrey A. Ozin, Hussameldin Ibrahim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404391160

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feysal M. Ali, D. D. Perovi&#263;, Geoffrey A. Ozin, Hussameldin Ibrahim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/engproc2024076081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Carbon Challenge: Design, Synthesis, and Chemisorption Behavior of Solid Sorbents in Direct Air Capture of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101740</link>
      <description>Liqi Qiu, Narges Mokhtarinori, Hongjun Liu, De&#8208;en Jiang, Jing Wang, Sheng Dai, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404421065

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liqi Qiu, Narges Mokhtarinori, Hongjun Liu, De&#8208;en Jiang, Jing Wang, Sheng Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron-Doped Polyphosphonitrile for Improved Selectivity in the Photocatalytic Conversion of Carbon Dioxide to Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5021798</link>
      <description>Xinlin Liu, YanSong Chu, Na Gong, Jiaqi Wang, Liguang Tang, Yu Gu, Jie Jin, Ziyang Lu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404424443

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinlin Liu, YanSong Chu, Na Gong, Jiaqi Wang, Liguang Tang, Yu Gu, Jie Jin, Ziyang Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5021798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proper N Coordination improves catalytic activity of graphene edge anchored Pt single atom for conversion of methane and carbon dioxide to acetic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114688</link>
      <description>Baoyu Huang, Xiaomei Zhao, Yang Ma, Zhengjun Fang, Molecular Catalysis. 570(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404436532

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baoyu Huang, Xiaomei Zhao, Yang Ma, Zhengjun Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tandem modulation strategy for copper-based catalysts: Towards efficient C-C coupling in the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.11.007</link>
      <description>Shiji Li, Zekun Zhang, Duowen Yang, Shanshan Li, Jing Wang, Wei Yan, Hao Xu, Journal of Environmental Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404443658

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiji Li, Zekun Zhang, Duowen Yang, Shanshan Li, Jing Wang, Wei Yan, Hao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.11.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioelectrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction by an engineered formate dehydrogenase from Thermoanaerobacter kivui</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53946-3</link>
      <description>Weisong Liu, Kuncheng Zhang, Jiang Liu, Yuanming Wang, Meng Zhang, Huijuan Cui, Junsong Sun, Lingling Zhang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404448505

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weisong Liu, Kuncheng Zhang, Jiang Liu, Yuanming Wang, Meng Zhang, Huijuan Cui, Junsong Sun, Lingling Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53946-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction: Solar-driven carbon dioxide reduction: a review of recent developments and future prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11696-024-03766-y</link>
      <description>Omar H. AL&#8208;Zoubi, Somavia Ameen, Farag M. A. Altalbawy, Carlos Rodriguez&#8208;Benites, Soumya V. Menon, Mandeep Kaur, I. B. Sapaev, Merwa Alhadrawi, G. V. Sivaprasad, Hussam Abdali Abdulridui, Chemical Papers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404261546

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Omar H. AL&#8208;Zoubi, Somavia Ameen, Farag M. A. Altalbawy, Carlos Rodriguez&#8208;Benites, Soumya V. Menon, Mandeep Kaur, I. B. Sapaev, Merwa Alhadrawi, G. V. Sivaprasad, Hussam Abdali Abdulridui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11696-024-03766-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured photo-active electrodes for the electrochemical reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4404389133</link>
      <description>Parviz Allazov, M Barr, Alireza Ranjbari, Sylvain Franger, Julien Bachmann, Pierre Millet, Lo&#239;c Assaud, No host. None(None)] 2019. https://openalex.org/W4404389133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Parviz Allazov, M Barr, Alireza Ranjbari, Sylvain Franger, Julien Bachmann, Pierre Millet, Lo&#239;c Assaud</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4404389133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transferring enzyme features to molecular CO2 reduction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cbpa.2024.102540</link>
      <description>Matth&#237;as Huber, Corinna R. Hess, Current Opinion in Chemical Biology. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404418780

                Carbon monoxide dehydrogenases and formate dehydrogenases efficiently catalyze the reduction of CO</description>
      <author>Matth&#237;as Huber, Corinna R. Hess</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cbpa.2024.102540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular level insights on the pulsed electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54122-3</link>
      <description>Ke Ye, Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Hyun Dong Jung, Peng Shen, So Min Jang, Zhe Weng, Seoin Back, Wen&#8208;Bin Cai, Kun Jiang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404252638

                Electrochemical CO</description>
      <author>Ke Ye, Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Hyun Dong Jung, Peng Shen, So Min Jang, Zhe Weng, Seoin Back, Wen&#8208;Bin Cai, Kun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54122-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palladium (II) pyridylidene sulfonamides (PYSAs) for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.140582</link>
      <description>Afshan Khurshid, Muhammad Nawaz Tahir, Tilo S&#246;hnel, Ehsan Ullah Mughal, Ryan J. Trovitch, M. Naveed Zafar, Journal of Molecular Structure. 1322(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404315305

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Afshan Khurshid, Muhammad Nawaz Tahir, Tilo S&#246;hnel, Ehsan Ullah Mughal, Ryan J. Trovitch, M. Naveed Zafar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.140582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Molecular and Two Dimensional Metalloporphyrin Catalysts for the Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-16402</link>
      <description>Amira Uddin, Rachel Crespo&#8208;Otero, Devis Di Tommaso, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404291661

                A computational investigation of the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2R) on metalloporphyrin (M-POR) catalysts, featuring varying metal centres (Ni, Fe, Cu, and Co), oxidation states, and anchoring ligands, was conducted using density functional theory calculations. The evaluation of the thermodynamic and electrochemical stability of the M-POR systems concluded that neutral systems are more stable than charged systems, with the doubly reduced systems being the most unstable. The reaction free energy profiles for CO2R to the C1 products CO and HCOOH were computed according to two possible mechanisms: coupled proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) and proton transfer &#8211; electron transfer (PT-ET). The PCET pathways was found to be by far the most favourable, leading to the preferential formation of HCOOH over CO. Among the catalysts, Fe-POR exhibited the best catalytic performance for CO/HCOOH formation. To evaluate competition with the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), overpotentials of the CO2R and HER were compared for all systems. This comparison, along with the PCET analysis, revealed that most systems favour HCOOH production. The most promising M-PORs were then to generate models of two-dimensional (2D) carbonaceous frameworks, exploring their potential for CO2R, with 2D Fe-PORs being active towards C1 formation.</description>
      <author>Amira Uddin, Rachel Crespo&#8208;Otero, Devis Di Tommaso</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-16402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of Bismuth Nanosheets on Copper Foam Coupled with Nanobubble Technology for Enhanced Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06898j</link>
      <description>Kai Wu, Pengwei Yang, Shuaijun Fan, Yifan Wu, Jingxiang Ma, Lijuan Yang, Hongtao Zhu, Xiaoying Ma, Hongjun Gao, Wen&#8208;Tong Chen, Jun Jia, Shuangchen Ma, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404353837

                The recycling of industrially emitted CO2 is an urgent environmental task. Electrochemical reduction of CO2 into valuable chemical products presents an attractive approach. However, due to the inherent high chemical...</description>
      <author>Kai Wu, Pengwei Yang, Shuaijun Fan, Yifan Wu, Jingxiang Ma, Lijuan Yang, Hongtao Zhu, Xiaoying Ma, Hongjun Gao, Wen&#8208;Tong Chen, Jun Jia, Shuangchen Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06898j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Using a New Ru&#8208;NAD Type Bis Carbonyl Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400657</link>
      <description>Debashis Ghosh, T. Kajiwara, Nandini M Gotgi, Koji Tanaka, European Journal of Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404428097

                A new ruthenium(II) NAD (NAD = Nicotinamide Adenine Dinucleotide) type bis&#8208;carbonyl complex, [Ru(bpy)(pbn)(CO)2]2+ [pbn = 2&#8208;(pyridin&#8208;2&#8208;yl)benzo[b]&#8208;1,5&#8208;naphthyridine; bpy = 2,2'&#8208;bipyridine] [1]2+, was successfully synthesized and fully characterized by single&#8208;crystal X&#8208;ray structural analysis, ESI&#8208;MS, IR and NMR spectroscopy. Complex [1]2+ together with [Ru(bpy)(pbn)(CO)(COOH)]+ and/or [Ru(bpy)(pbn) (CO)(CO2)]0 complexes exist as equilibrium mixtures in aqueous solutions as evident from spectroscopic study. Chemical reduction of [1]2+ resulted the formation corresponding NADH form i.e., [Ru(bpy)(pbnHH)(CO)2]2+ (pbnHH = 2&#8208;(pyridin&#8208;2&#8208;yl)&#8208;5,10&#8208;dihydrobenzo[b][1,5]naphthyridine) [1.HH]2+ as a two&#8208;electron&#8208;reduced species. The electrochemical behavior of complex [1]2+ in the presence of acid was investigated based on cyclic voltammetry analysis. A control potential electrolysis of [1]2+ afforded formate (HCOO&#8208;) as the major product with a lesser amount of CO and H2, whereas that of [Ru(bpy)2(CO)2]2+ complex produced CO as the main product with a lesser amount of HCOO&#8208; and H2. The experimental results suggest that the selectivity of HCOO&#8208; over CO should be due to catalytic hydride transfer from the NADH&#8208;type ligands of [1]2+ to CO2.</description>
      <author>Debashis Ghosh, T. Kajiwara, Nandini M Gotgi, Koji Tanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of UAVs and Remote Sensing Technologies for Atmospheric CO2 Capturing: A Study Application of UAVs and Remote Sensing in CO2 Reductions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53697/ijgaes.v1i3.3348</link>
      <description>Biplov Paneru, Bishwash Paneru, Ramhari Poudyal, Khem N. Poudyal, No host. 1(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404446436

                Human activities are a significant contributor to climate change, with rising levels of CO&#8322; in the atmosphere. Several carbon capture and sequestration (CCS) methods have been developed to address this issue. Uncrewed Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) and remote sensing technologies are emerging as significant improvements to the efficiency and effectiveness of atmospheric carbon capture initiatives. This research examines using UAVs and remote sensing technologies to monitor, quantify, and manage atmospheric CO&#8322; levels. Furthermore, the study explores the implications of integrating robotic-drone technology, emphasizing their ability to contribute to a sustainable future. These technologies, incorporating modern data collection and analysis methodologies, provide promising answers for climate change mitigation and long-term environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>Biplov Paneru, Bishwash Paneru, Ramhari Poudyal, Khem N. Poudyal</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53697/ijgaes.v1i3.3348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co Cluster-Modified Ni Nanoparticles with Superior Light-Driven Thermocatalytic CO2 Reduction by CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225338</link>
      <description>Mei Li, Yuhua Zhang, Na Sun, Dan Cheng, Peng Sun, Qian Zhang, Molecules. 29(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404331619

                Excessive fossil burning causes energy shortages and contributes to the environmental crisis. Light-driven thermocatalytic CO2 reduction by methane (CRM) provides an effective strategy to conquer these two global challenges. Ni-based catalysts have been developed as candidates for CRM that are comparable to the noble metal catalysts. However, they are prone to deactivation due to the thermodynamically inevitable coking side reactions. Herein, we reported a novel Co-Ni/SiO2 nanocomposite of Co cluster-modified Ni nanoparticles, which greatly enhance the catalytic durability for light-driven thermocatalytic CRM. It exhibits high production rates of H2 (rH2) and CO (rCO, 22.8 and 26.7 mmol min&#8722;1 g&#8722;1, respectively), and very high light-to-fuel efficiency (&#414;) is achieved (26.8%). Co-Ni/SiO2 shows better catalytic durability than the referenced catalyst of Ni/SiO2. Based on the experimental results of TG-MS, TEM, and HRTEM, we revealed the origin of the significantly enhanced light-driven thermocatalytic activity and durability as well as the novel photoactivation. It was discovered that the focused irradiation markedly reduces the apparent activation energy of CO2 on the Co-Ni/SiO2 nanocomposite, thus significantly enhancing the light-driven thermocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Mei Li, Yuhua Zhang, Na Sun, Dan Cheng, Peng Sun, Qian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXene quantum dot-sensitized heterostructures for broad solar spectrum CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102296</link>
      <description>Cheng&#8208;May Fung, Boon&#8208;Junn Ng, Yi&#8208;Hao Chew, Chen&#8208;Chen Er, Jingxiang Low, Xuecheng Guo, Xin Ying Kong, Lling&#8208;Lling Tan, Hiroshi &#332;nishi, Abdul Rahman Mohamed, Siang&#8208;Piao Chai, Cell Reports Physical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404319954

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng&#8208;May Fung, Boon&#8208;Junn Ng, Yi&#8208;Hao Chew, Chen&#8208;Chen Er, Jingxiang Low, Xuecheng Guo, Xin Ying Kong, Lling&#8208;Lling Tan, Hiroshi &#332;nishi, Abdul Rahman Mohamed, Siang&#8208;Piao Chai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening of Transition Metal-Nitrogen-Carbon Materials as Electrocatalysts for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145357</link>
      <description>Megan C. Davis, Wilton J. M. Kort-Kamp, Edward F. Holby, Piotr Zelenay, Ivana Matanovi&#263;, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404357011

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Megan C. Davis, Wilton J. M. Kort-Kamp, Edward F. Holby, Piotr Zelenay, Ivana Matanovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced formate production from sulfur modified copper for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.133817</link>
      <description>Feng Wang, Wenhao Jing, Shengjie Bai, Ya Liu, Liejin Guo, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404321820

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Wang, Wenhao Jing, Shengjie Bai, Ya Liu, Liejin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.133817</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Relationship between Electronic Behavior of Single Atom Catalysts and CO2 Reduction to Oxygenates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100141</link>
      <description>Fenghai Cao, Guangbo Liu, Xianbiao Wang, Li Tan, Noritatsu Tsubaki, EnergyChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404438100

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fenghai Cao, Guangbo Liu, Xianbiao Wang, Li Tan, Noritatsu Tsubaki</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the role of redox carriers in the reduction of CO2 by the oxo-acid: ferredoxin oxidoreductase superfamily</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.mie.2024.10.022</link>
      <description>Sheila C. Bonitatibus, Mathew Walker, Sean J. Elliott, Methods in enzymology on CD-ROM/Methods in enzymology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404402935

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sheila C. Bonitatibus, Mathew Walker, Sean J. Elliott</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.mie.2024.10.022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Second Sphere Control of CO2 Reduction Selectivity by Iron Porphyrins: The role of spin state</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2024.123439</link>
      <description>Suman Patra, Soumili Ghosh, Soumya Samanta, Abhijit Nayek, Abhishek Dey, Journal of Organometallic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404338960

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suman Patra, Soumili Ghosh, Soumya Samanta, Abhijit Nayek, Abhishek Dey</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2024.123439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin Pd-Loaded Cu2o Stabilises Cu+ to Facilitate Electrochemical Co2 Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5016771</link>
      <description>Zhongxiao Song, Xiaoye Du, Jaehyun Kim, Bo Gao, Dan Qian, Chunhui Xiao, Shujiang Ding, Ki Tae Nam, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404242260

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongxiao Song, Xiaoye Du, Jaehyun Kim, Bo Gao, Dan Qian, Chunhui Xiao, Shujiang Ding, Ki Tae Nam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5016771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient urea electrosynthesis from nitrite and CO2 reduction on single W atom catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.075</link>
      <description>Di Yuan, Yajie Jiang, Wenyu Du, Dongwei Ma, Ke Chu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404399123

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Di Yuan, Yajie Jiang, Wenyu Du, Dongwei Ma, Ke Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen radical-boosted electrocatalytic CO2 reduction using Ni-partnered heteroatomic pairs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53529-2</link>
      <description>Zhibo Yao, Hao Cheng, Yifei Xu, Xinyu Zhan, Song Hong, Xinyi Tan, Tai&#8208;Sing Wu, Pei Xiong, Y. L. Soo, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Leiduan Hao, Liang Xu, Alex W. Robertson, Bingjun Xu, Ming Yang, Zhenyu Sun, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404348913

                The electrocatalytic reduction of CO</description>
      <author>Zhibo Yao, Hao Cheng, Yifei Xu, Xinyu Zhan, Song Hong, Xinyi Tan, Tai&#8208;Sing Wu, Pei Xiong, Y. L. Soo, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Leiduan Hao, Liang Xu, Alex W. Robertson, Bingjun Xu, Ming Yang, Zhenyu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53529-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Integrated Solution of Energy Storage and CO2 Reduction: Trans-critical CO2 Energy Storage System Combining Carbon Capture with LNG Cold Energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144228</link>
      <description>Yin Liang, Yonglin Ju, Qianguo Lin, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404387933

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yin Liang, Yonglin Ju, Qianguo Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buildings in Hot Climate Zones&#8212;Quantification of Energy and CO2 Reduction Potential for Different Architecture and Building Services Measures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229812</link>
      <description>Doris &#214;sterreicher, Axel Seerig, Sustainability. 16(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404275302

                Reducing energy and associated greenhouse gas emissions in buildings is one of the key aspects of climate change on a global level. To put the building sector on a low carbon development path, policies and adequate financing play a crucial role in each region. In the global South, policies and regulations related to the decarbonization of the building stock are increasingly being implemented. For policy and decision makers, adequate data on the status quo of the building stock, as well as the quantification of energy reduction measures, are essential to make informed decisions on the building regulatory and funding framework. The objective of this study is to provide data-driven insights into the potential for energy and CO2 reduction in buildings across various hot climate zones in the Global South. A simulation-based approach was employed to model five different building types, ranging from residential homes to office buildings, under a variety of architectural and building services scenarios. The simulations were conducted using the dynamic building energy simulation tool EnergyPlus, which assessed the impact of various energy-saving measures under both current and projected future climate conditions. This study concludes that optimizing passive design features, such as improved windows, solar shading, and reflective surfaces, in conjunction with active systems like decentralized cooling units and renewable energy integration, can result in a notable reduction in energy demand and emissions. Our findings provide a robust basis for policymakers to develop targeted energy efficiency strategies for buildings in hot climate zones, which will play a crucial role in achieving climate goals in the Global South.</description>
      <author>Doris &#214;sterreicher, Axel Seerig</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu nanosheets with exposed (111) crystal facets for highly efficient electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction toward methanol production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce01015a</link>
      <description>yuyuan Chen, Yu-Chen Huang, Xia Hu, Sijie Lin, Dekun Ma, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404235533

                The exposed crystal facets of Cu have profound effect on its electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) activity and product selectivity. On the other hand, at present, most of studies on...</description>
      <author>yuyuan Chen, Yu-Chen Huang, Xia Hu, Sijie Lin, Dekun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce01015a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular catalyst coordinatively bonded to organic semiconductors for selective light-driven CO2 reduction in water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54026-2</link>
      <description>Jia&#8208;Wei Wang, Fengyi Zhao, Luc&#237;a Velasco, Maxime Sauvan, Dooshaye Moonshiram, Martina Salati, Zhi&#8208;Mei Luo, Sheng He, Tao Jin, Yanfei Mu, Mehmed Z. Ertem, Tianquan Lian, Antoni Llobet, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404252672

                The selective photoreduction of CO</description>
      <author>Jia&#8208;Wei Wang, Fengyi Zhao, Luc&#237;a Velasco, Maxime Sauvan, Dooshaye Moonshiram, Martina Salati, Zhi&#8208;Mei Luo, Sheng He, Tao Jin, Yanfei Mu, Mehmed Z. Ertem, Tianquan Lian, Antoni Llobet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54026-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of ZnIn2S4/SrTiO3/In(OH)3 heterojunction for antibiotic removal, H2 evolution and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177574</link>
      <description>Bangfu Ding, Shuai Liu, Yong Wang, Shuaiqi Liu, Liang Mao, Junying Zhang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404387958

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bangfu Ding, Shuai Liu, Yong Wang, Shuaiqi Liu, Liang Mao, Junying Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction over Ag/CuSn Electrodes: Modulation of C1, C2, and C3+ products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.11.032</link>
      <description>Yunji Gwon, Seon Young Hwang, Sooyeon Bae, Gaeun Yun, So Young Kim, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn, Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404450072

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunji Gwon, Seon Young Hwang, Sooyeon Bae, Gaeun Yun, So Young Kim, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.11.032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CO2-reduction methanogenesis in microbial electrosynthesis: Role of oxygen-containing groups on carbon-based cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131830</link>
      <description>Xuejiao Qi, Xuan Jia, Mingxiao Li, Meiying Ye, Yufang Wei, Fanhua Meng, Shan&#8208;Fei Fu, Beidou Xi, Bioresource Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404406183

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuejiao Qi, Xuan Jia, Mingxiao Li, Meiying Ye, Yufang Wei, Fanhua Meng, Shan&#8208;Fei Fu, Beidou Xi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic Ni/Fe functionalized, 3D printed, self-supporting catalytic-electrodes for CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133703</link>
      <description>Jiayi Sheng, Mingshu Gao, Hao Chen, Kai Zhao, Yan-Li Shi, Wei Wang, Fuel. 382(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404438440

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayi Sheng, Mingshu Gao, Hao Chen, Kai Zhao, Yan-Li Shi, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of the impact of novel photovoltaic materials on climate change: A numerical simulation study on surface temperature regulation and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5370292/v1</link>
      <description>Peng Zhang, Xiang Gao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404328671

                Abstract Global climate change is an urgent environmental challenge . To mitigate global warming, Solar Radiation Management (SRM) is being explored as a means to reduce the solar energy reaching Earth&#8217;s surface, thus controlling temperature rise. At the same time, greenhouse gas emissions remain the main cause of global warming. Large-scale photovoltaic installations, which are key for renewable energy generation, can also exacerbate local heat island effects and potentially impact both local and global climates . To address these issues, recent advancements in selective transmission and reflection photovoltaic materials have offered promising solutions. These materials achieve high energy conversion efficiency while reflecting significant portions of sunlight, thereby lowering surface temperatures. By combining solar radiation reflection with CO2 emissions reduction through clean energy generation, photovoltaic panels play a dual role in climate regulation . This study utilizes numerical simulations to evaluate the long-term climate impact of these novel photovoltaic materials, focusing on their effectiveness in surface temperature regulation and CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Peng Zhang, Xiang Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5370292/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UV&#8211;visible-infrared light driven photothermal synergistic catalytic reduction of CO2 over Cs3Bi2Br9/MoS2 S-scheme photocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.107</link>
      <description>Min Jin, Xiaotang Yang, Xuesheng Wang, Zhijie Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404437341

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Jin, Xiaotang Yang, Xuesheng Wang, Zhijie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countries need to provide clarity on the role of carbon dioxide removal in their climate pledges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad91c7</link>
      <description>William F. Lamb, Carl&#8208;Friedrich Schleussner, Giacomo Grassi, Stephen M. Smith, Matthew Gidden, Oliver Geden, Artur Runge-Metzger, Naomi E. Vaughan, Gregory F. Nemet, Injy Johnstone, Ingrid Schulte, Jan C. Minx, Environmental Research Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404331932

                Abstract Carbon dioxide removal (CDR) involves capturing CO2 from the atmosphere and storing it for decades to millennia. Alongside deep emissions reductions, CDR is required for meeting the temperature goal of the Paris Agreement (IPCC 2022). However, parties to the agreement do not currently distinguish CDR from emissions reductions in their climate pledges. In this perspective, we argue that this lowers transparency and hinders the assessment of how credible and ambitious mitigation plans are.</description>
      <author>William F. Lamb, Carl&#8208;Friedrich Schleussner, Giacomo Grassi, Stephen M. Smith, Matthew Gidden, Oliver Geden, Artur Runge-Metzger, Naomi E. Vaughan, Gregory F. Nemet, Injy Johnstone, Ingrid Schulte, Jan C. Minx</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad91c7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pristine and Cu-decorated &#968;-graphene-based materials for CO2 activation: A DFT(D)+ U Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ztx08-v3</link>
      <description>Kamal Kumar, Nora H. de Leeuw, Jost Adam, Abhishek Kumar Mishra, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404417467

                Capturing and repurposing anthropogenic carbon dioxide (CO2) is the traditional way to deal with climate change and lack of fossil fuel. CO2 adsorption (reduction) is the first step in this process. We have employed density functional theory-based calculations to investigate CO2 activation over the pristine and Cu-decorated carbon-based two-dimensional &#968;-graphene material and its hydrogenated forms, i.e., &#968;-graphone (half hydrogenated) and &#968;-graphane (fully hydrogenated). &#968;-graphene is a metallic allotrope of graphene containing 5-6-7 membered carbon rings. Our study found exothermic binding of CO2 with all three materials (for both pristine and Cu-decorated materials), indicating spontaneous physisorption. The presence of single atoms of the transition metal plays a significant role in increasing the activity of materials towards CO2 activation. We observed that the adsorption energy increases about three times after decorating a &#968;-graphene sheet with Cu atoms. In contrast, no significant variation is observed on &#968;-graphone or &#968;-graphane materials. Our Bader charge analysis confirms the charge transfer from 2d nano-sheets to the molecule, where the values of calculated adsorption energies and the density of states suggest that the interaction between CO2 and these three materials can be categorized as weak physisorption., while Cu decoration enhances the CO2 adsorption.</description>
      <author>Kamal Kumar, Nora H. de Leeuw, Jost Adam, Abhishek Kumar Mishra</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ztx08-v3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anticorrelation of net uptake of atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by the world ocean and terrestrial biosphere in current carbon cycle models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-5045-2024</link>
      <description>Stephen E. Schwartz, Biogeosciences. 21(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404423688

                Abstract. The rate at which atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) would decrease in response to a decrease in anthropogenic emissions or cessation (net zero emissions) is of great scientific and societal interest. Such a decrease in atmospheric CO2 on the centennial scale would be due essentially entirely to transfer of carbon into the world ocean (WO) and the terrestrial biosphere (TB), which are sink compartments on this timescale. The rate of decrease in excess atmospheric CO2 and the apportionment of this decrease into the two sink compartments have been examined in two prior model intercomparison studies, subsequent either to a pulse emission of CO2 or to abrupt cessation of anthropogenic CO2 emissions. The present study examines and quantifies inter-model anticorrelation in those studies in the net rate and extent of uptake of CO2 into the two sink compartments. Specifically, in each study the time-dependent coefficients characterizing the net transfer rate into the two sink compartments (evaluated as the net transfer rate normalized to excess atmospheric CO2 above the pre-pulse amount for the pulse experiment or as the net transfer rate divided by excess atmospheric CO2 above the preindustrial amount for the abrupt cessation experiment) were found to exhibit strong anticorrelation across the participating models. That is, models for which the normalized rate of uptake into the WO was high exhibited low uptake rate into the TB and vice versa. This anticorrelation in net transfer rate results in anticorrelation in net uptake extent into the two compartments that is substantially greater than would be expected simply from competition for excess CO2 between the two sink compartments. This anticorrelation, which is manifested in diminished inter-model diversity, can lead to artificially enhanced confidence in current understanding of the consequences of potential future reductions of CO2 emissions and in the global warming potentials of non-CO2 greenhouse gases relative to that of CO2.</description>
      <author>Stephen E. Schwartz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-5045-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scientific Case Against Net Zero: Falsifying the Greenhouse Gas Hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5539/jsd.v17n6p137</link>
      <description>Michael Simpson, Journal of Sustainable Development. 17(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404425509

                The UK Net Zero by 2050 Policy was undemocratically adopted by the UK government in 2019. Yet the science of so-called &amp;lsquo;greenhouse gases&amp;rsquo; is well known and there is no reason to reduce emissions of carbon dioxide (CO2), methane (CH4), or nitrous oxide (N2O) because absorption of radiation is logarithmic. Adding to or removing these naturally occurring gases from the atmosphere will make little difference to the temperature or the climate. Water vapor (H2O) is claimed to be a much stronger &amp;lsquo;greenhouse gas&amp;rsquo; than CO2, CH4 or N2O but cannot be regulated because it occurs naturally in vast quantities. This work explores the established science and recent developments in scientific knowledge around Net Zero with a view to making a rational recommendation for policy makers. There is little scientific evidence to support the case for Net Zero and that greenhouse gases are unlikely to contribute to a &amp;lsquo;climate emergency&amp;rsquo; at current or any likely future higher concentrations. There is a case against the adoption of Net Zero given the enormous costs associated with implementing the policy, and the fact it is unlikely to achieve reductions in average near surface global air temperature, regardless of whether Net Zero is fully implemented and adopted worldwide. Therefore, Net Zero does not pass the cost-benefit test. The recommended policy is to abandon Net Zero and do nothing about so-called &amp;lsquo;greenhouse gases&amp;rsquo;.</description>
      <author>Michael Simpson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5539/jsd.v17n6p137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Supported ZnO under Conditions of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Methanol: Why 0.2 ML Coverage?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02908</link>
      <description>Robert H. Lavroff, Edison Cummings, Kaustubh J. Sawant, Zisheng Zhang, Philippe Sautet, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404420877

                By hydrogenating carbon dioxide to value-added products such as methanol, heterogeneous catalysts can lower greenhouse gas emissions and generate alternative liquid fuels. The most common commercial catalyst for the reduction of CO2 to methanol is Cu/ZnO/Al2O3, where ZnO improves conversion and selectivity toward methanol. The structure of this catalyst is thought to be Zn oxy(hydroxyl) overlayers on the nanometer scale on Cu. In the presence of CO2 and H2 under reaction conditions, the Cu substrate itself can be restructured and/or partially oxidized at its interface with ZnO, or the Zn might be reduced, possibly completely to a CuZn alloy, making the exact structure and stoichiometry of the active site a topic of active debate. In this study, we examine Zn3 clusters on Cu(100) and Cu(111), as a subnano model of the catalyst. We use a grand canonical genetic algorithm to sample the system structure and stoichiometry under catalytic conditions: T of 550 K, initial partial pressures of H2 of 4.5 atm and CO2 of 0.5 atm, and 1% conversion. We uncover a strong dependence of the catalyst stoichiometry on the surface coverage. At the optimal 0.2 ML surface coverage, chains of Zn(OH) form on both Cu surfaces. On Cu(100), the catalyst has many thermally accessible metastable minima, whereas on Cu(111), it does not. No oxidation or reconstruction of the Cu is found. However, at a lower coverage of Zn, Zn3 clusters take on a metallic form on Cu(100), and slightly oxidized Zn3O on Cu(111), while the surface uptakes H to form a variety of low hydrides of Cu. We thus hypothesize that the 0.2 ML Zn coverage is optimal, as found experimentally, because of the stronger yet incomplete oxidation afforded by Zn at this coverage.</description>
      <author>Robert H. Lavroff, Edison Cummings, Kaustubh J. Sawant, Zisheng Zhang, Philippe Sautet, Anastassia N. Alexandrova</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of an Adaptive Ventilation Control System on Indoor Air Quality and Energy Consumption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229836</link>
      <description>Vasilica Vasile, Vlad Iordache, Valentin Mihai Radu, Cristian Petcu, Claudiu-Sorin Dragomir, Sustainability. 16(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404273108

                Indoor air quality (IAQ) and energy consumption (Q) are well-known building estimators, but they are used separately. Energy consumption is used during the design stage, while IAQ is used during operation. The novelty of our approach is that we propose using both estimators simultaneously during building operations. The purpose of this study was to find an adaptive ventilation strategy that maintained good indoor air quality with minimal energy consumption. The second novelty of our approach consists of IAQ estimation. While the operation of ventilation systems depends only on the indoor carbon dioxide (CO2) concentration at present, our novel approach uses a more global IAQ index that includes four different air pollutants. Physical models are used for the hourly prediction of the two indices: global IAQ and Q. This study presents a comparative analysis of several ventilation operations strategies: fixed versus adaptive. The main findings show that a decrease in the ventilation rate, na, from 3.5 h&#8722;1 to 2.0 h&#8722;1 leads to a diminishment in energy consumption of 42.9%, maintaining the global IAQ index under the limited health risk value (VRL). Moreover, an adaptive ventilation strategy of na, maintaining the global IAQ index value under VRL, achieves a further reduction in energy consumption of 72.9%, highlighting its efficiency.</description>
      <author>Vasilica Vasile, Vlad Iordache, Valentin Mihai Radu, Cristian Petcu, Claudiu-Sorin Dragomir</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The introduction of vertical solar power plants into the energy system of the European part of Russia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18822/byusu202401102-110</link>
      <description>&#1040;&#1085;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085; &#1040;&#1085;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1077;&#1074;&#1080;&#1095; &#1041;&#1091;&#1073;&#1077;&#1085;&#1095;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, V. N. Goryunov, Boris B. Dorogov, Yugra State University Bulletin. 20(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404249197

                Subject of research: optimal placement and operating modes of solar power plants, taking into account the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions. Purpose of research: determine the influence of different orientations of photovoltaic power plants on carbon dioxide emissions Object of research: photovoltaic plants Methods of research: a combination of data coverage analysis models and an analytical hierarchy process Main results of research: It is shown that vertical photovoltaic systems can reduce storage capacity or reduce the utilization rate of gas-fired power plants. Without any storage options, it is possible to reduce total carbon dioxide emissions to 10.2 million tons per year.</description>
      <author>&#1040;&#1085;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085; &#1040;&#1085;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1077;&#1074;&#1080;&#1095; &#1041;&#1091;&#1073;&#1077;&#1085;&#1095;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, V. N. Goryunov, Boris B. Dorogov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18822/byusu202401102-110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Logistics in E-commerce Industry: A Case Study on Daraz Nepal Pvt. Ltd.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3126/jacem.v9i1.71446</link>
      <description>Sujan Kharel, Sofina Maharjan, Journal of Advanced College of Engineering and Management. 9(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404376432

                This thesis explores the important role of last-mile delivery in the logistics sector, with a particular focus on the e-commerce sector. Daraz, a leader in e-commerce, currently relies on two- and four-wheeled gasoline-powered vehicles for last-mile deliveries, using a hub-based model spread across nine locations across the Kathmandu valley. In line with its commitment to environmental sustainability, Daraz aims to convert its entire fleet of gasoline-powered vehicles to electric alternatives, thereby contributing to the global effort to reduce the carbon emissions. Our research yields compelling findings that highlight the significant benefits of transitioning from internal combustion engines (ICEs) to electric vehicles in the context of e-commerce last-mile delivery. These results highlight the financial and ecological benefits of adopting electric mobility in the logistics sector. We recommend that organizations involved in last-mile delivery, especially in e-commerce, carefully consider the use of electric vehicles as a financially prudent and environmentally friendly option. This conversion promises significant fuel savings, significantly improved fuel efficiency and an extremely short payback period of less than 5 years. In addition to these findings, our research also examines the transformative potential of energy consumption and emissions reduction in last-mile logistics. The energy consumption by EV is found to be less than 50% than that of petrol option. We reveal a stark disparity between petrol and electric vehicles, with petrol two- and four-wheelers showing significant energy consumption and emissions, especially in the area of carbon dioxide (CO2). In summary, our research makes a compelling case for a cleaner, more sustainable and more economically viable future in last-mile logistics through the adoption of electric vehicles and other innovations.</description>
      <author>Sujan Kharel, Sofina Maharjan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3126/jacem.v9i1.71446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen-intercalation PdZn bimetallene for urea electro-synthesis from nitrate and carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04802d</link>
      <description>Ziqiang Wang, Yanan Wang, Shan Xu, Kai Deng, Hongjie Yu, You Xu, Hongjing Wang, Liang Wang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404332436

                Electrochemical co-reduction of carbon dioxide and nitrate is a green technology to replace traditional energy-intensive method for urea synthesis, and the development of high-performance catalysts is still a great challenge....</description>
      <author>Ziqiang Wang, Yanan Wang, Shan Xu, Kai Deng, Hongjie Yu, You Xu, Hongjing Wang, Liang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04802d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting CO2 electroreduction activity of porphyrinic conjugated microporous polyanilines via accelerating proton transfer dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05918b</link>
      <description>Feng Qiu, Chunyan Li, Xiaodong Xuan, Senhe Huang, Chenbao Lu, Hualin Lin, Sheng Han, Xiaodong Zhuang, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404327512

                Conjugated microporous polymers (CMPs) with &#960;-conjugated framework, inherent porosity and tunable structure have been considered as the promising platforms as electrocatalysts for carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). Promoting the proton...</description>
      <author>Feng Qiu, Chunyan Li, Xiaodong Xuan, Senhe Huang, Chenbao Lu, Hualin Lin, Sheng Han, Xiaodong Zhuang, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05918b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global forecasting of carbon concentration through a deep learning spatiotemporal modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122922</link>
      <description>Marc Semper, Manuel Curado, Jos&#233; F. Vicent, Journal of Environmental Management. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404414906

                Given the global urgency to mitigate climate change, a key action is the development of effective carbon concentration reduction policies. To this end, an influential factor is the availability of accurate predictions of carbon concentration trends. The existing spatiotemporal correlation as well as the diversity of influential factors, pose important challenges in accurately modeling these trends. In this work, different strategies based on deep learning are proposed with the aim of predicting global carbon dioxide and methane concentrations. For this purpose, satellite observations are used for six-month projections, covering geographical regions that span the globe. In addition, complementary environmental variables are integrated to improve the predictive capacity of the proposed models. The results obtained demonstrate the high accuracy of the predictions, in particular of models based on graphical neural networks, reaffirming the great potential of deep learning techniques in predicting carbon dioxide and methane concentrations. Likewise, the effectiveness of models based on deep learning to accurately predict carbon concentrations by incorporating dynamic and static information is demonstrated.</description>
      <author>Marc Semper, Manuel Curado, Jos&#233; F. Vicent</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pathways to Carbon Neutrality in Civil Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/89/20241118</link>
      <description>Yucheng Wang, Applied and Computational Engineering. 89(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404250207

                Abstract. With the development of the global economy and trade exchanges worldwide, urban infrastructure and industrial development have become part of the competition among countries. However, the construction industry and the production of chemical materials emit a large amount of carbon dioxide, leading to the continuous deterioration of the environment, so it is necessary to effectively reduce emissions. As a synonym for global emission reduction, carbon neutrality plays an important role in different industries, especially in civil engineering. In this paper, we start with building materials and green construction to explore the realization of carbon neutrality at the source and center of carbon emission in civil engineering. Firstly, we introduce the low-carbon production technologies of cement and steel, including calcium recycling and membrane separation technology in the cement industry, high-temperature combustion technology and carbon capture technology in steel industry. Then, we take renewable concrete as an example to discuss the emission reduction path of green building materials. Finally, it outlines how to carry out green construction, introduces assembly carbon reduction technology and energy integration system, and demonstrates the possibility of this green construction program in the case of "T&amp;A House".</description>
      <author>Yucheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/89/20241118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Mechanism and Effect of Different Viscosity Reducing Methods on Offshore Heavy Oil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2834/1/012093</link>
      <description>Hui Liao, Zongbin Liu, Dong Liu, Taotao Ge, Cheng-Lin Du, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2834(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404262491

                Abstract Bohai is rich in heavy oil. And its efficient development is significant. In this essay, ordinary heavy oil and extra one were selected, and the viscosity characteristics was also investigated referring to its internal composition. And so as the reducing viscosity effects of steam, oil-soluble viscosity reducer, diesel, emulsifier, flue gas and carbon dioxide. The experimental results show that resin and asphaltene content have positive effect on the viscosity of heavy oil. Compared with ordinary heavy oil, the drop is significantly greater when the temperature increases by 10&#176;C. For ordinary heavy oil, the inflection point temperature is from 50&#176;C to 70&#176;C, and for extra-heavy oil, it is above 100&#176;C. For ordinary heavy oil, its flow effect can be better improved without too high temperature, while it&#8217;s totally different for super heavy oil. For which, higher temperature and other auxiliary viscosity reduction methods are needed to achieve better flow performance. Diesel oil reduce viscosity of heavy oil by similar solubility principle, but the demand for diesel oil is large. At 50&#176;C, the viscosity of super heavy oil with 0.5% emulsion viscosity reducer added is 36 mPa&#183;s, but the water content needs to reach above 30%.Oil-soluble viscosity reducer reduces viscosity by dissolving asphaltenes and resins and dismantling aggregate structure of heavy oil aromatic flakes.However, the dosage should reach about 20 %, so that the viscosity of super heavy oil can be reduced to the level of dilute oil. Overall, for developing super heavy oil, steam compound with oil soluble viscosity reducer can be taken into account at the early production stage, and the emulsion viscosity reducer can be used in the middle development stage and wellbore viscosity reduction and lifting process. Finally, for ordinary heavy oil, flue gas&#8217;s viscosity reduction effects, nitrogen and carbon dioxide are investigated. It is found that the viscosity reduction effect of carbon dioxide is the best, followed by flue gas and nitrogen. Considering the offshore gas source, cost and carbon emission requirements, it is recommended to use flue gas in the field. The research provides theoretical guidance and technical reference for development of different types of offshore heavy oil.</description>
      <author>Hui Liao, Zongbin Liu, Dong Liu, Taotao Ge, Cheng-Lin Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2834/1/012093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Energy-Related-CO2-Emission Decoupling from Economic Expansion and CO2 Drivers: The Tianjin Experience in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229881</link>
      <description>Fengmei Yang, Qiuli Lv, Sustainability. 16(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404328715

                Cities are key areas for carbon control and reduction. The study of the decoupling between CO2 emissions and gross domestic product (GDP) and the drivers of CO2 emissions in cities facilitates the reduction of CO2 emissions to safeguard the development of the economy. This paper first calculates the CO2 emissions in Tianjin, China, from 2005 to 2022, then uses the Tapio decoupling index to quantify the decoupling status, and, finally, explores the energy-CO2-emission drivers through the Logarithmic Mean Divisia Index (LMDI) model. The findings indicate that (1) the decrease in CO2 emissions from industrial products and transport is the main reason for the decline. (2) During the period under investigation, the predominant condition observed was a state of weak decoupling. (3) Given the economic-output effect is the primary and substantial driver of energy CO2 emissions, it is essential to harmonize the interplay between economic-development approach and CO2 emissions to foster sustainable development in Tianjin. The industrial structure plays the most critical role in hindering the reduction of CO2 emissions; therefore, optimizing industrial structure can help achieve carbon reduction and control targets. These findings enrich the study of CO2 emission factors and can also interest urban policymakers.</description>
      <author>Fengmei Yang, Qiuli Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Progress of Dual&#8208;Site Tandem Catalysts in the Preparation of Multi Carbon Products by Electro Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202412812</link>
      <description>Wenjing Xu, Huishan Shang, Jie Guan, Jing Wang, Xiaoyu Jin, Limin Tao, Ziqiang Shao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404287316

                Abstract The era of an energy economy driven by &#8220;carbon neutrality&#8221; is putting forward stricter requirements for the use of carbon resources and the governance of CO 2 . Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide reaction (CO 2 RR), driven by renewable energy, is a practical energy storage technology with broad application prospects. It can reduce CO 2 into carbon&#8208;based fuels and chemical products. Among them, multi&#8208;carbon (C 2+ ) products have higher energy density and larger market size, and can significantly reduce the global demand for fossil fuels and close the artificial carbon cycle. Introducing additional active sites into Cu&#8208;based catalysts to prepare dual&#8208;site tandem catalysts can regulate the electronic and geometric structure of the catalysts, break linear scale relationships, reduce reaction potential barriers, and bring superb and stable catalytic performance. Various types of dual&#8208;site tandem catalysts are developed, and the understanding of the tandem effect is pushed to a higher level. This paper reviews several typical dual&#8208;site tandem catalysts: atom&#8211;atom dual&#8208;site tandem catalysts, atom&#8208;particle dual&#8208;site tandem catalysts, particle&#8211;particle dual&#8208;site tandem catalysts, and heterogeneous interface dual&#8208;site tandem catalysts. It then deeply analyzes the reaction mechanism and research progress of these advanced catalysts in CO 2 RR. In addition, the challenges and opportunities faced by such catalysts are also discussed.</description>
      <author>Wenjing Xu, Huishan Shang, Jie Guan, Jing Wang, Xiaoyu Jin, Limin Tao, Ziqiang Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202412812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Biochar on Soil Organic Carbon Mineralization in Citrus Orchards</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229967</link>
      <description>Zan&#8208;dong Ding, Rui Huang, Xianliang Li, Qi-Jun Fan, Lening Hu, Shengqiu Liu, Sustainability. 16(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404391793

                The primary ecological challenges in citrus orchards include soil acidification, nutrient depletion, and significant carbon dioxide emissions resulting from conventional cultivation practices. To address these challenges, citrus peel residues and cassava stalks underwent pyrolysis at 500 &#176;C to generate biochars. Different proportions of these biochars (1%, 2%, and 4%) were applied under controlled laboratory conditions to assess their impact on the mineralization of soil organic carbon in citrus orchards. The results indicated that both types of biochar effectively regulated the soil pH to approximately 5.5. Significantly, the addition of 4% cassava stalk biochar significantly increased the levels of available phosphorus and potassium. The phosphorus levels rose by 512.55%, and the potassium levels surged by 1434.01%. Additionally, the soil organic carbon increased to 16.7 g/kg. Conversely, the citrus peel biochar decreased the availability of phosphorus but resulted in the highest increase in available potassium, at 1523.75%, and elevated the soil organic carbon content to 13 g/kg. Both types of biochar enhanced the soil organic carbon mineralization rate to varying extents with increasing application ratios, simultaneously boosting the cumulative amount of organic carbon mineralized. Among the treatments, cassava stalk biochar displayed the lowest C0/SOC ratio, of 0.169, indicating its superior carbon retention capacity. Furthermore, cassava stalk biochar showed inhibitory effects on soil catalase and urease activities within the citrus orchard. Overall, the application of 4% cassava stalk biochar appears to be more beneficial for nutrient regulation and carbon sequestration in citrus orchard soils, while also contributing to the reduction in soil acidification by adjusting pH levels.</description>
      <author>Zan&#8208;dong Ding, Rui Huang, Xianliang Li, Qi-Jun Fan, Lening Hu, Shengqiu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Study on Miscible Phase and Imbibition Displacement of Crude Oil Injected with CO2 in Shale Oil Reservoir</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app142210474</link>
      <description>Haibo He, Xinfang Ma, Li Wang, Yu Zhang, Jianye Mou, Jia&#8208;Rui Wu, Applied Sciences. 14(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404357185

                Jimsar shale oil in China has undergone a rapid decline in formation energy and has a low recovery rate, with poor reservoir permeability. CO2 injection has become the main method for improving oil recovery. Pre-fracturing with CO2 energy storage in Jimsar shale oil has been performed, yielding a noticeable increase in oil recovery. However, the CO2 injection mechanism still requires a deeper understanding. Focusing on Jimsar shale oil in China, this paper studies the effect of CO2 on crude oil viscosity reduction, miscible phase testing, and the law of imbibition displacement. The results show that CO2 has a significant viscosity reduction effect on Jimsar shale oil, with a minimum miscible pressure between CO2 and Jimsar shale oil of 25.51 MPa, which can allow for miscibility under formation conditions. A rise in pressure increased the displacement capacity of supercritical CO2, as well as the displacement volume of crude oil. However, the rate of increase gradually declined. This research provides a theoretical basis for CO2 injection fracturing in Jimsar shale oil, which is helpful for improving the development effects of Jimsar shale oil.</description>
      <author>Haibo He, Xinfang Ma, Li Wang, Yu Zhang, Jianye Mou, Jia&#8208;Rui Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app142210474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the energy and environmental efficiency of the city's infrastructure based on optimizing its fuel and energy balance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24223/1999-5555-2024-17-3-172-180</link>
      <description>Yury V. Yavorovsky, Safety and Reliability of Power Industry. 17(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404420195

                The article considers the direction of increasing the energy and environmental efficiency of the city's energy infrastructure through the modernization of existing thermal power plants (TPP) and combined heat and power (CHP) plants using combined-cycle gas turbine (CCGT) plants. Fuel and energy balances of electric power plants have been constructed, and the energy and environmental effects of the use of CCGT have been assessed. The modeling of energy and environmental indicators for the thermal circuits of the CCGT was conducted using the Thermoflex, GT PRO software (Thermoflow) and the ISC Manager program developed at the National Research University "Moscow Power Engineering Institute (MPEI)". The analysis of CCGT efficiency in urban energy applications is based on modeling and optimizing the city&#8217;s fuel and energy balance (FEB). For this purpose, the OptiTEB program developed at the Department of PTS at the National Research University "M&#1056;EI" is used. Constructing fuel and energy systems in cities and regions is a pressing task that enables the planning of a strategy for the development of the urban fuel and energy complex (FEC), with an assessment of the magnitude of harmful emissions, including greenhouse gases. The article presents the results of work on establishing scientific foundations for modern heat supply systems, exemplified by a mathematical model of the Moscow thermal power plant and its optimization, taking into account the projected development of electric transport infrastructure over the coming decades, improving the thermal protection characteristics of newly constructed buildings, and the potential increase in the use of renewable energy sources (RES). The growth in the share of electric transport should be linked to an increase in the share of renewable energy sources (RES). Simply increasing the number of electric vehicles without a significant rise in renewable energy usage in the city's energy balance will not result in a reduction of carbon dioxide and harmful substance emissions. Expanding electricity generation through CCGT, alongside the growth of renewable energy use in the city, can lead to a significant decrease in carbon dioxide emissions.</description>
      <author>Yury V. Yavorovsky</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24223/1999-5555-2024-17-3-172-180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of exhaust emissions from MGO&#8211;bioethanol fuel blend using a combustion chamber</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/16878132241298338</link>
      <description>J. Kim, Jong Un Park, Tae&#8208;Ho Lee, Il-Seok Kang, Advances in Mechanical Engineering. 16(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404419191

                We conducted combustion tests with marine gas oil (MGO) blended with bioethanol (BE) in ratios of 0%&#8211;30% to address International Maritime Organization air pollution regulations on exhaust gases emitted from ships and fossil fuel resource depletion and achieve carbon neutrality. We designed and manufactured a standard 1-ton combustion chamber, using an attached gun-type burner to analyze the exhaust gases of each sample under similar conditions. Compared to pure MGO (BE0), the oxygen content increased by approximately 1.91% at the maximum blend ratio (BE30), while carbon dioxide decreased by 1.39%. Nitrogen oxides were reduced by approximately 30%. Sulfur oxides were minimal (&lt;0.03%), with MGO alone at approximately 0.08 ppm, confirming the superior quality of low-sulfur fuel. In all blends containing BE, no sulfur oxides were detected. Additionally, exhaust gas temperature decreased by 5.8%, and combustion efficiency decreased from 72.24% to 70.33%, a reduction of approximately 1.9%. This indicated that BE has a relatively lower calorific value; however, it provides a similar thermal output, with some reduction of exhaust emissions. A one-way ANOVA and post-hoc verification confirmed that with increased BE content, emission differences were significant ( p &lt; 0.01 level in all areas). Through this study, it was confirmed that the use of eco-friendly fuels such as bioethanol has excellent effects on reducing exhaust emissions. It is analyzed that it would help solve global warming and air environment pollution problems. Therefore, it is determined that the future application of MGO-bioethanol blended fuel as an eco-friendly alternative fuel for ships holds significant potential, and positive outcomes are anticipated.</description>
      <author>J. Kim, Jong Un Park, Tae&#8208;Ho Lee, Il-Seok Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/16878132241298338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prediction Method for Calculating Fracturing Initiation Pressure Considering the Modification of Rock Mechanical Parameters After CO2 Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112525</link>
      <description>Cuilong Kong, Yuxue Sun, Hao Bian, Jianguang Wei, Li Guo, Ying Yang, Chao Tang, Wei Xu, Ziyuan Cong, Anqi Shen, Processes. 12(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404301911

                The establishment of a more realistic CO2 fracturing model serves to elucidate the intricate mechanisms underlying CO2 fracturing transformation. Additionally, it furnishes a foundational framework for devising comprehensive fracturing construction plans. However, current research has neglected to consider the influence of CO2 on rock properties during CO2 fracturing, resulting in an inability to precisely replicate the alterations in the reservoir post-CO2 injection into the formation. This disparity from the actual conditions poses a substantial limitation to the application and advancement of CO2 fracturing technology. This work integrates variations in the physical parameters of rocks after complete contact and reaction with CO2 into the numerical model of crack propagation. This comprehensive approach fully acknowledges the impact of pre-CO2 exposure on the mechanical parameters of reservoir rocks. Consequently, it authentically restores the reservoir state following CO2 injection, ensuring a more accurate representation of the post-fracturing conditions. In comparison with conventional numerical simulation methods, the approach outlined in this paper yields a reduction in the error associated with predicting fracturing pressure by 9.8%.</description>
      <author>Cuilong Kong, Yuxue Sun, Hao Bian, Jianguang Wei, Li Guo, Ying Yang, Chao Tang, Wei Xu, Ziyuan Cong, Anqi Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planning and Optimisation of Renewable Energy Systems for Decarbonising Operations of Oil Refineries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41660-024-00461-z</link>
      <description>Christoph Lau, Yick Eu Chew, Bing Shen How, Viknesh Andiappan, Process Integration and Optimization for Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404234269

                Abstract Given the urgency to transition to low carbon future, oil refineries need to identify feasible strategies for decarbonisation. One way to address this is by integrating renewable energy systems. However, the high initial costs and intermittency appeared to be the key barriers for the adoption of renewable energy technologies. Hence, a multi-period optimisation model is developed via mixed integer linear programming in this work to determine the optimal renewable energy system in terms of cost and its optimal energy storage technology to enhance its flexibility for oil refinery operations. This model aims to minimise the costs of the renewable energy system while considering its ability to accommodate the varying energy demands across the time periods. An oil refinery case study is used to demonstrate the effectiveness of the developed model. The developed model is expected to propose an optimal renewable energy system that meets the energy demands and, at the same time, achieves the decarbonisation goal. Based on the results, the optimal renewable energy system comprises cost-effective technologies to generate various energy outputs including electricity, hydrogen, high-pressure and medium-pressure steam to meet energy demands. Additionally, the result of the case study shows that the integration of renewable energy systems achieves a reduction of 5,353 tonnes of carbon dioxide. Apart from that, the incorporation of energy-efficient energy storage results in a 10% reduction in the total cost of the optimal renewable energy system. Compressed hydrogen gas storage and battery were used to store excess hydrogen and electricity during periods with low demands and subsequently consumed during peak demand periods. This can, therefore, reduce the technological capacity required. With the aid of storage facilities, the flexibility of the renewable energy system is elevated in meeting varied demands, which otherwise would incur additional expenses.</description>
      <author>Christoph Lau, Yick Eu Chew, Bing Shen How, Viknesh Andiappan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41660-024-00461-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual&#8208;Site NiO/Bi3O4Br Heterojunction Catalyst for High&#8208;Efficiency CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401601</link>
      <description>Wenhan Jiang, Yiling He, Xinxin Zhu, Bo Liu, Yanbo Zhou, Yi Zhou, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404235445

                Solar light&#8208;driven conversion of CO2 into chemicals with high calorific value is regarded as an up&#8208;and&#8208;coming carbon utilization technology for alleviating the energy crisis. This technique faces the challenge of low CO2 conversion and product yield due to charge recombination in the catalyst. In this paper, a dual&#8208;reaction&#8208;site heterojunction catalyst was designed and fabricated by combining NiO with Bi3O4Br nanosheets, for the separation of CO2 reduction and H2O oxidation semireactions, which effectively promoted electrons and holes separation. The resulting catalyst exhibited a high CH4 production rate (8.12 &#956;mol/g) and selectivity (94.69%). Electron distribution and band structure were investigated to explain the satisfactory catalytic performance. In addition, combining the in&#8208;situ DRIFTS results, a formic acid&#8208;intermediated CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 reaction pathway was proposed. This work aims to pave the way for CH4 production via CO2 photoreduction with high efficiency and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Wenhan Jiang, Yiling He, Xinxin Zhu, Bo Liu, Yanbo Zhou, Yi Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Review of Approaches in Carbon Capture, and Utilization to Reduce Greenhouse Gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14416/j.asep.2024.11.004</link>
      <description>Ijlal Raheem, Atthasit Tawai, Suksun Amornraksa, Malinee Sriariyanun, Ankit Joshi, Madhulika A. Gupta, Wasinee Pongprayoon, Debraj Bhattacharyya, Sunil K. Maity, Applied Science and Engineering Progress. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404300453

                Addressing atmospheric CO2 levels is crucial for mitigating global warming and promoting sustainable fossil fuel use. This review explores various CO2 capture strategies, including pre-combustion, post-combustion, oxy-fuel combustion, direct air capture, chemical looping, and polymeric membranes. Each strategy is critically evaluated in terms of its advantages, limitations, and overall effectiveness. Additionally, this study discusses advanced separation techniques for captured CO2, emphasizing recent innovations in membrane technology integrated with cryogenic processes. This integration has the potential to economically extract CO2 from diverse industrial processes, offering significant benefits in terms of operational cost reduction and increased efficiency. A detailed market analysis is also presented to explore feasible CO2 utilization options, highlighting potential incentives and motivations for capturing CO2. Furthermore, the technological readiness level of various capture and separation techniques is assessed, offering insights into their development and progress over time. This comprehensive analysis aims to support the advancement of effective and economically viable CO2 management solutions, contributing to a more sustainable and climate-resilient future.</description>
      <author>Ijlal Raheem, Atthasit Tawai, Suksun Amornraksa, Malinee Sriariyanun, Ankit Joshi, Madhulika A. Gupta, Wasinee Pongprayoon, Debraj Bhattacharyya, Sunil K. Maity</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14416/j.asep.2024.11.004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton Pool for the Mitigation of Salt Precipitate Enhancing CO2 Electroreduction in a Flow Cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110807</link>
      <description>Yuexiu Chen, Bowen Wu, Linping Qian, Catalysts. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404254367

                Flow cells featuring a gas diffusion electrode (GDE) have emerged as an attractive platform for electrochemical CO2 reduction, offering high current densities (~300 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2) and low energy consumption. However, the formation of salt precipitates, particularly carbonate and bicarbonate, poses a significant deficiency by reducing the cell&#8217;s operational longevity. In this study, we present a novel approach to mitigate salt precipitates in real-time through acid&#8211;base interaction. Recovery efficiency and partial current density of the cell were used to evaluate the capability of removing salt precipitates and the maintenance of CO2 reduction reactions (CO2RRs). It was suggested that the direct treatment of intermittent acid rinse recovers the performance of CO2RRs to a large extent (&gt;97%), and the modification of the proton exchange resin reduces the reduction rate of partial current densities to 1/15 than that of the unmodified. This improvement enhances the cell&#8217;s catalytic performance, enabling the stability test for catalysts within the GDE-based flow cell.</description>
      <author>Yuexiu Chen, Bowen Wu, Linping Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficacy and safety of different noninvasive ventilation strategies for postextubation respiratory support in Neonatal Respiratory Distress Syndrome: a systematic review and network meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fped.2024.1435518</link>
      <description>Jiayi Yang, Hua Mei, Sheng Wang, Jie Zhang, Mengyue Huo, Chun Xin, Frontiers in Pediatrics. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404430800

                Objective The study aimed to compare the efficacy and safety of different noninvasive ventilation (NIV) modalities as primary respiratory support following extubation in Neonatal Respiratory Distress Syndrome (NRDS). Methods A search was conducted in PubMed, Embase, Cochrane, Web of Science, China National Knowledge Network (CNKI), Wanfang database, VIP, and Chinese Biomedical Literature databases with a search time limit of April 2024 for the year of construction, and included randomized controlled clinical trials of different modes of noninvasive respiratory support after extubation in NRDS. The primary outcome indicators were the need for re-tracheal intubation within 72 h of extubation on noninvasive ventilatory support and carbon dioxide retention (PCO2) 24 h after extubation. Secondary outcome indicators included the incidence of bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD), nasal injury, pneumothorax, intraventricular hemorrhage (IVH) or periventricular white matter softening (PVL), retinopathy of prematurity (ROP), necrotizing enterocolitis (NEC), and mortality rate. A systematic review and network meta-analysis of the literature was performed by two investigators who screened, extracted, and evaluated the quality of the data. A systematic review and network meta-analysis were then performed using R software. Results A total of 23 studies involving 2,331 neonates were analyzed. These studies examined four noninvasive respiratory modalities: continuous positive airway pressure ventilation (NCPAP), noninvasive intermittent positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV), bi-level positive airway pressure ventilation (N-BiPAP), and noninvasive high-frequency oscillatory ventilation (NHFOV). Results indicated that NHFOV, NIPPV, and N-BiPAP were significantly more effective than NCPAP in reducing the risk of reintubation (all P &amp;lt; 0.05), with NHFOV being the most effective. For carbon dioxide clearance, NHFOV outperformed both NIPPV and NCPAP ( P &amp;lt; 0.05). Regarding the reduction of bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD) incidence, NHFOV and NIPPV showed a significant advantage over NCPAP. Conclusions This network meta-analysis (NMA) suggested that NHFOV is the most effective mode of noninvasive respiratory support post-extubation, while NCPAP is the least effective. However, these findings should be interpreted with caution due to the limited number and quality of the studies included. Systematic Review Registration https://www.crd.york.ac.uk/PROSPERO/#recordDetails , identifier (CRD42024544886).</description>
      <author>Jiayi Yang, Hua Mei, Sheng Wang, Jie Zhang, Mengyue Huo, Chun Xin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fped.2024.1435518</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postharvest CO2 treatment and cold storage for &lt;i&gt;Drosophila suzukii&lt;/i&gt; (Diptera: Drosophilidae) fruit infestation control</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jee/toae264</link>
      <description>Nika Cvelbar Weber, &#352;. Modic, Primo&#382; &#381;igon, Jaka Razinger, Journal of Economic Entomology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404411812

                Abstract The invasive pest, spotted wing drosophila (Drosophila suzukii (Matsumura, 1931) or SWD), damages various soft-skinned fruits, severely impacting orchards and vineyards economically. Current sorting practices in commercial production may overlook early-stage SWD infestations, as visible signs take a few days to appear. Our study focused on managing SWD infesting fruits (blueberry, cherry, and raspberry) without visible signs using an artificial atmosphere with elevated CO2 and low temperature. We hypothesized that these factors affect SWD survival and possibly interact, with potential variations among different soft- or stone-fruit species or varieties. High CO2 concentrations and cold storage both negatively affected SWD development. A 24-h 100% CO2 fumigation, without cold storage, significantly reduced SWD infestations in all 3 fruit species studied. On the other hand, 10% CO2 without cold storage did not cause a significant infestation reduction in cherries. Cold storage alone was too slow to be considered effective. Concurrent low-temperature treatment and CO2 treatment reduced the insecticidal efficacy of CO2 fumigation. Optimal fruit sanitation was achieved with a 3-h 100% CO2 treatment at ambient temperature before cold storage. Raspberries were the most suitable host for SWD development, with over a 5-fold higher SWD development compared to blueberries and over 50 times more than in cherries. We discussed the observed interactions between CO2 fumigation and chilling and suggested a simple postharvest SWD management protocol using optimal CO2 levels, exposure times, and chilling periods&#8212;achievable without complex equipment.</description>
      <author>Nika Cvelbar Weber, &#352;. Modic, Primo&#382; &#381;igon, Jaka Razinger</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jee/toae264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected decline of the ocean carbon sink under record-high sea surface temperatures in 2023</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5198321/v1</link>
      <description>Jens Daniel M&#252;ller, Nicolas Gruber, Aline Schneuwly, Doroth&#233;e C. E. Bakker, Marion Gehlen, Luke Gregor, Judith Hauck, Peter Landsch&#252;tzer, Galen A. McKinley, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404298561

                Abstract In 2023, sea-surface temperatures (SST) reached record highs. Based on historical responses, this SST anomaly would suggest an increased oceanic CO2 uptake (-0.11&#177;0.03 PgC yr-1). In contrast, our observation-based estimates reveal that the global non-polar ocean absorbed about 10% less carbon than expected (+0.16&#177;0.28 PgC yr-1). This weakening occurred despite reduced CO2 outgassing in the tropics associated with El Ni&#241;o. Hence, the decline in CO2 uptake in 2023 materialised entirely in the extratropics, driven primarily by elevated SSTs in the Northern Hemisphere. Two ocean biogeochemical models demonstrate that in the subtropical North Atlantic the thermally-induced reduction in CO2 uptake was strongly mitigated by the depletion of dissolved inorganic carbon in the surface mixed layer. Such negative feedbacks cause an overall muted response of the ocean carbon sink to the record high SSTs, but this resilience may not persist under long-term warming or more severe SST extremes.</description>
      <author>Jens Daniel M&#252;ller, Nicolas Gruber, Aline Schneuwly, Doroth&#233;e C. E. Bakker, Marion Gehlen, Luke Gregor, Judith Hauck, Peter Landsch&#252;tzer, Galen A. McKinley</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5198321/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INFLUENCE OF PHASE COMPOSITION AND HEAT TREATMENT CONDITIONS OF IRON-OXIDE CATALYST ON ITS CHEMICAL PROPERTIES IN THE PROCESS OF METHYLBUTENE DEHYDROGENATION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55421/1998-7072_2024_27_4_41</link>
      <description>M.A. BOCHKOV, &#1053;. &#1042;. &#1059;&#1083;&#1080;&#1090;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1050;. &#1040;. &#1058;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, A.P. ANDREEV, D. A. Shiyan, M.G. KAZANSKAYA, T.L. PUCHKOVA, S.N. TUNTSEVA, Olga Bochkova, &#1061;. &#1069;. &#1061;&#1072;&#1088;&#1083;&#1072;&#1084;&#1087;&#1080;&#1076;&#1080;, Herald Of Technological University. 27(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404291564

                The present work is devoted to assessing the effect of heat treatment of iron oxide catalysts promoted by potassium and cerium on their activity, which is expressed quantitatively in the form of methylbutenes conversion, and selectivity in the process of methylbutenes dehydrogenation to isoprene, and interpreting the results obtained using kinetic modeling. Iron oxide catalysts were prepared by heat treatment of iron (II) hydroxide Fe(OH)2. The concentrations of the components of the reaction mixture, the conversion of methylbutenes and selectivity were experimentally determined during methylbutenes dehydrogenation in the presence of heat-treated iron oxide catalysts. It has been shown that an increase of &#945;-Fe2O3 hematite phase in the iron oxide catalyst helps to reduce the concentration of carbon dioxide and cracking products in the products of the methylbutenes dehydrogenation, which contributes to increased selectivity. The increase of &#945;-Fe2O3 hematite phase is observed with increasing heat treatment temperature from 298 K to 873 K. In all iron oxide catalysts promoted by potassium and cerium, after the methylbutenes dehydrogenation, the main phase is magnetite Fe3O4 (62.17% by wt.) and a more reduced form of iron oxide wustite FeO (13.81% by wt.) was identified. It can be assumed that the reduction of iron oxides in the iron oxide catalyst during the methylbutenes dehydrogenation is associated with the activity of the catalyst. The higher the activity of the iron oxide catalyst, the higher the concentration of hydrogen in the reaction mixture, which leads to a deeper reduction of iron oxide. As a result of kinetic modeling, it was demonstrated that the kinetic scheme, consisting of the reactions of methylbutene isomers dehydrogenation, isomerization of methylbutenes, cracking of methylbutene isomers and isoprene, interaction of coke with water, is complete enough to adequately describe the experimental data of the methylbutenes dehydrogenation.</description>
      <author>M.A. BOCHKOV, &#1053;. &#1042;. &#1059;&#1083;&#1080;&#1090;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1050;. &#1040;. &#1058;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, A.P. ANDREEV, D. A. Shiyan, M.G. KAZANSKAYA, T.L. PUCHKOVA, S.N. TUNTSEVA, Olga Bochkova, &#1061;. &#1069;. &#1061;&#1072;&#1088;&#1083;&#1072;&#1084;&#1087;&#1080;&#1076;&#1080;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55421/1998-7072_2024_27_4_41</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fuel Consumption Reductions in Heavy-Duty Vehicles With Crank Pulley Decoupler Mounted Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/detc2024-145589</link>
      <description>Saulius Pak&#353;tys, Shailesh Hegde, Angelo Bonfitto, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404316352

                Abstract An increasing amount of effort has been directed to ensure the minimization of carbon dioxide emissions within the transport industry, particularly in the light passenger vehicle segments. This has been achieved through many advancements such as mass and aerodynamic drag reduction as well as the electrification of powertrains. The heavy-duty vehicle segment contributes significantly to the total emissions of the transport sector, however fuel consumption through electrification poses some limitations. Fuel efficiency has been achieved by adopting higher fuel injection pressures generating an increase of the crankshaft nose oscillation making Front-End Accessory Drive (FEAD) design more challenging. This paper provides a solution, with the incorporation of a crank pulley decoupler that isolates the irregularities from the FEAD that arise at the crank of the internal combustion engine. The analysis of a 12.7 L engine tested with a steel pulley and with the decoupler is presented. The brake-specific fuel consumption map is obtained for the engine mounted with the steel pulley and with the decoupler through a dynamometer test. The engine maps are incorporated into a tractor trailer with a 4 &#215; 2 configuration in the Vehicle Energy consumption Tool (VECTO), evaluated over three driving cycles: long-haul delivery, regional delivery, and urban delivery. The outcome indicates a maximum relative fuel saving of 0.63% for a vehicle mounted with a decoupler compared to one mounted with a solid steel pulley.</description>
      <author>Saulius Pak&#353;tys, Shailesh Hegde, Angelo Bonfitto</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/detc2024-145589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Tandem Strategies for CO2 Electroreduction: from Electrocatalysts to Reaction System Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401604</link>
      <description>Peng&#8208;Fei Sui, Yicheng Wang, Xiaolei Wang, Subiao Liu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404319693

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) offers the opportunity to store renewable energy in the form of chemicals and fuels while simultaneously reducing CO2 emissions. Compared to low&#8208;carbon products such as carbon monoxide and formic acid, multicarbon products have demonstrated greater value in terms of economic feasibility. To date, various strategies have been developed to enhance electrocatalytic performance, with tandem strategies emerging as a promising approach, particularly for the formation of multicarbon products. In this review, current tandem strategies regarding CO2RR are thoroughly discussed, covering electrocatalyst designs from atomic&#8208;scale tandem electrocatalysts to macroscale electrode configurations as well as reaction system designs. Additionally, the internal reaction processes involving reduction product upgrades, the application of multi&#8208;physical tandem fields, and the tandem reaction systems are further summarized. This review aims to provide more fundamental insights into tandem strategies for CO2RR applications and inspire more creative ideas in the research community of CO2RR in light of this promising approach with its wide versatility, diversity and flexibility.</description>
      <author>Peng&#8208;Fei Sui, Yicheng Wang, Xiaolei Wang, Subiao Liu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401604</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Coconut Shell-Based Active Carbon Adsorbent on Motorcycle Exhaust Gas Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.70822/evrmata.v1i03.57</link>
      <description>Nahindi Putra Gitama, Nurul Hidayat, Dwi Pebrianti, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404367092

                This study focused on the utilization of active carbon derived from coconut shells as an adsorbent to reduce exhaust gas emissions in motorcycles. The research aimed to compare the exhaust emissions before and after installing active carbon in the muffler and to analyze its effect on the levels of CO, HC, and CO2 at different engine speeds. A laboratory experiment was conducted with varying masses of active carbon, and emission data were collected and analyzed using two-way ANOVA. The results demonstrated that with the use of 200 grams of active carbon, the CO emission decreased by 12.06%, HC by 16.96%, and CO2 by 9.17%. These reductions are attributed to the strong adsorptive properties of active carbon, which facilitated the physical and chemical separation of harmful gases. The study concluded that active carbon significantly reduces exhaust emissions, providing a practical solution for improving air quality in motorcycles. The findings offer an effective method for emission control that could be applied under various operating conditions, making it suitable for widespread implementation in emission-reduction systems for small engines.</description>
      <author>Nahindi Putra Gitama, Nurul Hidayat, Dwi Pebrianti</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.70822/evrmata.v1i03.57</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of building carbon emission based on grey Markov theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2753-8818/48/20240222</link>
      <description>Chenhao Zhao, Theoretical and Natural Science. 48(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404366504

                The increase in carbon emissions in the construction industry is one of the factors that lead to environmental problems and hinder the sustainable development of society and the construction industry. Therefore, there is an urgent need to rationally control carbon emissions by formulating scientific and effective energy-saving and emission reduction policies so as to safeguard the development of the industry. However, because of the uncertainty and complexity of CO2 emissions, more reliable prediction and assessment tools are needed to comprehensively analyze and predict CO2 emissions. This study combines the gray system theory and Markov principle to give full play to the advantages of the two methods, using Markov theory to determine the state transition probability, find out the characteristics of carbon emissions in the construction industry, and form a suitable gray Markov prediction model. The feasibility of the prediction model is demonstrated by calculating and examining the prediction model using data related to carbon emissions from the U.S. buildings from 2002 to 2022, which greatly improves the accuracy of CO2 emissions prediction.</description>
      <author>Chenhao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2753-8818/48/20240222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Carbon Neutrality: The Impact of Private AI Investment and Financial Development in the United States &#8211; An Empirical Study Using the STIRPAT Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56556/jescae.v3i4.982</link>
      <description>Shaharina Shoha, Sarder Abdulla Al Shiam, Shake Ibna Abir, Dipankar Saha, Shewly Bala, Md Shah Ali Dolon, Hasibur Rahman, Md. Eleais, Afsana Akhter, Mohammad Ridwan, Robeena Bibi, Journal of Environmental Science and Economics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404437050

                This investigation analyses the influence of private AI investment and financial development (FD) on CO2 emissions in the United States, using the STIRPAT framework to account for the functions of GDP, population, and foreign direct investment (FDI). The data's robustness was verified through the application of a variety of unit root tests, which confirmed that the variables are free of unit root issues and exhibit a varied order of integration. The ARDL bound test was used to investigate the cointegration among the variables and it found a long-run equilibrium relationship. The ARDL model results show that income, FDI, FD, and population significantly increase CO2 emissions in both the short and long term. In contrast, we found that private investment in AI led to a significant reduction in CO2 emissions over these time frames. Additional estimations were conducted using FMOLS, DOLS, and CCR methods to verify the ARDL results, all of which attested to the initial findings' robustness. In addition, the study implemented a pairwise Granger causality test to illustrate the directional relationships between the variables. There is a unidirectional causal link between GDP, private AI investment, FDI, population, and CO2 emissions, according to the findings. Most notably, we observed bidirectional causality between CO2 emissions and FD. Diagnostic tests further corroborated the validity of the study's conclusions, confirming that the model is free from specification errors, serial correlation, and heteroscedasticity.</description>
      <author>Shaharina Shoha, Sarder Abdulla Al Shiam, Shake Ibna Abir, Dipankar Saha, Shewly Bala, Md Shah Ali Dolon, Hasibur Rahman, Md. Eleais, Afsana Akhter, Mohammad Ridwan, Robeena Bibi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56556/jescae.v3i4.982</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Sustainable Production Planning of an Industrial Progressive Die Stamping Process Using Discrete Event Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/detc2024-143648</link>
      <description>Adri&#225;n Borbolla, Mohamed Nezar Aboujarra, Devarajan Ramanujan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404332967

                Abstract This paper investigates the use of discrete event simulation (DES) as a potential decision-support tool for environmentally sustainable production planning. We propose a comprehensive methodology that integrates DES design, dynamic CO2 intensity calculations, and in-depth scenario analysis. This approach facilitates simulation-driven production planning with an emphasis on evaluating and reducing the environmental impacts of manufacturing. Our methodology is applied to the evaluation of an industrial progressive die stamping process (PDSP). The PDSP is a part of a production line in a large Danish manufacturing company. The performance of the PDSP was simulated and evaluated for two working days: 09 Jan 2024 and 10 Jan 2024. Key performance indicators like utilization rate and lead time are assessed alongside environmental sustainability metrics such as process CO2 emissions and CO2 emissions per product. Building upon this baseline, we then simulate and compare two alternative production scenarios: i) increased production capacity and ii) variations in planning orders. These scenarios are then contrasted with the baseline model. Our results demonstrate the potential of DES in identifying new production strategies. The first scenario demonstrates a 7% increase in production capacity, corresponding to a 2.6% increase in process CO2 emissions. The second scenario demonstrates a 5% reduction in process CO2 emissions while retaining the same production capacity as the baseline model. These findings illustrate how DES can uncover production plans that prioritize sustainable manufacturing.</description>
      <author>Adri&#225;n Borbolla, Mohamed Nezar Aboujarra, Devarajan Ramanujan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/detc2024-143648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acidification and nutrient management are projected to cause reductions in shell and tissue weights of oysters in a coastal plain estuary</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3359</link>
      <description>Catherine Czajka, Marjorie A. M. Friedrichs, Emily B. Rivest, Pierre St&#8208;Laurent, Mark J. Brush, Fei Da, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404321596

                Abstract. Coastal acidification, warming, and nutrient management actions all alter water quality conditions that marine species experience, with potential impacts to their physiological processes. Decreases in calcite saturation state (&#937;Ca) and food availability, combined with warming water temperatures, pose a threat to calcifying organisms; however, the magnitude of future changes in estuarine systems is challenging to predict and is not well known. This study aims to determine how and where oysters will be affected by future acidification, warming, and nutrient reductions, and the relative effects of these stressors. To address these goals, an oyster bioenergetics model for Eastern oysters (Crassostrea virginica) was embedded in a 3-D coupled hydrodynamic-biogeochemistry model implemented for two tributaries in the lower Chesapeake Bay. Model simulations were forced with projected future conditions (mid-21st century atmospheric CO2, atmospheric temperature, and managed nutrient reductions) and compared with a realistic present-day reference run. Together, all three stressors are projected to reduce &#937;Ca and growth of oyster shell and tissue. Increased atmospheric CO2 and temperature are both projected to cause widespread reductions in &#937;Ca. The resulting reductions in oyster shell and tissue growth will be most severe along the tributary shoals. Future warming during peak oyster growing seasons is projected to have the strongest negative influence on tissue and shell growth, due to summer water temperatures reducing filtration rates, enhancing shell dissolution and oyster respiration rates, and increasing organic matter remineralization rates, thus reducing food availability. Nutrient reductions will exacerbate deficits in oyster food availability, contributing to further reductions in growth. Quantifying the effects of these stressors provides insight on the areas in the lower bay where oysters will be most vulnerable to mid 21st-century conditions.</description>
      <author>Catherine Czajka, Marjorie A. M. Friedrichs, Emily B. Rivest, Pierre St&#8208;Laurent, Mark J. Brush, Fei Da</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Estimation of CO2 Absorption Capacity Using Ionic Conductivity of Protonated Di-Methyl-Ethanolamine (DMEA) and Electrical Conductivity in Low-Concentration DMEA Aqueous Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112495</link>
      <description>Sang&#8208;Jun Han, Jin Han, Jung&#8208;Ho Wee, Processes. 12(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404243901

                The present study investigates the real-time estimation of CO2 absorption capacity (CAC) based on the electrical conductivity (EC) of low-concentration di-methyl-ethanolamine (DMEA) solutions (0.1&#8211;0.5 M). CO2 absorption experiments are conducted to measure the variation in CAC and EC during CO2 absorption, revealing a strong correlation between the two properties. The ionic conductivity of DMEAH+ formed during absorption is calculated to be 53.1 S&#183;cm2/(mol&#183;z), which is found to be larger than that of TEAH+ and MDEAH+. This can be attributed to the smaller molar mass and higher ionic mobility of DMEAH+. A significant finding is that the measured EC (ECM) of the DMEA solutions consistently demonstrates a lower value than the theoretically predicted value. This discrepancy is due to the larger ionic size of DMEAH+, which results in a reduction in the real mean ionic activity coefficient. This effect becomes more pronounced with increasing DMEA concentration. Consequently, a higher CAC is required to produce the same change in EC at higher amine concentrations. Based on these findings, an empirical equation is devised to estimate CAC from ECM in solutions of constant DMEA concentration. This equation will be employed as a practical approach for the in situ monitoring of CO2 absorption using DMEA aqueous solution.</description>
      <author>Sang&#8208;Jun Han, Jin Han, Jung&#8208;Ho Wee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Lanthanides on the Structure and Oxygen Permeability of
  Ti-doped Dual-phase Membranes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.02693</link>
      <description>Chao Zhang, Z. Xiang, Lingyong Zeng, Peifeng Yu, Kuan Li, Kangwang Wang, Longfu Li, Rui Chen, Huixia Luo, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404403988

                The trade-off effect of the oxygen permeability and stability of oxygen transport membranes (OTMs) still exists in working atmospheres containing CO2. Herein, we reported a new series of 60 wt%Ce0.9Ln0.1O2-{\delta}-40wt%Ln0.6Sr0.4Fe0.9Ti0.1O3-{\delta} (CLnO-LnSFTO, Ln = La, Pr, Nd, Sm, Gd, Tb) dual-phase OTMs by selecting different Ln elements based on the reported highly stable Ti-doped CPrO-PrSFTO. The effects of different Ln elements on the structure and oxygen permeability of Ti-doped dual-phase OTMs were systematically studied. Basically, as the atomic number of Ln elements increases, the unit cell parameters of both the fluorite phase and the perovskite phase become smaller. The unit cell volume and spatial symmetry of the perovskite phase are reduced, resulting in a reduction in oxygen permeability. The optimal CLaO-LaSFTO showed JO2 of 0.60 and 0.54 mL min-1 cm-2 with He and CO2 sweeping at 1000 oC, respectively. In addition, all CLnO-LnSFTO OTMs could work for more than 100 hours with no significant performance degradation in a CO2 atmosphere, maintaining excellent stability. This work explores candidate OTM materials for CO2 capture and oxygen separation, as well as provides some ideas for addressing the trade-off effect.</description>
      <author>Chao Zhang, Z. Xiang, Lingyong Zeng, Peifeng Yu, Kuan Li, Kangwang Wang, Longfu Li, Rui Chen, Huixia Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.02693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exercise limitations in amyloid cardiomyopathy assessed by cardiopulmonary exercise testing&#8212;A multicentre study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ehf2.15147</link>
      <description>Robin Willixhofer, Mauro Contini, Michele Emdin, Damiano Magr&#236;, Alice Bonomi, Elisabetta Salvioni, Fabrizio Celeste, Alberico Del Torto, Claudio Passino, C Capelle, Chiara Arzilli, Emiliano Fiori, Nicol&#242; Capra, Christina Kronberger, &#1053;. &#1056;. &#1045;&#1088;&#1084;&#1086;&#1083;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, Andreas A. Kammerlander, Beatrice Musumeci, Giuseppe Vergaro, Vincenzo Castiglione, Ren&#233; Rettl, Giacomo Tini, Andrea Baggiano, Iacopo Fabiani, Susanna Sciomer, Roza Badr Eslam, Piergiuseppe Agostoni, ESC Heart Failure. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404425956

                Abstract Aims Amyloid cardiomyopathy is caused by the deposition of light chain (AL) or transthyretin amyloid (ATTR) fibrils, that leads to a restrictive cardiomyopathy, often resulting in heart failure (HF) with preserved or reduced ejection fraction. This study aimed to determine whether cardiac output reduction or ventilation inefficiency plays a predominant role in limiting exercise in patients with amyloid cardiomyopathy. Methods We conducted a multicentre prospective study in patients with AL or ATTR cardiomyopathy who underwent cardiopulmonary exercise testing across four centres. Patients were compared with a propensity&#8208;score matched HF cohort based on age, gender, left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF), and peak oxygen consumption (VO 2 ). Results Data from 267 amyloid patients aged 77 (72, 81) years, 86% male, with a median N&#8208;terminal pro B&#8208;type natriuretic peptide (NT&#8208;proBNP) of 2187 (1140, 4383) ng/L, exercise parameters of peak VO 2 of 14.1 (11.6;16.9) mL/min/kg, a minute ventilation to carbon dioxide production (VE/VCO 2 ) slope of 37.4 (32.5, 42.6) and a LVEF of 50% (44%, 59%) were analysed. We identified 251 amyloid cardiomyopathy&#8211;HF matches. Amyloid patients had a signifnicantly higher VE/VCO 2 slope [37.4, inter quartile range (IQR): 32.7, 43.1 vs. 32.1, IQR: 28.7, 37.0, P &lt; 0.0001], NT&#8208;proBNP (2249, IQR: 1187, 4420 vs. 718, IQR: 405, 2161 ng/L, P &lt; 0.001), peak heart rate (121 &#177; 28 vs. 115 &#177; 27 beats/min, P = 0.007) and peak ventilation (51, IQR: 42, 62 vs. 43, IQR: 33, 53 L/min, P &lt; 0.0001) with earlier anaerobic threshold (VO 2 at AT: 8.9, IQR: 6.8, 10.8 vs. 10.8, IQR: 8.9, 12.7 mL/min/kg, P &lt; 0.0001) compared with HF. Between amyloid patients, AL patients ( n = 27) were younger (63, IQR: 58, 70 vs. 78, IQR: 72, 81 years, P &lt; 0.0001), had lower VE/VCO 2 slope (35.0, IQR: 30.0, 38.7 vs. 38.0, IQR: 32.8, 43.1, P = 0.019), higher end&#8208;tidal carbon dioxide partial pressure both at AT (35.1 &#177; 4.8 vs. 31.4 &#177; 4.7 mmHg, P &lt; 0.001) and peak exercise (32, IQR: 28, 35 vs. 30, IQR: 26, 33 mmHg, P = 0.039) as compared with ATTR ( n = 233). Conclusions A higher VE/VCO 2 slope and an earlier AT, determining functional capacity impairment, was assessed in patients with amyloid cardiomyopathy compared with the matched HF cohort. Additionally, patients with ATTR might display more severe exercise limitations as compared with AL.</description>
      <author>Robin Willixhofer, Mauro Contini, Michele Emdin, Damiano Magr&#236;, Alice Bonomi, Elisabetta Salvioni, Fabrizio Celeste, Alberico Del Torto, Claudio Passino, C Capelle, Chiara Arzilli, Emiliano Fiori, Nicol&#242; Capra, Christina Kronberger, &#1053;. &#1056;. &#1045;&#1088;&#1084;&#1086;&#1083;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, Andreas A. Kammerlander, Beatrice Musumeci, Giuseppe Vergaro, Vincenzo Castiglione, Ren&#233; Rettl, Giacomo Tini, Andrea Baggiano, Iacopo Fabiani, Susanna Sciomer, Roza Badr Eslam, Piergiuseppe Agostoni</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ehf2.15147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning structures and catalysis performance of two-dimensional covalent organic frameworks based on copper phthalocyanine building block and phenyl connector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-79563-0</link>
      <description>Yuexing Zhang, Junhao Peng, Guangsong Zhang, Xing&#8208;Guo Zhang, Limin Zhang, Qing Li, Guanfeng Tian, Xiaoli Wang, Ping Wu, Xueli Chen, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404432837

                Based on the experimentally reported stable and conductive two-dimensional covalent organic frameworks with copper phthalocyanine (CuPc) as building block and cyan substituted phenyl as connector (CuCOF-CN) as an electrocatalyst for CO2 reduction reaction (RR), first principle calculations were performed on CuCOF-CN and its analog with the CN being replaced by H (CuCOF). Comparatively studied on the crystal structures, electronic properties, and CO2RR performance of the two catalysts found that CuCOF has reduced crystal unit size, more positive charge on Cu and CuPc segments, smaller band gap, and lower reaction barrier for CO2 RR than CuCOF-CN. CuCOF is proposed to be good potential electrocatalyst with good environment friendliness. The substituent effect and structure-property-performance relationship would help for designing and fabricating new electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuexing Zhang, Junhao Peng, Guangsong Zhang, Xing&#8208;Guo Zhang, Limin Zhang, Qing Li, Guanfeng Tian, Xiaoli Wang, Ping Wu, Xueli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-79563-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of cannabis and tobacco smoking on male fertility and their relationship with sperm mitochondrial genetic variants in the Cytochrome C Oxidase genes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5328744/v1</link>
      <description>Houda Amor, Peter Michael Jankowski, Mohammad A. Al Smadi, Mazhar Salim Al Zoubi, Ingolf Juhasz&#8208;B&#246;ss, Mohamad Eid Hammadeh, Ayham Ismaeil, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404254321

                Abstract Although tobacco smoking declined among men at reproductive age, the use of cannabis increased. The aim of our study was to determine the impact of tobacco and cannabis on sperm quality, sperm DNA integrity tested by Chromomycin A3 (CMA3) and acridine orange (AO) and their association to genetic variants in the Cytochrome C Oxidase 1, 2 and 3 genes (MT-CO1, MT-CO2, and MT-CO3). Semen samples were collected and divided into 37 non-smokers (NS), 39 tobacco smokers (TS), and 37 cannabis smokers (CS). MT-CO1, MT-CO2 and MT-CO3 genes were amplified by PCR and sequenced by Sanger. The results showed reductions in normal sperm morphology and non-progressive motility in TS and CS compared to NS (p &lt; 0.001). However, immotile sperm, AO+, and CMA3 + scores were higher in the CS compared to TS and NS (p &lt; 0.001). Twenty-three nucleotide substitutions (SNPs) detected in the MT-CO1 gene, 15 SNPs detected in the MT-CO2 gene, and 30 SNPs detected in the MT-CO3 gene. None of these SNPs was different between the three groups. Tobacco and cannabis smoking altered the motility and morphology of the spermatozoa and sperm DNA integrity but was not associated with genetic variants in the MT-CO1, MT-CO2 and MT-CO3 genes.</description>
      <author>Houda Amor, Peter Michael Jankowski, Mohammad A. Al Smadi, Mazhar Salim Al Zoubi, Ingolf Juhasz&#8208;B&#246;ss, Mohamad Eid Hammadeh, Ayham Ismaeil</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5328744/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon mineralization potential and nutrient dynamics in soils under vegetation types and soil depths at Luot mountain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55250/jo.vnuf.9.2.2024.032-042</link>
      <description>Nguy&#7877;n Th&#7883; Thu Ph&#432;&#417;ng, Nguy&#7877;n Th&#7883; H&#242;a, Tr&#7847;n Th&#7883; Th&#250;y H&#7857;ng, Hung M. Bui, Pervez Khan, Journal of Forestry Science and Technology. 9(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404235196

                Soil mineralization is a crucial soil process that improves soil physical properties, enhances carbon sequestration, and provides essential minerals and available nutrients for plant growth. This study was conducted at five vegetation types and soil depths at Luot mountain area, located in VNUF campus, Hanoi city. Samples were incubated in the dark at 25&#176;C and measured at intervals of 1, 2, 5, 10, 15, 25, 35, and 40 days in the laboratory to determine C-CO2 respiration from soils. The study showed that CO2 emissions were highest in topsoils and decreased with deeper soil depths. Mineralized C-CO2 decreased from Shrubs &gt; Acacia + Native species (NS) &gt; Pinus + NS &gt; Native species &gt; Control. CO2 emissions peaked early in the incubation period and then stabilized in the 40-day incubation period. Larger aggregates (&#8805; 5mm) decreased significantly under most vegetation types, except for Shrubs, where the reduction was minimal. Aggregate size &#8805;3mm increased post-incubation, notably under Pinus + NS and Native species, with smaller aggregates also increasing slightly. Organic matter content was highest in the topsoil but decreased post-incubation due to microbial C mineralization. There was an increase in soil organic matter at 10-20 cm and 20-40 cm layers after incubation, especially under Shrubs. Available nitrogen slightly increased in soils post-incubation for most vegetation types. Phosphorus content increased post-incubation, peaking under Shrubs, while potassium levels were generally poor but increased during incubation. The study found that C-CO2 mineralization was strongly associated with soil porosity and pH, suggesting that higher porosity and optimal pH enhance mineralization, with organic matter content being crucial for available nutrient cycles in soils.</description>
      <author>Nguy&#7877;n Th&#7883; Thu Ph&#432;&#417;ng, Nguy&#7877;n Th&#7883; H&#242;a, Tr&#7847;n Th&#7883; Th&#250;y H&#7857;ng, Hung M. Bui, Pervez Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55250/jo.vnuf.9.2.2024.032-042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We must re-evaluate assumptions about carbon trading for effective
  climate change mitigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.08053</link>
      <description>Alyssa R. Pfadt-Trilling, Marie&#8208;Odile P. Fortier, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404406714

                Effective climate action depends on dismantling the assumptions and oversimplifications that have become the basis of climate policy. The assumption that greenhouse gases (GHG) are fungible and the use of single-point values in normalizing GHG species to CO2-equivalents can propagate inaccuracies in carbon accounting and have already led to failures of carbon offset systems. Separate emission reduction targets and tracking by GHG species are recommended to achieve long-term climate stabilization.</description>
      <author>Alyssa R. Pfadt-Trilling, Marie&#8208;Odile P. Fortier</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.08053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the Microenvironment of Zn&#8208;Based Metal&#8208;Organic Framework for Enhanced CO2 Electroreduction to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401529</link>
      <description>Tingting Zhan, Jiali Huang, Ying Yang, Yunbin Li, Xiuling Ma, Shengchang Xiang, Zhangjing Zhang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404292884

                Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction (ECR) has emerged as one of the most promising strategies to alleviate the energy crisis and CO2 pollution, for which a wide variety of catalysts are under development. Metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) with clear and designable structures are an excellent platform for ECR. Here, two isostructural N, O&#8208;coordinated Zn&#8208;MOFs, FJU&#8208;126&#8208;4F and FJU&#8208;126&#8208;CH3, based on terephthalic acid ligand with different groups (one is &#8208;4F, the other is &#8208;CH3) on the benzene ring, have been constructed for ECR catalysts. Significantly, the different functional groups make the performance difference of ECR. The maximum Faraday efficiency of formate (FEformate) for FJU&#8208;126&#8208;4F is 60.5% with the partial current density of formate (jformate) of &#8208;19.35 mA cm&#8208;2 at &#8208;1.47 V, while the optimum FEformate of FJU&#8208;126&#8208;CH3 is 50.2% with the jformate of &#8208;10.04 mA cm&#8208;2 at &#8208;1.57 V. The work provides insight into the rational design of MOF catalysts for ECR.</description>
      <author>Tingting Zhan, Jiali Huang, Ying Yang, Yunbin Li, Xiuling Ma, Shengchang Xiang, Zhangjing Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide capture in large-scale CCGT power plant from flue gases obtained from various fuel mixtures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24425/ather.2024.151999</link>
      <description>Navaneethan Subramanian, Pawe&#322; Madejski, Archives of Thermodynamics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404276961

                In this study, the thermodynamic analysis of a combined cycle gas turbine integrated with post-combustion carbon capture and storage using the solvent method is performed. The syngas obtained from the gasification of sewage sludge is mixed with methane and nitrogen-rich natural gas fuels at different proportions, used in the gas turbine, and the properties of fuel and flue gases are analyzed. The flue gas obtained from the fuel mixture is passed through the post-combustion carbon capture and storage at various load conditions to assess the heat and electricity required for the carbon capture process. The solvent used for the carbon capture from flue gases enables CO2 capture with the high efficiency of 90%. With the calculated results, the load conditions of flue gas using fuel mixtures are identified, which reduces the heat and power demand of post-combustion carbon capture and storage and provides the possibility to achieve neutral emission. The impact of selected operating conditions of post-combustion carbon capture and storage on the CO2 emission reduction process and on the power plant performances is investigated. Considering the factors of electricity generation, energy efficiency, heat supply to the consumers, operating load of post-combustion carbon cap-ture and storage and CO2 emission, the 50% mixture of syngas with both fuels performs better. Also, the use of a mixture of 2-amino-2methyl-1-propanol and piperazine with reboiler duty 3.7 MJ/kgCO2 in post-combustion carbon capture and storage slightly enhanced the performance of the power plant compared to the use of monoethanolamine with reboiler duty 3.8 MJ/kgCO2.</description>
      <author>Navaneethan Subramanian, Pawe&#322; Madejski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24425/ather.2024.151999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold Plasma Techniques for Sustainable Material Synthesis and Climate Change Mitigation: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110802</link>
      <description>Nitesh Joshi, L. Sivachandiran, Catalysts. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404283665

                In recent years, the emission of greenhouse gases (GHGs) has increased significantly, contributing to global warming. Among these GHGs, CH4, CO2, and CO are particularly potent contributors. Remediation techniques primarily rely on materials capable of capturing, storing, and converting these gases. Catalytic processes, particularly heterogeneous catalysis, are essential to chemical and petrochemical industries as well as environmental remediation. Due to the growing demand for catalysts, efforts are being made to reduce energy consumption and make technologies more environmentally friendly. Green chemistry emphasizes minimizing the use of hazardous reactants and harmful solvents in chemical processes. Achieving these principles should be paired with processes that reduce time and costs in catalyst preparation while improving their efficiency. Non-thermal plasma (NTP) has been widely used for the preparation of supported metal catalysts. NTP has attracted significant attention for its ability to improve the physicochemical properties of catalysts, enhancing process efficiency through low-temperature operation and shorter processing times. NTP has been applied to various catalyst synthesis techniques, including reduction, oxidation, metal oxide doping, surface etching, coating, alloy formation, surface treatment, and surface cleaning. Plasma-prepared transition-metal catalysts offer advantages over conventionally prepared catalysts due to their unique material properties. These properties enhance catalytic activity by lowering the activation energy barrier, improving stability, and increasing conversion and selectivity compared to untreated samples. This review demonstrates how plasma activation modifies material properties and, based on extensive literature, illustrates its potential to combat climate change by converting CO2, CH4, CO, and other gases, showcasing the benefits of plasma-treated materials and catalysts. A succinct introduction to this review outlines the advantages of plasma-based synthesis and modification over traditional synthesis techniques. The introduction also highlights the various types of plasma and their physical characteristics across different factors. Additionally, this review addresses methods by which materials are synthesized and modified using plasma. The latter section of this review discusses the use of non-thermal plasma for greenhouse gas mitigation, covering applications such as the dry reforming of CH4, CO and CH4 oxidation, CO2 reduction, and other uses of plasma-modified catalysts.</description>
      <author>Nitesh Joshi, L. Sivachandiran</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electrooxidation of Synthetic Bipyridyl Herbicide Wastewaters with Boron-Doped Diamond Electrodes: A Technical and Economic Study to Boost Their Application for Pollution Prevention in the Agricultural Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112486</link>
      <description>El&#237;a Alejandra Teutli-Sequeira, Rub&#233;n V&#225;squez-Medrano, Dorian Prato-Garc&#237;a, Jorge G. Ib&#225;&#241;ez, Processes. 12(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404281990

                Boron-doped diamond electrodes (BDDEs) offer a highly efficient pathway to mineralize recalcitrant compounds due to their reduced energy requirements, fewer chemical inputs, and mechanical stability. In this work, the electrochemical degradation of paraquat (PQ) and diquat (DQ) was studied using an undivided cell (Condiacell&#174;-type) at circumneutral pH, and under galvanostatic control. The roles of applied current density, volumetric flow rate, and herbicide concentration were systematically studied through a central composite design (CCD) using a closed-flow reaction setup. Under the best operating conditions (i.e., for PQ: 1.6 mA/cm2, 80 mL/min, and 70 mL/min, and 70 mg/L; and for DQ: 1.5 mA/cm2, 80 mL/min, and 73 mg/L), a spectrophotometric analysis evidenced that the herbicides were satisfactorily removed (ca. 100%) while mineralization degrees were above 90%. Furthermore, the produced effluents yielded significant increases in seed germination and root length, which suggest a reduction in toxicity. Energy consumptions of 0.13 and 0.18 kWh/g of TOC are reported with the electrochemical cells for the PQ and DQ treatments, respectively. The PQ and DQ treatments by electrooxidation are estimated to emit nearly 2.7 and 38.9 kg CO2/m3 of water treated, with a cost around USD 250/m3. Carbon emissions could be greatly decreased for PQ (0.28 kg CO2/m3) and DQ (0.40 kg CO2/m3) if electricity were generated from renewable resources. Although this study suggests that the use of BDDE can be considered as a green alternative for agrochemical removal due to lower carbon emissions, the environmental profile of the process is determined by the degree of renewability of the electrical grid of each country or region.</description>
      <author>El&#237;a Alejandra Teutli-Sequeira, Rub&#233;n V&#225;squez-Medrano, Dorian Prato-Garc&#237;a, Jorge G. Ib&#225;&#241;ez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Urea Synthesis via C&#8208;N Coupling over Fe&#8208;Based Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401565</link>
      <description>Santosh R. Waghela, Ashadul Adalder, Koushik Mitra, Uttam Kumar Ghorai, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404349733

                Electrochemical urea synthesis under ambient conditions offers a promising alternative to traditional methods, yet suffers from inefficient production due to poor binding of reactants to the catalyst surface, leading to competitive pathways. Here, we report an electrochemical route for urea synthesis by dual reduction of CO2 and N2 gases using FePc catalyst. The FePc electrocatalyst showed a urea yield rate of 357 &#181;mol h&#8722;1 gcat&#8722;1 with a Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 14.36% at &#8722;0.4 V vs RHE. This insight offers an awareness into the development of an electrochemical route for the efficient electrosynthesis of urea via C&#8211;N coupling.</description>
      <author>Santosh R. Waghela, Ashadul Adalder, Koushik Mitra, Uttam Kumar Ghorai</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential Reduction in Carbon Emissions in the Transport of Aggregates by Switching from Road-Only Transport to an Intermodal Rail/Road System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229871</link>
      <description>Francisco Javier L&#243;pez Acevedo, M.J. Herrero, J.I. Escavy, J. Bravo, Sustainability. 16(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404296309

                Aggregates are the second-most consumed product in the world after water. This geological resource is used as building and construction material, and its production in quarries and delivery to customers generates several environmental problems. Their transport from quarries to consumption points, almost entirely done by truck, also generates impacts such as an increase in traffic and noise and the emission of greenhouse gases and other pollutants. Transportation and storage of goods account for 15% of greenhouse gas emissions in Europe and will increase significantly by 2050. To mitigate this, the European Union suggested shifting 30% of long-distance road freight to cleaner alternatives, such as rail or waterborne transport. This approach neglects the enormous volume of short-distance freight movement and its impact on achieving the goal of reducing greenhouse gas emissions. In this study, the hypothesis to test is whether the use of an intermodal rail/road transport mode, instead of just roads, for the transport of some products can help reduce global CO2 emissions even for short distances. To test this, this study investigates the carbon emissions (and transport cost reduction) generated by rail/road intermodal aggregate transport for short distances in the Madrid region (Spain), rather than the currently used direct truck transport. An analysis of variables, such as aggregate supply, demand locations and amounts, and road and rail networks, using a geographical information system provides the associated carbon emissions of the different transport alternatives. To obtain a reduction in CO2 emissions, this study proposes the establishment of intermodal transfer facilities near consumption centers, where materials are primarily transported by rail, with road transport limited to the final delivery to consumption areas. The results anticipate a notable decrease in carbon emissions in aggregate transport and allow the establishment of more efficient and environmentally friendly rail/road intermodal transport that would help to meet the goals of reducing climate change while making the use of aggregates more environmentally friendly.</description>
      <author>Francisco Javier L&#243;pez Acevedo, M.J. Herrero, J.I. Escavy, J. Bravo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229871</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study on the Remanufacturing of Vacuum Insulation Panels from End-of-Life Refrigerators and Estimation of Carbon Reduction Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62765/kjlca.2024.25.1.21</link>
      <description>Jihwan Park, Hye Sook Lim, Korean Journal of Life Cycle Assessment. 25(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404333263

                This study investigates the current processes and technologies for remanufacturing vacuum insulation panels (VIPs) recovered from end-of-life refrigerators, with a focus on making them reusable. The potential industrial applications of these re-VIPs in the building and cold chain sectors are also explored. Based on the above remanufacturing process information, the carbon reduction potential through the reuse of VIPs was assessed using Life Cycle Assessment (LCA). The study concluded that VIPs intended for reuse are most suitable for the cold chain sector. Additionally, it was estimated that assuming 15,600 VIP refrigerators are processed annually at one recycling centers, approximately 32 tons of VIPs can be reused, potentially reducing carbon emissions by &#8722;94,282 kg CO2-eq.</description>
      <author>Jihwan Park, Hye Sook Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62765/kjlca.2024.25.1.21</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cybernetic Delay Analysis of the Energy&#8211;Economy&#8211;Emission Nexus in India via a Bistage Operational Amplifier Network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/electronics13224434</link>
      <description>Soumya Basu, Keiichi N. Ishihara, Electronics. 13(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404270383

                In analyzing the decoupling of emissions from economic growth, current literature foregoes the nonlinear complexities of macroeconomic systems, leading to ineffective energy transition policies, specifically for developing countries. This study focuses on the Indian energy&#8211;economy&#8211;emission nexus to establish a control system that internalizes inflation, trade openness, and fossil fuel imports with economic growth and macro-emissions to visualize the complex pathways of decoupling. Through long-term cointegration and vector error correction modeling, it was found that GDP and energy affect capital, inflation and energy imports, which are locked in a long-run negative feedback loop that ultimately increases emissions. Capital growth enables decoupling at 0.7% CO2 emissions reduction for every 1% capital growth, while 1% inflation growth inhibits decoupling by increasing CO2 emissions by 0.8%. A cybernetic fractional circuit of R-C elements and operational amplifiers was utilized to examine the delay of pulses from GDP to the loop elements, which revealed that capital is periodic with GDP pulses. However, inflation, being aperiodic with the clock pulses of GDP, causes the pulse-width of capital to decrease and fossil fuel imports to increase. Through the circuital model, it was possible to determine the exact policy intervention schedule in business cycle growth and recession phases that could build clean energy capital and limit inflation-induced recoupling.</description>
      <author>Soumya Basu, Keiichi N. Ishihara</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/electronics13224434</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Interplay Between China&#8217;s Regulated and Voluntary Carbon Markets and Its Influence on Renewable Energy Development&#8212;A Literature Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17225587</link>
      <description>Florentina Paraschiv, H. Schmid, Michael B. Schmitz, Vivian D&#252;nwald, Emma Groos, Energies. 17(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404285610

                This is the first review study that focuses on the interplay between China&#8217;s regulated and voluntary carbon markets, the Emissions Trading System (ETS), the China Certified Emission Reduction (CCER) scheme, and their combined influence on the development of renewable energy in the country. Through a comparative literature review of 52 peer-reviewed academic papers published between 2009 and 2024, this study aims to elucidate how these market mechanisms interact to drive renewable energy deployment. The findings indicate that both the ETS and the CCER system positively affect China&#8217;s renewable energy landscape. The ETS, with its Cap-and-Trade (CaT) mechanism, sets a cap on total emissions and allows for the trading of emission quotas, thereby creating financial incentives for companies to reduce emissions and invest in renewable energy. The CCER scheme complements the ETS by allowing companies to use the CCER scheme for a capped share of their ETS certificates, whereby the lower CCER price diverts investments to where the saved ton of CO2 in China is cheapest, further incentivizing investments in renewable energy. This dual mechanism allows for a more flexible and cost-effective approach to achieving emission reduction targets, thereby fostering an environment conducive to investment in renewable energy. It will stimulate additional investment in renewable energy projects in the long run, particularly in economically underdeveloped regions, contributing to both local economic development and national emission reduction targets.</description>
      <author>Florentina Paraschiv, H. Schmid, Michael B. Schmitz, Vivian D&#252;nwald, Emma Groos</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17225587</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Optimal Arrangement of Boats in a Coastal Maritime Passenger Lines System Using Graph Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229961</link>
      <description>Antonija Mi&#353;ura, Damir Vuki&#269;evi&#263;, Ana Peri&#263; Had&#382;i&#263;, Sustainability. 16(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404417815

                This paper presents research in the field of optimization in maritime passenger traffic that can ensure the long-term sustainability of coastal maritime passenger lines system. For the purpose of the research contained in this paper, it has been hypothesized that the optimal arrangement of boats within a coastal maritime passenger lines system will reduce the consumption of propulsion energy, the emission of harmful gasses and operating costs. The aim of this paper is to present an efficient algorithm for a reduction in propulsion energy consumption in coastal maritime passenger lines systems by reassigning boats to lines that they service. The problem is modeled using a bipartite graph and the solution is obtained by searching for optimal matching using Edmonds&#8217; algorithm. The authors apply, for the first time, Edmonds&#8217; algorithm to the problems of the optimization of assignments of boats to lines. The research results were confirmed by tests on a representative example. The optimization results on only 10 ships in the given example show yearly savings of 91,097.30 L of fuel (lowering costs by EUR 69,233.95) and reducing CO2 by 243.59 tons, which proves that this algorithm found a much more efficient arrangement that could result in a significant reduction in propulsion energy consumption, thus providing economic and ecological benefits.</description>
      <author>Antonija Mi&#353;ura, Damir Vuki&#269;evi&#263;, Ana Peri&#263; Had&#382;i&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16229961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Co-Firing Demonstration at Constellation Hillabee Siemens Energy SGT6-6000G Power Plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067181</link>
      <description>James K. Harper, Duane Gibeaut, Mark Lozier, Richard Sake, Thorsten Wolf, David R. Noble, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404394307

                Abstract Gas Turbines will need to reduce CO2 emissions and prove their flexibility based on market needs and new proposed rules [2]. Economically, utilizing existing gas turbine assets to meet these requirements will be of great benefit as compared to building new turbines. Even better, determining the lowest cost least intrusive upgrades required is of great interest to power producers. The demonstration described here was conducted on one (1) GT unit at the Constellation Hillabee power plant (Siemens Energy SGT6-6000G 2x1 configuration) which doubled the mass flow of hydrogen of previous record-breaking DLN demonstrations. The testing was done on an unaltered, existing GT asset, which provides great value for those GTs which are already providing power using natural gas. The demonstrated hydrogen blending percentage of 38.8% (resulting in approximately 18% reduction in CO2 emissions) proved the system capable of meeting the first BSER goals set forth in recent proposed US EPA gas turbine rules. Such demonstrations are of critical importance as they show the inherent capability to meet reduced carbon power generation requirements without more significant cost outlays. This report documents the evaluation, preparation, execution, and results from this demonstration testing. The results are provided for the gas turbine community to use as insight into the capability and flexibility of existing assets to meet the future demands of reduced carbon power generation. Specific information around safety, reliability, emissions, and operability are discussed to provide context around existing asset capability.</description>
      <author>James K. Harper, Duane Gibeaut, Mark Lozier, Richard Sake, Thorsten Wolf, David R. Noble</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of a 2-Bladed NACA 0018 Vertical Axis Wind Turbine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202459102005</link>
      <description>Olalekan Adebayo Olayemi, Tomisin Favour Ajide, Abdulbaqi Jinadu, Adebowale Martins Obalalu, D.O. Olayemi, Brijesh Prasad, Mohit Bajaj, E3S Web of Conferences. 591(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404386503

                Renewable energy has provided a stable electricity supply with a guaranteed reduction in CO2 production. There are various types of renewable energy, but wind energy appears to be the least expensive option compared to other renewable energy sources. The current study involves the performance investigation of an H Darrius wind turbine in Ilorin Kwara State, Nigeria. Using Ilorin wind data obtained from the Nigeria Meteorological Agency (NIMET), a 2-dimensional CFD analysis was performed on a two- bladed NACA 0018 airfoil profile with the aid of Ansys (Fluent) to unravel the implications of tip-speed ratio( TSR) and azimuthal increments on the instantaneous moment and power coefficients. The study shows that the accuracy of the results depends on the azimuthal increment used. An acceptable azimuthal increment is required for a low TSR, while an increment of 0.5 is a good choice for a high TSR, and the maximum power coefficient was obtained at a TSR of 4.5.</description>
      <author>Olalekan Adebayo Olayemi, Tomisin Favour Ajide, Abdulbaqi Jinadu, Adebowale Martins Obalalu, D.O. Olayemi, Brijesh Prasad, Mohit Bajaj</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202459102005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satellite-based Air Traffic Management (ATM) Systems' Impact on CO2 Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31229/osf.io/25g43</link>
      <description>Elia Montanari, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404374428

                This paper outlines the role that satellite-based services currently play in the European Air Traffic Management (ATM) system, and describes the expected evolution of this role as per the vision for integrated Communications, Navigation and Surveillance (iCNS) put forward in the European ATM Master Plan Edition 2020. The focus of the paper is on the environmental benefits, including a quantification of the reduction in CO2 emissions that can be expected in the 2035 timeframe once the ATM concepts that are currently under Research and Development (R&amp;amp;D) in the SESAR Digital European Sky Programme are deployed. Close collaboration between European ATM and space stakeholders is required during the R&amp;amp;D and the deployment phases in order for these environmental benefits to be realised, including in particular collaboration between the SESAR programme and the European Union Agency for the Space Programme (EUSPA) and the European Space Agency (ESA).</description>
      <author>Elia Montanari</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31229/osf.io/25g43</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Two&#8208;Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Electrochemical Glycerol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416178</link>
      <description>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404458317

                Electrochemical glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) is a promising candidate to couple with cathodic reaction, like hydrogen evolution reaction, to produce high&#8208;value product with less energy consumption. Two&#8208;dimensional conjugated metal&#8208;organic frameworks (2D c&#8208;MOFs), comprising square&#8208;planar metal&#8208;coordination motifs (e.g., MO4, M(NH)4, MS4), are notable for their programable active sites, intrinsic charge transport, and excellent stability, making them promising catalyst candidates for GOR. Here, we introduce a novel class of 2D c&#8208;MOFs electrocatalysts, M2[NiPcS8] (M=Co/Ni/Cu), which are synthesized via coordination of octathiolphthalocyaninato nickel (NiPc(SH)8) with various metal centers. Due to a fast kinetic and high activity of CoS4 sites for GOR, the electrocatalytic tests demonstrate that Co2[NiPcS8] supported on carbon paper displays a low GOR potential of 1.35 V vs. RHE at 10 mA cm&#8208;2, significantly reducing the overall water&#8208;electrolysis&#8208;voltage reduction by 0.27 V from oxygen evolution reaction to GOR, thereby outperforming Ni2[NiPcS8] and Cu2[NiPcS8]. Additionally, we have determined that the GOR activity of CoX4 linkage sites varies with different heteroatoms, following an experimentally and theoretically confirmed activity order of CoS4&gt;CoO4&gt;Co(NH)4. The GOR performance of Co2[NiPcS8] not only demonstrate superior performance among non&#8208;noble metal complex, but also provides critical insights on designing high&#8208;performance MOF electrocatalysts upon optimizing the electronic environment of active sites.</description>
      <author>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Integrated Energy&#8211;Water Systems Using Automated Targeting Modeling Considering the Energy&#8211;Water&#8211;Carbon Nexus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/w16223256</link>
      <description>Nor Erniza Mohammad Rozali, Muhammad Aidan Mohd Halmy, Peng Yen Liew, Water. 16(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404258011

                The swift expansion of the global population and economy has spurred growing requirements for energy and water in recent decades. Inefficient energy and water consumption, however, has led to an increase in CO2 emissions. Hence, the socio-economic development of a country must consider the interconnections between energy, water and carbon, as there are mutual dependencies among these three elements. This work considers the nexus between energy, water and carbon in the design of integrated energy&#8211;water systems using a new automated targeting modeling (ATM) framework. ATM incorporates the advantages of the insight-based Pinch method and a mathematical programming approach to provide visual understanding for a thorough analysis of the problem while guaranteeing accurate solutions. Minimum targets of power and water based on the integrated network operation were established by the ATM, with corresponding carbon emissions. A specific goal of annual carbon emissions reduction was set as the constraint and the ATM optimized the capacities of the components in the system accordingly to achieve minimum overall cost. The application of ATM on an industrial plant case study shows that a target of 45% reduction in the carbon discharge amount was achieved by shifting to greener fuel in the energy system at a minimum overall cost increase of 0.45% only. The framework can assist users in meeting power and water loads in their plant while planning for the appropriate decarbonization efforts at the minimum possible cost.</description>
      <author>Nor Erniza Mohammad Rozali, Muhammad Aidan Mohd Halmy, Peng Yen Liew</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/w16223256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Two&#8208;Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Electrochemical Glycerol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416178</link>
      <description>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404455598

                Electrochemical glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) is a promising candidate to couple with cathodic reaction, like hydrogen evolution reaction, to produce high&#8208;value product with less energy consumption. Two&#8208;dimensional conjugated metal&#8208;organic frameworks (2D c&#8208;MOFs), comprising square&#8208;planar metal&#8208;coordination motifs (e.g., MO4, M(NH)4, MS4), are notable for their programable active sites, intrinsic charge transport, and excellent stability, making them promising catalyst candidates for GOR. Here, we introduce a novel class of 2D c&#8208;MOFs electrocatalysts, M2[NiPcS8] (M=Co/Ni/Cu), which are synthesized via coordination of octathiolphthalocyaninato nickel (NiPc(SH)8) with various metal centers. Due to a fast kinetic and high activity of CoS4 sites for GOR, the electrocatalytic tests demonstrate that Co2[NiPcS8] supported on carbon paper displays a low GOR potential of 1.35 V vs. RHE at 10 mA cm&#8208;2, significantly reducing the overall water&#8208;electrolysis&#8208;voltage reduction by 0.27 V from oxygen evolution reaction to GOR, thereby outperforming Ni2[NiPcS8] and Cu2[NiPcS8]. Additionally, we have determined that the GOR activity of CoX4 linkage sites varies with different heteroatoms, following an experimentally and theoretically confirmed activity order of CoS4&gt;CoO4&gt;Co(NH)4. The GOR performance of Co2[NiPcS8] not only demonstrate superior performance among non&#8208;noble metal complex, but also provides critical insights on designing high&#8208;performance MOF electrocatalysts upon optimizing the electronic environment of active sites.</description>
      <author>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battery Electric Vehicle Lightweighting Strategies: Addressing Energy Consumption and Range Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15282/ijame.21.4.2024.4.0905</link>
      <description>Jason Pollock, Perk Lin Chong, Manu Ramegowda, Nashwan Dawood, Pengyan Guo, Lip Kean Moey, International Journal of Automotive and Mechanical Engineering. 21(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404416873

                In general, an internal combustion engine vehicle is still the convention in personal and commercial transport, but due to its high use stage CO2 emission, a shift is occurring in propulsion methods, and the use of battery electric vehicles (BEV) will become the new norm. BEV&#8217;s curb weight is, in general, greater than that of a conventional fuelled vehicle (CFV) for equivalent classes. Consequently, it is questionable that the level of BEV&#8217;s energy consumption is acceptable. The aim of this paper is to compare the mass induced energy consumption of CFV and BEV. The expectation is that the comparative study of energy consumption between CFV and BEV will provide insight for proposing a strategy to determine the extent to which lightweighting can be introduced to a BEV. Encouragingly, less exhaustive energy consumption can help by reducing range anxiety by increasing BEV range, resolving one issue facing a BEV. With a typical road condition for hilly and flat roads, various drive cycles are also taken into consideration, and the energy consumption profiles for CFV and BEV can be determined. The vehicle model involved using the MATLAB/Simulink software underpinned by longitudinal vehicle dynamic methods. The idea is to determine the amount of lightweighting of various components of a BEV through an iterative process based on energy consumption profiles. As a function of mass reduction, for comparative energy expenditure, the results showed that a range of 28 to 36% reduction in BEV mass was achieved, which in turn can increase the driving range by 36.4 to 46.8%.</description>
      <author>Jason Pollock, Perk Lin Chong, Manu Ramegowda, Nashwan Dawood, Pengyan Guo, Lip Kean Moey</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15282/ijame.21.4.2024.4.0905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstract 4146533: Association of Quantitative Echocardiographic Parameters with Peak VO2, Heart Rate Recovery, and VE/VCO2 from Cardiopulmonary Exercise Testing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.150.suppl_1.4146533</link>
      <description>Arundhati Sharma, Anubhuti Sharma, Kalyan Chaliki, TAYLOR VIGGIANO, Hari P. Chaliki, Satyajit Reddy, Circulation. 150(Suppl_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404382234

                Background: Cardiopulmonary Exercise Testing (CPET) analyzes physiologic information with gas exchange during exercise. Peak oxygen volume consumption (absolute peak VO2 and percent predicted peak VO2), minute ventilation divided by carbon dioxide volume (VE/VCO2 slope) and heart rate reduction after 1 minute of recovery (heart rate recovery, HRR) all have well-established prognostic cardiovascular implications. Aim: Given the wider use of echocardiography, we aimed to see if important CPET data could be determined from resting transthoracic echocardiography (TTE). Methods: In this retrospective study, cardiology patients above 18 years who underwent both resting TTE and a max-effort CPET within 3 months of each other (2017-2022) were included. Patients with a history of coronary artery bypass grafting, valve surgery, pacemakers, congenital heart disease, severe valve dysfunction and pulmonary hypertension were excluded before analysis. Univariate analysis with Spearman correlations was used to assess the relationship between 4 CPET measurements {absolute peak VO2 per kg, percent predicted peak VO2/kg (adjusted for age, sex and body surface area), HRR, and VE/VCO2}; and 22 quantitative TTE parameters. Bonferroni correction was applied within each set of correlations, with significance set at p-values &lt;0.025. Multivariate linear regression models were built for all the related TTE measurements to assess relationship with the 4 CPET parameters, adjusting for age and sex. Results: Table 1 shows, out of 1909 patients analyzed, our regression model is strongest for absolute peak VO2/kg (R-squared=0.57), with 3 significantly associated TTE parameters. For percent-predicted peak VO2 per kg, 4 TTE variables were significantly associated. For heart rate recovery, only LV stroke-volume index was correlated. No TTE parameters were associated with VE/VCO2. Conclusion: Notably, echocardiographic stroke volume and tricuspid valve regurgitation peak velocity exhibited a strong correlation with absolute peak VO2/kg and percent predicted peak VO2/kg. LV stroke volume index was correlated with heart rate recovery. VE/VCO2 was not associated with any resting echocardiographic parameters, suggesting this parameter is truly exercise-dependent.</description>
      <author>Arundhati Sharma, Anubhuti Sharma, Kalyan Chaliki, TAYLOR VIGGIANO, Hari P. Chaliki, Satyajit Reddy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.150.suppl_1.4146533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Effectiveness of the &#8216;Batch Operations&#8217; Energy Design Pattern to Mitigate the Carbon Footprint of Communication Peripherals on Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/s24227246</link>
      <description>Roberto Vergallo, Alberto Cagnazzo, Emanuele Mele, Simone Casciaro, Sensors. 24(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404330029

                The Internet of Things (IoT) is set to play a significant role in the future development of smart cities, which are designed to be environmentally friendly. However, the proliferation of these devices, along with their frequent replacements and the energy required to power them, contributes to a significant environmental footprint. In this paper we provide scientific evidences on the advantages of using an energy design pattern named &#8216;Batch Operations&#8217; (BO) to optimize energy consumption on mobile devices. Big ICT companies like Google already batch multiple API calls instead of putting the device into an active state many times. This is supposed to save tail energy consumption in communication peripherals. To confirm this, we set up an experiment where we compare energy consumption and carbon emission when BO is applied to two communication peripherals on Android mobile device: 4G and GPS. Results show that (1) BO can save up to 40% energy when sending HTTP requests, resulting in an equivalent reduction in CO2 emissions. (2) no advantages for the GPS interface.</description>
      <author>Roberto Vergallo, Alberto Cagnazzo, Emanuele Mele, Simone Casciaro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/s24227246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unfolding Electrolyzer Characteristics to Reveal Solar&#8208;to&#8208;Chemical Efficiency Potential: Rapid Analysis Method Bridging Electrochemistry and Photovoltaics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402027</link>
      <description>Oleksandr Astakhov, Th&#233;r&#232;se Cibaka, Lars Wieprecht, Uwe Rau, Tsvetelina Merdzhanova, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404403628

                Development of photovoltaic&#8211;electrochemical (PV&#8208;EC) systems for energy storage and industry decarbonization requires multidisciplinary collaborative efforts of different research groups from both photovoltaic and electrochemical research communities. Consequently, the evaluation of the solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical or solar&#8208;to&#8208;fuel efficiency of a new electrolyzer (EC) as a part of a PV&#8208;EC system is a time&#8208;consuming task that is challenging in a routine optimization loop. To address this issue, a new rapid assessment method is proposed. This method employs power balance requirements to unfold the input EC characteristics into the parameter space of PV&#8208;EC systems. The system parameters, composed with the EC output characteristics, yield the solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical efficiency attainable by the electrolyzer in combination with any PV device under any irradiance at any relative PV&#8208;to&#8208;EC scaling and any mode of power coupling. This comprehensive overview is achieved via a mathematically simple conversion of the EC characteristics in any spreadsheet software. The method, designed to streamline the development and minimize the efforts of both the photovoltaic and electrochemical communities, is demonstrated via the analysis of CO2&#8208;reduction electrolyzer characteristics and verified with dedicated PV&#8208;EC experiments.</description>
      <author>Oleksandr Astakhov, Th&#233;r&#232;se Cibaka, Lars Wieprecht, Uwe Rau, Tsvetelina Merdzhanova</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Build Orientation and Laser Scanning Strategies for Reducing Thermal Residual Stress in Topology-Optimized Automotive Components</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14111277</link>
      <description>Jeongho Yang, Youngsuk Jung, Jaewoong Jung, Jae Dong Ock, Shinhu Cho, Sang&#8208;Hu Park, Tae Hee Lee, Jiyong Park, Metals. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404248103

                This study investigates the reduction in thermal residual stress during the powder bed fusion (PBF) process in a non-standardized shape generated by topology optimization method in lightweight automotive part of brake caliper. While the caliper of the braking system for reducing the CO2 consumption in vehicle systems undergoes a redesign to increased strength and reduced weight, challenges arise due to biased melting area ratios in the topologically optimized design, causing the thermal deformation. To address this, our research proposes an efficient PBF scan strategy aimed at minimizing anisotropy and residual stress&#8212;a critical consideration for successful manufacturing. The effectiveness of the laser scan strategy is validated through testing on a brake dynamometer, following the JASO C406 test procedure, an authorized standard for commercial brake calipers. Furthermore, a comparative analysis between the conventional product and the proposed brake caliper highlights superior performance, particularly under lightweight conditions. This comprehensive approach contributes valuable insights to the field, offering a potential solution for overcoming manufacturing challenges associated with topologically optimized designs in automotive components.</description>
      <author>Jeongho Yang, Youngsuk Jung, Jaewoong Jung, Jae Dong Ock, Shinhu Cho, Sang&#8208;Hu Park, Tae Hee Lee, Jiyong Park</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14111277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use of Distributed Energy Resources Integrated with the Electric Grid in the Amazon: A Case Study of the Universidade Federal do Par&#225; Poraqu&#234; Electric Boat Using a Digital Twin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/machines12110803</link>
      <description>Bruno Santana De Albuquerque, Maria Em&#237;lia de Lima Tostes, Ubiratan Holanda Bezerra, Carminda C&#233;lia Moura de Moura Carvalho, Ayrton Lucas Lisboa do Nascimento, Machines. 12(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404263851

                Electric mobility is a global trend and necessity, with electric and solar boats offering a promising alternative for transportation electrification and carbon emission reduction, especially in the Amazon region. This study analyzes the system of a solar boat from an electric mobility project&#8212;to be implemented at Universidade Federal do Par&#225; (UFPA)&#8212;using MATLAB software for modeling. The Simulink tool was utilized to model the system, focusing on operational parameters such as module voltage, converter voltage, and speed. The results indicate that the solar boat&#8217;s operational cost is significantly lower compared to a similar internal combustion model, considering diesel&#8217;s high consumption and cost. The environmental impact is also reduced, with nearly 72 tons of CO2 emissions avoided annually, thanks to Brazil&#8217;s renewable energy matrix. Simulations confirmed the project&#8217;s parameters, demonstrating the efficiency of digital-twin technology in monitoring and predicting system performance. The study underscores the importance of digital twins and renewable energy in promoting sustainable transportation solutions, advocating for the replication of such projects globally. Future research should focus on further advancing digital-twin applications in electric mobility to enhance predictive maintenance and operational efficiency.</description>
      <author>Bruno Santana De Albuquerque, Maria Em&#237;lia de Lima Tostes, Ubiratan Holanda Bezerra, Carminda C&#233;lia Moura de Moura Carvalho, Ayrton Lucas Lisboa do Nascimento</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/machines12110803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Consumption and Fume Analysis: A Comparative Analysis of the Blasting Technique and Mechanical Excavation in a Polish Gypsum Open-Pit Mine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17225662</link>
      <description>Andrzej Biessikirski, Przemys&#322;aw Bodziony, Micha&#322; Dworzak, Energies. 17(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404301584

                This article presents a comparative assessment of energy consumption and fume emissions such as NOx, CO2, and CO associated with the excavation of a specified gypsum volume using two mining methods (blasting and mechanical extraction). The analysis was carried out based on a case study gypsum open-pit mine in Poland where both extraction methods are applied. The findings indicate that, for the same output volume, blasting operations require significantly less energy (ranging from 1298.12 MJ to 1462.22 MJ) compared to mechanical excavation (86,654.15 MJ). Furthermore, a substantial portion of the energy in blasting operations is attributed to explosive loading and drilling (970.95 MJ). Conversely, mechanical mining results in higher fume emissions compared to blasting. However, during mechanical extraction, the fumes are dispersed over a prolonged period of 275 h, whereas blasting achieves the same gypsum volume extraction in approximately 7.5 h. The prediction model suggests that, based on the obtained data, overall gypsum extraction will decline unless new operational levels are developed or the mine is expanded. This reduction in gypsum extraction will be accompanied by a corresponding decrease in energy consumption and emission of fumes.</description>
      <author>Andrzej Biessikirski, Przemys&#322;aw Bodziony, Micha&#322; Dworzak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17225662</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Based Praseodymium-Modified &#947;-Al2O3 Oxygen Carrier for Chemical Looping Combustion Process Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110801</link>
      <description>Muhammad Qasim, Noridah Osman, Muhammad Ayoub, Aqsha Aqsha, Catalysts. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404283818

                Chemical looping combustion (CLC) emerges as a cost-effective CO2 capture technology, demonstrating high competitiveness for both industrial and energy applications. This study explores the synthesis of a Cu-based, praseodymium (Pr)-modified gamma-alumina-supported (20CuPA) oxygen carrier (OC) through the wet impregnation method and investigates its performance in CLC. The characteristics of the synthesized OC were investigated using field emission scanning electron microscopy, energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy, temperature-programmed reduction analysis, and X-ray diffraction analysis. The CLC of methane gas was performed in a thermogravimetric analyzer (TA-Q50). The oxygen transport capacity (OTC) of the 20CuPA-based OC was investigated for 10 redox cycles. The impact of temperature and time as process variables in determining the OTC of OCs was studied. The TGA results indicated that the most important factor influencing the optimization of the OTC of OCs was time. In comparison to time, temperature had less of an impact on the OTC of 20CuPA-OC. The maximum OTC of 20CuPA-OC, which was 0.0546 mg of O2/mg of OC, was reached using optimized process variables, including a temperature of 800 &#176;C and a time of 3 min.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Qasim, Noridah Osman, Muhammad Ayoub, Aqsha Aqsha</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas content, geochemical characteristics and implications of coalbed methane from the Deep Area of Qi&#8217;Nan Coalmine in Huaibei Coalfield</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-79922-x</link>
      <description>Qiang Wei, Song Chen, Wu Yi, Herong Gui, Wei Jiang, Fengli Li, Shengjie Li, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404435504

                The objective of this work is to investigate the implications of geological influence factors on gas content and geochemical characteristics of deep-buried (&gt; 800 m) coalbed methane (CBM) reservoirs. Results show that bituminous coal accounts for the majority, which exhibits similar maturity but differ in maceral and chemical constituents. CBM reservoirs show low porosity, low permeability and moderate temperature, with thickness of 0.85&#8211;4.15 m. In addition, the total gas content is 4.58&#8211;12.33 m3/t (average of 8.83 m3/t). CH4 is the main component with concentration of 92.83&#8722;99.22% (average of 96.68%), and the &#948;13CCH4 and &#948;13DCH4 is &#8722; 53.78&#8240;&#8211;&#8722;44.62&#8240; (average of &#8722; 48.82&#8240;) and &#8722; 223.93&#8240;&#8211;&#8211;&#8722;4.49&#8240; (average of &#8722; 215.37&#8240;), respectively. All CBM samples are the mixtures of thermogenic gases and secondary biogenic gases with CO2 reduction. In addition, gas content characteristic at the critical point of burial depth is the result by positive and negative geological effects. CH4 concentration shows a wide range with the increases of buried depth, while the numerical values of which for the selected samples display complex variation characteristics. Furthermore, the values of &#948;13CCH4 and &#948;13DCH4 become heavier with the increases of buried depth. Besides, the above two geochemical parameters are related to Ro, max and reservoir temperature.</description>
      <author>Qiang Wei, Song Chen, Wu Yi, Herong Gui, Wei Jiang, Fengli Li, Shengjie Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-79922-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into CO and H2 Oxidation on Cu/CeO2 Single Atom Catalysts: A Computational Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-q61wb</link>
      <description>Parinya Tangpakonsab, Alexander Genest, Gareth S. Parkinson, G&#252;nther Rupprechter, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404378345

                Single atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted significant interest due to their unique properties and potential for enhancing catalytic performance in various chemical reactions. In this study, we atomistically explore adsorption properties and catalytic performance of single Cu atoms anchored at low-index CeO2 surfaces, focusing on the oxidation of CO and H2. Utilizing density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we report that Cu adatoms bind favorably on different CeO2 surfaces, following a stability order of (100)&gt;(110)&gt;(111). The charge transfer from a single adsorbed Cu atom to Ce leads to the reduction of Ce4+ to Ce3+ and the oxidation of Cu0 to Cu+. This strengthens molecular bonds at Cu sites, particularly for CO due to the less populated d-band, while H2 shows a by ~1 eV weaker adsorption. CO oxidation is energetically more favorable than H2 oxidation on the Cu/CeO2(111) surface. The rate-controlling steps for the Mars-van Krevelen oxidation involve the formation of a bent CO2- intermediate for CO and H2O for H2. The lattice oxygen atom at the interface plays a key role for both oxidation processes. Our findings highlight the potential of single atom catalyst, Cu/CeO2, for CO adsorption and oxidation in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Parinya Tangpakonsab, Alexander Genest, Gareth S. Parkinson, G&#252;nther Rupprechter</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-q61wb</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Impact of Magnets and Fins in Solar Desalination: Energetic, Exergetic, Economic, and Environmental Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112554</link>
      <description>Ajay Kumar Kaviti, Malavika Prasad, V. Bhanu Venkata Naga Teja, Vineet Singh Sikarwar, Processes. 12(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404415280

                This study investigates the effectiveness of combining magnets with parabolic and truncated fins in enhancing the distillation process of solar stills. The integration of magnets accelerated evaporation rates, while the fins increased the heat absorption area, resulting in improved output, vis-&#224;-vis traditional solar stills. A comparative assessment revealed that the parabolic fin solar still (PFS) with magnets outperformed the truncated fin solar still (TCFS), producing 20%, 15%, and 16% more distillate at three different depths (1, 2, and 3 cm). The superior performance of the PFS is attributed to the magnetism of the water and the fins&#8217; more extensive surface area for heat absorption. Efficiency measurements at a water depth of 1 cm showed that the PFS achieved the maximum energy and exergy efficiencies at 30.49% and 8.85%, respectively, compared with TCFS&#8217;s 25.23% and 6.22%. Economically, the PFS setup proved more feasible, with a 20.9% lower cost per liter of distilled water than TCFS. Additionally, the environmental impact assessment indicated a significant reduction in CO2 emissions, potentially generating revenues of approximately USD 1242.32 through carbon credits. These results reflect a considerable margin to enhance the efficiency of solar desalination through well-planned adjustments, which bodes well for the future of optimized solar distillation systems from an economic and environmental perspective.</description>
      <author>Ajay Kumar Kaviti, Malavika Prasad, V. Bhanu Venkata Naga Teja, Vineet Singh Sikarwar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12112554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerogarden: An aeroponics innovation project linking artificial intelligence and sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30574/ijsra.2024.13.2.2191</link>
      <description>Nicoletta Nandi, International Journal of Science and Research Archive. 13(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404457431

                Every year, 10.8 to 19.1 billion tonnes of CO2 are emitted through food exports, which accounts for roughly 21% - 37% of the world&#8217;s global total emissions. In the urge to expand businesses and ensure availability of all crops throughout the year, the quality of air is being compromised. The demand for crops rises in tandem with population growth and improvements in human well-being. In addition, most of these exported crops lose their nutritional value due to the unhealthy exposure of preservatives and other farming chemicals. There are multiple factors involved in crop production: land, labour, transportation, storage etc. Aeroponics is a relatively new farming system that eradicates numerous problems by using less land and water and requiring minimal labour and nutrients. The aim of this project is to convert the aeroponic farming unit into a 100% carbon-neutral, self-reliant unit called Aerogarden by integrating modern technology like Artificial Intelligence (AI). Every household having an Aerogarden unit can access fresh organic vegetables and microgreens that actually retain their nutritional value. By achieving this goal, non-agricultural nations' dependence on food imports will lessen, which will ultimately result in a reduction in the sector's carbon footprint. By giving people a way to directly support the international movement, the project also aims to support the UN's initiative to achieve the 17 Sustainable Development Goals.</description>
      <author>Nicoletta Nandi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30574/ijsra.2024.13.2.2191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal sizing of PV/wind/diesel generator/battery hybrid system for supplying electrical vehicle charging station under different load demands in Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ijlct/ctae190</link>
      <description>Ali Basem, Z. M. S. Elbarbary, Farruh Atamurotov, Iroda Abdullayeva, Anvar Reyimberganov, Natei Ermias Benti, International Journal of Low-Carbon Technologies. 19(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404289150

                Abstract Knowing the effect of different load distributions on the optimized sizes of the hybrid renewable energy systems (HRES) and the fixed price of Electric Vehicle (EV) charging station can be useful to potential investors in this sector. Additionally, the amount of CO2 emission under different load demands can help decision-makers in the installation of environmentally friendly EV charging stations. Investigation of fixed prices of installing power stations under different load demands leads to know whether electricity sell prices, and serves by the station owners are economically or not. This would also lead to give a reliable and economical plan to customers by station owners, where both time of arrival and charging prices have a pivotal role. Unlike previous similar studies that mostly consider one type of load demand, this study investigates the optimized HRESs including Photovoltaic panel (PV), Wind Turbine (WT), Diesel Generator (DG), and Battery (Bat) under five different proposed load demands (as electricity serving plans), reaching to the best economic, environmental, and space optimality systems. Three main sensitivity analyses upon the capacity shortage/inflation rate, capital cost of PV/WT, and solar global horizontal irradiation (GHI)/wind speed show the effect of changing the mentioned parameters on the economic, environment, and optimized systems&#8217; sizes. It is observed that increase in the solar radiation and/or wind speed leads to reduction in the optimal size of designed systems.</description>
      <author>Ali Basem, Z. M. S. Elbarbary, Farruh Atamurotov, Iroda Abdullayeva, Anvar Reyimberganov, Natei Ermias Benti</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ijlct/ctae190</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Briquetting of black soldier fly frass as a post-harvest stabilization strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2166/washdev.2024.249</link>
      <description>Rosemary M. Matheka, Simon M. Wandera, James M. Raude, Sylvia I. Murunga, Anthony Gachanja, Monica M. Ndolo, Journal of Water Sanitation and Hygiene for Development. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404298122

                ABSTRACT The production&#8211;consumption cycle needs a transition towards a circular economy where waste valorization is included. This study investigated briquetting as a stabilization method for black soldier fly frass (BSFF) with faecal matter, pig manure, and poultry manure as the larvae feed. Herein, dried BSFF was pyrolyzed at 350 &#176;C for 2 h to produce biochar then mixed with charcoal dust in equal ratio to produce biobriquettes through densification, with cassava gel (10 wt%) as binder. One-way ANOVA showed statistical significance in carbon, nitrogen, hydrogen, and oxygen. There were significant differences (p &amp;lt; 0.05) between the calorific value, moisture content, ash content, volatile matter, and fixed carbon of the briquettes. The fixed carbon, volatile matter, moisture, and ash content ranged from 29.66 &#177; 0.86 to 42.01 &#177; 0.92, 29.26 &#177; 0.52 to 32.59 &#177; 0.80, 2.95 &#177; 0.1 to 5.08 &#177; 0.04, and 21.48 &#177; 0.14 to 37.20 &#177; 0.29, respectively. The calorific value of the produced briquettes ranged from 16.25 &#177; 0.57 to 20.70 &#177; 0.53 MJ/kg, which exceeds the minimum requirement of 14.5 MJ/kg recommended for non-woody briquettes. During combustion, concentrations of NOx, N2O, CO, and CO2 varied significantly across the treatments with the acacia charcoal having the highest concentration of CO. Briquetting is a potential stabilization method for frass resulting in waste reduction, bioenergy production, reduced adverse effects of climate change, and enhanced sustainability.</description>
      <author>Rosemary M. Matheka, Simon M. Wandera, James M. Raude, Sylvia I. Murunga, Anthony Gachanja, Monica M. Ndolo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2166/washdev.2024.249</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Int&#233;gration &#233;conomique et qualit&#233; de l&#8217;environnement en Afrique : Une approche en termes de Panel ARDL</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.23882/emss25114</link>
      <description>Mustapha ZIKY, Mouna Ouarhi, Rachid OUCHCHIKH, Deleted Journal. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404421491

                African countries are committed to the creation of free trade areas as a means of consolidating trade links between African nations. Intra-African trade is expected to boost economic growth and improve macroeconomic performance and living standards in Africa. However, theoretical insights and empirical evidence suggest that these efforts risk being undermined by the adverse environmental consequences of trade, which are likely to undermine the continent's achievements in terms of sustainable development and poverty reduction. This paper aims to examine the environmental impact of intra-African trade while integrating FDI, economic growth, urbanization, and energy consumption. The study used a panel data set for 32 African countries over the period 1990-2020. The empirical analysis was based on the latest panel estimation techniques. More specifically, we used the Dumitrescu-Hurlin causality test, the second generation of unit root tests on panel data, and the PMG estimator to estimate an ARDL panel. The error correction term reveals the existence of a cointegrating relationship between CO2 and trade, FDI, and the other control variables. The results suggest that intra-African trade worsens environmental quality in Africa in the long term. Similarly, FDI has a similar ecological impact, corroborating the &#8216;pollution heaven&#8217; hypothesis. The results also refute the Environmental Kuznets Curve (EKC) hypothesis. Energy consumption plays a key role in the long-term deterioration of the environment. Finally, urbanization degrades the environment in line with the intuition of urban environmental transition theory.</description>
      <author>Mustapha ZIKY, Mouna Ouarhi, Rachid OUCHCHIKH</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.23882/emss25114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The economic, social, and environmental impact of ecologically centered integrated pest management practices in East Africa</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123241</link>
      <description>Kelvin Mulungu, Zewdu Abro, Saliou Niassy, Beatrice Muriithi, Jimmy Picthar, Michael Kidoido, Sevgan Subramanian, Samira Mohamed, Zeyaur R. Khan, Girma Hailu, Menale Kassie, Journal of Environmental Management. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404233375

                Agricultural pest management faces mounting challenges with increasing pressure to reduce chemical pesticide use while ensuring food security, and environmental sustainability. Ecologically centered approaches, such as integrated pest management (IPM), offer promising sustainable agroecological crop protection alternative solutions to pesticides. This study assesses the investment viability and environmental sustainability of two IPM interventions-mango fruit fly IPM (FF-IPM) and push-pull technology (PPT) in Kenya and Uganda, using project investment and adoption data from 2007 to 2021. The study also evaluates these technologies contribution to food security and poverty reduction. FF-IPM integrates biological control, cultural practices, and targeted bait traps to manage fruit flies in mango production, while PPT employs Desmodium and Brachiaria grass to control stemborers and striga weed. The findings highlight that these IPM interventions achieved a combined net present value of $500 million, with a benefit-cost ratio of about 8:1, and an internal rate of return of 21%, comparable to returns from improved crop varieties. These technologies also improved food security for 641,000 people, lifted 445,349 people above the poverty line, representing 2% of the poor population in both countries, and generated an average income increase of $5 per capita in Kenya and Uganda annually. Environmentally, they sequestered 2.7 million tons of CO2 equivalent, valued at $12.2 million, and are reducing pesticide use by 86,000 to 204,000 L per year. These results demonstrate the potential of IPM approaches to simultaneously enhance livelihoods, local economies, and generate global environmental public goods, suggesting that addressing adoption barriers could further amplify these positive outcomes.</description>
      <author>Kelvin Mulungu, Zewdu Abro, Saliou Niassy, Beatrice Muriithi, Jimmy Picthar, Michael Kidoido, Sevgan Subramanian, Samira Mohamed, Zeyaur R. Khan, Girma Hailu, Menale Kassie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bio-inspired Design and Performance Evaluation of Lawnmower Cutter Blade</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18311/jmmf/2024/45431</link>
      <description>S. H. Deshmukh, C. L. Gogte, Journal of Mines Metals and Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404356825

                This study presents a bio-inspired design approach for the engineering applications of agricultural implements, with practical implications for the field. The CAD modeling of bio-inspired serrated lawnmower cutter blades was followed by structural and fatigue analysis with a comparative evaluation of the performance of conventional plain cutter blades. This method involved the bionic transformation of a biological model of the serrated leg of the grasshopper, traced using MATLAB edge detection and image processing software. The solid modeling CAD software for the Bionic Blade lawnmower cutter blade converts this biological model into an engineering model. After designing the geometric shape of the bionic tooth profile's serrated cutting edge, the boundary conditions are evaluated for numerical simulation based on the machine specifications of the conventional lawnmower cutter. After analyzing the power of the motor, the rotational speed, and the torque, the static structural and fatigue analysis was carried out in numerical simulation software to synthesize the performance of the bionic lawnmower cutter blade for engineering analysis of deformation, shear stress, and fatigue life. The bionic design of the blade and conventional plain blades were manufactured using an Amada CO2 laser cutting machine and sheet metal bending processes for Stainless Steel (SS 304) material. The experimental validation of software simulation was carried out by field trials using the Bionic design of a lawnmower cutter blade to evaluate the performance improvement in cutting time and yield of grass cut in kg for 60 to 100 meters distance cutting. After comparing the performance of the plain blade and the design of the bionic blade, there was a reduction in abrasive wear, a 12.87% improvement in the cutting time, and a 14.8% increase in the yield of grass compared to the conventional blade. This performance improvement was attributed to the unique bionic design of serrated cutting-edge and ground clearance. The bio-inspired design approach has immense practical applications in designing agricultural implements, as confirmed by this performance evaluation of this case study of bio-inspired lawnmower cutter blades.</description>
      <author>S. H. Deshmukh, C. L. Gogte</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18311/jmmf/2024/45431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Irrigation Amount and Salinity Levels on Maize (Zea mays L.) Growth, Water Productivity and Carbon Emissions in Arid Region of Northwest China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14112656</link>
      <description>Qiang Zhou, Desheng Lyu, Wenhao Li, Yue Wen, Zhenhua Wang, Agronomy. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404244138

                To address the growing scarcity of freshwater resources, the use of saline water for agricultural irrigation is gaining increasing attention. This study presents findings from a two-year field experiment conducted during the 2023 and 2024 maize-growing seasons in northwestern China. The objective of the experiment was to evaluate the main and interactive effects of saline irrigation water on soil water&#8211;salt dynamics, maize growth, photosynthetic characteristics, water productivity, and carbon emissions. The experiment involved nine treatments with three irrigation amounts: 4500 m3 hm&#8722;2 (W1), 5625 m3 hm&#8722;2 (W2), and 6750 m3 hm&#8722;2 (W3), combined with three water salinity levels: 0.85 g L&#8722;1 (S1, freshwater), 3 g L&#8722;1 (S2), and 5 g L&#8722;1 (S3). Results indicated that both irrigation amount and salinity level significantly affected water&#8211;salt dynamics, with more soil accumulating in the 0&#8211;100 cm soil layer under saline irrigation water; however, this effect diminished with higher irrigation amounts. The maximum leaf area index and plant height were affected by both the irrigation amount and salinity level, as well as their interaction. Photosynthetic capacity declined with increasing salinity of the irrigation water, ultimately reducing grain yield and irrigation water use efficiency. Compared to freshwater (S1), the average maize grain yield under S2 and S3 treatments decreased by 6.28% and 15.43% in 2023 and by 7.82% and 17.48% in 2024, respectively. Additionally, for the same irrigation amount, higher salinity of the irrigation water (S2, S3) significantly reduced total soil CO2 emissions, with reductions of 10.08% and 27.53% in 2023, and 11.97% and 28.01% in 2024, respectively. In summary, to optimize the utilization of saline water, enhance maize yield, and improve soil carbon sequestration, we recommend maintaining the salinity of irrigation water below 3 g L&#8722;1, and using an irrigation amount of 6750 m3 hm&#8722;2 (W3S2) for optimal outcomes in the study area.</description>
      <author>Qiang Zhou, Desheng Lyu, Wenhao Li, Yue Wen, Zhenhua Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14112656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstract 4140462: Effects of Right Ventricular vs. Conduction System Pacing on Left Ventricular Systolic and Diastolic Function Reserve and Pulmonary Gas Exchange During Exercise Stress in Pacemaker Dependent Patients with Normal Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.150.suppl_1.4140462</link>
      <description>Songnan Wen, Courtney M. Wheatley, Jordan Parks, Catherine T. Wingler, Rose A. Simpson, Monique Silva, Hicham El Masry, Tasneem Z. Naqvi, Circulation. 150(Suppl_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404363690

                Background: Right ventricular pacing (RVP) can have adverse cardiac effects and cause pacing induced cardiomyopathy (PiCM). His bundle pacing (HBP)&amp;Left Bundle Branch area pacing (LBBAP) mimic physiologic conduction (PhysioP) and maintain biventricular synchrony. Hypothesis and Aims: Reduced left ventricular (LV) systolic function reserve in the presence of normal baseline LV ejection fraction (EF) could precede development of RV PiCM. Our aim was to compare the effects of RVP vs. PhysioP on bicycle exercise cardiopulmonary performance in patients with normal LVEF who required pacing for bradyarrhythmias. Methods: Patients with sinus rhythm and RVP or PhysioP&amp;ventricular pacing burden of &gt;70% who completed cardiopulmonary exercise test and simultaneous stress echocardiography (SE) were included. Pulmonary gas exchange was calculated using Ventilation/CO2 production at rest and during exercise. Changes in LV size, EF, longitudinal strain and diastolic function and gas exchange parameters were compared post and pre exercise in the 2 groups. Results: 25 of 29 patients completed the study [68 &#177; 23 yrs, 48% M; LVEF 56&#177;5%, 11 RVP, 14 PhysioP]. There was no difference in baseline demographic&amp;clinical variables, exercise duration, rest and peak heart rate and blood pressure between 2 groups. Pacing duration was 2.61&#177;1.48 yrs in RVP vs. 0.84&#177;0.67 yrs (p=0.003) in the Physio group. Resting echocardiographic parameters ( Table 1A) were comparable. Compared to RVP, reduction in LV end-diastolic volume (EDV) 3.4&#177;14.1 ml vs. -23.1&#177;18.1ml, p=0.006)&amp;LV end-systolic volume (ESV -5.7&#177;11.6 ml vs. -18.0&#177;9.5ml, p=0.01) was more pronounced in the PhysioP group. Changes in LVEF, LV strain&amp;diastolic function were not different between the 2 groups ( Table 1B ). There were no significant differences in changes in pulmonary gas exchange parameters in the 2 groups. Conclusions: In patients with normal LVEF and pacemaker dependent, RVP is associated with impaired but PhysioP with preserved LV systolic function reserve, which can be detected by exercise SE. SE may help identify patients at risk for RV PiCM. Benefit of PhysioP needs to be determined by larger studies with longer follow-up.</description>
      <author>Songnan Wen, Courtney M. Wheatley, Jordan Parks, Catherine T. Wingler, Rose A. Simpson, Monique Silva, Hicham El Masry, Tasneem Z. Naqvi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.150.suppl_1.4140462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstract 4142562: Mesenchymal Stromal Cell Delivery through Cardiopulmonary Bypass in Pediatric Cardiac Surgery &#8211; MeDCaP Phase I Trial</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.150.suppl_1.4142562</link>
      <description>Soichiro Henmi, Kumi Kobayashi, David Zurakowski, Steven J. Staffa, Kenneth Fulton, Anushree Datar, Jay Tanna, Chase D. McCann, Mark Nuszkowski, Nina Deutsch, Sarah D. Schlatterer, Mary T. Donofrio, Fahmida Hoq, Patrick J. Hanley, Gil Wernovsky, Yves d&#8217;Udekem, Shriprasad R. Deshpande, Catherine M. Bollard, Nobuyuki Ishibashi, Circulation. 150(Suppl_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404359873

                Introduction/Background: Neurodevelopmental impairment is a challenge for many children with complex congenital heart disease who undergo surgical intervention with cardiopulmonary bypass during the early postnatal period. Research Questions/Hypothesis: We hypothesized that bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stromal cell (BM-MSC) delivery through cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB) will improve neurodevelopmental outcome and post-operative course. Goals/Aims: The primary goal of this single-center, dose-escalation phase 1 trial was to assess the safety/feasibility and determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of BM-MSC treatment. Methods/Approach: Inclusion criteria of the phase 1 trial were neonates/infants (ages &#8804; 6 months) who underwent scheduled two-ventricle repair without arch reconstruction. Dose escalation was guided by a modified continual reassessment method at four dose levels (1-40x10^6 cells/kg). Dose limiting toxicity was assessed for 45 days after BM-MSC delivery. Secondary endpoints before discharge were compared with a historical cohort (n=222) by inverse probability of treatment weighting (IPTW) using the propensity score to balance the groups. Results/Data: Seventeen patients were enrolled from July 2020 to June 2023 (ventricular septal defect, n=9; tetralogy of Fallot, n=7; transposition of the great arteries, n=1; male, n=10). There were 3 serious adverse events all of which were related to cardiac surgery and not the BM-MSC product (junctional ectopic tachycardia, n=2; diaphragm paresis, n=1). Among 50 total events, there were no adverse events related to BM-MSCs. The BM-MSC dose was successfully escalated to the planned MTD (40x10^6 cells/kg), demonstrating safety and feasibility of this therapeutic delivery strategy. Consistent with results indicating little interference on CPB functions, electron microscopy studies showed no BM-MSC adherence on the CPB filter mesh at the MTD. Multivariable analyses with IPTW identified a reduction of CO2 and lactate levels in MeDCaP cases. We observed differences in white blood cell, monocyte, and platelet numbers between the two groups, suggesting possible interaction between endogenous blood cells and applied BM-MSCs. Conclusions: We confirmed the safety and feasibility of BM-MSC treatment during CPB at the proposed MTD level. Successful design and completion of a future phase 2 trial is needed to determine efficacy.</description>
      <author>Soichiro Henmi, Kumi Kobayashi, David Zurakowski, Steven J. Staffa, Kenneth Fulton, Anushree Datar, Jay Tanna, Chase D. McCann, Mark Nuszkowski, Nina Deutsch, Sarah D. Schlatterer, Mary T. Donofrio, Fahmida Hoq, Patrick J. Hanley, Gil Wernovsky, Yves d&#8217;Udekem, Shriprasad R. Deshpande, Catherine M. Bollard, Nobuyuki Ishibashi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.150.suppl_1.4142562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loose-fill heat insulation material obtained from hemp shives by steam explosion =Tvaika spr&#257;dzien&#257; no ka&#326;epju spa&#316;iem ieg&#363;ti beramie siltumizol&#257;cijas materi&#257;li</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22616/lbtuthesis/2024.012</link>
      <description>M&#257;rti&#326;&#353; And&#382;s, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404417615

                And&#382;s, M. &#8220;Loose-fill heat insulation material obtained from hemp shives by steam explosion&#8221;. Ph.D. thesis. Jelgava, LBTU, 2024. &#8211; 112 pages. The thesis text includes 10 tables, 60 images, 21 formulas and 225 references to the used literature sources. The doctoral thesis was developed in the Biorefining Laboratory of the Latvian State Institute of Wood Chemistry by support of the European Union 7th Framework Programme Wood Wisdom project &#8220;ProLignin&#8221; (2012-2014), National Research Program &#8220;ResProd&#8221; (2014-2017), European Regional Development Fund research results commercialization project No 1.2.1.2/16/I/001/ KC-PI-2020/13 "Commercialisation of the technology for the production of lignocellulosic bulk thermal insulation material" (2020&#8211;2022) and Fundamental and Applied Research lzp-2021/1-0599 &#8220;Investigation of eco-friendly thermal insulation materials from sustainable and renewable industrial crops residuals&#8221; project (2022&#8211;2024). Regulations&#8217; of the European Union and global best practice trends for limiting climate change have forced Latvia to implement actions for the rational consumption and saving of heat energy. Latvia has the lowest housing quality in the European Union, including buildings with relatively low thermal stability. EU regulations and society demand sustainable, health and environmentally friendly thermal insulation materials. As a solution to the urgent need for a new thermal insulation material produced from non-woody lignocellulosic biomass of local origin, a new loose-fill thermal insulation material that meets current regulations and environmental requirements has been developed from the by-product of agricultural plants &#8211; hemp shives &#8211; in the research of the doctoral thesis. The thesis is a detailed and fundamental, but at the same time a technological study, which includes the development of the pretreatment methodology for the hemp shives by the steam explosion of hemp shives, the study of the properties of the obtained fibrous materials and the evaluation of loose-fill thermal insulation material samples. As a result of the research, a steam explosion method was applied for the production of environmentally friendly thermal insulation material. The influence of the variable parameters of the steam explosion technology on the structure, properties and application possibilities of the obtained material in heat and sound insulation was studied, thus creating new knowledge about the application of the steam explosion technology in the processing of agricultural residues. The optimal processing parameters of the steam explosion method for obtaining loose-fill thermal insulation material from hemp shives are at a temperature of 235&#176; C, a pressure of 32 Bar with release immediately after reaching it, i.e. holding time 0 minutes. One of the most important scientific findings in the development of loose-fill thermal insulation material with steam explosion technology is the discovery that the most important is the adiabatic process (second phase &#8211; explosion), which performs fibrillation of the sample, maximally shortening the thermochemical process (first phase). By choosing the optimal processing conditions, it is possible to reduce the bulkiness up to 2.3 times, obtaining the best indicators of thermal inertia and thermal conductivity. The thermal insulation properties of the developed fiber loose-fill material (&#955;=0.043 W&#183;m-1&#183;K-1) are equivalent to analogs on the market. The research of the thesis has a significant practical value, as a practically applicable technology has been developed for the processing of by-products of hemp fiber production &#8211; hemp shives &#8211; into products with high added value, thus creating a knowledge-intensive, innovative product with commercialization and export potential. The developed product contributes to the growing demand for sustainable thermal insulation materials, as well as contributes to the achievement of Latvia's climate neutrality goals and the reduction of CO2 emissions in the field of energy efficiency.</description>
      <author>M&#257;rti&#326;&#353; And&#382;s</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22616/lbtuthesis/2024.012</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
