<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 01:12:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in photochemical/electrochemical synthesis of heterocyclic compounds from carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc02829e</link>
      <description>Yuyang Xie, Ying&#8208;Ming Pan, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401514803

                The primary greenhouse gas is carbon dioxide (CO2), which also serves as an excellent C1 building block for the synthesis of heterocyclic compounds. The preparation and transformation of these structures...</description>
      <author>Yuyang Xie, Ying&#8208;Ming Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc02829e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction in Aqueous Medium Using a Novel N4&#8208;Macrocyclic Cobalt Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400627</link>
      <description>Libo Sun, Tan Su, Adrian C. Fisher, Xin Wang, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401525254

                Abstract Molecular catalysts represent an exceptional class of materials in the realm of electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction (CO 2 RR), offering distinct advantages owing to their adaptable structure, which enables precise control of electronic configurations and outstanding performance in CO 2 RR. This study introduces an innovative approach to heterogeneous electrochemical CO 2 RR in an aqueous environment, utilizing a newly synthesized N4&#8208;macrocyclic cobalt complex generated through a dimerization coupling reaction. By incorporating the quaterpyridine moiety, this cobalt complex exhibits the capability to catalyze CO 2 RR at low overpotentials and reaches near&#8208;unity CO production across a wide potential range, as verified by the online mass spectrometry and in situ attenuated total reflectance&#8208;Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy. Comprehensive computational models demonstrate the superiority of utilizing quarterpyridine moiety in mediating CO 2 conversion compared to the counterpart. This work not only propels the field of electrochemical CO 2 RR but also underscores the promising potential of cobalt complexes featuring quaterpyridine moieties in advancing sustainable CO 2 conversion technologies within aqueous environments.</description>
      <author>Libo Sun, Tan Su, Adrian C. Fisher, Xin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of indium doped Bi/Bi2O3 catalyst for efficiently selective electroreduction of carbon dioxide to formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129205</link>
      <description>Ziyuan Yang, Xiaowei An, Zhongbao Feng, Yusrin Ramli, Changrui Feng, Peifen Wang, Xiaogang Wang, Shasha Li, Xiaogang Hao, Houfang Lu, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401537362

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyuan Yang, Xiaowei An, Zhongbao Feng, Yusrin Ramli, Changrui Feng, Peifen Wang, Xiaogang Wang, Shasha Li, Xiaogang Hao, Houfang Lu, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; into Syngas by N-Modified NiSb Nanowires</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01864</link>
      <description>Liheng Guan, Hui Fu, Li Wang, Juan Wang, Nan Zhang, Tianxi Liu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401546648

                Carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO</description>
      <author>Liheng Guan, Hui Fu, Li Wang, Juan Wang, Nan Zhang, Tianxi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of N-doped copper metal&#8211;organic frameworks for promoting photocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2229-2</link>
      <description>Fan Guo, Zong-Zheng He, Peng Wang, Xiaoyu Zhang, Hongjian Yu, Sheng Wang, Wei&#8208;Yin Sun, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401610358

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fan Guo, Zong-Zheng He, Peng Wang, Xiaoyu Zhang, Hongjian Yu, Sheng Wang, Wei&#8208;Yin Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2229-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Geopolymers and Limestone Calcined Clay in Reduction of Anthropogenic Carbon dioxide Emissions: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/seb4sdg60871.2024.10629713</link>
      <description>Ayodeji K. Ogundana, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401608346

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ayodeji K. Ogundana</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/seb4sdg60871.2024.10629713</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Spectroelectrochemistry Unravels the Mechanism of CO2 Electrocatalytic Reduction by an Fe Porphyrin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412417</link>
      <description>Marc Robert, Aude Salam&#233;, Mun Hon Cheah, Julien Bonin, Elodie Anxolab&#233;h&#232;re&#8208;Mallart, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401685964

                Iron porphyrins are molecular catalysts recognized for their ability to electrochemically and photochemically reduce carbon dioxide (CO2). The main reduction product is carbon monoxide (CO). CO holds significant industrial importance as it serves as a precursor for various valuable chemical products containing either a single carbon atom (C1), like methanol or methane, or multiple carbon atoms (Cn), such as ethanol or ethylene. Despite the long&#8208;established efficiency of these catalysts, optimizing their catalytic activity and stability and comprehending the intricate reaction mechanisms remain a significant challenge. This article presents a comprehensive investigation of the mechanistic aspects of the selective electroreduction of CO2 to CO using an iron porphyrin substituted with four trimethylammonium groups in the para position [(pTMA)FeIII&#8208;Cl]4+. By employing infrared and UV&#8208;Visible spectroelectrochemistry, changes in the electronic structure and coordination environment of the iron center can be observed in real&#8208;time as the electrochemical potential is adjusted, offering new insights into the reaction mechanisms. Catalytic species were identified, and evidence of a secondary reaction pathway was uncovered, potentially prompting a re&#8208;evaluation of the nature of the catalytically active species.</description>
      <author>Marc Robert, Aude Salam&#233;, Mun Hon Cheah, Julien Bonin, Elodie Anxolab&#233;h&#232;re&#8208;Mallart</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-bacterium modification strategies for photobiocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trechm.2024.07.003</link>
      <description>Yujing Jiang, Hanyu Li, Wenlei Zhu, Trends in Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401615139

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujing Jiang, Hanyu Li, Wenlei Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trechm.2024.07.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Critical Role of Binders in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110134</link>
      <description>Younghyun Chae, Hyunwook Kim, Dong Ki Lee, Ung Lee, Da Hye Won, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401668207

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Younghyun Chae, Hyunwook Kim, Dong Ki Lee, Ung Lee, Da Hye Won</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decarbonizing Urban Mobility: A Methodology for Shifting Modal Shares to Achieve CO2 Reduction Targets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16167049</link>
      <description>P&#225;ulo Ribeiro, Gabriel Dias, Jos&#233; F. G. Mendes, Sustainability. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401628288

                In most urban areas, mobility is predominantly reliant on automobiles, leading to significant negative environmental impacts, such as noise pollution, air pollution, and greenhouse gas emissions. To meet the objectives of the Paris Agreement, urgent action is required to decarbonize the mobility sector. This necessitates the development of assessment and planning tools to create effective decarbonization scenarios. Urban mobility must evolve to reduce dependency on fossil fuels by increasing public transport options and promoting active modes of transportation. This research presents a methodology to estimate the modal share required to shift car users to active modes and public transport, thereby achieving future CO2 emission reduction targets in the road transport sector. A case study in Braga, Portugal, demonstrates that to meet the 2040 target of 59,150 tons of CO2, 63% of trips must be made using active modes (e.g., walking and cycling) and 32% by public transport.</description>
      <author>P&#225;ulo Ribeiro, Gabriel Dias, Jos&#233; F. G. Mendes</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16167049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global reduction in sensitivity of vegetation water use efficiency to increasing CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2024.131844</link>
      <description>Yuanfang Chai, Chiyuan Miao, Wouter Berghuijs, Yunping Yang, Boyuan Zhu, Yong Hu, Louise Slater, Journal of Hydrology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401629992

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanfang Chai, Chiyuan Miao, Wouter Berghuijs, Yunping Yang, Boyuan Zhu, Yong Hu, Louise Slater</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2024.131844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modified Cu active sites by alloying for efficient electrocatalytic reduction CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.005</link>
      <description>Yan Wang, Ruikuan Xie, Naixuan Ci, Zhiyuan Zhu, Chaoyi Li, Guoliang Chai, Huajun Qiu, Yinghe Zhang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401503498

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Wang, Ruikuan Xie, Naixuan Ci, Zhiyuan Zhu, Chaoyi Li, Guoliang Chai, Huajun Qiu, Yinghe Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically precise alkynyl-protected Ag19Cu2 nanoclusters: Synthesis, structure analysis, and electrocatalytic CO2 reduction application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02702g</link>
      <description>Xiangou Zhu, Zhu Pan, Xuzi Cong, Guanyu Ma, Qing Tang, Li Wang, Zhenghua Tang, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401559294

                We report the synthesis, structure analysis, and electrocatalytic CO2 reduction application of Ag19Cu2(C&#8801;CArF)12(PPh3)6Cl6 (abbrevaited as Ag19Cu2, C&#8801;CArF: 3, 5-bis(trifluoromethyl)phenylacetylene) nanoclusters. Ag19Cu2 has characteristic absorbance feature, and is a superatomic cluster...</description>
      <author>Xiangou Zhu, Zhu Pan, Xuzi Cong, Guanyu Ma, Qing Tang, Li Wang, Zhenghua Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02702g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity and Selectivity in the Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 at CuSnx Electrocatalysts Using a Zero-Gap Membrane Electrode Assembly</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6fd7</link>
      <description>Monsuru Olatunji Dauda, John Hendershot, M. E. B. R. Bello, Junghyun Park, Alvaro Loaiza Orduz, Orhan Kizilkaya, Phillip Sprunger, Anthony Engler, Koffi P. C. Yao, Craig Plaisance, John Flake, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401598562

                Abstract In this study Cu, Sn, and bimetallic CuSnx nanoparticles were synthesized and evaluated as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction using zero gap membrane electrode assemblies. Results show bimetallic electrocatalysts with Sn contents above 10% yield formate as a primary product with Faradaic Efficiencies near 70% at 350 mA cm-2. Cu-Snx electrocatalysts with less than 10% Sn yield CO at current densities below 350 mA cm-2 and relatively lower cell potentials. When the low-Sn content bimetallic electrocatalysts were evaluated in alkaline anolytes at 350 mA cm-2, ethanol was recorded as the primary product (FE = 48.5% at Ecell &#8805; 3.0 V). We propose enhanced C2 activity and selectivity originate from Cu dimers adjacent to Sn atoms for bimetallic electrocatalyst with low-Sn content. The C2 active sites are lost when the surface Sn content exceeds 25-38%.</description>
      <author>Monsuru Olatunji Dauda, John Hendershot, M. E. B. R. Bello, Junghyun Park, Alvaro Loaiza Orduz, Orhan Kizilkaya, Phillip Sprunger, Anthony Engler, Koffi P. C. Yao, Craig Plaisance, John Flake</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6fd7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Construction of Cubi-Mof Derived Heterojunctions with Electron-Rich Effects Enhances Localized Co2 Enrichment Integrated with Si Photocathodes for Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4924748</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Jianming Hong, Jing Shang, Hiromi Yamashita, C. M. Wei, Yun Hang Hu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401542213

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Jianming Hong, Jing Shang, Hiromi Yamashita, C. M. Wei, Yun Hang Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4924748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reductive&#8208;Transmetalation Reactions of ZnR2/(AlCp*)4 Heterobimetallic Combinations and Application towards CO2 Insertion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400418</link>
      <description>Fabian Dankert, Eva Hevia, European Journal of Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401506794

                Organo&#8208;aluminum compounds are usually derived via salt metathesis reactions starting from aluminum halides and s&#8208;block organometallics such as organolithiums or Grignard reagents. Herein, an alternative route is reported using an Cp*Al(I)/Zn(II)R2 (Cp*= C5Me5; R = aryl) system which facilitates the formation of a range of halide and donor free heteroleptic triorgano&#8208;alanes of the general formula [Al(Cp*)R2]. Exposing the obtained alanes to an atmosphere of CO2 enables for the selective insertion of CO2 in their AlCp* moieties. State of the art quantum chemical calculations support experimental observations providing mechanistic insights on the observed reactivity of the [Al(Cp*)R2] complexes towards this unsaturated organic molecule.</description>
      <author>Fabian Dankert, Eva Hevia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Specific Activity during Electrochemical CO2 Reduction through Homogeneous Deposition of Gold Nanoparticles on Gas Diffusion Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ns1l4</link>
      <description>Takuya Yamada, Kazuyuki Iwase, Naoto Todoroki, Itaru Honma, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401549220

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) has attracted attention as a promising strategy for converting CO2 into value-added products. Gas diffusion electrodes (GDEs) loaded with metallic nanoparticles as electrocatalysts are expected to efficiently reduce CO2 due to the high specific surface area of such particles and the superior mass transport characteristics of GDEs. In the present study, GDEs loaded with homogeneous layers of sub-nanometer gold (Au) nanoparticles were fabricated using a radio frequency sputtering technique that had a low deposition rate. This allowed precise control of the catalyst loading. The Au-loaded GDEs exhibited significantly higher CO production efficiency compared with the electrodes fabricated by conventional deposition methods using dispersed Au nanoparticles. Additionally, a Au-loaded GDE having a catalytic layer thickness of 10 nm demonstrated a mass-based CO production activity of 1882 A g-&#185; at -0.85 V. This is the highest value yet reported. This work confirmed that the uniform deposition of sub-nanometer metallic particles gives enhanced catalyst utilization. The results of this research provide important insights into the design of efficient CO2RR electrodes and highlight the potential of radio frequency sputtering to fabricate high-performance CO2RR electrodes as an approach to realizing carbon-neutral technologies.</description>
      <author>Takuya Yamada, Kazuyuki Iwase, Naoto Todoroki, Itaru Honma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ns1l4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen Doping Retrofits the Coordination Environment of Copper Single-Atom Catalysts for Deep CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100415</link>
      <description>Yu-Xiang Zhang, Jia Zhao, Sen Lin, Chinese Journal of Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401529209

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Xiang Zhang, Jia Zhao, Sen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual structure cobalt sites on surface hydroxyl and oxygen vacancy of BiOCl for cooperative CO2 reduction and tetracycline oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124514</link>
      <description>Haoyu Sun, Haili Lin, Xuemei Jia, Xinyue Li, Shuang Li, Xin Jin, Qianlong Wang, Shifu Chen, Jing Cao, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401659343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoyu Sun, Haili Lin, Xuemei Jia, Xinyue Li, Shuang Li, Xin Jin, Qianlong Wang, Shifu Chen, Jing Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zr-MOF/MXene composite for enhanced photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction in atmospheric and industrial flue gas streams</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100274</link>
      <description>Meng Yang, Feng Yue, Shuo Zhang, L. Zhang, Cong Li, Mengke Shi, Yongpeng Ma, Mario Berrettoni, Xiaojing Zhang, Hongzhong Zhang, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. 13(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401560596

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meng Yang, Feng Yue, Shuo Zhang, L. Zhang, Cong Li, Mengke Shi, Yongpeng Ma, Mario Berrettoni, Xiaojing Zhang, Hongzhong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Bi2MoO6/Zn0.5Cd0.5S charge transfer through interface chemical bonds and surface defects for photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.103</link>
      <description>Zhongqiang Yuan, Jie Liu, Xiang Yu, Xuan Jian, Hao Zhang, Mimi Liu, Rui Cao, Yanan Hu, Xiaoming Gao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401559079

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongqiang Yuan, Jie Liu, Xiang Yu, Xuan Jian, Hao Zhang, Mimi Liu, Rui Cao, Yanan Hu, Xiaoming Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the electrochemical CO2 reduction performance of MoS2-supported Ni single atoms with transition metal substrate doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104938</link>
      <description>Yu-wang Sun, Lei Liu, Jing-yao Liu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401648296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-wang Sun, Lei Liu, Jing-yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104938</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot Electrons Induced by Localized Surface Plasmon Resonance in Ag/g-C3N4 Schottky Junction for Photothermal Catalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16162317</link>
      <description>Jiang Peng, Kun Wang, Wenrui Liu, Yuhang Song, Runtian Zheng, Lihua Chen, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Polymers. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401645586

                Converting carbon dioxide (CO2) into high-value-added chemicals using solar energy is a promising approach to reducing carbon dioxide emissions; however, single photocatalysts suffer from quick the recombination of photogenerated electron&#8211;hole pairs and poor photoredox ability. Herein, silver (Ag) nanoparticles featuring with localized surface plasmon resonance (LSPR) are combined with g-C3N4 to form a Schottky junction for photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction. The Ag/g-C3N4 exhibits higher photocatalytic CO2 reduction activity under UV-vis light; the CH4 and CO evolution rates are 10.44 and 88.79 &#181;mol&#183;h&#8722;1&#183;g&#8722;1, respectively. Enhanced photocatalytic CO2 reduction performances are attributed to efficient hot electron transfer in the Ag/g-C3N4 Schottky junction. LSPR-induced hot electrons from Ag nanoparticles improve the local reaction temperature and promote the separation and transfer of photogenerated electron&#8211;hole pairs. The charge carrier transfer route was investigated by in situ irradiated X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). The three-dimensional finite-difference time-domain (3D-FDTD) method verified the strong electromagnetic field at the interface between Ag and g-C3N4. The photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction pathway of Ag/g-C3N4 was investigated using in situ diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectra (DRIFTS). This study examines hot electron transfer in the Ag/g-C3N4 Schottky junction and provides a feasible way to design a plasmonic metal/polymer semiconductor Schottky junction for photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Jiang Peng, Kun Wang, Wenrui Liu, Yuhang Song, Runtian Zheng, Lihua Chen, Bao&#8208;Lian Su</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16162317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new strategy for CO2 storage and Al2O3 recovery from blast furnace slag and coal fly ash by employing vacuum reduction and alkali dissolution methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132865</link>
      <description>Haitao Yuan, Wenzhou Yu, Jiale Wen, Jing Wang, Joseph Emmanuel Nyarko-Appiah, Chenguang Bai, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401665404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haitao Yuan, Wenzhou Yu, Jiale Wen, Jing Wang, Joseph Emmanuel Nyarko-Appiah, Chenguang Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.132865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stepped copper sites coupling voltage-induced surfactant assembly to achieve efficient CO2 electroreduction to formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02697g</link>
      <description>Sicong Qiao, Guikai Zhang, Chun Song, Wenjie Xu, Wei Jiang, Yuyan Cao, Zhihui Zhang, Jing Zhang, Qingliang He, Li Song, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401581067

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) into formate holds great promise. However, the ongoing competition of parallel reactions, including the generation of hydrogen (H2), carbon monoxide (CO), and multi-carbon...</description>
      <author>Sicong Qiao, Guikai Zhang, Chun Song, Wenjie Xu, Wei Jiang, Yuyan Cao, Zhihui Zhang, Jing Zhang, Qingliang He, Li Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02697g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Frontiers of Cathode Catalysts in Lithium&#8211;Carbon Dioxide Batteries: A Mini Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12080222</link>
      <description>Jing Guo, Xin Yan, Xue Meng, Pengwei Li, Qin Wang, Qian Zhang, Shu Yan, Shaohua Luo, Inorganics. 12(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647013

                To mitigate the greenhouse effect and environmental pollution caused by the consumption of fossil fuels, recent research has focused on developing renewable energy sources and new high-efficiency, environmentally friendly energy storage technologies. Among these, Li&#8211;CO2 batteries have shown great potential due to their high energy density, long discharge plateau, and environmental friendliness, offering a promising solution for achieving carbon neutrality while advancing energy storage devices. However, the slow kinetics of the CO2 reduction reaction and the accumulation of Li2CO3 discharge on the cathode surface lead to a significant reduction in space and active sites. This in turn results in high discharge overpotential, low energy efficiency, and low power density. This study elucidates the charge&#8211;discharge reaction mechanisms of lithium&#8211;carbon dioxide batteries and systematically analyzes their reaction products. It also summarizes the latest research advancements in cathode materials for these batteries. Furthermore, it proposes future directions and efforts for the development of Li&#8211;CO2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Jing Guo, Xin Yan, Xue Meng, Pengwei Li, Qin Wang, Qian Zhang, Shu Yan, Shaohua Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12080222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Wildfire on Soil CO2 Emission and Bacterial Community in Plantations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/microorganisms12081666</link>
      <description>Yu Yang, Xuehui Liu, Shilin Huang, J. Jia, C.X. Wang, Lening Hu, Ke Li, Hua Deng, Microorganisms. 12(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401536401

                In order to study the effects of wildfires on soil carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions and microbial communities in planted forests, Pinus massoniana Lamb. and Cunninghamia lanceolata (Lamb.) Hook. forests were selected as the research subjects. Through a culture test with 60 days of indoor constant temperature, the soil physical and chemical properties, organic carbon mineralization, organic carbon components, enzyme activity, and microbial community structure changes of the two plantations after fire were analyzed. The results showed that wildfires significantly reduced soil CO2 emissions from the Pinus massoniana forests and Cunninghamia lanceolata forests by 270.67 mg&#183;kg&#8722;1 and 470.40 mg&#183;kg&#8722;1, respectively, with Cunninghamia lanceolata forests exhibiting the greatest reduction in soil CO2 emissions compared to unburned soils. Bioinformatics analysis revealed that the abundance of soil Proteobacteria in the Pinus massoniana and Cunninghamia lanceolata forests decreased by 6.00% and 4.55%, respectively, after wildfires. Additionally, redundancy analysis indicated a significant positive correlation between Proteobacteria and soil CO2 emissions, suggesting that the decrease in Proteobacteria may inhibit soil CO2 emissions. The Cunninghamia lanceolata forests exhibited a significant increase in soil available nutrients and inhibition of enzyme activities after the wildfire. Additionally, soil CO2 emissions decreased more, indicating a stronger adaptive capacity to environmental changes following the wildfire. In summary, wildfire in the Cunninghamia lanceolata forests led to the most pronounced reduction in soil CO2 emissions, thereby mitigating soil carbon emissions in the region.</description>
      <author>Yu Yang, Xuehui Liu, Shilin Huang, J. Jia, C.X. Wang, Lening Hu, Ke Li, Hua Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/microorganisms12081666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Soil Carbon Sequestration and Land Restoration through Tropical Forest Management</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56556/jase.v2i2.906</link>
      <description>Md. Shoaibur Rahman, Asif Raihan, S M A Bin Al Islam, Parson Paul, Sourav Karmakar, Journal of Agriculture Sustainability and Environment. 2(2)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4401658720

                Soil has a high capacity for absorbing carbon dioxide (CO2). The significance of soil organic carbon (SOC) in tropical regions is often overlooked, despite its crucial role. This study investigates the potential of forest management to enhance the sequestration of SOC and rehabilitate degraded tropical ecosystems. Sequestering soil organic carbon has the potential to improve soil fertility while also mitigating land degradation and reducing greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. The improvement of soil structure, aggregation, infiltration, faunal mobility, and nutrient cycling (specifically carbon, nitrogen, phosphorus, and sulfur) is observed. Managing forest ecosystems enhances carbon sequestration, mitigates climate change, and rehabilitates degraded land. By integrating organic residue management with nitrogen-fixing plants, afforestation or reforestation of marginal or degraded lands can effectively increase carbon storage in both biomass and soil. This approach also promotes soil health, improves food productivity, restores land quality, and contributes to the reduction of GHG emissions. The sequestration of carbon promotes the biological, physical, and chemical fertility of the soil, hence enhancing soil health.</description>
      <author>Md. Shoaibur Rahman, Asif Raihan, S M A Bin Al Islam, Parson Paul, Sourav Karmakar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56556/jase.v2i2.906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homogeneous Catalysis in N&#8208;formylation/N&#8208;methylation Utilizing Carbon Dioxide as the C1 Source</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400497</link>
      <description>Kuo&#8208;Wei Huang, Indranil Dutta, Sandeep Suryabhan Gholap, Mohammad Misbahur Rahman, Davin Tan, Qian Zhang, Shashikant U. Dighe, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401668431

                The growing emphasis on sustainable chemistry has driven research into utilizing carbon dioxide (CO2) as a nontoxic, abundant, and cost&#8208;effective C1 building block. CO2 offers a promising avenue for direct conversion into valuable chemicals ranging from fuels to pharmaceuticals. This review focuses on the utilization of CO2 for reductive N&#8208;formylation/N&#8208;methylation reactions of various amines, providing advantages over conventional methods involving toxic CO and other methylating reagents. The approach employs readily available reductants such as silane, borane reagents, and hydrogen (H2). The discussion encompasses recent developments in transition metal and organocatalyst systems for these reactions, highlighting mechanistic interpretations and factors influencing product selectivity.</description>
      <author>Kuo&#8208;Wei Huang, Indranil Dutta, Sandeep Suryabhan Gholap, Mohammad Misbahur Rahman, Davin Tan, Qian Zhang, Shashikant U. Dighe</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400497</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring of CO2 emission fluxes and organic C balance in limed sod-podzolic soil in winter rapeseed field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33245/2310-9270-2024-187-1-131-139</link>
      <description>Volodymyr Polovyy, L. Yashchenko, H. Rovna, B. V. Huk, Agrob&#236;olog&#236;&#226;. None(1(187))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401618224

                Management of carbon sequestration processes is one of the main issues in overcoming soil organic matter degradation in the Polissya zone, especially taking into account climate changes. There is a need to research and develop measures to reduce unproductive losses of CO2 from the soil, which will contribute to the stabilization of the organic carbon content in the soil under intensive agriculture. The goal of the research was to establish the peculiarities of CO2 emission fluxes formation and the balance of organic carbon in sod-podzolic soil on average over the cultivation years of winter rapeseed in short crop rotation at different doses of ameliorants and fertilizers. Research methods: field experiment, laboratory, computational and statistical analysis. According to the research results it was found that during the spring- summer period of cultivation of winter rapeseed cultivation in crop rotation the highest unproductive losses of CO2 from the soil can be traced in the variant without fertilizers. Significant reductions in the average daily emission fluxes of CO2 from the soil and unproductive losses of carbon dioxide were noted with the application of 1.5 doses of CaMg(CO3 )2 against the background of N120P90K120 to 218.5 kg/ha and 3.64 kg/ ha/h, respectively. Improvement of growing conditions in this variant contributes to increased accumulation of CO2 22% in the biomass of winter rapeseed and, accordingly, an increase in the share of crop residues when they are plowed into the soil to 62.8% of the total carbon dioxide emissions into the atmosphere. Taking into account the share of fertilizers and dolomite flour, the share of humus mineralization decreased to 22.6%. It was found that the application of 1.5 doses of CaMg(- CO3 ) 2 against the background of the recommended dose of fertilizer with the incorporation of by-products into the soil stabilizes the organic carbon balance at the level of 0.05 t/ha. Key words: winter rapeseed, CO2 emissions, chemical reclamation, fertilization, organic carbon balance.</description>
      <author>Volodymyr Polovyy, L. Yashchenko, H. Rovna, B. V. Huk</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33245/2310-9270-2024-187-1-131-139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering the Selectivity of CORR from Acetate to Ethanol via Tailoring the Thermodynamic Activity of Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412266</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Bao Zhang, Derong Chen, Ouwen Peng, Haibin Ma, Shibo Xi, Chao Wu, Qikun Hu, Kun Zhang, Junyuan Feng, Kian Ping Loh, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401686463

                The electrochemical conversion of carbon monoxide (CO) into oxygenated C2+ products at high rates and selectivity offers a promising approach for the two&#8208;step conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2). However, a major drawback of the CO electrochemical reduction in alkaline electrolyte is the preference for the acetate pathway over the more valuable ethanol pathway. Recent research has shed light on the significant impact of thermodynamic water activity on the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction pathways, but less is understood for the electrochemical reduction of CO. In this study, we investigated how the water activity at the electrified interface can be enhanced to adjust the selectivity between acetate and ethanol. We employed an ionomer modifier to lower the local concentration of alkali ions (via Donnan exclusion), successfully enhancing ethanol production while suppressing acetate formation. We observed a remarkable improvement in the Faradaic efficiency of ethanol and alcohol (i.e. ethanol, propanol etc), which reached 42.5% and 55.1%, respectively, at a current density of 700 mA cm&#8208;2. The partial current densities of ethanol and alcohol reached 698 and 942 mA cm&#8208;2 at 2000 mA cm&#8208;2. Furthermore, we achieved a 3.7&#8208;fold increase in the ethanol/acetate ratio, providing clear evidence of our successful modulation of product selectivity.</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Bao Zhang, Derong Chen, Ouwen Peng, Haibin Ma, Shibo Xi, Chao Wu, Qikun Hu, Kun Zhang, Junyuan Feng, Kian Ping Loh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering the Selectivity of CORR from Acetate to Ethanol via Tailoring the Thermodynamic Activity of Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412266</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Bao Zhang, Derong Chen, Ouwen Peng, Haibin Ma, Shibo Xi, Chao Wu, Qikun Hu, Kun Zhang, Junyuan Feng, Kian Ping Loh, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401685940

                The electrochemical conversion of carbon monoxide (CO) into oxygenated C2+ products at high rates and selectivity offers a promising approach for the two&#8208;step conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2). However, a major drawback of the CO electrochemical reduction in alkaline electrolyte is the preference for the acetate pathway over the more valuable ethanol pathway. Recent research has shed light on the significant impact of thermodynamic water activity on the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction pathways, but less is understood for the electrochemical reduction of CO. In this study, we investigated how the water activity at the electrified interface can be enhanced to adjust the selectivity between acetate and ethanol. We employed an ionomer modifier to lower the local concentration of alkali ions (via Donnan exclusion), successfully enhancing ethanol production while suppressing acetate formation. We observed a remarkable improvement in the Faradaic efficiency of ethanol and alcohol (i.e. ethanol, propanol etc), which reached 42.5% and 55.1%, respectively, at a current density of 700 mA cm&#8208;2. The partial current densities of ethanol and alcohol reached 698 and 942 mA cm&#8208;2 at 2000 mA cm&#8208;2. Furthermore, we achieved a 3.7&#8208;fold increase in the ethanol/acetate ratio, providing clear evidence of our successful modulation of product selectivity.</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Bao Zhang, Derong Chen, Ouwen Peng, Haibin Ma, Shibo Xi, Chao Wu, Qikun Hu, Kun Zhang, Junyuan Feng, Kian Ping Loh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How rainfall events modify trace gas mixing ratios in central Amazonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-8893-2024</link>
      <description>Luiz A. T. Machado, J. Kesselmeier, Santiago Bot&#237;a, Hella van Asperen, M. O. Andreae, Alessandro Ara&#250;jo, P. Artaxo, Achim Edtbauer, Ros&#225;ria R. Ferreira, Marco A. Franco, Hartwig Harder, Sam P. Jones, Cl&#233;o Q. Dias-J&#250;nior, Guido G. Haytzmann, Carlos A. Quesada, Shujiro Komiya, Jo&#353;t V. Lavri&#269;, Jos Lelieveld, Ingeborg Levin, A. C. N&#246;lscher, Eva Y. Pfannerstill, Mira L. P&#246;hlker, Ulrich P&#246;schl, Akima Ringsdorf, L. V. Rizzo, Ana Mar&#237;a Y&#225;&#241;ez&#8208;Serrano, Susan Trumbore, Wanda I. D. Valenti, Jordi Vil&#224;-Guerau De Arellano, David Walter, Jonathan Williams, Stefan Wolff, Christopher P&#246;hlker, Atmospheric chemistry and physics. 24(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401544461

                Abstract. This study investigates the rain-initiated mixing and variability in the mixing ratio of selected trace gases in the atmosphere over the central Amazon rain forest. It builds on comprehensive data from the Amazon Tall Tower Observatory (ATTO), spanning from 2013 to 2020 and comprising the greenhouse gases (GHGs) carbon dioxide (CO2) and methane (CH4); the reactive trace gases carbon monoxide (CO), ozone (O3), nitric oxide (NO), and nitrogen dioxide (NO2); and selected volatile organic compounds (VOCs). Based on more than 1000 analyzed rainfall events, the study resolves the trace gas mixing ratio patterns before, during, and after the rain events, along with vertical mixing ratio gradients across the forest canopy. The assessment of the rainfall events was conducted independently for daytime and nighttime periods, which allows us to elucidate the influence of solar radiation. The mixing ratios of CO2, CO, and CH4 clearly declined during rainfall, which can be attributed to the downdraft-related entrainment of pristine air from higher altitudes into the boundary layer, a reduction of the photosynthetic activity under increased cloud cover, and changes in the surface fluxes. Notably, CO showed a faster reduction than CO2, and the vertical gradient of CO2 and CO is steeper than for CH4. Conversely, the O3 mixing ratio increased across all measurement heights in the course of the rain-related downdrafts. Following the O3 enhancement by up to a factor of 2, NO, NO2, and isoprene mixing ratios decreased. The temporal and vertical variability of the trace gases is intricately linked to the diverse sink and source processes, surface fluxes, and free-troposphere transport. Within the canopy, several interactions unfold among soil, atmosphere, and plants, shaping the overall dynamics. Also, the mixing ratio of biogenic VOCs (BVOCs) clearly varied with rainfall, driven by factors such as light, temperature, physical transport, and soil processes. Our results disentangle the patterns in the trace gas mixing ratio in the course of sudden and vigorous atmospheric mixing during rainfall events. By selectively uncovering processes that are not clearly detectable under undisturbed conditions, our results contribute to a better understanding of the trace gas life cycle and its interplay with meteorology, cloud dynamics, and rainfall in the Amazon.</description>
      <author>Luiz A. T. Machado, J. Kesselmeier, Santiago Bot&#237;a, Hella van Asperen, M. O. Andreae, Alessandro Ara&#250;jo, P. Artaxo, Achim Edtbauer, Ros&#225;ria R. Ferreira, Marco A. Franco, Hartwig Harder, Sam P. Jones, Cl&#233;o Q. Dias-J&#250;nior, Guido G. Haytzmann, Carlos A. Quesada, Shujiro Komiya, Jo&#353;t V. Lavri&#269;, Jos Lelieveld, Ingeborg Levin, A. C. N&#246;lscher, Eva Y. Pfannerstill, Mira L. P&#246;hlker, Ulrich P&#246;schl, Akima Ringsdorf, L. V. Rizzo, Ana Mar&#237;a Y&#225;&#241;ez&#8208;Serrano, Susan Trumbore, Wanda I. D. Valenti, Jordi Vil&#224;-Guerau De Arellano, David Walter, Jonathan Williams, Stefan Wolff, Christopher P&#246;hlker</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-8893-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Methane, Carbon Dioxide, and Ammonia Emissions from Stored Pig Slurry Using Bacillus-Biological Additives and Aeration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/environments11080171</link>
      <description>Oumaima El bied, Martire Ang&#233;lica Terrero Turb&#237;, Melisa G&#243;mez Garrido, &#193;ngel Faz Cano, Jos&#233; A. Acosta, Environments. 11(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401510872

                This study delves into the innovative application of a novel bacterial and enzyme mixture alone or combined with aeration in mitigating emissions from pig slurry storage and explores their impacts on the methane (CH4), carbon dioxide (CO2), and ammonia (NH3) emissions from stored pig slurry. A dynamic chamber was used in this research to assess the efficacy of the treatments. Biological additives (HIPO-PUR&#205;N) of specific microbial strains were tested (a mixture ofof Bacillus subtilis, Bacillus megaterium, Bacillus licheniformis, Bacillus amyloliquefacien, and Bacillus thuringiensis) alone and combined with an aeration system (OXI-FUCH). Controlled experiments simulated storage conditions, where emissions of ammonia, methane, and carbon dioxide were measured. By analyzing the results statistically, the treatment with HIPO-PUR&#205;N demonstrated a significant reduction in CH4 emissions by 67% and CO2 emissions by 60% with the use of biological additives, which was increased to 99% and 87%, respectively, when combined with OXI-FUCH aeration, compared to untreated slurry. Ammonia emissions were substantially reduced by 90% with biological additives alone and by 76% when combined with aeration. The study was driven by the need to develop sustainable solutions for livestock waste management, particularly in reducing emissions from pig slurry. It introduces techniques that significantly lower greenhouse gases, aligning with circular economy goals and setting a new standard for sustainable agriculture. Furthermore, there is a need to validate that farmers can independently manage pig slurry using simple and effective treatments techniques with profound environmental benefits, encouraging broader adoption of climate-conscious practices.</description>
      <author>Oumaima El bied, Martire Ang&#233;lica Terrero Turb&#237;, Melisa G&#243;mez Garrido, &#193;ngel Faz Cano, Jos&#233; A. Acosta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/environments11080171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Atom Pairs Stabilize *OCCO Dipole Toward Highly Selective CO2 Electroreduction to C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411591</link>
      <description>Shenghua Chen, Xiaobo Zheng, Peng Zhu, Yapeng Li, Zechao Zhuang, Hangjuan Wu, Jiexin Zhu, Chunhui Xiao, Mingzhao Chen, Pingshan Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Ya&#8208;Ling He, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401526274

                Deeply electrolytic reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) to high&#8208;value ethylene (C2H4) is very attractive. However, the sluggish kinetics of C&#8208;C coupling seriously results in the low selectivity of CO2 electroreduction to C2H4. Herein, we report a copper&#8208;based polyhedron (Cu2) that features uniformly distributed and atomically precise bi&#8208;Cu units, which can stabilize *OCCO dipole to facilitate the C&#8208;C coupling for high selective C2H4 production. The C2H4 faradaic efficiency (FE) reaches 51% with a current density of 469.4 mA cm&#8722;2, much superior to the Cu single site catalyst (Cu SAC) (~0%). Moreover, the Cu2 catalyst has a higher turnover frequency (TOF, ~520 h&#8208;1) compared to Cu nanoparticles (~9.42 h&#8208;1) and Cu SAC (~0.87 h&#8208;1). In situ characterizations and theoretical calculations revealed that the unique Cu2 structural configuration could optimize the dipole moments and stabilize the *OCCO adsorbate to promote the generation of C2H4.</description>
      <author>Shenghua Chen, Xiaobo Zheng, Peng Zhu, Yapeng Li, Zechao Zhuang, Hangjuan Wu, Jiexin Zhu, Chunhui Xiao, Mingzhao Chen, Pingshan Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Ya&#8208;Ling He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Atom Pairs Stabilize *OCCO Dipole Toward Highly Selective CO2 Electroreduction to C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411591</link>
      <description>Shenghua Chen, Xiaoyan Zheng, Peng Zhu, Yapeng Li, Zechao Zhuang, Hangjuan Wu, Jiexin Zhu, Chunhui Xiao, Mingzhao Chen, Pingshan Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Ya&#8208;Ling He, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401526469

                Deeply electrolytic reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) to high&#8208;value ethylene (C2H4) is very attractive. However, the sluggish kinetics of C&#8208;C coupling seriously results in the low selectivity of CO2 electroreduction to C2H4. Herein, we report a copper&#8208;based polyhedron (Cu2) that features uniformly distributed and atomically precise bi&#8208;Cu units, which can stabilize *OCCO dipole to facilitate the C&#8208;C coupling for high selective C2H4 production. The C2H4 faradaic efficiency (FE) reaches 51% with a current density of 469.4 mA cm&#8722;2, much superior to the Cu single site catalyst (Cu SAC) (~0%). Moreover, the Cu2 catalyst has a higher turnover frequency (TOF, ~520 h&#8208;1) compared to Cu nanoparticles (~9.42 h&#8208;1) and Cu SAC (~0.87 h&#8208;1). In situ characterizations and theoretical calculations revealed that the unique Cu2 structural configuration could optimize the dipole moments and stabilize the *OCCO adsorbate to promote the generation of C2H4.</description>
      <author>Shenghua Chen, Xiaoyan Zheng, Peng Zhu, Yapeng Li, Zechao Zhuang, Hangjuan Wu, Jiexin Zhu, Chunhui Xiao, Mingzhao Chen, Pingshan Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Ya&#8208;Ling He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable solutions analysis of a bi-objective green inventory routing problem with heterogeneous fleet and different types of fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/ro/2024162</link>
      <description>Arianne Alves da Silva Mundim, Maristela Oliveira dos Santos, Reinaldo Mor&#225;bito, RAIRO - Operations Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647379

                One of the main agents responsible for global warming is greenhouse gases, especially carbon dioxide (CO2) associated with fuel combustion. Most works in the literature address logistics transportation from an economic perspective, giving little attention to the existing trade-off with sustainability. In this work, we develop a bi-objective approach to the inventory routing problem with heterogeneous fleet, where we minimize costs while simultaneously reducing CO2 emissions. First, we present an explicit vehicular equation developed to calculate CO2 emissions for different types of vehicles and fuels. We demonstrate that this equation is statistically precise by conducting a study with a database in which machine learning techniques were applied to assess the predictive accuracy of CO2 emissions. The comparison between the explicit equation and machine learning models proves its efficacy as a suitable approximation for practical applications. Then, we propose an augmented e-constrained method to find the efficient Pareto frontier using a branch-and-cut method. Computational experiments were conducted on 285 instances, of which 125 were adapted from the literature, solving the augmented e-constrained optimally. Result analysis indicates the ability of the approach to trade off between economy and sustainability, where, on average, lexicographic solutions show a 58% reduction in emissions and a 36% increase in costs. We conclude with a managerial analysis providing insights into the proposed approach, highlighting the advantages of using different vehicles and fuels.</description>
      <author>Arianne Alves da Silva Mundim, Maristela Oliveira dos Santos, Reinaldo Mor&#225;bito</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/ro/2024162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Response of babassu coconut shell and a&#231;ai biochar on soil attributes and gas emission</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56238/sevened2024.023-008</link>
      <description>Alexander Meneses&#8208;J&#225;come, L&#237;dia de Sousa, Alan Teixeira Alves, Matteus Silva, Hellen Patr&#237;cia Lemos Cordovil, Leane Castro de Souza, Luma Castro de Souza, Raphael Leone Cruz Ferreira, C&#226;ndido Ferreira de Oliveira Neto, Kamila Cunha de Meneses, Nilvan Carvalho Melo, Fl&#225;vio Jos&#233; Rodrigues Cruz, Seven Editora eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401669857

                Biochar from waste produced by pyrolysis benefits soil fertility, increases water and nutrient retention and reduces greenhouse gas emissions, promoting more sustainable agricultural practices. Thus, the objective of this study was to investigate the benefits of biochar produced from babassu and a&#231;a&#237; coconut shells on the physical, chemical and biological attributes of the soil, as well as on the mitigation of greenhouse gas emissions. A comprehensive literature review was carried out, exploring articles and books in scientific databases. The results showed that the biochar of babassu coconut shells and a&#231;a&#237; have significant impacts on the soil. In terms of soil attributes, an increase in water retention capacity, improvement in soil structure and an increase in the availability of essential nutrients for plants were observed. In addition, there was a reduction in the emission of gases such as carbon dioxide-CO2, methane-CH4 and nitrous oxide-N2O, important greenhouse gases, indicating the potential of biochar in mitigating climate change when incorporated into agricultural practices.</description>
      <author>Alexander Meneses&#8208;J&#225;come, L&#237;dia de Sousa, Alan Teixeira Alves, Matteus Silva, Hellen Patr&#237;cia Lemos Cordovil, Leane Castro de Souza, Luma Castro de Souza, Raphael Leone Cruz Ferreira, C&#226;ndido Ferreira de Oliveira Neto, Kamila Cunha de Meneses, Nilvan Carvalho Melo, Fl&#225;vio Jos&#233; Rodrigues Cruz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56238/sevened2024.023-008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide induced cerebral vasomotor reactivity in moderate-to-severe cerebral venous thrombosis patients and its impact on prognosis: A transcranial doppler-based prospective exploratory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jocn.2024.110779</link>
      <description>Prachi Sharma, Radhakrishnan Muthuchellappan, Suparna Bharadwaj, Dhritiman Chakrabarti, Priya Baby, Pritam Raja, Abhinith Shashidhar, Alok Mohan Uppar, Journal of Clinical Neuroscience. 128(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401536133

                Hyperventilation-induced intracranial pressure reduction might be impaired in cerebral venous thrombosis (CVT) patients. Using transcranial Doppler, we assessed carbon dioxide-vasomotor reactivity (CO</description>
      <author>Prachi Sharma, Radhakrishnan Muthuchellappan, Suparna Bharadwaj, Dhritiman Chakrabarti, Priya Baby, Pritam Raja, Abhinith Shashidhar, Alok Mohan Uppar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jocn.2024.110779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dynamic spatial effects of education investment on carbon emissions: heterogeneous analysis based on north-south differences in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenvs.2024.1432457</link>
      <description>Yuming Dong, Jialin Gao, Qiu Jian-yu, Yiniu Cui, Mengyao Guo, Frontiers in Environmental Science. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401590158

                This article is based on panel data from 266 cities in China from 2009 to 2020. Classical economics theory and Marxist political economy theory are used as the theoretical basis for the study. Static spatial Durbin model regression and dynamic spatial Durbin model regression are conducted to analyze the impact of education investment on carbon dioxide emissions. The results show that education investment can significantly reduce carbon dioxide emissions, not only through spatial spillover effects, but also through dynamic effects over time. The implementation of education investment in one city can have a positive impact on surrounding cities, thereby achieving a certain degree of reduction in carbon emissions. Additionally, the inhibitory effect of education investment on carbon emissions is more significant in the short term. Furthermore, the study found that there is significant heterogeneity in the effect of education investment on carbon dioxide emissions between northern and southern cities, with education investment in southern cities having a more significant effect. This may be related to the industrial structure and climate of southern cities. The conclusions of this study provide useful reference for the development of education policies and environmental protection policies. In the future, the government can increase education investment appropriately to achieve the goal of reducing carbon dioxide emissions. And research has shown that education investment can suppress carbon emissions by influencing changes in energy and industrial structures. Therefore, when using measures to reduce emissions in education investment, we can focus on these two aspects.</description>
      <author>Yuming Dong, Jialin Gao, Qiu Jian-yu, Yiniu Cui, Mengyao Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenvs.2024.1432457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The iron nitrogenase reduces carbon dioxide to formate and methane under physiological conditions: A route to feedstock chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado7729</link>
      <description>Niels N. Oehlmann, Frederik V. Schmidt, M Herzog, Annelise L. Goldman, Johannes G. Rebelein, Science Advances. 10(33)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401567175

                Nitrogenases are the only known enzymes that reduce molecular nitrogen (N 2 ) to ammonia. Recent findings have demonstrated that nitrogenases also reduce the greenhouse gas carbon dioxide (CO 2 ), suggesting CO 2 to be a competitor of N 2 . However, the impact of omnipresent CO 2 on N 2 fixation has not been investigated to date. Here, we study the competing reduction of CO 2 and N 2 by the two nitrogenases of Rhodobacter capsulatus , the molybdenum and the iron nitrogenase. The iron nitrogenase is almost threefold more efficient in CO 2 reduction and profoundly less selective for N 2 than the molybdenum isoform under mixtures of N 2 and CO 2 . Correspondingly, the growth rate of diazotrophically grown R. capsulatus strains relying on the iron nitrogenase notably decreased after adding CO 2 . The in vivo CO 2 activity of the iron nitrogenase facilitates the light-driven extracellular accumulation of formate and methane, one-carbon substrates for other microbes, and feedstock chemicals for a circular economy.</description>
      <author>Niels N. Oehlmann, Frederik V. Schmidt, M Herzog, Annelise L. Goldman, Johannes G. Rebelein</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado7729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphate Fertilization Without Pasture Burning Increase Biomass Productivity and Reduce Carbon Loss</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24857/rgsa.v18n4-179</link>
      <description>Luiz Carlos da Silva, Francisco de Almeida Lobo, Revista de Gest&#227;o Social e Ambiental. 18(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401575936

                Objective: In this work we evaluate the phosphorus fertilization without burning on the biomass productivity and the reduction of carbon loss from the pasture of Brachiaria brizantha in the Brazilian Amazon. Theoretical Framework: Brachiaria brizantha is the main cultivated pasture species in Brazil. The overgrazing and no nutrient replenishment in addition to the periodical burnings are the trigger factors of a gradual degradation since the 70&#8217;s in the Amazon. That fact suggests the need for research solutions to eliminate the use of this practice for pasture management. Method: A field experiment was carried out from September to November 2015 in a completely randomized blocks design. The treatments consisted of unburned pasture treated with 0, 25, 100 and 200 kg ha-1 of phosphorus compared to the pasture burning, with 4 blocks and 20 experimental plots. The experimental plots treated with phosphorus received agronomic doses of potassium and nitrogen applied on the soil surface. After applying the treatments, including the burning, the pasture was desiccated in order to homogenize the plant emergence and growth after the period without rain from July to September. Results and Discussion: The soil fertility attributes, components of biomass productivity, partial carbon stocks and the partial carbon retained in the pasture (not lost as carbon dioxide) were quantified at 56 days after the beggining of the experimental period. In comparison to the pasture burning, the treatments alter the soil phosphorus availability and, as a result, increase the partial biomass productivity and its carbon content, reducing the loss of carbon dioxide to the atmosphere. Research Implications: The practical and theoretical implications of this research are discussed, providing insights into how the results can be applied or influence practices in the field of pasture management without fire using. These implications could encompass on how to apply and how much of an alternative phosphate must be applied to the soil in order to supply phosphorus for B. brizantha instead of using fire as a strategy of pasture management. Originality/Value: This study contributes to the literature by highlighting the superiority of phosphorus application from alternative source allied to N and K fertilization compared to the pasture burning practice in the Southwestern Amazon. This innovative approach can be used as a base for new researches and applied in the level of cattle farmers.</description>
      <author>Luiz Carlos da Silva, Francisco de Almeida Lobo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24857/rgsa.v18n4-179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADEQUACY OF GREEN OPEN SPACE TO REDUCE CARBON DIOXIDE (CO2) AT UNESA CAMPUS JL. KETINTANG, SURABAYA, INDONESIA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26740/jggp.v22n1.p35-42</link>
      <description>Muzayanah Muzayanah, Eko Hariyadi Budiyanto, Nugroho Hari Purnomo, Bambang Hariyanto, JURNAL GEOGRAFI Geografi dan Pengajarannya. 22(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401681792

                Academic activity at the Unesa Ketintang Campus Surabaya Indonesia, to some extent, contributed to the increase of CO2 concentration in Surabaya City. The increase in CO2 concentration can be balanced by green open space. This study aims to determine the adequacy of green open space in Unesa Ketintang Street Campus in reducing CO2 in ambient air. The analysis unit uses a box model. The observation was carried out for six days in July-August 2021. The adequacy of green open space uses the CO2 reduction value (Net_CO2-Con), an indicator of reducing CO2 concentrations. Net_CO2-Con value is the cumulative concentration of CO2 in the surrounding air for 24 hours. The study results show that from 7 observation points, the average CO2 concentration ranges from 417 &#8211; 425 ppmV. The CO2 concentration reduction value (Net_CO2-Con) ranges from -19.46 to -87.69 ppmV. The minus sign (-) on the reduction value indicates that the green open space on the Unesa Campus is sufficient to reduce the CO2 concentration in the ambient air.</description>
      <author>Muzayanah Muzayanah, Eko Hariyadi Budiyanto, Nugroho Hari Purnomo, Bambang Hariyanto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26740/jggp.v22n1.p35-42</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Synergistic Drivers of CO2 and NOX Emissions from Thermal Power Generating Units in Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei, 2010-2020</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.0134.v1</link>
      <description>Yaolin Wang, Zilin Yuan, Haixu Zhang, Qingsong Guan, Shengxiang Rao, Chunlai Jiang, Zhongxia Duan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401589512

                Synergistic control of emissions of air pollutants and CO2 is critical to the dual challenges of air quality improvement and climate change in China. Based on the emission inventories of thermal power units in Beijing, Tianjin, and Hebei, this study analyzes the CO2 and NOX emission characteristics of these units, identifies and quantifies the synergistic drivers affecting these emission trends. Inventory data show that between 2010 and 2020, NOX emissions were reduced by 86.1%, while CO2 emissions were reduced by only 29.8%. Although significant progress has been made in reducing NOX emissions through measures such as end-of-pipe treatment, controlling CO2 emissions remains a difficult task. The index decomposition analysis reveals that economic growth is the main driver of CO2 and NOx emission growth, energy intensity reduction is the main driver of CO2 emission reduction, and end-of-pipe treatment is the main driver of NOX emission reduction. Currently, coal occupies about 87% of the energy consumption of thermal power units in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei, and remains the main type of energy for synergistic emissions, and the potential for emission reduction in the energy structure remains huge. For NOX emissions, it is expected that 90% of the reduction potential can be achieved through energy restructuring and end-of-pipe treatment. In conclusion, the high-precision unit-by-unit emission study confirms the effectiveness of the control policy for thermal power units in the region and provides some scientific reference for future policy formulation.</description>
      <author>Yaolin Wang, Zilin Yuan, Haixu Zhang, Qingsong Guan, Shengxiang Rao, Chunlai Jiang, Zhongxia Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.0134.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Microenvironment Tailoring Strategies of Atomically Dispersed Dual&#8208;Site Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407974</link>
      <description>Shiqing Huang, F K Lin, Shitao Wang, Xiaofei Zeng, Hao Ling, Xiayi Hu, Zhigang Shen, Dapeng Cao, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401658727

                Abstract Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) with atomically dispersed dual&#8208;sites, as an extension of single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs), have recently become a new hot topic in heterogeneous catalysis due to their maximized atom efficiency and dual&#8208;site diverse synergy, because the synergistic diversity of dual&#8208;sites achieved by asymmetric microenvironment tailoring can efficiently boost the catalytic activity by optimizing the electronic structure of DACs. Here, this work first summarizes the frequently&#8208;used experimental synthesis and characterization methods of DACs. Then, four synergistic catalytic mechanisms (cascade mechanism, assistance mechanism, co&#8208;adsorption mechanism and bifunction mechanism) and four key modulating methods (active site asymmetric strategy, transverse/axial&#8208;modification engineering, distance engineering and strain engineering) are elaborated comprehensively. The emphasis is placed on the effects of asymmetric microenvironment of DACs on oxygen/carbon dioxide reduction reaction. Finally, some perspectives and outlooks are also addressed. In short, the review summarizes a useful asymmetric microenvironment tailoring strategy to speed up synthesis of high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts for different reactions.</description>
      <author>Shiqing Huang, F K Lin, Shitao Wang, Xiaofei Zeng, Hao Ling, Xiayi Hu, Zhigang Shen, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Air Capture: Economy and Technical Cost of Low-Purity CO2 on Post-Capture Operating Cost</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4314/fuoyejet.v9i2.19</link>
      <description>Luqman K. Abidoye, FUOYE Journal of Engineering and Technology. 9(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401611181

                Direct air capture has the potential to capture from innumerable random, mobile and immobile small-scale carbon-emission sources. In this study, simulations result of Direct Air Capture (DAC) reveal the isentropic compression work increases as the mole fraction of CO2 decreases in the stream. At the same depth of sequestration, compression power requirement increases by 20% to sequestrate 10% CO2 stream compared to pure CO2. Also, sequestration at deeper geological layer further raises the power cost of the compression by approximately 14% from 1000 to 1500m and by almost 32% from 1500m to 2500m depth, for pure CO2. This increases to around 34% for storage at 2500m with 50% CO2 mole fraction and 36% for 20% CO2 fraction at the same depth. Similarly, the cost of cooling compressed CO2 increases in proportion to the reduction in CO2 mole fraction in the gas stream. It was shown that the solution density increase with impurities as a result of falling pH in the presence of N2 and O2.</description>
      <author>Luqman K. Abidoye</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4314/fuoyejet.v9i2.19</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing d/p&#8208;2&#960;* Orbitals Hybridization via Strain Engineering for Efficient Photoreduction CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411794</link>
      <description>Guosheng Zhou, Xinlin Liu, Yangrui Xu, Sheng Feng, Ziyang Lu, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401554689

                The photoconversion of CO2 into valuable chemical products using solar energy is a promising strategy to address both energy and environmental challenges. However, the strongly adsorbed CO2 frequently impedes the seamless advancement of the subsequent reaction by significantly increasing the reaction activation energy. Here, we present a BiFeO3 material with lattice strain that collaboratively regulates the d/p&#8208;2&#960;* orbitals hybridization between metal sites and *CO2 as well as *COOH intermediates to achieve rapid conversion of solidly adsorbed CO2 to critical *COOH intermediates, accelerating the overall CO2 reduction kinetics. Quasi in&#8208;situ X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and in&#8208;situ Fourier Transform infrared spectroscopy combined with theoretical calculation reveals that the optimized Fe sites enhance the adsorption and activation effect of CO2, and continuous internal electrons are rapidly transferred to the reaction sites and injected into the surface *CO2 and *COOH under the condition of illumination, which promotes the rapid formation and stability of *COOH. Certainly, the performance of CO2 photoreduction to CO is improved by 12.81&#8208;fold compared with the base material. This work offers a new perspective for the rapid photoreduction process of strongly adsorbed CO2.</description>
      <author>Guosheng Zhou, Xinlin Liu, Yangrui Xu, Sheng Feng, Ziyang Lu, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411794</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing d/p&#8208;2&#960;* Orbitals Hybridization via Strain Engineering for Efficient Photoreduction CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411794</link>
      <description>Guosheng Zhou, Xinlin Liu, Yangrui Xu, Sheng Feng, Ziyang Lu, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401554600

                The photoconversion of CO2 into valuable chemical products using solar energy is a promising strategy to address both energy and environmental challenges. However, the strongly adsorbed CO2 frequently impedes the seamless advancement of the subsequent reaction by significantly increasing the reaction activation energy. Here, we present a BiFeO3 material with lattice strain that collaboratively regulates the d/p&#8208;2&#960;* orbitals hybridization between metal sites and *CO2 as well as *COOH intermediates to achieve rapid conversion of solidly adsorbed CO2 to critical *COOH intermediates, accelerating the overall CO2 reduction kinetics. Quasi in&#8208;situ X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and in&#8208;situ Fourier Transform infrared spectroscopy combined with theoretical calculation reveals that the optimized Fe sites enhance the adsorption and activation effect of CO2, and continuous internal electrons are rapidly transferred to the reaction sites and injected into the surface *CO2 and *COOH under the condition of illumination, which promotes the rapid formation and stability of *COOH. Certainly, the performance of CO2 photoreduction to CO is improved by 12.81&#8208;fold compared with the base material. This work offers a new perspective for the rapid photoreduction process of strongly adsorbed CO2.</description>
      <author>Guosheng Zhou, Xinlin Liu, Yangrui Xu, Sheng Feng, Ziyang Lu, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411794</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosted Solar Thermochemical Low&#8208;temperature CO2 Splitting On Pt/CeO2 By Interface Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401295</link>
      <description>Teng Zong, Qianqian Shen, Yujia Han, Chongyan Ruan, Haibo Liu, Sheng Wang, Mingwei Tian, Ning Li, Yanyan Zhu, Xinming Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647596

                Solar thermochemical CO2 splitting using metal oxides is considered as a promising approach to produce solar fuels since it is capable to tap abundant sunlight directly and store solar energy in the renewable fuel. It remains a grand challenge to achieve highly efficient CO2 splitting at low temperature (&lt;800 oC) due to insufficient activation of metal oxides for CO2.Herein, the introduction of a small amount of Pt was found to be able to greatly increase the performance of CO2 splitting with the highest peak CO production rate of about 65 mL min&#8208;1 g&#8208;1, CO productivity of about 53 mL g&#8208;1, nearly 100% CO2 conversion and long&#8208;term stability for 0.5Pt/CeO2 which exceeded most of the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art transition metals&#8208;based oxides even at lower temperature (700 oC). This could be attributed to the addition of Pt leading to the formation of an interface (Pt0&#8208;Ov&#8208;Ce3+) after CH4 reduction, which improved CO2 activation and dissociation due to beneficial breakage of C=O bond by the cooperation of Pt0 and oxygen vacancies in the interface.</description>
      <author>Teng Zong, Qianqian Shen, Yujia Han, Chongyan Ruan, Haibo Liu, Sheng Wang, Mingwei Tian, Ning Li, Yanyan Zhu, Xinming Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Optimal Transition of an Urban Neighborhood towards an Energy Community and a Positive Energy District</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17164047</link>
      <description>Diego Viesi, Gregorio Borelli, Silvia Ricciuti, Giovanni Pernigotto, Md Shahriar Mahbub, Energies. 17(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401618776

                Building renovation is a key initiative to promote energy efficiency, the integration of renewable energy sources (RESs), and a reduction in CO2 emissions. Supporting these goals, emerging research is dedicated to energy communities and positive energy districts. In this work, an urban neighborhood of six buildings in Trento (Italy) is considered. Firstly, the six buildings are modeled with the Urban Modeling Interface tool to evaluate the energy performances in 2024 and 2050, also accounting for the different climatic conditions for these two time periods. Energy demands for space heating, domestic hot water, space cooling, electricity, and transport are computed. Then, EnergyPLAN coupled with a multi-objective evolutionary algorithm is used to investigate 12 different energy decarbonization scenarios in 2024 and 2050 based on different boundaries for RESs, energy storage, hydrogen, energy system integration, and energy community incentives. Two conflicting objectives are considered: cost and CO2 emission reductions. The results show, on the one hand, the key role of sector coupling technologies such as heat pumps and electric vehicles in exploiting local renewables and, on the other hand, the higher costs in introducing both electricity storage to approach complete decarbonization and hydrogen as an alternative strategy in the electricity, thermal, and transport sectors. As an example of the quantitative valuable finding of this work, in scenario S1 &#8220;all sectors and EC incentive&#8221; for the year 2024, a large reduction of 55% of CO2 emissions with a modest increase of 11% of the total annual cost is identified along the Pareto front.</description>
      <author>Diego Viesi, Gregorio Borelli, Silvia Ricciuti, Giovanni Pernigotto, Md Shahriar Mahbub</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17164047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IS CORPORATE SOCIAL RESPONSIBILITY A TOOL USED BY COMPANIES TO ENHANCE THEIR REPUTATION OR A CONTRIBUTION TO SUSTAINABILITY?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31435/rsglobal_ijite/30092024/8211</link>
      <description>Aysel Eminova, International Journal of Innovative Technologies in Economy. None(3(47))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401662104

                Sustainable development, corporate social responsibility and social sustainability, joint efforts for the benefit of society, reduction of carbon dioxide emissions are among the most discussed topics in modern economic literature and articles. Events, discussions and debates are held in this direction. Companies, regardless of size, join this trend and try to make CSR a major part of their strategy. The group of companies really does it and strives to take care of their employees, their families, other stakeholders and society as a whole, and does it with a true sense of social responsibility. Their only goal is to improve the social well-being of their employees, create equal, comfortable working conditions, provide social comfort in society and transmit positive energy. This can be considered an activity that has achieved its goal.On the other hand, some companies approach this work as a part of their marketing activities only to raise their reputation. Sometimes they use CSR to attract customers and partners who are sensitive to sustainable development and the environment, sometimes to increase the attractiveness of their brand, sometimes to avoid sanctions imposed by the government.The real value of CSR lies in honest intent and a long-term commitment to doing the right thing. Transparency, consistency and a focus on measurable impact are key. When businesses approach CSR with integrity, they not only improve their reputation, but also play a vital role in creating a sustainable and fair world for all.</description>
      <author>Aysel Eminova</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31435/rsglobal_ijite/30092024/8211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determination of the Diffusion Coefficients of Binary CH4 and C2H6 in a Supercritical CO2 Environment (500&#8211;2000 K and 100&#8211;1000 atm) by Molecular Dynamics Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17164028</link>
      <description>Chun&#8208;Hung Wang, K. R. V. Manikantachari, Art&#235;m E. Masunov, Subith Vasu, Energies. 17(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401584565

                The self-diffusion coefficients of carbonaceous fuels in a supercritical CO2 environment provide transport information that can help us understand the Allam Cycle mechanism at a high pressure of 300 atm. The diffusion coefficients of pure CO2 and binary CO2/CH4 and CO2/C2H6 at high temperatures (500 K~2000 K) and high pressures (100 atm~1000 atm) are determined by molecular dynamics simulations in this study. Increasing the temperature leads to an increase in the diffusion coefficient, and increasing the pressure leads to a decrease in the diffusion coefficients for both methane and ethane. The diffusion coefficient of methane at 300 atm is approximately 0.012 cm2/s at 1000 K and 0.032 cm2/s at 1500 K. The diffusion coefficient of ethane at 300 atm is approximately 0.016 cm2/s at 1000 K and 0.045 cm2/s at 1500 K. The understanding of diffusion coefficients potentially leads to the reduction in fuel consumption and minimization of greenhouse gas emissions in the Allam Cycle.</description>
      <author>Chun&#8208;Hung Wang, K. R. V. Manikantachari, Art&#235;m E. Masunov, Subith Vasu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17164028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emission Inventory of Central Processing Plant in the Oil and Gas Industry in Central Sulawesi</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59188/devotion.v5i7.758</link>
      <description>Achmad Alvinsyah Rasyidi, Arie Dipareza Syafei, Joni Hermana, Abdu F. Assomadi, Devotion Journal of Research and Community Service. 5(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401512240

                The Central Processing Plant (CPP) in Central Sulawesi, Indonesia, is one of the largest oil and gas industries in the world. This study aims to determine the magnitude of the greenhouse gas emission load and identify the operational facilities that produce the highest GHG emissions from CPP Donggi. The study results show an emission inventory for 2021 is 7.609ton CO2-eq per year or 365.78 tonnes of CO2 per TJ in 2021, for 2022 is 8.084ton C2Eq/355.50 tonnes CO2/TJ, and dan for 2023 is 7.565ton. The three highest carbon emission-generating facilities are the Gas Turbine Generator, Acid Gas Removal Unit, and Oil Heater. The research contributes to understanding the scale and distribution of greenhouse gas emissions from a specific industrial source and aids in directing efforts for emission reduction.</description>
      <author>Achmad Alvinsyah Rasyidi, Arie Dipareza Syafei, Joni Hermana, Abdu F. Assomadi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59188/devotion.v5i7.758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Policies and Countermeasures for the Phase-Out of Ozone-Depleting Substances (ODSs) over the Last 30 Years: A Case Study in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15080961</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Tien Tsai, Atmosphere. 15(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401583992

                It is well established that the reaction cycles involving some halogenated alkanes (so-called ozone-depleting substances&#8212;ODSs) contribute to the depletion of ozone in the stratosphere, prompting the Montreal Protocol (initially signed in 1987), and later amendments. The Protocol called for the scheduled phase-out of ODSs, including chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs), hydrochlorofluorocarbons (HCFCs), carbon tetrachloride (CCl4), halon, methyl chloroform (CH3CCl3), methyl chloride (CH3Cl), and even hydrofluorocarbons (HFCs). In view of the urgent importance of ozone layer protection to the global ecological environment, the Taiwanese government has taken regulatory actions to reduce ODS consumption since 1993, through the joint venture of the central competent authorities. Under the government&#8217;s regulatory requirements, and the industry&#8217;s efforts to adopt both alternatives to ODSs and abatement technologies, the phase-out of some ODSs (i.e., CFCs, CCl4, halon, and CH3CCl3) was achieved prior to 2010. The consumption of HCFCs and methyl chloride has significantly declined over the past three decades (1993&#8211;2022). However, HFC emissions indicated a V-type variation during this period. Due to local production and extensive use of HFCs in Taiwan, the country&#8217;s emissions increased from 663 kilotons of carbon dioxide equivalents (CO2eq) in 1993 to 2330 kilotons of CO2eq in 2001, and then decreased to 373 kilotons of CO2eq in 2011. Since then, the emissions of HFCs largely used as the alternatives to ODSs showed an upward trend, increasing to 1555 kilotons of CO2eq in 2022. To be in compliance with the Kigali Amendment (KA-2015) to the Montreal Protocol for mitigating global warming, the Taiwanese government has taken regulatory actions to reduce the consumption of some HFC substances with high global warming potential (GWP) under the authorization of the Climate Change Response Act in 2023, aiming at an 80% reduction by 2045 of the baseline consumption in 2024.</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Tien Tsai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15080961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring high catalytic performances of Cu-Co-O/N-doped carbon materials toward hydrogenation reduction and advanced oxidation reactions of 4-nitrophenol (PNP)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj02430c</link>
      <description>Pingyun Li, Shi&#8208;Yu Huang, Yanchao Shen, Yadan Wang, Xiaode Guo, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401549447

                This work reports high catalytic performances of Cu-Co-O/N-doped carbon materials toward hydrogenation reduction and advanced oxidation reaction of 4-nitrophenol (PNP). By incorporation Cu2+ and Co2+ with atomic ratio ranging from...</description>
      <author>Pingyun Li, Shi&#8208;Yu Huang, Yanchao Shen, Yadan Wang, Xiaode Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj02430c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of building carbon emission based on grey Markov theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2753-8818/40/20240222</link>
      <description>Chenhao Zhao, Theoretical and Natural Science. 40(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401589743

                The increase in carbon emissions in the construction industry is one of the factors that lead to environmental problems and hinder the sustainable development of society and the construction industry. Therefore, there is an urgent need to rationally control carbon emissions by formulating scientific and effective energy-saving and emission reduction policies so as to safeguard the development of the industry. However, because of the uncertainty and complexity of CO2 emissions, more reliable prediction and assessment tools are needed to comprehensively analyze and predict CO2 emissions. This study combines the gray system theory and Markov principle to give full play to the advantages of the two methods, using Markov theory to determine the state transition probability, find out the characteristics of carbon emissions in the construction industry, and form a suitable gray Markov prediction model. The feasibility of the prediction model is demonstrated by calculating and examining the prediction model using data related to carbon emissions from the U.S. buildings from 2002 to 2022, which greatly improves the accuracy of CO2 emissions prediction.</description>
      <author>Chenhao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2753-8818/40/20240222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degradation of biorefractory compounds by anodic oxidation on Magn&#233;li phase and electro-Fenton process </title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4773662/v1</link>
      <description>Imane Ouagued, Stella Lacour, Eddy Petit, A. Djafer, Abdellah Ouagued, Marc Cretin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647924

                Abstract The degradation of Rhodamine B (RhB) was studied using advanced electrochemical oxidation processes (EAOP): electro-Fenton (EF), anodic oxidation (AO) and electro-Fenton coupled with anodic oxidation (EF/AO) on a carbon felt (CF) cathode paired with either a sub-stoichiometric titanium dioxide Magn&#233;li phase (Ti4O7) anode or a platinized titanium (Ti/Pt) anode. The study revealed that operating conditions significantly impacted the kinetics of electrochemical reactions. Increasing the current density from 10 to 50 mA cm&#8722; 2 significantly accelerated the degradation of RhB, with 30 mA cm&#8722; 2 identified as the optimal current density, balancing energy consumption and degradation efficiency. The RhB concentration also influenced the degradation kinetics: higher concentrations required longer treatment times. The EF/AO coupling process proved particularly effective in degrading higher concentrations of RhB. Toxicity evaluation using the Microtox&#174; bioluminescence inhibition test showed reduced toxicity during the electrochemical degradation of the pollutant, with EF/AO presenting the most significant reduction. The EF/AO coupling also demonstrated superior total organic carbon (TOC) removal, reaching 90% at pH 3 compared to EF and AO alone, suggesting efficient mineralization of RhB and its by-products. Energy consumption (EC) remained relatively stable across all processes during a 480 min electrolysis period. High-resolution mass spectrometry confirmed the degradation pathways of RhB, involving chain oxidation reactions leading to the formation of intermediate products and mineralization to CO2 and H2O. This study demonstrates the potential of EF, AO and EF/AO coupling as effective methods for mineralizing Rhodamine B (RhB) from wastewater, contributing to sustainable and environmentally friendly wastewater treatment strategies.</description>
      <author>Imane Ouagued, Stella Lacour, Eddy Petit, A. Djafer, Abdellah Ouagued, Marc Cretin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4773662/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compound soil and atmospheric drought (CSAD) events and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; fluxes of a mixed deciduous forest: the occurrence, impact, and temporal contribution of main drivers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-3571-2024</link>
      <description>Liliana Scapucci, Ankit Shekhar, Sergio Aranda-Barranco, Anastasiia Bolshakova, Lukas H&#246;rtnagl, Mana Gharun, Nina Buchmann, Biogeosciences. 21(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401548483

                Abstract. With global warming, forests are increasingly exposed to &#8220;compound soil and atmospheric drought&#8221; (CSAD) events, characterized by low soil water content (SWC) and high vapour pressure deficit (VPD). Such CSAD events trigger responses in both ecosystem and forest-floor CO2 fluxes, which we know little about. In this study, we used multi-year daily and daytime above-canopy (18 years; 2005&#8211;2022) and daily forest-floor (5 years; 2018&#8211;2022) eddy covariance CO2 fluxes from a Swiss forest site by the name of CH-Lae (a mixed deciduous montane forest). The objectives were (1) to characterize CSAD events at CH-Lae, (2) to quantify the impact of CSAD events on ecosystem and forest-floor CO2 fluxes, and (3) to identify the major drivers and their temporal contributions to changing ecosystem and forest-floor CO2 fluxes during CSAD events and CSAD growing seasons. Our results showed that the growing seasons of 2015, 2018, and 2022 were the three driest at CH-Lae since 2005 (referred to as the CSAD years), exhibiting similar intensity and duration of the CSAD events but considerably different pre-drought conditions. The CSAD events reduced daily mean net ecosystem productivity (NEP) in all 3 CSAD years by about 38 % compared to the long-term mean, with the highest reduction observed during 2022 (41 %). This reduction in daily mean NEP was largely due to decreased gross primary productivity (GPP; &gt; 16 % below the long-term mean) rather than increased ecosystem respiration (Reco) during CSAD events. Furthermore, forest-floor respiration (Rff) decreased during the CSAD events in 2018 and 2022 (with no measurements in 2015), with a larger reduction in 2022 (41 %) than in 2018 (16 %), relative to the long-term mean (2019&#8211;2021). Using data-driven machine learning methods, we identified the major drivers of NEP and Rff during CSAD events. While daytime mean NEP (NEPDT) during the 2015 and 2018 CSAD events was limited by VPD and SWC, respectively, NEPDT during the 2022 CSAD event was strongly limited by both SWC and VPD. Air temperature had negative effects, while net radiation showed positive effects on NEPDT during all CSAD events. Daily mean Rff during the 2018 CSAD event was driven by soil temperature and SWC but was severely limited by SWC during the 2022 CSAD event. We found that a multi-layer analysis of CO2 fluxes in forests is necessary to better understand forest responses to CSAD events, particularly if the first signs of NEP acclimation to CSAD events &#8211; evident in our forest &#8211; are also found elsewhere. We conclude that CSAD events have multiple drivers with different temporal contributions, making predictions about site-specific CSAD events and long-term forest responses to such conditions more challenging.</description>
      <author>Liliana Scapucci, Ankit Shekhar, Sergio Aranda-Barranco, Anastasiia Bolshakova, Lukas H&#246;rtnagl, Mana Gharun, Nina Buchmann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-3571-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASSESSMENT OF THE MECHANICAL AND ENVIRONMENTAL PROPERTIES OF CONCRETES WITH HIGH LEVELS OF LIME FILLER AND FLY ASH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29183/2447-3073.mix2024.v10.n3.195-211</link>
      <description>Silvane Santos da Silva, Andr&#233; L&#252;beck, Geraldo Cechella Isaia, Gustavo Aguiar Isaia, Almir Barros da Silva Santos Neto, MIX Sustent&#225;vel. 10(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401679840

                This study evaluated the possibility of producing high strength concrete (HSC) by replacing Portland cement (PC) with high levels of limestone filler (LF) in binary mixtures and ternary mixtures of PC, LF and fly ash (FA) in contents varying from 50 % to 80 %, with the objective of reducing CO2 emissions during manufacture. Parameters evaluated were axial compression strength, CO2 emissions of the constituent materials and cost per m&#179; of concrete with focus on reductions in environmental impact. Results indicated the possibility of producing HSC with high LF and FA contents, reduced water/binder content (w/b = 0.25) and workability of 100 mm &#177; 20 mm through particle packaging and the use of a superplasticizer additive. The resulting concrete had axial compression strength of 51.8 MPa at 91 days with 77 kgco2/m3 of concrete for a mixture with 80 % of PC replaced with 70 % LF and 10 % FA. These amounts corresponded to the use of only 97 kg/m3 of PC (87 kg/m3 of clinker) and 104 L/m3 of water. Thus, it was demonstrated to be possible to obtain a HSC with fck of up to 80 MPa and low CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Silvane Santos da Silva, Andr&#233; L&#252;beck, Geraldo Cechella Isaia, Gustavo Aguiar Isaia, Almir Barros da Silva Santos Neto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29183/2447-3073.mix2024.v10.n3.195-211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Carbonation of Steel Slags Through Concurrent Wet Milling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40831-024-00895-2</link>
      <description>Anthony de Schutter, Luka Ceyssens, Giuseppe Granata, Tom Van Gerven, Journal of Sustainable Metallurgy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401510092

                Abstract This work studies mineral carbonation of steel slags with the aim to reduce the amount of slag that is landfilled. Besides permanently storing carbon dioxide (CO 2 ), carbonating the slags can improve their quality for use in beneficial applications and reduces the leaching of harmful heavy metals. In order to intensify the mineral carbonation process, mechanical activation is used to improve both the carbonation kinetics and yield. The milling is performed in a planetary ball mill which allows for high-intensity grinding, resulting in a fast reduction of the particle size and quick amorphization and disturbance of the crystal structure, allowing high reaction rates to be achieved. The effects of the three main processing parameters of a planetary ball mill&#8212;bead-to-powder ratio $$R$$  R  , bead size $$D$$  D  and milling speed $$S$$  S  &#8212;are investigated. Under optimal conditions, more than 50% of the maximum CO 2 uptake is achieved in only 6 min, representing a very significant improvement over regular slurry carbonation. Quantitative XRD allows to identify the reactivity of the different crystalline phases present in the slag under different milling conditions. With the help of a mass balance, the formation of an inert outer layer consisting of silica (SiO 2 ) is confirmed. This explains both the shell diffusion mechanism controlling the carbonation reaction and the total conversion being limited to 50&#8211;60%. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Anthony de Schutter, Luka Ceyssens, Giuseppe Granata, Tom Van Gerven</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40831-024-00895-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The carbon emission reduction effect of China&#8217;s national high-tech industrial development zones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-69753-1</link>
      <description>Zhong Shen, Yaqian Wu, Junzhi Li, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401654987

                The double carbon goal is a wide and profound economic and social systematic change. It is also crucial to China's sustainable development. How to promote emission reduction, the National High-Tech Industrial Development Zones(NHTDZs) policy is the key to addressing this problem. Based on urban data from 2003 to 2019 from China, this paper uses the multi-time point asymptotic difference method to explore the impact of the NHTDZs establishment on carbon emissions. The establishment of NHTDZs reduces CO2 emissions, which remains valid through robustness tests. The mechanism analysis demonstrated that the construction of NHTDZs reduces CO2 emissions by increasing innovation levels, increasing research expenditures and emphasizing human capital. Further analysis shown that geographic location, initial resource endowment, population size, and level of green finance development are difference in different cities. This provides guidance promoting the development of NHTDZs and future layout.</description>
      <author>Zhong Shen, Yaqian Wu, Junzhi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-69753-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexural behavior of reinforced bubble arch slabs: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61268/9s4s3q70</link>
      <description>, Al Rafidain Journal of Engineering Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401535377

                Concrete slabs are essential components of any building structure, providing thermal comfort and enhancing the overall quality of life for occupants. However, concrete slabs require a significant amount of concrete for flooring and roofing, contributing to substantial CO2 emissions&#8212;over 5% globally from cement production alone. This study explores the reduction of concrete in slabs through the incorporation of high-density polyethylene (HDPE) hollow spheres. These hollow spheres effectively eliminate non-structural concrete from the slab's middle, reducing its self-weight and increasing efficiency. This technique produces slabs that are 35-50% lighter, reducing loads on columns, walls, and foundations, while also cutting costs and CO2 emissions. Additionally, employing arched shapes, known for their structural efficiency, can further decrease material usage and associated costs. By combining arched and bubble techniques, we achieve our goal of creating lighter, more efficient concrete slabs.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61268/9s4s3q70</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sewage Vertical Infiltration Introduced Polygenic Multipollutants into Groundwater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/w16162305</link>
      <description>Yihan Dong, Yifan Han, Xu Han, Yaoxuan Chen, Yuanzheng Zhai, Water. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401642880

                With the increasing environmental impacts of human activities, the problem of polygenic multipollutants in groundwater has attracted the attention of researchers. Identifying the hydrobiogeochemical characteristics of the surface sewage that replenishes groundwater is crucial to addressing this problem. The input of polygenic multipollutants into groundwater leads to not only the mechanical superposition of pollutants but also the formation of secondary pollutant types. The evolution of polygenic multipollutants is influenced by aquifer characteristics, carbon sources, microbial abundance, etc. Therefore, this study took a sewage leakage point in Northwest China as the research object, carried out a controlled laboratory experiment on the impact of sewage discharge on groundwater, and, combined with long-term field monitoring results, determined the main hydrobiogeochemical processes of polygenic multipollutants and their secondary pollutants. The results showed that the redox environment and the gradient change in pH were identified as the most critical controlling factors. In oxidative groundwater during the early stage of vertical infiltration, sewage carries a substantial amount of NH4+, which is oxidized to form the secondary pollutant NO3&#8722;. As O2 is consumed, the reduction intensifies, and secondary pollutants NO3&#8722;, Mn (IV), and Fe(III) minerals are successively reduced. Compared with the natural conditions of rainwater vertical infiltration, the reaction rates and intensities of various reactions significantly increase during sewage vertical infiltration. However, there is a notable difference in the groundwater pH between sewage and rainwater vertical infiltration. In O2 and secondary pollutant NO3&#8722; reduction, a large amount of CO2 is rapidly generated. Excessive CO2 dissolves to produce a substantial amount of H+, promoting the acidic dissolution of Mn (II) minerals and generation of Mn2+. Sewage provides a higher carbon load, enhancing Mn (II) acidic dissolution and stimulating the activity of dissimilatory nitrate reduction to ammonium, which exhibits a higher contribution to NO3&#8722; reduction. This results in a portion of NO3&#8722; converted from NH4+ being reduced back to NH4+ and retained in the groundwater, reducing the denitrification&#8217;s capacity to remove secondary NO3&#8722;. This has important implications for pollution management and groundwater remediation, particularly monitored natural attenuation.</description>
      <author>Yihan Dong, Yifan Han, Xu Han, Yaoxuan Chen, Yuanzheng Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/w16162305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of eco-friendly high-performance mortar with the addition of iron ore tailings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29183/2596-237x.ensus2024.v12.n1.p540-549</link>
      <description>Abner Ara&#250;jo Fajardo, Silvia Roberta Souza, Jordana G Macedo, Vinicius Ferreira Lanna, White Jos&#233; dos Santos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401630600

                This study investigated the mechanical performance and durability of high-performance structural mortars with mineral admixture of iron ore tailings (IOT) at 112 days of age. Mortars containing IOT showed porosities lower than 2.1%, high compressive strength (&gt; 95 MPa) and flexural strength (37% higher) and a reduction of 4.55% in CO2 emissions. It is concluded that the incorporation of IOTs in mortars provides improvements in physical, mechanical and durability properties, in admixture to being ecologically more sustainable.</description>
      <author>Abner Ara&#250;jo Fajardo, Silvia Roberta Souza, Jordana G Macedo, Vinicius Ferreira Lanna, White Jos&#233; dos Santos</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29183/2596-237x.ensus2024.v12.n1.p540-549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnesium (Mg/Ca, &#948;&lt;sup&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt;Mg), boron (B/Ca, &#948;&lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;B), and calcium ([Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;]) geochemistry of Arctica islandica and Crassostrea virginica extrapallial fluid and shell under ocean acidification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1957</link>
      <description>Blanca Alvarez Caraveo, Maxence Guillermic, Alan M. Downey&#8208;Wall, Louise P. Cameron, Jill Sutton, John A. Higgins, Justin B. Ries, Katie E. Lotterhos, Robert A. Eagle, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401518269

                Abstract. The geochemistry of biogenic carbonates has long been used as proxies to record changing seawater parameters. However, the effect of ocean acidification on seawater chemistry and organism physiology could impact isotopic signatures and how elements are incorporated into the shell. In this study, we investigated the geochemistry of three reservoirs important for biomineralization &#8211; seawater, the extrapallial fluid (EPF), and the shell &#8211; in two bivalve species, Crassostrea virginica and Arctica islandica. Additionally, we examined the effects of three ocean acidification conditions (ambient: 500 ppm CO2, moderate: 900 ppm CO2, and high: 2800 ppm CO2) on the geochemistry of the same three reservoirs for C. virginica. We present data on calcification rates, EPF pH, measured elemental ratios (Mg/Ca, B/Ca), and isotopic signatures (&#948;26Mg, &#948;11B). In both species, comparisons of seawater and EPF Mg/Ca and B/Ca, [Ca2+], and &#948;26Mg indicate that the EPF has a distinct composition that differs from seawater. Shell &#948;11B did not faithfully record seawater pH and &#948;11B-calculated pH values were consistently higher than pH measurements of the EPF with microelectrodes, indicating that the shell &#948;11B may reflect a localized environment within the entire EPF reservoir. In C. virginica, EPF Mg/Ca and B/Ca, as well as absolute concentrations of Mg, B, and [Ca2+], were all significantly affected by ocean acidification, indicating that OA affects the physiological pathways regulating or storing these ions, an observation that complicates their use as proxies. Reduction in EPF [Ca2+] may represent an additional mechanism underlying reduction in calcification in C. virginica in response to seawater acidification. The complexity of dynamics of EPF chemistry suggest boron proxies in these two mollusc species are not straightforwardly related to seawater pH, but ocean acidification does lead to both a decrease in microelectrode pH and boron-isotope-based pH, potentially showing applicability of boron isotopes in recording physiological changes. Collectively, our findings show that bivalves have high physiological control over the internal calcifying fluid, which presents a challenge to using boron isotopes for reconstructing seawater pH.</description>
      <author>Blanca Alvarez Caraveo, Maxence Guillermic, Alan M. Downey&#8208;Wall, Louise P. Cameron, Jill Sutton, John A. Higgins, Justin B. Ries, Katie E. Lotterhos, Robert A. Eagle</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening New Mungbean Varieties for Terminal Drought Tolerance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14081328</link>
      <description>Sobia Ikram, Surya P. Bhattarai, Kerry B. Walsh, Agriculture. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401520705

                Rainfed mungbean crops in Queensland Australia frequently experience terminal drought (drought stress in the final stages of reproductive development), highlighting the importance of drought-tolerant varieties for sustainable mungbean production. Given there is limited information on the relative drought tolerance of current mungbean varieties in Australia, the study of genetic variations and mechanisms of drought tolerance in summer mungbean can provide a basis for developing drought-tolerant mungbean varieties. This study evaluated the physiological, biochemical, and phenological traits underpinning yield attributes associated with drought tolerance in selected mungbean varieties. Four new mungbean varieties (AVTMB#1 to 4) and the Australian commercial line (Jade-AU) were grown in tall (75 cm) polyvinyl chloride (PVC) lysimeters where drought stress was imposed at the early flowering stage (R1) and maintained until maturity. Drought stress significantly impacted all the varieties. Averaged across all the varieties, drought stress was associated with a reduction in stomatal conductance (gs) and photosynthetic rate (Asat) by 78% and 86%, respectively, compared to well-watered plants. Internal carbon dioxide concentration (Ci), the effective quantum yield of photosystem II (&#934;PSII) and maximum light-use efficiency of light-acclimated photosystem II (PSII) centres (Fv&#8217;/Fm&#8217;) were also decreased, while excitation pressure (1-qP) increased with drought treatment. A positive correlation (r = 0.60) existed between seed yield and &#934;PSII assessed at R1, while a weak correlation with Fv&#8217;/Fm&#8217; (r = 0.24) was observed. Excitation pressure (1-qP) at the R1 stage was negatively correlated with seed yield (r = &#8722;0.66). Therefore, leaf fluorescence measures, viz., 1-qP and &#934;PSII, were recommended for use in screening mungbean varieties for drought tolerance. The varieties, AVTMB#1 and AVTMB#4, respectively achieved 39 and 38% greater seed yields relative to the commercial variety, Jade-AU, under terminal drought conditions.</description>
      <author>Sobia Ikram, Surya P. Bhattarai, Kerry B. Walsh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14081328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual&#8208;metal sites drive tandem electrocatalytic CO2 to C2+ products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412568</link>
      <description>Guangwen Xie, Weiwei Guo, Zijian Fang, Zongxia Duan, Xianzhen Lang, Doudou Liu, Guoliang Mei, Yanling Zhai, Xiaofu Sun, Xiaoquan Lu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401580599

                The electrochemical conversion of CO2 into valuable chemicals is a promising route for renowable energy storage and the mitigation of greenhouse gas emission, and production of multicarbon (C2+) products is highly desired. Here, we report a 1.4%Pd&#8208;Cu@CuPz2 comprising of dispersive CuOx and PdO dual nanoclusters embedded in the MOF CuPz2 (Pz = Pyrazole), which achieves a high C2+ Faradaic efficiency (FEC2+) of 81.9% and C2+ alcohol FE of 47.5% with remarkable stability when using 0.1 M KCl aqueous solution as electrolyte in a typical H&#8208;cell. Particularly, the FE of alcohol is obviously improved on 1.4%Pd&#8208;Cu@CuPz2 compared to Cu@CuPz2. Theoretical calculations have revealed that revealed that the enhanced interfacial electron transfer facilitates the adsorption of *CO intermediate and *CO&#8722;*CO dimerization on the Cu&#8208;Pd dual sites bridged by Cu nodes of CuPz2. Additionally, the oxophilicity of Pd can stabilize the key intermediate *CH2CHO and promote subsequent proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer more efficiently, confirming that the formation pathway is skew towards *C2H5OH. Consequently, the Cu&#8208;Pd dual sites play a synergistic tandem role in cooperatively improving the selectivity of alcohol and accelerating reductive conversion of CO2 to C2+.</description>
      <author>Guangwen Xie, Weiwei Guo, Zijian Fang, Zongxia Duan, Xianzhen Lang, Doudou Liu, Guoliang Mei, Yanling Zhai, Xiaofu Sun, Xiaoquan Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual&#8208;metal sites drive tandem electrocatalytic CO2 to C2+ products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412568</link>
      <description>Guangwen Xie, Weiwei Guo, Zijian Fang, Zongxia Duan, Xianzhen Lang, Doudou Liu, Guoliang Mei, Yanling Zhai, Xiaofu Sun, Xiaoquan Lu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401584145

                The electrochemical conversion of CO2 into valuable chemicals is a promising route for renowable energy storage and the mitigation of greenhouse gas emission, and production of multicarbon (C2+) products is highly desired. Here, we report a 1.4%Pd&#8208;Cu@CuPz2 comprising of dispersive CuOx and PdO dual nanoclusters embedded in the MOF CuPz2 (Pz = Pyrazole), which achieves a high C2+ Faradaic efficiency (FEC2+) of 81.9% and C2+ alcohol FE of 47.5% with remarkable stability when using 0.1 M KCl aqueous solution as electrolyte in a typical H&#8208;cell. Particularly, the FE of alcohol is obviously improved on 1.4%Pd&#8208;Cu@CuPz2 compared to Cu@CuPz2. Theoretical calculations have revealed that revealed that the enhanced interfacial electron transfer facilitates the adsorption of *CO intermediate and *CO&#8722;*CO dimerization on the Cu&#8208;Pd dual sites bridged by Cu nodes of CuPz2. Additionally, the oxophilicity of Pd can stabilize the key intermediate *CH2CHO and promote subsequent proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer more efficiently, confirming that the formation pathway is skew towards *C2H5OH. Consequently, the Cu&#8208;Pd dual sites play a synergistic tandem role in cooperatively improving the selectivity of alcohol and accelerating reductive conversion of CO2 to C2+.</description>
      <author>Guangwen Xie, Weiwei Guo, Zijian Fang, Zongxia Duan, Xianzhen Lang, Doudou Liu, Guoliang Mei, Yanling Zhai, Xiaofu Sun, Xiaoquan Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Carbon Utilization for a Climate-Neutral Economy&#8211;Framework Necessities and Assessment Criteria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17164118</link>
      <description>Tjerk Zitscher, Martin Kaltschmitt, Energies. 17(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401685971

                The need to limit anthropogenic climate change to 1.5&#8211;2 &#176;C, as agreed in the Paris Agreement, requires a significant reduction of CO2 emissions resulting from the use of fossil carbon. However, based on current knowledge, carbon is expected to remain crucial in certain industrial sectors, e.g., the chemical industry. Consequently, it is essential to identify and utilize sustainable carbon sources in the future. In this context, various carbon sources were examined and classified in terms of their disruption of the Earth&#8217;s (fast) carbon cycle. Furthermore, the examined carbon sources were qualitatively analyzed with regard to their technical readiness level, their energy expenditure, and their current and future availability, as well as legal regulation within the European Union. As a result, only biogenic and mixed carbon from the ambient air can be considered genuinely sustainable within the Earth&#8217;s (fast) carbon cycle. Mixed carbon streams, e.g., from waste recycling, fall into a gray area. The same applies to certain process-related emissions that originally descend from fossil fuel energy. In terms of energy considerations, technical maturity, and exploitable potentials, prioritizing the utilization of biogenic carbon sources is advisable for the time being, especially for CO2 produced as a by-product originating from biogenic carbon carriers.</description>
      <author>Tjerk Zitscher, Martin Kaltschmitt</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17164118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating CO2 emissions in the residential sector: Life cycle assessment (LCA) using regional forestry design models in system dynamics (SD)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15376/biores.19.4.7072-7079</link>
      <description>Shunsuke Kaneko, Hyun Bae Kim, Takuyuki Yoshioka, BioResources. 19(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401537529

                This study used a sub-model within system dynamics to simulate and quantify CO2 emissions in the residential sector, focusing on the Nishikawa forestry region in Saitama Prefecture. The model evaluated emissions from the life cycle of houses, including production, transportation, use, maintenance, and disposal. The business as usual (BAU) scenario projects annual new housing inflows. The woody biomass utilization (WBU) scenario showed a 10% carbon reduction over 30 years by replacing new housing with timber construction, despite increased emissions from new constructions. The study highlights the economic benefits of utilizing carbon credits to support reforestation, making it possible to secure the sustainability of regional forestry to supply timber materials to the residential sector.</description>
      <author>Shunsuke Kaneko, Hyun Bae Kim, Takuyuki Yoshioka</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15376/biores.19.4.7072-7079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Intraphase Catalytic&#8208;Domain Transfer via CO2 Laser for Enhanced Nitrate&#8208;to&#8208;Ammonia Electroconversion and Zn&#8208;Nitrate Battery Behavior</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413774</link>
      <description>Yeryeong Lee, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Nuttapon Yodsin, Ahreum Min, Cheol Joo Moon, Siriporn Jungsuttiwong, Myong Yong Choi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401548055

                Developing sustainable energy solutions is critical for addressing the dual challenges of energy demand and environmental impact. In this study, a zinc&#8208;nitrate (Zn&#8208;NO3&#8722;) battery system was designed for the simultaneous production of ammonia (NH3) via the electrocatalytic NO3&#8722; reduction reaction (NO3RR) and electricity generation. Continuous wave CO2 laser irradiation yielded precisely controlled CoFe2O4@nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (CoFe2O4@NC) hollow nanocubes from CoFe Prussian blue analogs (CoFe&#8208;PBA) as the integral electrocatalyst for NO3RR in 1.0&#8208;M KOH, achieving a remarkable NH3 production rate of 10.9 mgh&#8722;1cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;0.47 V versus RHE with exceptional stability. In&#8208;situ and ex&#8208;situ methods revealed that the CoFe2O4@NC surface transformed into high&#8208;valent Fe/CoOOH active&#8208;species, optimizing the adsorption energy of NO3RR (*NO2 and *NO species) intermediates. Furthermore, DFT calculations validated the possible NO3RR pathway on CoFe2O4@NC starting with NO3&#8722; conversion to *NO2 intermediates, followed by reduction to *NO. Subsequent protonation forms the *NH and *NH2 species, leading to NH3 formation via final protonation. The Zn&#8208;NO3&#8722; battery utilizing the CoFe2O4@NC cathode exhibits dual functionality by generating electricity with a stable open&#8208;circuit voltage of 1.38&#8208;V versus Zn/Zn2+ and producing NH3. This study inspires the simple design of low&#8208;cost catalysts for NO3RR&#8208;to&#8208;NH3 conversion and positions the Zn&#8208;NO3&#8722; battery as a promising technology for industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Yeryeong Lee, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Nuttapon Yodsin, Ahreum Min, Cheol Joo Moon, Siriporn Jungsuttiwong, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413774</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Intraphase Catalytic&#8208;Domain Transfer via CO2 Laser for Enhanced Nitrate&#8208;to&#8208;Ammonia Electroconversion and Zn&#8208;Nitrate Battery Behavior</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413774</link>
      <description>Yeryeong Lee, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Nuttapon Yodsin, Ahreum Min, Cheol Joo Moon, Siriporn Jungsuttiwong, Myong Yong Choi, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401548542

                Developing sustainable energy solutions is critical for addressing the dual challenges of energy demand and environmental impact. In this study, a zinc&#8208;nitrate (Zn&#8208;NO3&#8722;) battery system was designed for the simultaneous production of ammonia (NH3) via the electrocatalytic NO3&#8722; reduction reaction (NO3RR) and electricity generation. Continuous wave CO2 laser irradiation yielded precisely controlled CoFe2O4@nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (CoFe2O4@NC) hollow nanocubes from CoFe Prussian blue analogs (CoFe&#8208;PBA) as the integral electrocatalyst for NO3RR in 1.0&#8208;M KOH, achieving a remarkable NH3 production rate of 10.9 mgh&#8722;1cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;0.47 V versus RHE with exceptional stability. In&#8208;situ and ex&#8208;situ methods revealed that the CoFe2O4@NC surface transformed into high&#8208;valent Fe/CoOOH active&#8208;species, optimizing the adsorption energy of NO3RR (*NO2 and *NO species) intermediates. Furthermore, DFT calculations validated the possible NO3RR pathway on CoFe2O4@NC starting with NO3&#8722; conversion to *NO2 intermediates, followed by reduction to *NO. Subsequent protonation forms the *NH and *NH2 species, leading to NH3 formation via final protonation. The Zn&#8208;NO3&#8722; battery utilizing the CoFe2O4@NC cathode exhibits dual functionality by generating electricity with a stable open&#8208;circuit voltage of 1.38&#8208;V versus Zn/Zn2+ and producing NH3. This study inspires the simple design of low&#8208;cost catalysts for NO3RR&#8208;to&#8208;NH3 conversion and positions the Zn&#8208;NO3&#8722; battery as a promising technology for industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Yeryeong Lee, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Nuttapon Yodsin, Ahreum Min, Cheol Joo Moon, Siriporn Jungsuttiwong, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413774</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of concretes produced with different ore sands &#8211; In search of highperformance and sustainable dosages</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29183/2596-237x.ensus2024.v12.n1.p629-637</link>
      <description>Cheila Barbosa de Souza, Mariana Rodrigues da Silva de Menezes, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401669938

                The sand from the processing of iron ore has been widely used in civil construction in Brazil, especially in the states of Minas Gerais, Esp&#237;rito Santo and S&#227;o Paulo. It is used as fine aggregate in the production of mortars, cement products and concrete. With the possibility of producing new sand in several iron ore mines in the state of Minas Gerais, the present study aimed to develop and analyze concrete dosages with various ore sands and sands present in the industrial market in the Belo Horizonte region. The replacement of natural river sand with mining sand in concrete dosages was evaluated and the Abrams curves were analyzed for the various dosages developed. It was possible to observe a performance gain in the dosages carried out with ore sands, with a reduction of up to 7% in cement consumption in the mixes. Thus, it can be concluded that the use of mining sand in the production of concrete is efficient, with technical and productive gains, promoting sustainable construction, reducing CO2 and promoting the circular economy in the construction chain.</description>
      <author>Cheila Barbosa de Souza, Mariana Rodrigues da Silva de Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29183/2596-237x.ensus2024.v12.n1.p629-637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Net zero performance evaluation of European Continent Countries considering Paris Agreement climate goals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1108/k-04-2024-0859</link>
      <description>Mehtap Dursun, Rana Duygu Alkurt, Kybernetes. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401672959

                Purpose Today&#8217;s one of the most important difficulties is tackling climate change and its effects on the environment. The Paris Agreement states that nations must balance the amount of greenhouse gases they emit and absorb until 2050 to contribute to the mitigation of greenhouse gases and to support sustainable development. According to the agreement, each country must determine, plan and regularly report on its contributions. Thus, it is important for the countries to predict and analyze their net zero performances in 2050. Therefore, the aim of this study is to evaluate European Continent Countries' net zero performances at the targeted year. Design/methodology/approach The European Continent Countries that ratified the Paris Agreement are specified as decision making units (DMUs). Input and output indicators are specified as primary energy consumption, freshwater withdrawals, gross domestic product (GDP), carbon-dioxide (CO 2 ) and nitrous-oxide (N 2 O) emissions. Data from 1980 to 2019 are obtained and forecasted using autoregressive integrated moving average (ARIMA) until 2050. Then, the countries are clustered based on the forecasts of primary energy consumption and freshwater withdrawals using k-means algorithm. As desirable and undesirable outputs arise simultaneously, the performances are computed using Pure Environmental Index (PEI) and Mixed Environmental Index (MEI) data envelopment analysis (DEA) models. Findings It is expected that by 2050, CO 2 emissions of seven countries remain constant, N 2 O emissions of seven countries remain stable and five countries&#8217; both CO 2 and N 2 O emissions remain constant. While it can be seen as success that many countries are expected to at least stabilize one emission, the likelihood of achieving net zero targets diminishes unless countries undertake significant reductions in emissions. According to the results, in Cluster 1, Turkey ranks last, while France, Germany, Italy and Spain are efficient countries. In Cluster 2, the United Kingdom ranks at last, while Greece, Luxembourg, Malta and Sweden are efficient countries. Originality/value In the literature, generally, CO 2 emission is considered as greenhouse gas. Moreover, none of the studies measured the net-zero performance of the countries in 2050 employing analytical techniques. This study objects to investigate how well European Continent Countries can comply with the necessities of the Agreement. Besides CO 2 emission, N 2 O emission is also considered and the data of European Continent Countries in 2050 are estimated using ARIMA. Then, countries are clustered using k-means algorithm. DEA models are employed to measure the performances of the countries. Finally, forecasts and models validations are performed and comprehensive analysis of the results is conducted.</description>
      <author>Mehtap Dursun, Rana Duygu Alkurt</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1108/k-04-2024-0859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Regulating Ecosystem Services of Urban Trees: A Case Study of a Green Space at Chungnam National University Using i-Tree Eco</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/f15081446</link>
      <description>Wencelito Palis Hintural, Hyung-Min Jeon, Seoyoung C. Kim, Susie Go, Byung Bae Park, Forests. 15(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401639072

                Urban green spaces (UGSs) provide numerous ecosystem services (ESs) that are essential to the well-being of the residents. However, these services are often neglected in regional urban development and spatial planning. This study quantified the ESs of a 10.25 ha UGS at Chungnam National University, Daejeon, Republic of Korea, comprising 27 species with 287 tree individuals, using i-Tree Eco. Key regulating ESs investigated included air pollution removal, carbon storage and sequestration, oxygen production, energy use reduction, avoidance of surface runoff, and replacement and functional values. Results revealed significant annual environmental benefits: 131 kg air pollutants removed (USD 3739.01 or &#8361;5.16 M), 1.76 Mg carbon sequestered, which is equivalent to 0.18 Mg CO2 ha&#8722;1 yr&#8722;1 (USD 289.85 or &#8361;0.40 M), 2.42 Mg oxygen produced, energy savings (including carbon offset) valued at USD 391.29 (&#8361;0.54 M), and 203 m3 reduction in surface runoff (USD 413.09 or &#8361;0.57 M). The annual total benefits of these urban trees amounted to USD 4833.86 (&#8361;6.67 M), USD 16.83/tree, or USD 0.089/capita. Additionally, these trees had replacement and functional values estimated at USD 311,115.17 (&#8361;429.3 M). The study underscores that species selection and abundance of urban trees are fundamental for maximizing the ES delivery in urban areas, highlighting the role of UGSs in ecological and economical sustainability in cities. These insights are valuable for urban planners and policymakers to optimize benefits of UGSs in cities.</description>
      <author>Wencelito Palis Hintural, Hyung-Min Jeon, Seoyoung C. Kim, Susie Go, Byung Bae Park</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/f15081446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use of Distributed Energy Resources Integrated with the Electric Grid in the Amazon: A Case Study of the UFPA Poraqu&#234; Electric Boat Using Digital Twin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.0420.v1</link>
      <description>Bruno Santana De Albuquerque, Maria Em&#237;lia de Lima Tostes, Ubiratan Holanda Bezerra, Carminda Carvalho, A. R. do Nascimento, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401590368

                Electric mobility is a global trend and necessity, with electric and solar boats offering a promising alternative for transportation electrification and carbon emission reduction, especially in the Amazon region. This study analyzes the system of a solar boat from the SIMA project, to be implemented at UFPA, using MATLAB software for modeling. The Simulink tool was utilized to model the system, focusing on operational parameters such as module voltage, converter voltage, and speed. Results indicate that the solar boat's operational cost is significantly lower compared to a similar internal combustion model, considering diesel's high consumption and cost. The environmental impact is also reduced, with nearly 72 tons of CO2 emissions avoided annually, thanks to Brazil's renewable energy matrix. Simulations confirmed the project's parameters, demonstrating the efficiency of digital twin technology in monitoring and predicting system performance. The study underscores the importance of digital twins and renewable energy in promoting sustainable transportation solutions, advocating for the replication of such projects globally. Future research should focus on further advancing digital twin applications in electric mobility to enhance predictive maintenance and operational efficiency.</description>
      <author>Bruno Santana De Albuquerque, Maria Em&#237;lia de Lima Tostes, Ubiratan Holanda Bezerra, Carminda Carvalho, A. R. do Nascimento</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.0420.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability Development through a Nearly Zero Energy Building Implementation Case: An Office Building in South Jakarta</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16167027</link>
      <description>Farizal Farizal, Muhammad Aqil Noviandri, Hanif Hamdani, Sustainability. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401645811

                Nearly zero energy buildings (NZEBs) might play a significant role in addressing current global environmental problems, i.e., greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Buildings are one of the main electricity consumers. With current electricity production coming mainly from fossil fuel power plants, buildings contribute indirectly to GHG emissions. This report shows potential energy-saving alternatives (thus reducing the carbon footprints) for an 18-story office building in South Jakarta&#8217;s central business district. Four alternatives are considered, namely cooling tower and CWP pump replacement, BAS installation, LED dim light replacement, and solar panel installation. The project that implements all four alternatives indeed produces the biggest emissions savings. However, its net present value (NPV) is negative, which means the project is not economically feasible. Furthermore, any combination of projects involving solar panel installation will produce negative NPVs. The combination of cooling tower and CWP pump replacement, BAS installation, and LED dim light replacement will be the best option, with an NPV of IDR 437,853,822, an energy consumption index (IKE) value of 11.76 (meaning the &#8220;efficient&#8221; building category) and a carbon emissions reduction of 1172.65 tons of CO2.</description>
      <author>Farizal Farizal, Muhammad Aqil Noviandri, Hanif Hamdani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16167027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of Silica Fly Ash and Wood Bottom Ash on Cement Hydration and Durability of Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17164031</link>
      <description>Jurgita Malai&#353;kien&#279;, Marija Vai&#269;ien&#279;, Materials. 17(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401537013

                This research addresses a notable gap in understanding the synergistic effects of high carbon wood bottom ash (BA) and silica fly ash (FA) on cement hydration and concrete durability by using them as a supplementary material to reduce the amount of cement in concrete and CO2 emissions during cement production. This study analyses the synergistic effect of FA and BA on cement hydration through X-ray diffraction (XRD), thermal analysis (TG, DTG), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), density, ultrasonic pulse velocity (UPV), compressive strength, and temperature monitoring tests. In addition, it evaluates concrete properties, including compressive strength, UPV, density, water absorption kinetics, porosity parameters, predicted resistance to freezing and thawing cycles, and results of freeze&#8211;thawing resistance. The concrete raw materials were supplemented with varying percentages of BA and FA, replacing both cement and fine aggregate at levels of 0%, 2.5%, 5%, 10% and 15%. The results indicate that a 15% substitution of BA and FA delays cement hydration by approximately 5 h and results in only a 6% reduction in compressive strength, with the hardened cement paste showing a strength similar to a 15% replacement with FA. Concrete mixtures with 2.5% BA and 2.5% FA maintained the same maximum hydration temperature and duration as the reference mix. Furthermore, the combined use of both ashes provided adequate resistance to freeze&#8211;thaw cycles, with only a 4.7% reduction in compressive strength after 150 cycles. Other properties, such as density, UPV and water absorption, exhibited minimal changes with partial cement replacement by both ashes. This study highlights the potential benefits of using BA and FA together, offering a sustainable alternative that maintains concrete performance while using waste materials.</description>
      <author>Jurgita Malai&#353;kien&#279;, Marija Vai&#269;ien&#279;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17164031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13C-enriched carbonate precipitates reveal intense methanogenic oil degradation in the upper Wuerhe Formation, Northwest China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1130/g52293.1</link>
      <description>Liu Wen-dong, Wenxuan Hu, Wenxuan Hu, Xiaolin Wang, Jian Cao, Xiang-Long Luo, Shichao An, Wenwen Li, Dongming Zhi, Weiqiang Li, Geology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401539087

                Microbial methanogenesis from crude oil is an important source of CH4 for gas reservoirs and atmospheric greenhouse gases. However, its petrological records have not been found in natural environments, and the geological conditions under which it may occur remain unclear. Here, we provide the first petrological evidence of Fe(III)-mediated methanogenic hydrocarbon degradation in a deep subsurface oil reservoir in Northwest China. The major findings are as follows: (1) highly positive &#948;13C values (up to +16&#8240;) of secondary calcite attributed to methanogenesis; (2) paragenetic relation of high-&#948;13C calcite to biodegraded hydrocarbon; and (3) remarkably high FeO contents (up to 8 wt%) and heavy &#948;56Fe ratios (up to +0.52&#8240;) in calcite, indicative of microbial Fe(III) reduction. Our study shows that methanogenic hydrocarbon degradation can occur in Fe(III)-reducing environments. This process transformed hydrocarbons into CO2 and CH4, where the former mostly precipitated as Fe-rich calcite (the carbon sink), while the latter, representing an estimated &#8275;1968 Tg, might have escaped into the overburden and atmosphere from the Permian reservoir during the Late Triassic to Early Jurassic, which may have acted as an important CH4 source in changing global climate in the geological past.</description>
      <author>Liu Wen-dong, Wenxuan Hu, Wenxuan Hu, Xiaolin Wang, Jian Cao, Xiang-Long Luo, Shichao An, Wenwen Li, Dongming Zhi, Weiqiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1130/g52293.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different-Sized Dual Electrical Submersible Pumps (ESPs) Novel Applications: Sustainable Production and Reduced Carbon Emission</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/219555-ms</link>
      <description>Manal Al&#8208;Eid, H. T. Alqudaihi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401679532

                Abstract Dual Electrical Submersible Pumps (ESPs) have gained widespread adoption across the oil industry. While current applications are predominated by identical size systems to achieve the sole goal of extended run life, incorporating different-sized systems can open the door for expanded applications and operational benefits. This paper introduces various novel applications of dual ESPs that can lead to sustained production target and minimized carbon footprint. The procedure includes gathering reservoir, wellbore, and surface network data. Subsequently, simulation models are used to select and evaluate ESP units of varying capacities, leading to an optimized design for enhanced efficiency. The system incorporates non-return valves (NRVs), facilitating seamless alternation between the two systems and eliminating the need for well intervention and associated carbon emissions. Throughout the ESP operation cycle, an integrated reservoir and network surveillance system is essential for continuous monitoring and analysis of data to determine the most efficient system for prevailing conditions. The comprehensive simulations cover various application scenarios for different-sized ESPs, revealing compelling results such as around 20% reduction in power consumption and a substantial annual cut of around 100-200 metric tons of CO2 emission reduction per system. Furthermore, the study explores the potential application in addressing reservoir parameters uncertainty, showcasing how ESPs of different sizes can offer wider operating ranges. Additional benefits include the ability of dual systems to achieve target rates within maximum allowable network pressures, eliminating the need for surface network upgrades. In conclusion, integrating real-time reservoir data with the novel application of dual ESP illustrates numerous energy and production optimization opportunities. This study emphasizes the significance of data-driven decision-making to provide a path towards more eco-friendly and efficient ESP applications. Additionally, it offers a robust foundation for enhancing environmental stewardship while maintaining ESP operational excellence.</description>
      <author>Manal Al&#8208;Eid, H. T. Alqudaihi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/219555-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Impact of the Digital Economy on Carbon Emission Reduction and Its Spatial Spillover Effect&#8212;The Case of Eastern Coastal Cities in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijgi13080293</link>
      <description>Zhong Jin, Ye Duan, Caizhi Sun, Hongye Wang, ISPRS International Journal of Geo-Information. 13(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401685520

                The expansion of the digital economy is crucial for halting climate change, as carbon emissions from urban energy use contribute significantly to global warming. This study uses the Difference-in-Differences Model and the Spatial Durbin Model determine whether the digital economy may support the development of reducing carbon emissions and its geographic spillover effects in Chinese cities on the east coast. In addition, it looks more closely at the effects of lowering carbon emissions in space by separating them into direct, indirect, and spatial impact parts. The findings show that (1) from 2012 to 2021, the digital economy favored carbon emission reductions in China&#8217;s eastern coastline cities, as supported by the robustness test. (2) The link between digital economy growth and carbon emissions is highly variable, with smart city development and urban agglomeration expansion both cutting city carbon emissions considerably. Successful digital economy strategies can lower CO2 emissions from nearby cities. (3) Eastern coastal cities have a considerable spatial spillover impact, and the digital economy mitigates local energy consumption and carbon emissions while simultaneously enhancing environmental quality in nearby urban areas. This analysis proposes that the peak carbon and carbon neutrality targets can be met by increasing the digital economy and enhancing regional environmental governance cooperation.</description>
      <author>Zhong Jin, Ye Duan, Caizhi Sun, Hongye Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijgi13080293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand-Canonical Variational Theory of Oscillatory Fields at Electrified Metal-Solution Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-c5dvr</link>
      <description>M. Zhang, Yanxia Chen, Michael Eikerling, Jun Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401651543

                The oscillatory fields near the electrode surface are not considered in the classical models of electrical double layer (EDL), while holding immense importance for stability, activity, and selectivity of interfacial reactions. Here, we develop a unified theoretical framework for oscillatory fields in the EDL under constant potential conditions, combining an orbital-free DFT treatment of electrons on the metal side and a statistical field theory of charged fluids on the electrolyte side. The resulting grand potential is a hybrid functional of electron density, electric potential, and solvent polarization, referred to as density-potential-polarization functional theory (DPPFT). Built on the DPPFT, an EDL model for the Ag(110)-KPF6 aqueous interface is parameterized with experimental double layer capacitance (Cdl) data. The calibrated model is then employed to study the influence of electronic, ion, and solvent properties on the EDL structure and capacitance. Cdl profiles at different crystal faces and in various electrolyte solutions are rationalized coherently. We reveal that intensified ion layering leads to elevated capacitances at the potential of zero charge (PZC) and narrowed ionic peaks in the Cdl profile. Contrary to classical models, the DPPFT model allows co-ions to have an appreciable density near the electrode surface, opening an avenue to decipher the origin of the anomalous anion effects on electrochemical CO2 reduction. The presented framework adds much-needed realism to the modelling of EDLs.</description>
      <author>M. Zhang, Yanxia Chen, Michael Eikerling, Jun Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-c5dvr</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use of pumice stone and silica fume as precursor material for the design of a geopolymer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.147701.2</link>
      <description>Alexis Iv&#225;n Andrade Valle, Tito Castillo, Cristian Andr&#233;s Marcillo Zapata, M Rodr&#237;guez, Andrea Natal&#237; Z&#225;rate Villacr&#233;s, Marcelo David Guerra Valladares, Mayte Lisbeth Mieles Mari&#241;o, Jefferson Javier Castillo Cevallos, F1000Research. 13(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401521981

                Background Geopolymers are alternative materials to cement because they require less energy in their production process; hence, they contribute to the reduction in CO2 emissions. This study aims to evaluate the possibility of using industrial residues such as silica fume (SF) to improve the physical and mechanical properties of a pumice stone (PS)-based geopolymer. Methods Through an experimental methodology, the process starts with the extraction, grinding, and sieving of the raw material to carry out the physical and chemical characterization of the resulting material, followed by the dosage of the geopolymer mixture considering the factors that influence the resistance mechanical strength. Finally, the physical and mechanical properties of the geopolymer were characterized. This research was carried out in four stages: characterization of the pumice stone, design of the geopolymer through laboratory tests, application according to the dosage of the concrete, and analysis of the data through a multi-criteria analysis. Results It was determined that the optimal percentage of SF replacement is 10%, which to improves the properties of the geopolymer allowing to reach a maximum resistance to compression and flexion of 14.10 MPa and 4.78 MPa respectively, showing that there is a direct relationship between the percentage of SF and the resistance. Conclusions Geopolymer preparation involves the use of PS powder with a composition rich in silicon and aluminum. The factors influencing strength include the ratio of sodium silicate to sodium hydroxide, water content, temperature, curing time, molarity of sodium hydroxide, and binder ratio. The results showed an increase in the compression and flexural strength with 10% SF replacement. The geopolymer&#8217;s maximum compressive strength indicates its non-structural use, but it can be improved by reducing the PS powder size.</description>
      <author>Alexis Iv&#225;n Andrade Valle, Tito Castillo, Cristian Andr&#233;s Marcillo Zapata, M Rodr&#237;guez, Andrea Natal&#237; Z&#225;rate Villacr&#233;s, Marcelo David Guerra Valladares, Mayte Lisbeth Mieles Mari&#241;o, Jefferson Javier Castillo Cevallos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.147701.2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Mediterranean ocean biogeochemistry of the Last Glacial Maximum</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/cp-20-1785-2024</link>
      <description>Katharina Six, Uwe Mikolajewicz, Gerhard Schmiedl, Climate of the past. 20(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401523894

                Abstract. We present results of simulations performed with a physical&#8211;biogeochemical ocean model of the Mediterranean Sea for the Last Glacial Maximum (LGM) and analyse the differences in physical and biochemical states between the historical period and the LGM. Long-term simulations with an Earth system model based on ice sheet reconstructions provide the necessary atmospheric forcing data, oceanic boundary conditions at the entrance to the Mediterranean Sea, and river discharge to the entire basin. Our regional model accounts for changes in bathymetry due to ice sheet volume changes, reduction in atmospheric CO2 concentration, and an adjusted aeolian dust and iron deposition. The physical ocean state of the Mediterranean during the LGM shows a reduced baroclinic water exchange at the Strait of Gibraltar, a more sluggish zonal overturning circulation, and the relocation of intermediate and deep-water-formation areas &#8211; all in line with estimates from palaeo-sediment records or previous modelling efforts. Most striking features of the biogeochemical realm are a reduction in the net primary production, an accumulation of nutrients below the euphotic zone, and an increase in the organic matter deposition at the seafloor. This seeming contradiction of increased organic matter deposition and decreased net primary production challenges our view of possible changes in surface biological processes during the LGM. We attribute the origin of a reduced net primary production to the interplay of increased stability of the upper water column, changed zonal water transport at intermediate depths, and lower water temperatures, which slow down all biological processes during the LGM. Cold water temperatures also affect the remineralisation rates of organic material, which explains the simulated increase in the organic matter deposition, which is in good agreement with sediment proxy records. In addition, we discuss changes in an artificial tracer which captures the surface ocean temperature signal during organic matter production. A shifted seasonality of the biological production in the LGM leads to a difference in the recording of the climate signal by this artificial tracer of up to 1 K. This could be of relevance for the interpretation of proxy records like, e.g., alkenones. Our study not only provides the first consistent insights into the biogeochemistry of the glacial Mediterranean Sea but will also serve as the starting point for transient simulations of the last deglaciation.</description>
      <author>Katharina Six, Uwe Mikolajewicz, Gerhard Schmiedl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/cp-20-1785-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Changing Inlet Modes in Ski Face Masks on Adolescent Skiing: A Finite Element Analysis Based on Head Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/modelling5030049</link>
      <description>Minxin Huang, Ruiqiu Zhang, X. Zhang, Modelling&#8212;International Open Access Journal of Modelling in Engineering Science. 5(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401577321

                Due to the material properties of current ski face masks for adolescents, moisture in exhaled air can become trapped within the material fibers and freeze, leading to potential issues such as breathing difficulties and increased risk of facial frostbite after prolonged skiing. This paper proposes a research approach combining computational fluid dynamics (CFD) and ergonomics to address these issues and enhance the comfort of adolescent skiers. We developed head and face mask models based on the head dimensions of 15&#8211;17-year-old males. For enclosed cavities, ensuring the smooth expulsion of exhaled air to prevent re-inhalation is the primary challenge. Through fluid simulation of airflow characteristics within the cavity, we evaluated three different inlet configurations. The results indicate that the location of the air inlets significantly affects the airflow characteristics within the cavity. The side inlet design (type II) showed an average face temperature of 35.35 &#176;C, a 38.5% reduction in average CO2 concentration within the cavity, and a smaller vortex area compared to the other two inlet configurations. Although the difference in airflow velocity within the cavity among the three configurations was minimal, the average exit velocity differed by up to 0.11 m/s. Thus, we conclude that the side inlet configuration offers minimal obstruction to airflow circulation and better thermal insulation when used in the design of fully enclosed helmets. This enhances the safety and comfort of adolescent wearers during physical activities in cold environments. Through this study, we aim to further promote the development of skiing education, enhance the overall quality of adolescents&#8217; skiing, and thus provide them with more opportunities for the future.</description>
      <author>Minxin Huang, Ruiqiu Zhang, X. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/modelling5030049</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
