<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:43:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Production of Ethylene and Hydrogen Peroxide from Paired Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction and Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304247</link>
      <description>Sotirios Mavrikis, Mich&#233;l K. Nieuwoudt, Maximilian G&#246;ltz, Sophie Ehles, Andreas K&#246;rner, Andreas Hutzler, Emeric Fossy, Andreas Zervas, Oshioriamhe Brai, Moritz Wegener, Florian Doerrfuss, Peter Bouwman, Stefan Rosiwal, Ling Wang, Carlos Ponce de Le&#243;n, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392807699

                Abstract Paired electrolysis offers an auspicious strategy for the generation of high&#8208;value chemicals, at both the anode and cathode, in an integrated electrochemical reactor. Through efficient electron utilization, routine product misuse at overlooked electrodes can be prevented. Here, an original paired electrosynthetic system is reported that can convert CO 2 to ethylene (C 2 H 4 ) at the cathode, and water to hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) at the anode under a single pass of electric charge. Amongst various investigated copper (Cu) nanomorphologies, the bespoke mixed Cu nanowire/nanoparticle catalyst recorded a peak C 2 H 4 Faraday efficiency ( FE ) of 60% following 370 h of electrolysis at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 , while the tailored boron&#8208;doped diamond (BDD) anode accumulated an unprecedented &#8776;1% w/w of H 2 O 2 in 4 m K 2 CO 3 upon applying 300 mA cm &#8722;2 for 10 h. When paired, the dual C 2 H 4 &#8208;H 2 O 2 electrochemical cell attains a combined FE of 120% for 50 h at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 , a combined energy efficiency (EE) of 69%, and a 50% decrease in the overall electrical energy consumption (EEC) compared to the individual electrosynthesis of C 2 H 4 and H 2 O 2 .</description>
      <author>Sotirios Mavrikis, Mich&#233;l K. Nieuwoudt, Maximilian G&#246;ltz, Sophie Ehles, Andreas K&#246;rner, Andreas Hutzler, Emeric Fossy, Andreas Zervas, Oshioriamhe Brai, Moritz Wegener, Florian Doerrfuss, Peter Bouwman, Stefan Rosiwal, Ling Wang, Carlos Ponce de Le&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Promotion for the Performance of Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction by Vacancy Engineering and N-Doped Carbon Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4728334</link>
      <description>Min Wang, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Fanlin Kong, Baolin Liu, Zhende Wu, Yali Cao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392839620

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Wang, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Fanlin Kong, Baolin Liu, Zhende Wu, Yali Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4728334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prospects for the Development of Nanocomposite Catalysts for the Oxidative Conversion of C1-C4 Alkanes with Carbon Dioxide to Produce Hydrogen/Synthesis Gas and Organic Compounds: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11237-024-09790-z</link>
      <description>Sergiy O. Soloviev, Theoretical and Experimental Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393011083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sergiy O. Soloviev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11237-024-09790-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distribution of Carbon Dioxide Emissions and Potential Consequences for Their Reduction in Louisiana</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31390/gradschool_theses.5821</link>
      <description>Mohammad I. Zia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392795875

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohammad I. Zia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31390/gradschool_theses.5821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How informal environmental regulations constrain carbon dioxide emissions under pollution control and carbon reduction: Evidence from China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118732</link>
      <description>Po Kou, Ying Han, Baoling Jin, Tian Li, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392983203

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Po Kou, Ying Han, Baoling Jin, Tian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Supported Silver Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33540/2122</link>
      <description>Francesco Mattarozzi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392835293

                The work described in this thesis was aimed at understanding the influence of structural properties of silver catalysts supported on carbon for the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to CO. This goal was achieved by rationally designing, characterizing and testing cathode materials. This enabled a correlation between material properties and the catalytic performance. Chapter 1 describes the potential benefits of electrochemistry and electrocatalysis in the context of global warming. The CO2 electrocatalytic reduction to value-added chemicals was described, including the effect of different metal electrodes and buffer electrolytes. Specifically, a background is given on the CO2RR to CO over silver electrocatalysts, and the properties of carbon electrodes, based on literature. In chapter 2, the effect of surface-modification of carbon-based electrodes on the reduction of CO2 to CO is systematically treated. The surface chemistry of the electrodes was characterized with acid-base titration, potentiometric titration and XPS. The basic surface properties (high point of zero charge) of the N functionalized carbon catalyst led to an increased CO production with respect to the O-functionalized and reduced carbon materials. The CO turnover frequency per surface group for pyridinic groups was higher than for O-containing groups. This study demonstrated the possibility to tune the surface properties of carbon materials to enhance the ability of the electrocatalyst to reduce CO2 to CO. In chapter 3, the effect of silver nanoparticle size on the CO2 reduction to CO is discussed. Using the surface modification methods described in chapter 2, control over the ligand-free silver particle size was achieved by tuning the surface properties of the carbon supports. It was demonstrated that the silver particle size, in the range of 10 to 30 nm, decreased by increasing the density of O-containing group on the support. The small nanoparticles (11 nm diameter) effectively steered the selectivity towards CO, even greater than the selectivity achieved by bulk silver electrodes under the same conditions. In chapter 4, the aim was to suppress the hydrogen formation over the high surface area carbon support by functionalizing the surface of the support with alkylamines. The effect of the number of carbon atoms in the alkyl chain on the HER suppression and CO selectivity was investigated. Alkylamine functionalization successfully suppressed H2 evolution, while at the same time promoting CO production. This resulted in a 1 to 2 H2 to CO ratio for the catalyst functionalized with hexylamine, more favorable than for the pristine carbon-based catalyst (benchmark), able to generate only a 3.3 to 1 H2 to CO ratio. In chapter 5, the catalytic properties of oxide-derived silver nanowires, are explored. XRD and XPS analysis confirmed that by selecting the final potential during the oxidation procedure, both different silver oxidations states and different nanowires roughness were achieved as a function of the oxidation potential. This surface-modification procedure enhanced the catalytic properties of the nanowires. The active surface-normalized CO partial current density increased 3.7-times when the pristine nanowires were oxidized to 1.0 V vs Ag/AgCl in basic electrolyte solution.</description>
      <author>Francesco Mattarozzi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33540/2122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of organic cations in the electrochemical reduction of CO2 in aprotic solvents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-wl1bg</link>
      <description>James McGregor, Jay T. Bender, Amanda Petersen, Louise M. Ca&#241;ada, Jan Rossmeisl, Joan F. Brennecke, Joaquin Resasco, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392917891

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 is sensitive to the microenvironment surrounding catalytic active sites. Although the impact of changing electrolyte composition on CO2 reduction kinetics in aqueous electrolytes has been studied intensively, less is known about the influence of the electrochemical environment in non-aqueous solvents. Here, we present data demonstrating that organic alkyl ammonium cations influence catalytic performance in non-aqueous media and describe a physical model that rationalizes these observations. Using results from a combination of kinetic, spectroscopic, and computational techniques, we argue that the interfacial electric field present at the catalyst surface is sensitive to the molecular identity of the organic cation in the aprotic electrolyte. This is true irrespective of solvent, electrolyte ionic strength, or the supporting electrolyte counter anion. Our results suggest that changes in the interfacial field can be attributed to differences in the cation-electrode distance. Changes in the electric field strength are consequential to CO2R to CO as they modify the energetics of the kinetically relevant CO2 activation step.</description>
      <author>James McGregor, Jay T. Bender, Amanda Petersen, Louise M. Ca&#241;ada, Jan Rossmeisl, Joan F. Brennecke, Joaquin Resasco</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-wl1bg</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Strain in Electrocatalytic Materials for CO2 Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00514g</link>
      <description>Junshan Lin, Ning Zhang, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392813161

                The electrocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable carbon-based compounds has attracted considerable attention. In the quest for efficient electrocatalysts, strain engineering, characterized by localized relative deformation, emerges as...</description>
      <author>Junshan Lin, Ning Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00514g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the Electrochemical Reduction of Co2 on Au25(Sr)18- Nanocluster</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4761900</link>
      <description>Dominic Alfonso, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392876479

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dominic Alfonso</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4761900</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction on a copper foam electrode at elevated pressures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150478</link>
      <description>Nandalal Girichandran, Saeed Saedy, Ruud Kortlever, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392878167

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nandalal Girichandran, Saeed Saedy, Ruud Kortlever</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced non-metal catalyzed CO2 reduction on doped biphenylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.096</link>
      <description>Meng-Rong Li, Xinwei Chen, Zheng&#8208;Zhe Lin, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392820593

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meng-Rong Li, Xinwei Chen, Zheng&#8208;Zhe Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.096</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous designed metal-organic framework for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2&#8212;a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05468-7</link>
      <description>Shanker Babu, Abinaya Stalinraja, Takumi Nagasaka, Keerthiga Gopalram, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392817745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shanker Babu, Abinaya Stalinraja, Takumi Nagasaka, Keerthiga Gopalram</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05468-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consecutive Reduction of Five Carbon Dioxide Molecules by Gas-Phase Niobium Carbide Cluster Anions Nb&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;: Unusual Mechanism for Enhanced Reactivity by the Carbon Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00371</link>
      <description>Yiheng Zhang, Jia-Bi Ma, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392799839

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiheng Zhang, Jia-Bi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Potential of Suspension Electrodes for Enhanced Limiting Currents in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ya00611e</link>
      <description>Nathalie E. G. Ligthart, Gerard Prats Vergel, JT Johan Padding, David A. Vermaas, Energy advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392887580

                CO2 conversion is an important part of the transition towards clean fuels and chemicals. However, low solubility of CO2 in water and its slow diffusion cause mass transfer limitations in...</description>
      <author>Nathalie E. G. Ligthart, Gerard Prats Vergel, JT Johan Padding, David A. Vermaas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ya00611e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient photoelectrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formate via Bi-Doped InOCl nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174220</link>
      <description>Yibo Jia, Huimin Yang, Rui Chen, Yi Zhang, Fanfan Gao, Nan Cheng, Jiaqi Yang, Xuemei Gao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392975989

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yibo Jia, Huimin Yang, Rui Chen, Yi Zhang, Fanfan Gao, Nan Cheng, Jiaqi Yang, Xuemei Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphology Evolution of CuO Supported on CeO2 and Its Role in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-06473-x</link>
      <description>Seungwon Hong, Kshirodra Kumar Patra, Jihun Oh, JOM. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392794974

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seungwon Hong, Kshirodra Kumar Patra, Jihun Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-06473-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Blood Cell (RBC)-like Ni@N&#8211;C composites for Efficient Electrochemical CO2 Reduction and Zn-CO2 Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta08049h</link>
      <description>Lei Han, Chengwei Wang, Haiping Xu, Ming Yang, Bing Liu, Ming Liu, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392854289

                Developing high-activity and selectivity electrocatalysts for reducing CO2 to value-added products provides an alternative pathway to alleviate the energy crisis and greenhouse effect. Herein, we presented a ligand-assisted supermolecule-derived red...</description>
      <author>Lei Han, Chengwei Wang, Haiping Xu, Ming Yang, Bing Liu, Ming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta08049h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in Membrane Technologies for Enhanced Water Splitting and Co2 Reduction: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52783/jchr.v14.i2.3372</link>
      <description>, Journal of Chemical Health Risks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393005861

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52783/jchr.v14.i2.3372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 synergistic emission reduction and health benefits of PM2.5 reaching WHO-III level in Pearl River Delta</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2024.120441</link>
      <description>Yijia Zheng, Wei Zeng, Shucheng Chang, Long Wang, Calvin C.Y. Liao, Y. H. Zhang, Atmospheric Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392820920

                Protecting human health is one of the fundamental goals of continuous air quality improvement. Considering the same sources of CO2 and air pollutants emissions, their emission control measures often have a certain degree of synergistic emission reduction effects To balance the costs and policy efficiency, policy makers should assess the synergistic benefits of CO2 emission reduction when formulating air quality improvement strategies. Aimed at the air quality improvement strategy targeting WHO-III level (i.e. 15 &#956;g/m3) for PM2.5 in the Pearl River Delta (PRD) region, this study evaluates the synergistic CO2 reduction effects and the associated health benefits from this strategy which includes a range of air pollution prevention and control measures. The results of the study show that promoting the attainment of WHO-III for PM2.5 in the PRD region can bring about 74 Mt of synergistic CO2 emission reduction, resulting in an 18% reduction of CO2 emissions in the PRD compared to 2017. Among various measures considered, industrial restructuring, power supply transition and industrial energy consumption transformation exhibit the most pronounced synergistic effects. Therefore, these measures are recommended to be prioritized and promoted in the next stage of air pollution prevention and CO2 emission reduction. Furthermore, when the PM2.5 concentration in the PRD region reaches the WHO-III level, the number of PM2.5-related deaths will be estimated to reduce approximately 5.5 thousand compared to that in the current policy scenario. Through continuous structural transformation and emission reduction efforts, it not only facilitates the decline in regional PM2.5 concentration but also helps more regional residents to live in an environment with a relatively low PM2.5 concentration. In addition, in order to reduce the health impacts of PM2.5, it is recommended that the government should guide people to change their production and living styles in order to reduce pollutant emissions from anthropogenic activities.</description>
      <author>Yijia Zheng, Wei Zeng, Shucheng Chang, Long Wang, Calvin C.Y. Liao, Y. H. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2024.120441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Tuning of the Selectivity of Cu-Based Interface for Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction by Ligand Modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4760891</link>
      <description>Yonggao Yan, Tongxian Li, Manuel Oliva&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Yuguo Zhao, Shuo Wang, Xin Chen, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392973237

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yonggao Yan, Tongxian Li, Manuel Oliva&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Yuguo Zhao, Shuo Wang, Xin Chen, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4760891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi&#8208;metallic Layered Catalysts for Stable Electrochemical CO2 Reduction to Formate and Formic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301894</link>
      <description>Tu N. Nguyen, Behnam Nourmohammadi Khiarak, Zijun Xu, Amirhossein Farzi, Sharif Md. Sadaf, Ali Seifitokaldani, Cao-Thang Dinh, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392882857

                We report the development of bismuth (Bi) gas diffusion electrodes on a polytetrafluoroethylene&#8208;based electrically conductive silver (Ag) substrate (Ag@Bi), which exhibits high Faradaic efficiency (FE) for formate of over 90% in 1 M KOH and 1 M KHCO3 electrolytes. The catalyst also shows high selectivity of formic acid above 85% in 1 M NaCl catholyte, which has a bulk pH of 2&#8208;3 during ECR, at current densities up to 300 mA cm&#8208;2. In 1 M KHCO3 condition, the Ag@Bi maintains a formate FE above 90% for at least 500 hours at the current density of 100 mA cm&#8208;2. We found that Ag@Bi catalysts degrade over time due to the leaching of Bi in the NaCl catholyte. To overcome this challenge, we deposited a layer of Ag nanoparticles on the surface of Ag@Bi to form a multi&#8208;layer Ag@Bi/Ag catalyst. This designed catalyst exhibits 300 hours of stability with FE for formic acid &#8805; 70% at 100 mA cm&#8208;2. Our work establishes a new strategy for achieving the operational longevity of ECR under wide pH conditions, which is critical for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Tu N. Nguyen, Behnam Nourmohammadi Khiarak, Zijun Xu, Amirhossein Farzi, Sharif Md. Sadaf, Ali Seifitokaldani, Cao-Thang Dinh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transient Pulsed Discharge Preparation of Graphene Aerogel Supported Asymmetric Cu Cluster Catalysts Promote CO2 Reduction to Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3991307/v1</link>
      <description>Wenxing Chen, Kaiyuan Liu, Hao Shen, Zhiyi Sun, Qiang Zhang, Guoqiang Liu, Zhongti Sun, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392922115

                Abstract Precisely designing asymmetrical structure is an efficient strategy to optimize the performance of metallic catalysts for electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reactions. Herein, a transient high-density current induced by pulsed discharge is used to rapidly construct graphene aerogel (GAs) supported asymmetric Cu cluster catalysts. Cu atoms decomposed by CuCl 2 are converged on graphene surfaces in GAs together with oxygen originating from the intense current and instantaneous high temperature. The atomic and electronic structures of Cu nanoclusters exhibit asymmetric distribution due to lattice distortion and O-doping in Cu crystals. Typically, in CO 2 reduction reactions, the selectivity and activity of ethanol are related to the asymmetric structure and strong interfacial interaction of Cu-O/C moieties, exhibiting an ideal Faradaic efficiency (ethanol 75.3% and C 2+ products 90.5%) at -1.1 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). Meanwhile, the benefit of the strong interaction between Cu nanoclusters and GA supports, the catalyst exhibits long-term stability. In situ XAFS reveals that the Cu 4 -Cu/C 2 O 1 interaction displays the effective active sites in CO 2 RR. The pathways of corresponding products and the reaction mechanism on Cu 4 -Cu/C 2 O 1 moieties are revealed through the in situ attenuated total reflectance Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy and the calculation of density functional theory. This work gives a new solution to solve the challenge for balancing the activity and stability of asymmetric-structure catalysts toward energy conversion reactions.</description>
      <author>Wenxing Chen, Kaiyuan Liu, Hao Shen, Zhiyi Sun, Qiang Zhang, Guoqiang Liu, Zhongti Sun, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3991307/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulate the Adsorption of Oxygen-Containing Intermediates to Promote the Reduction of Co2 to Ch4 on Ni-Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4764056</link>
      <description>Hedan Yao, Liuyi Pan, Xi Yao, Wenhong Li, Yi Qin, Dong Li, Yingxia Wang, Wenjie Xue, Qianqian Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392955133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hedan Yao, Liuyi Pan, Xi Yao, Wenhong Li, Yi Qin, Dong Li, Yingxia Wang, Wenjie Xue, Qianqian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4764056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-doped Cu2O with the tunable Cu0 and Cu+sites for selective CO2 electrochemical reduction to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.03.012</link>
      <description>Yao Shen, Ling-Bo Qian, Qing Xu, S. S. Wang, Yong Chen, Hong L&#252;, Yingke Zhou, Jiexu Ye, Jingkai Zhao, Xiang Gao, Shihan Zhang, Journal of Environmental Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392894348

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Shen, Ling-Bo Qian, Qing Xu, S. S. Wang, Yong Chen, Hong L&#252;, Yingke Zhou, Jiexu Ye, Jingkai Zhao, Xiang Gao, Shihan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.03.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable preparation of Cu2O/Cu-CuTCPP MOF heterojunction for enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159937</link>
      <description>Miao Sun, Xiao Xu, Shihao Min, Jie He, Kun Li, Longtian Kang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392907560

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miao Sun, Xiao Xu, Shihao Min, Jie He, Kun Li, Longtian Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gram-scale synthesis of Ni-Zn diatomic sites catalyst for efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114050</link>
      <description>Jinchao Li, Zhipeng Cao, Xinai Zhang, Ling Gao, Xueling Li, Liang Chen, Yaping Zhang, Qingchun Zhang, Ping Zhang, Tianxia Liu, Molecular Catalysis. 558(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392930254

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinchao Li, Zhipeng Cao, Xinai Zhang, Ling Gao, Xueling Li, Liang Chen, Yaping Zhang, Qingchun Zhang, Ping Zhang, Tianxia Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Metalated Porphyrin-Based MOFs Coupled with Anatase as Photocatalysts for CO2 Reduction: The Effect of Metalation Proportion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17061483</link>
      <description>Maria Anagnostopoulou, Val&#233;rie Keller, Konstantinos C. Christoforidis, Energies. 17(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393006588

                Converting carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable chemicals such as fossil resources via photocatalysis requires the development of advanced materials. Herein, we coupled zirconium-based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) containing porphyrin and Cu-porphyrin with anatase TiO2. The effect of the porphyrin metalation proportion was also investigated. Notably, while the use of free-base porphyrin as the organic linker resulted in the development of PCN-224, the presence of Cu-porphyrin provided mixed-phase MOF structures containing both PCN-224 and PCN-222. MOF/TiO2 composites bearing partial (50%) metalated porphyrin were proven more active and selective towards the production of CH4, at ambient conditions, in the gas phase and using water vapors without the use of hole scavengers. The optimized composite bearing 15 wt.% of the partial metalated MOF was three times more active than pure TiO2 towards CH4 production. This study provides insights on the effect of precise materials engineering at a molecular level on the development of advanced MOF-based photocatalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Maria Anagnostopoulou, Val&#233;rie Keller, Konstantinos C. Christoforidis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17061483</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
