<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 01:19:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress and Future Perspectives of Ionic Liquid-Based Carbon Dioxide Capture and Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.10.002</link>
      <description>Anum Zafar, Karolina Matuszek, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Xinyi Zhang, Green Energy &amp; Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403426780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anum Zafar, Karolina Matuszek, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Xinyi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.10.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development and application of carbon dioxide direct mineralization technology and emission reduction device</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2853/1/012035</link>
      <description>Dongfang Li, Zheng Zhang, Zengyang Huang, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2853(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403451764

                Abstract This study analyzes the principles and methods of carbon dioxide mineralization fixation to address the challenges posed by global climate and ecological changes, achieve carbon neutrality goals, and solve carbon utilization issues in the development of the fluorosilicon new material industry. The research focuses on the direct mineralization reaction system of carbon dioxide flue gas and the development of a carbon dioxide emission reduction device utilizing wet mineralized gas treatment technology. To implement alkaline waste management for industrial solid waste. The research shows that the wet carbon dioxide mineralization and emission reduction device can make the alkaline solution better mineralize carbon dioxide, avoid the gas discharge too fast and affect the reaction rate. At the same time, the solution is mixed and the exhaust linkage is carried out to further improve the reaction rate, and provide a reference for the development of large-scale carbon dioxide utilization technology suitable for high energy consumption industries.</description>
      <author>Dongfang Li, Zheng Zhang, Zengyang Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2853/1/012035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Two-dimensional Tellurophosphates: Visible Light Photocatalysts for Water Splitting and Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105255</link>
      <description>Sajid Ur Rehman, Haris Habib, Zeeshan Tariq, Hafiz Muhammad Naeem Ullah, Faheem K. Butt, Xiaoming Zhang, Chuanbo Li, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403464897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sajid Ur Rehman, Haris Habib, Zeeshan Tariq, Hafiz Muhammad Naeem Ullah, Faheem K. Butt, Xiaoming Zhang, Chuanbo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of carbon dioxide to methane and ethanol on the surface of graphyne-like boron nitride (BNyen) monolayer: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112380</link>
      <description>Mohamed J. Saadh, Ahmed Mahal, Maha Mohammed Tawfiq, Abbas Hameed Abdul Hussein, Aseel Salah Mansoor, Usama Kadem Radi, Ahmad J. Obaidullah, Parminder Singh, Ahmed Elawady, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403330022

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohamed J. Saadh, Ahmed Mahal, Maha Mohammed Tawfiq, Abbas Hameed Abdul Hussein, Aseel Salah Mansoor, Usama Kadem Radi, Ahmad J. Obaidullah, Parminder Singh, Ahmed Elawady</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposition of Cu 3D structures suitable for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2024.35.2.1</link>
      <description>Birut&#279; Serapinien&#279;, Laurynas Stai&#353;i&#363;nas, Algirdas Selskis, Remi&#173;gi&#173;jus Ju&#353;k&#279;nas, L. Gudavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Jurga Juodkazyt&#279;, R. Ramanauskas, Chemija. 35(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403406643

                Porous Cu foam electrodes, suitable for cathodic CO2 reduction, were deposited in an acidic sulphate solution with different additives to obtain structures with a high real surface area and an adequate mechanical stability. The influence of the electrodeposition time and solution composition on the porosity parameters, microstructure and stiffness of Cu 3D structures was evaluated. Neither ammonium acetate nor polyethylene glycol were found to be effective additives to the Cu sulphate electrolyte to achieve the main objectives. Only the presence of Cl&#8211; ions in the deposition solution resulted in a threefold increase in the real surface area and the achievement of a sufficient mechanical stability of the Cu 3D structure. The latter effect is related to the specific influence of Cl&#8211; ions during the electrodeposition process on the microstructural characteristics, such as the size of micropores in the walls of holes and crystallite aggregates that form dendritic branches. These structural changes, in contrast to the Cu samples deposited in a solution without additives, resulted in larger real surface areas, while the denser structures deposited in the presence of Cl&#8211; ions ensured the mechanical stability of the 3D structure.</description>
      <author>Birut&#279; Serapinien&#279;, Laurynas Stai&#353;i&#363;nas, Algirdas Selskis, Remi&#173;gi&#173;jus Ju&#353;k&#279;nas, L. Gudavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Jurga Juodkazyt&#279;, R. Ramanauskas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2024.35.2.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring reaction mechanisms for CO2 reduction on Carbides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05592f</link>
      <description>Naveed Ashraf, Atef Iqbal, Younes Abghoui, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403330125

                The electrocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable fuels offers immense promise in pursuing sustainable energy solutions. The robustness and intriguing electronic properties of Transition metal carbides (TMCs) traditionally...</description>
      <author>Naveed Ashraf, Atef Iqbal, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05592f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling the Polarity of Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks to Promote Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416367</link>
      <description>Xiaolong Zhang, Junnan Chen, Xiaogang Wang, Yingjun Dong, Jiapeng Ji, Linbo Li, Ming Xue, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403335645

                The addition of polar functional groups to porous structures is an effective strategy for increasing the ability of metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) to capture CO2 by enhancing interactions between the dipoles of the polar functional groups and the quadrupoles of CO2. However, the potential of MOFs grafted to polar functional group to activate CO2 has not been investigated in the context of CO2 electrolysis. In this study, we report a mixed&#8208;ligand strategy to incorporate various functional groups in the MOFs. We found that substituents with strong polarity led to increased catalytic performance of electrochemical CO2 reduction for these polarized MOFs. Both experimental and theoretical evidence indicates that the presence of polar functional groups induces a charge redistribution in the micropores of MOFs. We have shown that higher electron densities of sp2&#8208;carbon atoms in benzimidazolate ligands reduces the energy barrier to generate *COOH, which is simultaneously controlled by the mass transfer of CO2. Our research offers an effective method of disrupting local electron neutrality in the pores of electrocatalysts/supports to activate CO2 under electrochemical conditions.</description>
      <author>Xiaolong Zhang, Junnan Chen, Xiaogang Wang, Yingjun Dong, Jiapeng Ji, Linbo Li, Ming Xue, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling the Polarity of Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks to Promote Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416367</link>
      <description>Xiaolong Zhang, Junnan Chen, Li Wang, Yingjun Dong, Jiapeng Ji, Linbo Li, Ming Xue, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403335649

                The addition of polar functional groups to porous structures is an effective strategy for increasing the ability of metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) to capture CO2 by enhancing interactions between the dipoles of the polar functional groups and the quadrupoles of CO2. However, the potential of MOFs grafted to polar functional group to activate CO2 has not been investigated in the context of CO2 electrolysis. In this study, we report a mixed&#8208;ligand strategy to incorporate various functional groups in the MOFs. We found that substituents with strong polarity led to increased catalytic performance of electrochemical CO2 reduction for these polarized MOFs. Both experimental and theoretical evidence indicates that the presence of polar functional groups induces a charge redistribution in the micropores of MOFs. We have shown that higher electron densities of sp2&#8208;carbon atoms in benzimidazolate ligands reduces the energy barrier to generate *COOH, which is simultaneously controlled by the mass transfer of CO2. Our research offers an effective method of disrupting local electron neutrality in the pores of electrocatalysts/supports to activate CO2 under electrochemical conditions.</description>
      <author>Xiaolong Zhang, Junnan Chen, Li Wang, Yingjun Dong, Jiapeng Ji, Linbo Li, Ming Xue, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT investigations of the MoS2 properties as photocatalyst for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4403445063</link>
      <description>R. Favre, Tangui Le Bahers, Pascal Raybaud, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4403445063

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Favre, Tangui Le Bahers, Pascal Raybaud</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4403445063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performing electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reactions at a high pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43979-024-00106-7</link>
      <description>Baoliang Chen, M. Feng, Yi&#8208;Ping Phoebe Chen, J.-L. Yang, Ya Liu, Carbon Neutrality. 3(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403401447

                Abstract Electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction technology offers an effective way to convert CO 2 into valuable chemicals and fuels, presenting a sustainable solution for carbon emissions. Current electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction technologies encounter significant issues such as salt precipitation and hydrogen evolution, which prevent energy conversion efficiency, selectivity, current density, and stability from simultaneously meeting industrial standards. In recent years, researchers have discovered that increasing the CO 2 pressure on the gas supply could enhance the coverage of the catalyst and activate more CO 2 reduction reaction sites on the catalyst surface, which provides a practical and effective approach for optimizing the energy conversion and mass transfer. In this review, we provide a comprehensive review of the development history and current status of high-pressure CO 2 electrocatalytic reduction technology, focusing on its reaction devices, catalytic performance, and reaction mechanisms. Furthermore, we summarize and offer insights into the most promising research avenues to propel the field forward.</description>
      <author>Baoliang Chen, M. Feng, Yi&#8208;Ping Phoebe Chen, J.-L. Yang, Ya Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43979-024-00106-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Riddle of the Sands: Co2 Emissions Reduction and California's Renewables Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4989267</link>
      <description>G. Cornelis van Kooten, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403466478

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. Cornelis van Kooten</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4989267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous C-doped C3N5 as a superior photocatalyst for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124701</link>
      <description>Aathira M. Sadanandan, Mohammed Fawaz, Nithinraj Panangattu Dharmarajan, Matej Hu&#353;, Gurwinder Singh, C. I. Sathish, Bla&#382; Likozar, Zhixuan Li, Ajanya M. Ruban, Chung&#8208;Hwan Jeon, Jae&#8208;Hun Yang, Prashant Kumar, Ajayan Vinu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403409752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aathira M. Sadanandan, Mohammed Fawaz, Nithinraj Panangattu Dharmarajan, Matej Hu&#353;, Gurwinder Singh, C. I. Sathish, Bla&#382; Likozar, Zhixuan Li, Ajanya M. Ruban, Chung&#8208;Hwan Jeon, Jae&#8208;Hun Yang, Prashant Kumar, Ajayan Vinu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to ethylene using cuprous oxide derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1482168</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Fei Dong, Dejun Fu, Zhifeng Zhang, Zhiqiang Wu, Hongjian Zhao, W. Liu, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403395491

                Copper-based materials play a vital role in the electrochemical transformation of CO 2 into C 2 /C 2+ compounds. In this study, cross-sectional octahedral Cu 2 O microcrystals were prepared in situ on carbon paper electrodes via electrochemical deposition. The morphology and integrity of the exposed crystal surface (111) were meticulously controlled by adjusting the deposition potential, time, and temperature. These cross-sectional octahedral Cu 2 O microcrystals exhibited high electrocatalytic activity for ethylene (C 2 H 4 ) production through CO 2 reduction. In a 0.1 M KHCO 3 electrolyte, the Faradaic efficiency for C 2 H 4 reached 42.0% at a potential of &#8722;1.376 V vs. RHE. During continuous electrolysis over 10 h, the FE (C 2 H 4 ) remained stable around 40%. During electrolysis, the fully exposed (111) crystal faces of Cu 2 O microcrystals are reduced to Cu 0 , which enhances C-C coupling and could serve as the main active sites for catalyzing the conversion of CO 2 to C 2 H 4 .</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Fei Dong, Dejun Fu, Zhifeng Zhang, Zhiqiang Wu, Hongjian Zhao, W. Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1482168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial photosynthetic system for diluted CO2 reduction in gas-solid phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53066-y</link>
      <description>Ya Wang, Jianxin Wei, Hong&#8208;Liang Tang, Luhua Shao, Long&#8722;Zhang Dong, Xiao-Yu Chu, Yanxia Jiang, Guiling Zhang, Fengming Zhang, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403328377

                Rational design of robust photocatalytic systems to direct capture and in-situ convert diluted CO2 from flue gas is a promising but challenging way to achieve carbon neutrality. Here, we report a new type of host-guest photocatalysts by integrating CO2-enriching ionic liquids and photoactive metal-organic frameworks PCN-250-Fe2M (M = Fe, Co, Ni, Zn, Mn) for artificial photosynthetic diluted CO2 reduction in gas-solid phase. As a result, [Emim]BF4(39.3 wt%)@PCN-250-Fe2Co exhibits a record high CO2-to-CO reduction rate of 313.34 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 under pure CO2 atmosphere and 153.42 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 under diluted CO2 (15%) with about 100% selectivity. In scaled-up experiments with 1.0 g catalyst and natural sunlight irradiation, the concentration of pure and diluted CO2 (15%) could be significantly decreased to below 85% and 10%, respectively, indicating its industrial application potential. Further experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that ionic liquids not only benefit CO2 enrichment, but also form synergistic effect with Co2+ sites in PCN-250-Fe2Co, resulting in a significant reduction in Gibbs energy barrier during the rate-determining step of CO2-to-CO conversion. Artificial photosynthetic diluted CO2 reduction from fuel gas is promising but challenging for carbon neutrality. Here, the authors report a host-guest system by integrating CO2-enriching ionic liquids and photoactive metal-organic frameworks, greatly enhancing CO2-to-CO conversion efficiency.</description>
      <author>Ya Wang, Jianxin Wei, Hong&#8208;Liang Tang, Luhua Shao, Long&#8722;Zhang Dong, Xiao-Yu Chu, Yanxia Jiang, Guiling Zhang, Fengming Zhang, Ya&#8208;Qian Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53066-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Photothermal Mxene-Derived Heterojunction for Boosted Co2 Reduction and Tunable Ch4 Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4984152</link>
      <description>Yixiang Zhao, Zhen Wang, Weirui Chen, Jiajia Wang, Yiming Tang, Laisheng Li, Jing Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403332924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yixiang Zhao, Zhen Wang, Weirui Chen, Jiajia Wang, Yiming Tang, Laisheng Li, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4984152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of CO2 emissions by recycling low-potential heat from the Benfield CO2 removal process at a natural gas hydrogen production plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-024-03032-5</link>
      <description>Dawid Hajduga, Lucjan Chmielarz, Marek Bugdol, Clean Technologies and Environmental Policy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403377287

                Abstract The EU policies related to CO 2 emission strictly define the stages of carbon neutrality achieving. According to these regulations, all production installations that emit carbon dioxide will be charged additional emission fees from 2026 to fully in 2035. Analysis of the increasing emission fees shows that in some industries incurring such additional costs will result in a lack of profitability of the products. Industries directly related to the food sector, such as nitrogen fertiliser production, are strategic in the economies of all countries. Nitrogen fertilisers are produced from ammonia, which is synthesised on a large scale from hydrogen and nitrogen. Hydrogen is produced by natural gas reforming with water vapour resulting in syngas (mixture of H 2 , CO, CO 2 , H 2 O), which CO in the next step reacts with water vapour (water gas shift reaction) producing H 2 and CO 2 . CO 2 is separated from hydrogen using the Benfield method. The analysis of the Benfield process (one process of hydrogen production) shows a possible way to reduce CO 2 emission by optimising heat balance. It was shown that in the proposed technology the heat recovery reaches 89%, while the level below 30% was reported for other available technologies. The proposed solution is based on recirculation and reuse of heat, which is lost in other technologies. The analysis is for a process balance in a medium-sized hydrogen production installation. The analysis considers also the correlations with other installations thermally linked to hydrogen production. The economic balance showed the great financial benefits of this solution. In the scenario discussed, the CO 2 emission factor was reduced by 20%. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Dawid Hajduga, Lucjan Chmielarz, Marek Bugdol</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-024-03032-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Capping Ligands on Metal-Nanoparticle-Driven Hydrogen Evolution and CO2 Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/3418_2024_116</link>
      <description>Gerard Mart&#237;, &#193;lvaro Lozano-Roche, Nuria Romero, Laia Franc&#224;s, Karine Philippot, Roger Bofill, Jordi Garc&#237;a&#8208;Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala, Topics in organometallic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403433128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gerard Mart&#237;, &#193;lvaro Lozano-Roche, Nuria Romero, Laia Franc&#224;s, Karine Philippot, Roger Bofill, Jordi Garc&#237;a&#8208;Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/3418_2024_116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Charge Delivery within Covalently Ligated Cobalt Phthalocyanine Electrocatalyst for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03220a</link>
      <description>Alena Kochubei, Aleksei N. Marianov, Yuming Wu, Mengxin Liu, Haoyue Sun, Jun Huang, Oliver J. Conquest, Teng Lu, Yun Liu, Catherine Stampfl, Yijiao Jiang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403460694

                Cobalt(II) phthalocyanine (CoPc) complexes are some of the most active catalysts for CO2 electroreduction reaction (CO2ERR). However, these organic complexes are non-conductive, thus the CO2ERR rate is hindered by the...</description>
      <author>Alena Kochubei, Aleksei N. Marianov, Yuming Wu, Mengxin Liu, Haoyue Sun, Jun Huang, Oliver J. Conquest, Teng Lu, Yun Liu, Catherine Stampfl, Yijiao Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03220a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Structural Dynamics of Cu@Ag Core-Shell Nanoparticles during CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926022</link>
      <description>Daniel Arenas Esteban, Lien Pacquets, Daniel Choukroun, Saskia Hoekx, Ajinkya Kadu, Jonathan Schalck, Nick Daems, Tom Breugelmans, Sara Bals, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496461

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel Arenas Esteban, Lien Pacquets, Daniel Choukroun, Saskia Hoekx, Ajinkya Kadu, Jonathan Schalck, Nick Daems, Tom Breugelmans, Sara Bals</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Construction of Cubi-Mof Derived Heterojunctions with Electron-Rich Effects Enhances Localized Co2 Enrichment Integrated with Si Photocathodes for Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4987328</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Jingwei Hong, Jing Shang, Hiromi Yamashita, Chaohai Wei, Yun Hang Hu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403385945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Jingwei Hong, Jing Shang, Hiromi Yamashita, Chaohai Wei, Yun Hang Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4987328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-controlled formation of NixPy catalyst using environmental TEM for potential application in CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926038</link>
      <description>Kshipra Sharma, Tianyi Hu, Kimberly A. Dick, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496672

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kshipra Sharma, Tianyi Hu, Kimberly A. Dick</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ TEM/EELS and spatially resolved XAS/XRF analysis of CuO electrocatalyst for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412925028</link>
      <description>M. Schuster, Gea T. van de Kerkhof, Angela E. Goode, Ur&#353;a Podbev&#353;ek, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496016

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Schuster, Gea T. van de Kerkhof, Angela E. Goode, Ur&#353;a Podbev&#353;ek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412925028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical reduction of nitrate to ammonia using Fe-based catalyst: insights into N2, CO2, and CO environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114482</link>
      <description>Seon Young Hwang, Gaeun Yun, So Young Kim, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403457588

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seon Young Hwang, Gaeun Yun, So Young Kim, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114482</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stimulating the C&#8722;C coupling ability of ultrafine copper nanoclusters via nitrogen coordination for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124704</link>
      <description>Yanan Cao, Guodong Sun, Mingzhen Hu, Zhe Wang, Xiaoxin Yang, Xinhu Liang, Zengjian Cai, Hao Ren, Fengyi Shen, Dan Cheng, Kebin Zhou, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403409751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Cao, Guodong Sun, Mingzhen Hu, Zhe Wang, Xiaoxin Yang, Xinhu Liang, Zengjian Cai, Hao Ren, Fengyi Shen, Dan Cheng, Kebin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep decarbonization strategy for synergistic reduction of CO2 and air pollutant emissions in metropolises: A case study of Suzhou, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esd.2024.101575</link>
      <description>Feiyue Qian, Yan Zhu, Cui Da, Xinrui Zheng, Zhiming Liu, Chunchen Lu, Yuanyuan Cheng, Chuanming Yang, Energy Sustainable Development/Energy for sustainable development. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403365101

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feiyue Qian, Yan Zhu, Cui Da, Xinrui Zheng, Zhiming Liu, Chunchen Lu, Yuanyuan Cheng, Chuanming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esd.2024.101575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photoelectrochemical CO2 reduction activity towards selective generation of alcohols over CuxO/SrTiO3 heterojunction photocathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solmat.2024.113203</link>
      <description>Guguloth Venkanna, Sovan Kumar Patra, Gajanan U. Kapure, Kamal K. Pant, Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells. 278(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403385242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guguloth Venkanna, Sovan Kumar Patra, Gajanan U. Kapure, Kamal K. Pant</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solmat.2024.113203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO2 Reduction via S-Scheme Heterojunction of Amorphous/Crystalline Metal-free Carbon Nitride Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156777</link>
      <description>Liting Wu, Dingyi Yang, Yalin Dong, Ze Wang, Yu Zhang, Tingting Wang, Liang Cheng, Yong Wang, Yizhang Wu, Chemical Engineering Journal. 500(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403503972

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liting Wu, Dingyi Yang, Yalin Dong, Ze Wang, Yu Zhang, Tingting Wang, Liang Cheng, Yong Wang, Yizhang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando TEM Studies of Re@Cu2O-SnO2 catalysts during CO2 reduction reaction with optimized liquid flow configuration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926012</link>
      <description>Cecilia Irene Gho, Katarzyna Bejtka, Marco Fontana, Maria J. Lopez Tendero, Alberto Lopera L&#243;pez, Roger Mir&#243;, Miriam D&#237;az de los Bernardos, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Stefan Merkens, Andrey Chuvilin, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Angelica Chiodoni, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403497223

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cecilia Irene Gho, Katarzyna Bejtka, Marco Fontana, Maria J. Lopez Tendero, Alberto Lopera L&#243;pez, Roger Mir&#243;, Miriam D&#237;az de los Bernardos, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Stefan Merkens, Andrey Chuvilin, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Angelica Chiodoni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the effect of CO2 and H2O on NO reduction of biomass char by the equivalent characteristic spectrum method via an on-line mass spectrometer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.133438</link>
      <description>Guangming Chen, Wang Chuanhao, Shiyuan Li, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403329993

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guangming Chen, Wang Chuanhao, Shiyuan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.133438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Electrocatalyst Modified with Pyridinium-Based Ionic Liquids for the Efficient Synthesis of Ethylene Through Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4984145</link>
      <description>Ruining He, Xiantao Yang, Kelei Huang, Jing Xu, Zhangfa Tong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403332957

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruining He, Xiantao Yang, Kelei Huang, Jing Xu, Zhangfa Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4984145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting selectivity for multi-carbon products in electrochemical CO2 reduction via enhanced hydroxide adsorption in ultrafine CuOx/CeOx Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114445</link>
      <description>Harshad A. Bandal, Mintesinot Dessalegn Dabaro, Hern Kim, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403424715

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harshad A. Bandal, Mintesinot Dessalegn Dabaro, Hern Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction on Single-Atom aluminum catalysts supported on graphene and N-doped Graphene: Mechanistic insights and hydration effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161523</link>
      <description>Shiuan&#8208;Yau Wu, Tsai-Chun Chuang, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403427125

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiuan&#8208;Yau Wu, Tsai-Chun Chuang, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zif-67-Derived Nico2o4 Hollow Nanocages Coupled with G-C3n4 Nanosheets as Z-Scheme Photocatalysts for Enhancing Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4984154</link>
      <description>Fanwei Meng, Chao Qu, Lanyang Wang, Decai Yang, Zezhong Zhao, Qingsong Ye, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403332941

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fanwei Meng, Chao Qu, Lanyang Wang, Decai Yang, Zezhong Zhao, Qingsong Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4984154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Molecular Dispersion of Crown Ether&#8208;Decorated Cobalt Phthalocyanineon Carbon Nanotubes for Robust CO2 Reduction through Host&#8208;Guest Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418156</link>
      <description>&#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403494193

                Immobilizing molecular catalysts on electro&#8208;conductive supports (for example, multi&#8208;walled carbon nanotubes, CNTs) represent a promising way to well&#8208;defined catalyst/support interfaces, which has shown appreciable performance for catalytic transformation. However, their full potential is far from achieved due to insufficient utilization of the intrinsic activity for each immobilized molecular catalyst, especially at loadings that should allow decent current densities. In the present work, we discover host&#8208;guest interaction between tetra&#8208;crown ether substituted cobalt phthalocyanine and metal ions, for example K+ ions, not only eliminate catalyst aggregation at immobilization procedures but also reinforce catalyst/support interactions by additional electrostatic attractions under operational conditions. Through simple dip&#8208;coating procedures, a successful single&#8208;molecular dispersion is achieved. Such a catalyst/electrode interface is stable and can selectively catalyze CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion (&#65310;96%) with almost unchanged turnover frequency (TOF) at all loading conditions, which implies a full utilization of the intrinsic activity of supported molecular catalysts. Therefore, a simultaneous achievement of high TOF and high current density (TOF of 111 s&#8208;1 at 38 mA/cm2) is achieved, in an aqueous H&#8208;type electrolyzer at an overpotential of 570 mV.</description>
      <author>&#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Molecular Dispersion of Crown Ether&#8208;Decorated Cobalt Phthalocyanineon Carbon Nanotubes for Robust CO2 Reduction through Host&#8208;Guest Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418156</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403494457

                Immobilizing molecular catalysts on electro&#8208;conductive supports (for example, multi&#8208;walled carbon nanotubes, CNTs) represent a promising way to well&#8208;defined catalyst/support interfaces, which has shown appreciable performance for catalytic transformation. However, their full potential is far from achieved due to insufficient utilization of the intrinsic activity for each immobilized molecular catalyst, especially at loadings that should allow decent current densities. In the present work, we discover host&#8208;guest interaction between tetra&#8208;crown ether substituted cobalt phthalocyanine and metal ions, for example K+ ions, not only eliminate catalyst aggregation at immobilization procedures but also reinforce catalyst/support interactions by additional electrostatic attractions under operational conditions. Through simple dip&#8208;coating procedures, a successful single&#8208;molecular dispersion is achieved. Such a catalyst/electrode interface is stable and can selectively catalyze CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion (&#65310;96%) with almost unchanged turnover frequency (TOF) at all loading conditions, which implies a full utilization of the intrinsic activity of supported molecular catalysts. Therefore, a simultaneous achievement of high TOF and high current density (TOF of 111 s&#8208;1 at 38 mA/cm2) is achieved, in an aqueous H&#8208;type electrolyzer at an overpotential of 570 mV.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concentration of carbon dioxide in products of combustion of GTE NK-16ST and NK-16-18ST</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31772/2712-8970-2023-24-4-697-705</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1072;&#1082;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Siberian Aerospace Journal. 24(4)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4403393562

                This paper considers the design of two combustion chambers of a gas turbine engine running on natural gas. One combustion chamber has 32 burners, and the other has 136 nozzles located in two rows in the flame tube head. A major contributor to global warming is considered to be the significant emissions of greenhouse gases, primarily CO2, including those emitted by gas turbine engines and power plants. The reduction of carbon dioxide levels by developing a set of structural measures in the combustion chamber is one of the urgent tasks of engine construction which requires a solution in order to meet modern environmental requirements for gas turbine engines serving as blower drives for gas compressor units. The presented research is dedicated to the analysis of influence of changes in combustion chamber design on reduction of &#1057;&#1054;2 level in exhaust gases of gas turbine engine NK-16ST. Two modifications of the combustion chamber are considered. The first one was a serial combustion chamber with diffusion combustion, the second one was a modernized combustion chamber with a modified front device. Each of the chambers considered was tested as part of the engine. During the study, combustion products were sampled directly in the exhaust shaft and their concentrations, including the CO2 content, were determined. As a result of this work, it was confirmed that there is a possibility to reduce the concentration of CO2 in the engine combustion products up to 20 % without affecting the engine parameters. This reduction in carbon dioxide content was made possible by reducing the completeness of fuel combustion in the combustion chamber. The obtained data on changes in CO2 concentration can be useful in selecting the most suitable mode of engine operation, and the presented approaches to combustion processes organization can be used by developers in designing combustion chambers of natural gas-fired gas turbine engines.</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1072;&#1082;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31772/2712-8970-2023-24-4-697-705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A hybrid electro-thermochemical device for methane production from the air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53336-9</link>
      <description>Yao&#8208;Wei Huang, Da Xu, Shuai Deng, Meng Lin, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403467171

                Coupling direct air capture (DAC) with methane (CH4) production is a potential strategy for fuel production from the air. Here, we report a hybrid electro-thermochemical device for direct CH4 production from air. The proposed device features the cogeneration of carbon dioxide (CO2) and hydrogen (H2) in a single compartment via a bipolar membrane electrodialysis module, avoiding a separate water electrolyzer, followed by a thermochemical methanation reaction to produce CH4. H2-induced disturbances lead to efficient CO2 extraction without pumping requirement. The energy consumption and techno-economic analysis predict an energy reduction of 37.8% for DAC and a cost reduction of 36.6% compared with the decoupled route, respectively. Accordingly, CH4 cost is reduced by 12.6%. Our proof-of-concept experiments show that the energy consumption for CO2 release and H2 production is 704.0 kJ mol&#8722;1 and 967.4 kJ mol&#8722;1, respectively with subsequent methanation achieving a 97.3% conversion of CO2 and a CH4 production energy of 5206.4 kJ mol&#8722;1 showing a promising pathway for fuel processing from the air. Direct capture and conversion of CO2 from the atmosphere is appealing to realize negative emissions but challenging due to the inherent low CO2 concentration. Here, authors report a proof-of-concept hybrid electro-thermochemical device for direct CH4 production from the air.</description>
      <author>Yao&#8208;Wei Huang, Da Xu, Shuai Deng, Meng Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53336-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel ionic liquids phase change absorption system for carbon dioxide capture and utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132832</link>
      <description>Yuqing Chang, Yujiao Wu, Ruoke Liu, Jian Shen, Zhijun Zhou, Tianlin Wang, Xiaochun Chen, Fuel. 377(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403366057

                In order to achieve low cost, and reduce energy consumption during regeneration, a novel ionic liquid phase change absorbent composed of tetraethylenepentamine [TEPA] imidazole [Im] and diethylene glycol dimethyl ether (DGME) and water was designed for CO2 capture applications. The absorbent [TEPAH][Im]+DM+H2O can achieves a CO2 absorption capacity of 2.08 mol CO2/mol ILs, the rich phase volume accounts for 15.6 vol%, and the mass fraction of CO2 is 99 %, this greatly reduces the regenerative volume of the absorption system, showing the potential of energy saving and emission reduction. After five absorption&#8211;desorption cycles, the regeneration efficiency of the system remained above 96 %. The CO2 capture mechanism was analyzed using both 13C NMR spectroscopy and density functional theory (DFT) calculations to elucidate its underlying processes. The cation [TEPAH]+ and the anion [Im]- each undergo a reaction with CO2 to produce carbamate, followed by hydrolysis of carbon dioxide to yield carbonate. The absorption system's phase transition behavior primarily arises from variations in CO2 product solubility across solvents. Moreover, the ionic liquid facilitated the conversion of CO2 into quinazoline-2,4 (1H, 3H)-dione with a remarkable yield of 98 %. Even after five cycles, the ILs maintained substantial catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Yuqing Chang, Yujiao Wu, Ruoke Liu, Jian Shen, Zhijun Zhou, Tianlin Wang, Xiaochun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re-Imagining Trade Policy and Energy Efficiency: Groundbreaking Pathways to Strengthen Environmental Sustainability in South Korea</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14209443</link>
      <description>Dongxue Wang, Yugang He, Applied Sciences. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403491441

                This study explores the long-term interplay between trade policy, energy efficiency, and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions in South Korea, using data spanning from 1985 to 2023. By applying the Fourier autoregressive distributed lag (FARDL) model, the analysis reveals that while trade liberalization initially leads to a 0.23% increase in CO2 emissions for each 1% rise in trade openness&#8212;driven by the energy demands of industrial expansion&#8212;integrating energy efficiency standards within trade agreements helps mitigate these effects over time; this results in a 0.26% reduction in emissions for every 1% improvement in energy efficiency. The study also highlights the dual role of foreign direct investment (FDI), which contributes to a short-term 0.08% rise in emissions but significantly reduces carbon intensity in the long term by facilitating the adoption of cleaner technologies. These findings underscore the importance of innovation and FDI in decoupling economic growth from environmental degradation. The study advocates for the incorporation of energy efficiency measures into trade agreements and the prioritization of green technologies, recommending strategies that could enable South Korea to reduce its CO2 emissions by up to 40% by 2030. This research positions South Korea as a key actor in achieving global climate goals while maintaining economic competitiveness, offering valuable insights into the balance between sustainable development and industrial growth.</description>
      <author>Dongxue Wang, Yugang He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14209443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing CO2 Emission of POME Treatment System Using MILP Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.1065.v1</link>
      <description>Sivakumar Pallikodathan, Hasfalina Che Man, Tinia Idaty, A. B. R. Sulaiman, Gunasilan Nagarajoo, Mohamad Firdza Shukery, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403439460

                This paper presents a strategic planning model aimed at optimizing the economic and environmental impacts of Palm Oil Mill Effluent (POME) treatment systems. The model determines the optimal selection of POME treatment systems to minimize environmental impact, specifically focusing on three systems: Anaerobic Digester Tank System (ADT), Covered Lagoon System (CL) with biogas capture, and Open Pond System (OP). The model incorporates constraints related to Fresh Fruit Bunch (FFB) production, POME generation, Biological Oxygen Demand (BOD), Chemical Oxygen Demand (COD), and Carbon Dioxide (CO2) emissions. The optimization framework, formulated as a mixed-integer linear programming (MILP) model, is solved using the GAMS 40.1.0 software. Integer decision variables are used to represent the choice of POME treatment systems that minimize environmental impact. The study specifically considers the ADT, CL, and OP systems, with results indicating that the ADT system is the most effective in reducing BOD, COD, and CO2 equivalent emissions, thereby highlighting its environmental benefits. The model has selected the ADT treatment system, which exhibits the lowest COD, BOD and CO2e emissions. Specifically, the COD registered an 85% reduction rate from 84,830 mg/L to 12,725 mg/L. The BOD level was reduced by 88% resulting in a BOD level from 41,208 mg/L to 4,945 mg/L. The minimum CO2e emission that can be archived was about 3,034 t CO2e per annum. This model provides a valuable tool for governmental agencies and policymakers to guide the private sector in developing environmentally sustainable POME treatment strategies.</description>
      <author>Sivakumar Pallikodathan, Hasfalina Che Man, Tinia Idaty, A. B. R. Sulaiman, Gunasilan Nagarajoo, Mohamad Firdza Shukery</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.1065.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freestanding Germanium Photonic Crystal Waveguide for a Highly Sensitive and Compact Mid-Infrared On-Chip Gas Sensor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssensors.4c00941</link>
      <description>Inki Kim, Jinha Lim, Joonsup Shim, Juhyuk Park, Seung&#8208;Yeop Ahn, Hyeong-Rak Lim, Sanghyeon Kim, ACS Sensors. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403471605

                The performance of mid-infrared (MIR) on-chip gas sensors, operating via laser absorption spectroscopy, hinges critically on light&#8211;matter interaction dynamics, significantly influenced by external confinement and the effective light path length. Conventional on-chip sensors, however, face challenges in achieving the required limit of detection for highly sensitive applications, primarily due to their intrinsically short effective light path. Furthermore, these sensors are limited in their spectral range coverage within the MIR spectrum by the constraints of standard silicon-based platforms. To overcome these limitations, our research presents a novel approach to fabricate a freestanding germanium (Ge) photonic crystal waveguide (PCW) on a germanium-on-insulator (Ge&#8211;OI) platform, utilizing yttrium oxide (Y2O3) as the buried oxide layer. This device leverages the broad transparent windows of Ge and Y2O3, broadening the spectral coverage across the MIR range. The introduction of the PCW and its slow light effect significantly elevate external confinement and light&#8211;matter interactions, enabling a notable reduction in waveguide length, which traditionally limits on-chip configurations. The freestanding structure not only expands the sensing region and enhances external confinement but also prevents the emergence of leaky modes within the PCW. As a result, our compact sensor achieves an exceptionally low LoD of 7.56 ppm for carbon dioxide (CO2) sensing at the operational wavelength of 4.23 &#956;m, with a compact waveguide length of only 800 &#956;m.</description>
      <author>Inki Kim, Jinha Lim, Joonsup Shim, Juhyuk Park, Seung&#8208;Yeop Ahn, Hyeong-Rak Lim, Sanghyeon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssensors.4c00941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dry Reforming of Methane (DRM) over Hydrotalcite-Based Ni-Ga/(Mg, Al)Ox Catalysts: Tailoring Ga Content for Improved Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100721</link>
      <description>Ahmed Yagoub Elnour, Ahmed E. Abasaeed, Anis H. Fakeeha, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Salwa B. Alreshaidan, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403455288

                Dry reforming of methane (DRM) is a promising way to convert methane and carbon dioxide into syngas, which can be further utilized to synthesize value-added chemicals. One of the main challenges for the DRM process is finding catalysts that are highly active and stable. This study explores the potential use of Ni-based catalysts modified by Ga. Different Ni-Ga/(Mg, Al)Ox catalysts, with various Ga/Ni molar ratios (0, 0.1, 0.3, 0.5, and 1), were synthesized by the co-precipitation method. The catalysts were tested for the DRM reaction to evaluate their activity and stability. The Ni/(Mg, Al)Ox and its Ga-modified Ni-Ga/(Mg, Al)Ox were characterized by N2 adsorption&#8211;desorption, Fourier Transform Infrared Spectroscopy (FTIR), H2-temperature-programmed reduction (TPR), X-ray diffraction (XRD), thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) and Raman techniques. The test of catalytic activity, at 700 &#176;C, 1 atm, GHSV of 42,000 mL/h/g, and a CH4: CO2 ratio of 1, revealed that Ga incorporation effectively enhanced the catalyst stability. Particularly, the Ni-Ga/(Mg, Al)Ox catalyst with Ga/Ni ratio of 0.3 exhibited the best catalytic performance, with CH4 and CO2 conversions of 66% and 74%, respectively, and an H2/CO ratio of 0.92. Furthermore, the CH4 and CO2 conversions increased from 34% and 46%, respectively, when testing at 600 &#176;C, to 94% and 96% when the catalytic activity was operated at 850 &#176;C. The best catalyst&#8217;s 20 h stream performance demonstrated its great stability. DFT analysis revealed an alteration in the electronic properties of nickel upon Ga incorporation, the d-band center of the Ga modified catalyst (Ga/Ni ratio of 0.3) shifted closer to the Fermi level, and a charge transfer from Ga to Ni atoms was observed. This research provides valuable insights into the development of Ga-modified catalysts and emphasizes their potential for efficient conversion of greenhouse gases into syngas.</description>
      <author>Ahmed Yagoub Elnour, Ahmed E. Abasaeed, Anis H. Fakeeha, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Salwa B. Alreshaidan, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Modeling of the Fluids Petroleum Flow Through the Supersonic Separator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47191/ijmcr/v12i10.01</link>
      <description>Doru B&#226;rsan, Timur Chis, Lauren&#539;iu Prodea, INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MATHEMATICS AND COMPUTER RESEARCH. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403337791

                In the context of increasing concerns regarding the amplification of the thermal effects of climate change, the Council of the European Union has proposed the reduction (up to the elimination) of the use of fossil fuels. For this purpose, the implementation of new ecological (renewable) fuels is being analyzed to reduce the carbon dioxide footprint, natural gas being the transition fuel. Also, in the next period, an increase in the demand for methane, the exploitation of condensate deposits, those with natural gas mixed with acid gases (containing hydrogen sulfide, carbon dioxide, and nitrogen), as well as oil deposits with associated natural gas, which will require their treatment (to eliminate saline or non-saline water, mechanical impurities, of condensate and acid gases). At the same time, the exploitation of offshore deposits in deep waters will be emphasized, which will lead to the location of treatment equipment on the seabed. The present work discusses the simulation of natural gas treatment processes, focusing on the separation from methane (in the supersonic field) of water, condensate, and acid gases.</description>
      <author>Doru B&#226;rsan, Timur Chis, Lauren&#539;iu Prodea</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47191/ijmcr/v12i10.01</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental investigation of dodecanoic acid&#8211;tetradecanoic acid&#8211;dodecanol ternary mixture based nanoparticle enriched-phase change material for food preservation applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/09544089241285099</link>
      <description>Nilesh Kumar Jain, Deepak Paliwal, Pankaj Jain, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers Part E Journal of Process Mechanical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403374824

                In this research, a novel phase change material (PCM), containing dodecanoic acid-tetradecanoic acid-dodecanol ternary mixture, designated as pure mixture, dispersed with two carbon-based nanoparticles, i.e., graphene nanoplatelets - multiwall carbon nanotube and graphene nanoplatelets-titanium dioxide, with 1% weight fraction, is prepared and is designated as nanoparticle-enriched-phase change material. The chemical and thermal analysis of pure ternary mixture and nanoparticle-enriched-phase change material was conducted using X-ray diffraction, Scanning electron microscopy, Differential scanning calorimetry, Fourier transform infrared, Thermo gravimetric analyser and Thermal conductivity analyser techniques. The pure mixture possess melting and freezing temperature of 15.6&#176;C and 8.4&#176;C with a melting-freezing latent heat (LH) of 131.5 J/g and 125.4 J/g, respectively. The thermal conductivity exhibited a significant increase of 187.6% in the case of pure mixture with graphene nanoplatelets- multiwall carbon nanotube and 41.7% for pure mixture with graphene nanoplatelets-titanium dioxide. Moreover, the PCM remained thermally stable in both cases, even with the incorporation of nanoparticles. The melting as well as freezing LHs were reduced by about 18.17% and 18.02% for graphene nanoplatelets- multiwall carbon nanotube dispersed PCM and, 12.49% and 9.49% for graphene nanoplatelets- titanium dioxide dispersed PCM, respectively, in comparison with the pure mixture. Similarly, the melting/freezing temperatures, gets also reduced by 9.6%/8.3% and 10.9%/8.3%, respectively, for both mixtures. The pure mixture with graphene nanoplatelets- multiwall carbon nanotube exhibited a substantial decrease in both charging and discharging times, with reductions of 28.48% and 18.73%, respectively, in comparison to pure mixture, at an air inlet velocity of 3 m/s.</description>
      <author>Nilesh Kumar Jain, Deepak Paliwal, Pankaj Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/09544089241285099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of green credit policy on carbon emissions based on China&#8217;s provincial panel data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-73942-3</link>
      <description>Xuerui Yang, Lianmei Zhu, Tong Wei, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403432116

                The attainment of "carbon peaking" and "carbon neutrality" is of utmost significance for the optimal progress of China's economy. As the main channel for green finance, the carbon reduction effectiveness of green credit policy is worth discussing. This article constructs an analytical framework for green credit, carbon emissions and technological advancement. Based on panel data from 30 provincial administrative regions in China from 2012 to 2021, this article uses the mediation effect model and the Spatial Durbin Model to investigate the transmission mechanism and spatial spillover effect of green credit policies on carbon emissions. According to baseline regression model results, our study revealed that overall, carbon emissions were reduced by green credit. The spatial spillover effect of green credit on carbon emissions points to the interconnectedness of different regions in terms of environmental impact. The significant negative indirect effect indicates that the increase of local green credit also has a significant inhibitory effect on surrounding carbon dioxide emissions. It suggests that efforts to reduce carbon emissions in one area can have positive consequences for neighboring regions as well. Green credit is able to reduce carbon emissions indirectly via technological advancement, according to the mechanism testing mediation effect model. This paper presents policy recommendations for relevant departments.</description>
      <author>Xuerui Yang, Lianmei Zhu, Tong Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-73942-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing copper waste to develop silicon-carbon anode materi als for lithium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52304/.v26i3.538</link>
      <description>M. M. Kurbanov, A. Avvalboev, I. Ashurov, U. Choriev, &#1061;. &#1041;. &#1040;&#1096;&#1091;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Penghui Ji, &#171;&#1059;&#1079;&#1073;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1081; &#1092;&#1080;&#1079;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1081; &#1078;&#1091;&#1088;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083;&#187;. 26(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403372153

                This study dedicated to a novel method for synthesizing silicon-carbon (Si/C) and silicon dioxide-carbon (SiO2/C) nanocomposite anodes for lithium-ion batteries, utilizing industrial copper slags from the Almalyk Mining and Metallurgical Complex as a cost-effective source of SiO2. The synthesized nanocomposites address key challenges in lithium-ion battery anodes, including the volumetric expansion of silicon and its low conductivity, by leveraging the high lithiation capacity of silicon combined with the structural stability and conductivity of carbon. Amorphous SiO3 was extracted from copper slags via ammonium fluoride (NH4F) treatment and subsequently reduced to metallurgical-grade silicon through carbothermal reduction. The resulting SiO2/C and Si/C composites were thoroughly characterized using SEM, XRD, and electrochemical analyses, demonstrating improved electrochemical performance, favorable particle size distribution, and stability. This approach not only reduces material costs but also promotes environmental sustainability by repurposing industrial waste, offering promising candidates for high-performance lithium-ion battery anodes.</description>
      <author>M. M. Kurbanov, A. Avvalboev, I. Ashurov, U. Choriev, &#1061;. &#1041;. &#1040;&#1096;&#1091;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Penghui Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52304/.v26i3.538</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrate-dependent antimony oxidase in an uncultured &lt;i&gt;Symbiobacteriaceae&lt;/i&gt; member</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae204</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Zhipeng Yin, Wei Ma, Jialong Hao, Fei Tian, Jianbo Shi, The ISME Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403469138

                Abstract Autotrophic antimony (Sb) oxidation coupled to nitrate reduction plays an important role in the transformation and detoxification of Sb. However, the specific oxidase involved in this process has yet to be identified. Herein, we enriched the microbiota capable of nitrate-dependent Sb(III) oxidation and identified a new Sb(III) oxidase in an uncultured member of Symbiobacteriaceae. Incubation experiments demonstrated that nitrate-dependent Sb(III) oxidation occurred in the microcosm supplemented with Sb(III) and nitrate. Both the 16S rRNA gene and metagenomic analyses indicated that a species within Symbiobacteriaceae played a crucial role in this process. Furthermore, carbon-13 isotope labelling with carbon dioxide-fixing Rhodopseudomonas palustris in combination with nanoscale secondary ion mass spectrometry revealed that a newly characterized oxidase from the dimethylsulfoxide reductase family, designated as NaoABC, was responsible for autotrophic Sb(III) oxidation coupled with nitrate reduction. The NaoABC complex functions in conjunction with the nitrate reductase NarGHI, forming a redox loop that transfers electrons from Sb(III) to nitrate, thereby generating the energy necessary for autotrophic growth. This research offers new insights into the understanding of how microbes link Sb and nitrogen biogeochemical cycles in the environment.</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Zhipeng Yin, Wei Ma, Jialong Hao, Fei Tian, Jianbo Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in the understanding of selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.67</link>
      <description>Ruihu Lu, Yan Liu, Ziyun Wang, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403350545

                Abstract The electrochemical synthesis for value&#8208;added chemicals and fuels via carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) offers an effective route to close the anthropogenic carbon cycle and store renewable energy. Currently, the copper&#8208;based catalyst is still the only choice for generating various CO 2 RR species beyond two electron products. However, the wide range of CO 2 RR products generated on copper leads to low selectivity, and their low concentrations in electrolytes pose great costs in the downstream purification process and significantly challenge the scalability of this technology. To make this technology economically viable, enhancing product selectivity is crucial. In this review, we identify the primary CO 2 RR species and discuss the latest insights into the reaction mechanisms controlling CO 2 RR selectivity. Then, we examined factors that affect CO 2 RR selectivity. Emphasizing these factors in catalyst design, we highlight the importance of advanced technologies to expand our knowledge and prospects for the future of the CO 2 RR.</description>
      <author>Ruihu Lu, Yan Liu, Ziyun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.67</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst Design and Engineering for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;to&#8208;Formic Acid Electrosynthesis for a Low&#8208;Carbon Economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404980</link>
      <description>Karthik Peramaiah, Moyu Yi, Indranil Dutta, Sudipta Chatterjee, Huabin Zhang, Zhiping Lai, Kuo&#8208;Wei Huang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403359797

                Abstract Formic acid (FA) has emerged as a promising candidate for hydrogen energy storage due to its favorable properties such as low toxicity, low flammability, and high volumetric hydrogen storage capacity under ambient conditions. Recent analyses have suggested that FA produced by electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) reduction reaction (eCO 2 RR) using low&#8208;carbon electricity exhibits lower fugitive hydrogen (H 2 ) emissions and global warming potential (GWP) during the H 2 carrier production, storage and transportation processes compared to those of other alternatives like methanol, methylcyclohexane, and ammonia. eCO 2 RR to FA can enable industrially relevant current densities without the need for high pressures, high temperatures, or auxiliary hydrogen sources. However, the widespread implementation of eCO 2 RR to FA is hindered by the requirement for highly stable and selective catalysts. Herein, the aim is to explore and evaluate the potential of catalyst engineering in designing stable and selective nanostructured catalysts that can facilitate economically viable production of FA.</description>
      <author>Karthik Peramaiah, Moyu Yi, Indranil Dutta, Sudipta Chatterjee, Huabin Zhang, Zhiping Lai, Kuo&#8208;Wei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and swift heating technique for crafting highly graphitized carbon and crystalline silicon (Si@GC) composite anodes for lithium&#8208;ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240025</link>
      <description>Chinmayee Padwal, Xijue Wang, Hong Duc Pham, Thi My Linh Hoang, Sagadevan Mundree, Deepak P. Dubal, Battery energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403484794

                Abstract The synthesis of battery materials from biomass as feedstock is not only effective but also aligns with sustainable practices. However, current methods like slow pyrolysis/heating are both energy&#8208;intensive and economically impractical. Hence, integrating energy&#8208;efficient technologies becomes imperative to curtail substantial energy consumption and, consequently, minimize carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) emissions during electricity usage. Herein, we employed a one&#8208;step pyrolysis/reduction based on the microwave heating method to synthesize a composite of high&#8208;purity silicon and highly graphitized carbon (Si@GC) from rice husk as feedstock. Compared to the conventional heating methods, the Si@GC samples prepared via the microwave heating method required less time (30&#8211;50 min). Benefiting from ultrahigh heating rates, the highly graphitized carbon and crystalline silicon composite was successfully synthesized. The synthesis by microwave irradiation showed homogenous material, excellent surface area, essential functional groups, and crystallinity revealing the outstanding reaction kinetics to form the material. The as&#8208;synthesized Si@GC composite anode material delivered a high discharge capacity of 799 mAh/g with high cyclic stability of ~71% over 120 cycles. The ex situ ToF&#8208;SIMS revealed great inorganic SEI composition, mainly consisting of the fluorinated species and carbonate species produced at the initial cycle. This investigation provides a novel rapid heating method for the synthesis of battery materials, which can also be extended for other materials and applications.</description>
      <author>Chinmayee Padwal, Xijue Wang, Hong Duc Pham, Thi My Linh Hoang, Sagadevan Mundree, Deepak P. Dubal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiffGLE: Differentiable Coarse-Grained Dynamics using Generalized
  Langevin Equation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.08424</link>
      <description>Jinu Jeong, Ishan Nadkarni, N. R. Aluru, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403444161

                Capturing the correct dynamics at the Coarse-Grained (CG) scale remains a central challenge in the advancement of systematic CG models for soft matter simulations. The Generalized Langevin Equation (GLE), rooted in the Mori-Zwanzig formalism, provides a robust framework for incorporating friction and stochastic forces into CG models, that are lost due to the reduction in degrees of freedom. Leveraging recent advancements in Automatic Differentiation (AD) and reformulating the non-Markovian GLE using a colored noise ansatz, we present a top-down approach for accurately parameterizing the non-Markovian GLE for different coarse-grained fluids that accurately reproduces the velocity-autocorrelation function of the original All-Atom (AA) model. We demonstrate our approach on two different fluids namely, SPC/E water and carbon dioxide which have distinct structure and dynamical characteristics. Importantly, by being end-to-end differentiable, this approach offers a simplified and efficient solution to achieving accurate CG dynamics, effectively bypassing the complexities inherent in most bottom-up methods.</description>
      <author>Jinu Jeong, Ishan Nadkarni, N. R. Aluru</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.08424</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited Manganese Dioxides and Their Composites as Electrocatalysts for Energy Conversion Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401907</link>
      <description>Masaharu Nakayama, Wataru Yoshida, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403463183

                Enhancing the efficiencies of electrochemical reactions for converting renewable energy into clean chemical fuels as well as generating clean energy is critical to achieving carbon neutrality. However, this enhancement can be achieved using materials that are not constrained by resource limitations and those that can be converted into devices in a scalable manner, preferably for industrial applications. This review explores the applications of electrochemically deposited manganese dioxides (MnO2) and their composites as electrochemical catalysts for oxygen evolution (OER) and hydrogen evolution reactions for converting renewable energy into chemical fuels. It also explores their applications as electrochemical catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and bifunctional OER/ORR for the efficient operation of fuel cells and metal&#8211;air batteries, respectively. Manganese is the second most abundant transition metal in the Earth&#8217;s crust, and electrodeposition represents a binder&#8208;free and scalable technique for fabricating devices (electrodes). To propose an improved catalyst design, the studies on the electrodeposition mechanism of MnO2 as well as the fabrication techniques for MnO2&#8208;based nanocomposites accumulated in the development of electrodes for supercapacitors are also included in this review.</description>
      <author>Masaharu Nakayama, Wataru Yoshida</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Selectivity Tandem Photocatalytic Methanation of CO2 by Lacunary Polyoxometalates&#8208;Stabilized *CO Intermediate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413594</link>
      <description>Qian Zhu, Zhaohui Li, Tao Zheng, Xingxing Zheng, Si Liu, Shen Gao, Xionghui Fu, Xiaofang Su, Yihua Zhu, Yuanming Zhang, Yongge Wei, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403359913

                Stabilizing specific intermediates to produce CH4 remains a main challenge in solar&#8208;driven CO2 reduction. Herein, g&#8208;C3N4 is modified with saturated and lacunary phosphotungstates (PWx, x = 12, 11, 9) to tailor the CO2 reduction pathway to yield CH4 in high selectivity. Increased lacuna of phosphotungstates leads to higher CH4 yield and selectivity, with a superior CH4 selectivity of 80% and 40.8 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8208;1&#183;h&#8208;1 evolution rate for PW9/g&#8208;C3N4. Conversely, g&#8208;C3N4 and PWx alone show negligible CH4 production. The conversion of CO2 to CH4 follows a tandem catalytic process. CO2 is initially activated on g&#8208;C3N4 to form *CO intermediates, meanwhile photogenerated electrons derived from g&#8208;C3N4 transfer to PWx. Then the reduced PWx captures *CO, which is subsquently hydrogenated to CH4. With the injection of two photogenerated electrons, PW9 is capable of adsorbing and activating *CO. However, the reduced PW12 and PW11 are incapable of adsorbing *CO due to the small energy of occupied molecular orbitals, which is the reason for the poorer activity of PWx/g&#8208;C3N4 (x = 12, 11) compared with that of PW9/g&#8208;C3N4. This work provides new insights to regulate highly selective CO2 photoreduction to CH4 by utilizing lacuna of polyoxometalates to enhance the interaction of metals in polyoxometalates with key intermediates.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhu, Zhaohui Li, Tao Zheng, Xingxing Zheng, Si Liu, Shen Gao, Xionghui Fu, Xiaofang Su, Yihua Zhu, Yuanming Zhang, Yongge Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electroencephalographic depression after abruptly increasing partial pressure of end-tidal carbon dioxide: a case series</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871-024-02764-7</link>
      <description>Shikuo Li, Yuyi Zhao, Qifeng Wang, Xuehan Li, Chao Chen, Yunxia Zuo, BMC Anesthesiology. 24(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403423909

                Prolonged electroencephalographic depression during surgery is associated with poor outcomes for patients. However, the published literature on electroencephalographic depression caused by a sudden increase in the partial pressure of end-tidal carbon dioxide (PETCO2) is lacking. We report four patients who were scheduled for laparoscopic liver surgery under general anesthesia. During the process of EEG monitoring with Sedline, four patients experienced electroencephalographic depression closely after a sudden increase in PETCO2. The four patients showed that electroencephalographic depression mainly manifested as a slow in EEG frequency, a reduction in the amplitude and power of EEG, and a decrease in spectral edge frequency. Patient state index was elevated in three cases. To summarize, our patients showed EEG depression when PETCO2 suddenly increased, which suggests that clinical doctors should be alert to electroencephalographic depression when the PETCO2 abruptly increases. EEG monitoring devices should be applied in patients with possible hypercapnia. Anesthesiologists must comprehensively interpret the raw EEG, spectral edge frequency, and density spectral array data, in addition to patient sedation index values.</description>
      <author>Shikuo Li, Yuyi Zhao, Qifeng Wang, Xuehan Li, Chao Chen, Yunxia Zuo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871-024-02764-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Results on the Use of Straw Cover and Effective Microorganisms for Mitigating GHG and Ammonia Emissions in Pig Slurry Storage Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14101788</link>
      <description>Martire Ang&#233;lica Terrero Turb&#237;, Melisa G&#243;mez Garrido, Oumaima El bied, Jos&#233; Gregorio Cuevas Bencosme, &#193;ngel Faz Cano, Agriculture. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403400565

                Spain has been the largest pork producer in the EU in recent years, leading to significant pig slurry (PS) production that requires proper management to prevent environmental impacts. The objectives of this study were to quantify greenhouse gas (GHG) and ammonia emissions and to characterize the PS in storage pond systems. A straw cover pond (SP) and addition of effective microorganisms (EMs) in a biological pond (BP) were used to treat the slurries. During two periods (autumn and spring), PS was characterized and GHG (CO2, CH4, N2O) and NH3 emissions were measured with a dynamic chamber. After 5 weeks of storage, BP achieved a reduction of 96% for CO2, 98% for CH4 and 59% for NH3 compared to the control pond (CP) in spring, while SP presented a 74% reduction for CO2 in autumn, and 60% and 97% reductions for CH4 and NH3, respectively, in spring. Additionally, the PS samples showed a decreasing trend for EC, dry matter, COD, BOD5, total N, NH4+-N, Org.-N, NO3&#8722;-N, and PO43&#8722; during both seasons. This preliminary study shows promise in reducing GHG/NH3 emissions and improving PS properties, but further replication is recommended. Varying straw cover thickness, optimizing EM dose, and a pH reduction may enhance outcomes.</description>
      <author>Martire Ang&#233;lica Terrero Turb&#237;, Melisa G&#243;mez Garrido, Oumaima El bied, Jos&#233; Gregorio Cuevas Bencosme, &#193;ngel Faz Cano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14101788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Selectivity Tandem Photocatalytic Methanation of CO2 by Lacunary Polyoxometalates&#8208;Stabilized *CO Intermediate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413594</link>
      <description>Qian Zhu, Zhaohui Li, Tao Zheng, Xingxing Zheng, Si Liu, Shen Gao, Xionghui Fu, Xiaofang Su, Yi Zhu, Yuanming Zhang, Yongge Wei, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403359942

                Stabilizing specific intermediates to produce CH4 remains a main challenge in solar&#8208;driven CO2 reduction. Herein, g&#8208;C3N4 is modified with saturated and lacunary phosphotungstates (PWx, x = 12, 11, 9) to tailor the CO2 reduction pathway to yield CH4 in high selectivity. Increased lacuna of phosphotungstates leads to higher CH4 yield and selectivity, with a superior CH4 selectivity of 80% and 40.8 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8208;1&#183;h&#8208;1 evolution rate for PW9/g&#8208;C3N4. Conversely, g&#8208;C3N4 and PWx alone show negligible CH4 production. The conversion of CO2 to CH4 follows a tandem catalytic process. CO2 is initially activated on g&#8208;C3N4 to form *CO intermediates, meanwhile photogenerated electrons derived from g&#8208;C3N4 transfer to PWx. Then the reduced PWx captures *CO, which is subsquently hydrogenated to CH4. With the injection of two photogenerated electrons, PW9 is capable of adsorbing and activating *CO. However, the reduced PW12 and PW11 are incapable of adsorbing *CO due to the small energy of occupied molecular orbitals, which is the reason for the poorer activity of PWx/g&#8208;C3N4 (x = 12, 11) compared with that of PW9/g&#8208;C3N4. This work provides new insights to regulate highly selective CO2 photoreduction to CH4 by utilizing lacuna of polyoxometalates to enhance the interaction of metals in polyoxometalates with key intermediates.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhu, Zhaohui Li, Tao Zheng, Xingxing Zheng, Si Liu, Shen Gao, Xionghui Fu, Xiaofang Su, Yi Zhu, Yuanming Zhang, Yongge Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power&#8208;to&#8208;Ethanol Using Bimetallic Catalysts: Reaction Paths, Transfer to Gas Diffusion Electrode, and Future Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elsa.202400017</link>
      <description>Elisabeth Gr&#228;fin von Westarp, Burkhard Hecker, Hermann Tempel, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel, Electrochemical Science Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403394539

                ABSTRACT Ethanol is a promising product for the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), as ethanol as a value&#8208;added product can help to enable the near&#8208;term feasibility of this technique, thus Power&#8208;to&#8208;ethanol can act as a pioneering process for the CO 2 RR. Furthermore, CO 2 RR offers a green production process for ethanol in addition to biomass fermentation. However, the formation of ethanol via electrolysis often competes with ethylene production, which makes the selective formation of ethanol more difficult. We show that this problem can be circumvented by using a bimetallic catalyst that provides abundant *CO and thus activates an alternative and selective reaction path for ethanol. However, this study was carried out in an aqueous&#8208;fed H&#8208;type electrolyzer, which has mass transport limitations and thus insufficient current densities. To solve this issue, the studied catalyst is transferred to a gas diffusion electrode. Here we emphasize that, in addition to other relevant parameters, the choice of the binder also can have a high impact on the performance of the electrode. As an outlook, various enhanced reactor designs and their influence on ethanol formation are presented.</description>
      <author>Elisabeth Gr&#228;fin von Westarp, Burkhard Hecker, Hermann Tempel, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elsa.202400017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy use and greenhouse gas emissions in selected tea factories in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pclm.0000329</link>
      <description>Joy Kibet, Sammy Letema, PLOS Climate. 3(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403448486

                Tea sector is a major contributor to Kenya&#8217;s economy through foreign exchange via export. However, extensive amount of energy is required to produce one kilogram of tea, making tea processing energy-intensive. Comparing greenhouse gas emissions from different types of energy consumed in tea factories is imperative to enable policymakers make informed intervention in emission reduction. Reducing greenhouse gas emissions in tea factories is one of the pathways to meeting Kenya&#8217;s nationally determined 32% reduction of carbon emissions by 2030 and commitment to the Paris Agreement. This paper assesses greenhouse gas emissions from different sources of energy used in four tea factories in Kenya. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change emission factor is used to calculate the total emissions of each type of energy used for 5 years. Life cycle assessment using SimaPro 8 software, Eco-indicator 99 method and Eco invent database was used to assess the specific compound causing the emission. The findings reveal that the 5-year greenhouse gas emissions by biogas, solar, wood, briquettes, and electricity are 336.111, 7.108, 3057.729, and 1,338.28 kg CO 2 /MWh, respectively. Firewood has the highest concentration of carbon dioxide, while solar energy has the least. Analysis of variance confirms significant difference (0.05&gt;p = 0.0272) in greenhouse gas emissions from the different energy sources. Post-hoc analyses shows a significant difference in emissions between solar and firewood (p&lt;0.0125) and no significant difference between other sources of energy. The key environmental hotspot is the energy intensive processes such as drying involved in tea production and processing, which leads to consumption of fossil fuel in the factories. To reduce such key hotspot, switching to renewable energy sources is key. Sustainability in the tea sector can therefore be achieved through switching to macadamia briquettes as a source of thermal energy and a combination of electricity and solar for electrical energy.</description>
      <author>Joy Kibet, Sammy Letema</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pclm.0000329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Thermal Chamber Expansion of VH-SAGD Process Using CO2-Inducing Effect for Heavy Oil Reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102260</link>
      <description>Haojun Xie, Shiming Zhang, Guanghuan Wu, Wei Li, Processes. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403448923

                In heavy oil thermal recovery processes, higher pressure usually leads to low dryness and expansion difficulty for the injected steam in thermal recovery processes, which will result in lower oil recovery and more carbon emissions. This paper proposed a new CO2-inducing method to accelerate the steam chamber expansion, based on a core flooding experiment and numerical simulation. First, the CO2 showed significant viscosity reduction at high pressure in the PVT test. In the core flooding experiment, the CO2 provided strong flow conductivity in porous media for the thermal flooding, as the CO2 pre-injection restrained the steam condensation. Using the CO2-inducing method, CO2 pre-injection before steam built a fast flow channel in a relatively higher permeability layer and reduced the thermal injection pressure by about 1.0~2.4 MPa. As a result, the steam overlap around the injection wells became slower and the gravity drainage process was able to heat and displace the heavy oil above the channel. Furthermore, the CO2 gas trapped at the top reduced heat loss by about 12.4%. The field numerical simulation showed that this new method improved thermal recovery by 7.5% and reduced CO2 emissions by about 18 million kg/unit for the whole process. This method changes the conventional thermal expansion direction by CO2 inducing effect and fundamentally reduces heat loss, which provides significant advantages in low-carbon EOR.</description>
      <author>Haojun Xie, Shiming Zhang, Guanghuan Wu, Wei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio carbon footprints and decarbonization progress of China's asset managers: a decade analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4976708/v1</link>
      <description>Dabo Guan, Jinglei Wang, Xiang Yu, Wenqiang Wang, Gesangyangji Gesang, Jie Li, Shuping Li, Ning Zhang, Zengkai Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403386894

                Abstract Despite repeated calls to reduce CO2 emissions, asset managers continue to invest heavily in carbon-intensive assets, creating hidden carbon bombs within their equity portfolios. Timely tracking of portfolio carbon footprints is essential as a dynamic tool for monitoring companies' efforts to reduce carbon reduction. However, the availability and quality of firm-level CO2 emissions data present significant challenges in measuring financed emissions. As a result, potential climate-related risks for asset managers are likely to be severely underestimated. This study analyses CO2 emissions embodied in the equity portfolios of 105 Chinese asset managers from 2010 to 2020. Results show that over 50% of financed emissions comes from carbon-intensive assets, primarily emitted by individual high-emitting companies. Positively, some managers have reallocated capital towards High-tech Industries and Advanced Services during the period, and achieved over 50% reduction in carbon intensity. Comparison between asset managers' commitments versus actual mitigation actions shows that five out of six leading asset managers in China have failed to take their mitigation actions, despite their commitment to the UN Principles for Responsible Investment (UNPRI). Our qualitative analysis provide scientific evidence for China's asset managers in measuring companies&#8217; portfolio carbon footprints and supporting their decarbonization pathways.</description>
      <author>Dabo Guan, Jinglei Wang, Xiang Yu, Wenqiang Wang, Gesangyangji Gesang, Jie Li, Shuping Li, Ning Zhang, Zengkai Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4976708/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Electro&#8208;Biosynthesis of Ectoine from Greenhouse Gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415445</link>
      <description>Shuqi Guo, Chengbo Li, Xiaohan Huang, Yanjing Su, Chenyue Zhang, Yizhou Dai, Yuan Ji, Rongzhan Fu, Tingting Zheng, Qiang Fei, Daidi Fan, Chuan Xia, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403475883

                Converting greenhouse gases into valuable products has become a promising approach for achieving a carbon&#8208;neutral economy and sustainable development. However, the conversion efficiency depends on the energy yield of the substrate. In this study, we developed an electro&#8208;biocatalytic system by integrating electrochemical and microbial processes to upcycle CO2 into a valuable product (ectoine) using renewable energy. This system initiates the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to methane, an energy&#8208;dense molecule, which then serves as an electrofuel to energize the growth of an engineered methanotrophic cell factory for ectoine biosynthesis. The scalability of this system was demonstrated using an array of ten 25 cm2 electrochemical cells equipped with a high&#8208;performance carbon&#8208;supported isolated copper catalyst. The system consistently generated methane at the cathode under a total partial current of approximately &#8722;37 A (~175 mmolCH4 h&#8211;1) and O2 at the anode under a total partial current of approximately 62 A (~583 mmolO2 h&#8211;1). This output met the requirements of a 3&#8208;L bioreactor, even at maximum CH4 and O2 consumption, resulting in the high&#8208;yield conversion of CO2 to ectoine (1146.9 mg L&#8211;1). This work underscores the potential of electrifying the biosynthesis of valuable products from CO2, providing a sustainable avenue for biomanufacturing and energy storage.</description>
      <author>Shuqi Guo, Chengbo Li, Xiaohan Huang, Yanjing Su, Chenyue Zhang, Yizhou Dai, Yuan Ji, Rongzhan Fu, Tingting Zheng, Qiang Fei, Daidi Fan, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Electro&#8208;Biosynthesis of Ectoine from Greenhouse Gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415445</link>
      <description>Shuqi Guo, Chengbo Li, Xiaohan Huang, Yanjing Su, Chenyue Zhang, Yizhou Dai, Yuan Ji, Rongzhan Fu, Tingting Zheng, Qiang Fei, Daidi Fan, Chuan Xia, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403475936

                Converting greenhouse gases into valuable products has become a promising approach for achieving a carbon&#8208;neutral economy and sustainable development. However, the conversion efficiency depends on the energy yield of the substrate. In this study, we developed an electro&#8208;biocatalytic system by integrating electrochemical and microbial processes to upcycle CO2 into a valuable product (ectoine) using renewable energy. This system initiates the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to methane, an energy&#8208;dense molecule, which then serves as an electrofuel to energize the growth of an engineered methanotrophic cell factory for ectoine biosynthesis. The scalability of this system was demonstrated using an array of ten 25 cm2 electrochemical cells equipped with a high&#8208;performance carbon&#8208;supported isolated copper catalyst. The system consistently generated methane at the cathode under a total partial current of approximately &#8722;37 A (~175 mmolCH4 h&#8211;1) and O2 at the anode under a total partial current of approximately 62 A (~583 mmolO2 h&#8211;1). This output met the requirements of a 3&#8208;L bioreactor, even at maximum CH4 and O2 consumption, resulting in the high&#8208;yield conversion of CO2 to ectoine (1146.9 mg L&#8211;1). This work underscores the potential of electrifying the biosynthesis of valuable products from CO2, providing a sustainable avenue for biomanufacturing and energy storage.</description>
      <author>Shuqi Guo, Chengbo Li, Xiaohan Huang, Yanjing Su, Chenyue Zhang, Yizhou Dai, Yuan Ji, Rongzhan Fu, Tingting Zheng, Qiang Fei, Daidi Fan, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fossil Diesel, Soybean Biodiesel and Hydrotreated Vegetable Oil: A Numerical Analysis of Emissions Using Detailed Chemical Kinetics at Diesel Engine Like Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15101224</link>
      <description>Leonel R Cancino, Jessica F. Rebelo, Felipe Kraus, Eduardo Homem de Siqueira Cavalcanti, Val&#233;ria S. de B. Pimentel, D&#233;cio Magioli Maia, Ricardo Almeida Barbosa de S&#225;, Atmosphere. 15(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403399750

                Nowadays, emissions from internal combustion engines are a relevant topic of investigation, taking into account the continuous reduction of emission limits imposed by environmental regulatory agencies around the world, obviously as the result of earnest studies that have pointed out the impact on the human health of high levels of contaminants released into the environment. Over recent years, the use of biofuels has contributed to attenuating this environmental issue; however, new problems have been raised, such as NOx emissions tend to increase as the biofuel percentage in the fuel used in engines increases. In this research, the emissions of a compression ignition internal combustion engine modeled as a variable volume reactor with homogeneous combustion were numerically investigated. To analyze the combustion process, a detailed kinetics model tailored specifically for this purpose was used. The kinetics model comprised 30,975 chemical reactions involving 691 chemical species. Mixtures of fuel surrogates were then created to represent the fuel used in the Brazilian fuel marketplace, involving (i) fossil diesel&#8212;&#8220;diesel A&#8221;, (ii) soybean diesel&#8212;&#8220;biodiesel&#8221;, and (iii) hydrotreated vegetable oil&#8212; &#8220;HVO&#8221;. Surrogate species were then selected for each of the aforementioned fuels, and blends of those surrogates were then proposed as mixture M1 (diesel A:biodiesel:HVO&#8212;90:10:0), mixture M2 (diesel A:biodiesel:HVO&#8212;85:15:0), and mixture M3 (diesel A:biodiesel:HVO&#8212;80:15:5). The species allowed in the kinetics model included all the fuel surrogates used in this research as well as the target emission species of this study: total hydrocarbons, non-methane hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide, methane, nitrogen oxides, carbon dioxide, soot, and soot precursors. When compared to experimental trends of emissions available in the literature, it was observed that, for all the proposed fuel surrogates blends, the numerical approach performed in this research was able to capture qualitative trends for engine power and the target emissions in the whole ranges of engine speeds and engine loads, despite the CO and NOx emissions at specific engine speeds and loads.</description>
      <author>Leonel R Cancino, Jessica F. Rebelo, Felipe Kraus, Eduardo Homem de Siqueira Cavalcanti, Val&#233;ria S. de B. Pimentel, D&#233;cio Magioli Maia, Ricardo Almeida Barbosa de S&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15101224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing urban road CO2 emissions: A study based on GPS data from heavy diesel trucks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4815865/v1</link>
      <description>Meijiao Qu, Jiachen Xu, Chao He, Ji&#8208;Guang Wang, Jiaqiang Li, Longqing Zhao, Haisheng Yu, Yanlin Chen, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403343015

                Abstract The determination of carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions from heavy-duty diesel trucks (HDTs) is important for the development of traffic emission reduction strategies. This study quantified the CO2 emissions from 5,996 HDTs on different road types using a bottom-up approach combined with the application of the International Vehicle Emissions (IVE) model based on 1.24 million trajectory points. A correlation analysis was conducted on the hourly traffic flow, driving mileage, speed, and CO2 emissions of HDTs in the urban area of Kunming, China. The traditional emission intensity allocation method was improved by establishing a high-resolution (1 &#215; 1 km) emission inventory using trajectory points and the road network density. The results indicated that higher driving speeds can reduce CO2 emissions, but HDTs typically maintain speeds of 40&#8211;60 km/h, with emission coefficients around 500 kg/km; HDTs complying with China III standards are significant contributors to CO2 emissions; Regional CO2 emissions from HDTs are highly influenced by traffic flow and driving distances; Vehicle restriction policies contribute to increased nighttime emissions; A pollution spatial allocation method based on trajectory point density and road network density better reflects the regional spatial distribution of CO2 emissions from HDTs; CO2 spatial distribution is predominantly concentrated in the southeast of urban areas, primarily influenced by urban industrial layout.</description>
      <author>Meijiao Qu, Jiachen Xu, Chao He, Ji&#8208;Guang Wang, Jiaqiang Li, Longqing Zhao, Haisheng Yu, Yanlin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4815865/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Nexus between Greenhouse Emissions, Environmental Degradation and Green Energy in Europe: A Critique of the Environmental Kuznets Curve</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17205109</link>
      <description>Alexandra Horobe&#355;, Lucian Bela&#351;cu, Magdalena Radulescu, Daniel Balsalobre&#8208;Lorente, Cosmin-Alin Bo&#355;oroga, Cristina-Carmencita Negreanu, Energies. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403392329

                This study examines the intricate relationship between economic growth and European environmental degradation via the Environmental Kuznets Curve (EKC). Our results contest the traditional inverted U-shape model of the Environmental Kuznets Curve, indicating that the theory may not be consistently applicable across European countries. Utilizing CS-ARDL and MMQR modelling, we reveal substantial regional disparities. Western European nations demonstrate a typical Environmental Kuznets Curve (EKC) pattern in the short term, characterized by an initial increase in emissions alongside GDP development, followed by a subsequent fall. Conversely, Eastern and Balkan nations exhibit a U-shaped connection, described by an early decline in emissions followed by a subsequent increase as their development levels increase. The influence of renewable energy differs, as it decreases emissions in the short term in Western Europe. However, its long-term impacts are variable, especially when contrasted with its more pronounced effect on emissions in Eastern and Balkan countries. Furthermore, trade openness intensifies environmental degradation in the short-term across all regions, although its long-term impact diminishes, particularly concerning greenhouse gases (GHG). The relationship between renewable energy and trade openness is substantial for the short-term reduction of carbon dioxide emissions, but this effect declines with time. The results indicate that a uniform environmental policy throughout Europe may lack efficacy. Customized strategies to expedite the transition in Western Europe and more specific interventions in Eastern Europe are essential to harmonize economic progress with environmental sustainability. Future research should examine the determinants of the diminishing long-term effects of renewable energy and the interplay between trade and environmental policies.</description>
      <author>Alexandra Horobe&#355;, Lucian Bela&#351;cu, Magdalena Radulescu, Daniel Balsalobre&#8208;Lorente, Cosmin-Alin Bo&#355;oroga, Cristina-Carmencita Negreanu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17205109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Methods of Asbestos Waste Management as Innovative Solutions for Recycling and Sustainable Cement Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16208798</link>
      <description>K. Durczak, Micha&#322; Pyzalski, Tomasz Brylewski, Micha&#322; Juszczyk, Agnieszka Le&#347;niak, Marek Libura, Leonas Ustinovi&#269;ius, Mantas Vai&#353;noras, Sustainability. 16(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403336309

                Managing asbestos waste presents a significant challenge due to the widespread industrial use of this material, and the serious health and environmental risks it poses. Despite its unique properties, such as resistance to high temperatures and substantial mechanical strength, asbestos is a material with well-documented toxicity and carcinogenicity. Ensuring the safe removal and disposal of asbestos-containing materials (ACM) is crucial for protecting public health, the environment, and for reducing CO2 emissions resulting from inefficient waste disposal methods. Traditional landfill disposal methods have proven inadequate, while modern approaches&#8212;including thermal, chemical, biotechnological, and mechanochemical methods&#8212;offer potential benefits but also come with limitations. In particular, thermal techniques that allow for asbestos degradation can significantly reduce environmental impact, while also providing the opportunity to repurpose disposal products into materials useful for cement production. Cement, a key component of concrete, can serve as a sustainable alternative, minimizing CO2 emissions and reducing the need for primary raw materials. This work provides insights into research on asbestos waste management, offering a deeper understanding of key initiatives related to asbestos removal. It presents a comprehensive review of best practices, innovative technologies, and safe asbestos management strategies, with particular emphasis on their impact on sustainable development and CO2 emission reduction. Additionally, it discusses public health hazards related to exposure to asbestos fibers, and worker protection during the asbestos disposal process. As highlighted in the review, one promising method is the currently available thermal degradation of asbestos. This method offers real opportunities for repurposing asbestos disposal products for cement production; thereby reducing CO2 emissions, minimizing waste, and supporting sustainable construction.</description>
      <author>K. Durczak, Micha&#322; Pyzalski, Tomasz Brylewski, Micha&#322; Juszczyk, Agnieszka Le&#347;niak, Marek Libura, Leonas Ustinovi&#269;ius, Mantas Vai&#353;noras</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16208798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Sequestration by Preparing Recycled Cement, Recycled Aggregates, and Recycled Concrete from Construction and Demolition (C&amp;amp;D) Wastes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205020</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Rong Huang, Junjie Wang, Yi Zhang, Materials. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403392074

                As the world&#8217;s largest producer of construction waste, China&#8217;s recycling and related policies are of the biggest concern to the world. However, the effective disposal and reuse of this waste has become an important issue since currently China still has a very low recycling ratio compared to developed countries, and most of the waste concrete was only simply broken and used as low-grade recycled aggregates for subgrade cushion, cement stabilized crushed stone, and filler wall. In this paper, a concrete cycle model focusing on how to effectively recycle and utilize waste concrete is put forward to prepare high quality recycled concrete, especially through a series of technical means, such as effective separation, carbon sequestration, and reactivation. Producing high quality recycled concrete can not only replace traditional concrete but also effectively reduce the consumption and waste of raw materials. What&#8217;s more, the calculation results show a potential of significantly carbon sink; for every ton of recycled cement produced, the CO2 emission could be reduced by 0.35&#8211;0.77 tons compared to ordinary Portland cement, corresponding to a reduction of 47%&#8211;94%; and for every ton of recycled concrete produced, the CO2 emission could be reduced by 0.186 tons compared to normal concrete. A yearly CO2 sequestration of 1.4&#8211;3.08 gigatonnes could happen if the ordinary Portland cement could be replaced by the recycled cement around the world. Taking the currently accumulated construction and demolition (C&amp;D) wastes globally, the production of recycled cement, recycled aggregates, and recycled concrete could induce a significant carbon sink in the world.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Rong Huang, Junjie Wang, Yi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI in Business Aviation Route Optimization: Reducing Fuel Consumption and Environmental Impact</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47941/jbsm.2284</link>
      <description>Victor Mgbachi, Journal of Business and Strategic Management. 9(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403375924

                Purpose: This paper reviews ways that artificial intelligence could be used to make business aviation operations most fuel-efficient, cheapest in cost of operation, and smallest in terms of ecological footprint. The research elaborated possible ways of using AI in the spheres of flight planning, predictive maintenance, fuel management, emission tracking, and compliance in business aviation. Methodology: It was also empirical case-study-oriented research that investigated the impacts of AI-driven technologies on business aviation operators, basically NetJets, VistaJet, and Flexjet. The impacts are from route optimization to predictive maintenance, fuel management, and compliance with regulations. Information such as fuel consumption, CO2 emissions, and operational efficiency was obtained before and after the adoption of AI technologies. Findings: The fuel savings from AI-driven systems are reaching a point of salience, at 9 to 14% in the various cases, with associated reductions in CO2 emissions. AI-powered predictive maintenance resulted in a 20% reduction in unscheduled events, thereby bettering the availability of fleets. Artificial intelligence increased overall efficiency and improved decisions for in-flight, real-time operations management while conforming to regulatory requirements in reporting. Additionally, AI is going to bring tremendous values in optimizing SAFs and aircraft energy-efficient technology to make flying sustainable. Unique Contribution to Theory, Policy, and Practice: This work contributes to AI in aviation by demonstrating its practical application in reducing environmental impacts and operational costs in business aviation. It provides a framework for integrating AI into aviation management systems and highlights the importance of public-private cooperation for wider AI adoption. The findings are valuable for policymakers, business aviation operators, and industry leaders aiming to advance sustainability and regulatory compliance</description>
      <author>Victor Mgbachi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47941/jbsm.2284</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermochemical Heterolytic Hydrogenation Catalysis Proceeds Through Polarization-Driven Hydride Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3rp1x</link>
      <description>Hai&#8208;Xu Wang, Yogesh Surendranath, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403476363

                Heterolytic hydrogenations, which split H2 across a hydride acceptor and proton acceptor, are a key class of reactions that span the chemical value chain, including CO2 hydrogenation to formate and NADH regeneration from NAD+. The dominant mechanistic models for heterogeneous catalysis of these reactions invoke classical surface mechanisms that ignore the role of interfacial charge separation. Herein, we quantify the electrochemical potential of the catalyst during turnover and uncover evidence supporting an interfacial electrochemical hydride transfer mechanism for this overall thermochemical reaction class. We find that the proton acceptor induces spontaneous electrochemical polarization of the metal catalyst surface, thereby controlling the thermodynamic hydricity of the surface M&#8211;H intermediates and driving rate-determining electrochemical hydride transfer to the hydride acceptor substrate. Overall, this model invokes that heterolytic hydrogenations proceed via the coupling of two electrochemical half-reactions, the hydrogen reduction reaction (HRR) and hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR), which convert H2 to hydride and proton, respectively. This mechanistic framework, which applies across diverse reaction media and for the hydrogenation of CO2 to formate and NAD+ to NADH, enables the determination of intrinsic reaction kinetics and exposes design principles for the future development of sustainable hydrogenation reactivity.</description>
      <author>Hai&#8208;Xu Wang, Yogesh Surendranath</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3rp1x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resource Efficiency as an environmental performance metric for industry: the case of clinker manufacturing in Europe</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31219/osf.io/8gd27</link>
      <description>Ana Morgado, Hannes Gauch, Jonathan M. Cullen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403383923

                Control-data exergy-based Resource Efficiency (RE) analysis is applied to investigate resource use and efficiency improvements in the cement industry to understand what insights can be gained into the efficiency of clinker manufacturing and possible decarbonisation options when having full access to material and energy flows from the manufacturing plant control system. Mapping of the resources in and out of the clinker manufacturing section showed that total resource input is dominated by the flow of fuels, with the clinker burning section constituting the most energy and emissions-intensive part of the process. The plant is found to have an annual mean RE of 47.8% in compound operation, and 38.3% in direct operation. Three improvement options are identified: recycling of dust, reduction of heat transfer losses across the kiln, and optimisation of the plant&#8217;s continuous operation, with heat losses reduction having the largest improvement potential in terms of the overall plant RE and the reduction of CO2 emissions. Despite providing a detailed representation of the real-time operation capable of identifying potential improvement interventions, the use of control-data is found to be highly intensive and time-consuming. In the future, it would be interesting to investigate whether the same level of insights into the efficiency and potential for decarbonisation of clinker manufacturing could be gained using less data.</description>
      <author>Ana Morgado, Hannes Gauch, Jonathan M. Cullen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31219/osf.io/8gd27</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed standardization changes in the assessment of concrete durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5604/01.3001.0054.7473</link>
      <description>G. Bajorek, Z. Giergiczny, In&#380;ynieria i Budownictwo. LXXX(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403446216

                The article presents the concept of concrete durability based on the system of concrete resistance classes to ERC exposure included in the proposed standardization documents (EN 206-1 together with EN 206-100 and Eurocode 2). According to the ERC concept, the performance properties of concrete are tested using recognized test methods, and the results are assessed on the basis of criteria independent of the composition of the tested concrete. The ERC durability concept is open to new technical and standardization solutions in the field of concrete composition (new additives) and cement and should replace the generally applicable prescriptive solutions. This solution is important from the point of view of reducing the emissions of the cement industry (production of multi-component cements and the use of new non-clinker main ingredients) and reducing the carbon footprint of concrete (CO2 reduction classes of concrete according to prEN 206-1)</description>
      <author>G. Bajorek, Z. Giergiczny</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5604/01.3001.0054.7473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Sewage Sludge Stabilization, Pathogen Removal, and Biomass Production through Indigenous Microalgae Promoting Growth: A Sustainable Approach for Sewage Sludge Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling9050097</link>
      <description>Hajer Ben Hamed, Antoine Debuigne, Hetty KleinJan, Dominique Toye, Ang&#233;lique L&#233;onard, Recycling. 9(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403490659

                Sewage sludge (SS), a byproduct of wastewater treatment plants, poses significant environmental and health risks if not properly handled. Conventional approaches for SS stabilization often involve costly and energy-consuming processes. This study investigated the effect of promoting native microalgae growth in SS on its stabilization, pathogen bacteria removal, and valuable biomass production. The effect on settleability, filterability, and extracellular polymeric substances (EPSs) was examined as well. Experiments were conducted in photobioreactors (PBRs) without O2 supply and CO2 release under controlled parameters. The results show a significant improvement in SS stabilization, with a reduction of volatile solids (VSs) by 47.55%. Additionally, fecal coliforms and E. coli were efficiently removed by 2.25 log and 6.72 log, respectively. Moreover, Salmonella spp. was not detected after 15 days of treatment. The settleability was improved by 71.42%. However, a worsening of the sludge filterability properties was observed, likely due to a decrease in floc size following the reduction of protein content in the tightly bound EPS fraction. Microalgae biomass production was 16.56 mg/L/day, with a mean biomass of 0.35 g/L at the end of the batch treatment, representing 10.35% of the total final biomass. These findings suggest that promoting native microalgal growth in SS could be sustainable and cost-effective for SS stabilization, microalgal biomass production, and the enhancement of sludge-settling characteristics, notwithstanding potential filtration-related considerations.</description>
      <author>Hajer Ben Hamed, Antoine Debuigne, Hetty KleinJan, Dominique Toye, Ang&#233;lique L&#233;onard</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling9050097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Assessment of an Airline Company within the Scope of Circular Economy Based Waste Management</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30518/jav.1509650</link>
      <description>Sinem B&#252;y&#252;ksaat&#231;&#305; Kiri&#351;, Binnur G&#252;r&#252;l, Journal of Aviation. 8(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403336784

                The rapid growth in the aviation sector has prompted the industry to act and develop new and sustainable business models due to the greenhouse gases and waste generated inherently by the sector. In this context, this study provides an assessment of identifiable areas and determinants of circular economy in an airline company, considering its environmental impacts. As a result of the assessment, it has been observed that the airline company conducts initiatives in reduction, reuse, and recycling, along with the management of cabin materials and waste segregation. Action plans are in place regarding the reduction, substitution, or elimination of single-use plastics in material selection. In order to mitigate both the environmental and economic impacts of paper consumption, the company is undertaking digitalization efforts within its business processes. The weight of aircraft is a crucial factor in the amount of fuel consumed and the quantity of CO2 emissions released. Therefore, airlines prefer to use lightweight materials inside the aircraft to reduce weight. Plastic catering materials are among these lightweight options. Unfortunately, due to the adverse environmental impacts of plastics, reducing their usage and, if possible, phasing them out are essential measures that airlines need to take. Consequently, the airline company under this study has removed the plastic outer packaging of the packaged materials used in the cabin. Furthermore, it continues its efforts to remove plastic materials used during catering services or replace them with biodegradable alternatives.</description>
      <author>Sinem B&#252;y&#252;ksaat&#231;&#305; Kiri&#351;, Binnur G&#252;r&#252;l</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30518/jav.1509650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobility Infrastructure Optimization via Stochastic Relaxation the Traffic Flow Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5093651/v1</link>
      <description>Stefano Bilotta, Enrico Collini, Marco Fanfani, Paolo Nesi, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403461561

                Abstract Urban traffic congestion and pollution represent critical challenges for sustainable city development. In this paper, we presents a novel approach to optimizing urban mobility infrastructure using a stochastic relaxation algorithm. The method is designed to address the growing challenges of traffic congestion, fuel consumption, and CO2 emissions in rapidly urbanizing cities. The system automates the generation and evaluation of road network modifications, drastically reducing the time and effort required for traditional simulation-based approaches. By utilizing real-time traffic data and traffic flow reconstruction algorithms within the Snap4City platform, the proposed system allows for the efficient exploration of "what-if" scenarios, optimizing key performance indicators such as travel time, fuel use, and emissions. A case study conducted in Florence, Italy, demonstrates significant improvements in traffic conditions, fuel efficiency, and emissions reduction, underscoring the system's potential to enhance urban mobility in a sustainable manner. This system has been developed exploiting the Snap4City platform Scenario Editor and platform.</description>
      <author>Stefano Bilotta, Enrico Collini, Marco Fanfani, Paolo Nesi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5093651/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Straightforward Model for Quantifying Local pH Gradients Governing the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09521</link>
      <description>Samuel S. Veroneau, Alaina C. Hartnett, Jaeyune Ryu, Hyukhun Hong, Cyrille Costentin, Daniel G. Nocera, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403326469

                The production and consumption of protons by an electrocatalyst will, under certain conditions, generate localized microenvironments with properties distinct from those of the bulk solution. These local properties are particularly impactful for reactions involving proton-coupled electron transfer, where the generation of locally basic or acidic environments may significantly influence the energy efficiency and reaction selectivity of the electrocatalyst. Whereas local pH environments have been observed and characterized in reductive half-reactions, including the CO2 reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions, the incompatibility of conventional techniques and materials has limited studies in oxidative half-reactions, including the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which provides the reducing equivalents for solar-to-fuels electrolysis. With the straightforward parameters bulk pH, buffer composition and pKa, and mass transport, we develop a model for describing local pH as a function of current density regardless of the microscopic details of the mechanism. Using an acid-stable PbOx OER catalyst, we observe the formation and dissipation of pH gradients during the OER and validate the model with voltammetric and potentiometric studies. The model predicts how local acidic environments can develop over a narrow OER current density window, thus providing further motivation for the development of OER catalysts that are stable to acid, even when operating in basic aqueous conditions. More generally, the model is not restricted to the OER and is useful for determining the onset of local pH gradients for other electrocatalytic reactions that involve the consumption or generation of protons in energy conversion reactions.</description>
      <author>Samuel S. Veroneau, Alaina C. Hartnett, Jaeyune Ryu, Hyukhun Hong, Cyrille Costentin, Daniel G. Nocera</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09521</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melatonin Rinsing Treatment Associated with Storage in a Controlled Atmosphere Improves the Antioxidant Capacity and Overall Quality of Lemons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/foods13203298</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Eric Zheng, Ziqin Lin, Ze Miao, Yuhang Li, Shenqiang Hu, Yanan Gao, Yuqian Jiang, Lingling Pang, Xihong Li, Foods. 13(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403484294

                Antioxidant capacity is one of the most important biological activities in fruits and vegetables and is closely related to human health. In this study, &#8216;Eureka&#8217; lemons were used as experimental materials and stored at 7&#8211;8 &#176;C MT (melatonin, 200 &#956;mol, soaked for 15 min) and CA (controlled atmosphere, 2&#8211;3% O2 + 15&#8211;16% CO2) individually or in combination for 30 d. The changes in lemon fruits&#8217; basic physicochemical properties, enzyme activities, and antioxidant capacities were studied. Comparing the combined treatment to the control, the outcomes demonstrated a significant reduction in weight loss, firmness, stomatal opening, and inhibition of polyphenol oxidase (PPO) and peroxidase (POD) activities. Additionally, the combined treatment maintained high levels of titratable acidity (TA), vitamin C (VC), total phenolic content (TPC), and antioxidant capacity and preserved the lemon aroma. Meanwhile, the correlation between fruit color, aroma compounds, and antioxidant capacity was revealed, providing valuable insights into the postharvest preservation of lemons. In conclusion, the combined treatment (MT + CA) was effective in maintaining the quality and antioxidant capacity of lemons.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Eric Zheng, Ziqin Lin, Ze Miao, Yuhang Li, Shenqiang Hu, Yanan Gao, Yuqian Jiang, Lingling Pang, Xihong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/foods13203298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag-Mediated Growth of Au/Ag&#8211;Cu Ternary Heterostructures for Selective Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12952</link>
      <description>Wenhao Xu, Taishi Xiao, Jie Chen, Junxiang Shu, Jili Li, Yao Ma, Xiang Li, Zihan Zhong, Zitao Zhang, Yefei Li, Qing Zhang, Zhengzong Sun, Yun Tang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403382319

                Copper (Cu)-based nanocatalysts play crucial roles in the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (ECO2RR) for sustainable energy resources. Particularly, Cu-based nanostructures incorporating Au and Ag are promising, offering enhanced activity, selectivity, and stability. However, precise control over the structure and composition of heterostructures remains challenging, hindering the development of highly efficient catalysts. Herein, we present a silver (Ag) transition-layer-mediated approach to synthesize ternary heterostructures with two specific morphologies, namely, Au/Ag&#8211;Cu-side and Au/Ag&#8211;Cu-tip, which exhibit different Ag&#8211;Cu interface epitaxial patterns. The two heterostructures achieve high C2 product selectivity in ECO2RR. Especially, the Au/Ag&#8211;Cu-side structure achieves 50.3% C2 selectivity with 35.5% ethanol, while the tip structure shows higher ethylene selectivity. Our study reveals the impact of the Ag layer in directing deposition sites on heterostructure growth and further facilitating the design of multicomponent Cu-based catalysts with enhanced structural integrity and ECO2RR performance.</description>
      <author>Wenhao Xu, Taishi Xiao, Jie Chen, Junxiang Shu, Jili Li, Yao Ma, Xiang Li, Zihan Zhong, Zitao Zhang, Yefei Li, Qing Zhang, Zhengzong Sun, Yun Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Hybrid Vehicle Integration in Nablus Urban Shared-Taxis: Cost-Benefit and Exhaust Emissions Assessment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35552/anujr.a.39.1.2317</link>
      <description>Sharif Bassam Salman, Khaled Al&#8208;Sahili, An-Najah University Journal for Research - A (Natural Sciences). 39(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403414127

                There is a worldwide concern about the increase in vehicles&#8217; exhaust emissions of traditional fuels and the rise in fuel prices. Nablus city is a major city in the West Bank, Palestine with peculiar topography and traffic congestion. This increases fuel consumption and the gas emission of the diesel operated public transport (PT) shared-taxi vehicles. This paper investigates the viability of introducing hybrid vehicles to the urban shared-taxis in highly congested areas with peculiar topography. Interviews were conducted and questionnaires were distributed among PT drivers and route managers to obtain the operational and cost characteristics of each route. The existing expenses and revenues and gas emissions of diesel vehicles were analyzed. Expenses-revenues analysis revealed that there is no immediate urgency in switching all diesel-fuel shared-taxis to hybrid; therefore, two scenarios were developed. The first was replacing old PT cars (2009 or older) with hybrid vehicles, which provided an average financial saving of 20.9% with a reduction in exhausts emission of CO2-equivalent by 33%. The second scenario included replacing PT vehicles with production dates from 2009-2014, which produced financial savings of 15% and reduction of exhaust emissions by 35%. The comparison showed a preference for the first scenario at the current time, while implementing other scenarios gradually. The first scenario is simple and close to reality; as old vehicles should typically be replaced. The study recommends using hybrid vehicles for new shared-taxis introduced to the service, and establishing national level policies to encourage the use of alternative fuels for the transportation sector, focusing on PT. However, several critical factors must be considered, including topography and route characteristics.</description>
      <author>Sharif Bassam Salman, Khaled Al&#8208;Sahili</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35552/anujr.a.39.1.2317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of Intracellular Elemental Sulfur Oxidation in Beggiatoa leptomitoformis, Where Persulfide Dioxygenase Plays a Key Role</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252010962</link>
      <description>Tatyana S. Rudenko, Liubov Trubitsina, Vasily V. Terentyev, Ivan V. Trubitsin, Valentin Borshchevskiy, Svetlana Tishchenko, Azat Gabdulkhakov, Alexey A. Leontievsky, M. Yu. Grabovich, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 25(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403379065

                Representatives of the colorless sulfur bacteria of the genus Beggiatoa use reduced sulfur compounds in the processes of lithotrophic growth, which is accompanied by the storage of intracellular sulfur. However, it is still unknown how the transformation of intracellular sulfur occurs in Beggiatoa representatives. Annotation of the genome of Beggiatoa leptomitoformis D-402 did not identify any genes for the oxidation or reduction of elemental sulfur. By searching BLASTP, two putative persulfide dioxygenase (PDO) homologs were found in the genome of B. leptomitoformis. In some heterotrophic prokaryotes, PDO is involved in the oxidation of sulfane sulfur. According to HPLC-MS/MS, the revealed protein was reliably detected in a culture sample grown only in the presence of endogenous sulfur and CO2. The recombinant protein from B. leptomitoformis was active in the presence of glutathione persulfide. The crystal structure of recombinant PDO exhibited consistency with known structures of type I PDO. Thus, it was shown that B. leptomitoformis uses PDO to oxidize endogenous sulfur. Additionally, on the basis of HPLC-MS/MS, RT-qPCR, and the study of PDO reaction products, we predicted the interrelation of PDO and Sox-system function in the oxidation of endogenous sulfur in B. leptomitoformis and the connection of this process with energy metabolism.</description>
      <author>Tatyana S. Rudenko, Liubov Trubitsina, Vasily V. Terentyev, Ivan V. Trubitsin, Valentin Borshchevskiy, Svetlana Tishchenko, Azat Gabdulkhakov, Alexey A. Leontievsky, M. Yu. Grabovich</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252010962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incorporation of Nanoalumina in Potassium Feldspar-based Phosphoric Acid Activated Geopolymer Composites: A Sustainable Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13074/jent.2024.09.243840</link>
      <description>M. Nanthini, R Ganesan, V.M. Jaganathan, Journal of Environmental Nanotechnology. 13(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403388437

                This study investigates the potential of potassium feldspar-phosphate-based geopolymer concrete as a sustainable replacement to traditional concrete, addressing the environmental concerns associated with CO2 emissions during cement production. While geopolymer concrete offers a promising path towards sustainability, its performance often falls short of Portland cement concrete. This study investigates the use of nanoalumina in improving the performance of geopolymer concrete. A ternary mix was formulated with potassium feldspar powder, metakaolin and rice husk ash, incorporating varying percentages of nanoalumina geopolymer concrete mixes. The mechanical characteristics of the resulting geopolymer composites were assessed through compressive and split tensile strength tests. The findings revealed that a 4% nanoalumina dosage (GC-N4) yielded the most significant improvement in strength and durability. The GC-N4 mix performed superior in all metrics, demonstrating the highest compressive (41.82 MPa) and split tensile (3.7 Mpa) strengths. Reduction in water absorption and durability aspects were also optimum in GC-N4. These results highlight the potential of incorporating nanoalumina into a ternary mix of potassium feldspar powder, metakaolin and rice husk ash to significantly enhance the overall performance of geopolymer concrete, promoting its wider adoption as a sustainable construction material.</description>
      <author>M. Nanthini, R Ganesan, V.M. Jaganathan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13074/jent.2024.09.243840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Micro Fulfilment Centers in Alleviating, in a Sustainable Way, the Urban Last Mile Logistics Problem: A Systematic Literature Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16208774</link>
      <description>Andreas Karaoulanis, Sustainability. 16(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403336362

                This systematic literature review has as its aim to discuss how the use of micro fulfilment centers can help logistics and supply chain professionals in alleviating the urban last mile logistics problem. This systematic literature review adapts the SALSA approach, the PRISMA 2009 checklist, and the PRISMA 2020 flow diagram, while its validity is based on the utilization of the qualitative CASP checklist. In addition to the above, certain inclusion/exclusion criteria were used. The findings of this review underline that micro fulfilment centers are a key new approach in terms of alleviating the last mile logistics problem, in urban areas where space is extremely limited via a reduction in CO2 emissions, the use of new technologies not only in operations but also in the delivery of goods and the increase in customer satisfaction. This is an original and breakthrough literature review as it covers a gap in the existing literature that has to do with the role of micro fulfilment centers in urban areas in terms of alleviating the last mile logistics problem, a topic about which not much have been written until now as it is quite novel. This literature review gives a clear path for the researcher of the future in terms of approaching the urban last mile logistics problem via the lens of the use of micro fulfilment centers, while it contributes to the urban logistics industry in several ways.</description>
      <author>Andreas Karaoulanis</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16208774</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Catalyst Surfaces at Work: introducing Mixed Isotope Operando Infrared Spectroscopy (MIOIRS)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k44l1</link>
      <description>Matteo Monai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403377064

                This perspective focuses on the characterization of supported metal catalyst by operando and CO infrared (IR) spectroscopy. CO IR spectroscopy is a powerful technique to probe catalyst surfaces, and is used to identify single atom catalysts, estimate metal surface availability to the gas phase, and measure catalyst Lewis acidity. However, the interpretation of CO IR spectra on metal surfaces is not trivial, and influenced by dipole-dipole interactions among CO molecules at medium to high coverage. Such phenomenon results in spectral distortions, such as intensity transfer among IR bands, appearance of spurious bands, and shifts in band position. Dipole-dipole interactions have been widely investigated and understood in the 1950s&#8211;90s, but the implications for operando spectroscopy have been seemingly overlooked in literature, with a few exceptions. Inspired by seminal studies in the field, I propose here the use of mixed isotopic streams, such as diluted 13CO in 12CO, to reduce dipole coupling effects and retrieve more information from operando IR spectra in reactions involving CO, such as CO oxidation or hydrogenation reactions. Similarly, mixed 13CO2/12CO2 streams may be applied in CO2 hydrogenation, where adsorbed CO is commonly observed. The proposed name of the technique is Mixed Isotope Operando IR Spectroscopy, MIOIRS. In this perspective, I will first summarize the nature of dipole-dipole interactions in adsorbed CO layers, and their effects on CO IR spectra. Then, I will briefly describe how diluted isotopic mixtures of CO can partially break the coupling among adsorbates and reduce spectral distortion. In both sections, I will give a few showcases of the implications of vibrational coupling in heterogeneous catalysts characterization. Finally, I will discuss the possible implications of MIOIRS for the detection and quantification of defect and surface sites on metal nanoparticles, the characterization of bimetallic nanoparticles surfaces, and the kinetics of CO intermediates adsorbed on different active sites. Notably, MIOIRS may be expanded to other reactions in which adsorbates have strong permanent dipoles, such as in self-catalytic reduction for NOx abatement.</description>
      <author>Matteo Monai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k44l1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
