<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 01:25:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing carbon enrichment by metal&#8211;organic cage to improve the electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction performance of silver-based catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.011</link>
      <description>Shouxin Zhang, Yao Luo, Xuli Hu, Zhenyao Li, Yu&#8208;Shan Wu, Wei Wei, Wei Wang, Xiang&#8208;Kui Gu, Junchen Xu, Mingyue Ding, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405105539

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shouxin Zhang, Yao Luo, Xuli Hu, Zhenyao Li, Yu&#8208;Shan Wu, Wei Wei, Wei Wang, Xiang&#8208;Kui Gu, Junchen Xu, Mingyue Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Strategies of Indium&#8208;Based Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400548</link>
      <description>Xinwang Zhu, Xu Yan, Lan Ran, Shanyong Chen, Zengxia Pei, Xiaoqing Qiu, Small Structures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405151422

                In electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (CO 2 RR), indium (In)&#8208;based catalysts with low toxicity and environmental benefits are renowned for their specific high selectivity for formic acid and intrinsic inertia for the competing hydrogen evolution reaction. However, recent studies have reported various products over In&#8208;based catalysts showing comparable or even higher selectivity for carbon monoxide (CO) than for formic acid (HCOOH), puzzling the reaction pathway for CO 2 reduction. This article presents a comprehensive review of recent studies on electrocatalytic CO 2 RR over In&#8208;based catalysts highlighting the formation pathway of specific products. First, the mechanism of electrocatalytic CO 2 RR with the multiple reaction pathways is concluded considering the relationship between reaction intermediates and selectivity. Furthermore, the regulation strategies for multiple product formation are summarized, including crystalline phase engineering, alloying, nanostructuring, and structural modulation of In single atom, where the effect of key intermediates (*COOH, *OOCH, and *OCHO) on product generation is systematically discussed to achieve high selectivity. Finally, the intrinsic regulation mechanisms of these strategies are analyzed and the challenges and opportunities for the development of next&#8208;generation In&#8208;based catalysts are proposed.</description>
      <author>Xinwang Zhu, Xu Yan, Lan Ran, Shanyong Chen, Zengxia Pei, Xiaoqing Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent developments in carbon nitride for enhanced photocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jscs.2024.101956</link>
      <description>Tehmeena Ishaq, Rabia Naeem, Ayesha Qayyum, Maryam Yousaf, Zainab Ehsan, Aamal A. Al-Mutairi, Ali Irfan, Sami A. Al&#8208;Hussain, Rab Nawaz, Magdi E. A. Zaki, Journal of Saudi Chemical Society. 28(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405174448

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tehmeena Ishaq, Rabia Naeem, Ayesha Qayyum, Maryam Yousaf, Zainab Ehsan, Aamal A. Al-Mutairi, Ali Irfan, Sami A. Al&#8208;Hussain, Rab Nawaz, Magdi E. A. Zaki</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jscs.2024.101956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano titanium dioxide coating &lt;i&gt;Haematococcus pluvialis&lt;/i&gt; enhances photoelectric carbon dioxide reduction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1142/s1088424624500664</link>
      <description>Yu Xiao, Yuantao Chen, Wei Zhang, Liming Shao, Journal of Porphyrins and Phthalocyanines. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405195570

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Xiao, Yuantao Chen, Wei Zhang, Liming Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1142/s1088424624500664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of high-performance photocatalysts for solar-driven hydrogen production and carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26599/cf.2024.9200025</link>
      <description>Chan Woo Lee, Jeong Hyun Kim, Megalamane S. Bootharaju, Taeghwan Hyeon, Byoung&#8208;Hoon Lee, Carbon Future. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405196696

                Photocatalysis presents a promising pathway for clean energy generation by leveraging solar energy under environmentally benign conditions with minimal pollutant emissions. However, its widespread application is hindered by low catalytic efficiency, stemming from limited light absorption, rapid recombination of photo-excited electrons, and suboptimal charge carrier potential for target reactions. This review discusses advanced strategies to enhance photocatalytic performance by modulating photocatalytic supports and refining co-catalysts. Techniques such as hydrogenation and extrinsic doping of photocatalytic supports are highlighted for their ability to broaden light absorption and prolong electron lifetimes. Additionally, the strategic design of co-catalysts, including the use of nanoclusters and atomically dispersed catalysts, is emphasized for optimizing charge carrier potential and improving atomic utilization efficiency. This review aims to guide researchers in developing high-performance photocatalysts for clean energy applications, including CO2 reduction and plastic waste photoreforming, thereby contributing to the advancement of sustainable energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Chan Woo Lee, Jeong Hyun Kim, Megalamane S. Bootharaju, Taeghwan Hyeon, Byoung&#8208;Hoon Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26599/cf.2024.9200025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pivotal role of triethanolamine species in Rhodi-um-catalysed carbon dioxide photoreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-5dcf2</link>
      <description>Alisa Ranscht, Albert Sol&#233;&#8208;Daura, Thomas C. Robinson, Ashta C. Ghosh, Youven Benseghir, Mohammed H. Alkhurisi, Cindy&#8208;Ly Tavera&#8208;M&#233;ndez, Pauline Bredy, Elsje Alessandra Quadrelli, Anne Lesage, J. Canivet, Caroline Mellot&#8208;Draznieks, Florian M. Wisser, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405202708

                To achieve high catalytic activity of artificial photosystems in carbon dioxide reduction or water reduction/oxidation into renewable energy vectors, the use of sacrificial electron do-nors (SEDs) remains mandatory. Despite significant progress in artificial photocatalysis, a detailed understanding of the influence of the SEDs on the reaction mechanism is still lack-ing. We have explored the roles of triethanolamine as SED in the selective CO2 to formic acid photoreduction promoted by various pentamethylcyclopentadienyl rhodium(III)-based porous materials as model catalysts, including polyoxometalate-doped systems. In the pres-ence of anionic polyoxometalates, agglomeration of protonated triethanolamine close to the catalytically active site favours H2 evolution over CO2 reduction, which can be modulated through the degree of confinement imposed by the pores size. Radical trapping experiments and EPR spectroscopy show that triethanolamine-radicals are crucial for a high activity in CO2 reduction. Triethanolamine-radicals act as electron relays in the efficient two-electron activation of the catalyst, regardless whether a homogeneous or a heterogeneous catalyst is used. In contrast, triethylamine-radicals cause deactivation of the one-electron reduced cata-lyst, thus highlighting the effect of different SED-intermediates and underling the im-portance of an appropriate SED.</description>
      <author>Alisa Ranscht, Albert Sol&#233;&#8208;Daura, Thomas C. Robinson, Ashta C. Ghosh, Youven Benseghir, Mohammed H. Alkhurisi, Cindy&#8208;Ly Tavera&#8208;M&#233;ndez, Pauline Bredy, Elsje Alessandra Quadrelli, Anne Lesage, J. Canivet, Caroline Mellot&#8208;Draznieks, Florian M. Wisser</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-5dcf2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Monoxide Dehydrogenases on Functionalized Carbon Nanotubes forReversible CO2 to CO Conversion</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4405299325</link>
      <description>Alan Le Goff, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405299325

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alan Le Goff</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4405299325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial-Temporal Features of Taxi Carbon Dioxide Emissions and Reduction Strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1061/9780784485484.293</link>
      <description>Mingzhi Wang, Jingdong Jin, Chunjiao Dong, Y X Li, Junyue Wang, CICTP 2021. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405294988

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingzhi Wang, Jingdong Jin, Chunjiao Dong, Y X Li, Junyue Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1061/9780784485484.293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of overlapping layout of Fe/TiO2 on CO2 reduction with H2 and H2O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15406/mojsp.2019.03.00028</link>
      <description>Akira Nishimura, Daichi Tatematsu, Ryuki Toyoda, Masafumi Hirota, Akira Koshio, Kokai Fumio, Eric Hu, MOJ Solar and Photoenergy Systems. 3(1)] 2019. https://openalex.org/W4405255328

                Fe-doped TiO2 (Fe/TiO2) film photocatalyst was prepared by sol-gel dip-coating, and pulse arc plasma process. The netlike glass fiber was used as a base material for the photocatalyst since it had a porous structure. The CO2 reduction performance with H2 and H2O into CO over the Fe/TiO2 photocatalyst was investigated. In addition, this study investigated overlapping two Fe/TiO2 coated on netlike glass fiber in order to utilize the light more effectively as well as increase the amount of photocatalyst for CO2 reduction. The characterization of prepared Fe/TiO2 film coated on netlike glass fiber was analyzed by SEM, EPMA, TEM, EDX and EELS. Furthermore, the CO2 reduction performance of the Fe/TiO2 film was tested under a Xe lamp with or without ultraviolet (UV) light, respectively. The results show that the CO2 reduction performance peaks under the condition of CO2/H2/H2O=1:1:0.5 in both cases with UV light and without UV light illumination. The highest concentration of CO with the Fe/TiO2 overlapped photocatalyst is 1.2 times of that with the single Fe/TiO2 photocatalyst. On the other hand, results also show the highest molar quantity of CO per weight of photocatalyst for Fe/TiO2 overlapped is almost half of single Fe/TiO2.</description>
      <author>Akira Nishimura, Daichi Tatematsu, Ryuki Toyoda, Masafumi Hirota, Akira Koshio, Kokai Fumio, Eric Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15406/mojsp.2019.03.00028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the synthesis of methylamine by electrocatalytic CO2 and NO3&#8722; co-reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.125136</link>
      <description>F.&#8208;T. LUO, Ling Guo, Jinyang Li, Journal of Solid State Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405098234

                No abstract</description>
      <author>F.&#8208;T. LUO, Ling Guo, Jinyang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.125136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical reduction of CO2 on pure and doped Cu2O(1 1 1)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.056</link>
      <description>H. Y. Liu, Lei Zhu, Zhichao Yu, Haoyun Bai, Hui Pan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405175780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Y. Liu, Lei Zhu, Zhichao Yu, Haoyun Bai, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deactivation of Copper Electrocatalysts During CO2 Reduction Occurs via Dissolution and Selective Redeposition Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f</link>
      <description>Marjan Bele, Bla&#382; Tomc, Azeezulla Nazrulla Mohammed, Primo&#382; &#352;ket, Matja&#382; Fin&#353;gar, Angelja Kjara &#352;urca, Ana Rebeka Kam&#353;ek, Martin &#352;ala, Jan &#352;iler Hudoklin, Matej Hu&#353;, Bla&#382; Likozar, Nejc Hodnik, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405237621

                As electrochemical CO2 reduction (ECR) nears industrialisation levels, addressing the uncontrolled stability, restructuring, and deactivation of copper (Cu) catalysts during operation becomes as crucial as achieving high activity and selectivity...</description>
      <author>Marjan Bele, Bla&#382; Tomc, Azeezulla Nazrulla Mohammed, Primo&#382; &#352;ket, Matja&#382; Fin&#353;gar, Angelja Kjara &#352;urca, Ana Rebeka Kam&#353;ek, Martin &#352;ala, Jan &#352;iler Hudoklin, Matej Hu&#353;, Bla&#382; Likozar, Nejc Hodnik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-Modulated Cu Reconstruction to Steer the Hydride/Hydroxyl Pathway of Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54227/elab.20240010</link>
      <description>Peng Yang, Energy Lab. 2(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405121354

                Reconstructing metal-organic complexes effectively generates hybrid nanocatalysts for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction (eCO2R), but the role of metal-ligand interactions in shaping these hybrids and their influence on the electronic states of the reduced Cu species remain unclear. Herein, we impregnate Cu(II) acetate (Cu(OAc)2) into two Zirconium-based metal organic frameworks (MOFs) with different ligands to in situ construct Cu-based nanocatalysts for eCO2R. We show that Cu-ligand interactions crucially determine the transformation of Cu(OAc)2 during electrolysis, with biphenyl linkers forming agglomerated Cu2O particles and bipyridine linkers yielding highly dispersed Cu crystallites. This ligand-modulated Cu reconstruction diverges eCO2R towards C2 and C1 pathways, with agglomerated Cu2O particles producing C2+ products and smaller Cu crystallites achieving a maximum CH4 Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 60.3% &#177; 0.5% at 600 mA/cm2. In situ IR and Raman spectra unveil that larger Cu2O particles accumulate Cu-OH, increasing local alkalinity and *CO coverage, which favors asymmetric C-C coupling to yield C2+ products. Conversely, smaller Cu crystallites undergo rapid consumption of OH- and Cu-OH, decreasing alkalinity and promoting metal hydride (M-H) formation and sequential hydrogenation of *CO toward CH4 production. This study signifies the exploitation of metal-organic filler-host interactions to manipulate catalyst reconstruction for tailoring local environment towards selective eCO2R.</description>
      <author>Peng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54227/elab.20240010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Pathway Regulation for Gaseous and Liquid Products of Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction under Adsorbate Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419456</link>
      <description>Feng Hu, Xiaoqian Xu, Yajie Sun, Chuan Hu, Shuning Shen, Sheng Wang, Lei Gong, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405187869

                Halide anion adsorption on transition metals can improve the performance of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), while the specific reaction mechanisms governing selective CO2RR pathways remain unclear. In this study, we demonstrate for the first time the distinct pathways for gaseous (CO) and liquid products (formate and ethanol) on the well&#8208;defined Ag&#8208;Cu nanostructures with controlled chlorination, respectively. We show that CO2 conversion to CO on Ag/AgCl can be tuned by adjusting the thickness of AgCl layer, achieving a Faradaic efficiency (FE) near 100% over a broad potential range in a 0.5 M KHCO3 using flow cell. In contrast, the optimized Cl&#8208;Ag/Cu system enables the conversion of CO2 into liquid products including formate and ethanol with a total FE nearing 100%, delivering high current density under similar conditions. In situ infrared experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that the lateral adsorbate of *OCHO intermediate facilitates the thermodynamics of both the CO pathway on Cl&#8208;Ag(111) and the formate pathway on Cl&#8208;Ag/Cu(111) by reducing Gibbs free energy barriers of each potential&#8208;limit step. This work uncovers the role of chlorination in the tuning of C&#8208;bound or O&#8208;bound intermediates during CO2RR on Ag&#8208;Cu catalysts, determining the reaction pathway under lateral adsorbate effects.</description>
      <author>Feng Hu, Xiaoqian Xu, Yajie Sun, Chuan Hu, Shuning Shen, Sheng Wang, Lei Gong, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Pathway Regulation for Gaseous and Liquid Products of Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction under Adsorbate Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419456</link>
      <description>Feng Hu, Xiaoqian Xu, Yajie Sun, Chuan Hu, Shuning Shen, Sheng Wang, Lei Gong, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405188591

                Halide anion adsorption on transition metals can improve the performance of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), while the specific reaction mechanisms governing selective CO2RR pathways remain unclear. In this study, we demonstrate for the first time the distinct pathways for gaseous (CO) and liquid products (formate and ethanol) on the well-defined Ag-Cu nanostructures with controlled chlorination, respectively. We show that CO2 conversion to CO on Ag/AgCl can be tuned by adjusting the thickness of AgCl layer, achieving a Faradaic efficiency (FE) near 100% over a broad potential range in a 0.5 M KHCO3 using flow cell. In contrast, the optimized Cl-Ag/Cu system enables the conversion of CO2 into liquid products including formate and ethanol with a total FE nearing 100%, delivering high current density under similar conditions. In situ infrared experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that the lateral adsorbate of *OCHO intermediate facilitates the thermodynamics of both the CO pathway on Cl-Ag(111) and the formate pathway on Cl-Ag/Cu(111) by reducing Gibbs free energy barriers of each potential-limit step. This work uncovers the role of chlorination in the tuning of C-bound or O-bound intermediates during CO2RR on Ag-Cu catalysts, determining the reaction pathway under lateral adsorbate effects.</description>
      <author>Feng Hu, Xiaoqian Xu, Yajie Sun, Chuan Hu, Shuning Shen, Sheng Wang, Lei Gong, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Further study of CO2 electrochemical reduction to gas products on Cu: Influence of the electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110742</link>
      <description>Zekun Zhang, Shiji Li, Qian Zhang, Shanshan Li, Yang Liu, Wei Yan, Hao Xu, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405212383

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zekun Zhang, Shiji Li, Qian Zhang, Shanshan Li, Yang Liu, Wei Yan, Hao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size, Shape, Facet and Support Dependent Selectivity of Cu nanoparticles in CO2 reduction through multiparameter optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03567d</link>
      <description>Anjana Tripathi, Ranjit Thapa, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405291315

                This study investigates the limited selectivity of Cu111 surface for C-C bond formation during CO2 reduction and explores factors influencing selectivity using Cu nanoparticles smaller than 2 nm. Optimal nanoparticle...</description>
      <author>Anjana Tripathi, Ranjit Thapa</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03567d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defective TiO2 for CO2 Photoreduction: Influence of Alkaline Agent and Reduction Temperature Modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115162</link>
      <description>Rudolf Ricka, Agnieszka Wanag, Ewelina Kusiak&#8208;Nejman, Miroslava Edelmannov&#225;, Martin Reli, Marcin &#321;api&#324;ski, Grzegorz S&#322;owik, Antoni W. Morawski, Kamila Ko&#269;&#237;, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405287334

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rudolf Ricka, Agnieszka Wanag, Ewelina Kusiak&#8208;Nejman, Miroslava Edelmannov&#225;, Martin Reli, Marcin &#321;api&#324;ski, Grzegorz S&#322;owik, Antoni W. Morawski, Kamila Ko&#269;&#237;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Cu+ species by Al-doping with enhanced *CO coverage for highly efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction to C2+ products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07386j</link>
      <description>Yuhui Chen, Xuerong Wang, Qianqian Zhao, Shulin Zhao, Albert Pang, Luyao Yang, Yidan Sun, Yu Wang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405219630

                The copper-based oxide catalysts have garnered significant attention due to their remarkable capacity for selectively producing multicarbon (C2+) compounds in CO2 reduction by renewable-electricity-driven. However, the Cu+ species in catalysts...</description>
      <author>Yuhui Chen, Xuerong Wang, Qianqian Zhao, Shulin Zhao, Albert Pang, Luyao Yang, Yidan Sun, Yu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07386j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of novel catalysts bearing s-heptazine-based ligand for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4405144559</link>
      <description>Benjamin Louis, Johan Loison, Pascale Maldivi, Lionel Dubois, Julie Andrez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405144559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Benjamin Louis, Johan Loison, Pascale Maldivi, Lionel Dubois, Julie Andrez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4405144559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Deactivation of Copper Electrocatalysts During CO2 Reduction Occurs via Dissolution and Selective Redeposition Mechanism"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405275574

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Deactivation of Copper Electrocatalysts During CO2 Reduction Occurs via Dissolution and Selective Redeposition Mechanism"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274971

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Deactivation of Copper Electrocatalysts During CO2 Reduction Occurs via Dissolution and Selective Redeposition Mechanism"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405275659

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst-free reduction of CO2: Achieved by spontaneous generation of hydrogen radicals through nanobubbles-water system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158526</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Ben Niu, Gaodong Yang, Aosheng Chang, Sheng Wang, Zhibing Zhang, Ying Chen, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405221608

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Ben Niu, Gaodong Yang, Aosheng Chang, Sheng Wang, Zhibing Zhang, Ying Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Deactivation of Copper Electrocatalysts During CO2 Reduction Occurs via Dissolution and Selective Redeposition Mechanism"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405275209

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Deactivation of Copper Electrocatalysts During CO2 Reduction Occurs via Dissolution and Selective Redeposition Mechanism"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274951

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Correction: Iron sulfide-catalyzed gaseous CO2 reduction and prebiotic carbon fixation in terrestrial hot springs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55040-0</link>
      <description>Jingbo Nan, Shunqin Luo, Quoc Phuong Tran, Albert C. Fahrenbach, Wenning Lu, Yingjie Hu, Zongjun Yin, Jinhua Ye, Martin J. Van Kranendonk, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405107395

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingbo Nan, Shunqin Luo, Quoc Phuong Tran, Albert C. Fahrenbach, Wenning Lu, Yingjie Hu, Zongjun Yin, Jinhua Ye, Martin J. Van Kranendonk</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55040-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Deactivation of Copper Electrocatalysts During CO2 Reduction Occurs via Dissolution and Selective Redeposition Mechanism"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274907

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Deactivation of Copper Electrocatalysts During CO2 Reduction Occurs via Dissolution and Selective Redeposition Mechanism"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Marjan Bele, Bla&#382; Tomc, Azeezulla Nazrulla Mohammed, Primo&#382; &#352;ket, Matja&#382; Fin&#353;gar, Angelja Kjara &#352;urca, Ana Rebeka Kam&#353;ek, Martin &#352;ala, Jan &#352;iler Hudoklin, Matej Hu&#353;, Bla&#382; Likozar, Nejc Hodnik, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405275344

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marjan Bele, Bla&#382; Tomc, Azeezulla Nazrulla Mohammed, Primo&#382; &#352;ket, Matja&#382; Fin&#353;gar, Angelja Kjara &#352;urca, Ana Rebeka Kam&#353;ek, Martin &#352;ala, Jan &#352;iler Hudoklin, Matej Hu&#353;, Bla&#382; Likozar, Nejc Hodnik</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06466f/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on CO2 reduction reaction in the proton conducting solid oxide electrolysis reactor with Fe catalyst layer coverage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.483</link>
      <description>Yanhong Zhang, Ruiqing Song, Jie Zou, Jiaming Chu, Haiyang Lan, Juan Zhou, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405104818

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanhong Zhang, Ruiqing Song, Jie Zou, Jiaming Chu, Haiyang Lan, Juan Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Study of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction on 2D Graphitic Carbon Nitride Supported Single&#8208;Atom (Al and P) Catalysts (SACs)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400908</link>
      <description>Manoj Wijesingha, Yirong Mo, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405099351

                To mitigate the adverse effects of CO2 emissions, CO2 electroreduction to small organic products is a preferable solution and potential catalysts include the single&#8208;atom catalyst (SAC) which comprises individual atoms dispersed on 2D materials. Here, we used aluminium and phosphorus as the active sites for CO2 electroreductions by embedding them on the 2D graphitic carbon nitride (g&#8208;C3N4) nano&#8208;surface. The resulting M&#8208;C3N4 (M = Al and P) SACs were computationally studied for the CO2 electroreduction using density functional theory (DFT) and ab&#8208;initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations. Computations showed that CO2 can be adsorbed to the active sites in forms of a frustrated Lewis pair (Al/N or P/N) or single atom Al or P. The adsorbed CO2 can be converted to various intermediates by gaining proton and electron (H+ + e&#8208;) pairs, a process simulated as electroreduction. While both SACs prefer to produce HCOOH with low potential determining steps (PDSs) and small overpotential values of 0.25 V and 0.08 V for Al&#8208;C3N4 and P&#8208;C3N4 respectively, to produce CH4, P&#8208;C3N4 exhibits a lower potential barrier of 0.9 eV than Al&#8208;C3N4 (1.07~1.17 eV).</description>
      <author>Manoj Wijesingha, Yirong Mo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of MIMII-PC6 dual-atom electrocatalysts for efficient and selective electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to C1 and C2 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101613</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Xiang Feng, Yangyang Song, Haixia Wang, Chen Chen, Xian Zhao, Weiliu Fan, Materials Today Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405237089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Xiang Feng, Yangyang Song, Haixia Wang, Chen Chen, Xian Zhao, Weiliu Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of CO2 to C2 products by tandem actives sites of a novel 2D/3D structured photoelectrocatalyst Ag/Cu2O/g-C3N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115058</link>
      <description>Huanan Qi, Xiaoyu Han, Jiangpeng Fu, Jing Wang, Xuan Jia, MingHao Zhao, Xiaona Wang, Zhongtian Fu, Jun Zhang, Xin Zhao, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405142667

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huanan Qi, Xiaoyu Han, Jiangpeng Fu, Jing Wang, Xuan Jia, MingHao Zhao, Xiaona Wang, Zhongtian Fu, Jun Zhang, Xin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical prediction of the reaction mechanism underlying the active phase of Bn (n = 3&#8211;5) and Cu-doped electron deficient Bn-1 clusters: Reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112564</link>
      <description>H. Liu, Ling Fu, Chao He, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405097843

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Liu, Ling Fu, Chao He</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicted C&#8211;N coupling performance of lateral heterostructure interfaces between two types of layered materials for electrochemical synthesis of acetamide and Ammonia via reduction of CO2 and N2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.121082</link>
      <description>Tianhang Zhou, Chen Shen, Xiyu Wang, Xingying Lan, Yi Xiao, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405287968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianhang Zhou, Chen Shen, Xiyu Wang, Xingying Lan, Yi Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.121082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Carbon Nanorods Encapsulating Bismuth Nanoparticles Promote p-Si Nanowire Array for Photoelectrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03361</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Chen, Jihu Kang, Mingyue Zou, Keke Wang, Min Liu, Wenzhang Li, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405168751

                Photoelectrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide to high value-added chemicals is one of the effective means to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and alleviate the energy crisis. In this study, porous carbon nanorods encapsulating bismuth (Bi) nanoparticles were synthesized using a metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF)-assisted spatial confinement and high-temperature carbonization strategy and then modified on silicon nanowires to construct a Si&#8211;Bi@Cx composite photocathode. The presence of the plasmonic metal Bi enhances the light absorption and improves the selectivity of carbon dioxide reduction products as reactive substances. At &#8722;0.9 V vs RHE, the Si&#8211;Bi@C800 photocathode achieves a faradaic efficiency for formic acid (FEHCOOH) of up to 91.23%, with a production rate of 88.5 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1&#183;cm&#8211;2. Further experimental analysis and in situ infrared spectroscopy results showed that the porous carbon nanorods with strong hydrophobicity not only reduce the contact between the electrode and water and inhibit the occurrence of the hydrogen evolution reaction but also accelerate the mass transfer of CO2 molecules and increase the local CO2 concentration. Simultaneously, Bi nanoparticles promote the formation of the *OCHO intermediate and realize the efficient conversion of CO2 to formic acid. This study lays a foundation for constructing active sites on silicon-based semiconductors.</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Chen, Jihu Kang, Mingyue Zou, Keke Wang, Min Liu, Wenzhang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Assessment of the Performance and Emissions of an Otto Power Generator Group Operating with Wet Ethanol at a High Volumetric Compression Ratio</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236187</link>
      <description>Vin&#237;cius Guerra Moreira, S&#233;rgio de Morais Hanriot, Tales Gon&#231;alves Nazareno, Bruno Eust&#225;quio Pires Ferreira, Rafael Motter Juliatti, Hairton J&#250;nior Jos&#233; da Silveira, Cristiana Maia, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405186821

                This work presents an experimental study of the performance and emissions of an internal combustion engine operating in the Otto cycle with a high volumetric compression ratio (17:1). The engine was initially fueled with the standard ethanol used in Brazil, with 7% distilled water (E93W07); we then studied the effects of using different ethanol-in-water mixtures, or &#8216;wet ethanol&#8217;, with 17%, 27%, 37%, and 47% distilled water concentrations. The tests were carried out with power loads of 5.0&#8211;25.0 kW at 5.0 kW intervals and with power loads of 27.5&#8211;35.0 kW at 2.5 kW intervals, whether by adding up the loads or by taking them away. The ignition timing was changed to evaluate each load imposed on the engine to avoid knocking. Specific fuel consumption (SFC), brake thermal efficiency (BTE), carbon dioxide emissions (CO2), carbon monoxide (CO), nitrogen oxides (NOx), and total hydrocarbon content (THC), as well as the internal pressure in the cylinder and the heat release rate, were measured, and the results are compared. The results show a reduction in CO and NOx and an increase in THC emissions. However, there were no significant changes in CO2 emissions when the distilled water percentage in ethanol increased. Regarding the brake thermal efficiency, it was observed that it remained approximately constant for all blends, with the same load being applied to the engine shaft, reaching a maximum value of 35%. The results obtained confirm the technical feasibility of operating an internal combustion engine in the Otto cycle with a high volumetric compression ratio using ethanol with up to 47% distilled water without significant loss of performance.</description>
      <author>Vin&#237;cius Guerra Moreira, S&#233;rgio de Morais Hanriot, Tales Gon&#231;alves Nazareno, Bruno Eust&#225;quio Pires Ferreira, Rafael Motter Juliatti, Hairton J&#250;nior Jos&#233; da Silveira, Cristiana Maia</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Climate Change Alter the Swimming Behavior of Larval Stone Crabs?: A Guided-Inquiry Lesson</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5334/cjme.117</link>
      <description>Abigail L. Smith, Jean Labadie, Angela Busse, E. Solomon, Clare Farrell, Daniel M. Holstein, Z. George Xue, Philip M. Gravinese, Current The Journal of Marine Education. 39(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405285744

                The ocean has absorbed ~one third of the excess atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) released since the Industrial Revolution. When the ocean absorbs excess CO2, a series of chemical reactions occur that result in a reduction in seawater pH, a process called ocean acidification. The excess atmospheric CO2 is also resulting in warmer seawater temperatures. These stressors pose a threat to marine organisms, especially during earlier life stages (i.e., larvae). The larvae of species like the Florida stone crab (Menippe mercenaria) are free swimming, allowing a population to disperse and recruit into new habitats. After release, stone crab larvae undergo vertical swimming excursions in response to abiotic stimuli (gravity, light, pressure) allowing them to control their depth. Typically, newly hatched larvae respond to abiotic cues that would promote a shallower depth distribution, where surface currents can transport them offshore to complete development. As larvae develop offshore, they become less sensitive to certain abiotic stimuli, which promotes a deeper depth distribution that may expose them to variable current speeds, thus influencing the direction of advection (horizontal movement). Environmental stressors like ocean acidification and elevated seawater temperatures may also impact the larvae&#8217;s natural response to these abiotic stimuli throughout ontogeny (development). Changes in their natural swimming behavior due to climate stressors could, therefore, influence the transport and dispersal of the species. This guided-inquiry lesson challenges introductory marine biology and oceanography students to determine how future ocean pH and temperature projections could impact the swimming behavior of Florida stone crab larvae.</description>
      <author>Abigail L. Smith, Jean Labadie, Angela Busse, E. Solomon, Clare Farrell, Daniel M. Holstein, Z. George Xue, Philip M. Gravinese</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5334/cjme.117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Infectious Disease Risk Management on Indoor Environmental Quality in Lecture Rooms: Current Performance and Future Considerations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310792</link>
      <description>Adam O&#8217;Donovan, F Delaney, Ta&#239;na Ouvrard, Pierre A. Geoffroy, Paul D. O&#8217;Sullivan, Sustainability. 16(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405184789

                The global COVID-19 pandemic has resulted in significant and accelerated developments in ventilation practises, where the need to ventilate buildings has been put centre stage. Longer-term ventilation approaches are now more likely to utilise hybrid ventilation strategies to address the challenge of ensuring resilient indoor thermal environments that are carbon neutral while also minimising the risk of long-range airborne infectious spread of viral pathogens. In the short term, there are many existing buildings which may not undergo retrofit for some time, and consequently, risk mitigation strategies have been implemented in these buildings by utilising existing systems. This paper will present an indoor environmental quality evaluation of ten university lecture rooms both before, during and after changes in ventilation management behaviour and systems that were accelerated due to the COVID-19 pandemic. The results indicate a mean reduction in internal carbon dioxide levels of between 46% and 67% when pre-COVID-19 and COVID-19 datasets are compared and between 11% and 62% when pre-COVID-19 and post-COVID-19 datasets are compared. Changes in behaviour and systems have reduced the time spent above thresholds conducive to virus growth by between 8% and 54%, depending on the lecture room. Despite this, a &#8220;rebound&#8221; can be observed in many rooms, with CO2 levels appearing to be trending toward pre-pandemic levels. This work indicates the effect of behavioural and system changes on ventilation and the potential risk for virus spread. The results indicate a need to retrofit existing lecture rooms with more advanced natural or mechanical systems to ensure consistent indoor environmental quality.</description>
      <author>Adam O&#8217;Donovan, F Delaney, Ta&#239;na Ouvrard, Pierre A. Geoffroy, Paul D. O&#8217;Sullivan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;Designing&lt;/scp&gt; and screening single&#8208;atom alloy catalysts for &lt;scp&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; reduction to &lt;scp&gt;CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;OH&lt;/scp&gt; via &lt;scp&gt;DFT&lt;/scp&gt; and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18678</link>
      <description>Wenyu Zhou, Haisong Feng, Shihong Zhou, Mengxin Wang, Yuping Chen, Chenyang Lu, Hao Yuan, Jing Yang, Qun Li, Luxi Tan, Lichun Dong, Yong&#8208;Wei Zhang, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405247170

                Abstract Carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) utilization technology is of great significance for achieving carbon neutrality, in which the catalytic materials play crucial roles, and among them, single&#8208;atom alloys (SAAs) are of particular interests. In this study, density functional theory (DFT) calculations and machine learning are employed to assess the effectiveness of Cu&#8208;, Ag&#8208;, and Ni&#8208;host SAAs as catalysts for electrochemical CO 2 reduction to CH 3 OH. The Gibbs free energies of 477 elementary reactions across 35 SAAs involved in CO 2 reduction are calculated, and by utilizing this dataset, a trained gradient boosting regression model is established with an excellent accuracy. Subsequently, the properties of 46 unknown SAAs are predicted, including their pathways, products, potential&#8208;determining steps (PDS), and corresponding Gibbs free energies of the PDS ( G PDS ). Three promising candidates, ZnCu, AuAg and MoNi, stand out due to their lowest G PDS among Cu&#8208;, Ag&#8208; and Ni&#8208; hosted SAAs, respectively.</description>
      <author>Wenyu Zhou, Haisong Feng, Shihong Zhou, Mengxin Wang, Yuping Chen, Chenyang Lu, Hao Yuan, Jing Yang, Qun Li, Luxi Tan, Lichun Dong, Yong&#8208;Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-objective cropping pattern optimization and comparative assessment with the food-energy-water nexus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2166/ws.2024.254</link>
      <description>Volkan Hac&#305;s&#252;leyman, Mehmet &#214;zger, Water Science &amp; Technology Water Supply. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405199172

                ABSTRACT Agriculture is the largest consumer of water, accounting for nearly 70% of global freshwater consumption, and it also uses about 30% of the world's energy. This creates an increasing challenge for the efficient use of water and energy resources while adequately meeting food demand. Therefore, understanding the interrelations between food, energy, and water resources is crucial. In this study, a multi-objective linear programming model was employed to identify alternative scenarios for optimal cropping areas that minimize water use in agriculture and maximize agricultural income. Different weight coefficients were assigned to these objective functions to generate various cropping scenarios. Once the optimal cropping patterns for each scenario were determined, parameters such as water use, energy requirements, agricultural revenue, and carbon dioxide emissions were calculated based on the food-energy-water nexus. The results for each alternative crop pattern scenario were then analyzed. The results indicate that prioritizing the objective of minimizing water use leads to an average reduction of 3.35% in water use, 1.18% in energy demand, and 0.26% in carbon dioxide emissions, while agricultural income increases by an average of 1% compared to the base scenario. Conversely, when maximizing agricultural income is prioritized, there is an average increase of 2.05% in agricultural income.</description>
      <author>Volkan Hac&#305;s&#252;leyman, Mehmet &#214;zger</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2166/ws.2024.254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Green Development of Industrial Parks on the Reduction of Carbon Emissions in Urban Areas&#8212;Empirical Research on Green Industrial Parks in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024ef005161</link>
      <description>Xiang Yu, Wentao Hu, Mudan Wang, Earth s Future. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405278837

                Abstract China has over 2,500 national and provincial industrial parks, stimulating the economics growth, meanwhile being the primary sources of carbon dioxide emissions and other pollutants. Assessing the mechanisms and impacts of the policies of pilot programs of green industrial parks on urban carbon emissions offers critical insights into the efficacy and application of green and low&#8208;carbon development. This study utilizes a staggered difference&#8208;in&#8208;differences model to examine the impact of green industrial park pilot policies. The results demonstrate that green industrial parks have effectively reduced carbon emissions of the studied counties in terms of total and intensity. The economic scales and the administrative levels of any given city significantly influence the implementation effect of green industrial park policy. In applying the green industrial park policy, reducing the carbon emissions is more pronounced in cities with larger economic scales and higher administrative levels. Environmental regulation policies and green industrial park pilot policies exhibit a certain degree of substitution effect. The green industrial parks drive urban carbon emission reduction through three main channels: enhancing green technologies, optimizing industrial structures, and elevating economic agglomeration levels. Overall, this study provides a new perspective, a methodological reference, and empirical evidence for promoting green and low&#8208;carbon development for industrial parks in the different regions and developing countries.</description>
      <author>Xiang Yu, Wentao Hu, Mudan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024ef005161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Industrial Competitiveness on Carbon Emission Intensity: Evidence From Improved EKC Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06305</link>
      <description>, Global NEST Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405353156

                &lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US" style="font-size:12.0pt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;,serif"&gt;&lt;span style="layout-grid-mode:line"&gt;Industrial sector is regarded as the main source of carbon dioxide emission, and prior studies have mostly examined the effects of carbon reduction policies on the competitiveness of industries. However, whether and how industrial competitiveness affects carbon emission intensity (CEI) remains unclear. We develop the Environmental Kuznets Curve model (EKC) which introduces the characteristics of carbon dioxide and industrial life cycle. Additionally, we empirically investigate the impact mechanism of industrial competitiveness on CEI based on the panel data of 30 provinces in China from 2008 to 2019. The results show that: (1) Improving industrial competitiveness can significantly reduce CEI, in which outward foreign direct investment (OFDI) has a partial mediating role. (2) regional heterogeneities exist in the carbon mitigating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US" style="font-size:12.0pt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;,serif"&gt;&lt;span style="layout-grid-mode:line"&gt; effect of the industrial competitiveness, as it is larger and significant in the Northeast and West, but it is not significant in the East and Central. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US" style="font-size:12.0pt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;,serif"&gt;(3) &lt;span style="layout-grid-mode:line"&gt;The demarcation point between the investment-driven stage and the innovation-driven stage is -0.6993, and the demarcation point between the innovation-driven stage and the wealth-driven stage is -0.2776. &lt;/span&gt;(4) &lt;span style="layout-grid-mode:line"&gt;The carbon reduction effect of the industrial competitiveness is larger and significant in the investment-driven stage and the innovation-driven stage, but it is not significant in the wealth-driven stage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US" style="font-size:12.0pt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;,serif"&gt;&lt;span style="layout-grid-mode:line"&gt; Accordingly, for countries in the world, improving industrial competitiveness and then realizing industrial upgrading is an effective way to reduce carbon emission intensity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30955/gnj.06305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Potential Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Methanol over Nickel&#8208;Based Hollow 0D Carbon Superstructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403809</link>
      <description>Sayantan Chongdar, Rupak Chatterjee, S. K. Reza, Sitaram Pal, Ranjit Thapa, Rajaram Bal, Asim Bhaumik, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405257617

                Abstract Electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) to valuable fuels and chemical feedstock is a sustainable strategy to lower the anthropogenic CO 2 concentration, thereby dynamising the carbon cycle in the environment. CH 3 OH on the other hand is undoubtedly the most desirable C 1 product of CO 2 RR. However, selective electroreduction of CO 2 &#8208;to&#8208;CH 3 OH is very challenging and only limited catalysts are reported in literature. Pyrolyzing metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) to generate carbon matrix impregnated with metal nanoparticles, heralds exciting electrocatalytic properties. This study unveiled the morphological evolution of a mixed&#8208;ligand Ni&#8208;MOF (Ni&#8208;OBBA&#8208;Bpy) during pyrolysis, to generate Ni nanoparticles anchored 0D porous hollow carbon superstructures (Pyr&#8208;CP&#8208;800 and Pyr&#8208;CP&#8208;600). This unique morphology invokes high specific surface area and surface roughness to the materials, which synergistically facilitates the selective electroreduction of CO 2 &#8208;to&#8208;CH 3 OH. In comparison to most of the previously reported Ni electrocatalysts that mainly produced CO, Pyr&#8208;CP&#8208;800 selectively yielded CH 3 OH with Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 32.46% at &#8722;0.60 V versus RHE (reversible hydrogen electrode) in 1.0 M KOH solution, which is highest among other reported Ni&#8208;based electrocatalysts in the literature, to best of our knowledge. Additionally, insights from density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed that Ni (111) plane to be the active site toward the electrochemical. CO 2 &#8208;to&#8208;CH 3 OH formation.</description>
      <author>Sayantan Chongdar, Rupak Chatterjee, S. K. Reza, Sitaram Pal, Ranjit Thapa, Rajaram Bal, Asim Bhaumik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Protection Analysis of Hypersonic Reentry Nose Cone with Multi-Row Disk Spike Using Lateral Single/Multi Jets: A Computational Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067366</link>
      <description>Hanting Gao, Dan Zhu, Journal of Fluids Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405141836

                Abstract This research examines the efficacy of employing lateral multi jets to decrease thermal effects on the blunt body featuring a multi-row disk spike, which holds significant importance in the design of high-speed vehicles. The main novelty of the model is the combination of the spike with Multiple row disk along with the injection of the coolant jet. The study thoroughly analyzes the cooling mechanism of lateral jets and assesses the influence of coolant jet positioning on heat reduction of the nose and mechanical spike. This study employed RANS equations with SST turbulence model for the simulation of the high-speed flow around the nose cone with Multi-Row Disk Spike. A comparison is made between the effectiveness of CO2 and helium jets, both as single and multiple injectors. The results display that a single CO2 jet released near the tip of the spike is the most effective, and placing the lateral coolant injector away from the main body effectively manages aerodynamic heating. Additionally, the research compares the heat load reduction achieved by triple lateral jets and concludes that the CO2 jet is the most efficient option for thermal protection of the main body. The role of the spike in reduction of the heat load is reduced 20% when CO2 jet is released from all lateral injectors.</description>
      <author>Hanting Gao, Dan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067366</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of the quality and mechanical properties of metal layers from low-carbon steel obtained by the WAAM method with the use of additional using additional mechanical and ultrasonic processing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17212/1994-6309-2024-26.4-75-91</link>
      <description>Yu I Karlina, V Yu Konyukhov, T.M. Oparina, Metal Working and Material Science. 26(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405195843

                Introduction. Additive manufacturing is a technology that enables three-dimensional (3D) components to be printed layer by layer according to digital models. Completely different from traditional manufacturing methods such as casting, forging, and machining, additive manufacturing is a near net shape manufacturing process that can greatly enhance design freedom and reduce manufacturing runtime. The material processing challenges in Wire and Arc Additive Manufacturing (WAAM) are related to achieving performance metrics related to geometric, physical, and material properties. Tight tolerances and stringent surface integrity requirements cannot be achieved by utilizing stand-alone AM technologies. Therefore, WAAM parts typically require some post-processing to meet requirements related to surface finish, dimensional tolerances and mechanical properties. It is therefore not surprising that the integration of AM with post-processing technologies into single and multi-setup machining solutions, commonly referred to as hybrid AM, has become a very attractive proposition for industry. The purpose of the work is to evaluate the quality and mechanical properties of the resulting metal layers of mild steel by WAAM method using additional mechanical and ultrasonic processing. Research Methods. To conduct the experiments, a set of welding equipment was used &#8212; a single-phase inverter device KEMPPI Kempomat 1701, designed for welding with wire in shielding gases. A mixture of argon and carbon dioxide (80 % argon and 20 % CO2) was used as a shielding gas. SV-08G2S (0.8 C-2 Mg-Si) wire was used as the surfacing material. A plate made of steel St3 with overall dimensions 150&#215;100&#215;5 mm was used as a base for surfacing. The surface of the plate before surfacing was thoroughly cleaned from the layer of oxides, oil, rust and other contaminants. For this purpose mechanical cleaning of the surface was used with BOSCH abrasive wheel with a diameter of 125 mm diameter and a grit size of 120. Before surfacing the surface of the product was degreased with white spirit. The gas flow rate was set at 8 dm3/min. To select the optimal wire feed rate and volt-ampere characteristic, surfacing was performed at each adjustment step of wire feed rate, and voltage. Mechanical statistical tensile tests, chemical composition analysis and metallographic studies were also performed. Results and Discussion. Gas porosity is a typical defect that occurs during the WAAM process and should be eliminated because it adversely affects the mechanical properties. Initially, gas porosity leads to a reduction in the mechanical strength of the part due to damage from microcrack formation. In addition, it often causes the surfaced layer to have worse fatigue properties due to the spatial distribution of different shape and size structures. In our experiments we found that a wire feed speed range of 5&#8211;6 m/min is optimal. Increasing the flow rate of shielding gas in the range of 8&#8211;14 l/min allows reducing porosity in the surfaced metal to almost zero. The mechanical properties of the surfaced beads show that the average value of yield strength after machining is higher than that of unprocessed specimens. The data obtained from these experiments are in good agreement with those reported in the literature. The presented results can be used in real WAAM technological processes.</description>
      <author>Yu I Karlina, V Yu Konyukhov, T.M. Oparina</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17212/1994-6309-2024-26.4-75-91</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A sustainable Response Surface Methodology and Analytic Hierarchy Process - Weighted Aggregated Sum Product Assessment model to Evaluate Performance and Emissions Characteristics of Diesel engine using Clove Oil Biodiesel Blend</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067361</link>
      <description>Pawan Kumar Singotia, Vijay Kumar, Akhilesh Kumar Choudhary, Naveen Jain, Journal of energy resources technology.. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405106670

                Abstract Replacing diesel with biodiesel generally results in a decrease in exhaust emissions like carbon monoxide, hydrocarbon, particulate matter, and carbon dioxide. However, nitrogen oxide emissions show increasing trends. On the other hand, a decrease in nitrogen oxide emissions has been found using various additives with diesel and biodiesel blends. In this work the experimentations are carried out on diesel, B30 (70% v/v diesel+30% v/v biodiesel), and the B30CL1000 (70% v/v diesel+30% v/v biodiesel+1000 ppm clove oil) to evaluate the performance and emissions of diesel engine. The Response Surface Methodology based approach has been applied to evaluate the effect of different engine operating parameters on engine performance and emission while fueled with the B30CL1000 fuel blend. Further, the Analytic Hierarchy Process - Weighted Aggregated Sum Product Assessment method has been applied to identify the optimal setting of the parameters and rank the optimal engine operating range for the B30CL1000 blend. From results, elicited that the accumulation of 1000 ppm of antioxidant (clove oil) additives in the B30 blend resulted in a reduction in the brake-specific fuel consumption by up to 11.5% at higher loads. Brake thermal efficiency increased by 16.3% at low load conditions for the B30CL1000 blend. After that the B30CL1000 blend showed a 2% drop in carbon monoxide emission at higher loads and the decreased nitrogen oxide emission for the B30CL1000 blend has been also reported as 12% at low loads and 2% at higher loads which follows a similar trend as exhaust gas temperature. The 5th experimental run having CR (17), EGR (0%) and Load (12kg) has been ranked as 1.</description>
      <author>Pawan Kumar Singotia, Vijay Kumar, Akhilesh Kumar Choudhary, Naveen Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A simple procedure for freezing triaxial test specimens and determining the final moisture content after liquefaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1680/jgele.24.00019</link>
      <description>Fernando A. M. Marinho, F&#225;bio Mariz Gon&#231;alves, Rodrigo Bernardo Serafim, Mariane Borba de Lemos, G&#233;otechnique Letters. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405109499

                Accurately determining the critical state line in specimens subjected to undrained triaxial tests, particularly those prone to liquefaction, relies on precise void ratio determination. Procedures exist to determine volume variations throughout all stages of the testing process until the final failure condition is reached. However, these procedures have not demonstrated the same level of accuracy as the method used for freezing the samples and subsequently determining the water content and void ratio. The conventional procedure for freezing the specimen involves placing the entire base of the triaxial system, including the tubes and valves, in a freezer. However, this process not only causes damage to the valves, requiring frequent replacement and increasing the cost of the tests but also necessitates a dedicated freezer for this specific procedure. This paper presents a simple and safe procedure for freezing specimens without detaching the base and exposing the valves and the entire system to low temperatures. The key advantage of this procedure over conventional methods is the reduction of material and time costs without compromising the accuracy of determining the void ratio. The specimen is frozen within minutes using solid carbon dioxide (dry ice), and determining water content is easily accomplished.</description>
      <author>Fernando A. M. Marinho, F&#225;bio Mariz Gon&#231;alves, Rodrigo Bernardo Serafim, Mariane Borba de Lemos</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1680/jgele.24.00019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The MOF&#8208;Derived Ag@M&#8208;N/Al&#8208;O Catalyst for Highly Selective Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7946</link>
      <description>Yichen Liu, Zhengchuang Zhao, Yanyan Zhu, Ruifang Xiang, Xiu&#8208;Yan Dong, Mohammad K. Parvez, Mohammed S. Al&#8208;Dosari, Ying Pan, Applied Organometallic Chemistry. 39(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405220283

                ABSTRACT For ensuring the economic feasibility of the electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), which can be used to reduce the catalyst load and increase the catalytic activity of CO 2 RR by using carrier materials. Here, we report the systematic alteration of metal chloride on bipyridine groups in MOF&#8208;253(Al) using modified metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) as precursors and the introduction of Ag nanoparticles to prepare catalysts Ag@M&#8208;N/Al&#8208;O (M = Co, Ni, Zn, Cu). EDS spectra showed the uniform dispersion of Ag nanoparticles. In addition, the chemical structure of the catalyst was analyzed by XPS and PXRD, which proved the existence of M&#8208;N and Al&#8208;O bonds. The interaction with Ag nanoparticles leads to electron density reconstruction, and the stable *COOH intermediates with electron delocalization enhanced by polymetallic electron configuration modulation are conducive to CO production. The results show that Ag@Co&#8208;N/Al&#8208;O can achieve 85.6% FE for CO and has good stability within 12 h. This work provides a new idea for CO 2 RR material design using MOFs as a precursor catalyst.</description>
      <author>Yichen Liu, Zhengchuang Zhao, Yanyan Zhu, Ruifang Xiang, Xiu&#8208;Yan Dong, Mohammad K. Parvez, Mohammed S. Al&#8208;Dosari, Ying Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Industrial CO2 Emission Intensity and Its Driving Mechanism Under China&#8217;s Dual Carbon Target</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310785</link>
      <description>Jinfang Sun, Wenkai Li, Kaixiang Zhu, Mengqi Zhang, Haihao Yu, Xiaoyu Wang, Guodong Liu, Sustainability. 16(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405190935

                As global climate change becomes increasingly severe, industrial CO2 emissions have received increasing attention, but the impact factors and driving mechanisms of industrial CO2 emission intensity remain unclear. Based on panel data from 2010 to 2021 in Shandong Province, a key economic region in eastern China, the industrial CO2 emission intensity under China&#8217;s dual carbon target was analyzed using multivariate ordination methods. The results showed that (1) total CO2 emissions from industry are increasing annually, with an average growth rate of 3.74%, and electricity, coal, and coke are the primary sources of CO2 emissions. (2) Total CO2 emissions originated primarily from the heavy manufacturing, energy production, and high energy intensity industry categories, and the CO2 emission intensity of different types of energy increased by 21.24% from 2010 to 2021. (3) CO2 emission intensity is significantly positively correlated with the proportion of high energy intensive industry, energy consumption intensity, and investment intensity and significantly negatively correlated with gross industrial output. In addition, the effects of different types of energy on industrial CO2 emission intensity varied, and coal, coke, electricity, and diesel oil were significantly positively correlated with CO2 emission intensity. Therefore, to reduce the CO2 emission intensity of the industrial sector in the future and to achieve China&#8217;s dual carbon target, it is necessary to adjust and optimize the industrial and energy structure, strengthen technological progress and innovation, improve energy utilization efficiency, improve and implement relevant policies for industrial carbon reduction, and then ensure the sustainable development of the economy, society, and environment.</description>
      <author>Jinfang Sun, Wenkai Li, Kaixiang Zhu, Mengqi Zhang, Haihao Yu, Xiaoyu Wang, Guodong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physiological and Biochemical Responses of Pseudocereals with C3 and C4 Photosynthetic Metabolism in an Environment with Elevated CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13233453</link>
      <description>Bruna Evelyn Paschoal Silva, Stef&#226;nia Nunes Pires, Sheila Bigolin Teixeira, Simone Ribeiro Lucho, Natan da Silva Fagundes, Larissa Herter Centeno, Filipe Selau Carlos, Fernanda Reolon, Luis Ant&#244;nio de Avila, Sidnei Deuner, Plants. 13(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405185247

                The present work aimed to investigate the effect of increasing CO2 concentration on the growth, productivity, grain quality, and biochemical changes in quinoa and amaranth plants. An experiment was conducted in open chambers (OTCs) to evaluate the responses of these species to different levels of CO2 {a[CO2] = 400 &#177; 50 &#956;mol mol&#8722;1 CO2 for ambient CO2 concentration, e[CO2] = 700 &#177; 50 &#956;mol mol&#8722;1 CO2 for the elevated CO2 concentration}. Growth parameters and photosynthetic pigments reflected changes in gas exchange, saccharolytic enzymes, and carbohydrate metabolism when plants were grown under e[CO2]. Furthermore, both species maintained most of the parameters related to gas exchange, demonstrating that the antioxidant system was efficient in supporting the primary metabolism of plants under e[CO2] conditions. Both species were taller and had longer roots and a greater dry weight of roots and shoots when under e[CO2]. On the other hand, the panicle was shorter under the same situation, indicating that the plants invested energy, nutrients, and all mechanisms in their growth to mitigate stress in expense of yield. This led to a reduction on panicle size and, ultimately, reducing quinoa grain yield. Although e[CO2] altered the plant&#8217;s metabolic parameters for amaranth, the plants managed to maintain their development without affecting grain yield. Protein levels in grains were reduced in both species under e[CO2] in the average of two harvests. Therefore, for amaranth, the increase in CO2 mainly contributes to lowering the protein content of the grains. As for quinoa, its yield performance is also affected, in addition to its protein content. These findings provide new insights into how plants C3 (amaranth) and C4 (quinoa) respond to e[CO2], significantly increasing photosynthesis and its growth but ultimately reducing yield for quinoa and protein content in both species. This result ultimately underscore the critical need to breed plants that can adapt to e[CO2] as means to mitigate its negative effects and to ensure sustainable and nutritious crop production in future environmental conditions.</description>
      <author>Bruna Evelyn Paschoal Silva, Stef&#226;nia Nunes Pires, Sheila Bigolin Teixeira, Simone Ribeiro Lucho, Natan da Silva Fagundes, Larissa Herter Centeno, Filipe Selau Carlos, Fernanda Reolon, Luis Ant&#244;nio de Avila, Sidnei Deuner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13233453</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Analysis of Irrigation Mist and CO2 vs. Direct CO2 Blower in On-Pump Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting Anastomosis: Efficacy, Efficiency, and Fibrillation upon De-Clamping and Micro-Embolic Gas Activity Incidence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina60122035</link>
      <description>Ignazio Condello, Giuseppe Speziale, Flavio Fiore, Giuseppe Nasso, Medicina. 60(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405239100

                Background and Objectives: In coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) on pump, achieving optimal visualization is critical for surgical precision and safety. The use of blowers to clear the CABG anastomosis poses risks, including the formation of micro-embolic gas bubbles, which can be insidious and increase the risk of cerebral or myocardial complications. This retrospective study compares the effectiveness of the use of irrigation mist and CO2 versus a direct CO2 blower without irrigation in terms of visualization, postoperative fibrillation, and micro-embolic gas activity. Materials and Methods: The study involved 40 patients who underwent on-pump CABG, with 20 patients assigned to the irrigation mist and CO2 group (ClearView&#8482;) and 20 to the direct CO2 blower group. Primary outcomes included the quality of intraoperative visualization, the incidence of fibrillation at aortic de-clamping, and the presence of micro-embolic gas activity detected via transesophageal echocardiography (TEE) in the cardiac chambers. Results: Patients in the irrigation mist and CO2 group experienced superior visualization and reduced tissue desiccation. Fibrillation at the time of aortic de-clamping occurred in two patients (10%) using the irrigation mist and CO2, compared to eight patients (40%) using the direct CO2 blower. Additionally, TEE monitoring revealed lower levels of micro-embolic gas activity in the irrigation mist and CO2 group, indicating a potential reduction in gas embolization risk. Conclusions: The irrigation mist and CO2 system not only provides enhanced visualization during CABG but also significantly reduces the incidence of fibrillation during aortic de-clamping and micro-embolic gas activity. These findings suggest improved patient safety and outcomes, highlighting the irrigation mist and CO2 system as a potentially safer alternative to direct CO2 blowing in the context of myocardial revascularization.</description>
      <author>Ignazio Condello, Giuseppe Speziale, Flavio Fiore, Giuseppe Nasso</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina60122035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wet-spun Ni, N-Codoped Macroporous Carbon Fibers for Efficient CO2 Electroreduction and Zn-CO2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06665k</link>
      <description>Liu Han, Chengwei Wang, Haiping Xu, Y. Ming, Bing Li, Ming Liu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405204277

                Developing efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts for the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) is highly desirable for carbon neutrality and clean energy. Herein, a self-sacrificing template-assisted wet spinning method is developed...</description>
      <author>Liu Han, Chengwei Wang, Haiping Xu, Y. Ming, Bing Li, Ming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06665k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical and Environmental Evaluation of CO2-based Booster Refrigeration Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18273/revuin.v23n3-2024009</link>
      <description>Daniel Vergara-Teran, Gustavo Aranda-Gil, Carlos Amaris, Revista UIS Ingenier&#237;as. 23(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405107373

                The present study deals with the performance evaluation of four CO2 booster refrigeration system configurations: a conventional, a parallel compressor, an ejector-based, and an NH3/CO2 cascade configuration, under the ambient conditions of the city of Bucaramanga, Colombia. Applying detailed energy and exergy analyses, as well as an evaluation of environmental impact through Total Equivalent Warming Impact (TEWI), it was identified that the ejector-based configuration as the most energy-efficient, exhibiting a 13.2% reduction in annual power consumption compared to the conventional system. The cascade configuration demonstrated the lowest exergy destruction above 26&#176;C, highlighting its potential under higher ambient temperatures. Furthermore, the ejector-based configuration consistently achieved the highest 2nd law efficiency across the temperature range set. The environmental impact analysis showed the ejector-based configuration also had the lowest TEWI, with a 14.36% reduction. The results underscore the importance of selecting appropriate refrigeration configurations based on local climate conditions.</description>
      <author>Daniel Vergara-Teran, Gustavo Aranda-Gil, Carlos Amaris</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18273/revuin.v23n3-2024009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling x-ray computed tomography and gray-level co-occurrence matrix to assess the evolution of microstructural damage in coal treated with supercritical CO2 fluid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0246083</link>
      <description>Peng Luo, Zhenyu Zhang, Zihao Kan, Kangsheng Xue, Zhenjian Liu, Physics of Fluids. 36(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405280685

                The reliability of segmentation of x-ray computed tomography (CT) images based on user-selected thresholds is important for analyzing supercritical CO2 (ScCO2)-water-induced microstructural damage in coal. In this study, a novel approach is introduced by integrating the gray-level co-occurrence matrix (GLCM) method with CT to analyze the evolution of microstructural damage in coal treated by ScCO2-water. The factors influencing GLCM calculation are also examined. GLCM heat maps and statistics were employed to visualize and quantitatively analyze the evolution of microstructural damage. The results show that the application of image grayscale registration and noise reduction to GLCM statistics did not produce directional bias, with noise reduction having a more significant impact. The pixel pairings depicted in GLCM heat maps provide insights into the spatial distribution of pore-fracture (in the low-density quadrant) and mineral components (in the high-density quadrant) within CT images, elucidating the evolution of micro-damage in coal samples. After the ScCO2-water treatment, a conspicuous rise in pixel pair counts within the low-density quadrant can be observed, accompanied by significant dissolution of the highest-density minerals, leading to a maximal reduction in pixel values within the high-density quadrant. Moreover, GLCM statistics show that the maximum damage location after ScCO2-water treatment does not completely match the initial coal. An accurate description of the evolution of GLCM statistics in the structural damage behavior induced by CO2 injection into deep coal-rock reservoirs is crucial, suggesting that these GLCM statistics have the potential to predict structural damage and reservoir instability during the geological sequestration of CO2.</description>
      <author>Peng Luo, Zhenyu Zhang, Zihao Kan, Kangsheng Xue, Zhenjian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0246083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two&#8208;Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Photochemical Transformations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422382</link>
      <description>Huaping Wang, Huilan Yang, Yi Liu, Mingchao Wang, Zhixuan Zhang, Yongchao Zheng, Xu-Bing Li, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Xinliang Feng, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405231842

                Photochemical transformation represents an attractive pathway for the conversion of earth-abundant resources, such as H2O, CO2, O2, and N2, into valuable chemicals by utilizing sunlight as an energy source. Recently, two-dimensional conjugated metal-organic frameworks (2D c-MOFs) have emerged as the focal points in the field of photo-to-chemical conversion due to their advantages in light harvesting, electrical conductivity, mass transport, tunable electronic and porous structures, as well as abundant active sites. In this review, we highlight various physical and chemical features of 2D c-MOFs that can contribute to enhanced photo-induced exciton generation, charge transport, proton migration and redox catalysis. Then, the existing strategies to integrate suitable light absorbers and/or co-catalysts onto 2D c-MOFs for photochemical transformations (with a particular focus on H2 evolution, CO2 reduction and O2 reduction) have been discussed. Finally, the challenges and opportunities of using 2D c-MOFs in other photochemical applications (e.g., N2 fixation, organic synthesis, and environmental remediation) are assessed.</description>
      <author>Huaping Wang, Huilan Yang, Yi Liu, Mingchao Wang, Zhixuan Zhang, Yongchao Zheng, Xu-Bing Li, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Xinliang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Lighting Systems Implementation Methodology Aligned with SDGs and International Standards: A Case Study in a Mexican Technological Institute</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162410831</link>
      <description>Jorge Alberto C&#225;rdenas Maga&#241;a, Marco Antonio Celis Cris&#243;stomo, Juan Miguel Gonz&#225;lez L&#243;pez, Sergio Sandoval-Perez, Daniel A. Verde Romero, Francisco Miguel Hern&#225;ndez L&#243;pez, Efra&#237;n Villalvazo Laureano, Emmanuel Vega Negrete, Jaime Jalomo Cuevas, Ram&#243;n Ch&#225;vez-Bracamontes, Pedro S&#225;nchez, Sustainability. 16(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405259407

                This paper presents a comprehensive holistic methodology implemented for sustainable lighting systems in educational institutions. The proposed methodology is aligned with the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), particularly with SDG 7 (Affordable and Clean Energy) and SDG 13 (Climate Action), and it follows international standards. The six-step process includes viability analysis, project design simulation using DIALux 4.13 software, the installation of LED lighting systems, and the redesign of some electrical circuits, followed by an analysis of return on investment and the monitorization of CO2 and energy consumption. The proposed methodology results in significant return on investment (ROI), primarily achieved through energy savings and reduced maintenance costs. The implementation of LED tubes, combined with occupancy and natural light sensors, leads to a 66% reduction in energy consumption and a reduction of 15.63 tons (metric tons) of CO2 annually, translating into a quick payback period of approximately 2.36 years. Additionally, the system includes Long-Term Monitoring, which ensures that energy consumption and lighting levels are continuously tracked.</description>
      <author>Jorge Alberto C&#225;rdenas Maga&#241;a, Marco Antonio Celis Cris&#243;stomo, Juan Miguel Gonz&#225;lez L&#243;pez, Sergio Sandoval-Perez, Daniel A. Verde Romero, Francisco Miguel Hern&#225;ndez L&#243;pez, Efra&#237;n Villalvazo Laureano, Emmanuel Vega Negrete, Jaime Jalomo Cuevas, Ram&#243;n Ch&#225;vez-Bracamontes, Pedro S&#225;nchez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162410831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of the pregnancy and labour course in women who underwent COVID-19 during pregnancy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/jpm-2024-0302</link>
      <description>Elvira Shukenova, Meil&#279; Minkauskien&#279;, Nurzhamal Dzhardemalieva, Lyailya Koshenova, Sh. O. Ospanova, Journal of Perinatal Medicine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405128400

                Abstract Objectives This study aims to analyze the impact of COVID-19 on pregnancy and labor, focusing on its effects on maternal and child health. The research explores the relationships between coronavirus infection and clinical and laboratory parameters, as well as the risks of pregnancy complications and adverse birth outcomes. Methods The study involved 60 pregnant women diagnosed with COVID-19. A comprehensive evaluation of clinical and laboratory indicators was conducted, employing correlation, regression, logistic analyses to determine risk factors. Results There was a strong inverse correlation between carbon dioxide levels and haematocrit (&#8722;0.76), and a direct correlation between blood pH and partial pressure of oxygen (0.73). COVID-19 was associated with increased risks of preterm labor (OR=1.82), stillbirth (OR=2.11), pre-eclampsia (OR=1.46), and foetal distress. Multivariate analysis revealed a 200 g reduction in neonatal birth weight and higher risks of hospitalisation (OR=1.8), postpartum hemorrhage (OR=2.3), and preterm delivery (OR=2.5). Comorbid conditions such as cardiovascular abnormalities, diabetes, obesity, thrombophilias exacerbated the risks of complications, including pre-eclampsia, neonatal respiratory distress syndrome, venous thromboembolism. Conclusions COVID-19 infection increases the likelihood of pregnancy complications and adverse outcomes, especially in women with comorbidities. These findings highlight the need for preventive strategies and risk management protocols for pregnant women during future outbreaks, emphasizing the importance of further research in this field.</description>
      <author>Elvira Shukenova, Meil&#279; Minkauskien&#279;, Nurzhamal Dzhardemalieva, Lyailya Koshenova, Sh. O. Ospanova</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/jpm-2024-0302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two&#8208;Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Photochemical Transformations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422382</link>
      <description>Huaping Wang, Huilan Yang, Yi Liu, Mingchao Wang, Zhixuan Zhang, Yongchao Zheng, Xu-Bing Li, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Xinliang Feng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405231494

                Photochemical transformation represents an attractive pathway for the conversion of earth&#8208;abundant resources, such as H2O, CO2, O2, and N2, into valuable chemicals by utilizing sunlight as an energy source. Recently, two&#8208;dimensional conjugated metal&#8208;organic frameworks (2D c&#8208;MOFs) have emerged as the focal points in the field of photo&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion due to their advantages in light harvesting, electrical conductivity, mass transport, tunable electronic and porous structures, as well as abundant active sites. In this review, we highlight various physical and chemical features of 2D c&#8208;MOFs that can contribute to enhanced photo&#8208;induced exciton generation, charge transport, proton migration and redox catalysis. Then, the existing strategies to integrate suitable light absorbers and/or co&#8208;catalysts onto 2D c&#8208;MOFs for photochemical transformations (with a particular focus on H2 evolution, CO2 reduction and O2 reduction) have been discussed. Finally, the challenges and opportunities of using 2D c&#8208;MOFs in other photochemical applications (e.g., N2 fixation, organic synthesis, and environmental remediation) are assessed.</description>
      <author>Huaping Wang, Huilan Yang, Yi Liu, Mingchao Wang, Zhixuan Zhang, Yongchao Zheng, Xu-Bing Li, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Xinliang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ML-Enabled Solar PV Electricity Generation Projection for a Large Academic Campus to Reduce Onsite CO2 Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236188</link>
      <description>Sahar Zargarzadeh, Aditya Ramnarayan, Felipe R. de Castro, Michael Ohadi, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405186362

                Mitigating CO2 emissions is essential to reduce climate change and its adverse effects on ecosystems. Photovoltaic electricity is 30 times less carbon-intensive than coal-based electricity, making solar PV an attractive option in reducing electricity demand from fossil-fuel-based sources. This study looks into utilizing solar PV electricity production on a large university campus in an effort to reduce CO2 emissions. The study involved investigating 153 buildings on the campus, spanning nine years of data, from 2015 to 2023. The study comprised four key phases. In the first phase, PVWatts gathered data to predict PV-generated energy. This was the foundation for Phase II, where a novel tree-based ensemble learning model was developed to predict monthly PV-generated electricity. The SHAP (SHapley Additive exPlanations) technique was incorporated into the proposed framework to enhance model explainability. Phase III involved calculating historical CO2 emissions based on past energy consumption data, providing a baseline for comparison. A meta-learning algorithm was implemented in Phase IV to project future CO2 emissions post-solar PV installation. This comparison estimated a potential emissions reduction and assessed the university&#8217;s progress toward its net-zero emissions goals. The study&#8217;s findings suggest that solar PV implementation could reduce the campus&#8217;s CO2 footprint by approximately 18% for the studied cluster of buildings, supporting sustainability and cleaner energy use on the campus.</description>
      <author>Sahar Zargarzadeh, Aditya Ramnarayan, Felipe R. de Castro, Michael Ohadi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Solar-Assisted CCHP Systems: Enhancing Efficiency and Reducing Emissions Through Harris Hawks-Based Mathematical Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310694</link>
      <description>Uchechi Ukaegbu, Lagouge K. Tartibu, C.W. Lim, Sustainability. 16(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405119278

                The increasing demand for energy, driven by technological advances, population growth, and economic expansion, has intensified the focus on efficient energy management. Tri-generation systems, such as Combined Cooling, Heating, and Power (CCHP) systems, are of particular interest due to their efficiency and sustainability. Integrating renewable energy sources like solar power with traditional fossil fuels further optimizes CCHP systems. This study presents a novel method for enhancing the CCHP system efficiency by identifying the optimal design parameters and assisting decision makers in selecting the best geometric configurations. A mathematical programming model using the Harris Hawks optimizer was developed to maximize the net power and exergy efficiency while minimizing CO2 emissions in a solar-assisted CCHP system. The optimization resulted in 100 Pareto optimal solutions, offering various choices for performance improvement. This method achieved a higher net power output, satisfactory exergy efficiency, and lower CO2 emissions compared to similar studies. The study shows that the maximum net power and exergy efficiency, with reduced CO2 emissions, can be achieved with a system having a low compression ratio and low combustion chamber inlet temperature. The proposed approach surpassed the response surface method, achieving at least a 4.2% reduction in CO2 emissions and improved exergy values.</description>
      <author>Uchechi Ukaegbu, Lagouge K. Tartibu, C.W. Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methane emission reduction through hydrogen blending in a large bore 2-stroke lean-burn natural gas compressor engine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/ffuel.2024.1404367</link>
      <description>Greg Vieira, Rachel Lorenzen, Mark Patterson, Daniel H. Olsen, Frontiers in Fuels. 2(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405202905

                Impending and increasingly stringent emissions regulations regarding natural gas compressor engines drive the research behind blending hydrogen with natural gas to make these internal combustion engines and their combustion process more efficient. This investigation seeks to answer two fundamental questions: will blending hydrogen with natural gas reduce overall engine fuel consumption, and can greenhouse gas emissions be reduced by blending hydrogen with natural gas? A 4-cylinder Cooper&#8211;Bessemer GMV engine, housed at Colorado State University&#8217;s Powerhouse facility, was investigated for hydrogen&#8211;natural gas blending using multiple engine configurations. A lean-burn engine uses an active pre-combustion chamber as its ignition source, along with electronically activated high pressure fuel injection in the main combustion chamber. One configuration tested utilized high-pressure fuel injection and blending in hydrogen, up to 40% by volume, in both the main chamber and pre-combustion chamber fuel supplies. A second configuration, where the main combustion chamber fuel was solely natural gas and only the pre-combustion chamber received hydrogen-blended natural gas, was also tested. The final configuration to be tested used low pressure fuel injection with mechanically actuated valves in the main chamber with a traditional spark plug ignition source. All engine configurations saw reductions in methane emissions of up to 30% using blended natural gas and hydrogen. Carbon dioxide emissions were also shown to be reduced for the two configurations. A reduction in brake-specific fuel consumption of up to 2% was also seen for two configurations. These results support the hypothesis that blending hydrogen into natural gas can reduce engine total fuel consumption and reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
      <author>Greg Vieira, Rachel Lorenzen, Mark Patterson, Daniel H. Olsen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/ffuel.2024.1404367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Energy Efficiency of School Buildings: A Case Study of Thermal Insulation and Window Replacement Using Cost-Benefit Analysis and Energy Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236176</link>
      <description>Du&#353;an Ran&#273;elovi&#263;, Vladan Jovanovi&#263;, Marko Ignjatovi&#263;, Janusz Marchwi&#324;ski, O&#322;eksij Kopy&#322;ow, Vuk Milo&#353;evi&#263;, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405186636

                This study demonstrates the benefits of comprehensive school building (SB) energy efficiency (EE) improvements through building envelope renovations, lighting upgrades, and changes to cleaner heat sources. The parametric study in the building energy simulation software was used to check the application of various interventions on the energy consumption of existing SBs while reducing CO2 emissions with the most profitable return on investment (ROI). The energy savings from window replacements did not correspond with expectations. However, other measures such as the wall, roof insulation, and lighting modernization improved EE by up to 152 kWh/m2 and 41 kg/m2 CO2/m2 annually. The study also points to a significant trade-off between district heating (which reduces CO2 but has a slower ROI) and other heating solutions. The results suggest that climate-specific insulation thickness and glazing type needs are required, and optimal insulation strategies are shown to improve EE by 48&#8211;56% and CO2 reductions of 45&#8211;56%. Lighting replacement and biogas boiler use were both impactful. The findings support the importance of sustainable practices, which should stimulate educational awareness and environmental responsibility. This research presents actionable insights for EE and sustainable development from within educational facilities.</description>
      <author>Du&#353;an Ran&#273;elovi&#263;, Vladan Jovanovi&#263;, Marko Ignjatovi&#263;, Janusz Marchwi&#324;ski, O&#322;eksij Kopy&#322;ow, Vuk Milo&#353;evi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Analysis of Soot Dynamics in C3H8 Oxy-Combustion with CO2 and H2O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17246232</link>
      <description>Yue Xin, Bowen Liang, Yindi Zhang, Mengting Si, Jinisper Joseph Cunatt, Energies. 17(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405259639

                Oxygen-enriched combustion is increasingly recognized as a viable approach for clean energy production and carbon capture, offering substantial benefits for boosting combustion efficiency and mitigating pollutant emissions, which makes it widely adopted in various industrial applications. Liquefied petroleum gas (LPG), predominantly consisting of propane (C3H8), is commonly utilized in numerous combustion systems, yet its emissions of soot particulates have raised considerable environmental concerns. This study delves into the combustion dynamics and soot formation behavior of propane, the principal component of LPG, under oxy-fuel combustion conditions, with the inclusion of H2O and CO2, utilizing both experimental techniques and numerical simulations. The results reveal that CO2 and H2O suppress soot formation through distinct mechanisms. CO2 decreases soot nucleation and surface growth by lowering flame temperature and H atom concentration, but it minimally enhances soot oxidation. H2O significantly reduces soot formation by chemically increasing OH radical concentration, thereby enhancing soot oxidation. A detailed decoupling analysis further shows that CO2&#8217;s influence is predominantly thermal and chemical, resulting in lower OH levels and an elongated flame shape. In contrast, H2O&#8217;s substantial thermal and chemical effects decrease flame height and promote soot reduction. These insights advance the understanding of soot formation control in oxy-fuel combustion, offering strategies to optimize combustion efficiency and minimize environmental impact.</description>
      <author>Yue Xin, Bowen Liang, Yindi Zhang, Mengting Si, Jinisper Joseph Cunatt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17246232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Policy to Practice: The Influence of Institutional Quality on the Management of Migration in Africa</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47772/ijriss.2024.8110120</link>
      <description>Elangwe Cyntia Malike, Ongo Nkoa Bruno Emmanuel, Minkoua Nzie Jules Rene, International Journal of Research and Innovation in Social Science. VIII(XI)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405130582

                This study assesses the extent to which institutional quality affects international migration in Africa, using a panel data of 44 countries within the time period of 2000 to 2020. The new economics of labour migration theory and the new institutional economics theory were mobilized. Through the adoption of the principal component analysis, the institutional quality index variable was obtained by the joint combination of the six institutional quality measures including; voice and accountability, political stability, rule of law, control of corruption, government effectiveness and regulatory quality. The study employed the use of the generalized methods of moments estimation technique to investigate the relationship between institutional quality and international migration in Africa. Findings show that government effectiveness, political stability, regulatory quality and the institutional quality index have positive significant correlation with international migration in Africa; the control variables including carbon-dioxide emissions, infrastructure, unemployment, inflation, population growth, total natural resource rents, trade openness and gross fixed capital formation all record positive and negative significant correlations international migration and these results were robust to those analysed by use of the simultaneous quantile regression and the Driscoll and Kraay standard errors estimation techniques. The study therefore, recommends that the governing organs of the nations in the African Continent should endeavour to stimulate cooperation, develop concrete political policies regarding immigration and co-development through effectively ensuring the adoption of strong natured institutions that embark on sustainably adhering to equitable reduction in corruption practices, political instabilities and full government effectiveness in every sector of the nations.</description>
      <author>Elangwe Cyntia Malike, Ongo Nkoa Bruno Emmanuel, Minkoua Nzie Jules Rene</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47772/ijriss.2024.8110120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Policy Scenarios for Carbon Emissions in Road Passenger Transport in Austria up to 2050</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21926/aeer.2404026</link>
      <description>Marina Maier, Amela Ajanovi&#263;, Reinhard Haas, Advances in Environmental and Engineering Research. 05(04)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405097830

                The transport sector currently contributes to about 25% of total CO2-emissions in the EU as well as in Austria. The largest share is caused by individual passenger car transport, primarily powered by fossil fuels. It is imperative to replace conventional cars with sustainable alternative technologies and explore alternative modes of transportation, all while reducing the overall vehicle kilometres driven. To meet climate targets, the implementation of effective policies is crucial, and phasing out fossil fuel vehicles is an inevitable step. The core objective of this study is to analyze which policy strategies in road passenger transport in Austria up to 2050 lead to a significant reduction in CO2-emissions. To do so, four scenarios for energy consumption and CO2-emissions, are derived and modelled: a Business-as-Usual Scenario, a Phase-Out-Scenario of fossil fuels, a Tax-Scenario and a Green-Policy-Scenario. Of specific relevance is that our approach is considering flow and embedded CO2-emissions. The major driving factors considered encompass income, vehicle kilometres driven, vehicle power, fuel intensity, and specific CO2-emission factors. The BAU-Scenario continues current policy trends without major changes. The Phase-Out- Scenario looks at gradually stopping the use of fossil fuel vehicles. The Tax-Scenario uses higher financial measures to reduce the use of high-emission vehicles. The Green-Policy-Scenario combines various strategies to encourage public transport and active mobility and improve vehicle efficiency. The major conclusions are: (i) The total vehicle kilometres travelled and overall vehicle stock must be reduced. (ii) Focusing on BEVs is not sufficient; a modal shift towards public transport and active mobility is important. (iii) Public transport and active mobility need to be made more attractive options. These steps will help reduce emissions and create more sustainable urban environments.</description>
      <author>Marina Maier, Amela Ajanovi&#263;, Reinhard Haas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21926/aeer.2404026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Assessments of At-Sea and Inland Low- and Medium-Pressure CO2 Transport</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236171</link>
      <description>Ingeborg Treu R&#248;e, Pauline Oeuvray, Marco Mazzotti, Simon Roussanaly, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405186651

                Developing cost-efficient systems for transporting CO2 is key to accelerating the deployment of carbon capture and storage. The present work explores the impact of reducing the pressure of tank-based inland and at-sea transport on their techno-economic performance. The study uses established techno-economic models for CO2 transport, adjusted with the most up-to-date knowledge on the costs of low-pressure containment and transport. In particular, the impact of cargo tank material and design on the transport costs show that low-pressure cargo tank systems can be 50% less expensive than medium-pressure systems if materials with similar price and strength can be used. This results in reductions in transport costs as high as 30% for long distances. This is partly driven by the currently suggested size limitation on medium-pressure shipping that limits its economies of scale. If this limitation is alleviated, the cost advantage of low-pressure shipping compared to medium-pressure is more limited (10&#8211;20%) although it remains advantageous. The same scaling effects on capacity were not found for truck and barge inland transport, thus yielding 1&#8211;10% cost reductions of low-pressure transport relative to medium-pressure transport. These results imply that future systems may combine medium-pressure inland and low-pressure at-sea transport and that efficient solutions connecting the two must be investigated.</description>
      <author>Ingeborg Treu R&#248;e, Pauline Oeuvray, Marco Mazzotti, Simon Roussanaly</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing corporate transition plans using a production asset-based planning approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5245457/v1</link>
      <description>David Kampmann, Saphira Rekker, Ruan Min, Gireesh Shrimali, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405157121

                Abstract Corporate transition plans (TPs) are increasingly seen as crucial components of assessing the compatibility and credibility of corporate commitments to meet climate targets. However, robust and transparent methods to assess the credibility of disclosed TPs are lacking. Here we propose a novel open-source methodology for assessing the credibility of corporate TPs based on asset-level data to estimate CO2 emission trajectories: the production asset-based planning approach (APA). We test this approach on a sample of ten electric utilities and ten steel companies and find that only three of the companies&#8217; stated TPs are compatible with Paris-aligned benchmarks. We also find that 12% and 42% of existing carbon-intensive assets operated by electric utility and steel companies, respectively, will require reinvestment before 2030, posing significant carbon lock-in risk. Applying this method will ensure that TPs can be assessed in a robust manner and help drive CO2 emission reductions towards achieving the Paris climate target.</description>
      <author>David Kampmann, Saphira Rekker, Ruan Min, Gireesh Shrimali</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5245457/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the nexus between medical gases and ion channel function: implications for therapeutic innovation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4103/mgr.medgasres-d-24-00076</link>
      <description>Chitaranjan Mahapatra, Medical Gas Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405166232

                Medical gases such as oxygen (O2), nitric oxide (NO), carbon dioxide (CO2), and xenon (Xe) are indispensable in contemporary medical practice. These gases are widely used in various therapeutic scenarios, including critical care, anesthesia, and respiratory therapy. While their primary applications are well established, emerging research suggests that these gases can modulate the function of ion channels&#8212;integral membrane proteins that facilitate the passage of ions across cell membranes. Ion channels such as potassium (K+), sodium (Na+) and calcium (Ca2+) ion channels play a pivotal role in maintaining cellular homeostasis, regulating the membrane potential, and mediating signal transduction. The interaction between medical gases and ion channel function is an evolving area of research with significant implications for therapeutic innovation. This perspective examines the mechanisms by which medical gases influence ion channel activity and explores the potential clinical implications of these interactions. O2 is essential for cellular respiration and energy production, but its influence extends beyond these fundamental processes. O2 levels can modulate the activity of various ion channels, leading to diverse physiological and pathological outcomes. O2-sensitive K+ channels, particularly the voltagegated K+ (Kv) family, play crucial roles in regulating vascular tone and respiratory responses to hypoxia (low O2 levels).1 Under hypoxic conditions, these channels are inhibited, leading to membrane depolarization and Ca2+ influx, which results in vasoconstriction. This mechanism is especially important in pulmonary circulation, where hypoxia-induced vasoconstriction redirects blood flow to better-oxygenated regions of the lungs. Additionally, the inhibition of Kv channels by hypoxia is central to the response of the carotid body, a key mechanism in regulating respiratory drive under low O2 conditions. O2 also affects Na+ channels (Nav), particularly in the central nervous system. Hypoxia can inhibit Nav channels, reducing neuronal excitability and potentially contributing to neuroprotection during ischemic events.2 Conversely, hyperoxia (high O2 levels) has been shown to increase Nav channel activity, which can exacerbate excitotoxicity (neuronal damage caused by the excessive release of glutamate or other excitatory plasma membrane receptors) and neuronal damage under certain pathological conditions. NO is a versatile signaling molecule involved in various physiological processes, including vasodilation, neurotransmission, and immune responses. Its interactions with ion channels are central to its broad biological effects. NO modulates Ca2+ channels (Cav) through multiple mechanisms.3 Directly, NO can nitrosylate cysteine residues on Cav channels, altering their gating properties. Indirectly, NO stimulates guanylate cyclase, increasing cyclic guanosine monophosphate levels and activating protein kinase G, which phosphorylates the channels. The modulation of Cav channels by NO is crucial in regulating vascular smooth muscle tone, where NO-induced inhibition of these channels leads to vasodilation and a reduction in blood pressure. NO is known to modulate ion channels through S-nitrosylation, a process where NO attaches to specific cysteine residues on the channel protein. This modification can change the channel's structural configuration, affectingion conductance and gating properties. In large- conductance Ca2+-activated K+ (BKCa) channels, structural changes induced by gas interactions can influence the selectivity filter, altering the ability of the channel to discriminate between different ions.4 The activation of BKca channels by NO is a key mechanism in NO-mediated vasodilation. NO can activate these channels directly through S-nitrosylation (covalent attachment of a nitric oxide group to a cysteine thiol within a protein to form an S-nitrosothiol) or indirectly via the cyclic guanosine monophosphate&#8211;protein kinase G pathway. The activation of BKca channels leads to hyperpolarization of the cell membrane, which reduces Ca2+ entry and promotes the relaxation of vascular smooth muscle cells. CO2 plays a crucial role in maintaining acid&#8211;base balance and is a potent regulator of ion channel function. Changes in CO2 levels, which lead to alterations in the intracellular and extracellular pH, can significantly impact ion channel activity. Proton-sensitive ion channels, such as acid-sensingion channels and certain two-pore domain K+ (K2p) channels, are directly influenced by pH changes due to fluctuations in CO2 levels.5 Acid-sensing ion channels are activated by extracellular acidosis (low pH), contributing to the sensation of pain, particularly under ischemic conditions where CO2 levels are elevated. In contrast, K2P channels are inhibited by acidosis, leading to membrane depolarization and increased excitability in neurons and other excitable cells. CO2-induced acidosis also affects gamma-aminobutyric acid type A receptors, which are chloride ion channels critical for inhibitory neurotransmission in the central nervous system.6 Acidosis enhances the activity of gamma-aminobutyric acid type A receptors, increasing inhibitory tone in the brain. This mechanism may contribute to the sedative effects of CO2 and its role in modulating respiratory drive. Xe, a noble gas with unique anesthetic properties, is distinguished by its minimal side effects and lack of significant cardiovascular depression. Xe's anesthetic and neuroprotective effects are primarily mediated through its interactions with ion channels and neurotransmitter receptors. One of the most extensively studied interactions of Xe is with N-methyl-D-aspartate (NMDA) receptors, a subtype of glutamate receptor involved in excitatory neurotransmission and synaptic plasticity.7 Xe inhibits NMDA receptors by competing with glycine at its coagonist binding site. This inhibition is believed to underlie Xe's anesthetic and neuroprotective effects, as NMDA receptor overactivation is associated with excitotoxicity and neuronal damage in conditions such as stroke and traumatic brain injury. Xe also modulates K+ channels, particularly the TWIK- related K+ channel (TREK-1), which is a member of the two-pore-domain potassium family. TREK- 1 channels are mechanosensitive and play a role in setting the resting membrane potential and providing neuroprotection.8 Xe activates TREK-1 channels, leading to membrane hyperpolarization and reduced neuronal excitability, which may contribute to its anesthetic and neuroprotective effects. Figure 1 provides an overview of how different gases modulate ion channels across the cell membrane, influencing the membrane potential.Figure 1: A schematic diagram illustrating how various gases regulate different ion channels, influencing membrane excitability by altering the membrane potential.The N-methyl-D-aspartate, gamma-aminobutyric acid type A, and acid-sensing ion channels are represented by NMDA, GABA, and ASIC, respectively. &#916;V denotes the change in the membrane potential. X+ is the nonspecific ion flow via nonspecific ion channels by neurotransmitter activation. ASIC: Acid-sensing ion channels; cGMP: cyclic guanosine 3',5'-cyclic monophosphate; GABA: gamma-aminobutyric acid; NMDA: N-methyl-D-aspartate; PKG: protein kinase G.The interactions between medical gases and ion channels have significant clinical implications. Understanding these interactions can elucidate the mechanisms underlying the therapeutic effects of medical gases, highlight potential adverse effects, and pave the way for innovative therapeutic strategies. Ion channels play a critical role in various physiological processes, making them attractive targets for therapeutic interventions.9 Medical gases could be used to modulate these channels, offering new treatment options for various conditions. For example, NO donors are already used clinically to treat conditions such as pulmonary hypertension by promoting vasodilation through the activation of K+ channels.10 Similarly, the neuroprotective effects of Xe in conditions such as stroke and traumatic brain injury could be harnessed through its modulation of NMDA receptors and potassium channels. While medical gases offer therapeutic benefits, their interactions with ion channels can also lead to adverse effects.11 For example, prolonged hyperoxia can exacerbate excitotoxicity by increasing sodium channel activity, potentially leading to neuronal damage. Similarly, excessive NO can lead to overactivation of K+ channels, causing hypotension and other cardiovascular issues. Therefore, understanding these interactions is crucial for optimizing the safe and effective use of medical gases in clinical settings. Further research is needed to fully elucidate the mechanisms by which medical gases interact with ion channels. This includes exploring the effects of these gases on less well-studied ion channels and understanding how these interactions vary across different tissues and disease states. Advances in this area could lead to the development of new gas-based therapies or the optimization of existing therapies for a broader range of clinical applications. Moreover, the development of selective ion channel modulators that mimic the effects of medical gases could offer a targeted approach for treating various conditions without the need for gas administration. For example, small molecules that selectively modulate O2- sensitive potassium channels could be developed to treat hypoxia-related disorders without the complications associated with O2 therapy. The interaction between medical gases and ion channels represents a promising and clinically significant area of research. Gases such as O2, NO, CO2, and Xe have profound effects on ion channel function, influencing a wide range of physiological processes and therapeutic outcomes. Ion channel agonists and antagonists of Na+, K+, and Ca2+ can help manage cellular pathologies by modulating the effects of gases such as NO, CO2, and O2. For Na+ channels, agonists such as veratridine enhance channel activity, whereas antagonists such as lidocaine and tetrodotoxin inhibit depolarization to reduce cellular excitability. K+ channel agonists, including minoxidil and retigabine, promote channel opening to stabilize the membrane potential, whereas antagonists such as 4-aminopyridine block these channels to delay repolarization. Ca2+ channel agonists such as Bay K8644 increase channel activity, boosting intracellular Ca2+ levels, whereas antagonists, such as nifedipine and verapamil reduce Ca2+ influx, help to prevent calcium overload. Together, these agents offer therapeutic options for counteracting gas-induced alterations in ion channel behavior. Understanding these interactions provides valuable insights into the mechanisms of action of these gases and opens new avenues for therapeutic intervention. As research progresses, this field holds the potential to revolutionize the management of various medical conditions through innovative gas-based and ion channel- targeted therapies.</description>
      <author>Chitaranjan Mahapatra</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4103/mgr.medgasres-d-24-00076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Flow and Geomechanics Coupling in Faulted Reservoirs for CO2 Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/220000-pa</link>
      <description>Andrea C. Ferrari, Stefano Nardean, Silvia Monaco, Timur Garipov, Stefano Mantica, A. Cominelli, SPE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274510

                Summary Accurately reproducing the coupling of fluid flow in porous media and rock mechanics is crucial for the modeling of CO2 geological storage to properly evaluate and prevent the risk of inducing fault instability during injection operations. As an alternative to using monolithic flow/mechanical suites, the process can be modeled by linking individual codes, that is i, a reservoir simulator for flow and a geomechanical package to account for fluid-induced stress change, which tackle the two problems sequentially. We developed a flexible numerical framework from which different coupling logics can be selected (i.e., one-way coupling, two-way iterative coupling, and two-way explicit coupling), which are characterized by different levels of accuracy and computational costs. A multirate, two-way coupling algorithm, which allows the flow and mechanical simulators to exchange information periodically rather than at every timestep, is also available to reduce the computational cost of two-way coupled simulations. In this work, we use this coupling infrastructure to perform numerical experiments aimed at defining whether sequential iterative coupling is strictly needed or not, and which less expensive logic can be used to attain a similar solution accuracy. First, a synthetic test case is used to illustrate the onset of fault instability during CO2 injection operations for different sets of coupling parameters (type and frequency), rock properties, and fault permeability. It is thus possible to evaluate, for a reasonable range of coupling strength, which depends on fluids and rock properties, the optimal level of coupling. Results are strongly influenced by the coupling strength, and two-way iterative coupling should be selected for tightly coupled systems to accurately reproduce the fault behavior. For a loosely coupled system, instead, the one-way approach should be the preferred choice due to its lower computational cost. Later, we consider CO2 injection into a realistic formation, and we analyze the impact of the coupling frequency on the computational performance. We show that, for complex cases, there is no one-to-one correspondence between the reduction in the number of coupling iterations and the reduction in computational time for increasing coupling period.</description>
      <author>Andrea C. Ferrari, Stefano Nardean, Silvia Monaco, Timur Garipov, Stefano Mantica, A. Cominelli</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/220000-pa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Assessment of Microalgae-Based Products for Carbon Dioxide Utilization in Thailand: Biofertilizer, Fish Feed, and Biodiesel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.159019.1</link>
      <description>Adeel Rafiq, Cameron W. Morris, Abigail Schudel, Shabbir H. Gheewala, F1000Research. 13(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405196093

                Background Microalgae-based products offer a sustainable solution for food, fuel, and agricultural inputs, presenting environmental benefits and economic opportunities. A comprehensive assessment is needed to understand their potential in supporting sustainability goals, considering the complex interplay between production methods, energy sources, and environmental impacts. Methods This study evaluated the environmental impacts of three microalgae-derived products &#8211; biodiesel, fish feed, and biofertilizer &#8211; through a comprehensive life cycle assessment. Nine scenarios were explored comparing three electricity profiles (current Thai mix, 50% renewable/50% current mix hybrid, 100% renewable) across the three products. The assessment evaluated environmental impacts and potential economic benefits of transitioning to these microalgae-based alternatives. Results and discussion All products demonstrated potential for significant environmental benefits under increased renewable energy scenarios. Fish feed consistently exhibited the lowest environmental impacts across all categories examined, showing substantial improvements with increased renewable energy use. With an annual demand of 0.4 million tonnes, fish feed could generate USD 560 million in revenue and reduce CO2 emissions by 1.1 million tonnes. Fulfilling the projected biodiesel demand of 4,015 million liters per year through microalgae production could yield approximately USD 3.5 billion in revenue and reduce CO2 emissions by 30 million tonnes compared to conventional fossil-based diesel. Additionally, algal biofertilizer production could meet a 5 million tonnes annual demand, offering USD 2 billion in revenue while reducing CO2 emissions by 6 million tonnes yearly. Collectively, these products could offset 37 million tonnes of CO2, representing about 14% of Thailand&#8217;s total CO2 emissions, contributing significantly to the country&#8217;s Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) target of 20-30% greenhouse gas emissions reduction. Conclusion Transitioning to microalgae-based products could transform the aquaculture, energy, and agricultural sectors, potentially supporting the national climate change mitigation goals, if implemented.</description>
      <author>Adeel Rafiq, Cameron W. Morris, Abigail Schudel, Shabbir H. Gheewala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.159019.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Respostas fisiol&#243;gicas de &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Theobroma cacao&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; L. submetidas ao alagamento por longos per&#237;odos</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32712/2446-4775.2024.1325</link>
      <description>Bruno Eust&#225;quio Cirilo Silva, Marlinda Rufina Jolomba Silva, Deleted Journal. 18(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405284259

                The aim of this study was to evaluate the physiological responses of cocoa plants (Theobroma cacao L.) subjected to water stress under flooding in different periods. The study was conducted in a greenhouse at the Capixaba Institute for Research, Technical Assistance and Rural Extension (INCAPER), located in Linhares-Es. The cultivars used for Theobroma cacao L. were cocoa varieties CCN 51 and TSH 1188, the first being used as a scion and the second as a rootstock. The experiment was carried out with cocoa seedlings under stress in a flooded environment, arranged in buckets and submerged in water, under different time conditions. Readings were taken at 0, 1, 2, 4 and 8 days of flooding. Measurements of net CO2 assimilation, stomatal conductance, transpiration and water use efficiency were performed, all using IRGA. The treatment 2 days after flooding did not differ from the control treatment (without flooding), while in the treatment 4 DAA there was a reduction in the net CO2 assimilation content. Plants flooded for 8 days showed lenticel growth, showing an attempt to alleviate environmental conditions. There was no interference by flooding in the PI and PII photosystems; the photosynthetic apparatus remained stable.</description>
      <author>Bruno Eust&#225;quio Cirilo Silva, Marlinda Rufina Jolomba Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32712/2446-4775.2024.1325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using agent-based modelling to simulate the emission reduction potential of CCUS technologies in China under alternative policy packages</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad9c9b</link>
      <description>Changgen Dong, Zhuoluo Sun, Jingjing Jiang, Yang Yang, Environmental Research Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405222993

                Abstract Carbon capture, utilisation, and storage (CCUS) technologies are essential for achieving the 1.5 &#176;C target. Predicting the emission reduction potential of CCUS technology is particularly important for countries to pursue carbon neutrality. However, the existing literature assessing the potential lacks consideration of the structural changes in industrial product demand and the trade-offs companies face between CCUS and traditional emission reduction technologies. This study used agent-based modelling (ABM) to simulate the emission reduction potential of CCUS in China's thermal power, steel, cement, and chemical industries from 2022 to 2060 under scenarios of different carbon prices, subsidies, and technology progress rates. The possible biases of the traditional prediction model were corrected incorporating the structural changes in industrial product demand and the marginal abatement cost curves of traditional emission reduction technologies for the four major industries into the ABM model. The simulation results indicate that under each of the 10 possible scenarios, China's CCUS technologies will reach 100% penetration in the four mentioned industries by 2060, with the emission reduction potential fluctuating between 2,222 and 1,568 Mt of CO2 (corresponding to 40% and 10% share of thermal power, respectively). The difference comes in the scaled-up threshold time point and the growth trend. Sensitivity analyses show that the carbon price affects changes in the emission reduction potential of CCUS technologies the most, while the impact of subsidies, rates of technological progress and oil prices were not significant. The stepped carbon price policy can effectively regulate and promote the expansion of CCUS emission reduction potential, which is worth considering for policymakers.&amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Changgen Dong, Zhuoluo Sun, Jingjing Jiang, Yang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad9c9b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Neutrality Pathways for Industrial Parks and Reduction Potential Based on Text Analysis and Empirical Research</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310771</link>
      <description>Yuheng Sun, Zhengyuan Feng, Fangtao Liu, Yuanhang Li, Jun Ning, Hang Fu, Shoujuan Tang, Guangxin Liu, Jing Wang, Lei Shi, Sustainability. 16(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405196088

                Climate change is seriously threatening ecological environments essential for human survival. Achieving the carbon neutrality goals of industrial parks (IPs), the gathering places of industrial activity, plays a crucial role in climate change mitigation and in promoting sustainable industrial development. In this study, we use an AI-facilitated literature review and empirical research to analyze and classify the 12 pathways for carbon neutrality for IPs based on the development nature and carbon flow framework. In addition, the carbon emission reduction potentials of various pathways are quantified using a case study. The results of the literature analysis show that, in terms of IP carbon emission reductions, most research has focused on the energy infrastructure related to energy management and utilization, as well as the service infrastructure related to the carbon footprint and industrial symbiosis. Among the 148 studies, &#8220;industrial symbiosis&#8221; and &#8220;carbon footprint&#8221; appeared with frequencies of 1278 and 474, respectively. Additionally, 102 of these studies mentioned decarbonization of energy infrastructure. In total, 11 of the carbon neutrality pathways existed in the empirical research, with the exception of carbon storage, and among them, 7 pathways are applied across all 104 IPs. Case studies indicate that the pathways with greater reduction potentials were the energy infrastructure, carbon capture, and the product and waste infrastructure, with potential reductions of 250,000 tons, 200,000 tons, and 145,080 tons of CO2 emissions, respectively. This study provides valuable references for IPs to achieve their carbon neutrality goals.</description>
      <author>Yuheng Sun, Zhengyuan Feng, Fangtao Liu, Yuanhang Li, Jun Ning, Hang Fu, Shoujuan Tang, Guangxin Liu, Jing Wang, Lei Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Patient who has only one Lung Experiences Severe Hypercapnia. How the use of HFNC Has Had a Positive Impact on Patient life: A Case Report</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47363/jccsr/s1/2024(6)319</link>
      <description>Piccirillo Silvia, Journal of Clinical Case Studies Reviews &amp; Reports. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405255274

                Background The literature doesn&#8217;t contain examples of patients with one lung who were treated with High Flow Nasal Cannula (HFNC) after identifying hypoxemic and hypercapnic respiratory failure secondary to pneumonia. Discussion A 69 years-old male COPD associated, who had already a posttraumatic exeresis from an accident at work, went to the ER of our Hospital to severe dyspnea. At CT of thorax, an consolidation was found in the left basal region. Arterial blood gas analysis revealed severe hypercapnia and severe hypoxemia. The patient was admitted to the Emergency Medicine, where NIV + OLT was administered. We were contacted for a transfer. In our department, a bronchoscopy was performed, which documented the presence of dense secretions. A new antibiotic therapy was initiated and was placed on High-Flow Nasal Cannula (HFNC). The decision to use HFNC was considered for better secretion management, for CO2 wash-out effect and humidified gas mixtures. During hospitalization, the patient adapted to this system, and a progressive improvement was observed. Results and Conclusion Follow-up 30- 90 days showed a significant reduction in blood CO2 levels. The chronic use of HFNC is still under study, we believe it could be a possible solution for patients with global chronic respiratory failure and stable COPD.</description>
      <author>Piccirillo Silvia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47363/jccsr/s1/2024(6)319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: Sustainable forest management under climate change conditions &#8212; A focus on biodiversity conservation and forest restoration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/ffgc.2024.1533425</link>
      <description>Arbi J. Sarkissian, Mykola Kutia, Frontiers in Forests and Global Change. 7(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405123132

                Exposing the complex challenges with incentivizes for sustainable forest management are amongst the several highlights presented in this Research Topic. Zwerts et al. examined the feasibility of protecting Intact Forest Landscapes (IFLs) through Forest Stewardship Council (FSC) certification, drawing attention to the delicate balance between conservation and economic viability. They explored the spatial distributions of IFLs to determine the percentage of overlap forest management units (MUs) have within them, which they express as the 'conservation burden' . Their findings emphasize the need for nuanced approaches to protecting IFLs through alternative measures for generating value (e.g., payments for ecosystem services) that also consider local socio-economic contexts. This study contributes to the broader discourse on GIS and modeling techniques, particularly with respect to fragmented landscapes shown in other recent studies (Myroniuk et al., 2020). Their study also emphasizes the need for transferring knowledge of socioeconomic and ecological interactions to diverse stakeholders to facilitate broader sustainable forest management efforts globally.China, through its government-sponsored payments for ecosystem services (PES) schemes, has contributed to one of the largest expansions of planted forests in the world over the last few decades (Salzman et al., 2018;Zhai et al., 2023). This has especially played a crucial role in storing carbon, stabilizing soils, and providing watershed services (Cheng et al., 2024;Wen and Th&#233;au, 2020). In this issue, Zhang et al. provided a comprehensive analysis of the economic potential of reforestation in China as a means to achieve carbon neutrality by 2060. Their study constructs spatially disaggregated marginal abatement cost (MAC) curves to project the effects of carbon pricing on enhancing reforestation efforts across different regions in China. The key findings indicate that carbon prices of US $20 and $50 per ton of CO2 could significantly increase reforestation efforts, leading to substantial carbon dioxide removals over the next four decades. The results emphasize the importance of targeting reforestation policies to regions with the highest abatement potential to maximize cost-effectiveness. This research aligns with the themes of the special issue by addressing the integration of economic strategies with ecological restoration efforts, particularly in mitigating climate change.China's planted forests have been estimated to capture carbon by nearly threefold over the last three decades (Cheng et al., 2024). Yet the capacity of these forests to sustain carbon storage over the next several decades will largely depend on the implementation of sustainable forestry strategies (Yu et al., 2024), including harvesting of timber and replanting with diverse native species (Hua et al., 2022). on these recent developments, Fan et al. developed a framework for evaluating Forest Landscape Restoration (FLR) suitability in the Saihanba Nature Reserve, Hebei province, located within the "Three-Norths Shelter Belt." The study employs a matter-element model to assess the suitability of different areas for restoration based on factors such as land cover type, landscape structure, soil quality, and topography. The findings reveal that approximately 55.55% of the study area is suitable for restoration, predominantly comprising natural secondary forests characterized by large patch areas, close patch distances, and complex patch shapes. The study's insights are crucial for informing sustainable forest management practices that integrate ecological considerations with landscape-level restoration efforts, contributing to broader goals of biodiversity conservation and ecosystem resilience in the face of climate change.Understanding the complex dynamics of biotic and abiotic factors influencing natural landscapes is essential for effective forest restoration and conservation efforts, which are often hampered by the impacts of climate change. Khan et al. focused on the vegetation dynamics of Pinus gerardiana Wallichex. D. Don forest in South Waziristan, Pakistan, showing how aspectual variations influence species richness and abundance. They revealed critical insights into the role of microclimatic conditions in forest management, for both restoration and conservation efforts. The study underscores the importance of sustainable management practices to conserve these ecologically valuable landscapes, contributing to our understanding of the assessment, restoration, and preservation of wood and non-wood resources.Climate change has also imposed biotic challenges to sustainable management of forest resources. Aslam et al. investigated the effectiveness of various pesticides at different concentrations and temperatures for controlling Odontotermes obesus, a termite species that poses a significant threat to certain vulnerable forest ecosystems. The study evaluates the mortality rates and behavioral responses of termites when exposed to pesticides and found that chlorantraniliprole, particularly at higher temperatures, was the most effective pesticide, showing the lowest lethal time (LT50). This research aligns with the themes of the special issue by contributing to sustainable forest management practices. It emphasizes the importance of understanding species-specific responses to pesticide treatments in the context of integrated pest management (IPM), which is crucial for maintaining forest health and resilience.Finally, Jin et al. investigated how climate change could affect the potential geographic distribution of three significant subtropical tree species in China: Cunninghamia lanceolata, Pinus taiwanensis, and Quercus glauca. Using the MaxEnt model and data on various environmental variables, their study predicts shifts in the suitable habitats of these species under current and future climate scenarios (2050s and 2090s). The findings reveal that climate factors, particularly temperature and precipitation, play a more significant role than soil and topography in determining these species' distributions. Notably, C. lanceolata is expected to experience a northward expansion of its habitat, while P. taiwanensis and Q. glauca may face substantial reductions in their suitable areas, with Q. glauca at significant risk. The study emphasizes the importance of early intervention and adaptive management to mitigate these impacts. This research is highly relevant to the themes of the special issue as it underscores the importance of understanding species-specific responses to climate change for effective forest management and conservation strategies. The insights provided can inform the development of adaptive management practices and contribute to global efforts in forest restoration and biodiversity conservation under changing climatic conditions.As major drivers of biodiversity loss and degradation of ecosystem services globally (Marques et al., 2019), reconciling how to improve agriculture and forestry activities sustainably continues to be one of the hallmark challenges of our time. In this decade of ecosystem restoration, Forest Landscape Restoration (FLR) efforts must therefore consider the importance of food security (De Pinto et al., 2020), including its role in agroforestry activities broadening social, environmental, and ecological benefits (Bosshard et al., 2021). We are also reminded of the trade-offs involved in forest restoration efforts, particularly those between plantations and native forests (Hua et al., 2022), if forests are to remain resilient under a changing climate. This also points to the trade-offs between long-term benefits over short-term costs through investing in genetic diversity (e.g., species suitability, seed sourcing, and planting stocks) to achieve more resilient FLR efforts (Nef et al., 2021).With this collection, we aim to advance the understanding of sustainable forest management in the context of climate change. The articles in this Research Topic provide evidence that successful forest management requires a multifaceted approach, integrating ecological, economic, and social considerations, also echoed in recent contributions within this journal (Mantilla Contreras et al., 2023). As we continue to confront the challenges of climate change and biodiversity loss, the insights gained from these studies will be invaluable in shaping policies and practices that promote the long-term health and resilience of the world's forests.</description>
      <author>Arbi J. Sarkissian, Mykola Kutia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/ffgc.2024.1533425</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidation Temperature-Dependent Electrochemical Doping of WO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Deposited via Atomic Layer Deposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06105</link>
      <description>Alexandria R. C. Bredar, Hannah R. M. Margavio, Carrie L. Donley, Neil Spinner, Nyaan Amin, Gregory N. Parsons, Jillian L. Dempsey, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405181953

                Silicon-based photoelectrochemical devices show promise for the performance of light-driven CO2 reduction but suffer from instability under photoelectrochemical conditions relevant to CO2 reduction. Coating silicon electrodes with thin layers of metal oxides has shown promise to passivate unstable silicon surfaces, and many different metal oxides can be deposited on silicon using various techniques. In this study, we investigate the fundamental photoelectrochemical performance of WO3-coated silicon photoelectrodes, which were generated by oxidation of W-metal films deposited via atomic layer deposition on both degenerately doped (nSi+) and low-doped (pSi) silicon. Two different oxidation temperatures were investigated (400 and 600 &#176;C), and it was found that the monoclinic phase of WO3 predominates at both temperatures but that more grain boundaries are present in the 600 &#176;C film. From X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, the stoichiometry of both films was found to be 1:3 W:O, and low electron energy loss experiments indicate band gaps of 3.0 and 3.1 eV for 400 and 600 &#176;C films, respectively. Cyclic voltammetry experiments showed that the electron transfer kinetics increased after continued redox cycling, particularly for the material produced at 400 &#176;C. X-ray photoelectron spectra suggest that the observed increase in electrode conductivity is due to the formation of oxygen vacancies in the film. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy indicated that charge transport through the films was impacted by the grain boundaries that formed during oxidation of the film. Photoelectrochemical studies on pSi/WO3 electrodes were highly variable, only producing a photocurrent and photovoltage with some samples. Our best sample, formed at 400 &#176;C, produced a photovoltage of 180 mV, which is lower than what has previously been reported for WO3-coated silicon (500 mV). We hypothesize that the variability in photoelectrochemical experiments arose from a roughened WSiOx interface that is generated during film preparation. WO3 shows promise as a metal oxide coating for silicon, but our results suggest that formation of a high-quality interface between Si and WO3 is vital for best performance.</description>
      <author>Alexandria R. C. Bredar, Hannah R. M. Margavio, Carrie L. Donley, Neil Spinner, Nyaan Amin, Gregory N. Parsons, Jillian L. Dempsey</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contribution of Wind Assisted Propulsion for a Liner Vessel on a Route in the Adriatic Sea</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3233/pmst240039</link>
      <description>Ante &#268;ali&#263;, Marko Katalini&#263;, Progress in marine science and technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405196655

                Air pollution from the shipping industry is an ongoing problem that requires exploring innovative technologies for effective resolution. The integration of wind-assisted ship propulsion (WASP) technology offers a promising route towards decarbonisation of the shipping industry. The paper investigates possible fuel savings and CO2 reduction by implementing wind assisted propulsion on a case-study vessel operating on a known route in the Adriatic Sea. The long-term contribution of added wind propulsion is analysed by implementing a Velocity Prediction Program (VPP) and available meteorological data for the area of interest. VPP is modified to predict the contribution of wind propulsion to the overall propulsion necessary to achieve the vessel design speed. The case study quantifies long-term fuel savings for ship operating a liner route and harnessing favourable (predictable) north-west winds, complementing the conventional propulsion systems.</description>
      <author>Ante &#268;ali&#263;, Marko Katalini&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3233/pmst240039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Transition Planning in Achieving the Net Zero Emission 2060 Target in the Provincial Electricity Sector North Sumatra</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58451/ijebss.v3i2.199</link>
      <description>Muhamad Iqbal Sutikno, Suhanan Suhanan, Ahmad Agus Setiawan, International Journal of Engineering Business and Social Science. 3(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405277797

                This research discusses the energy transition towards the Net Zero Emissions (NZE) 2060 target in the electricity sector of North Sumatra Province. The challenges faced include dependence on fossil fuels, high greenhouse gas emissions, and limited renewable energy capacity. The study aims to model energy transition scenarios, evaluate the optimal renewable energy mix, and determine emission reduction strategies in the electricity sector using LEAP-NEMO software. This study uses a forecasting-based simulation modeling method with a mathematical approach through LEAP software and NEMO optimization framework. Three scenarios were analyzed, namely Business As Usual (BAU), Net Zero Emissions Carbon Capture Storage (NZE CCS), and Net Zero Emissions Full Renewable Energy (NZE FRE). The simulation results show that the NZE FRE scenario is able to achieve a 100% renewable energy mix by 2060, outperforming the BAU (42.1%) and NZE CCS (70.8%) scenarios. Solar, biomass, hydro, and geothermal energy are the main sources of energy, with solar energy as the largest contributor. Greenhouse gas emissions are reduced by up to 265.9 million tons of CO2 (70.5%) compared to the BAU scenario. These findings provide policy recommendations that support the implementation of renewable energy, reduction of greenhouse gas emissions, and fiscal policies that internalize environmental costs. The study also highlights the importance of investing in clean energy technologies to realize a sustainable electricity system in Indonesia.</description>
      <author>Muhamad Iqbal Sutikno, Suhanan Suhanan, Ahmad Agus Setiawan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58451/ijebss.v3i2.199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A regenerative architectural solution for decarbonizing the construction sector in Algeria: lightweight and low-carbon insulating mortar</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.38152/bjtv7n4-029</link>
      <description>Haitem Amine Daghmoum, Karima Anouche, Brazilian Journal of Technology. 7(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405129238

                The building sector is responsible for a significant portion of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, thereby exacerbating climate change. To meet the growing need to minimize carbon footprints and improve construction energy efficiency, the development of eco-friendly building materials is crucial. This research concentrates on the development and assessment of lightweight insulating low-carbon mortar. This material is regarded as a prospective solution for regenerative architecture in Algeria due to its advantageous properties. This research aims to explore the characteristics of this material within the context of regenerative architecture, assessing its potential to enhance thermal insulation and energy efficiency of buildings and reduce CO2 emissions. This approach aligns with the principles of the "Materials" petal of the Living Building Challenge (LBC) certification, promoting architecture that goes beyond sustainability to become regenerative. To this end, we proceeded to make samples, conduct testing and laboratory studies on several specimens of this material, and perform digital simulations using RETA software. This mortar, is composed of low-CO&#8322; cement and lightweight aggregates, providing notable advantages in thermal insulation, energy efficiency, and GHG emissions reduction. In this way, it is observed that the thermal performance of buildings is improved, with a potential reduction in thermal energy consumption of up to 20% and a decrease in GHG emissions of up to 40% compared to conventional mortars. These, allows us to conclude that this ecological mortar contributes in initiatives that promote energy efficiency and sustainable development, promoting a transition towards more environmentally respectful regenerative architecture in Algeria and globally.</description>
      <author>Haitem Amine Daghmoum, Karima Anouche</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.38152/bjtv7n4-029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of Direct Operating Costs for the Wright Spirit Electric Aircraft</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/aerospace11121007</link>
      <description>Katie Goodge, Paul Withey, Aerospace. 11(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405111893

                Global warming and CO2 emissions have become increasingly pressing concerns, with the aviation industry contributing significantly to these issues. In response, efforts have been made to develop environmentally sustainable aviation solutions. This paper examines the Direct Operating Costs (DOCs) of the Wright Spirit, one of the options for electric flight, compared to the conventional BAe 146 on which the Wright Spirit is based. Utilising methodologies adapted from previous studies (largely the AEA method), the analysis investigates various factors influencing DOC including battery prices, flight duration, and charging time. The results indicate a 73% increase in overall DOCs from the BAe 146 to the Wright Spirit, largely influenced by battery costs and lifespan. However, an 83% reduction in fuel/energy costs suggests the potential viability of the Wright Spirit, particularly with anticipated reductions in battery prices. For instance, a quartering of battery prices could result in a GBP 5 increase in costs for 1 h flights; compared to the BAe 146. Moreover, the analysis finds the battery lifespan and charging time to be the most important factors to control in order to increase commercial feasibility. Ticket price comparisons suggest that the Wright Spirit&#8217;s costs align closely with current market prices, with a flight from Paris to Heathrow predicted to cost the airline GBP 136.10 per passenger. Future research could explore alternative electric aircraft designs to further assess their impact on DOCs and ticket prices</description>
      <author>Katie Goodge, Paul Withey</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/aerospace11121007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic and environmental impacts of Telemedicine: insights from a Brazilian orthopedic referral center</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5567735/v2</link>
      <description>Fabio Seiji Mazzi Yamaguchi, Hector Fugihara Kroes, Gabriel Benevides Valiate Martins, Gustavo Estefan Lage, Vitor Matheus Silva, Bruno Alves Rudelli, Raphael Martus Marcon, Henrique Melo de Campos Gurgel, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405108171

                Abstract Introduction: Telemedicine has emerged as a key tool to overcome socioeconomic disparities, expand healthcare access, and reduce environmental impacts. Its adoption surged during the COVID-19 pandemic, minimizing travel-related barriers and ensuring continuity of care. In Brazil, where regional inequities in healthcare access and pollution heavily affect public health, telemedicine holds significant promise. However, further research is needed to quantify its economic and environmental benefits. Moreover, examining how socioeconomic factors influence patients' preferences for telemedicine is essential. These correlations help identify patterns that may influence telemedicine adoption and provide deeper insights into how socioeconomic factors can affect access to and benefits from remote healthcare services. Objective: To evaluate the economic and environmental impacts of telemedicine use and the correlation of socioeconomic variables with telemedicine preference in patients with hip pathologies at a tertiary referral center in S&#227;o Paulo, Brazil. Methods: A cross-sectional study (January-June 2024) analyzed telemedicine patients, collecting data on preferences, demographics, travel, and costs (transport and food). Avoided distance, time, and pollutant emissions were calculated using Google Maps and emission factors. Correlations were conducted between patients' preference for telemedicine and their socioeconomic data. Statistical analyses used Wilcoxon, chi-square, and logistic regression tests. Results: 148 patients participated, with 77.7% preferring telemedicine. The mean avoided travel distance was 168.84 km, with a mean time saving of 223.97 minutes. Patients using public transport and private cars saved, respectively, USD 12.62 and USD 28.95. Telemedicine also reduced pollutant emissions, avoiding approximately 7 tons of carbon dioxide. Telemedicine preference was positively associated with higher income (p = 0.0283). Other variables showed no statistically significant associations. Conclusion: Telemedicine led to significant time and cost savings, as well as a reduction in pollutant emissions. These findings demonstrate telemedicine&#8217;s potential to improve access and reduce environmental impacts. Preference for telemedicine was positively associated with higher income, highlighting potential barriers for lower-income populations. Further research is needed to address the lower adherence to virtual consultations among socioeconomically disadvantaged groups.</description>
      <author>Fabio Seiji Mazzi Yamaguchi, Hector Fugihara Kroes, Gabriel Benevides Valiate Martins, Gustavo Estefan Lage, Vitor Matheus Silva, Bruno Alves Rudelli, Raphael Martus Marcon, Henrique Melo de Campos Gurgel</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5567735/v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clonal differences in ecophysiological responses to imposed drought in selected &lt;i&gt;Eucalyptus grandis&lt;/i&gt; x &lt;i&gt;E. urophylla&lt;/i&gt; hybrids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/treephys/tpae160</link>
      <description>Tiago Massi Ferraz, Sebasti&#227;o Oliveira Maia J&#250;nior, Guilherme Augusto Rodrigues Souza, Danilo For&#231;a Baroni, Weverton Pereira Rodrigues, Elias Fernandes de Sousa, Ricardo Miguel Penchel, Rodolfo Ara&#250;jo Loos, F&#225;bio Afonso Mazzei Moura de Assis Figueiredo, Miroslava Rako&#269;evi&#263;, Eliemar Campostrini, Tree Physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274973

                Measuring ecophysiological responses of Eucalyptus clones grown under reduced water availability could assist in clonal selection for climate resilience. We hypothesized that clonal variation in chlorophyll a fluorescence was more readily detected than variations in leaf-level gas-exchanges when two-year-old E. grandis x E. urophylla hybrid clones (C1, C2, C3, and C4) were grown under rainfed (RF) and water-restricted (WR) conditions were evaluated during dry and rainy seasons, in the morning and midday diurnal periods. The C2 clone was the most drought tolerant as it had a similar net CO2 assimilation rate (A) considering the RF and WR conditions at midday during the dry season, while C1, C3, and C4 CO2 assimilation rates (A) decreased by 29.1 %, 28.3%, and 13%, respectively. This response was associated with a reduction to a lesser extent in leaf water potential, stomatal conductance (gs) and transpiration rates (E) (ca. 10%, 30% and 13% under WR, respectively), when compared to the other clones during the dry season at midday. The lower leaf to air vapor pressure deficit of C2 contributed to its greater water use efficiency (WUE), resulting in greater total dry mass gain. C1, C3 and C4 were less drought tolerant, decreasing gs, E and especially A under WR, resulting in lower WUE and total dry mass gain. Chlorophyll a fluorescence indexes were better indicators of drought tolerance compared to gas-exchange parameters in definition of drought tolerance of clonal Eucalyptus. Three drought sensitive clones showed low photochemical efficiency under WR, with the electron transport rate being impaired between photosystems II and I, indicated by the greater changes in photosynthetic performance index (PIabs). Under WR conditions, Fv/Fm, &#936;0, &#934;E0, and PIabs decreased in all clones while &#934;D0 and DI0/CS0 increased, with C2 showing the most stable responses suggesting that the photochemical apparatus was the less damaged by drought. Thus, C2 was the best clone for regions with water scarcity.</description>
      <author>Tiago Massi Ferraz, Sebasti&#227;o Oliveira Maia J&#250;nior, Guilherme Augusto Rodrigues Souza, Danilo For&#231;a Baroni, Weverton Pereira Rodrigues, Elias Fernandes de Sousa, Ricardo Miguel Penchel, Rodolfo Ara&#250;jo Loos, F&#225;bio Afonso Mazzei Moura de Assis Figueiredo, Miroslava Rako&#269;evi&#263;, Eliemar Campostrini</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/treephys/tpae160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Use of Fly Ash and Marble Coarse Aggregates as Eco-Friendly Replacements in Concrete Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2478/jaes-2024-0031</link>
      <description>Saloua Filali, Abdelkader Nasser, Journal of Applied Engineering Sciences. 14(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405231118

                Abstract This study investigates the feasibility of utilizing fly ash and marble coarse aggregates as sustainable substitutes in concrete production, responding to the increasing demand for infrastructure and the necessity to diminish the carbon footprint of construction materials. By partially substituting cement, a material that generates substantial greenhouse gas emissions, fly ash, a by-product of coal combustion, recognizes its capacity to reduce CO2 emissions. The stone processing industry produces marble waste, which, by repurposing otherwise wasted byproducts, offers an environmentally sustainable solution, simultaneously reducing the use of natural resources in the manufacture of traditional aggregates. The research aims to assess the effects of incorporating various ratios of fly ash, ranging from 10% to 50%, and marble coarse aggregates, ranging from 10% to 90%, on the workability, compressive strength, split tensile strength, and flexural strength. The results show a moderate decrease in a slump, with an 18.66% reduction at 50% marble coarse aggregates and 30% fly ash, and a significant increase in compressive strength, with a 60.22% improvement at 56 days with 40% fly ash and 70% marble coarse aggregates. Split tensile strength also improved by 35.50% to 36.66%. Non-destructive tests confirmed the structural integrity of the concrete. This study emphasizes the potential of fly ash and marble coarse aggregates as eco-friendly substitutes in concrete production.</description>
      <author>Saloua Filali, Abdelkader Nasser</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2478/jaes-2024-0031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Cogeneration to Support a Net-Zero, High-Renewable Electricity Grid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17246219</link>
      <description>Juan Matthews, William Bodel, Gregg Butler, Energies. 17(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405242412

                UK Government projections anticipate increasing electricity use, provided by variable renewables (i.e., wind and solar PV). A side effect of increasing the proportion of variable renewable generation is increased support costs, including curtailment, energy storage, and (most significantly) the cost of supplying electricity for periods of high demand when variable renewable generation is low. As the proportion of variable renewable capacity increases, demand for supporting capacity increases but the capacity factor of the support generation decreases, raising the support costs. Using nuclear power for dedicated baseload supply makes the situation worse. This paper explores in the UK context an original low-cost solution using nuclear cogeneration with hydrogen production as the main application. Electricity is diverted at low cost to the grid at times of high demand when renewables are not available. This ensures nuclear maintains a high capacity factor. When higher temperature advanced systems become available, using thermal energy storage will increase the nuclear electrical capacity. This &#8220;Flexible Nuclear&#8221; scenario substantially reduces support costs for accommodating variable renewables, saving GBP 14 bn/yr and leading to an 80% reduction in CO2 equivalent emissions, compared to a recent UK Government scenario utilising a large capacity of hydrogen and unabated gas generation at very low capacity factors.</description>
      <author>Juan Matthews, William Bodel, Gregg Butler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17246219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial Upgrading of Lignin Depolymerization: Enhancing Efficiency with Lignin&#8208;First Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400954</link>
      <description>Aditya Ponukumati, Rhiannon Carr, Zahra Ebrahimpourboura, Yifeng Hu, N. ANAND, Yu Gao, Zeyu Shang, Anirudh Krishnamurthy, Mark Mba Wright, Tae Seok Moon, Marcus Foston, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405197262

                Chemical depolymerization of lignin is a non&#8208;selective process that often generates a wide distribution of product compounds, denoted herein as lignin breakdown products (LBPs). To address this limitation, we developed a hybrid lignin conversion approach that employs a lignin&#8208;first catalytic approach on biomass and subsequent microbial upgrading. A Pd/C catalyst was used for reductive catalytic fractionation (RCF) of poplar biomass, and Rhodococcus opacus PD630 (R. opacus PD630) was then cultivated on the resulting LBPs. This RCF approach increases the total biomass utilization by R. opacus PD630 over base&#8208;catalyzed depolymerization (BCD) reactions that were performed in the absence of Pd/C and molecular hydrogen (H2). LBPs generated using RCF resulted in higher cell growth per gram of biomass. Cellulose in the residual biomass after RCF treatment also showed enhanced enzymatic digestibility due to saccharification yields over 40%. Techno&#8208;economic analysis (TEA) and life cycle analysis (LCA) of this hybrid lignin conversion scheme, integrated into a cellulosic bioethanol plant, decreased the minimum ethanol selling price from $4.07/gallon (base case) to $3.94/gallon. Global warming potentials ranged from 29 and 30.5 CO2,eq/MJ. These results highlight the potential for an industrial hybrid conversion&#8208;based biorefinery scheme that utilizes lignin&#8208;first catalytic deconstruction and R. opacus PD630 upgrading.</description>
      <author>Aditya Ponukumati, Rhiannon Carr, Zahra Ebrahimpourboura, Yifeng Hu, N. ANAND, Yu Gao, Zeyu Shang, Anirudh Krishnamurthy, Mark Mba Wright, Tae Seok Moon, Marcus Foston</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400954</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Implementation of Carbon Emission Disclosures and Subsidiaries in Indonesia in Comparison to Brazil and Congo: An Overview Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31219/osf.io/2p8vu</link>
      <description>Evi Aryati Arbay, D. Agung Krisprimandoyo, Rudi Sukandar, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405179675

                Objectives: The quantity of CO2 emissions that combustion energy sources in power plants, cars, industry, business sectors, households, and other sectors emit into the atmosphere would influence global warming. Therefore, reducing global warming may be achieved by energy efficiency technology and low-carbon energy sources. By examining how MRV, a ground-breaking REDD+ technology from Indonesia, Brazil, and Congo Governance, transformed forested landscapes into carbon domain that could be observed and controlled via the use of data-intensive mapping and techniques model. Theoretical Framework: To reduce deforestation, REDD+ was initially designed to be a scheme in which rich countries would compensate poor countries with trees (maybe through carbon markets). However, there have been questions over whether REDD+ will lead to significant reductions in emissions. Carbon reductions in the forest sector are becoming increasingly important for reducing emissions and meeting the NDC. Method: This study looks at literature reviews as a research method in addition to giving an overview of the many types of reviews and some standards for conducting and assessing literature review articles regarding carbon emission declarations and subsidiaries in Congo, Brazil, and Indonesia might be used. Result and Discussion: This study should be identified and analysed as follows: (i) Districts and regionals should be given incentives to produce or harvest more timber instead of disincentives from Nation Governance; (ii) State Forest mining fees should be increased to fully defray the costs of reclamation and rehabilitation of areas mined; (iii) Tightening technical requirements for underground mining in protection forests would limit the number of mining permits that local governments could be granted. Research Implications: This study achieved sustainable and equitable growth for everybody, there will need to be greater global collaboration on trade and climate change about carbon emission disclosures and subsidiaries. Originality/Value: This study identified and analysed carbon emission disclosures and subsidiaries in Indonesia, Brazil, and Congo also how to imply the regulations among those country.</description>
      <author>Evi Aryati Arbay, D. Agung Krisprimandoyo, Rudi Sukandar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31219/osf.io/2p8vu</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decarbonization of oil rig platforms: An integrated approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30574/wjarr.2022.14.3.0655</link>
      <description>Kelvin Edem Bassey, World Journal of Advanced Research and Reviews. 14(3)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4405263930

                The decarbonization of oil rig platforms is increasingly critical as the global energy sector transitions toward more sustainable practices. This paper presents an integrated approach to reducing carbon emissions from offshore oil rigs, focusing on the synergy of renewable energy integration, carbon capture and storage (CCS), operational efficiency, and supportive policy frameworks. Offshore oil platforms are significant contributors to greenhouse gas emissions, and their decarbonization is essential for aligning the oil and gas industry with global climate goals. This paper explores the potential of renewable energy sources, such as offshore wind and solar power, to replace fossil fuel-based energy generation on oil rigs. The integration of hybrid energy systems that combine wind, solar, and energy storage solutions offers a promising path toward continuous and reliable power supply while reducing emissions. Additionally, the implementation of CCS technologies on oil platforms is reviewed, highlighting their role in capturing and storing CO2 emissions, thereby mitigating their environmental impact. Operational efficiency and process optimization are also examined as critical components of decarbonization efforts. By improving energy efficiency, reducing flaring, and enhancing digitalization and automation, oil rigs can significantly lower their carbon footprint. Waste heat recovery is identified as another opportunity to convert excess heat from operations into useful energy, further contributing to emission reductions. The paper also emphasizes the importance of policy and regulatory support in driving decarbonization initiatives. Effective regulatory frameworks, economic incentives, and international cooperation are crucial for overcoming the technical, economic, and social challenges associated with decarbonizing oil rig platforms. In conclusion, the decarbonization of oil rig platforms requires a comprehensive and integrated approach that leverages technological innovation, operational improvements, and robust policy support. By addressing the challenges and opportunities outlined in this paper, the oil and gas industry can play a vital role in the global effort to reduce carbon emissions and combat climate change.</description>
      <author>Kelvin Edem Bassey</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30574/wjarr.2022.14.3.0655</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Torrefaction Temperature Effects on Grindability of Wheat Straw Using TG-FTIR Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067363</link>
      <description>Xinming Wang, Zhiwei Wang, Gaofeng Chen, Zaifeng Li, Shuhua Yang, Xinze Du, Ashwani K. Gupta, Journal of energy resources technology.. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405106833

                Abstract Torrefaction used for pretreatment of biomass can enhance grindability along with significant reduction of energy consumption required for pulverization to aid in large-scale utilization of biomass energy. In this study, torrefaction experiments of wheat straw were conducted at different temperatures using an experimental furnace facility. The influence of torrefaction temperature on the grindability of resulting wheat straw was explored using a Hardgrove grindability index tester and thermogravimetric-Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (TG-FTIR). Increase in torrefaction temperature significantly enhanced the carbon content of wheat straw and decreased oxygen content to result in decreased O/C ratio from 0.66 to 0.39. The calorific value increased by 24% from 15.42 MJ/kg to 19.17 MJ/kg. Increase in torrefaction temperature from 220 &#176;C to 269 &#176;C increased the grindability index from 29 to 115. The grindability of wheat straw can be controlled to values similar to that of coal by tuning the torrefaction temperature. The main gas components released during torrefaction were H2O, CH4, CO2, and CO. Thermogravimetric data showed 29% solid residue from the raw wheat straw. Increase in torrefaction temperature increased the solid residue to 41%. Pyrolysis of wheat straw at different torrefaction temperatures can be grouped into three stages of dehydration, rapid pyrolysis, and carbonization. This study reveals effective large-scale utilization of torrefied wheat straw biomass having high heating value of the solid fuel after torrefaction pretreatment.</description>
      <author>Xinming Wang, Zhiwei Wang, Gaofeng Chen, Zaifeng Li, Shuhua Yang, Xinze Du, Ashwani K. Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genomic and proteomic characterization of sulfate-reducing symbionts of gutless marine annelids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.12.09.627487</link>
      <description>Grace D&#8217;Angelo, Manuel Kleiner, Anna Mankowski, Jeronimo Cifuentes-Anticevic, Eileen Kroeber, Marlene Violette, Valerie De Anda, Nicole Dubilier, Manuel Liebeke, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405175475

                Sulfate-reducing bacteria inhabit marine and terrestrial environments, forming syntrophic associations with other bacteria, archaea and eukaryotes. A notable example is the symbiosis between sulfate-reducing bacteria (SRB) and gutless oligochaete worms found in marine sediments worldwide. These endosymbionts participate in a syntrophic sulfur exchange with the primary endosymbiont of gutless oligochaetes, a sulfur-oxidizing bacterium, thus providing otherwise inaccessible metabolic capabilities to the animal host. Here, we used a combination of metagenomic and metaproteomic analysis to describe the metabolic functions of SRBs from gutless annelids. Identified as members of the Desulfobacteria class, closely related to the Desulfococcus and Desulfosarcina genera, these SRB symbionts exhibit a range of common and unique metabolic capabilities. Our analyses revealed their core metabolism of complete oxidation of acetate to CO2 via the Wood-Ljungdahl pathway, glyoxylate bypass of the TCA cycle, degradation of glycine as a nitrogen source, and presence of transporters for essential nutrients. A large-scale genome comparison revealed that the sulfate-reducing endosymbionts, named here "Candidatus Desulfoconcordia", have metabolic distinctions with respect to their free-living counterparts that could indicate adaptation to the energy and nutrient requirements of their symbiotic niche. The enrichment of functions like peptidases and amino acid transporters together with their abundant expression in the proteomes and the reduction of sugar and sulfur scavenging functions in the symbiotic genomes indicate a symbiosis-driven ecological role distinct from free-living SRBs. Our study revealed the metabolic capabilities that have enabled "Candidatus Desulfoconcordia" to adapt to their multi-domain associations.</description>
      <author>Grace D&#8217;Angelo, Manuel Kleiner, Anna Mankowski, Jeronimo Cifuentes-Anticevic, Eileen Kroeber, Marlene Violette, Valerie De Anda, Nicole Dubilier, Manuel Liebeke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.12.09.627487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving cold resistance and shelf life of Carica papaya Linn through 1- methylcyclopropene and geranium oil applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26656/fr.2017.8(s7).9</link>
      <description>Meng Yi Loh, Noranizan Mohd Adzahan, Ezzat Mohamad Azman, Soo Peng Koh, Noor Liyana Yusof, Food Research. 8(Supplementary 7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405200773

                The perishability and susceptibility to chilling of Carica papaya Linn have impeded its long-distance exportation, posing challenges to international trade investments. This study explores the efficacy of 1-MCP and geranium oil (GO) treatments in enhancing papaya's cold tolerance. Designated concentrations for 1-MCP were 300 and 600 mg/L, and for GO, 2% and 4% (v/v), with exposure times set at 30 and 60 mins. Subsequently, the fruits were stored at 4&#176;C for 16 days, and various parameters such as chilling injury (CI), weight loss (WL), respiratory rate (RR), firmness, colour, total soluble solids (TSS), titratable acidity (TA), pH, and ripening index (RI) were assessed at 4-day intervals. The results demonstrated a significant reduction in chilling damage in treated fruits. Specifically, the 60-minute exposure to 600 mg/L 1-MCP (MCP600+60) delayed the development of CI symptoms by at least 4 days compared to the control. At day 16, MCP600+60 exhibited the least WL (1.93%), O2 consumption (4.19&#177;0.25 mL/kg/hr), and CO2 production (4.05&#177;0.17 mL/kg/hr). Treated fruits, especially MCP600+60 and 30-minute exposure to 4% (v/v) GO (GO4+30), preserved firmness and colour. In GO treatments, GO4+30 showed the least increase in TSS (1.69-fold) and pH (1.09-fold). The highest TA and RI were reported in MCP600+60 and GO4+30. Overall, MCP600+60 emerged as the most effective treatment for enhancing papaya's cold tolerance and storage quality based on our study.</description>
      <author>Meng Yi Loh, Noranizan Mohd Adzahan, Ezzat Mohamad Azman, Soo Peng Koh, Noor Liyana Yusof</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26656/fr.2017.8(s7).9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of fiber direction on the tribological behavior of carbon-reinforced PEEK at elevated temperature for application in gas turbine engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067410</link>
      <description>Marie-Laurence Cliche, Robert Mone, Andre C. Liberati, Pantcho Stoyanov, Journal of Tribology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405306656

                Abstract The aerospace industry aims for net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050, requiring gas turbine engines to reduce CO2 emissions. This will impact engine material selection due to harsher operating conditions, limiting traditional metal/alloy use. While fibre-reinforced polymers (FRP) composites are commonly used in the aerospace industry, their use in gas turbine engines is often restricted by the lower operating temperatures of the polymer matrix. However, many studies have demonstrated the tribological potential of FRP in the fan section of the engines, but little attention has been given to the potential of orienting the fibers in the normal (i.e., out-of-plane) direction relative to the wear surface to leverage the anisotropic properties of FRP composites. This study aims to investigate the impact of fiber orientation on the tribological properties of carbon fiber/PEEK (CF-PEEK) at elevated temperatures. Three CF-PEEK samples with different fiber rientations were selected for the purpose of this study (parallel, anti-parallel and normal directions), as well as a fourth sample of pure PEEK. Tribological tests were conducted using a ball-on-disk tribometer at an elevated temperature of 200&#176;C to evaluate wear and friction behavior. The worn surfaces and counterfaces were analyzed using confocal laser scanning microscopy (CLSM), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and energy dispersive X-ray Spectroscopy (EDS). The findings reveal that CF-PEEK with fibers oriented in the normal direction demonstrates significantly enhanced tribological performance at elevated temperatures, achieving a 95% reduction in the friction coefficient and a 92% decrease in the wear rate compared to pure PEEK. A wear mechanism has been proposed to explain the superior wear resistance of normally oriented fibers in CF-PEEK, linking it to the development of a fiber-based interface during the run-in phase and the formation of a uniform transfer film.</description>
      <author>Marie-Laurence Cliche, Robert Mone, Andre C. Liberati, Pantcho Stoyanov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4067410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic ventilation and cooling of the building using the combination of wind deflector and solar chimney (state 3D with differential perspective)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58396/gbm020104</link>
      <description>Ahmadi Hamidreza Babaeyan, S&#225;nchez-Torija Jorge Gallego, Green Buildings and Materials. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405157037

                Using new sources of energy and inventing new methods for energy consumption has always been the focus of researchers. The building sector is known to contribute largely in total energy consumption and CO2. Expanding the availability of energy storage technology and materials is considered as crucial as discovering new energy sources. The International Energy Outlook by the EIA (Energy Information Administration of the outlook) examines and predicts future trends in building energy usage. It anticipates a 34% growth in energy consumption within the built environment over the next two decades, with an average annual increase of 1.5%. By 2030, it is projected that approximately 67% of this consumption will be attributed to dwellings, while the non-domestic sectors will account for about 33%. This study endeavors to combine one of these ventilation techniques from ancient Persian architecture, known as the windcatcher in the form of an innovative roof radiative cooling (Windcatcher) with a solar chimney. In order to save energy consumption and reduce environmental problems by presenting the idea of using solar energy to exhaust the air inside the building through the chimney and using the latent heat of water evaporation to create cooling that is carried out in the direction of the wind by the windcatcher. Hence, fuel consumption can be created in hot and dry areas, in a comfortable environment with suitable humidity conditions. The purpose of this research is to introduce computational areas (3D) and determine the governing values and methods calculated by Ansys Fluent software, which has enabled the use of suction and the creation of moisture balance and heat reduction without fuel consumption, which plays an important role in It implements energy efficiency in the building. This system is also able to save 60% cooling energy and 80% of the ventilation energy during peak hours in a warm and arid climate. Furthermore, the effects of a wall opening on ventilation and thermal efficiency were examined.</description>
      <author>Ahmadi Hamidreza Babaeyan, S&#225;nchez-Torija Jorge Gallego</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58396/gbm020104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Agricultural Residues from Hot and Cold Climates as Sustainable SCMs for Low-Carbon Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310715</link>
      <description>Mohammed M. Ahmed, A. Sadoon, M. T. Bassuoni, A. Ghazy, Sustainability. 16(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405113782

                Supplementary cementitious materials (SCMs), such as fly ash, slag, and silica fume, predominantly derived from industrial waste, are widely utilized in concrete due to their proven ability to enhance both its mechanical and durability properties. Moreover, these SCMs play a crucial role in mitigating the carbon footprint of concrete by reducing its cement content, which is responsible for approximately 8% of global CO2 emissions. However, the sustainability and long-term availability of conventional SCMs are increasingly under scrutiny, particularly in light of the impending shutdown of coal-fired power plants, which threatens the future supply of fly ash. As a result, the concrete industry faces an urgent need to identify alternative SCMs to maintain and advance eco-friendly practices. This article stands out from previous reviews by employing a bibliometric analysis to comprehensively explore the use of commonly utilized agricultural ashes (rice husk, palm oil, and sugarcane bagasse), prevalent in tropical and subtropical regions as SCMs. Additionally, it provides valuable insights into the potential of cold-weather crops (e.g., barley, canola, and oat) that demonstrate promising pozzolanic reactivity. The study critically evaluates and compares the physical and chemical characteristics of agricultural ashes from both hot and cold climates, assessing their influence on the fresh, mechanical, and durability properties of concrete. It also addresses the challenges and limitations associated with their use. Furthermore, in line with the United Nations and Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) sustainability goals, the review evaluates the environmental benefits of using agricultural ashes, emphasizing waste reduction, resource conservation, and energy savings. This comprehensive review paper should deepen the understanding of agricultural ashes as sustainable SCMs, providing a strategic direction for the construction industry to adopt low-carbon concrete solutions across various climates while promoting advancements in production methods, performance standards, and emerging technologies such as hybrid materials and 3D printing.</description>
      <author>Mohammed M. Ahmed, A. Sadoon, M. T. Bassuoni, A. Ghazy</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su162310715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growth vs. green: unpacking the economic&#8211;environmental dilemma in major carbon emitters with panel ARDL analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44274-024-00173-8</link>
      <description>Shikha Daga, Kiran Yadav, Vijay Lakshmi, Pardeep Singh, Discover Environment. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405187599

                Today's world is facing a criticalglobal challenge of rising temperatures and disrupted ecosystems, primarily driven by increased carbon emissions. The study aims to determine the major factors leading to carbon emissions in five major carbon-emitting countries: China, the United States, India, Russia, and Japan. Specifically, it explores the interplay between economic growth, natural resource rent (Natural Resource Rent: The economic benefit a country gains from its natural resources, such as oil or minerals, after subtracting the cost of extracting and using them), technological change, renewable energy use, and carbon emissions. The study postulates that economic growth and natural resource extraction bear a substantial interaction that contributes to carbon emissions. At the same time, technological change and the usage of renewable energy could probably become imperative to alleviate such emissions. This research, therefore, provides a good insight into the determinants of CO2 emissions in these key economies and the probable pathways toward emission reduction through innovation and harnessing of renewable sources of energy. Utilizing the comprehensive dataset between 1990 and 2021 and employing the ARDL [Panel ARDL (Autoregressive Distributed Lag): A statistical method used to analyze how different factors affect each other over time in a dataset that includes multiple subjects (e.g., countries)] model on the panel data, this study examines both the short- and long-term effects of these variables on carbon emissions, considering cross-country heterogeneity. The results underscore the significance related to guidelines for sustainable development practices and the necessity for these leading economies to lead the shift towards sustainability. By identifying factors that can mitigate emissions and enhance resilience, this research provides useful inputs to the policymakers who intend to promote renewable sources of energy usage along with technological upgrades. This study's results contribute to the existing literature by making it a significant resource for future policy formulation and academic research in the field of mitigating climate change.</description>
      <author>Shikha Daga, Kiran Yadav, Vijay Lakshmi, Pardeep Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44274-024-00173-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfate-Reducing Bacteria Isolated from an Oil Field in Kazakhstan and a Description of Pseudodesulfovibrio karagichevae sp. nov.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/microorganisms12122552</link>
      <description>Salimat K. Bidzhieva, T. P. Tourova, Denis S. Grouzdev, Salima R. Samigullina, Diyana S. Sokolova, &#1040;. &#1041;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1083;&#1090;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1091;&#1089;, Alexander N. Avtukh, &#1042;. &#1052;. &#1058;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1096;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, Andrey V. Mardanov, Nurlan S. Zhaparov, Tamara N. Nazina, Microorganisms. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405284255

                Sulfidogenic bacteria cause numerous issues in the oil industry since they produce sulfide, corroding steel equipment, reducing oil quality, and worsening the environmental conditions in oil fields. The purpose of this work was to isolate and taxonomically identify the sulfidogenic bacteria responsible for the corrosion of steel equipment at the Karazhanbas oil field (Kazakhstan). In this study, we characterized five sulfidogenic strains of the genera Pseudodesulfovibrio, Oleidesulfovibrio, and Acetobacterium isolated from the formation water of the Karazhanbas oil field (Kazakhstan). Sulfate-reducing strain 9FUST revealed 98.9% similarity of the 16S rRNA gene sequence with the closely related strain &#8216;Pseudodesulfovibrio methanolicus&#8217; 5S69T and was studied in detail to enhance the taxonomic resolution. Strain 9FUST grew optimally at 23&#8211;28 &#176;C, pH 6.5, and 0&#8211;2% (w/v) NaCl. The strain used lactate, pyruvate, methanol, ethanol, fructose, ribose, and H2/CO2 (in the presence of acetate) as carbon and energy sources for sulfate reduction. Iso-C17:1 &#969;11, C15:0, iso-C15:0, and C16:0 were the predominant fatty acids. The genome is 4.20 Mbp with a G + C content of 64.0%. The average nucleotide identity and digital DNA&#8211;DNA hybridization values with Pseudodesulfovibrio spp. genomes were 72.5&#8211;91.6% (&lt;95%) and 18.5&#8211;45.0% (&lt;70%), respectively, and supported our conclusion that 9FUST (=VKM B-3654T = KCTC 25498T) belonged to a novel Pseudodesulfovibrio species, for which the name Pseudodesulfovibrio karagichevae sp. nov. is proposed. Pangenome analysis of sixteen Pseudodesulfovibrio species and functional annotation analysis of identified genes revealed complete modules of enzymes of the main metabolic pathways, characteristic of bacteria of this genus, and unique genes highlighting the adaptations of strain 9FUST in carbohydrate metabolism, nutrient uptake, and environmental stress response. Isolation of these strains expands our understanding of the diversity of sulfidogens in oil reservoirs and can be used to test the effectiveness of biocides used in an oil field.</description>
      <author>Salimat K. Bidzhieva, T. P. Tourova, Denis S. Grouzdev, Salima R. Samigullina, Diyana S. Sokolova, &#1040;. &#1041;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1083;&#1090;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1091;&#1089;, Alexander N. Avtukh, &#1042;. &#1052;. &#1058;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1096;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, Andrey V. Mardanov, Nurlan S. Zhaparov, Tamara N. Nazina</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/microorganisms12122552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diaphragm ultrasonography: A picture is worth a thousand words</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1113/ep092452</link>
      <description>Ken D. O&#8217;Halloran, Experimental Physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405120786

                The diaphragm is the primary muscle of inspiration. Diaphragm dysfunction is surprisingly common, presenting in acute critical care, cardiorespiratory diseases, cancer cachexia, endocrine disorders, and neuromuscular and neurodegenerative diseases amongst other scenarios (Laghi et al., 2021). Assessment of diaphragm performance involves measurement of transdiaphragmatic pressure, which assesses the force-generating capacity of the diaphragm in situ, typically by eliciting a twitch contraction of the diaphragm by electrical or magnetic activation of the phrenic nerves. A limitation of the approach, however, is that it does not reveal explicit detail of the shortening capacity of the muscle during contraction, which is an important aspect of diaphragm performance. The dome-shaped diaphragm muscle flattens during contraction increasing intra-thoracic volume, thereby decreasing intra-thoracic pressure, facilitating airflow into the lungs during inspiration. Work (force &#215; distance) and power (force &#215; velocity) are key measures of muscle performance, and therefore tools to complement the assessment of diaphragm force are warranted and could have additional experimental and clinical value. In this issue of Experimental Physiology, Illidi and Romer (2024) combine ultrasonography and respiratory manometry to quantify the change in contractile performance of the diaphragm during fatigue in healthy humans. Recreationally active, young male participants were recruited and enrolled in randomised fashion to two commonly employed experimental protocols designed to elicit diaphragm fatigue: (1) a low-force, high-velocity task of maximal isocapnic ventilation, and (2) a high-force, low-velocity task of maximal inspiratory resistive loading. Transdiaphragmatic pressure (gastric pressure minus oesophageal pressure) and ultrasound-derived data (diaphragm excursion) in response to phrenic nerve stimulation by magnetic stimulation and during a CO2-rebreathe test were performed before and after each fatiguing task. Two post-trial time points were assessed to measure fatigue at 10 and 30 min following each loading task. Measurement of diaphragm excursion parameters allowed for the calculation of mean excursion velocity. Diaphragm work and power were subsequently calculated incorporating pressure and ultrasound-derived measurements. Muscle fatigue is the reversible decline in force or power due to contractile activity. Based upon the measurement of transdiaphragmatic pressure, both loading tasks used in the study elicited diaphragm fatigue with similar reductions in transdiaphragmatic twitch pressure for maximal isocapnic ventilation and inspiratory resistive loading tasks. These reductions were notably less than those reported by others for the same tasks (Luo et al., 2001), and reductions were not seen in all participants, which the authors surmise may relate to participant demographics and in particular training status, as several participants in the study by Illidi and Romer (2024) were competitive athletes. Ultrasonography proved feasible for the assessment of fatigue-induced changes in diaphragm contraction in healthy participants. Inspiratory resistive loading resulted in significant decreases in ultrasound-derived measures of crural diaphragm absolute shortening and shortening velocity. The dominant change in diaphragm excursion measures, especially velocity of shortening, combined with the secondary changes in transdiaphragmatic pressure resulted in significant decreases in calculated diaphragm work and power lasting at least 30 min following completion of the loading task. Surprisingly, but intriguingly, maximal isocapnic ventilation had no effect on any of the ultrasound-derived measures. The authors offer a fair-spirited discussion addressing this unexpected outcome. In short, it is complicated! A variety of inter-related factors contribute to fatigue under different loading conditions. Whereas differences in the magnitude of fatigue elicited by force/pressure tasks compared to velocity/flow tasks have been described by other investigators, previous assessments of contractile function used maximal inspiratory manoeuvres that are highly dependent upon participant effort and motivation, which further complicates interpretation. A key advantage of the assessment of fatigue employed by Illidi and Romer (2024) is the use of objective, effort-independent, combined multi-metric determination of contractile performance. Illidi and Romer (2024) confirm the benefit of attendant use of ultrasound to assess diaphragm function demonstrating the power of imaging. But as always, the devil is in the detail! The study design and execution were meticulous. Yet, a relatively small sample size of young fit males was studied, including athletes, which limits generalisability of the findings to a wider population, especially an older population, which may be especially relevant to the consideration of diaphragm performance given the recognised decline in diaphragm and respiratory performance with advancing age. By design the study was restricted to male participants owing to the known sex differences in fatigue (Guenette et al., 2010), but diaphragm dysfunction in clinical settings is indiscriminate, so it will be important into the future to build a comparable portfolio in female participants. Combined diaphragm ultrasonography and respiratory manometry may have important application in the context of critical care, to monitor the expected diaphragm dysfunction following prolonged mechanical ventilation and to complement existing approaches to successful weaning, avoiding extubation failure (Dres et al., 2017). To date, diaphragm ultrasound alone to predict weaning outcome has yielded inconsistent results (see Laghi et al., 2021). A potential limitation of the study by Illidi and Romer (2024) is inference of diaphragm muscle performance based on crural diaphragm excursions. Whereas the action of the crural diaphragm is generally reflective of whole muscle, the costal diaphragm compartments contribute mostly to the action of the diaphragm as an inspiratory pump. Moreover, generally with ultrasound assessments, there are concerns with repeatability and reproducibility (i.e., variation in repeated measures within and between sonographers). Nevertheless, Illidi and Romer (2024) provide us with a potentially valuable tool to interrogate diaphragm function in health and disease. Sole author. The author declares no conflicts of interest. None.</description>
      <author>Ken D. O&#8217;Halloran</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1113/ep092452</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
