<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:43:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress on the Surface and Bulk Modification of Carbon Nitrides for Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400136</link>
      <description>Sisi Ma, Shuaipeng Wang, Xin Wang, Songcan Wang, Energy technology (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393276940

                Photocatalytic CO 2 reduction has been considered as a green and sustainable approach to solve energy and environmental problems. However, the CO 2 reduction efficiency of various types of semiconductor photocatalysts studied at this stage is far from realizing practical applications. The challenge of photocatalytic CO 2 reduction is to design photocatalysts with excellent catalytic performance. This article summarizes the carbon nitride materials for efficient CO 2 reduction and obtaining high value&#8208;added products. The physicochemical properties of carbon nitride materials are discussed in terms of the photocatalytic mechanisms (bandgap tuning, high specific surface area, shorter electron&#8211;hole transmission paths, increasing the number of active sites, etc.). The present review provides the latest research progress of carbon nitride modification strategies. The prospects and challenges for the application of carbon nitride materials for CO 2 reduction are presented. This review article will provide useful guidance for further research on carbon nitride materials for efficient photocatalytic CO 2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Sisi Ma, Shuaipeng Wang, Xin Wang, Songcan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Design of Transition Metal-Based Catalysts for Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01456</link>
      <description>Liang Guo, Jingwen Zhou, Fu Liu, Xiangchuan Meng, Yangbo Ma, Fengkun Hao, Yi Xiong, Zhanxi Fan, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Guo, Jingwen Zhou, Fu Liu, Xiangchuan Meng, Yangbo Ma, Fengkun Hao, Yi Xiong, Zhanxi Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ladder type covalent organic frameworks constructed with natural units for the oxygen and carbon dioxide reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150812</link>
      <description>Minghao Liu, Shuai Yang, Yubin Fu, Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Jun He, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng, Chemical engineering journal (1996. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393282347

                Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) constructed with metallocyclophane units and organic linkers have found application as electrocatalytic systems. Nevertheless, the majority of linkers within COFs necessitate intricate design and synthesis. Conversely, the potential utilization of natural building blocks in COF construction remains largely unexplored. In this study, we constructed a natural COF (CoPc-EA-COF) by employing a natural phenolic molecule (ellagic acid (EA)) as the linker and Co-hexadecafluorophthalocyanine (CoPc) as blocks. This framework serves as an electrocatalyst for both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). The incorporation of EA units imparts the CoPc-EA-COF with elevated electronic conductivity, enhanced CO2 binding affinity, and superior reductive capacity compared to the controlled COF lacking EA units. The CoPc-EA-COF demonstrated enhanced performance in the ORR, as evidenced by a half-wave potential of 0.80 V. Moreover, it showcased elevated activity and selectivity in the CO2RR, achieving a maximum CO faradic efficiency of 97.32 % at &#8722; 0.8 V, along with turnover frequency (TOF) values reaching 2092 h&#8722;1. Theoretical calculations revealed that the presence of EA units facilitated the generation of OOH* and COOH* species, which are pivotal in the rate-determining stages of both ORR and CO2RR processes. The contribution of EA units significantly bolstered the overall catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Minghao Liu, Shuai Yang, Yubin Fu, Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Jun He, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The reduction mechanism of C1 product from carbon dioxide catalyzed by Ni-doped g-C3N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Molecular catalysis (Online). 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393305887

                This work employs density functional theory (DFT) to scrutinize the catalytic efficacy of nano nickel (Ni) clusters supported by graphitic carbon nitride (Nin@g-C3N4, where n ranges from 1 to 6) in the context of the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Structural examination revealed that Nin@g-C3N4 possesses a substantial binding energy (-1.63 eV to -7.72 eV), confirming the structural stability of the catalyst in the CO2RR. Electronic structure analysis revealed a pronounced orbital overlap near the Fermi level between the 3d orbital of Ni atoms and the 2p orbital of adjacent cavity nitrogen atoms in Nin@g-C3N4. Further insights are gleaned from the calculations of the Bader charge and energy band, indicating significant charge transfer and band gap alteration, suggesting enhanced conductivity due to Ni doping on g-C3N4. The catalytic performance in the CO2RR is predominantly influenced by the size of the doped Ni clusters. The Ni4@g-C3N4 cluster demonstrated optimal efficiency in producing formic acid (HCOOH) with a limiting potential of -0.12 V. In contrast, the Ni5@g-C3N4 cluster excels in methane (CH4) formation, with a limiting potential of -0.35 V. Additionally, these catalysts exhibit marked inhibition of the hydrogen evolution reaction, further underscoring their potential in CO2RR applications.</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of iron oxide supported on activated coke for catalytic reduction of sulfur dioxide by carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106488</link>
      <description>Shanchuan Li, Tai Feng, Qiwen Kong, Jun Li, Peiyi Liu, Peng Ni, Cuiping Wang, Journal of analytical and applied pyrolysis (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393306954

                In view of the low utilization rate of by-product in limestone-gypsum wet flue gas desulfurization process, a method of catalytic reduction of SO2 to elemental sulfur was proposed. In this work, supported iron catalyst using activated coke as supporter was prepared and characterized. Moreover, the performance of SO2 reduction using CO as reducing agent at various Fe loadings, temperatures, gaseous hourly space velocities and CO/SO2 molar ratios was studied. Research shows that, compared with other metals, the highest catalytic activity is achieved over Fe-based catalyst. The iron sulfide is the main active component during the catalytic reduction reaction, hence the catalyst needs to be presulfided before use. The micropores of activated coke become more abundant after loading Fe, whereas excessive increase of Fe loading may bloke the mesopores and weaken the catalytic activity. Higher reaction temperature, lower GHSV and a stoichiometric molar ratio are conducive to the improvement of SO2 conversion and S yield. The catalytic performance at lower temperatures was further improved by loading Co. When the Co loading is 4 wt.%, the SO2 conversion rate reaches 90.9% at 400 &#176;C because loading Co enhances the redox performance of the catalyst surface. The findings are instructive for the development of cost-effective carbon-based catalysts for resource recovery of sulfur.</description>
      <author>Shanchuan Li, Tai Feng, Qiwen Kong, Jun Li, Peiyi Liu, Peng Ni, Cuiping Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Cofed Carbon Dioxide Modifies the Local Coordination Environment of Zeolite-Supported, Atomically Dispersed Chromium to Promote Ethane Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c00995</link>
      <description>Wenqi Zhou, Noah Felvey, Jiawei Guo, Adam S. Hoffman, Simon R. Bare, Ambarish Kulkarni, Ron C. Runnebaum, Coleman X. Kronawitter, Journal of the American Chemical Society (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393308679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenqi Zhou, Noah Felvey, Jiawei Guo, Adam S. Hoffman, Simon R. Bare, Ambarish Kulkarni, Ron C. Runnebaum, Coleman X. Kronawitter</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c00995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Membrane contactor-photocatalytic hybrid system for carbon dioxide capture and conversion to formic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102085</link>
      <description>Andi Rina Ayu Astuti, Wibawa Hendra Saputera, Danu Ariono, I Gede Wenten, Dwiwahju Sasongko, Results in engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393359313

                The escalating demand for Carbon Capture and Utilization (CCU) schemes to mitigate CO2 emissions has propelled research into more efficient methods of CO2 conversion, such as the production of formic acid. While traditional approaches often require harsh operating conditions and substantial energy inputs, photocatalysis offers a promising alternative by harnessing CO2, water, and light for formic acid production. This study evaluates the performance and reaction kinetics of CO2 capture and conversion to formic acid using an integrated membrane contactor and photocatalytic process. Investigation into various CO2 absorbents and reduction catalysts reveals that TEA achieves a CO2 loading of 0.957 moles of CO2/mole of solvent, while NaOH achieves 0.75 moles of CO2/mole of solvent over a 4-hour operation period. Subsequent photoreduction of CO2 results in formic acid concentration of 15.89 ppm using ZnO and 10.16 ppm using TiO2 within the same 4-hour operation period at a gas flow rate of 800 ml/min. The rate of CO2 photoreduction to formic acid emerges as the limiting factor in this integrated process, indicating a need for further optimization. Key parameters identified for optimal performance include a UV source of 500 W, a medium pH of 10, and a catalyst loading of 0.5 g/L. This study contributes to the advancement of CCU technologies by demonstrating the feasibility of integrating CO2 capture and photoreduction using membrane contactors and photocatalytic systems, paving the way for sustainable formic acid production.</description>
      <author>Andi Rina Ayu Astuti, Wibawa Hendra Saputera, Danu Ariono, I Gede Wenten, Dwiwahju Sasongko</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supported Tetra-Atom Clusters on G-Cn as Catalysts for Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4780685</link>
      <description>Wenjing Zhou, Xuxin Kang, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393376349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjing Zhou, Xuxin Kang, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4780685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis, study and characterization of new molecular catalysts for reduction of carbon dioxide with a view to use it as a carbon source.</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393356945</link>
      <description>Marc Bourrez, HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe). None(None)] 2012. https://openalex.org/W4393356945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marc Bourrez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393356945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Iron Oxides for CO2 Capture Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071673</link>
      <description>Antonio Fabozzi, Francesca Cerciello, Osvalda Senneca, Energies (Basel). 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393388356

                The iron industry is the largest energy-consuming manufacturing sector in the world, emitting 4&#8211;5% of the total carbon dioxide (CO2). The development of iron-based systems for CO2 capture and storage could effectively contribute to reducing CO2 emissions. A wide set of different iron oxides, such as hematite (Fe2O3), magnetite (Fe3O4), and w&#252;stite (Fe(1&#8722;y)O) could in fact be employed for CO2 capture at room temperature and pressure upon an investigation of their capturing properties. In order to achieve the most functional iron oxide form for CO2 capture, starting from Fe2O3, a reducing agent such as hydrogen (H2) or carbon monoxide (CO) can be employed. In this review, we present the state-of-the-art and recent advances on the different iron oxide materials employed, as well as on their reduction reactions with H2 and CO.</description>
      <author>Antonio Fabozzi, Francesca Cerciello, Osvalda Senneca</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071673</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Prediction Leads to Synthesize GDY Supported InOx Quantum Dots for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202318080</link>
      <description>Feng He, Xi Chen, Yurui Xue, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393314672

                The preparation of formic acid by direct reduction of carbon dioxide is an important basis for the future chemical industry and is of great significance. Due to the serious shortage of highly active and selective electrocatalysts leading to the development of direct reduction of carbon dioxide is limited. Herein the target catalysts with high CO2RR activity and selectivity were identified by integrating DFT calculations and high&#8208;throughput screening and by using graphdiyne (GDY) supported metal oxides quantum dots (QDs) as the ideal model. It is theoretically predicted that GDY supported indium oxide QDs (i.e., InOx/GDY) is a new heterostructure electrocatalyst candidate with optimal CO2RR performance. The interfacial electronic strong interactions effectively regulate the surface charge distribution of QDs and affect the adsorption/desorption behavior of HCOO* intermediate during CO2RR to achieve highly efficient CO2 conversion. Based on the predicted composition and structure, we synthesized the advanced catalytic system, and demonstrates superior CO2&#8208;to&#8208;HCOOH conversion performance. The study presents an effective strategy for rational design of highly efficient heterostructure electrocatalysts to promote green chemical production.</description>
      <author>Feng He, Xi Chen, Yurui Xue, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202318080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Prediction Leads to Synthesize GDY Supported InOx Quantum Dots for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202318080</link>
      <description>Feng He, Xi Chen, Yurui Xue, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie (International ed. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393314720

                The preparation of formic acid by direct reduction of carbon dioxide is an important basis for the future chemical industry and is of great significance. Due to the serious shortage of highly active and selective electrocatalysts leading to the development of direct reduction of carbon dioxide is limited. Herein the target catalysts with high CO2RR activity and selectivity were identified by integrating DFT calculations and high&#8208;throughput screening and by using graphdiyne (GDY) supported metal oxides quantum dots (QDs) as the ideal model. It is theoretically predicted that GDY supported indium oxide QDs (i.e., InOx/GDY) is a new heterostructure electrocatalyst candidate with optimal CO2RR performance. The interfacial electronic strong interactions effectively regulate the surface charge distribution of QDs and affect the adsorption/desorption behavior of HCOO* intermediate during CO2RR to achieve highly efficient CO2 conversion. Based on the predicted composition and structure, we synthesized the advanced catalytic system, and demonstrates superior CO2&#8208;to&#8208;HCOOH conversion performance. The study presents an effective strategy for rational design of highly efficient heterostructure electrocatalysts to promote green chemical production.</description>
      <author>Feng He, Xi Chen, Yurui Xue, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202318080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen in aviation: A simulation of demand, price dynamics, and CO2 emission reduction potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.241</link>
      <description>Katrin Oesingmann, Wolfgang Grimme, Janina Scheelhaase, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393349720

                Aviation contributes to anthropogenic climate change by emitting both carbon dioxide (CO2) and non-CO2 emissions through the combustion of fossil fuels. One approach to reduce the climate impact of aviation is the use of hydrogen as an alternative fuel. Two distinct technological options are presently under consideration for the implementation of hydrogen in aviation: hydrogen fuel cell architectures and the direct combustion of hydrogen. In this study, a hydrogen demand model is developed that considers anticipated advancements in liquid hydrogen aircraft technologies, forecasted aviation demand, and aircraft startup and retirement cycles. The analysis indicates that global demand for liquid hydrogen in aviation could potentially reach 17 million tons by 2050, leading to a 9% reduction in CO2 emissions from global aviation. Thus, the total potential of hydrogen in aviation extends beyond this, considering that the total market share of hydrogen aircraft on suitable routes in the model is projected to be only 27% in 2050 due to aircraft retirement cycles. Additionally, it is shown, that achieving the potential demand for hydrogen in aviation depends on specific market prices. With anticipated declines in current production costs, hydrogen fuel costs would need to reach about 70 EUR/MWh by 2050 to fulfill full demand in aviation, assuming biofuels provide the cheapest option for decarbonization alongside hydrogen. If e-fuels are the sole option for decarbonization alongside hydrogen, which is the more probable scenario, the entire hydrogen demand potential in aviation would be satisfied according to this study's estimates at significantly higher hydrogen prices, approximately 180 EUR/MWh.</description>
      <author>Katrin Oesingmann, Wolfgang Grimme, Janina Scheelhaase</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental study and equilibrium analysis on thermal reduction of CO2 by CFB gasification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101623</link>
      <description>Siyuan Zhang, Chen Liang, Xiaofang Wang, Zhengwang Zhu, Journal of the Energy Institute (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393281964

                CO2 can be involved in the CFB gasification process as one of the gasifying agents and be reduced to CO. In this paper, the feasibility of using CFB gasification process to reduce CO2 was investigated by using a bench-scale CFB gasifier. The effect of gasifying agent parameters including the CO2 substitution for N2, the O2 concentration and O2/C were studied. The result of experiments was compared with the chemical equilibrium calculations. The experimental result shows that the reduction of CO2 can be realized in CFB gasification, and the yield of CO in O2/CO2 atmosphere is higher than that that in air atmosphere. When the O2 concentration is 30%, the CO2 conversion reached the maximum of 0.017 Nm3(CO2)/kg(coal). However, the conversion of CO2 is limited by temperature and char reactivity at higher CO2 concentration. The gradual increase in CO2 yield with increasing O2/C suggests that at approximate temperature, the increase in O2/C enhances the oxidation of C and CO. When O2/C is greater than 0.45, the gasification results reach equilibrium. Under other conditions, the gasification results differ from the chemical equilibrium significantly. This is due to the change in the dominant reaction of the gasification process from the combustion reactions to the Boudouard reaction.</description>
      <author>Siyuan Zhang, Chen Liang, Xiaofang Wang, Zhengwang Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Studies for CO2/CO Reduction in Flow&#8208;Based Devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400070</link>
      <description>Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Yu&#8208;Chia Chang, Yiyu Chen, Yao Jane Hsu, Kang-Lin Peng, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, ChemNanoMat (Weinheim). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393191149

                Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) conducted in a flow&#8208;based device exhibits a substantial enhancement in Faradaic efficiency and catalytic current density compared to a conventional H&#8208;type configuration. This highlights the distinct catalytic environment and behavior inherent in flow cells as opposed to H cells. To investigate the authentic properties of a catalyst within a flow&#8208;based device, customized flow cells have been specifically devised for operando techniques during CO2RR and CORR, rather than resorting to an in&#8208;situ three&#8208;electrode H&#8208;type configuration with its disparate catalytic environment and performance. This approach ensures a catalytic environment identical to that employed in electrochemical measurements. This review delineates the disparities between H&#8208;type and flow&#8208;based cells as well as the operando techniques tailored for flow&#8208;based devices, including X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy and Raman spectroscopy, preserving a consistent catalytic environment. It also compiles recent findings on copper&#8208;based systems using operando flow&#8208;based devices. The operando insights reveal a significant augmentation in catalytic current density, impacting both chemical properties and crystal structures. Furthermore, the observation of various catalytic intermediates enriches our comprehension. In essence, the application of operando techniques to flow&#8208;based devices furnishes a comprehensive understanding of the catalytic behavior exhibited by diverse systems, propelling progress toward achieving Net Zero emissions.</description>
      <author>Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Yu&#8208;Chia Chang, Yiyu Chen, Yao Jane Hsu, Kang-Lin Peng, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of bulk and surface oxide evolution in copper foams for electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-024-01151-0</link>
      <description>Fan Yang, Shan Jiang, Si Liu, Paul Beyer, Stefan Mebs, Michael Haumann, Christina Roth, Holger Dau, Communications chemistry. 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393270447

                Abstract Oxide-derived copper (OD-Cu) materials exhibit extraordinary catalytic activities in the electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), which likely relates to non-metallic material constituents formed in transitions between the oxidized and the reduced material. In time-resolved operando experiment, we track the structural dynamics of copper oxide reduction and its re-formation separately in the bulk of the catalyst material and at its surface using X-ray absorption spectroscopy and surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy. Surface-species transformations progress within seconds whereas the subsurface (bulk) processes unfold within minutes. Evidence is presented that electroreduction of OD-Cu foams results in kinetic trapping of subsurface (bulk) oxide species, especially for cycling between strongly oxidizing and reducing potentials. Specific reduction-oxidation protocols may optimize formation of bulk-oxide species and thereby catalytic properties. Together with the Raman-detected surface-adsorbed *OH and C-containing species, the oxide species could collectively facilitate *CO adsorption, resulting an enhanced selectivity towards valuable C 2+ products during CO 2 RR.</description>
      <author>Fan Yang, Shan Jiang, Si Liu, Paul Beyer, Stefan Mebs, Michael Haumann, Christina Roth, Holger Dau</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-024-01151-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hemispheric asymmetric response of tropical cyclones to CO2 emission reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-024-00632-2</link>
      <description>Chao Liu, Soon&#8208;Il An, Jiuwei Zhao, Seok&#8208;Woo Son, Fei&#8208;Fei Jin, Ruifen Zhan, npj climate and atmospheric science. 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393392587

                Abstract Tropical cyclones (TCs) are among the most devastating natural hazards for coastal regions, and their response to human activities has broad socio-economic relevance. So far, how TC responds to climate change mitigation remains unknown, complicating the design of adaptation policies. Using net-zero and negative carbon emission experiments, we reveal a robust hemisphere-asymmetric hysteretic TC response to CO 2 reduction. During the decarbonization phase, the Northern Hemisphere TC frequency continues to decrease for several more decades, while the Southern Hemisphere oceans abruptly shifts to a stormier state, with the timescales depending on mitigation details. Such systematic changes are largely attributed to the planetary-scale reorganization of vertical wind shear and midlevel upward motion associated with the hysteretic southward migration of the Intertropical Convergence Zone, underpinned by the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation and El Ni&#241;o-like mean state changes. The hemispheric contrast in TC response suggests promising benefits for most of the world&#8217;s population from human action to mitigate greenhouse gas warming, but it may also exacerbate regional socioeconomic disparities, for example by putting more pressure on small open-ocean island states in the Southern Hemisphere to adapt to TC risks.</description>
      <author>Chao Liu, Soon&#8208;Il An, Jiuwei Zhao, Seok&#8208;Woo Son, Fei&#8208;Fei Jin, Ruifen Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-024-00632-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of complexes inspired from formate dehydrogenases : Application to the homogeneous catalysis of CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393355905</link>
      <description>Thibault Fogeron, HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe). None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4393355905

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thibault Fogeron</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393355905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Sensitivity and Catalyst Restructuring for CO2 Electro-reduction on Copper</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-z3dlp</link>
      <description>Dongfang Cheng, Khanh&#8208;Ly C. Nguyen, Vaidish Sumaria, Ziyang Wei, Zisheng Zhang, Winston Gee, Yichen Li, Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, Markus Heyde, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Philippe Sautet, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393200362

                Cu is the most promising metal catalyst for CO2 electroreduction (CO2RR) to multi-carbon products, but the structure sensitivity of the reaction and the stability versus restructuring of the catalyst surface under reaction conditions are still controversial. Here, atomic scale simulations of surface energies and reaction pathway kinetics supported by experimental evidence unveil that CO2RR does not take place on perfect planar Cu(111) and Cu(100) surfaces but rather on steps or kinks defects, and that these planar surfaces tend to restructure in reaction conditions to the active stepped surfaces. By combining basin hopping global sampling and grand canonical density functional theory, we show that the extremely low CO coverage on (111) and (100) surfaces, originating from sluggish CO2 conversion and unfavorable CO binding, limits the ability of these surfaces to reduce CO2 to multi-carbon products. Steps and kinks at surfaces, despite the lack of decrease in C-C coupling barriers on these sites, exhibit a significant increase in activity arising from beneficial CO2 activation and higher CO coverage. Notably, the square motifs adjacent to defects, not the defects themselves, are the active sites for CO2RR via synergistic effect. In addition, the strong binding of CO on defective sites acts as a thermodynamic driving force for the restructuring of planar surfaces to active stepped terminations under reactive conditions. We evaluate these mechanisms against experiments of CO2RR on UHV-prepared ultraclean Cu surfaces. Overall, our findings highlight the structural sensitivity in steering CO2RR and elucidate the origin of in situ restructuring of Cu catalysts during the reaction. We furthermore feature that the active sites for CO2RR are created under reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>Dongfang Cheng, Khanh&#8208;Ly C. Nguyen, Vaidish Sumaria, Ziyang Wei, Zisheng Zhang, Winston Gee, Yichen Li, Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, Markus Heyde, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-z3dlp</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and lifetime of diffusion-trapped oxygen in oxide-derived copper CO2 reduction electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01132-5</link>
      <description>Zan Lian, Federico Dattila, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393379673

                Abstract Oxide-derived Cu has an excellent ability to promote C&#8211;C coupling in the electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction. However, these materials largely rearrange under reaction conditions; therefore, the nature of the active site remains controversial. Here we study the reduction process of oxide-derived Cu via large-scale molecular dynamics with a precise neural network potential trained on first-principles data and introducing experimental conditions. The oxygen concentration in the most stable oxide-derived Cu increases with an increase of the pH, potential or specific surface area. In long electrochemical experiments, the catalyst would be fully reduced to Cu, but removing all the trapped oxygen takes a considerable amount of time. Although the highly reconstructed Cu surface provides various sites to adsorb oxygen more strongly, the surface oxygen atoms are not stable under common experimental conditions. This work provides insight into the evolution of oxide-derived Cu catalysts and residual oxygen during reaction and also a deep understanding of the nature of active sites.</description>
      <author>Zan Lian, Federico Dattila, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01132-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique dendritic Bi2S3 with ultrathin nanosheets rich in S vacancy-defect toward promoting highly efficient photothermal CO2 reduction into CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00152d</link>
      <description>Yong Zhou, Qiutong Han, Zhigang Zou, Yan Shen, Xin Zhou, Qinghua He, Yanjun Zhu, Catalysis science &amp; technology (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393391190

                The catalytic reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) into value-added chemicals utilizing solar energy is a promising strategy to simultaneously address global warming and energy crisis. The tree-like Bi2S3 catalytic material,...</description>
      <author>Yong Zhou, Qiutong Han, Zhigang Zou, Yan Shen, Xin Zhou, Qinghua He, Yanjun Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00152d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-engineering Cu-based catalysts to accelerate the electrochemical reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc00819g</link>
      <description>Ying Liu, Rui Zhang, Ke-sheng Xiao, Fenghui Ye, Xinyue Ma, Wei Liu, Han Dong Yin, Baoguang Mao, Xueyu Song, Chuangang Hu, Chemical communications (London. 1996. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393388285

                Two typical Cu-based complex catalysts with piperazine (PR) and p-phenylenediamine (pPDA) ligands were designed to elucidate that the ligands can tailor the reduction behavior of the Cu species and thus...</description>
      <author>Ying Liu, Rui Zhang, Ke-sheng Xiao, Fenghui Ye, Xinyue Ma, Wei Liu, Han Dong Yin, Baoguang Mao, Xueyu Song, Chuangang Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc00819g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of CO2 Emission Reduction in Aviation Using Mix of 2,4% Biofuel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61306/icaneat.v1i1.203</link>
      <description>Ratih Sekartadji, Ali Musyafa, Lalu Muhamad Jaelani, Ervina Ahyudanari, No host. 1(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393343580

                The activities of flight have an impact on the environment. Combustion from aircraft fuel produces chemical products that have been emitted from the high-speed aircraft engine. Aircraft engines produce emissions that are similar to other emissions resulting from fossil fuel combustion. The transportation sector include land and air transportation produced 22,4 % from all energy sector. To reduce aircraft emissions while maintaining healthy economic growth, the aviation sector needs to reduce the use of fossil jet fuel by using sustainable aviation fuel. The use of biofuel in airplanes does not completely replace the fuel we use today, but gradually starting with a mixture of 10 % or 20 %. Several European countries and China have used biofuels made from waste in each country. Likewise in Indonesia, Pertamina collaborates with ITB, producing aircraft fuel from palm oil. The flight test using a Garuda Boeing 737 aircraft was successful using a mixture of 2.4% biofuel in October 2023. The CO2 emission estimation calculations at three large airports in Indonesia, Soekarno-Hatta International Airport Jakarta, Juanda International Airport Surabaya and Sultan Hasanuddin International Airport Makassar that using aviation fuel and a mix of aviation fuel with 2.4 % biofuel, reduce by 2.83 % - 2.95 %.</description>
      <author>Ratih Sekartadji, Ali Musyafa, Lalu Muhamad Jaelani, Ervina Ahyudanari</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61306/icaneat.v1i1.203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Mechanism on Copper: Relation between Mesoscopic Mass Transport and Intrinsic Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4189647/v1</link>
      <description>Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, Joonbaek Jang, Martina R&#252;scher, Maximilian Winzely, Dolores Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Eber Reyes-Lopez, Samanvaya Srivast, Panagiotis D. Christofides, Philippe Sautet, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393377846

                Abstract A multi-scale first-principles transport-reaction model is derived for the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to fuels and chemicals on polycrystalline copper electrodes. The model utilizes a continuous stirred-tank reactor (CSTR)-volume approximation that captures the relative timescales for mesoscale stochastic processes at the electrode/electrolyte interface that determine product selectivity. The model is built starting from a large experimental dataset obtained under a broad range of well-defined transport regimes in a gastight rotating cylinder electrode cell. Product distributions under different conditions of transport, applied potential, and bulk electrolyte concentration are rationalized by introducing dimensionless numbers that reduce complexity and capture relative timescales for mesoscopic and microscopic dynamics of electrocatalytic reactions on copper electrodes. This work demonstrates that one CO2 reduction mechanism can explain differences in selectivity reported for copper-based electrocatalysts when mass transport, concentration polarization effects, and primary and secondary current distributions are taken into account.</description>
      <author>Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, Joonbaek Jang, Martina R&#252;scher, Maximilian Winzely, Dolores Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Eber Reyes-Lopez, Samanvaya Srivast, Panagiotis D. Christofides, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4189647/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indoor CO2 capture-driven passive cooling for photovoltaics with ventilation energy reduction utilizing amine-functionalized adsorbents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118351</link>
      <description>Seonggon Kim, Minjae Kim, Kwangjin Jang, Sam S. Yoon, Wonjoon Choi, Hoseong Lee, Joon Hyung Shim, Yong Tae Kang, Energy conversion and management. 307(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393332891

                In carbon capture, utilization, and storage processes, CO2 capture consumes 80 % of total energy consumption, reaching 3&#8211;8 MJ/kg which poses a formidable challenge. Conversely, buildings are responsible for approximately 40 % of final energy consumption and contribute over 30 % of CO2 emissions, highlighting the urgent need to reduce the building energy. In this work, a sustainable indoor CO2 capture-driven passive cooling system is developed for building-integrated photovoltaics with ventilation energy reduction by coating amine-impregnated mesoporous silica (PEI/MCM-41) to the rear of PV cells using supersonic cold spraying method. During nighttime, it effectively mitigates indoor CO2 concentration increase due to human respiration by capturing 1.64 mmol/g of CO2, enabling a reduction of 180 MJ/kg-thermal in winter and 30.4 MJ/kg-electric in summer within the building. In daylight hours, PV cells generate electricity, and the supplied radiant solar heat is consumed for CO2 desorption (latent cooling), lowering the average temperature of the PV cells and improving the power efficiency. PEI/MCM-41 achieves a remarkable cooling energy density of 242 J/g and average cooling power of 357 W/m2. It has been demonstrated that the present system can simultaneously reduce the building energy consumption and CO2 emission.</description>
      <author>Seonggon Kim, Minjae Kim, Kwangjin Jang, Sam S. Yoon, Wonjoon Choi, Hoseong Lee, Joon Hyung Shim, Yong Tae Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118351</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Mn/Cu Bi-metallic MOF for electrochemical CO2 reduction into valuable products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05859-w</link>
      <description>Usman Raza, Naseem Iqbal, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Awais Ahmad, Journal of solid state electrochemistry (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393192117

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Usman Raza, Naseem Iqbal, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Awais Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05859-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen&#8208;Bonded Organic Framework Supporting Atomic Bi&#8722;N2O2 Sites for High&#8208;Efficiency Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202404015</link>
      <description>Changli Wang, Zengtao Lv, Yarong Liu, Rui Li, Chia&#8208;Chung Sun, Jinming Wang, Liuhua Li, Xiangjian Liu, Xiao Feng, Wenxiu Yang, Bo Wang, Angewandte Chemie (International ed. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393192087

                Single atomic catalysts (SACs) offer a superior platform for studying the structure&#8208;activity relationships during electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Yet challenges still exist to obtain well&#8208;defined and novel site configuration owing to the uncertainty of functional framework&#8208;derived SACs through calcination. Herein, a novel Bi&#8722;N2O2 site supported on the (1 1 0) plane of hydrogen&#8208;bonded organic framework (HOF) is reported directly for CO2RR. In flow cell, the target catalyst Bi1&#8208;HOF maintains a faradaic efficiency (FE) HCOOH of over 90% at a wide potential window of 1.4 V. The corresponding partial current density ranges from 113.3 to 747.0 mA cm&#8722;2. And, Bi1&#8208;HOF exhibits a long&#8208;term stability of over 30 h under a successive potential&#8208;step test with a current density of 100~400 mA cm&#8722;2. Density function theory (DFT) calculations illustrate that the novel Bi&#8722;N2O2 site supported on the (1 1 0) plane of HOF effectively induces the oriented electron transfer from Bi center to CO2 molecule, reaching an enhanced CO2 activation and reduction. Besides, this study offers a versatile method to reach series of M&#8722;N2O2 sites with regulable metal centers via the same intercalation mechanism, broadening the platform for studying the structure&#8208;activity relationships during CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Changli Wang, Zengtao Lv, Yarong Liu, Rui Li, Chia&#8208;Chung Sun, Jinming Wang, Liuhua Li, Xiangjian Liu, Xiao Feng, Wenxiu Yang, Bo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202404015</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
