<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:43:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of the Cu Foam on the Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12020057</link>
      <description>Yuan-Gee Lee, Hui-Hsuan Chiao, Yu&#8211;Ching Weng, Chyi-How Lay, Inorganics (Basel). 12(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391753550

                Unlike the flat Cu sheet, we employed Cu foam to explore the specific porous effect on the expanding specific area. We found that the foam structure is superior to the sheet feature in the specific location from the morphology investigation. In the practical measurement of surface area, we found that the adsorbate could aptly agglomerate, resulting in a consequential block in the transport path. The specific location of the Cu foam was underestimated because the channels of the deep foam layer were blocked by the agglomerated adsorbate. To explore the protonation process of the electro-reduction, we adopted the carbonate electrolyte as the control group in contrast to the experimental group, the bicarbonate electrolyte. In the carbonate electrolyte, the primary intermediate was shown to be CO molecules, as verified using XPS spectra. In the bicarbonate electrolyte, the intermediate CO disappeared; instead, it was hydrogenated as a hydrocarbon intermediate, CHO*. The bicarbonate ion was also found to suppress electrocatalysis in the deep structure of the Cu foam because its high-molecular-weight intermediates accumulated in the diffusion paths. Furthermore, we found a promotion of the oxidation valence on the electrode from Cu2O to CuO, when the electrode structure transformed from sheet to foam. Cyclic voltammograms demonstrate a succession of electro-reduction consequences: at low reduction potential, hydrogen liberated by the decomposition of water; at elevated reduction potential, formic acid and CO produced; and at high reduction potential, CH4 and C2H4 were formed from &#8722;1.4 V to &#8722;1.8 V.</description>
      <author>Yuan-Gee Lee, Hui-Hsuan Chiao, Yu&#8211;Ching Weng, Chyi-How Lay</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12020057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress of MXene as a Cocatalyst in Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceja.2024.100593</link>
      <description>Zhe Wang, Samar Al Jitan, Inas M. AlNashef, Blaise L. Tardy, Giovanni Palmisano, Chemical Engineering Journal Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391760771

                Due to the excessive consumption of fossil fuel resources and the emission of a substantial quantity of CO2 into the environment, it is urgent to develop clean energy solutions. In order to reduce carbon emissions from the source, it is effective approach to convert CO2 into various renewable energy fuels. Inspired by the photosynthesis of green plant, CO2 is converted into clean fuel with the aid of catalysts. Regarding the separation and transfer of photogenerated charge carriers, and inadequate adsorption and activation of CO2 on the surface of catalysts, the current semiconductors utilized in photocatalysis have low efficiency. As a result, the current efficiency of photocatalysts is far from meeting the need for practical industrial demands. MXene materials, for example Ti3C2Tx (9980 S cm&#8722;1), have emerged as a promising candidate for CO2 reduction due to the significant number of active sites for functional groups, high conductivity and low defects, large surface areas, and outstanding visible light photoelectronic properties. This review provides a critical overview of the recent progress regarding MXene as a co-catalyst in photocatalytic CO2 reduction systems. We systemically explore the fundamental principles and reaction mechanisms associated with separating and transferring photogenerated charge carriers. Additionally, we investigate the basic properties of MXene as a co-catalyst in the context of CO2 reduction. Furthermore, this review also elucidates the impacts of the microstructure of photocatalysts on enhancing photocatalytic performance. Finally, the challenges and opportunities in using MXene as a co-catalyst for CO2 reduction have been presented to inspire further research in this field.</description>
      <author>Zhe Wang, Samar Al Jitan, Inas M. AlNashef, Blaise L. Tardy, Giovanni Palmisano</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceja.2024.100593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High selective electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide to ethylene enabled by regulating the microenvironment over Cu-Ag nanowires</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.028</link>
      <description>D. D. Fan, Zhang Shi-ji, Yumeng Li, Bin Hua, Ruopeng Li, Yaqiang Li, Anmin Liu, Peixia Yang, Jinqiu Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391850244

                Copper-based tandem catalysts are effective candidates for yielding multi-carbon (C2+) products in electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2RR). However, these catalysts still face a significant challenge regarding in the low selectivity for the production of a specific product. In this study, we report a high selectivity of 77.8 %&#177;2% at &#8722;1.0 V (vs RHE) for the production of C2H4 by using a Cu88Ag12NW catalyst which is primarily prepared through a combined Cu-Ag co-deposition and wet chemical method, employing an attractive strategy focused on regulating the microenvironment over Cu-Ag nanowires. The experimental and computational studies show that the higher *CO coverage and lower intermediate adsorption energy are important reasons for achieving the high C2H4 selectivity of Cu88Ag12NW catalyst. Comsol simulation results indicate that dense nanowires exhibit a nano-limiting effect on OH&#8722; ions, thereby leading to an increase in local pH and promoting coupling reactions. The catalyst demonstrates no noticeable decrease in current density or selectivity even after 12 h of continuous operation. The Cu-Ag nanowire composite exhibits remarkable catalytic activity, superior faradaic efficiency, excellent stability, and easy synthesis, which highlights its significant potential for electro-reducing carbon dioxide into valuable products.</description>
      <author>D. D. Fan, Zhang Shi-ji, Yumeng Li, Bin Hua, Ruopeng Li, Yaqiang Li, Anmin Liu, Peixia Yang, Jinqiu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Termination Dependent Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction on Ti&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00320a</link>
      <description>Ling Meng, Likai Yan, Francesc Illas, Francesc Illas, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391853343

                The use of two-dimensional (2D) MXene materials as highly efficient electrocatalysts for carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) has gained considerable attention in the last years. However, current computational studies on...</description>
      <author>Ling Meng, Likai Yan, Francesc Illas, Francesc Illas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00320a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic sponges for wastewater treatment, carbon dioxide reduction, and hydrogen production: a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10311-024-01696-5</link>
      <description>Akash Balakrishnan, Meenu Mariam Jacob, Mahendra Chinthala, Nanditha Dayanandan, M. N. Ponnuswamy, Dai&#8208;Viet N. Vo, Environmental Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391881021

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akash Balakrishnan, Meenu Mariam Jacob, Mahendra Chinthala, Nanditha Dayanandan, M. N. Ponnuswamy, Dai&#8208;Viet N. Vo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10311-024-01696-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benzyl alcohol promoted electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide and C2 production by Cu2O/Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149800</link>
      <description>Qianqian Wang, Xinfa Wei, Yan Li, Juanjuan Luo, Lisong Chen, Jianlin Shi, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391896197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianqian Wang, Xinfa Wei, Yan Li, Juanjuan Luo, Lisong Chen, Jianlin Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide Lingual Tonsil Reduction for Obstructive Sleep Apnea: A Feasibility Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.23937/2572-4053.1510043</link>
      <description>Fontenot Andee, Chuan Liu, Dewan Karuna, Journal of sleep disorders and management. 9(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391907254

                Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) is characterized by frequent episodes of upper airway collapse during sleep. The lingual tonsil, when hypertrophic, can contribute to airway obstruction. The purpose of this study was to establish the utility and safety of the carbon dioxide (CO2) laser for tonsillar reduction in the management of OSA.</description>
      <author>Fontenot Andee, Chuan Liu, Dewan Karuna</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.23937/2572-4053.1510043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of reduction of carbon dioxide emissions from blast furnace under conditions of using advanced and existing blast furnace melting technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52150/2522-9117-2023-37-158-174</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1051;. &#1063;&#1072;&#1081;&#1082;&#1072;, B. V. Kornilov, A. O. Moskalyna, V. V. Lebid, M. M. Iziumskyi, M. H. Dzhyhota, Fundamental and applied problems of ferrous metallurgy. 37(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391829285

                The article discusses the results of heat and power and exergy calculations of the possibilities of new and existing technologies to reduce carbon dioxide emissions and coke consumption, increase pig iron production by injecting hydrogen and hydrogen-containing fuel additives (coke and natural gas) into the furnace, using metal additives, increasing the blast temperature, heat losses, and improving gas distribution in the blast furnace. The calculations were performed using a mathematical model of the complete energy balance of blast furnace smelting developed at the Iron and Steel Institute of Z. I. Nekrasov National Academy of Sciences of Ukraine, and the impact of the potential of new and existing technologies on reducing CO2 emissions and technical and economic indicators of blast furnace smelting was assessed when the consumption of pulverized coal, hydrogen and hydrogen-containing fuel additives and their combinations in a wide range was changed. The limit values for the injection of hydrogen and hydrogen-containing fuel additives into the blast furnace horn have been determined, which are determined by the following factors: the degree of direct reduction of iron, theoretical combustion temperature, the presence of industrial oxygen, and the temperature of the furnace gas. The study results showed that CO2 emissions in blast furnace production can be reduced by 25-30% by making changes to blast furnace technology and depend on investments, the raw material and energy base of the steelmaker, and the level of existing blast furnace technology. The paper considers the impact of low-cost measures to increase the blast temperature, use of clean metal additives, reduce heat losses, and improve gas distribution in the blast furnace on the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions and technical and economic indicators of blast furnace smelting. The results can be useful for determining the economic feasibility of a particular measure to reduce CO2 emissions in blast furnace production.</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1051;. &#1063;&#1072;&#1081;&#1082;&#1072;, B. V. Kornilov, A. O. Moskalyna, V. V. Lebid, M. M. Iziumskyi, M. H. Dzhyhota</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52150/2522-9117-2023-37-158-174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene-based CO2 reduction electrocatalysts: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5805(24)60839-5</link>
      <description>Zelin Wu, Congwei Wang, Xiaoxiang Zhang, Quangui Guo, Junying Wang, New Carbon Materials. 39(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391768389

                The reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) by electrochemical methods for the production of fuels and value-added chemicals is an effective strategy for overcoming the global warming problem. Due to the stable molecular structure of CO2, the design of highly selective, energy-efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts is key. For this reason, graphene and its derivatives are competitive for CO2 electroreduction with their unique and excellent physical, mechanical and electrical properties and relatively low cost. In addition, the surface of graphene-based materials can be modified using different methods, including doping, defect engineering, production of composite structures and wrapped shapes. We first review the fundamental concepts and criteria for evaluating electrochemical CO2 reduction, as well as the catalytic principles and processes. Methods for preparing graphene-based catalysts are briefly introduced, and recent research on them is summarized according to the categories of the catalytic sites. Finally, the future development direction of CO2 electroreduction technology is discussed.</description>
      <author>Zelin Wu, Congwei Wang, Xiaoxiang Zhang, Quangui Guo, Junying Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5805(24)60839-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gallium Nitride&#8208;Based Artificial Photosynthesis Integrated Devices for Solar Hydrogen Generation and Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119600862.ch11</link>
      <description>Baowen Zhou, Peng Zhou, Dong Wu, Zetian Mi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391875089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baowen Zhou, Peng Zhou, Dong Wu, Zetian Mi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119600862.ch11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect engineering of carbon-based electrocatalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5805(24)60833-4</link>
      <description>Youjun Lu, B. S. Cheng, Hui Zhan, Peng Zhou, New Carbon Materials. 39(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391768363

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction is an important way to achieve carbon neutrality by converting CO2 into high-value-added chemicals using electric energy. Carbon-based materials are widely used in various electrochemical reactions, including electrocatalytic CO2 reduction, due to their low cost and high activity. In recent years, defect engineering has attracted wide attention by constructing asymmetric defect centers in the materials, which can optimize the physicochemical properties of the material and improve its electrocatalytic activity. This review summarizes the types, methods of formation and defect characterization techniques of defective carbon-based materials. The advantages of defect engineering and the advantages and disadvantages of various defect formation methods and characterization techniques are also evaluated. Finally, the challenges of using defective carbon-based materials in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction are investigated and opportunities for their use are discussed. It is believed that this review will provide suggestions and guidance for developing defective carbon-based materials for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Youjun Lu, B. S. Cheng, Hui Zhan, Peng Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5805(24)60833-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of CO2 emissions reduction via by-product hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.138</link>
      <description>Chao Wang, Yongqiang Li, Junmin Wan, Yi Hu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391849200

                Hydrogen is a clean energy in the world and by-product hydrogen is an important part of global hydrogen production. The yield of by-product hydrogen accounts for 18% of hydrogen production globally. To analyze the current stage and calculate CO2 emissions reduction of by-product hydrogen, sources, purification technology, utilization models, comparison of by-product hydrogen and other hydrogen resources, reduction of CO2 emissions, prospects of industrial by-product hydrogen were analyzed from the respective of industrial utilization. The resources of by-product hydrogen will get expanded further. It can facilitate the utilization of industrial by-product hydrogen to establish industrial zone with the factories producing by-product hydrogen and the downstream factories utilizing by-product hydrogen under the current technology conditions. By analyzing the relevant data, it is calculated that the utilization of industrial by-product hydrogen can reduce CO2 emissions by 6.11x105 t per year in 2022. With the development of hydrogen purification technology, by-product hydrogen can provide an efficient and economical way to reduce CO2 emissions for global warming migration before the completion of green hydrogen substitution for other hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Chao Wang, Yongqiang Li, Junmin Wan, Yi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.138</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction by Urea Hangman Mn Terpyridine species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202304218</link>
      <description>Minghong Li, Fang Huang, Ping Zhang, Ying Xiong, Yaping Zhang, F&#275;i Li, Cheng Huang Lin, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391881952

                Based on our previous study in chemical subtleties of the proton tunneling distance for metal hydride formation (PTD&#8208;MH) to regulate the selectivity of CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), we have developed a family of Mn terpyridine derivatives, in which urea groups functioning as multipoint hydrogen&#8208;bonding hangman to accelerate the reaction rate. We found that such changes to the second coordination sphere significantly increased the turnover frequency (TOF) for CO2 reduction to ca. 360 s&#8208;1 with this family of molecular catalysts while maintaining high selectivity (ca. 100% &#177; 3) for CO even in the presence of a large amount of phenol as proton source. Notably, the compounds studied in this manuscript all exhibit large value for CO as that achieved by Fe porphyrins derivates, while saving up to 0.55 V in overpotential with respect to the latter.</description>
      <author>Minghong Li, Fang Huang, Ping Zhang, Ying Xiong, Yaping Zhang, F&#275;i Li, Cheng Huang Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202304218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to promote CO2 reduction in urban households from a micro perspective?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.130683</link>
      <description>Yang Xu, Qingsong Wang, Suqing Tian, Mengyue Liu, Yujie Zhang, Xueliang Yuan, Qiao Ma, Chengqing Liu, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391773165

                Climate change has received widespread international attention. Household CO2 reduction can play an important role in mitigating climate change. Therefore, studying household carbon reduction plans is one of the research hotspots. Using a Survey-Evaluation-Optimization approach, this study constructs a methodology system for urban household CO2 reduction from micro perspective. It is found that the direct household CO2 emissions in the target community are about 1580 kgCO2/(cap&#183;yr). Cooing and heat supply, cooking, hot water heating are stable and important components, accounting for about 70%. In some households, internal measures such as adjusting the temperature of air conditioning, canceling the insulation of water heaters, and changing travel modes show good CO2 reduction effects, reaching up to 650 kgCO2/yr. When the external measures are introduced to implement, the CO2 reduction effect of the internal measures is weakened, but the overall effect is improved. Especially when the low-carbon adjustment of power structure is introduced, the overall CO2 reduction can be increased by 35%. Based on this methodology, decision makers can obtain &#8220;one community, one policy&#8221; targeted implementation plan for household carbon reduction.</description>
      <author>Yang Xu, Qingsong Wang, Suqing Tian, Mengyue Liu, Yujie Zhang, Xueliang Yuan, Qiao Ma, Chengqing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.130683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling of Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction and CH4 Oxidation for Efficient Methyl Formate Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee00087k</link>
      <description>Quan Zhang, Yangshen Chen, Shuai Yan, Ximeng Lv, Chao Yang, Min Kuang, Gengfeng Zheng, Energy and Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391854676

                The electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) is promising for converting this greenhouse gas into value-added chemicals, while it suffers from limited energy efficiency and product variability. The direct coupling...</description>
      <author>Quan Zhang, Yangshen Chen, Shuai Yan, Ximeng Lv, Chao Yang, Min Kuang, Gengfeng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee00087k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction to Formate by a Cobalt Phosphino-Thiolate Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3sc06805f</link>
      <description>Jeremy A Intrator, David Vel&#225;zquez, Sicheng Fan, Enrico Mastrobattista, Christine Yu, Smaranda C. Marinescu, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391759409

                Electrochemical conversion of CO2 to value-added products serves as an attractive method to store renewable energy as energy-dense fuels. Selectivity in this type of conversion can be limited, often leading...</description>
      <author>Jeremy A Intrator, David Vel&#225;zquez, Sicheng Fan, Enrico Mastrobattista, Christine Yu, Smaranda C. Marinescu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3sc06805f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Air Capture and Utilization: Life Cycle Assessment and CO2 Reduction Potential Estimation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3892596/v1</link>
      <description>Alexander Ryota Keeley, Andrew Chapman, Sunbin Yoo, Kenichi Kurita, Junya Kumagai, Dyah Ika Rinawati, Tianhui Fan, Shunsuke Managi, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391749337

                Abstract Reducing the concentration of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) in the atmosphere to combat climate change is a global challenge. Direct air capture (DAC) is a new set of technologies that directly removes CO 2 from the air; therefore, DAC can address emissions from any source. This paper begins by reviewing the literature on negative emission technologies to summarize the most recent technological developments. We then conduct a life cycle assessment on one of the most recently developed technologies, the direct air capture and utilization (DAC-U) system. DAC-U systems, like photovoltaic systems, can be installed in various locations, including homes, offices, and mega-plants, resulting in a highly scalable, on-site system that can be deployed in various ways. Based on the life cycle assessment results, this article presents the CO 2 capture and reduction potential of the DAC-U system, with a focus on installations in households, and examines the willingness to adopt the system in Japan. Our results show that the DAC-U system functions as a negative emission technology and demonstrate the large CO 2 capture and reduction potential of the DAC-U system through household-level installations.</description>
      <author>Alexander Ryota Keeley, Andrew Chapman, Sunbin Yoo, Kenichi Kurita, Junya Kumagai, Dyah Ika Rinawati, Tianhui Fan, Shunsuke Managi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3892596/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free-Standing Single-Atom Catalyst-Based Electrodes for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41918-023-00193-7</link>
      <description>M. Nur Hossain, Lei Zhang, Roberto Neagu, Enoch Rassachack, Electrochemical Energy Reviews. 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391775270

                Abstract Electrochemical CO 2 reduction technology could solve the CO 2 -induced climate warming by electrochemically converting atmospheric CO 2 back into fuel, essentially recycling it and building a low carbon emission economy. However, the electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) poses a significant challenge due to the highly stable and linear CO 2 molecules, in addition to a proton-coupled multi-electron transfer process. Thus, highly active catalysts, placed on activity bolstering materials, and permeable electrodes are crucial for CO 2 RR. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have recently garnered increasing interest in the electrocatalysis community due to their potentially high mass efficiency and cost benefits (every atom is an active center, resulting in nearly 100% utilization) and adjustable selectivity (higher uniformity of the active sites compared to nanoparticles). However, preserving the accessibility and activity of the SACs inside the electrode poses major materials development and electrode design challenges. A conventional layered structure SAC electrode typically consists of a gas diffusion layer (GDL), a microporous layer (MPL) and a SAC catalyst layer (SACCL), fabricated by using a powder bonding process. However, this process usually encounters issues such as delamination and instability of SACs due to the weak binder-catalyst-support interface. Conversely, the free-standing SAC electrode design has the potential to overcome these issues by eliminating the GDL, MPL, and need of a binder, in contrast to the powder bonding process. This work first reviews the latest developments in experimental and modeling studies of powdered SAC electrode by the traditional powder bonding process. Next, it examines the development towards the free-standing SAC electrode for high-performance electrochemical reduction of CO 2 . The synthesis-structure-fabrication-performance relationships of SAC-based materials and associated electrodes are analyzed. Furthermore, the article presents future challenges and perspectives for high-performance SAC electrodes for CO 2 RR. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>M. Nur Hossain, Lei Zhang, Roberto Neagu, Enoch Rassachack</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41918-023-00193-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-Utilization of Wastewater Sludge and Heavy Metals for Single-Atom Electrocatalytic Reduction of Gaseous Co2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4725703</link>
      <description>Baiqin Zhou, Zhida Li, Xinyue He, Chunyue Zhang, Shanshan Pi, Min Yang, Shiguo Zhang, Guifeng Li, Ziqi Zhang, Lu Lu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391826229

                Waste activated sludge (WAS), heavy metals and CO2 are three waste streams that exist in wastewater treatment plants. Synergetic management of these wastes for their valorization and cyclic utilization is rarely reported. Herein, we employed sludge-derived extracellular polymeric substances (EPS) as a matrix to adsorb heavy metal Ni in wastewater, the formed EPS-Ni precursor was directly electrospun and carbonized to fabricate a gas diffusion electrode (GDE) for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (ECO2RR). This approach can atomically disperse Ni to form quantitative Ni single atom catalysts (SACs) exposed at each nanofiber of the GDE. Moreover, abundant N element in the EPS was proved to play a key role in the formation of Nx-Ni (mixture of N3-Ni and N4-Ni) sites that enabled GDE to reduce CO2 to CO with high efficiency. The Ni3+ over prevailingly reported Ni+ in Ni SACs was observed and showed its high ECO2RR catalytic activity. The integration of both catalyst synthesis and electrode fabrication simplified the GDE manufacture process, thus reducing the material cost. The GDE was installed in a membrane electrode assembly (MEA) for direct gaseous CO2 reduction and generated a current up to 50 mA&#8901;cm-1 with a desirable CO selectivity (CO:H2 ratio of ~100 and ~75% Faraday efficiency of CO production) under 2.69 cell voltage. This strategy takes advantage of all waste streams generated on site and can consolidate traditionally separated treatment processes to save costs, produce value-added products and generate carbon benefits during wastewater treatment.</description>
      <author>Baiqin Zhou, Zhida Li, Xinyue He, Chunyue Zhang, Shanshan Pi, Min Yang, Shiguo Zhang, Guifeng Li, Ziqi Zhang, Lu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4725703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering stable Cu+-Cu0 sites and oxygen defects in boron-doped copper oxide for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to C2+ products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149710</link>
      <description>Charles Q. Yang, Ruichen Wang, Yu Chen, Jinhua Xiao, Zhiwei Huang, Bihong Lv, Huawang Zhao, Xiaomin Wu, Guohua Jing, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391848551

                Cu-based catalysts inevitably undergo surface reconstruction during the electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) process. Thus, it is a challenge to construct stable Cu+-Cu0 sites of Cu-based catalysts. In this study, we report a simple and facile engineering strategy for stable Cu+-Cu0 sites and oxygen defects derived from the boron-doped copper oxide (B-CuxO) as an efficient CO2RR electrocatalyst. The 5 % B-CuxO exhibited 48.32 % C2+ products Faraday efficiency (FE) for 12 h at &#8722;1.0 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) in H-cell, which was far superior to CuxO (23.78 %). Combining density functional theory (DFT) and in situ Attenuated Total Reflection Fourier Transform Infrared spectroscopy (in situ ATR-FTIR), a higher electronic depletion on the catalyst surface inhibited the electrons accumulation around Cu sites, thereby maintaining the positive charge and inhibiting the complete reduction of Cu+. Moreover, the high oxygen defects in 5 % B-CuxO could effectively activate CO2 into *CO. We emphasized that Cu+ functioned as the primary active site by facilitating adsorption and dimerization of *CO, whereas Cu0 assisted in optimizing CO2 activation.</description>
      <author>Charles Q. Yang, Ruichen Wang, Yu Chen, Jinhua Xiao, Zhiwei Huang, Bihong Lv, Huawang Zhao, Xiaomin Wu, Guohua Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149710</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence Vision Technology Application of Automatic Steam&amp;amp;Heat Flow Detection Integrated with Carbon Dioxide Reduction and Brackish Water Treatment: A Sustainable Environmental Merit of Carbon Neutrality Through Solar-Driven Distillation Device</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4727259</link>
      <description>Shibiao Fang, Wenrong Tu, Wei Lu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391851772

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Shibiao Fang, Wenrong Tu, Wei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4727259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect and interface engineering for promoting electrocatalytic N-integrated CO2 co-reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64588-7</link>
      <description>Zhichao Wang, Mengfan Wang, Yunfei Huan, Tao Qian, Jie Xiong, Chengtao Yang, Chenglin Yan, Chinese Journal of Catalysis. 57(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391741567

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhichao Wang, Mengfan Wang, Yunfei Huan, Tao Qian, Jie Xiong, Chengtao Yang, Chenglin Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64588-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Correction: Substantial reductions in non-CO2 greenhouse gas emissions reductions implied by IPCC estimates of the remaining carbon budget</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01254-5</link>
      <description>Joeri Rogelj, Robin Lamboll, Communications Earth &amp; Environment. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391809086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joeri Rogelj, Robin Lamboll</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-024-01254-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backbone Engineering of Polymeric Catalysts for High&#8208;Performance CO2 Reduction in Bipolar Membrane Zero&#8208;Gap Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202400414</link>
      <description>Geng Li, Libei Huang, Chengpeng Wei, Hanchen Shen, Yong Liu, Qiang Zhang, Jianjun Su, Yun Mi Song, Weihua Guo, Xiaohu Cao, Ben Zhong Tang, Marc Robert, Ruquan Ye, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391778724

                Bipolar membranes (BPMs) have emerged as a promising solution for mitigating CO2 losses, salt precipitation and high maintenance costs associated with the commonly used anion&#8208;exchange membrane electrode assembly for CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). However, the industrial implementation of BPM&#8208;based zero&#8208;gap electrolyzer is hampered by the poor CO2RR performance, largely attributed to the local acidic environment. Here, we report a backbone engineering strategy to improve the CO2RR performance of molecular catalysts in BPM&#8208;based zero&#8208;gap electrolyzers by covalently grafting cobalt tetraaminophthalocyanine onto a positively charged polyfluorene backbone (PF&#8208;CoTAPc). PF&#8208;CoTAPc shows a high acid tolerance in BPM electrode assembly (BPMEA), achieving a high FE of 82.6% for CO at 100 mA/cm2 and a high CO2 utilization efficiency of 87.8%. Notably, the CO2RR selectivity, carbon utilization efficiency and long&#8208;term stability of PF&#8208;CoTAPc in BPMEA outperform reported BPM systems. We attribute the enhancement to the stable cationic shield in the double layer and suppression of proton migration, ultimately inhibiting the undesired hydrogen evolution and improving the CO2RR selectivity. Techno&#8208;economic analysis shows the least energy consumption (957 kJ/mol) for the PF&#8208;CoTAPc catalyst in BPMEA. Our findings provide a viable strategy for designing efficient CO2RR catalysts in acidic environments.</description>
      <author>Geng Li, Libei Huang, Chengpeng Wei, Hanchen Shen, Yong Liu, Qiang Zhang, Jianjun Su, Yun Mi Song, Weihua Guo, Xiaohu Cao, Ben Zhong Tang, Marc Robert, Ruquan Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202400414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backbone Engineering of Polymeric Catalysts for High&#8208;Performance CO2 Reduction in Bipolar Membrane Zero&#8208;Gap Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202400414</link>
      <description>Geng Li, Libei Huang, Chengpeng Wei, Hanchen Shen, Yong Liu, Qiang Zhang, Jianjun Su, Yun Mi Song, Weihua Guo, Xiaohu Cao, Ben Zhong Tang, Marc Robert, Ruquan Ye, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391778725

                Bipolar membranes (BPMs) have emerged as a promising solution for mitigating CO2 losses, salt precipitation and high maintenance costs associated with the commonly used anion&#8208;exchange membrane electrode assembly for CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). However, the industrial implementation of BPM&#8208;based zero&#8208;gap electrolyzer is hampered by the poor CO2RR performance, largely attributed to the local acidic environment. Here, we report a backbone engineering strategy to improve the CO2RR performance of molecular catalysts in BPM&#8208;based zero&#8208;gap electrolyzers by covalently grafting cobalt tetraaminophthalocyanine onto a positively charged polyfluorene backbone (PF&#8208;CoTAPc). PF&#8208;CoTAPc shows a high acid tolerance in BPM electrode assembly (BPMEA), achieving a high FE of 82.6% for CO at 100 mA/cm2 and a high CO2 utilization efficiency of 87.8%. Notably, the CO2RR selectivity, carbon utilization efficiency and long&#8208;term stability of PF&#8208;CoTAPc in BPMEA outperform reported BPM systems. We attribute the enhancement to the stable cationic shield in the double layer and suppression of proton migration, ultimately inhibiting the undesired hydrogen evolution and improving the CO2RR selectivity. Techno&#8208;economic analysis shows the least energy consumption (957 kJ/mol) for the PF&#8208;CoTAPc catalyst in BPMEA. Our findings provide a viable strategy for designing efficient CO2RR catalysts in acidic environments.</description>
      <author>Geng Li, Libei Huang, Chengpeng Wei, Hanchen Shen, Yong Liu, Qiang Zhang, Jianjun Su, Yun Mi Song, Weihua Guo, Xiaohu Cao, Ben Zhong Tang, Marc Robert, Ruquan Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202400414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-Free Carbon Dot-Microporous Graphitic Carbon Heterojunctions as Photocatalysts for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00007b</link>
      <description>Ana Garc&#237;a-Mulero, Mar&#237;a Cabrero-Antonino, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Ana Primo, Sustainable Energy and Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391790255

                A series of photocatalysts containing various loadings of carbon dots (CD) on microporous graphitic carbons (mpC) was prepared by pyrolysis at 900 &#176;C under inert atmosphere of &#945;-cyclodextrin containing preformed...</description>
      <author>Ana Garc&#237;a-Mulero, Mar&#237;a Cabrero-Antonino, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Ana Primo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00007b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting CuO/Cu(OH)2 for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to HCOOH: The study on pyridine-modified surface active sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.113929</link>
      <description>Ying Zhou, Xiaohui Ren, Xusheng Wang, Jiayao Mao, Haoran Zhang, J. Wang, Yisi Yang, Feng Ma, Huating Liu, Na Feng, Rongsheng Chen, Hongwei Ni, Molecular Catalysis. 556(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391764442

                Copper-based catalysts have been extensively investigated for electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 owing to their unique capabilities. To our notice, organic molecules can be employed as molecular modifiers to tailor the CO2 reduction selectivity of Cu-based catalysts. Herein, three kinds of molecular modifiers, pyridine, triethylamine, and potassium hydroxide have been utilized for fabricating Cu-based electrocatalysts. Experimental investigations reveal that pyridine as molecular modifiers have the ability to alter the surface active sites of the Cu-based catalysts. The modification can facilitate the conversion of CO2 into HCOOH. Notably, the highest Faradaic efficiency achieved in our tests for HCOOH can reach to an impressive value of 80.2 %. Moreover, the catalyst maintains its structure and performance with high stability that exceeding 10 h at a current density of 30 mA cm&#8722;2 (-1.1 V vs. RHE). Based on structural characterization and theoretical calculations, we propose that the pyridine molecule can facilitate CO2 accumulation, and the pyridine modification of the CuO/Cu(OH)2 surface active site can reduce the reaction energy barrier for the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to HCOOH.</description>
      <author>Ying Zhou, Xiaohui Ren, Xusheng Wang, Jiayao Mao, Haoran Zhang, J. Wang, Yisi Yang, Feng Ma, Huating Liu, Na Feng, Rongsheng Chen, Hongwei Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.113929</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
