<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:18:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of transition-metal-cluster-anchored g-C3N4 for the electrochemical catalytic hydrogenation of carbon dioxide to C1 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115076</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Huining Feng, Ruiyang Tang, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406167755

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Huining Feng, Ruiyang Tang, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel solid oxide electrochemical cell for simultaneous processing of carbon dioxide and ethane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2025.207026</link>
      <description>Ahmad Abu Hajer, Andrew Kasick, Jason Trembly, Applied Catalysis O Open. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406211851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ahmad Abu Hajer, Andrew Kasick, Jason Trembly</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2025.207026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction of Methane Replacement with Carbon Dioxide in Hydrate during Injection of Liquid Carbon Dioxide into Formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s0015462824604674</link>
      <description>G. G. Tsypkin, Fluid Dynamics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406236296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. G. Tsypkin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s0015462824604674</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Self-assembly of Nanomaterials in Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/2025.20219</link>
      <description>Yi Lu, Applied and Computational Engineering. 127(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406247492

                The rapid development of nanomaterial self-assembly technology has greatly favored the field of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) and allowed for better control of catalyst structure and composition. Various self-assembly methods, such as DNA-directed assembly, matrix-assisted technology and solvent evaporation, have been used to improve catalytic efficiency and selectivity. Various newly created self-assembled catalysts have also contributed to the development of CO2RR, such as metal oxide catalysts, organic polymers and frameworks, organometallic frameworks and hybrid systems. This paper explored the application of the self-assembled nanocatalysts in CO2RR through a literature review and case studies, with an emphasis on how these methods can reduce CO2 to valuable products such as CO, methane and C2 compounds. The main results highlight the impact of self-assembled structures on improving reaction kinetics and product selectivity. The paper finds that self-assembly technologies and self-assembly nanocatalysts offer potential breakthroughs in improving CO reduction efficiency and contribute to the development of carbon capture and conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Yi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/2025.20219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper/metal oxide heterostructures for electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03057-1</link>
      <description>Jinsheng Yan, Fangmu Wang, Shuai Yin, Jing Zhang, Wei Jiang, Guigao Liu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406307837

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinsheng Yan, Fangmu Wang, Shuai Yin, Jing Zhang, Wei Jiang, Guigao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03057-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper&#8208;Catalysed Electrochemical CO2 Methanation via the Alloying of Single Cobalt Atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417008</link>
      <description>Jiawei Li, Miaojin Wei, Bifa Ji, Sunpei Hu, Jing Xue, Donghao Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yifan Ye, Jilong Xu, Jie Zeng, Ruquan Ye, Yongping Zheng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406319031

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) to methane (CH4) presents a promising solution for mitigating CO2 emissions while producing valuable chemical feedstocks. Although single&#8208;atom catalysts have shown potential in selectively converting CO2 to CH4, their limited active sites often hinder the realization of high current densities, posing a selectivity&#8208;activity dilemma. In this study, we developed a single&#8208;atom cobalt (Co) doped copper catalyst (Co1Cu) that achieved a CH4 Faradaic efficiency exceeding 60% with a partial current density of &#8208;482.7 mA cm&#8208;2. Mechanistic investigations revealed that the incorporation of single Co atoms enhances the activation and dissociation of H2O molecules, thereby lowering the energy barrier for the hydrogenation of *CO intermediates. In situ spectroscopic experiments and density functional theory simulations further demonstrated that the modulation of the *CO adsorption configuration, with stronger bridge&#8208;binding, favours deep reduction to CH4 over the C&#8208;C coupling or CO desorption pathways. Our findings underscore the potential of Co1Cu catalysts in overcoming the selectivity&#8208;activity trade&#8208;off, paving the way for efficient and scalable CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Jiawei Li, Miaojin Wei, Bifa Ji, Sunpei Hu, Jing Xue, Donghao Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yifan Ye, Jilong Xu, Jie Zeng, Ruquan Ye, Yongping Zheng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Cu Active Centers: Local Structure and Mechanism Modulation for Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423092</link>
      <description>Xupeng Qin, Qizheng An, Jing Shang, Xiuxiu Zhang, Qinghua Liu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406247059

                Abstract Reducing carbon dioxide &#65288;CO 2 &#65289;to high&#8208;value products using green renewable energy is a promising approach for addressing energy and greenhouse effect issues. Consequently, electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) technology has become a current research hotspot. Since the discovery of the high activity and selectivity of copper in the CO 2 RR, atomically dispersed Cu catalysts have garnered widespread attention due to their efficient atom utilization, unique electronic structure, and outstanding catalytic performance. However, a great challenge remains in providing rational catalyst design principles to achieve the regulation of product distribution. A clear understanding of catalytic materials and an in&#8208;depth interpretation of the mechanism as well as the elucidation of the design strategy and research progress toward different products are the keys to building the understanding for solving the above problem. Therefore, this review starts with the introduction of advanced characterization techniques to reveal catalyst structure and reaction mechanisms. Then, various optimization strategies and the applications of atomically dispersed Cu catalysts in producing various high&#8208;value targeted products are summarized and discussed. Finally, the perspectives on atomically dispersed Cu catalysts in the CO 2 RR field toward future development are offered.</description>
      <author>Xupeng Qin, Qizheng An, Jing Shang, Xiuxiu Zhang, Qinghua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the Global Focus on Methane Reduction Detract from the Global Attempts to Reduce Carbon Dioxide Emissions?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18520/cs/v127/i3/284-289</link>
      <description>J. R. Bhatt, Current Science. 127(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406177490

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. R. Bhatt</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18520/cs/v127/i3/284-289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partial oxidation of methane based on optimized gas flow with efficient thermal recirculation and carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144732</link>
      <description>Huaming Dai, Chongxue Zou, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406272835

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huaming Dai, Chongxue Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental and Modeling Study for the Solar-Driven CO2 Electrochemical Reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app15020549</link>
      <description>Matteo Agliuzza, Roberto Speranza, Andrea Lamberti, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Adriano Sacco, Applied Sciences. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406171439

                With the rising levels of atmospheric CO2, electrochemistry shows great promise in decarbonizing industrial processes by converting CO2 into valuable products through scalable and sustainable technologies. In this framework, the present study investigates the solar-driven CO2 reduction toward carbon monoxide, achieved by the integration between the electrochemical reactor and dye-sensitized solar cells (DSSCs), both in experimental and modeling perspectives. COMSOL&#174; Multiphysics 6.3 was used to develop a detailed finite element method model of the electrochemical cell integrated with a photovoltaic module, validated with the experimental results that demonstrated a strong correlation. A 2D model was designed, incorporating cathode and anode regions divided by an ion-exchange membrane. The model includes platinum foil and silver nanoparticles as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction and CO2 reduction reaction, respectively. Integration with the fundamental equations of the DSSCs was simulated to analyze the solar-driven CO2 reduction behavior under solar irradiance variations, offering a valuable tool for optimizing operating conditions and predicting the device performance under different environmental conditions. The integrated device successfully produces CO with a faradaic efficiency of 73.85% at a current density of J = 3.35 mA/cm2 under 1 sun illumination, with the result validated and reproduced by the mathematical model. Under reduced illumination conditions of 0.8 and 0.6 suns, faradaic efficiencies of 68.5% and 64.1% were achieved, respectively.</description>
      <author>Matteo Agliuzza, Roberto Speranza, Andrea Lamberti, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Adriano Sacco</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app15020549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Understanding of the Antimony-Bismuth Alloy Promoted Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08653h</link>
      <description>Jiameng Sun, Wanfeng Yang, Bin Yu, Yalong Liu, Yong Zhao, Guanhua Cheng, Zhonghua Zhang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406232920

                Introducing bismuth (Bi) into antimony (Sb) forming Sb-Bi alloys offers a promising way to enhance the electrocatalytic activity of Sb for CO2 reduction to formate. However, there is currently a...</description>
      <author>Jiameng Sun, Wanfeng Yang, Bin Yu, Yalong Liu, Yong Zhao, Guanhua Cheng, Zhonghua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08653h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Metal Oxides Stabilize Cu Oxidation States for Electrocatalytical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402510</link>
      <description>Yu Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yuan Ji, Xu Li, Qiu Jiang, Chuan Xia, Tingting Zheng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406331856

                Modulating the oxidation state of copper (Cu) is crucial for enhancing the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), particularly for facilitating deep reductions to produce methane (CH4) or multi-carbon (C2+) products. However, Cu&#948;+ sites are thermodynamically unstable, fluctuating their oxidation states under reaction conditions, which complicates their functionality. Incorporating interfacial metal oxides has emerged as an effective strategy for stabilizing these oxidation states. This review provides an in-depth examination of the reaction mechanisms occurring at oxide-modified Cu&#948;+ sites, offering a comprehensive understanding of their behavior. We explore how Cu/metal oxide interfaces stabilize Cu oxidation states, showing that oxides-modified Cu catalysts often enhance selectivity for C2+ or CH4 products by stabilizing Cu+ or Cu2+ sites. In addition, we discuss innovative strategies for the rational design of efficient Cu catalytic sites tailored for specific deep CO2RR products. The review concludes with an outlook on current challenges and future directions, offering new insights into the rational design of selective and efficient CO2RR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yu Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yuan Ji, Xu Li, Qiu Jiang, Chuan Xia, Tingting Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to produce the C2+ products: from selectivity to rational catalyst design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04159c</link>
      <description>Xudong Shi, Rui&#8208;tang Guo, Heng-fei Cui, Cong Liu, Weiguo Pan, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406184123

                Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 (eCO2RR) into valuable multi-carbon (C2+) products is an effective strategy for combating climate change and mitigating energy crises. The high energy density and diverse applications of...</description>
      <author>Xudong Shi, Rui&#8208;tang Guo, Heng-fei Cui, Cong Liu, Weiguo Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04159c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Reductions Utilising Self-Stressing Steel Fibre Reinforced Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-69626-8_66</link>
      <description>Martins Suta, L&#299;ga Gaile, Rolands Cepur&#299;tis, Lecture notes in civil engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406177653

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Martins Suta, L&#299;ga Gaile, Rolands Cepur&#299;tis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-69626-8_66</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposition of Bismuth Dendrites on Oxide-Derived Copper Foam Enhancing Electrochemical CO2 Reduction to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010052</link>
      <description>Jialin Xu, Li Lv, Chunlai Wang, Yun Liang, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406174685

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to formate offers a promising pathway to mitigate the energy crisis and realize carbon neutrality. Bismuth (Bi), as a metal catalyst for the CO2RR, is considered to have great potential in producing formate, yet hindered in low current density and selectivity. Herein, we constructed an oxide-derived copper foam substrate (OD-Cu) to improve the electrocatalytic properties of Bi dendrites loaded on its surface. Bi electrodeposited on the OD-Cu (Bi/OD-Cu) grows as pinecone-like dendrites, exhibiting a high formate faradaic efficiency (FEformate) of 97.2% and a formate partial current density of ~24 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;0.97 V vs. RHE (reversible hydrogen electrode) in an H-cell. Notably, the Bi/OD-Cu electrode demonstrates an FEformate of 95.8% at &#8722;0.97 V vs. RHE and a total current density close to 90 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;1.17 V vs. RHE in a neutral flow cell. The experimental studies reveal that the remarkable CO2RR performance of the Bi/OD-Cu results from the electron transfer from Cu to Bi, which optimizes adsorption of the CO2&#8226;&#8722; and boosts reaction kinetics. This study emphasizes the crucial role of substrate engineering strategies in enhancing catalytic activity and shows the possibility for a porous metal electrode in advancing the industrialization of formate production.</description>
      <author>Jialin Xu, Li Lv, Chunlai Wang, Yun Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances on Carbon Capture and Electrochemical CO2 Reduction with Amphiphile Surfactants and Polymers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115394</link>
      <description>Fentahun Wondu Dagnaw, Ruiqi Li, Yilin Xie, Qing&#8208;Xiao Tong, Jing&#8208;Xin Jian, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406213677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fentahun Wondu Dagnaw, Ruiqi Li, Yilin Xie, Qing&#8208;Xiao Tong, Jing&#8208;Xin Jian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare-earth neodymium single atom catalyst for efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2025.115199</link>
      <description>Tonglin Yang, Fangqi Yang, Fan Yang, Yang Ding, Fa Cao, Quan Zhang, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406269651

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tonglin Yang, Fangqi Yang, Fan Yang, Yang Ding, Fa Cao, Quan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2025.115199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving environmental sustainability in the EU specialized milk farms: Strategic CO2 emission reductions for a greener future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/00307270241300340</link>
      <description>B&#252;lent M&#236;ran, Emre Burcu &#214;zkaraova G&#252;ng&#246;r, Outlook on Agriculture. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406217450

                This study assesses the environmental efficiences of specialized milk farms across the European Union (EU) countries, with a focus on CO2 emissions reduction. Using Tone's model under the assumption of generalized returns to scale, the analysis reveals an average environmental efficiency score of 0.599. Countries like Malta, Ireland, Italy, and the Netherlands have achieved full environmental efficiency, exemplifying optimal environmental performance. In contrast, countries such as Slovakia and Estonia demonstrate lower efficiency, suggesting significant opportunities for emission reductions. Czechia, Bulgaria, and Estonia show environmental efficiency levels ranging from 0.24 to 0.30. In contrast, Finland, Portugal, Romania, Lithuania, Croatia, Hungary, Latvia, and Slovenia have achieved efficiency levels that fall between the average of 0.30 and a value of 0.599. The study highlights that higher populated and higher-income countries tend to exhibit higher environmental efficiency. The findings suggest that to improve environmental efficiency, milk production should be concentrated in larger farms, with an emphasis on sustainable agricultural practices, advanced technologies, and efficient resource management. Furthermore, the study recommends targeted policies and strategies to enhance environmental efficiency, particularly in countries with lower population densities and incomes. These strategies include transitioning to pasture-grazing systems, improving nitrogen use efficiency, enhancing animal welfare, and investing in advanced farming technologies. The study underscores the importance of integrating environmental considerations into broader agricultural policies to achieve sustainability in the specialized milk farms of the EU.</description>
      <author>B&#252;lent M&#236;ran, Emre Burcu &#214;zkaraova G&#252;ng&#246;r</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/00307270241300340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Product Selectivity of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction at Copper-Tin Composite Oxide Nanofibers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178574</link>
      <description>Subin Choi, Taehui Kwon, Youngmi Lee, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406185994

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subin Choi, Taehui Kwon, Youngmi Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DISPLACE Post-Combustion Carbon Capture Technology Integration in a Steel Plant for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144739</link>
      <description>Nicola Zecca, Leonie L&#252;cking, Dora-Andreea Chis&#259;li&#539;&#259;, Jurriaan Boon, H.A.J. van Dijk, Johannis A.Z. Pieterse, Antonio Giuffrida, Giampaolo Manzolini, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406240280

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicola Zecca, Leonie L&#252;cking, Dora-Andreea Chis&#259;li&#539;&#259;, Jurriaan Boon, H.A.J. van Dijk, Johannis A.Z. Pieterse, Antonio Giuffrida, Giampaolo Manzolini</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encapsulating perovskite quantum dots into 3D COF for visible light-driven CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2300-8</link>
      <description>Xinxin Wang, Yucheng Jin, Xiya Yang, Qingyu Luan, Tianyu Wang, Dongdong Qi, Kang Wang, Jianzhuang Jiang, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406198000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinxin Wang, Yucheng Jin, Xiya Yang, Qingyu Luan, Tianyu Wang, Dongdong Qi, Kang Wang, Jianzhuang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2300-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabricating an ohmic junction of Ag/CdS for highly efficient multi-electron reduction of CO2 to CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105807</link>
      <description>Chaoqiang Li, Xiangyu Xu, Aizhong Jia, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406282833

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoqiang Li, Xiangyu Xu, Aizhong Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the role of oxygen vacancies in CO2 photothermal catalytic reduction to methanol over 2D Bi2WO6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3199-9</link>
      <description>Hongxia Fan, Tao Liu, Liang-Fen Zhen, Antony Rajendran, Jie Feng, Wenying Li, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406320460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongxia Fan, Tao Liu, Liang-Fen Zhen, Antony Rajendran, Jie Feng, Wenying Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3199-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-period Deployment of Electrochemical CO2-to-CO Reduction Technology Considering Time Varying Uncertainties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-024-00373-1</link>
      <description>W. Chun, Su Hyeon Lee, Kosan Roh, Seongmin Heo, Korean Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406198333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W. Chun, Su Hyeon Lee, Kosan Roh, Seongmin Heo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-024-00373-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic electrolyte cations promote non-aqueous CO2 reduction by mediating interfacial electric fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01278-2</link>
      <description>Jon-Marc McGregor, Jay T. Bender, Amanda Schramm Petersen, Louise M. Ca&#241;ada, Jan Rossmeisl, Joan F. Brennecke, Joaquin Resasco, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406231824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jon-Marc McGregor, Jay T. Bender, Amanda Schramm Petersen, Louise M. Ca&#241;ada, Jan Rossmeisl, Joan F. Brennecke, Joaquin Resasco</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01278-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Digital Economy, R&amp;amp;D Investments, and CO2 Emissions: Unraveling Reduction Potentials in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/rsee2010004</link>
      <description>Yuexin Zhao, Peng Wang, Regional science and environmental economics. 2(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406324801

                This study explores the relationships between the digital economy, R&amp;D investment, and carbon emissions, as well as the mediating role of financial technology (fintech). Despite a growing body of research, the impact of the digital economy on carbon emissions remains contested, partly due to the limited scope and inconsistent measures in existing studies. Additionally, while R&amp;D is a pivotal driver of modern development, its potential quadratic effects on carbon emissions in China remain unexplored. By employing a comprehensive Digital Economy Index and analyzing panel data from 2011 to 2020 across Chinese regions, this study provides new insights into how digitalization and innovation influence carbon emissions. The findings reveal a positive linear correlation between the digital economy and CO2 emissions over the last decade. Moreover, R&amp;D investments exhibit an inverse U-shaped relationship with emissions, acting as an effective factor in reducing CO2 emissions. Notably, the turning point of this relationship occurs in Quadrant I, where most regions are clustered, indicating substantial efficiency gains from early-stage R&amp;D investments and their significant potential to enhance sustainable development. Furthermore, fintech emerges as a significant mediator in the R&amp;D&#8211;emissions dynamic, underscoring its critical role in this context.</description>
      <author>Yuexin Zhao, Peng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/rsee2010004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CO2 Reduction via Cu Nanocrystals Decorated Perovskite as Cathode for Solid Oxide Electrolysis Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.01.041</link>
      <description>Yan Lin, Min Xu, Xi Chen, Shuo Chen, Xiang Li, Wenle Yan, Ruixue Zhou, Di Chen, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406194311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Lin, Min Xu, Xi Chen, Shuo Chen, Xiang Li, Wenle Yan, Ruixue Zhou, Di Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.01.041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolating and stabilizing active copper species in layered double hydroxide to enhance electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115959</link>
      <description>Mingzhu Yue, Wenfu Xie, Ziyi Zhong, Min Li, Tianyu Zhang, Mingfei Shao, Hao Li, Qiang Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406309936

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingzhu Yue, Wenfu Xie, Ziyi Zhong, Min Li, Tianyu Zhang, Mingfei Shao, Hao Li, Qiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the cobalt phthalocyanine molecules by introducing adjacent cubic molybdenum carbide nanoparticles for accelerated proton transfer towards efficient CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwaf010</link>
      <description>Yunxiang Lin, Shaocong Wang, Hengjie Liu, Xue Liu, Li Yang, Xiaozhi Su, Lei Shan, Xiyu Li, Li Song, National Science Review. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406275274

                Abstract Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an important application that can considerably mitigate environmental and energy crises. However, the slow proton-coupled electron transfer process continues to limit overall catalytic performance. Fine-tuning the reaction microenvironment by accurately constructing the local structure of catalysts provides a novel approach to enhancing reaction kinetics. Here, cubic-phase &#945;-MoC1&#8722;x nanoparticles were incorporated into a carbon matrix and coupled with cobalt phthalocyanine molecules (&#945;-MoC1&#8722;x&#8211;CoPc@C) for the co-reduction of CO2 and H2O, achieving an impressive Faradaic efficiency for CO close to 100%. Through a combination of in-situ spectroscopies, electrochemical measurements, and theoretical simulations, it is demonstrated that &#945;-MoC1&#8722;x nanoparticles and CoPc molecules with the optimized local configuration serve as the active centers for H2O activation and CO2 reduction, respectively. The interfacial water molecules were rearranged, forming a dense hydrogen bond network on the catalyst surface. This optimized microenvironment at the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface synergistically enhanced water dissociation, accelerated proton transfer, and improved the overall performance of CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Yunxiang Lin, Shaocong Wang, Hengjie Liu, Xue Liu, Li Yang, Xiaozhi Su, Lei Shan, Xiyu Li, Li Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwaf010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the co-utilization of methanol and CO2 into 1-butanol by equipping synergistic reductive glycine pathway in Butyribacterium methylotrophicum</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2025.132071</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Shengji Li, Chenxi Ma, Rui Zhang, Jialun Qin, Kequan Chen, Xin Wang, Bioresource Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406308731

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Shengji Li, Chenxi Ma, Rui Zhang, Jialun Qin, Kequan Chen, Xin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2025.132071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting US data center CO2 emissions using AI models: emissions reduction strategies and policy recommendations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/frsus.2024.1507030</link>
      <description>Rohan Jha, Rishabh Jha, Mazhar Islam, Frontiers in Sustainability. 5(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406228644

                Data centers are poised for unprecedented growth due to a revolution in Artificial Intelligence (AI), rise in cryptocurrency mining, and increasing cloud demand for data storage. A sizable portion of the data centers&#8217; growth will occur in the US, requiring a tremendous amount of power. Our hypothesis is that the expansion of data centers will contribute to an increase in US CO 2 emissions. To estimate CO 2 emissions, we applied three forecasted power demands for data centers and applied 56 NREL (National Renewable Energy Laboratory) power mixes and policy scenario cases using 11 AI models. Among these, the linear regression model yielded the most accurate predictions with the highest R-square. We found that overall CO 2 emissions in the US could increase up to 0.4&#8211;1.9% due to expansion of data centers by 2030. This increase represents ~3&#8211;14% of CO 2 emissions from the US power sector by 2030. Using the state-level power mix forecasts for 2030 among increasing CO 2 emission scenarios, we predict that Virginia&#8217;s power mix will maintain emissions in line with the US average, while the Texas, Illinois, and Washington&#8217;s power mix are expected to reduce emissions due to greater renewables in their power mix in 2030. However, Illinois and Washington may face challenges due to their limited power resource availability. In contrast, New York and California&#8217;s power mix may increase CO 2 emissions due to higher natural gas in their power mix in 2030. The highest variability in data center CO 2 emissions stems from AI-driven demand and improvements in data center efficiency and is followed by the power mix. To reduce CO 2 emissions from data centers, we offer pathways such as reducing power consumption, improving power mix with renewable sources, and using hydrogen in power plants. We propose focusing on New Mexico and Colorado for data centers to minimize CO 2 emissions. Finally, we highlight a set of federal policies supplemented by states to facilitate CO 2 emission reductions across energy, emissions, waste, R&amp;amp;D, and grid infrastructure.</description>
      <author>Rohan Jha, Rishabh Jha, Mazhar Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/frsus.2024.1507030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning covalent bonding of single transition metal atom doped in S vacant MoS2 for catalytic CO2 reduction reaction product selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162339</link>
      <description>Poobodin Mano, Thanadol Jitwatanasirikul, Thantip Roongcharoen, Kaito Takahashi, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;, Applied Surface Science. 688(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406168446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Poobodin Mano, Thanadol Jitwatanasirikul, Thantip Roongcharoen, Kaito Takahashi, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Ni-Co synergy in bifunctional hydroxide cocatalysts for better cooperation of CO2 reduction and H2O oxidation in 2D S-scheme photosynthetic systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60174-9</link>
      <description>Lingxuan Hu, Yan Zhang, Qian Lin, Fengying Cao, Weihao Mo, Shuxian Zhong, Hongjun Lin, Liyan Xie, Leihong Zhao, Song Bai, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 68(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406199753

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingxuan Hu, Yan Zhang, Qian Lin, Fengying Cao, Weihao Mo, Shuxian Zhong, Hongjun Lin, Liyan Xie, Leihong Zhao, Song Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60174-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Reduction with High Bulk Turnover Numbers at Small Overpotentials by a fac-Mn(bpy)(CO)3L Complex with a Redox-Active, Electron Reservoir Ligand</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5784204/v1</link>
      <description>Andy G&#225;lvez-Rodr&#237;guez, Octavio Martinez-Perez, Steven H. Bergens, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406162961

                Abstract The electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CRR) is required to convert CO2 into useful commodity chemicals with renewable energy thereby reducing global greenhouse gas emissions. We report significantly enhanced CRR activity by incorporating the s-donating, e- reservoir ligand Imdye (1-imidazole-2,4,6-tri(carbazol-9-yl)-3,5-dicyanobenzene) within the complex fac-[MnI(bpy)(CO)3(Imdye)]+ (bpy = 2,2'-bipyridine). The reduction potentials of Imdye, MnI/0, and CO2 to CO are close, allowing the active catalyst [Mn0(bpy)(CO)2(Imdye-)]- to provide 2e- to CO2 at small overpotentials. This system reduces CO2 to CO with bulk turnover numbers up to 830 very near the CRR reduction potential. This CRR activity arose from Imdye promoting the CRR at small overpotentials, and from utilizing the electrooxidation of CH3OH/H2O to CO2, 6H+ and 6e- at the Pt counter electrode, neutralizing pH changes from the CRR. These strategies will apply to most CRR electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Andy G&#225;lvez-Rodr&#237;guez, Octavio Martinez-Perez, Steven H. Bergens</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5784204/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide (CO2 ) emissions and mitigation efforts based on Bogor City's green open space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33751/injast.v5i2.8513</link>
      <description>Annisa Choerinita Kusuma Wardhani, Rita Retnowati, Yossa Istiadi, Indonesian Journal of Applied Environmental Studies. 5(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406276672

                One of the risks associated with climate change is carbon dioxide (CO2) emission, which can negatively affect human health and the ecosystem. The CO2 emission can lead to a decline in urban area quality that surpasses the environment's carrying capacity. This research aimed to investigate the relationship between CO2 Emissions from Transportation (X1), Household (X2), and Business Sector (X3) with the CO2 reduction of green open space (Y). The hypothesis is that there is a negative correlation between CO2 emissions from transportation, households, and businesses and CO2 reduction from green open spaces. A quantitative research design was adopted using the Slovin formula and cluster random sampling. The Normality and Homogeneity Tests are used to analyze research data. The study yielded the following results: first, the coefficient of determination (r2) = 0.003 indicates a relationship between CO2 emissions from transportation with CO2 reduction from green open space, with a 0.3% contribution. The second finding is that there is a 0.1% contribution from CO2 reduction from green open space to the CO2 emissions of households, as indicated by the coefficient of determination (r2) = 0.001. Third, a correlation of 0.1% between CO2 reduction from green open space and CO2 emissions from the Business Sector is indicated by the coefficient of determination (r2) = 0.001. Thus, using the regression equation Y = 2320.432 &#8211; 0.16X1 &#8211; 0,25 X2 &#8211; 0,007 X3, there is an overall significant relationship between CO2 emissions from transportation, CO2 emissions from households, and CO2 emissions from the business sector with the reduction of CO2 from green open space.</description>
      <author>Annisa Choerinita Kusuma Wardhani, Rita Retnowati, Yossa Istiadi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33751/injast.v5i2.8513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Interconnections Among Environmental Degradation, Energy Consumption, Information and Communication Technology, and Total Factor Productivity in Iran</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5829/ijee.2025.16.03.12</link>
      <description>, Iranica Journal of Energy and Environment. 16(03)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406367433

                Information and Communication Technology (ICT) is recognized as a critical driver of economic development in the modern era, significantly enhancing the productivity of production factors. However, the widespread adoption of ICT, particularly in countries reliant on fossil fuels, may contribute to increased greenhouse gas emissions, including carbon dioxide (CO2). So, this study investigates the interconnections among ICT, CO2, renewable energy, and Total Factor Productivity (TFP) in Iran. This descriptive-analytical and applied study used time series data from the World Bank and Iran Statistics Center from 2000 to 2023. This study, the Autoregressive Distributed Lag (ARDL) model to evaluate the long-term and short-term dynamic, unit root tests and diagnostic tests CUSUM and CUSUMQ and Canonical Co-Integrating Regression (CCR) Dynamic least squares (DOLS), and fully modified least squares (FMOLS) have been used to validate the results of ADRL estimates. The results of the ARDL estimation method showed that in the long run, TFP and economic growth on carbon dioxide had a coefficient of 0.07 and 0.14, respectively. Renewable energy consumption with a coefficient of -0.0808 had a significant negative role in reducing carbon dioxide. The coefficient of -0.286 obtained for the ICT variable at 95% indicates a reduction in carbon dioxide in parallel with the development of ICT. CUSUM and CUSUMQ confirmed the stability of the parameters, and CCR, DOLS, and FMOLS regressions confirmed the results of the ADRL model. The study recommends adopting green technologies and effective energy policies to balance productivity gains with environmental protection.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5829/ijee.2025.16.03.12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper&#8208;Catalysed Electrochemical CO2 Methanation via the Alloying of Single Cobalt Atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417008</link>
      <description>Jiawei Li, Miaojin Wei, Bifa Ji, Sunpei Hu, Jing Xue, Donghao Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yifan Ye, Jilong Xu, Jie Zeng, Ruquan Ye, Yongping Zheng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406339255

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) to methane (CH4) presents a promising solution for mitigating CO2 emissions while producing valuable chemical feedstocks. Although single&#8208;atom catalysts have shown potential in selectively converting CO2 to CH4, their limited active sites often hinder the realization of high current densities, posing a selectivity&#8208;activity dilemma. In this study, we developed a single&#8208;atom cobalt (Co) doped copper catalyst (Co1Cu) that achieved a CH4 Faradaic efficiency exceeding 60% with a partial current density of &#8208;482.7 mA cm&#8208;2. Mechanistic investigations revealed that the incorporation of single Co atoms enhances the activation and dissociation of H2O molecules, thereby lowering the energy barrier for the hydrogenation of *CO intermediates. In situ spectroscopic experiments and density functional theory simulations further demonstrated that the modulation of the *CO adsorption configuration, with stronger bridge&#8208;binding, favours deep reduction to CH4 over the C&#8208;C coupling or CO desorption pathways. Our findings underscore the potential of Co1Cu catalysts in overcoming the selectivity&#8208;activity trade&#8208;off, paving the way for efficient and scalable CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Jiawei Li, Miaojin Wei, Bifa Ji, Sunpei Hu, Jing Xue, Donghao Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yifan Ye, Jilong Xu, Jie Zeng, Ruquan Ye, Yongping Zheng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Methanol on Pt(111) Modified with a Pd Monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05442</link>
      <description>Aleksandra Wawrzyniak, Marc T. M. Koper, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406259351

                Electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO2) conversion to value-added, highly reduced chemicals such as methanol (CH3OH) is a promising possibility for producing renewable fuel and simultaneous CO2 recycling. However, this process remains a challenge, with only a few selective electrocatalysts known. Here, we present a study of a palladium monolayer on a platinum (111) single crystal (PdML/Pt(111)) as an electrocatalyst for CO2 conversion to CH3OH. A custom-made setup was employed in order to detect and quantify gaseous and liquid CO2 reduction products in sufficient concentrations despite the limitations of working with a single-crystalline electrode. Under ambient reaction conditions, a Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 1.5% at &#8722;0.9 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) was obtained while using CO2 as the reactant. Other reaction intermediates, carbon monoxide (CO) and formaldehyde (HCHO) were subsequently used as reactants, leading to FEs of 1.8 and 2.5%, respectively, whereas formic acid is not reduced. The corresponding mechanism concluded from our work is compared to the literature. The electrocatalyst introduced here, with a highly well-defined structure for CO2 conversion to CH3OH, opens up possibilities for further catalytic explorations.</description>
      <author>Aleksandra Wawrzyniak, Marc T. M. Koper</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abundant and active acetogens enhance the carbon dioxide sink of Blue Carbon ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.07.631696</link>
      <description>Karen Rodriguez Martinez, Francesco Ricci, Gaofeng Ni, Naima Iram, Robin Palfreyman, R. Axay&#225;catl Gonz&#225;lez-Garc&#237;a, James K. Heffernan, Chris Greening, Mar&#237;a Fernanda Adame, Esteban Marcellin, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406181238

                Blue Carbon ecosystems, which include all tidal wetlands, mitigate climate change by capturing and storing carbon dioxide (CO2) from the atmosphere. Most carbon fixation in these systems is thought to be driven by plant and microbial photosynthesis, whereas chemosynthetic processes are assumed to play a minor role. However, these ecosystems often contain anoxic environments ideal for chemosynthetic microbes such as acetogens. Here, we show that acetogens are abundant and active mediators of carbon sequestration in tidal wetland soils by pairing gene- and genome-resolved metagenomic analysis with isolation and analysis of gas-fermenting acetogens in bioreactors. Metagenomic profiling revealed that diverse microbes can mediate carbon fixation, primarily through the Calvin-Benson-Bassham cycle and Wood-Ljungdahl pathways. These include various bacteria and archaea capable of reductive acetogenesis. On this basis, we grew bacterial enrichment cultures from tidal wetland soils using the gases hydrogen and CO2 as the sole energy and carbon sources. Bioreactor analysis revealed that these enrichments are dominated by clostridial acetogens that grow rapidly by converting CO2 into acetate and other products. Collectively, these results reveal Blue Carbon ecosystems harbour communities that can exclusively subsist by using CO2 as their sole electron acceptor and for carbon fixation, thereby providing evidence of a novel carbon sink pathway within these ecosystems beyond the known mechanisms of photosynthetic carbon fixation and soil sequestration. Additionally, the discovery and isolation of these chemosynthetic communities provide opportunities for developing further mechanisms of CO2 removal through industrial gas fermentation.</description>
      <author>Karen Rodriguez Martinez, Francesco Ricci, Gaofeng Ni, Naima Iram, Robin Palfreyman, R. Axay&#225;catl Gonz&#225;lez-Garc&#237;a, James K. Heffernan, Chris Greening, Mar&#237;a Fernanda Adame, Esteban Marcellin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.07.631696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface modification of sputtered, thin film silver electrodes for sustainable and highly efficient electroreduction of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-q7lwd-v4</link>
      <description>Domenico Grammatico, Janine Lichtenberger, Christian M. Pichler, Matthias Kogler, Th&#233;odoros Dimopoulos, H. Kern, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406219302

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) is one of the most promising ways to valorise CO2 as a source of carbon. The development of novel, efficient and scalable catalysts for CO2 electroreduction in electrolysers is still a big challenge. This paper reports on the preparation of sustainable, efficient, and stable gas diffusion electrodes utilizing silver as catalyst for the CO2 electroreduction to CO. The catalyst is prepared by sputter deposition and subsequent surface modification by oxygen plasma. It is uniformly deposited as a thin layer on the hydrophobic porous structure of polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE), minimizing the amount of silver required and simultaneously addressing the problem of substrate flooding by the electrolyte. This leads to a synergetic, beneficial impact on the CO2RR, as evaluated in a flow reactor with gas-fed CO2. The optimized gas diffusion electrodes, with high porosity and electrochemical surface area, show high activity at low overpotentials, faradaic efficiency for CO over 90% and stability tested over periods up to 24 hours. This approach allows for high performance using a minimal amount of metal, while exploiting the processing advantages of sputtering as an industrial state-of-the-art, high-throughput technique.</description>
      <author>Domenico Grammatico, Janine Lichtenberger, Christian M. Pichler, Matthias Kogler, Th&#233;odoros Dimopoulos, H. Kern</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-q7lwd-v4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contrasting Summertime Trends in Vehicle Combustion Efficiency in Los Angeles, CA and Salt Lake City, UT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c11701</link>
      <description>Cindy C. Ya&#241;ez, Ryan Bares, C. I. Czimczik, John C. Lin, Jiachen Zhang, S. E. Bush, F. M. Hopkins, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406166434

                Policy interventions and technological advances are mitigating emissions of air pollutants from motor vehicles. As a result, vehicle fleets are expected to progressively combust fuel more efficiently, with a declining ratio of carbon monoxide to carbon dioxide (CO/CO2) in their emissions. We assess trends in traffic combustion efficiency in Los Angeles (LA) and Salt Lake City (SLC) by measuring changes in summertime on-road CO/CO2 between 2013 and 2021 using mobile observations. Our data show a reduction in CO/CO2 in LA, indicating an improvement in combustion efficiency that likely resulted from stringent regulation of CO emissions. In contrast, we observed an increase in CO/CO2 values in SLC. While slower progress in SLC compared to LA may be partially due to a later adoption of vehicle emission regulations in Utah compared to California, differing driving conditions and fleet composition may also be playing a role. This is evidenced by increased CO/CO2 in LA during the COVID-19 pandemic, which led to faster driving speeds and changes to the fleet composition. Our results demonstrate the success of California's CO-reducing policy interventions and illustrate the impacts of traffic characteristics on vehicle combustion efficiency and air pollutant emissions.</description>
      <author>Cindy C. Ya&#241;ez, Ryan Bares, C. I. Czimczik, John C. Lin, Jiachen Zhang, S. E. Bush, F. M. Hopkins</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c11701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of in-barrel CO2 saturation level on morphology and structure development of milk protein extrudates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ijfood/vvae095</link>
      <description>Bindvi Arora, Syed S. H. Rizvi, International Journal of Food Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406232506

                Abstract The combined effect of the operating pressure and supercritical carbon dioxide (SC-CO2) injection level on structure development during puffing of milk protein concentrate by supercritical fluid extrusion was studied. The extrudates were analyzed using scanning electron microscopy, texture analyzer, and electrophoresis. Extrudates obtained with SC-CO2 injection rate corresponding to the equilibrium solubility demonstrated a highly porous structure (mean pore size &amp;lt; 500 &#956;m, mean pore wall thickness &amp;lt; 40 &#956;m). In contrast, both undersaturated and oversaturated conditions formed extrudates having fewer large irregular pores (mean pore size &amp;gt; 700 &#956;m, mean pore wall thickness &amp;gt; 80 &#956;m). Reduction in interfacial tension with increasing CO2 concentration favored homogeneous nucleation up to saturation CO2 levels, resulting in uniformly porous extrudates. SC-CO2 input rate above the saturation levels resulted in undissolved gas vacuoles in the melt, allowing dissolved CO2 to diffuse into them at die exit, favoring coalescence. These findings could have significant utility in designing novel milk protein-based puffed products of predefined structural and physicochemical properties.</description>
      <author>Bindvi Arora, Syed S. H. Rizvi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ijfood/vvae095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential and costs required for methane removal to compete with BECCS as a mitigation option</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ada813</link>
      <description>Yann Gaucher, Katsumasa Tanaka, Daniel Johansson, Olivi&#233;r Boucher, Philippe Ciais, Environmental Research Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406206510

                Abstract Methane is the second most important anthropogenic greenhouse gas causing warming after carbon dioxide, and the emission reductions potentials are known to be limited due to the difficulty of abating agricultural methane. We explore in this study the emerging option of atmospheric methane removal (MR) that could complement carbon dioxide removal (CDR) in mitigation pathways. MR is technologically very challenging and potentially very expensive, so the main question is at which cost per ton of methane removed is MR more cost effective than CDR. To address this question, we use an intertemporal optimization climate-GHG-energy model to evaluate the MR cost and removal potential thresholds that would allow us to meet a given climate target with the same or a lower abatement cost and allowing for equal or higher gross CO2 emissions than if CDR through BECCS were an option. We also compare the effects of MR and CDR on the cost-effective mitigation pathways achieving four different climate targets. Using the ACC2-GET integrated carbon cycle, atmospheric chemistry, climate and energy system model, we consider a generic MR technology characterized by a given unit cost and a maximal removal potential. We show that to totally replace bioenergy based CDR with MR, the MR potential should reach at least 180 to 290 MtCH4 per year, i.e., between 50% and 90% of current anthropogenic methane emissions, with maximum unit cost between 11,000 and 69,000 $/tCH4, depending on the climate target. Finally, we found that replacing CDR by MR reshapes the intergenerational distribution of climate mitigation efforts by delaying further the mitigation burden.</description>
      <author>Yann Gaucher, Katsumasa Tanaka, Daniel Johansson, Olivi&#233;r Boucher, Philippe Ciais</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ada813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Manufacturing Practices for Zero-Emission Vehicles: Analyzing the Role of Predictive Analytics in Achieving Carbon Neutrality</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5024423</link>
      <description>Shakir Syed, SSRN Electronic Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406208051

                Reducing production-related carbon dioxide emissions is a crucial prerequisite for achieving the European goal of carbon neutrality by 2050. This study provides an overview of possible emissions by using a current vehicle and the corresponding expressions, as well as the options that need to be addressed. Since industry contributes significantly to global greenhouse gas emissions, the effect of manufacturing emissions on all stages of a vehicle's lifecycle is noticeable. Predictive maintenance is called "new oil," and the application of advanced analytics is considered the driving source of a fundamental change at the production site. In addition to the early prediction of defects and the reduction of downtime and lower repair costs, one possible application is dealing with increased demand for zero-emission vehicle production to gain carbon neutrality in manufacturing. This essay aims to address sustainable manufacturing practices regarding zero-emission vehicles. The focus of the research is placed on the car industry, but the presented research could be utilized as the basis of application in any common car production. Since vehicle manufacturing is more pollution-inclined than the vehicle's use, it is essential to find an energy source that will sustain this industry's growth and, at the same time, respect the environment and keep pollutants practically zero. This is why, in this essay, electric-powered vehicles are outlined to substitute cars powered by conventional internal combustion drives, as they do not consume liquids and do not emit CO2 or other harmful gases. In addition to the benefits in terms of the environment, they are cleaner and generally healthier for the people who use them and eco-friendly, which is the goal of the project from every perspective of modern society. The application of advanced analytics is suitable not merely for energy development or sustainability; precisely, the intelligence could also be used in the production of systems. However, if power is a kind of energy, this paper will focus on its application in aspects of car industry production. The overall aim can be defined as an analysis of the benefits and downsides of using predictive analytics to improve the environmental aspects of the production domain by providing cleaner cars. The importance of corresponding illustrations is emphasized, and the essay ends with the connection between the importance of the industry's contribution from an environmental point of view and the necessity for sustainability aspects.</description>
      <author>Shakir Syed</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5024423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Effects of Salinity, Redox State, Soil Type, and Colloidal Size Fractionation on Greenhouse Gas Production in Coastal Wetland Soils</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.170158332.29336750/v2</link>
      <description>Nicholas Ward, Madison Bowe, Katherine A. Muller, Xingyuan Chen, Qian Zhao, Rosalie Chu, Zezhen Cheng, Thomas Wietsma, Ravi Kukkadapu, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406255924

                Coastal wetlands, including freshwater systems near large lakes, rapidly bury carbon, but less is known about how they transport carbon either to marine and lake environments or to the atmosphere as greenhouse gases (GHGs) such as carbon dioxide and methane. This study examines how GHG production and organic matter (OM) mobility in coastal wetland soils vary with the availability of oxygen and other terminal electron acceptors. We also evaluated how OM and redox-sensitive species varied across different size fractions: particulates (0.45&#8211;1&#956;m), fine colloids (0.1&#8211;0.45&#956;m), and nano particulates plus truly soluble (&lt;0.1&#956;m; NP+S) during 21-day aerobic and anaerobic slurry incubations. Soils were collected from the center of a freshwater coastal wetland (FW-C) in Lake Erie, the upland-wetland edge of the same wetland (FW-E), and the center of a saline coastal wetland (SW-C) in the Pacific Northwest, USA. Anaerobic methane production for FW-E soils were 47 and 27,537 times greater than FW-C and SW-C soils, respectively. High Fe2+ and dissolved sulfate concentrations in FW-C and SW-C soils suggest that iron and/or sulfate reduction inhibited methanogenesis. Aerobic CO2 production was highest for both freshwater soils, which had a higher proportion of OM in the NP+S fraction (64&#177;28% and 70&#177;10% for FW-C and FW-E, respectively) and organic C:N ratios reflective of microbial detritus (5.3&#177;5.3 and 5.3&#177;7.0 for FW-E and FW-C, respectively) compared to SW-C, which had a higher fraction of particulate (58&#177;9%) and fine colloidal (19&#177;7%) OM and organic C:N ratios reflective of vegetation detritus (11.4 &#177; 1.7). The variability in GHG production and shifts in OM size fractionation and composition observed across freshwater and saline soils collected within individual and across different sites reinforce the high spatial variability in the processes controlling OM stability, mobility, and bioavailability in coastal wetland soils.</description>
      <author>Nicholas Ward, Madison Bowe, Katherine A. Muller, Xingyuan Chen, Qian Zhao, Rosalie Chu, Zezhen Cheng, Thomas Wietsma, Ravi Kukkadapu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.170158332.29336750/v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Cyclizative Carboxylation of Alkene-Tethered Aryl Isocyanides with Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.orglett.4c04426</link>
      <description>Haitao Liu, Meng Guo, Mengying Jia, Jianwei Zhang, Xianxiu Xu, Organic Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406307963

                Herein, we present an unprecedented electrochemical reductive cyclizative carboxylation of o-vinylphenyl isocyanides with carbon dioxide achieved without the use of metal catalysts. This protocol demonstrates a broad substrate scope and good functional group tolerance, facilitating the rapid assembly of 2-oxoindolin-3-acetic acids in good to high yields with excellent regioselectivity. Furthermore, these structural motifs may have potential applications in formal synthesis of bioactive natural products.</description>
      <author>Haitao Liu, Meng Guo, Mengying Jia, Jianwei Zhang, Xianxiu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.orglett.4c04426</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Environmental Contaminants and the Impact of Green Technologies on Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33002/jelp040309</link>
      <description>Awodezi Henry, Ikechukwu Kwubosu, Journal of Environmental Law &amp; Policy. 04(03)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406334151

                Environment has been defined as the natural world in which living things dwell and grow. There are certain factors which often pose challenges to the environment and are capable of interrupting capacity building as well as sustainability. This research evaluates such factors as environmental contaminants which include any chemical, biological, or radiological substance or matter that hurts air, water, soil or living organisms. However, with the advancement of green technologies on the environment, there is a revolutionary change with regards to clean energy production, solar power, reduction of emissions of carbon dioxide, use of alternative fuels and other technologies that are less harmful to the environment than fossil fuels. This research focuses on clean energy production such as solar energy and other technologies that serve the best purpose of reducing emissions of carbon dioxide usually generated by vehicles, motorcycles and fuel power generators majorly in the cities, particularly in the industrial environments. These emissions from vehicle engines, power generators, gas flaring and other environmental contaminants are very dangerous to human health. Many, who have ingested these emissions, have serious interference with their bodies&#8217; internal functioning, causing diseases like cancer, itching in the eyes and respiratory disorders like asthma. The pressing need to explore green technologies for sustainability becomes imperative and this gave rise to this research. To achieve this aim, this research adopts the doctrinal research methodology in examining the natural environmental contaminants and the impact of green technologies on climate change. On this premise, this research recommends tremendous exploration of green technologies as a recipe for a sustainable environment.</description>
      <author>Awodezi Henry, Ikechukwu Kwubosu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33002/jelp040309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Impact Does Net Zero Action on Road Transport and Building Heating Have on Exposure to UK Air Pollution?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c05601</link>
      <description>Nosha Assareh, Andrew Beddows, Gregor Stewart, Mike Holland, Daniela Fecht, Heather Walton, Dimitris Evangelopoulos, D. L. Wood, Tuan V. Vu, David Dajnak, Christian Brand, Sean Beevers, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406233995

                This study explores the cobenefits of reduced nitrogen dioxide (NO2), ozone (O3), and particulate matter (PM), through net zero (NZ) climate policy in the UK. Two alternative NZ scenarios, the balanced net zero (BNZP) and widespread innovation (WI) pathways, from the UK Climate Change Committee's Sixth Carbon Budget, were examined using a chemical transport model (CTM). Under the UK existing policy, Business as Usual (BAU), reductions in NO2 and PM were predicted by 2030 due to new vehicle technologies but plateau by 2040. The BNZP and WI scenarios show further reductions particularly by 2040, driven by accelerated electric vehicle (EV) uptake and low-carbon heating in buildings, with the building contribution to PM reduction being 2&#8211;3 times greater than road transport. The results demonstrate that the NZ transition to EVs (cars and vans) reduces both exhaust and nonexhaust emissions, as well as reducing traffic volumes. O3 trends are complex with a small overall increase by 2030 and a decrease by 2040. Although uncertain, 2050 predictions of BNZP showed important additional air pollution benefits. Our findings highlight the efficacy of NZ strategies, providing insights for UK and international policymakers interested in the air pollution cobenefits of climate policy.</description>
      <author>Nosha Assareh, Andrew Beddows, Gregor Stewart, Mike Holland, Daniela Fecht, Heather Walton, Dimitris Evangelopoulos, D. L. Wood, Tuan V. Vu, David Dajnak, Christian Brand, Sean Beevers</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c05601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Opportunities to Incentivize Low-Carbon Regeneration of Buildings in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095964</link>
      <description>Valeri&#1110; Deshko, Anatolijs Borodi&#326;ecs, Nadia Buyak, Inna Bilous, Olena Naumchuk, Iryna Sukhodub, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406313146

                Given the consequences of military actions in Ukraine and global and national goals to achieve decarbonization across all sectors of the economy, the authors evaluate opportunities for low-carbon recovery of the construction sector. In particular, an analysis of the impact of providing a highly energy-efficient building thermal envelope and its heat supply using renewable energy sources during the modernization of the existing administrative building in Ukraine to the level of the requirements of the European Union was carried out. This analysis considered economic, technical, and environmental factors. Thus, the authors present the results of dynamic modeling of the building's energy consumption at different levels of building insulation and make a payback forecast for improving the thermal envelope and using various sources of heat supply (including using a heat pump and a pellet boiler). To assess emissions reduction of the proposed building modernization options, an analysis of the existing national methods of calculating carbon dioxide emissions was carried out, and the option of a combination of a heat pump and photovoltaic panels was considered.</description>
      <author>Valeri&#1110; Deshko, Anatolijs Borodi&#326;ecs, Nadia Buyak, Inna Bilous, Olena Naumchuk, Iryna Sukhodub</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095964</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Fe, Co, Ni-based single atom catalysts and the progress of their application in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.65</link>
      <description>Yuquan Yang, Meifang Huang, Bin-Bin Gao, Chenjing Wang, Hongjing Wu, Yanru Yuan, Jinlong Zheng, Microstructures. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406190925

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have garnered considerable attention owing to their profound potential in promoting the efficient utilization of metal resources and attaining atomic-level economy. Fe, Co, Ni SACs have demonstrated broad application prospects in electrocatalysis due to their tunable composition and structure, as well as their unique electronic properties. Firstly, the various preparation methods for Fe, Co, Ni SACs are outlined in this review, including high-temperature pyrolysis, impregnation, chemical vapor deposition, and atomic layer deposition. These methods not only enhance the utilization efficiency of metal atoms but also ensure the stability of the catalysts. Subsequently, this review summarizes the recent progress in the applications of Fe, Co, Ni SACs for electrocatalysis, with a particular focus on their efficacy in hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, and nitrogen reduction reaction. Despite remarkable advancements, Fe, Co, Ni SACs still face challenges related to large-scale production, stability enhancement, comprehensive characterization, and mechanistic exploration. Finally, this review discusses these challenges and proposes strategies to address them in order to fully realize the potential of Fe, Co, Ni SACs as high-performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuquan Yang, Meifang Huang, Bin-Bin Gao, Chenjing Wang, Hongjing Wu, Yanru Yuan, Jinlong Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.65</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Effects of Scco2 Cooling and Mql Conditions on the Milling Machinability of Titanium Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5092431</link>
      <description>Lanyu Shi, Youkang Yin, Chenguang Wang, Tao Wang, Lu Yang, Qi Wang, Qinglong An, Weiwei Ming, Ming Chen, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406237585

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Study on the Effects of Scco2 Cooling and Mql Conditions on the Milling Machinability of Titanium Alloys 46 Pages Posted: 10 Jan 2025 See all articles by Lanyu ShiLanyu Shiaffiliation not provided to SSRNYoukang Yinaffiliation not provided to SSRNChenguang Wangaffiliation not provided to SSRNTao Wangaffiliation not provided to SSRNLu Yangaffiliation not provided to SSRNQi Wangaffiliation not provided to SSRNQinglong Anaffiliation not provided to SSRNWeiwei Mingaffiliation not provided to SSRNMing Chenaffiliation not provided to SSRN Abstract Titanium alloys are widely utilized in aerospace and other industries due to their exceptional mechanical properties. However, the milling of titanium alloys often encounters engineering challenges such as severe tool wear and suboptimal surface integrity. This study aims to enhance the milling machinability of titanium alloys though the application of optimized supercritical CO2 (scCO2) cooling and minimum quantity lubrication (MQL) conditions. A finite element calculation model for milling titanium alloy under various cooling/lubrication conditions (CLCs) was developed. The instantaneous flow behaviors and heat transfer characteristics of the auxiliary medium were rigorously analyzed. Based on the milling experiments of titanium alloy, the effects of operating parameters and CLCs on the process parameters, surface integrity, and tool wear were systematically investigated. A coherent scheme for matching the energy field parameters with milling parameters to achieve the low-damage cutting of titanium alloys was developed. The results indicate that the implementation of scCO2-oil on water based on MQL (scCO2-OoWMQL) can productively address the issue of oil film rupture and insufficient wear reduction observed with the sole use of MQL or scCO2 cooling. Additionally, this composite technique significantly improved surface integrity of titanium alloy and ensures excellent preservation of the cutting-edge condition. The average resultant cutting force (Fr) and maximum cutting temperature (Tmax) increase with cutting speed (vc), feed per tooth (ft), and radial depth of cut (ae), whereas surface roughness (Sa) decreases with vc. Within the range of experimental parameters, the optimal combination of machining parameter was found to be vc=60 m/min, ft=0.09 mm/z, ae=0.3 mm, and ap=3 mm. When scCO2-OoWMQL is applied in conjunction with this combination, a significant reduction of 21.65% in Sa is achieved compared to dry cutting. Keywords: Supercritical carbon dioxide, Minimum Quantity Lubrication, Titanium alloy, Milling machinability, Surface integrity, Tool wear mechanism Suggested Citation: Suggested Citation Shi, Lanyu and Yin, Youkang and Wang, Chenguang and Wang, Tao and Yang, Lu and Wang, Qi and An, Qinglong and Ming, Weiwei and Chen, Ming, Study on the Effects of Scco2 Cooling and Mql Conditions on the Milling Machinability of Titanium Alloys. Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=5092431 Lanyu Shi affiliation not provided to SSRN ( email ) No Address Available Youkang Yin affiliation not provided to SSRN ( email ) No Address Available Chenguang Wang affiliation not provided to SSRN ( email ) No Address Available Tao Wang affiliation not provided to SSRN ( email ) No Address Available Lu Yang affiliation not provided to SSRN ( email ) No Address Available Qi Wang affiliation not provided to SSRN ( email ) No Address Available Qinglong An affiliation not provided to SSRN ( email ) No Address Available Weiwei Ming affiliation not provided to SSRN ( email ) No Address Available Ming Chen (Contact Author) affiliation not provided to SSRN ( email ) No Address Available Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Do you have a job opening that you would like to promote on SSRN? Place Job Opening Paper statistics Downloads 0 Abstract Views 2 60 References PlumX Metrics Feedback Feedback to SSRN Feedback (required) Email (required) Submit</description>
      <author>Lanyu Shi, Youkang Yin, Chenguang Wang, Tao Wang, Lu Yang, Qi Wang, Qinglong An, Weiwei Ming, Ming Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5092431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-tin bimetallic aerogel alloy for the electroreduction of CO2 to formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04703f</link>
      <description>Bo Ren, Jing Shao, Hongji Li, Qingming Xu, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406239696

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) enables the conversion of CO2 into various value-added hydrocarbons, with formate formate garnering significant interest due to its high energy density and efficient conversion...</description>
      <author>Bo Ren, Jing Shao, Hongji Li, Qingming Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04703f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semipermanent Continuous Formic Acid Production from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by Controlling Ion Transport Using Boron-Doped Diamond Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06705</link>
      <description>Shingo Araki, Yasuaki Einaga, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406259126

                Boron-doped diamond (BDD) is an excellent functional electrode material used as a working electrode in the electrochemical reduction of CO2. Formic acid production with approximately 100% Faradaic efficiency has been achieved via CO2 reduction using BDD electrodes. In this study, we investigated the production performance stability during long-term electrolysis by focusing on ion transport in the electrolyte during electrolysis. Initially, we investigated the behavior of potassium ions (K+) and pH during long-term electrolysis in detail. A relationship was observed between the change in ion concentrations and formic acid production, crucial in formic acid production. Based on this knowledge, we successfully achieved stable formic acid production for an extremely long time (1264 h) by controlling ion transport. In addition to utilizing the durability of BDD electrodes as stable electrode materials, controlling ion transport has paved the way for the industrialization of formic acid production via CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Shingo Araki, Yasuaki Einaga</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide to formate using a robust metal-independent &lt;i&gt;Thiobacillus&lt;/i&gt; formate dehydrogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/10242422.2025.2450363</link>
      <description>Daan M. van Vliet, Lorenzo C. Schwerdtfeger, August E. Frissen, Rick H. A. M. van de Vondervoort, Mattijs K. Julsing, Carmen G. Boeriu, Tom A. Ewing, Biocatalysis and Biotransformation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406275958

                The capture and utilization of CO2 from industrial off-gases to produce commodity chemicals has the potential to make an important contribution to the transition to a circular economy. Formate, and its conjugate formic acid, is a potential sustainable platform chemical that can be produced from CO2. Electrochemical reduction of CO2 to formate is a promising route, but biocatalysis with formate dehydrogenase (FDH) as biocatalyst may offer advantages for industrial implementation such as mild conditions, high product selectivity, and less expensive down-stream processing. Here, we investigated the potential of a metal-independent Thiobacillus FDH (TsFDH) as a biocatalyst for the production of formate from CO2-rich industrial offgases. An excellent stability was demonstrated, also in the presence of potential off-gas impurities. A formate titer of 14 mM could be achieved at pH 6.5 and 37 &#176;C, with an initial specific productivity of 0.37 mmol g&#8722;1FDH h&#8722;1. TsFDH compares favorably to metal-dependent FDHs with respect to stability, O2-sensitivity and activity at low pH values, but unfavorably in terms of CO2 reduction activity, hampering its potential as industrial biocatalyst. Specific rates could be significantly improved by further reaction engineering, and possibly also by enzyme engineering.</description>
      <author>Daan M. van Vliet, Lorenzo C. Schwerdtfeger, August E. Frissen, Rick H. A. M. van de Vondervoort, Mattijs K. Julsing, Carmen G. Boeriu, Tom A. Ewing</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/10242422.2025.2450363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzy multi-objective optimization model to design a sustainable closed-loop manufacturing system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.2591</link>
      <description>Sajida Kousar, A U Alvi, Nasreen Kausar, Harish Garg, Seifedine Kadry, Jung-Eun Kim, PeerJ Computer Science. 11(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406302170

                Republicans and Democrats practically everywhere have been demonstrating concerns about environmental conservation to achieve sustainable development goals (SDGs) since the turn of the century. To promote fuel (energy) savings and a reduction in the amount of carbon dioxide CO 2 emissions in several enterprises, actions have been taken based on the concepts described. This study proposes an environmentally friendly manufacturing system designed to minimize environmental impacts. Specifically, it aims to develop a sustainable manufacturing process that accounts for energy consumption and CO 2 emissions from direct and indirect energy sources. A multi-objective mathematical model has been formulated, incorporating financial and environmental constraints, to minimize overall costs, energy consumption, and CO 2 emissions within the manufacturing framework. The input model parameters for real-world situations are generally unpredictable, so a fuzzy multi-objective model will be developed as a way to handle it. The validity of the proposed ecological industrial design will be tested using a scenario-based approach. Results demonstrate the high reliability, applicability, and effectiveness of the proposed network when analyzed using the developed techniques.</description>
      <author>Sajida Kousar, A U Alvi, Nasreen Kausar, Harish Garg, Seifedine Kadry, Jung-Eun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.2591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Methanol Synthesis from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Using Cu/ZnO Catalysts: Insights from First&#8208;Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400345</link>
      <description>Cong Xi, Yixin Nie, Hongjuan Wang, Cunku Dong, Jiuhui Han, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, Small Structures. 6(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406236598

                Catalytic hydrogenation of carbon dioxide to methanol offers a promising avenue for recycling CO 2 , enhancing environmental sustainability. Cu/ZnO has long been identified as one of the most effective heterogeneous catalysts for this reaction, yet the detailed understanding of its reaction mechanism and active sites remains incomplete. Recent advances have highlighted the critical role of defects, such as ZnCu steps and stacking faults on Cu surfaces, in enhancing catalyst performance. Here this concept is explored through first&#8208;principles surface simulations of six models, featuring diverse Cu&#8211;Zn combinations and specific coordination environments under realistic conditions. It is revealed that Cu/ZnO catalysts with kink defects, rather than surface ZnCu alloys, exhibit optimal activity for methanol synthesis. Specifically, the findings demonstrate how intermediate configurations and rate&#8208;determining steps vary with changes in surface structure and reveal the role of the kink in promoting CO 2 reduction to methanol through electronic structure calculation. Moreover, it is found that the predominant synthetic pathway for CH 3 OH from CO 2 involves the reverse water gas shift and CO hydrogenation, rather than the formate route, on Cu/ZnO surfaces with kinks.</description>
      <author>Cong Xi, Yixin Nie, Hongjuan Wang, Cunku Dong, Jiuhui Han, Xi&#8208;Wen Du</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health system and environmental factors affecting global progress towards achieving End TB targets between 2015 and 2020</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7189/jogh.15.04004</link>
      <description>Haileab Fekadu Wolde, Archie C. A. Clements, Kefyalew Addis Alene, Journal of Global Health. 15(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406245452

                Health system and environmental factors play a significant role in achieving the World Health Organization (WHO) End Tuberculosis (TB) targets. However, quantitative measures are scarce or non-existent at a global level. We aimed to measure the progress made towards meeting the global End TB milestones from 2015 to 2020 and identify health system and environmental factors contributing to the success. We obtained data from ten different online data repositories and used principal component analysis to create domain-specific health system performance measures. We used radar charts and dumbbell plots to show the country's progress in ending TB with their health systems. Lastly, we used a linear regression model to identify key health systems and environmental predictors of the percent reduction in TB incidence and mortality. There was a high variation in TB incidence and mortality reduction between countries and WHO regions. Of all countries included, 75 (39.3%) achieved more than a 20% reduction in TB incidence between 2015 and 2020. However, only 31 (16.2%) reached a 35% reduction in TB mortality. The European Region achieved the highest incidence reduction, exceeding the 2020 milestone with a 25% reduction. The African Region also made notable progress, achieving an 18% mortality reduction despite its relatively poor health systems. Health system factors, such as TB financing, TB-specific health service delivery, access to medicine, and governance, were significantly associated with TB mortality reduction between 2015 and 2020. Environmental factors, such as average annual temperature and air particulate matter concentration, were found to have a significant negative effect on TB incidence and mortality reduction. Weak health systems were identified as major barriers to achieving the End TB milestones in most high-burden countries. Hence, strengthening health systems with a special focus on TB financing, service delivery, and access to medicine in these countries should be prioritised to achieve global TB mortality reduction targets. Countries should follow WHO's air quality guidelines and rapidly reduce carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emissions to mitigate the impact of environmental factors.</description>
      <author>Haileab Fekadu Wolde, Archie C. A. Clements, Kefyalew Addis Alene</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7189/jogh.15.04004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Waste to Resource: Evaluation of the Technical and Environmental Performance of Concrete Blocks Made from Iron Ore Tailings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020552</link>
      <description>Luciana Chaves Weba, J&#250;lia Maria Medalha Resende Oliveira, Alexandra Do Nascimento Souza, Lu&#237;s Antunes, Jos&#233; Maria Franco de Carvalho, Wanna Carvalho Fontes, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406304604

                This study investigates the use of iron ore tailings (IOTs) as recycled aggregates in segmental blocks, focusing on technical performance, CO2 emissions, and embodied energy using the cradle-to-gate approach. IOTs replaced fine aggregates in concrete at 25%, 50%, and 75% by volume, achieving compressive strengths of 16.23 MPa, 10.02 MPa, and 3.93 MPa, respectively. Raw material production accounted for 98% of CO2 emissions and 86% of embodied energy. Producing blocks at mining sites offered limited environmental benefits due to longer transport distances. Despite this, the results showed a 6% reduction in CO2 emissions and a 35% improvement in mechanical&#8211;environmental performance (CO2 emissions weighted by compressive strength) compared to traditional concrete. These findings underscore the potential of IOT-based concrete for segmental block production.</description>
      <author>Luciana Chaves Weba, J&#250;lia Maria Medalha Resende Oliveira, Alexandra Do Nascimento Souza, Lu&#237;s Antunes, Jos&#233; Maria Franco de Carvalho, Wanna Carvalho Fontes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Uniformity Properties and Corrosion Resistance of Zinc&#8211;Nickel Composite Coating Enhanced by Nano-SiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings15010071</link>
      <description>Sujie Chang, Yuanhao Wang, Jianpeng Wang, Zerui Hao, Yang Yang, Y.Y. Wang, Xinyi Wang, Fan Cao, Lei Shi, Coatings. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406242903

                In this study, pre-treated low-carbon steel substrates were electroplated with Zinc&#8211;Nickel (ZN) alloy composite coatings enhanced by the incorporation of nano-silicon dioxide (SiO2) particles in an alkaline solution. ZN deposits with varying concentrations of nano-SiO2&#8212;specifically, 1, 2, 3, 5, and 10 wt%&#8212;were achieved by adjusting the ratio between the nano-SiO2 and ZN alloy electroplating solutions. The influence of the nano-SiO2 content on both the quality of the coating and its corrosion behavior was investigated in detail. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy-dispersive spectroscopy (EDS), and an atomic force microscope (AFM) were utilized to assess the surface, cross-section structure, elemental composition, and thickness of the coatings. Notably, the addition of nano-SiO2 improved the microstructure of the coating, leading to a reduction in grain size as well as enhancements in uniformity and density while revealing that co-deposition reached an optimal concentration at 3 wt% nano-SiO2. The corrosion behavior of coated specimens was evaluated through electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) and polarization techniques within a 3.5 wt% NaCl solution serving as a corrosive medium. Specifically, for typical prepared coatings, the corrosion current density decreased from 1.410 &#215; 10&#8722;4 A&#183;cm&#8722;2 to 5.762 &#215; 10&#8722;6 A&#183;cm&#8722;2, which is a remarkable reduction by one to two orders of magnitude relative to the SiO2-free coatings mentioned previously. These findings provide a straightforward approach for selecting 3 wt% nano-SiO2 as an effective additive in ZN composite coatings.</description>
      <author>Sujie Chang, Yuanhao Wang, Jianpeng Wang, Zerui Hao, Yang Yang, Y.Y. Wang, Xinyi Wang, Fan Cao, Lei Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings15010071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat-Fluid-Solid-Coupled Model for Flue Gas Displacement of CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; in Coal Seams and Its Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10428</link>
      <description>Gang Bai, Xuepeng Wang, Jue Wang, Xueming Li, Tianyu Xin, Z. H. Liu, Jie Wei, Chaojun Fan, Zehao Jing, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406218229

                The objective of this study was to evaluate the effect of injecting flue gas (CO2, N2, and O2) originating from coal-fired power plants into a coal seam on CH4 extraction and CO2 geological storage. To this end, a multifield thermal-fluid-solid-coupled mathematical model of flue gas injection extraction was established. The results showed that with the increase in time increase, the volume concentration of CH4 decreased, but the CO2, N2, and O2 increased. Compared with single extraction, the gas injection extraction brought about a significant reduction in the pressure and content of CH4, an increase in the CH4 extraction rate, and an increase in the effective radius of CH4 extraction. In the single extraction, the temperature of the reservoir decreased, and its permeability increased. In the gas injection extraction, the temperature near the gas injection hole increased, whereas the temperature near the extraction hole decreased, and the permeability decreased overall. A method of measuring the effective radius of gas extraction by temperature is presented. The storage and extraction times of CO2 exhibited a linear relationship, and the CO2 escape rate increased gradually. The longer the gas injection extraction time, the greater the risk of coal and gas (CO2) outbursts.</description>
      <author>Gang Bai, Xuepeng Wang, Jue Wang, Xueming Li, Tianyu Xin, Z. H. Liu, Jie Wei, Chaojun Fan, Zehao Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-Range Metal&#8211;Sorbent Interactions Determine CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture and Conversion in Dual-Function Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c13606</link>
      <description>Shradha Sapru, Kelle D. Hart, Chengshuang Zhou, Gennaro Liccardo, Jinwon Oh, Margaret J. Hollobaugh, Jorge Osio&#8208;Norgaard, Arun Majumdar, Bert D. Chandler, Matteo Cargnello, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406169008

                Carbon capture and utilization involve multiple energy- and cost-intensive steps. Dual-function materials (DFMs) can reduce these demands by coupling CO2 adsorption and conversion into a single material with two functionalities: a sorbent phase and a metal for catalytic CO2 conversion. The role of metal catalysts in the conversion process seems salient from previous work, but the underlying mechanisms remain elusive and deserve deeper investigation to achieve maximum utilization of the two phases. Here, preformed colloidal Ru nanoparticles were deposited onto a "NaOx"/Al2O3 sorbent to prepare prototypical DFMs with controlled phases for CO2 capture and hydrogenation to CH4. Ru addition was found to double the high-temperature CO2 adsorption capacity by activating the "NaOx"/Al2O3 sorbent phase during a reductive pretreatment step. Most importantly, low Ru loadings were sufficient to ensure maximum CO2 adsorption and conversion. This was attributed to the key role of the metal&#8211;sorbent interactions, wherein Ru was required to hydrogenate strongly bound CO2 on the "NaOx"/Al2O3 sorbent to CH4 via the H2 activated on Ru. This interaction facilitated rate-determining carbonate migration and subsequent hydrogenation at the metal&#8211;sorbent interface. Overall, Ru controlled the CO2 hydrogenation reaction rate, while the "NaOx"/Al2O3 sorbent dictated the CO2 uptake capacity. By controlling metal&#8211;sorbent interactions at the molecular level, we demonstrate the critical role of the two phases and their synergy, facilitating the design of DFMs with maximum CO2 capture and conversion efficiency.</description>
      <author>Shradha Sapru, Kelle D. Hart, Chengshuang Zhou, Gennaro Liccardo, Jinwon Oh, Margaret J. Hollobaugh, Jorge Osio&#8208;Norgaard, Arun Majumdar, Bert D. Chandler, Matteo Cargnello</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c13606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropogenic Methane Emission In India: Sources Of Methane Reduction Through Circular Economy For Mitigating Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5087878</link>
      <description>R. Subramanian, Balaji Chandramohan, S. Sunitha, SSRN Electronic Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406234287

                Methane, one of the major greenhouse gases (GHGs) produced due to various anthropogenic activities, is on the rise with increasing population and urbanization. It is the second most important greenhouse gas which is 28 times as potent as carbon dioxide at trapping heat in the atmosphere and contributes to the formation of ground-level ozone. It is the second largest contributor of climate change, accounting for about 16% of the warming effect. India is one of the major methaneemitting countries where methane emission is from human activities such as agriculture, livestock centric fermentation, and urban waste dumping in areas like urban wetlands. Though methane is a byproduct in the industrial process and despite new technologies being available for methane recovery, methane emission continues to grow without the use of circular economy owing to inadequate investment on the one hand and the growing population and urbanization on the other hand. Atmospheric burden due to methane emission can be reduced substantially with the practice of waste reduction, waste recycling and conversion of biowaste into energy. The paper suggests technological use, innovations and development needs to be relevant for both business success and environmental sustainability. The present paper takes a modest attempt to describe the production of methane based on different anthropogenic activities, its contribution to the GHGs and the possibilities of reducing methane through the practice of following circular economy.</description>
      <author>R. Subramanian, Balaji Chandramohan, S. Sunitha</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5087878</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Techno-Economic Analysis of Negative Emission Co2 Power Plant vs Ccgt with Ccs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5087251</link>
      <description>Chao Fu, Gonzalo del Alamo, Pawe&#322; Zi&#243;&#322;kowski, Kamil Stasiak, Maja Kaszuba, Milad Amiri, Pawe&#322; D&#261;browski, Halina Pawlak-Kruczek, Micha&#322; Ostrycharczyk, Marcin Baranowski, Krystian Krochmalny, Micha&#322; Czerep, Mateusz Kowal, Pawe&#322; Madejski, &#321;ukasz Nied&#378;wiecki, Navaneethan Subramanian, Dariusz Mikielewicz, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406169957

                A techno-economic analysis is performed on the negative CO2 emission gas power plant (nCO2PP) vs combined cycle gas turbine (CCGT) with carbon capture and storage (CCS). In nCO2PP it can be distinguished following three islands: the fuel preparation, power generation and CO2 separation and capture, respectively. The nCO2PP and CCGT with CCS are modeled in commercial software. The CCGT power plant with amine capture has been used as reference to represent state-of-the-art power generation technology. Both CAPEX and OPEX as well as incomes from sewage sludge disposal and avoided CO2 emissions have been included in the techno-economic analyses. The boundary of the cost analyses includes the power plants, CO2 capture processes and conditioning. The results show that the levelized cost of electricity (LCOE) of the nCO2PP using exhaust gas gasifier is comparable to the reference CCGT with amine capture. Due to the high electrical energy consumption and equipment cost, the LCOE is much higher when the plasma gasifier is used. The LCOE strongly depends on the income from sewage sludge disposal and avoided CO2 emissions. Further reductions of LCOE are expected for the nCO2PP with the development of the technology maturity.</description>
      <author>Chao Fu, Gonzalo del Alamo, Pawe&#322; Zi&#243;&#322;kowski, Kamil Stasiak, Maja Kaszuba, Milad Amiri, Pawe&#322; D&#261;browski, Halina Pawlak-Kruczek, Micha&#322; Ostrycharczyk, Marcin Baranowski, Krystian Krochmalny, Micha&#322; Czerep, Mateusz Kowal, Pawe&#322; Madejski, &#321;ukasz Nied&#378;wiecki, Navaneethan Subramanian, Dariusz Mikielewicz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5087251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decorating pore environment via cationic units of covalent organic frameworks for enhancing CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.34</link>
      <description>Minghao Liu, Guojuan Liu, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng, Chemical Synthesis. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406188869

                The conversion performance for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) relies on the affinity of CO2 molecules. Ionic covalent organic frameworks (COFs) are promising platforms for CO2RR due to the accessible catalytic sites in the skeleton, high CO2 combination ability and the electronic conductivity. However, most ionic COFs are constructed via pre-functionalization of the monomers or post-modification of the skeleton, encountering incomplete loading or uneven distribution of the active sites. In this work, a cationic porphyrin-based COF using the (3-carboxypropyl)trimethylammonium and Co-porphyrin units is developed through the sub-stoichiometric bottom-up synthesis method to fine-tune the pore environment for modulating the binding ability of CO2. Compared to base COFs, the cationic COFs exhibit improved electronic conductivity, high CO2 adsorption uptakes and enhanced reducibility, further improving the electrocatalytic CO2RR performance. Notably, the cationic COF achieves a high CO selectivity of 93% and a partial current density of 24.6 mA&#183;cm-2. This work not only offers considerable insights for improving the catalytic performance of COFs through the cationic groups but also provides a stoichiometry method to modulate the pore environment.</description>
      <author>Minghao Liu, Guojuan Liu, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.34</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;&#916;&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inversion setup for estimating European fossil CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-397-2025</link>
      <description>Carlos G&#243;mez-Ortiz, Guillaume Monteil, Sourish Basu, Marko Scholze, Atmospheric chemistry and physics. 25(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333402

                Abstract. Independent estimation and verification of fossil CO2 emissions on a regional and national scale are crucial for evaluating the fossil CO2 emissions and reductions reported by countries as part of their nationally determined contributions (NDCs). Top-down methods, such as the assimilation of in situ and satellite observations of different tracers (e.g., CO2, CO, &#916;14CO2, XCO2), have been increasingly used for this purpose. In this paper, we use the Lund University Modular Inversion Algorithm (LUMIA) to estimate fossil CO2 emissions and natural fluxes by simultaneously inverting in situ synthetic observations of CO2 and &#916;14CO2 over Europe. We evaluate the inversion system by conducting a series of observing system simulation experiments (OSSEs). We find that in regions with a dense sampling network, such as western/central Europe, adding &#916;14CO2 observations in an experiment where the prior fossil CO2 and biosphere fluxes are set to zero allows LUMIA to recover the time series of both categories. This reduces the prior-to-truth root mean square error (RMSE) from 1.26 to 0.12 TgC d&#8722;1 in fossil CO2 and from 0.97 to 0.17 TgC d&#8722;1 in biosphere fluxes, reflecting the true total CO2 budget by 91 %. In a second set of experiments using realistic prior fluxes, we find that in addition to retrieving the time series of the optimized fluxes, we are able to recover the true regional fossil CO2 budget in western/central Europe by 95 % and in Germany by 97 %. In all experiments, regions with low sampling coverage, such as southern Europe and the British Isles, show poorly resolved posterior fossil CO2 emissions. Although the posterior biosphere fluxes in these regions follow the seasonal patterns of the true fluxes, a significant bias remains, making it impossible to close the total CO2 budget. We find that the prior uncertainty of fossil CO2 emissions does not significantly impact the posterior estimates, showing similar results in regions with good sampling coverage like western/central Europe and northern Europe. Finally, having a good prior estimate of the terrestrial isotopic disequilibrium is important to avoid introducing additional noise into the posterior fossil CO2 fluxes.</description>
      <author>Carlos G&#243;mez-Ortiz, Guillaume Monteil, Sourish Basu, Marko Scholze</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-397-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo-Catalytic Reduction of Nitrate by Ag-TiO2/Formic Acid Under Visible Light: Selectivity of Nitrogen and Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/w17020155</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Shi, Yi Min Xie, Jun Xia, Xiaolin Zhang, Hui Cheng, Jialin Chen, Water. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406230607

                Ubiquitous nitrate (NO3&#8722;) in groundwater sources is considered a hazard compound for human health. Photo-catalytic reduction by Ag-TiO2/formic acid/visible light represents an emerging method for NO3&#8722; removal without secondary pollution. In this contribution, the removal of NO3&#8722; by photo-catalytic reduction and the selectivity of N2 were systematically investigated under varied conditions, including concentrations of Ag-TiO2, NO3&#8722;, and formic acid (HCOOH). The removal efficiency of NO3&#8722; reached 84.47%, 82.68% of which was converted to N2 under the optimal conditions: NO3&#8722; at 50 mg-N/L, Ag-TiO2 at 1.0 g/L, HCOOH at 20.05 mmol/L, and reaction time at 120 min. The removal of NO3&#8722; was enhanced mainly by CO2&#8722; rather than by photo-generated electrons or HCOO&#8722;. The results of this study indicated that the production of &#183;CO2&#8722; by Ag-TiO2 and HCOOH under visible light catalysis can achieve efficient NO3&#8722; removal.</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Shi, Yi Min Xie, Jun Xia, Xiaolin Zhang, Hui Cheng, Jialin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/w17020155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lifecycle Analysis of a Floating Power Plant Using Biomethane as a Drop-In Fuel for Cold Ironing of Vessels at Anchorage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en18020253</link>
      <description>George Mallouppas, Angelos Ktoris, Elias A. Yfantis, Sotiris Petrakides, Marios Drousiotis, Energies. 18(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406160431

                The purpose of this research article is to perform a greenhouse gas (GHG) impact assessment using a lifecycle analysis of a cold-ironing solution for vessels at anchorage in a retrofitted barge and a marine genset combusting biomethane in dual fuel mode. A lifecycle methodology is developed based on the 4th International Maritime Organization (IMO) GHG study. Eleven impact scenarios are evaluated in terms of CO2 and harmful pollutants (SOx, CO, PM10, PM2.5, NMVOC, and NOx). Vessels operated by Petronav Ship Management Ltd are examined, specifically M/T Alexandria and M/T Astraia. The scenarios reveal CO2 reductions of up to 21% and CO increases of up to 60% due to the combustion of biomethane in dual fuel mode, alongside SOx reductions of up to 20% with increasing biomethane energy substitution. Particulates and NOx decrease due to the utilization of biomethane. This article presents a pragmatic solution for cold ironing for vessels at anchorage with proven lower GHG emissions with the exception of increased CO emissions, therefore the benefits outweigh the drawbacks.</description>
      <author>George Mallouppas, Angelos Ktoris, Elias A. Yfantis, Sotiris Petrakides, Marios Drousiotis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en18020253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Slag Content and Carbonation/Ageing on Freeze-Thaw Resistance of Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2478/ncr-2024-0012</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ahsan Iqbal, Teemu Ojala, Fahim Al-Neshawy, Jouni Punkki, Nordic Concrete Research/Nordic concrete research. 71(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406215153

                Abstract The construction industry is pursuing the reduction of CO2 emissions and the development of lowcarbon concrete. LOIKKA research project was initiated in Finland with the aim to reduce the CO2 emissions of concrete manufacturing by 50%. The use of blast furnace slag was seen as the most competitive way to significantly reduce CO2 emissions of concrete. However, incorporating slag in concrete can lead to durability complications, particularly concerning salt freeze-thaw resistance. This study investigates the effects of slag content, carbonation/ageing, and pre-curing conditions on the freeze-thaw and salt freeze-thaw resistance of concrete. Additionally, it evaluates the compressive strength development and porosity differences of test concretes. Slab tests were conducted to determine the surface scaling and internal damage resistance of concrete specimens. The results showed that high slag content and carbonation reduced salt freeze-thaw resistance. The incorporation of 50% slag content as the cement clinker replacement is considered critical. An increase in slag content led to a decrease in the compressive strength at 7 days due to the low reactivity of slag but achieved the highest compressive strength at 91 days with 70% slag content. These insights contribute to our understanding of the durability properties of concrete incorporating slag.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ahsan Iqbal, Teemu Ojala, Fahim Al-Neshawy, Jouni Punkki</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2478/ncr-2024-0012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Role of Potential and Cation Effect on Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction in All-Alkynyl-Protected Ag&lt;sub&gt;15&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15112</link>
      <description>Yuping Chen, Xia Zhou, Xunying Liu, Zhenghua Tang, Likai Wang, Qing Tang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406164919

                Atomically precise metal nanoclusters (NCs) have emerged as an intriguing class of model catalysts for electrochemical CO2 reduction reactions (CO2RR). However, the interplay between the interface environment (e.g., potential, cation concentration) and electron&#8211;proton transfer (ET/PT) kinetics&#9472;particularly in alkynyl-protected metal NCs&#9472;remains poorly understood. Here, we combined first-principles simulations and electrochemical experiments to investigate the role of potential and cation effect on CO2RR performance in a prototype all-alkynyl-protected Ag15(C&#8801;C&#8211;CH3)+ cluster. Our simulations revealed that the applied reduction potential triggers the elimination of the alkynyl ligand via sequentially breaking two &#960;-type Ag&#8211;C bonds and one &#963;-type Ag&#8211;C bond to expose the catalytically active Ag sites, and the barrier of the Ag&#8211;C breakage monotonically decreases with the lowering in potential. Furthermore, we show that introducing the inner-sphere Na+ ions greatly enhances *CO2 activation and promotes proton transfer to generate *COOH and *CO by forming the Na+&#8211;CO2(*COOH) complexes, while the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) from water dissociation is greatly suppressed, thus dramatically improving the selectivity of CO2 electroreduction. The electrochemical measurements further validated our predictions, where the CO Faradaic efficiency (FECO) and current density (jCO) show a pronounced dependence on the Na+ concentration. At an optimal concentration of 0.1 M NaCl, FECO can reach up to &#8764;96%, demonstrating the crucial role of cations in promoting the CO2RR. Our findings provide vital insights into the atomic-level reaction mechanism of the CO2RR on alkynyl-protected Ag15 NCs and highlight the important role of potential and electrolyte cation in governing the electron/proton transfer kinetics.</description>
      <author>Yuping Chen, Xia Zhou, Xunying Liu, Zhenghua Tang, Likai Wang, Qing Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techno-Economic and Environmental Analysis of an Off-grid Hybrid Renewable Energy System for Rural Electrification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36108//laujet/4202.81.0460</link>
      <description>P. I. Adeleru, Isaiah G. Adebayo, LAUTECH Journal of engineering and Technology. 18(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406187128

                Rural electrification is key to socio-economic development in developing countries like Nigeria. However, extending the national grid to remote rural areas is expensive and time consuming, and the traditional power supply method also involves utilization of a standalone renewable energy source such as Solar which have their associated drawbacks due to their unreliability in nature. Hence, this research carried out a techno-economic and environmental analysis of an off-grid hybrid renewable energy system for rural electrification using Kepler Optimization Algorithm (KOA). Feasibility study on electricity and hourly load demand assessment of Alayin village was conducted and village load profile was estimated. Mathematical modeling of each hybrid RES was formulated. A KOA technique was employed to carry out optimal sizing and check the cost efficiency of BG/ PHES/ Battery, PV/PHES/Battery, and the hybrid RES (PV/BG/PHES/Battery). Simulation of the model was done using MATLAB R2021a. The value obtained was validated with Gravitational Search Algorithm (GSA) for performance evaluation using Levelized Cost of Energy (LCOE), Loss of Power Supply Probability (LPSP) and CO2 reduction in manure management as performance metrics. The results of the analysis showed an appreciable reduction on the LCOE and CO2 with high reliability using KOA-hybrid RES compared with GSA-hybrid RES.</description>
      <author>P. I. Adeleru, Isaiah G. Adebayo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36108//laujet/4202.81.0460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Modeling and Experimental Investigation of CO2-Hydrocarbon System Within Cross-Scale Porous Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020277</link>
      <description>Feiyu Chen, Linghui Sun, Bowen Li, Xiuxiu Pan, Siyu Jian, Xu Huo, Zhirong Zhang, Chun Feng, Molecules. 30(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333918

                CO2 flooding plays a crucial role in enhancing oil recovery and achieving carbon reduction targets, particularly in unconventional reservoirs with complex pore structures. The phase behavior of CO2 and hydrocarbons at different scales significantly affects oil recovery efficiency, yet its underlying mechanisms remain insufficiently understood. This study improves existing thermodynamic models by introducing Helmholtz free energy as a convergence criterion and incorporating adsorption effects in micro- and nano-scale pores. This study refines existing thermodynamic models by incorporating Helmholtz free energy as a convergence criterion, offering a more accurate representation of confined phase behavior. Unlike conventional Gibbs free energy-based models, this approach effectively accounts for confinement-induced deviations in phase equilibrium, ensuring improved predictive accuracy for nanoscale reservoirs. Additionally, adsorption effects in micro- and nano-scale pores are explicitly integrated to enhance model reliability. A multi-scale thermodynamic model for CO2-hydrocarbon systems is developed and validated through physical simulations. Key findings indicate that as the scale decreases from bulk to 10 nm, the bubble point pressure shows a deviation of 5% to 23%, while the density of confined fluids increases by approximately 2%. The results also reveal that smaller pores restrict gas expansion, leading to an enhanced CO2 solubility effect and stronger phase mixing behavior. Through phase diagram analysis, density expansion, multi-stage contact, and differential separation simulations, we further clarify how confinement influences CO2 injection efficiency. These findings provide new insights into phase behavior changes in confined porous media, improving the accuracy of CO2 flooding predictions. The proposed model offers a more precise framework for evaluating phase transitions in unconventional reservoirs, aiding in the optimization of CO2-based enhanced oil recovery strategies.</description>
      <author>Feiyu Chen, Linghui Sun, Bowen Li, Xiuxiu Pan, Siyu Jian, Xu Huo, Zhirong Zhang, Chun Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce[N(SiMe3)2]3(THF)3&#8208;Catalyzed Hydroboration of CO2, Esters and Epoxides with Pinacolborane: Selective Synthesis of Methanol in Multigram Scale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403449</link>
      <description>Md Jabed Hossain, Brij Kumar Shah, Soumya Ranjan Dash, Kashish, Kumar Vanka, Shabana Khan, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406228960

                In this work, we have reduced CO2 with HBpin to afford borylated methanol product selectively in ~99% yield using Ce[N(SiMe3)2]3(THF)3 as a catalyst. This led to multigram scale isolation of methanol obtained from CO2 reduction via the hydrolysis of borylated methanol, this establishes the potential of Ce[N(SiMe3)2]3(THF)3 as an efficient homogeneous catalyst for the bulk scale methanol synthesis. A practical application of this catalytic system was also shown by reducing CO2&#8208;containing motorbike exhaust efficiently and selectively. Further, C&#8210;O bond activation of esters and epoxides using HBpin and 1&#8208;2 mol% of Ce[N(SiMe3)2]3(THF)3 at 60 &#176;C afforded the borylated alcohols in good to excellent yields, which can easily be hydrolysed to the eco&#8208;friendly corresponding alcohol. The stoichiometric experiments were performed to prove the formation of in&#8208;situ generated cerium hydride [Ce]&#8208;H as an active catalyst.</description>
      <author>Md Jabed Hossain, Brij Kumar Shah, Soumya Ranjan Dash, Kashish, Kumar Vanka, Shabana Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Lattice Oxygen of Bi2O3 by Interstitial Insertion of Indium for Efficient Formic Acid Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423658</link>
      <description>Junjie Wang, Wu Tang, Zhaozhao Zhu, Yingxi Lin, Lei Zhao, Haiyuan Chen, Xueqiang Qi, Xiaobin Niu, Rui Wu, Jun Song Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333304

                Bismuth oxide (Bi2O3) emerges as a potent catalyst for converting CO2 to formic acid (HCOOH), leveraging its abundant lattice oxygen and the high activity of its Bi&#8208;O bonds. Yet, its durability is usually impeded by the loss of lattice oxygen causing structure alteration and destabilized active bonds. Herein, we report an innovative approach via the interstitial incorporation of indium (In) into the Bi2O3, significantly enhancing bond stability and preserving lattice oxygen. The optimized In&#8208;Bi2O3&#8208;100 catalyst achieves over 90% Faradaic efficiency for HCOOH production across a wide potential range, in both H&#8208;cells and flow cells, maintaining robust stability after 100 hours of continuous operation. In&#8208;situ surface&#8208;enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy and theoretical calculations reveal that the interstitial In doping precisely tunes the adsorption of CO2* and OCHO* intermediate, facilitating rapid conversion. Further in&#8208;situ Raman spectroscopy confirms the role of In bolstering the oxidized structure's stability within Bi2O3, critical for sustaining lattice oxygen during electrochemical CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Junjie Wang, Wu Tang, Zhaozhao Zhu, Yingxi Lin, Lei Zhao, Haiyuan Chen, Xueqiang Qi, Xiaobin Niu, Rui Wu, Jun Song Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Lattice Oxygen of Bi2O3 by Interstitial Insertion of Indium for Efficient Formic Acid Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423658</link>
      <description>Junjie Wang, Wu Tang, Zhaozhao Zhu, Yingxi Lin, Lei Zhao, Haiyuan Chen, Xueqiang Qi, Xiaobin Niu, Rui Wu, Jun Song Chen, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333687

                Bismuth oxide (Bi2O3) emerges as a potent catalyst for converting CO2 to formic acid (HCOOH), leveraging its abundant lattice oxygen and the high activity of its Bi-O bonds. Yet, its durability is usually impeded by the loss of lattice oxygen causing structure alteration and destabilized active bonds. Herein, we report an innovative approach via the interstitial incorporation of indium (In) into the Bi2O3, significantly enhancing bond stability and preserving lattice oxygen. The optimized In-Bi2O3-100 catalyst achieves over 90% Faradaic efficiency for HCOOH production across a wide potential range, in both H-cells and flow cells, maintaining robust stability after 100 hours of continuous operation. In-situ surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy and theoretical calculations reveal that the interstitial In doping precisely tunes the adsorption of CO2* and OCHO* intermediate, facilitating rapid conversion. Further in-situ Raman spectroscopy confirms the role of In bolstering the oxidized structure's stability within Bi2O3, critical for sustaining lattice oxygen during electrochemical CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Junjie Wang, Wu Tang, Zhaozhao Zhu, Yingxi Lin, Lei Zhao, Haiyuan Chen, Xueqiang Qi, Xiaobin Niu, Rui Wu, Jun Song Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Oxygen Vacancy&#8208;Copper Pair Sites on Inverse CeO2/Cu Catalyst Enable Efficient CO2 Electroreduction to Ethanol in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202424248</link>
      <description>Yan Qiao, Shenyu Shen, Chenghui Mao, Yongchun Xiao, Wenchuan Lai, Yanan Wang, Xingyu Zhong, Yangfan Lu, Jiong Li, Jingjie Ge, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Yaqiong Su, Minhua Shao, Zheng Hu, Hongwen Huang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210556

                Renewable electricity&#8208;driven electrochemical reduction of CO2 offers a promising route for production of high&#8208;value ethanol. However, the current state of this technology is hindered by low selectivity and productivity, primarily due to limited understanding of the atomic&#8208;level active sites involved in ethanol formation. Herein, we identify that the interfacial oxygen vacancy&#8208;neighboring Cu (Ov&#8208;Cu) pair sites are the active sites for CO2 electroreduction to ethanol. A linear correlation between the density of Ov&#8208;Cu pair sites and ethanol productivity is experimentally evidenced. Moreover, a high Faradaic efficiency of 48.5% and a partial current density of 344.0 mA cm&#8208;2 for ethanol production are achieved over the inverse CeO2/Cu catalyst with a high density of Ov&#8208;Cu pair sites in acid. Mechanistic studies that combine density functional theory calculations and spectroscopic techniques propose an Ov&#8208;involved mechanism where interfacial Ov sites directly activate and dissociate CO2 into *CO in a thermodynamically spontaneous manner, thus favoring the subsequent *CHO formation and asymmetric CHO&#8208;CO coupling. Besides, the asymmetric Ov&#8208;Cu pair sites could preferentially stabilize the *CH2CHOH intermediate, resulting in the favorable formation of ethanol over ethylene. Our findings provide new atomic&#8208;level insights into CO2 electroreduction to ethanol, paving the way for the rational design of future catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yan Qiao, Shenyu Shen, Chenghui Mao, Yongchun Xiao, Wenchuan Lai, Yanan Wang, Xingyu Zhong, Yangfan Lu, Jiong Li, Jingjie Ge, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Yaqiong Su, Minhua Shao, Zheng Hu, Hongwen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202424248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Oxygen Vacancy&#8208;Copper Pair Sites on Inverse CeO2/Cu Catalyst Enable Efficient CO2 Electroreduction to Ethanol in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202424248</link>
      <description>Yan Qiao, Shenyu Shen, Chenghui Mao, Yongchun Xiao, Wenchuan Lai, Yanan Wang, Xingyu Zhong, Yangfan Lu, Jiong Li, Jingjie Ge, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Yaqiong Su, Minhua Shao, Zheng Hu, Hongwen Huang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210558

                Renewable electricity&#8208;driven electrochemical reduction of CO2 offers a promising route for production of high&#8208;value ethanol. However, the current state of this technology is hindered by low selectivity and productivity, primarily due to limited understanding of the atomic&#8208;level active sites involved in ethanol formation. Herein, we identify that the interfacial oxygen vacancy&#8208;neighboring Cu (Ov&#8208;Cu) pair sites are the active sites for CO2 electroreduction to ethanol. A linear correlation between the density of Ov&#8208;Cu pair sites and ethanol productivity is experimentally evidenced. Moreover, a high Faradaic efficiency of 48.5% and a partial current density of 344.0 mA cm&#8208;2 for ethanol production are achieved over the inverse CeO2/Cu catalyst with a high density of Ov&#8208;Cu pair sites in acid. Mechanistic studies that combine density functional theory calculations and spectroscopic techniques propose an Ov&#8208;involved mechanism where interfacial Ov sites directly activate and dissociate CO2 into *CO in a thermodynamically spontaneous manner, thus favoring the subsequent *CHO formation and asymmetric CHO&#8208;CO coupling. Besides, the asymmetric Ov&#8208;Cu pair sites could preferentially stabilize the *CH2CHOH intermediate, resulting in the favorable formation of ethanol over ethylene. Our findings provide new atomic&#8208;level insights into CO2 electroreduction to ethanol, paving the way for the rational design of future catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yan Qiao, Shenyu Shen, Chenghui Mao, Yongchun Xiao, Wenchuan Lai, Yanan Wang, Xingyu Zhong, Yangfan Lu, Jiong Li, Jingjie Ge, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Yaqiong Su, Minhua Shao, Zheng Hu, Hongwen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202424248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe and Sn Single-Site-Based Electrodes for High-Current CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction in Acid Media and Stable Zn&#8211;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02704</link>
      <description>Jiajun Hu, Sara Goberna&#8208;Ferr&#243;n, Laura Simonelli, Nieves L&#243;pez&#8208;Salas, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Jorge Albero, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406221844

                Electrocatalytic CO2 conversion is a promising method for reducing the dependence on fossil fuels and lowering CO2 emissions. However, challenges such as suppression of the competing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and long-term stability, especially in acidic media, among others, hinder its industrial application. Herein, Fe and Sn single sites supported on an N-doped carbon support (FSNC) was prepared by direct pyrolysis of selected precursors. XANES and EXAFS measurements confirmed the presence of Fe and Sn single atoms coordinated to N or O atoms in the N-doped carbon. An analogous material synthesized by deposition of Fe and Sn precursors on a previously fabricated N-doped carbon matrix (FS/NC), followed by thermal reduction, rendered Fe&#8211;O small clusters and Sn single atoms. FSNC was tested for CO2 reduction, obtaining a CO Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 92%, while the CO FE of FS/NC was 63%. We attributed the differences in selectivity to the interaction between the Fe and Sn single sites, while the Fe&#8211;O clusters are inactive for this reaction. Double-layer capacitance (CDL) and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) measurements confirmed a larger electrochemically active surface area and lower charge-transfer resistance, respectively, in FSNC. In addition, FSNC demonstrated a high CO FE (90%) under acidic conditions (pH = 2.1), demonstrating that this electrocatalyst can effectively suppress the HER under acidic conditions. Moreover, 5 cm2 electrodes containing FSNC were fabricated, and their stability was tested for 20 h of continuous operation in an electrochemical flow cell at different current densities (50&#8211;350 mA/cm2), demonstrating improved stability at high current densities and under acidic conditions. Finally, FSCN-based cathodes were also tested in a Zn&#8211;CO2 battery, achieving a maximum power density of 2.54 mW/cm2 at 0.48 V with a current density of 5.2 mA/cm2 and demonstrating outstanding rechargeability and stability upon 50 continuous charge&#8211;discharge cycles for 50 h.</description>
      <author>Jiajun Hu, Sara Goberna&#8208;Ferr&#243;n, Laura Simonelli, Nieves L&#243;pez&#8208;Salas, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Jorge Albero</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studies of the expansion mechanism on different pellets under hydrogen-rich reducing atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00084433.2024.2447644</link>
      <description>Shuo Wang, Fengman Shen, Xiaobo Zhang, Haiyan Zheng, Xin Jiang, Qiangjian Gao, Canadian Metallurgical Quarterly. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406297394

                In response to the need to develop green low-carbon iron smelting technology, blast furnace hydrogen reduction technology is of great significance for reducing CO2 emissions from the ironmaking system. This study focuses on the change in swelling behaviour of different types of pellets during the blast furnace hydrogen smelting process. It analyses the reduction swelling index (RSI/%) and compression strength before and after reduction at 900&#176;C in a variety of reduction gas atmospheres, among other indices. The results show that under the condition of ore grade, the reduction expansion rate of pellet increases with the increase of grade. With the increase of basicity (R) (0 &#8764; 0.25) and the Mg-Al ratio (M/A) (0.4 &#8764; 1.4), the reduction in expansion of the pellet shows an upward trend. However, the RSI/% shows a downward trend with the increase of the synergistic effect of ore silicon and aluminium (S + A). The compression strength after reduction increases to different degrees with the increase of the proportion of hydrogen in the reduction atmosphere; the maximum increase was about 0.591 KN. SEM-EDS detection was carried out on pellet in different reduction atmospheres, and the structure and component changes of various regions during the reduction process were analysed.</description>
      <author>Shuo Wang, Fengman Shen, Xiaobo Zhang, Haiyan Zheng, Xin Jiang, Qiangjian Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00084433.2024.2447644</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Specific Activity during Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction through Homogeneous Deposition of Gold Nanoparticles on Gas Diffusion Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02254</link>
      <description>Takuya Yamada, Kazuyuki Iwase, Naoto Todoroki, Itaru Honma, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406308799

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) has attracted attention as a promising strategy for converting CO2 into value-added products. Gas diffusion electrodes (GDEs) loaded with metallic nanoparticles as electrocatalysts are expected to efficiently reduce CO2 due to the high specific surface area of such particles and the superior mass transport characteristics of GDEs. In the present study, GDEs loaded with homogeneous layers of gold (Au) nanoparticles were fabricated using a radio frequency sputtering technique that had a low deposition rate. This allowed for precise control of the catalyst loading. The Au-loaded GDEs exhibited a significantly higher CO production efficiency compared with the electrodes fabricated by conventional deposition methods using dispersed Au nanoparticles. Additionally, a Au-loaded GDE having a catalytic layer thickness of 10 nm demonstrated a mass-based CO production activity of 1882 A g&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.85 V. This is the highest value yet reported. This work confirmed that the uniform deposition of metallic nanoparticles provides enhanced catalyst utilization. The results of this research provide important insights into the design of efficient CO2RR electrodes and highlight the potential of radio frequency sputtering to fabricate high-performance CO2RR electrodes as an approach to realizing carbon-neutral technologies.</description>
      <author>Takuya Yamada, Kazuyuki Iwase, Naoto Todoroki, Itaru Honma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24&#8208;Epibrassinolide Improves Potato (&lt;i&gt;Solanum tuberosum&lt;/i&gt; L.) Tolerance to Alkaline Salt Stress by Regulating Antioxidant Defence and Photosynthetic Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jac.70022</link>
      <description>Yong Wang, Ruyan Zhang, Xingxing Wang, Shujuan Jiao, Weina Zhang, Yichen Kang, Ming Li, Jiali Xie, Xinyu Yang, Yuhui Liu, Shuhao Qin, Journal of Agronomy and Crop Science. 211(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406250805

                ABSTRACT Alkaline salt stress, as a more diverse stress, severely affects the growth and development of potato ( Solanum tuberosum L.) and leads to yield reduction. Brassinosteroids have been shown to regulate plant growth and play an essential role under environmental stress. However, the physiological responses by which brassinosteroids confer alkaline salt stress tolerance in potato remain unclear. We used potato &#8216; Atlantic &#8217; as experimental material. The effects of 0.01, 0.1, 1 and 10 &#956;mol&#183;L &#8722;1 of 24&#8208;epibrassinolide (EBR) on the physiological and photosynthetic characteristics of potato under alkaline salt stress (300 mmol&#183;L &#8722;1 NaHCO 3 ) were studied. The results showed that exogenous EBR increased the antioxidant enzyme activities, increased the content of osmoregulatory substances and decreased the production of peroxidation products in potato leaves under alkaline salt stress. EBR treatment improved the photosynthetic characteristics by accumulating more photosynthetic pigments. This was manifested by an increase in net photosynthetic rate, transpiration rate and stomatal conductance, and a decrease in intercellular carbon dioxide concentration. In addition, exogenous EBR increased the maximal quantum yield of photosystem II photochemistry and the effective PSII quantum yield of potato PSII under alkaline salt stress and ultimately increased yield. Potato tuber yield was significantly increased by 27.31% and 29.17% in T4 treatment compared to T1 in 2022 and 2023, respectively. Cluster and correlation analyses further demonstrated the beneficial effects of exogenous EBR on physiology, photosynthetic characteristics and potato yield under alkaline salt stress. In conclusion, exogenous EBR can enhance the tolerance of potato to alkaline salt stress by improving the antioxidant system and photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Yong Wang, Ruyan Zhang, Xingxing Wang, Shujuan Jiao, Weina Zhang, Yichen Kang, Ming Li, Jiali Xie, Xinyu Yang, Yuhui Liu, Shuhao Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jac.70022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Free NH3 Co-firing Behavior in Fluidized Bed Reactor: Effect of Blending Ratio and Stoichiometric Ratio</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15231/jksc.2024.29.4.061</link>
      <description>Kim Js, Min-Woo Kim, Kyeong&#8208;Ho Kim, Haotian Ma, Seung-Mo Kim, Byoung-Hwa Lee, Chung&#8208;Hwan Jeon, Journal of the Korean Society of Combustion. 29(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406228322

                NH3, as one of the carbon-free fuels, is emerging as a new energy source for power generation. NH3 is being partially introduced into thermal power plants, accelerating its practical application as a fuel. In this study, experiments are conducted to apply NH3 in circulating fluidized bed(CFB) boilers. The objective of this research is to investigate fundamentally the effects of NH3 co-firing ratios(0-50%) and the stoichiometric ratio(SR) on combustion and various exhaust emissions to derive the optimal conditions for NH3 co-firing with coal using a bubbling fluidized bed(BFB) reactor. Results indicate that as the NH3 co-firing ratio increased, the emission values of CO2 and SO2 generated from coal combustion decreased. as the NH3 co-firing ratio increase up to 30~40%, the NOx gradually increase while higher co-firing ratio result in lower NOx value because unburned NH3 remaining in the reducing zone contribute to NOx reduction by selective non-catalytic reduction(SNCR) reactions. Furthermore NH3 should be injected into an appropriate reducing zone with a low SR for effective NOx reduction.</description>
      <author>Kim Js, Min-Woo Kim, Kyeong&#8208;Ho Kim, Haotian Ma, Seung-Mo Kim, Byoung-Hwa Lee, Chung&#8208;Hwan Jeon</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15231/jksc.2024.29.4.061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A photosynthesis&#8208;derived bionic system for sustainable biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414981</link>
      <description>Na Chen, Ruichen Shen, Tianpei He, Na Du, Jing Xi, Yangbing Yang, Lilei Yu, Quan Yuan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406319475

                &#8220;Cell factory&#8221; strategy based on microbial anabolism pathways offers an intriguing alternative to relieve the dependence on fossil fuels, which are recognized as the main sources of CO2 emission. Typically, anabolism of intracellular substance in cell factory requires the consumption of sufficient reduced nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NADPH) and adenosine triphosphate (ATP). However, it is of great challenge to modify the natural limited anabolism and to increase the insufficient level of NADPH and ATP to optimum concentrations without causing metabolic imbalance. Inspired by the natural photosynthesis process in which NADPH and ATP can both be produced through the coupled electron&#8208;proton transfer processes driven by sunlight, herein we designed a light&#8208;driven bionic system composed of three modules including photo&#8208;induced electron module, electron transfer channel module and proton gradient module. The proposed strategy of light&#8208;driven bionic system enables for achieving simultaneous and controllable supplies of NADPH and ATP, thus facilitating both highly efficient CO2 fixation and biomanufacturing. The proposed light&#8208;driven bionic system design strategy in this work might pave new sustainable ways for reducing power and energy regeneration to optimize microbial metabolism, offering intriguing alternatives for CO2 emission reduction and high value&#8208;added chemical biomanufacturing.</description>
      <author>Na Chen, Ruichen Shen, Tianpei He, Na Du, Jing Xi, Yangbing Yang, Lilei Yu, Quan Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A photosynthesis&#8208;derived bionic system for sustainable biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414981</link>
      <description>Na Chen, Ruichen Shen, Tianpei He, Na Du, Jing Xi, Yangbing Yang, Lilei Yu, Quan Yuan, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406319476

                "Cell factory" strategy based on microbial anabolism pathways offers an intriguing alternative to relieve the dependence on fossil fuels, which are recognized as the main sources of CO2 emission. Typically, anabolism of intracellular substance in cell factory requires the consumption of sufficient reduced nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NADPH) and adenosine triphosphate (ATP). However, it is of great challenge to modify the natural limited anabolism and to increase the insufficient level of NADPH and ATP to optimum concentrations without causing metabolic imbalance. Inspired by the natural photosynthesis process in which NADPH and ATP can both be produced through the coupled electron-proton transfer processes driven by sunlight, herein we designed a light-driven bionic system composed of three modules including photo-induced electron module, electron transfer channel module and proton gradient module. The proposed strategy of light-driven bionic system enables for achieving simultaneous and controllable supplies of NADPH and ATP, thus facilitating both highly efficient CO2 fixation and biomanufacturing. The proposed light-driven bionic system design strategy in this work might pave new sustainable ways for reducing power and energy regeneration to optimize microbial metabolism, offering intriguing alternatives for CO2 emission reduction and high value-added chemical biomanufacturing.</description>
      <author>Na Chen, Ruichen Shen, Tianpei He, Na Du, Jing Xi, Yangbing Yang, Lilei Yu, Quan Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Intraday Impacts of Wind Energy on Wholesale Electricity Prices and Carbon Emissions in Great Britain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5087315</link>
      <description>Hanchen Xiao, Xiaoyi Mu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406198308

                This paper studies the intra-day impacts of wind power on wholesale electricity prices and carbon emissions in Great Britain. Exploiting hourly variations across years from 2008 to 2019, we differentiate the longer-term impact of wind power, largely due to capacity increases, and the short-term impact driven by weather conditions. The results show that the expansion of wind energy significantly decreases wholesale electricity prices in most hours, although the effect is not uniform. The prices decrease more during peak hours than during off-peak hours, with no significant effect during the ramping-up and ramping-down hours. However, over the sample period, the negative effects of wind expansion and load reduction on wholesale electricity prices are more than offset by the increases in carbon and fuel prices. Wind expansion, load reduction, and increases in carbon prices all contributed to the significant reduction in CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Hanchen Xiao, Xiaoyi Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5087315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the role of production capacity in mitigating carbon emissions: a case study of Algeria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34140/bjbv7n1-008</link>
      <description>Bouazza Elamine Zemr&#305;, Mohammed Fouad Gassem, Brazilian Journal of Business. 7(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406314937

                This study examines the relationship between productive capacity and CO2 emissions in Algeria, addressing the pressing challenge of sustainable development in the context of climate change. The aim is to explore how enhancing production capacity can influence environmental outcomes, particularly in terms of carbon emissions. To achieve this, the study employs an Auto Regressive Distributed Lag (ARDL) model, with results validated through an Error Correction Model (ECM), using data from 1990 to 2023. The findings reveal that improvements in productive capacity contribute to a long-term reduction in CO2 emissions per capita. However, an increase in energy consumption has the potential to undermine these gains, underlining the need for greater energy efficiency. Key policy recommendations suggest prioritizing investments in energy-efficient technologies, thereby enhancing Algeria&#8217;s productive capacity while minimizing environmental impact. This framework provides a valuable pathway for aligning economic growth with sustainable environmental practices, offering actionable insights for policymakers aiming to balance development with climate goals.</description>
      <author>Bouazza Elamine Zemr&#305;, Mohammed Fouad Gassem</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34140/bjbv7n1-008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of low frequency vibration to the turning of ultra-high molecular weight polyethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/20550340.2025.2449631</link>
      <description>Jack Rooke, R.D. Bonnell, Emily Pickford, Adam Brown, David Curtis, Advanced Manufacturing Polymer &amp; Composites Science. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406242955

                Medical implant manufacturing is a growing sector and therefore requires improved manufacturing practices. In the case of total hip arthroplasty, the most challenging component to meet the ISO standard (ISO 7206-2:2011) is the acetabular liner, often made from ultra-high molecular weight polyethylene (UHMWPE). UHMWPE machining is associated with several manufacturing challenges, including swarf control. This research used low frequency vibration (LFV), an intermittent cutting process and supercritical CO2 (scCO2) to aid chip segmentation and prevent swarf nesting. Machining trials have demonstrated a significant reduction in swarf nesting relative to a traditional process (91% reduction from LFV and 98% reduction when using LFV and scCO2). The surface roughness (*Ra_Symbol*) also had an indirect improvement from using LFV (53% reduction on the inner hemisphere), leading to all parts meeting the roughness requirement of ISO 7206-2:2011. The results have demonstrated machinability benefits for UHMWPE, reducing the operator intervention required and component scrap rates.</description>
      <author>Jack Rooke, R.D. Bonnell, Emily Pickford, Adam Brown, David Curtis</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/20550340.2025.2449631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chest Wall Restriction Device for Modeling Respiratory Challenges and Dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.08.24319742</link>
      <description>Victoria Ribeiro Rodrigues, L. Hoyos Mejia, Riccardo Zucchi, Paul W Davenport, Nicola Napoli, medRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406201976

                Breathing relies on unrestricted movement of the chest wall to maintain oxygen and carbon dioxide balance. Understanding the effects of chest and abdominal restrictions on respiratory function is critical for studying conditions such as respiratory diseases, extreme environments, and load-induced impairments. However, existing methods to simulate these restrictions are limited, lacking the ability to provide both static and dynamic conditions or precise load control. To address these gaps, we developed a novel chest wall and abdomen restriction device capable of independently applying and measuring static and dynamic loads with adjustable and reproducible force levels. Separate bands for the chest and abdomen enable targeted restrictions, with constant force springs providing resistance during dynamic conditions and immobilization during static conditions. Integrated sensors quantify applied loads and respiratory mechanics. To validate the device, healthy participants underwent pulmonary function testing and respiratory analysis under baseline, static restriction, and dynamic restriction conditions. Significant reductions in forced expiratory volume (FEV1) and forced vital capacity (FVC) were observed under restrictions compared to baseline. Other respiratory metrics, including inspiratory volume, inspiratory time, and peak inspiratory airflow, also showed significant differences, highlighting distinct effects of static and dynamic restrictions. Pressure variability tests confirmed the reproducibility and adjustability of applied loads, while displacement data from linear variable differential transducers (LVDTs) validated the device's ability to distinguish static and dynamic effects. This device addresses prior limitations by enabling precise, reproducible loading and independent control of chest and abdominal restrictions. Its versatility supports research into respiratory diseases, extreme environments, and respiratory mechanics. The results demonstrate the device's potential to advance respiratory function research and expand its clinical and experimental applications.</description>
      <author>Victoria Ribeiro Rodrigues, L. Hoyos Mejia, Riccardo Zucchi, Paul W Davenport, Nicola Napoli</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.08.24319742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Praktik Rantai Pasok Berkelanjutan: Penerapan Milk Run di Industri Plastik</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54324/j.mtl.v11i3.1464</link>
      <description>Rahman Soesilo, Alex J. Valentine, Suryo Sulistyo, Jurnal Manajemen Transportasi &amp; Logistik (JMTRANSLOG). 11(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406166908

                This study aims to explore the impact of implementing the Milk Run method in supply chain of plastic industry in PT RPI. By reducing the distance of 48 km per day, equivalent to 1,200 km in a month of deliveries, the research highlights significant changes in logistics&#8217; efficiency, cost savings, and carbon emission reduction. More connected travel patterns allow trucks to combine pick-ups or deliveries of multiple sources in single trip to enhance the overall logistics&#8217; efficiency. Reducing the distance contributes to saving transportation&#8217;s cost by lowering fuel consumption and maintaining vehicle expenses. Reducing a 1,200 km distance, assumed that a fuel consumption rate of 7 km per liter and a carbon emission rate of 2.68 kg CO2 per liter, could result in a substantial carbon emission reduction. This study provides a foundation for further research, including route and scheduling optimization, in-depth environmental impact analysis, and Milk Run implementation in other industries. The findings offer a comprehensive overview of Milk Run effectiveness in the plastic industry, emphasize operational advantages, economic impact, and commitment to sustainability.</description>
      <author>Rahman Soesilo, Alex J. Valentine, Suryo Sulistyo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54324/j.mtl.v11i3.1464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASSESSING THE PUBLIC PERCEPTION AND TARGETED IMPLEMENTATION OF ELECTRIC MOTORCYCLES IN DENPASAR CITY RELATED TO EMISSION REDUCTION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24843/ejes.2024.v18.i02.p10</link>
      <description>Otniel Stefen Adi Prasetyo, Qomariatus Sholihah, &#1045;driana Pang&#1077;stuti, Takahiro Osawa, Rio Aldi Prasetyo, ECOTROPHIC Jurnal Ilmu Lingkungan (Journal of Environmental Science). 18(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406320273

                Using an electric motorcycles can contribute to decreasing emissions in the transportation sector. Government policies and various socialization programs have supported the development of electric vehicles. This research was conducted to determine the public perception and implementation of electric motorcycles in Denpasar City. The public perception was obtained through questionnaires and in-depth interviews with related key persons. The statistical analysis of the questionnaire indicated a good category with a score of 3.43. The level of community acceptance was influenced by quieter and environmentally friendly technology, electricity tax subsidies, and lower electric fuel costs. The interview with community and government representatives reinforced the public acceptance finding affected by the intensive public outreach program and a vehicle installment payment scheme. As the result, The implementation target was rated optimistic, with a potential CO2 emission reduction of up to 32,641 tons/year in 2026. All the efforts to implement electric motorcycles in Denpasar City by the goverments have met the requirements to achieve acceptance of perceptions in the people of Denpasar City. This thing&#8217;s very important to reaching out the scenario of reducing CO2 emissions by 2026. In addition, it is important to have a more study regarding to the sustainability of the electric motorcycles ecosystem, such as the availability of data sources update from related agencies that show efforts to improve infrastructure by producers, the number of charging station and selling stations, as well as opportunities for domestic production and incentive policies. Keywords: Electric Motorcycles; Emission; Implementation Targets; Level of Acceptance; Public Perception</description>
      <author>Otniel Stefen Adi Prasetyo, Qomariatus Sholihah, &#1045;driana Pang&#1077;stuti, Takahiro Osawa, Rio Aldi Prasetyo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24843/ejes.2024.v18.i02.p10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A REVIEW OF BIO-BASED MATERIALS AS REINFORCEMENT IN CONCRETE COMPOSITES: MECHANICAL, CARBON CAPTURE, AND SELF-HEALING PERFORMANCE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3992/jgb.20.1.221</link>
      <description>Le Van Hai, Gu-Joong Kwon, Dadigala Ramakrishna, Bandi Rajkumar, Song-Yi Han, Nguyen Duc Quang, Hyun-Oh Shin, Seung-Hwan Lee, Journal of Green Building. 20(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406229477

                ABSTRACT Bio-based materials, including wood, non-woody plants, marine materials, and biochar resources, have attracted interest for use in cement and concrete composites in recent years. This review investigates the diverse resources of bio-based materials and their functionalities in different aspects of concrete composites, such as mechanical properties, carbon capture, sound absorption, and self-healing. The results show that plant-based materials play an important role in reinforcement fillers and present functionalities for carbon capture, energy storage, and crack self-healing. By incorporating 0.1&#8211;4% of various types of bio-based materials, it demonstrates that there is no adverse effect on the mechanical properties of concrete composites. This incorporation also results in a significant reduction in CO2 emissions through C-capture, thereby offering greener construction products. There is limited documentation on the concrete self-healing functionality of seashells, eggshells, and biochar-based materials. However, plant-based materials exhibit good self-healing functionality, making it possible for the advancement of functional bio-based materials in the construction industry. These advantages include good mechanical properties, good self-healing functionality, and reduced CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Le Van Hai, Gu-Joong Kwon, Dadigala Ramakrishna, Bandi Rajkumar, Song-Yi Han, Nguyen Duc Quang, Hyun-Oh Shin, Seung-Hwan Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3992/jgb.20.1.221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Design of Ice Thermal Energy Storage Unit Integrated into a Marine Air Conditioning System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095963</link>
      <description>Yang Yu, Wenbin Cui, Chong Zhang, Hong&#8208;Rui Fan, Yi Wei, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406313107

                Greenhouse gas emission from ships is currently one of the environmental issues for the shipping industry. Considering the marine air conditioning system consumes much energy on board ships, and to improve its efficiency and thus reduce CO2 emission, an ice thermal energy storage (ICE-TES) unit was designed and integrated into a marine air conditioning system on a real ship. Four cases distinguished with the shaved peak value of cooling load as 4%, 8%, 12%, and 16% were analyzed, and with the increasing shaving percent the integration of ICE-TES unit could reduce more electricity consumed for air cooling, and a upmost reduction of 1.49% was achieved (saved fuel by 33.99 kg/day). Furthermore, the rated power of compressor was optimized subsequently, the corresponding average COP of the system was enhanced from 2.36 to 2.45, and the saving in electricity consumption was promoted to 5.23% (saved fuel by 95.53 kg/day). Environmental analysis showed that CO2 emission was reduced by up to 2.84%, and the payback period for the optimized system could be shortened to 2.50 years. Thus this study proves the feasibility of the integration of ICE-TES unit with central air conditioning systems specifically for marine applications.</description>
      <author>Yang Yu, Wenbin Cui, Chong Zhang, Hong&#8208;Rui Fan, Yi Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Evaluation of Ceiling Cooling with PCM in the Hot-Dry Climate of Yazd, Iran: An Experimental Analysis of Energy, Environmental, and Economic Impacts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15020198</link>
      <description>Mehran Rabani, Mina Alafzadeh, Mehrdad Rabani, Buildings. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406334922

                The present study investigates experimental cooling from the ceiling using phase change materials (PCMs) in Yazd, a city characterized by a hot and dry climate. A one-fourth scale model of a real room, measuring 4 m &#215; 3 m &#215; 3 m, was employed for the analysis. To evaluate system performance and the impact of PCM on energy consumption reduction, three configurations were considered: a simple PCM system, a PCM system with a fan (PCM-F), and a PCM system with a mini cooler (PCM-C). Additionally, to assess the influence of window configurations on ventilation, temperature, and comfort conditions within the model, three scenarios were examined: two open windows, one open window, and no windows. The economic analysis compared the two systems with the fan and mini cooler against a full mechanical cooling system without PCMs. Furthermore, CO2 emissions and environmental impacts associated with the systems were also evaluated. The results indicate that the presence of PCMs in the ceiling, due to heat absorption during phase change, leads to a temperature reduction of 5 to 10 &#176;C in the ceiling and a 3.2 &#176;C reduction in the average room temperature compared to the scenario without PCMs. The findings demonstrate that ceiling cooling with PCMs significantly contributes to energy consumption reduction during peak hours of cooling demand. Specifically, the PCM-F system results in a 92% reduction, and the PCM-C system leads to a 71% reduction in total cost compared to the reference mechanical cooling system. Additionally, the PCM-F system achieves approximately a 36% reduction, and the PCM-C system results in a 34% reduction in environmental impact relative to the reference full mechanical cooling system.</description>
      <author>Mehran Rabani, Mina Alafzadeh, Mehrdad Rabani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15020198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphitic Carbon Nitride: Achieving Superlow Friction and Wear on Engineering Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00696</link>
      <description>Lin Li, Tao Lin, Jie Sun, Hanjun Gong, Yun Bai, Kai Gao, ACS Applied Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406254470

                Graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) is a typical two-dimensional (2D) material acclaimed for its layered structure and electronic properties, showcasing promise across various domains such as catalysis, CO2 reduction, and lubrication. In this study, g-C3N4 is synthesized as an oil-based nanoadditive within oleic acid (OA), exhibiting superlow friction coefficient (COF) within steel/steel contacts under high pressure. When dispersed g-C3N4 in OA at a concentration of 0.25 wt %, the COF is reduced from 0.077 to 0.022 compared to the base oil. The amino groups in g-C3N4 promote the formation of continuous friction films, creating a composite tribofilm made of carbon layers, carbon nitride, and iron oxides. This tribofilm effectively prevents direct contact between tribopairs, leading to significant friction reduction and enhanced antiwear properties. These findings offer insights into the design of lubricant additives for base oils and highlight the promising potential of carbon nitride in lubrication and tribology applications.</description>
      <author>Lin Li, Tao Lin, Jie Sun, Hanjun Gong, Yun Bai, Kai Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Equilibrium and Energy Consumption Analysis on Biomass and Iron Oxides Direct Reduction Ironmaking Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met15010057</link>
      <description>Guanyong Sun, C. Guo, Hui Ma, XU Wenlong, Le Wang, Metals. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406233621

                Biomass ironmaking is crucial for carbon reduction in the ironmaking industry. To understand this process better, the iron production capacity and energy requirements of biomass were studied. A thermodynamic equilibrium model and energy consumption model for the biomass and iron oxide reduction system at 100&#8211;1300 &#176;C was established by the minimum free Gibbs energy method. The effects of factors such as biomass type, temperature, and initial amount of iron oxide on the system were analyzed. The research results indicated that the maximum ironmaking capacity of biomass was determined by the element content of carbon, hydrogen and oxygen in biomass and temperature. The equilibrium H2/(H2 + H2O) and CO/(CO + CO2) at the maximum iron yield were affected not by the biomass species and element content, but by temperature. The reduction capacity of the ten selected biomass types decreased with a temperature increase from 700 &#176;C to 1300 &#176;C. For the 1 kg of pine sawdust and iron oxide system, the maximum equilibrium state amount of metallic iron was 23.05 mol at 718 &#176;C, and the minimum system energy consumption per ton Fe was 1.16 GJ at 800 &#176;C and 1.18 GJ at 900 &#176;C. These research results will provide a key basis for a deeper understanding of the intrinsic mechanism of biomass ironmaking.</description>
      <author>Guanyong Sun, C. Guo, Hui Ma, XU Wenlong, Le Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met15010057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental and public health implications of CO2 migration - causal networks as an evaluation tool</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5069864</link>
      <description>Linda Stalker, Karsten Michael, Charles Jenkins, Kate L. Holland, Luk Peeters, Matthew Myers, Andrew S. Ross, Noreen Clarke, SSRN Electronic Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406170840

                In reviewing the literature related to risks of leakage or seepage of CO2 into the near surface, it can become challenging to evaluate what the material risks and consequences might be. This is particularly the case for policy makers, regulators, stakeholders and the general public. IEAGHG commissioned a study to help present some of the well-known canon (to long-term researchers of CCS) in measurement, monitoring and verification of CO2 in the subsurface, and how leakage might result in any material consequences to the environment or public health in the shallow subsurface and surface environments. This was done using a causal network approach to illustrate/review various aspects of what could happen during leakage events and evaluate the likelihood and consequences of those potential events in a consistent manner. The basis of this work was a comprehensive review of previous research related to the environmental impacts of CO2 leakage including natural analogues, controlled-release field trials, geochemical laboratory experiments and numerical modelling studies. Critical aspects for describing and quantifying consequences include CO2 leakage pathways, rates and volumes, sensitivity of environmental receptors, animals and humans, and general climate risks, limits of detection using state of the art equipment and what mitigation options might be available. Causal networks are an effective approach to demonstrating the chain of effects, risks and mitigation strategies for specific target locations for onshore gas developments. A simplified offline tool was developed that uses many of the same workflows to summarize/review different aspects of CCS before highlighting risks, consequences and mitigation strategies that are currently described in the literature. A series of nodes make up the flow path from the major driving force, that is emissions reduction, through to endpoints or impacts. Definitions and detailed reviews underpin each node, and a systematic assessment concludes each nodal section. This allows the reader to consider aspects that are of interest, rather than following a linear and traditional reporting format. The broad conclusion from this work is that while many of the processes are possible, they only have material impacts in rare instances that mostly can be mitigated. It should be noted that this is a global evaluation and that the same workflow may result in a different risk assessment locally for a specific geographic area and project. This key message is important to communicate in a clear, facts-based approach to help the deployment of CCS projects.</description>
      <author>Linda Stalker, Karsten Michael, Charles Jenkins, Kate L. Holland, Luk Peeters, Matthew Myers, Andrew S. Ross, Noreen Clarke</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5069864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Philippines&#8217; Energy Transition: Assessing Emerging Technology Options Using OSeMOSYS (Open-Source Energy Modelling System)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cli13010014</link>
      <description>Lara Dixon, Rudolf Yeganyan, Naomi Tan, Carla Cannone, Mark Howells, Vivien Foster, Fernando Plazas-Ni&#241;o, Climate. 13(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406167139

                The Philippines aspires for a clean energy future but has become increasingly reliant on imported fossil fuels due to rising energy demands. Despite renewable energy targets and a coal moratorium, emissions reductions have yet to materialize. This study evaluates the potential of offshore wind (floating and fixed), floating solar PV, in-stream tidal, and nuclear power to contribute to a Net-Zero energy plan for the Philippines, utilizing the Open-Source Energy Modelling System (OSeMOSYS). Seven scenarios were analyzed, including least-cost, renewable energy targets; Net-Zero emissions; and variations in offshore wind growth and nuclear power integration. Floating solar PV and offshore wind emerged as key decarbonization technologies, with uptake in all scenarios. Achieving Net-Zero CO2 emissions by 2050 proved technically feasible but requires substantial capital, particularly after 2037. Current renewable energy targets are inadequate to induce emissions reductions; and a higher target of ~42% by 2035 was found to be more cost-effective. The addition of nuclear power showed limited cost and emissions benefits. Emissions reductions were projected to mainly occur after 2038, highlighting the need for more immediate policy action. Recommendations include setting a higher renewables target, offshore wind capacity goals, a roadmap for floating solar PV, and better incentives for private investment in renewables and electric transport.</description>
      <author>Lara Dixon, Rudolf Yeganyan, Naomi Tan, Carla Cannone, Mark Howells, Vivien Foster, Fernando Plazas-Ni&#241;o</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cli13010014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-free Energy Transition in Thermal Power Plant:Ammonia Injection Strategies Analysis in Boiler Simulator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15231/jksc.2024.29.4.001</link>
      <description>Sang-Keun Song, Ji Hwan Lee, Hyeong-Bin Moon, Seung-Mo Kim, Gyeong-Min Kim, Chung&#8208;Hwan Jeon, Journal of the Korean Society of Combustion. 29(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406228337

                The International Energy Agency(IEA) predicts that by 2050, hydrogen and ammonia will account for approximately 19% of the global energy demand. Ammonia, with a high hydrogen content and a higher boiling point than hydrogen, presents itself as a favorable energy storage medium. This study investigates the effects of ammonia injection position and coal grade on combustion characteristics and emissions in coal-fired power plants as part of the transition towards carbon neutrality. ADTF(Ammonia Drop Tube Furnace) experiments were conducted to assess NOx, CO2, N2O, and NH3 slip emissions under low-load conditions. The findings from ADTF experiments indicate that ammonia injection position significantly impacts combustion characteristics and emissions. Coal B, a lower grade coal with high volatile matter, exhibited better combustion characteristics and lower UBC emissions compared to Coal A. NOx emissions were influenced by the ammonia injection position, with a low injection position leading to NOx reduction due to the effect of ammonia as a reducing agent in the combustion environment. Mixed coal showed trends similar to Coal A, but it could serve as a solution for utilizing high-grade coal and exhibited better emission levels in some aspects compared to single coal cases. So, underscores the potential of ammonia-coal co-firing in achieving significant emission reductions and enhancing the combustion efficiency of coal-fired boilers.</description>
      <author>Sang-Keun Song, Ji Hwan Lee, Hyeong-Bin Moon, Seung-Mo Kim, Gyeong-Min Kim, Chung&#8208;Hwan Jeon</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15231/jksc.2024.29.4.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Hyphenated &lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt; Infrared and Raman Spectroscopies in Interfacial Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c04419</link>
      <description>Xindi Xu, Weiyi Zhang, Xian&#8208;Yin Ma, Xianxian Qin, Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Hong Li, Yanliang Zhang, Kun Jiang, Wen&#8208;Bin Cai, Analytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406198298

                To address the pressing demand for hyphenated in situ characterization of the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interfaces at the molecular level, we report herein a technical note to demonstrate the hyphenation of in situ electrochemical surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy (SEIRAS) and shell-isolated nanoparticle enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SHINERS). The core setup incorporates a top-down configured Raman optic fiber head loaded on a 3-dimension positioning module and a bottom-up configured attenuated total reflection infrared spectroscopy (ATR-IR) spectroelectrochemical cell accommodated in a custom-designed optical accessory. The feasibility of this integrated design is initially validated by the simultaneous measurement of two model systems, namely, potential dependent adsorption of pyridine on a Au film electrode and the CO2 reduction reaction on a Cu film electrode by in situ SEIRAS and SHINERS, yielding distinct and complementary spectral information.</description>
      <author>Xindi Xu, Weiyi Zhang, Xian&#8208;Yin Ma, Xianxian Qin, Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Hong Li, Yanliang Zhang, Kun Jiang, Wen&#8208;Bin Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c04419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fueling Climate Solutions: A Federal Clean Fuel Standard (Cfs) for the USA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095478</link>
      <description>Cato Sandford, Chris Malins, Maria Cecilia P. Moura, J. L. Martin, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406306068

                A clean fuel standard (CFS) is a regulatory instrument that aims to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from the use of transportation fuel. It establishes a lifecycle emissions benchmark (the 'compliance schedule') against which fuels may be rewarded or penalized. This paper explains the CFS mechanism and examines the prospects for a national CFS in the USA that covers road and aviation segments. We introduce the CFS Scenario Compliance Model (CSCM), and two ambitious scenarios of transportation decarbonization which are consistent with an economy that reaches net zero emissions in 2050. Our 'High-ZEV' scenario is characterized by rapid transition of the vehicle fleet, while the 'High-Liquid' scenario emphasizes rapid scale-up of next-generation fuel production. These scenarios achieve a 87-94% reduction in road transportation carbon intensity by 2050. In addition, we model an ~84% reduction for aviation fuel (this includes carbon removals, but excludes the climate impact of aviation's non-CO2 emissions). Policy considerations for the design of a national CFS in the USA include the ambition of target-setting, investment support, and use of feedstock caps to mitigate sustainability risks. Cross-sectoral linkages mean that target-setting in transportation policy should be coupled with transitions towards renewable electricity and climate-efficient farming practices.</description>
      <author>Cato Sandford, Chris Malins, Maria Cecilia P. Moura, J. L. Martin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of a Turbulent Non-premixed Combustion Model for the Design of an Ammonia-fueled Burner</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15231/jksc.2024.29.4.108</link>
      <description>Gibeom Park, Won Yang, Taeyoung Chae, Changkook Ryu, Journal of the Korean Society of Combustion. 29(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406228341

                Ammonia has emerged as a carbon-free fuel to replace conventional fossil fuels for CO2 emission reduction. However, it has a low flame speed, low flame temperature, and potential for high NOx emissions compared to conventional fuels. Computation fluid dynamics(CFD) can play a key role in developing industrial ammonia-fueled burners to achieve stable ignition and suppress NOx-forming reactions. However, the large computational domain restricts the use of advanced models such as eddy dissipation concept(EDC) for consideration of the detailed reaction mechanism with turbulence-chemistry interaction. In this study, the performance of the steady and unsteady diffusion flamelet models(S/UDFM) for ammonia combustion was evaluated in a 80 kWth non-premixed swirl burner. Although S/UDFM overestimated N2O emissions, it effectively captured NOx and ammonia emission trends similar to that of EDC under different combustion conditions. When compared to experiments, S/UDFM predicted NO and NH3 emission trend effectively, making it a computationally efficient reaction model for CFD applications to design evaluation of industrial ammonia combustion systems.</description>
      <author>Gibeom Park, Won Yang, Taeyoung Chae, Changkook Ryu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15231/jksc.2024.29.4.108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation and Reactivity of Silicon Oxyhydrides in Nickel Hydrogenation Catalysts Supported on Silica</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2025-bd0d8</link>
      <description>Bram T. Kapp&#233;, Robin Vogel, Jaap N. Louwen, Bettina Baumgartner, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Matteo Monai, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406182944

                Silica is generally regarded as an inert support in the field of heterogeneous catalysis, including hydrogenation-dehydrogenation catalysis, on which hydrogen spillover is debated. Since supported hydrogenation and dehydrogenation catalysts are generally activated in H2 as reducing gas at medium-high temperatures (350&#8211;500 &#176;C), we suspected that hydride formation could occur during such catalyst pretreatments. In this work, we investigated silicon oxyhydride (SiHxOy, SiHx for brevity) formation during the reduction pretreatment of a set of Ni/SiO2 catalyst materials using in situ diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS). We observed two distinct vibrational bands located at ~ 2275 and ~ 2257 cm&#8722;1, which we assigned to SiH and SiH2 species, as supported by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Since these vibrational bands are absent after hydrogenation of pure silica, we propose that the formation of hydrides was caused by hydrogen spillover from Ni metal nanoparticles supported on silica. The decrease in the band areas with rising temperature was used in a van t &#8216;Hoff plot to yield enthalpy values of ~ 26 and ~ 42 kJ/mol for the apparent reaction of hydride species, suggesting an equilibrium with IR-inactive or very mobile species. The reactivity of the SiHx species was also investigated, by dosing methanol, water and CO2 as probe molecules on the pre-reduced Ni/SiO2 catalysts. Methanol reacted the fastest with the hydride species, followed by water, while CO2 did not show any interaction with the hydrides. We anticipate this work will contribute to changing the view of silica as an inert support material, and to the understanding of H spillover in more general.</description>
      <author>Bram T. Kapp&#233;, Robin Vogel, Jaap N. Louwen, Bettina Baumgartner, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Matteo Monai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2025-bd0d8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An analysis of the transport impact of finish building on-ramps and off-ramps from the Dnipro embankment to the Darnytskyi Bridge in Kyiv</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56318/as/2.2024.172</link>
      <description>Dmytro Bespalov, Volodymyr Tarasiuk, Mykola Osetrin, Maksym Dorosh, Oleksii Pryimachenko, Architectural studies. 10(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406314881

                This study was aimed at assessing the effectiveness of design solutions for the development of Kyiv&#8217;s transport infrastructure based on transport modelling and analysis of possible socio-economic effects. To do this, a four-step algorithm for modelling transport demand was used, based on data from sociological surveys, territory plans, and forecasts for 2030. The results of the study showed significant changes in the functioning of the Kyiv transport network as a result of the implementation of the proposed design solutions. The transport modelling helped to estimate quantitative indicators such as traffic volumes on major highways, as well as qualitative changes such as reduced congestion, shorter travel times, and cost savings. One of the key results was that the opening of new exits and entrances to the Darnytskyi Bridge on the left bank contributed to a slight increase in bridge capacity, but the biggest effect was seen on the approaches to the bridge. The additional approaches have increased traffic volumes, which indicates improved transport accessibility for drivers using this transport hub. The results related to environmental performance were also important. The reduction in congestion resulted in a reduction in CO2 emissions, which is a significant contribution to improving the environmental situation in the city. In terms of cost-effectiveness, the results demonstrated significant savings in transport losses, confirming that the implementation of the proposed measures has a positive impact on transport infrastructure, as well as reducing financial losses associated with travel. Thus, the results of the study confirmed that the proposed design solutions have a positive impact on the development of the transport network, increasing capacity and reducing negative environmental impact, which opens up opportunities for creating a more efficient transport system that meets the requirements of sustainable development and improves the overall quality of life of Kyiv residents</description>
      <author>Dmytro Bespalov, Volodymyr Tarasiuk, Mykola Osetrin, Maksym Dorosh, Oleksii Pryimachenko</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56318/as/2.2024.172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Unique Reactivity of Cu for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction with a 3-Site Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03157</link>
      <description>Joel B. Varley, Nitish Govindarajan, Joel W. Ager, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406183696

                Cu-based catalysts for the electrochemical reduction of CO2 and CO exhibit a perplexingly unique reactivity toward multicarbon based products compared to other studied electrocatalysts. Here we use insights gained from a recent phenomenological 3-site microkinetic model and grand-canonical density functional theory calculations to clarify the importance of an underemphasized aspect critical to Cu's unique reactivity: a population of so-called "reservoir" sites. Using model Cu surface motifs, we discuss how these types can be represented by undercoordinated structural defects like step edges and grain boundaries which form a network of highly anisotropic migration channels. These pathways are found to be amenable for feeding *CO over time to reactive sites like Cu adatoms more active toward C&#8211;C coupling. These results highlight an often overlooked aspect of catalyst optimization: reservoir site engineering, which exploits surface mobility and presents an equally important avenue for electrocatalyst engineering oversimply maximizing active site densities.</description>
      <author>Joel B. Varley, Nitish Govindarajan, Joel W. Ager</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Near&#8208;Infrared Chromisms of a Heteromerous Overcrowded Ethylene with Large Permanent Dipole Moment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422448</link>
      <description>Akihiro Shimizu, Y. Misaki, Chihiro Kondo, Ayane Kayama, Takashi Hirose, Hiroyasu Sato, Ryo Shintani, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210533

                An overcrowded ethylene composed of electron&#8208;donating anion, naphthoxide, and electron&#8208;accepting cation, acridinium, has been synthesized. It is in equilibrium between a folded conformer having a smaller permanent dipole moment with visible light absorption and a twisted conformer having a larger permanent dipole moment with NIR light absorption. The overcrowded ethylene shows multiple NIR chromisms, such as solvatochromism, thermochromism, mechanochromism, vapochromism, halochromism, and amphoteric electrochromisms, which are caused by the conformational change between folded and twisted conformers or by controlling the energy difference between the HOMO of the donor moiety and the LUMO of the acceptor moiety. The small difference between the HOMO energy level of naphthoxide moiety and the LUMO energy level of acridinium moiety, and their weak interaction are crucial for NIR absorption and large dipole moment in the twisted conformer. The drastic change in the ratio of folded and twisted conformers by changing the polarity of solvents, the detection of CO2, and the disappearance of NIR absorption by electrochemical oxidation and reduction are noteworthy for this new type of organic dye.</description>
      <author>Akihiro Shimizu, Y. Misaki, Chihiro Kondo, Ayane Kayama, Takashi Hirose, Hiroyasu Sato, Ryo Shintani</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Near&#8208;Infrared Chromisms of a Heteromerous Overcrowded Ethylene with Large Permanent Dipole Moment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422448</link>
      <description>Akihiro Shimizu, Y. Misaki, Chihiro Kondo, Ayane Kayama, Takashi Hirose, Hiroyasu Sato, Ryo Shintani, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210534

                An overcrowded ethylene composed of electron&#8208;donating anion, naphthoxide, and electron&#8208;accepting cation, acridinium, has been synthesized. It is in equilibrium between a folded conformer having a smaller permanent dipole moment with visible light absorption and a twisted conformer having a larger permanent dipole moment with NIR light absorption. The overcrowded ethylene shows multiple NIR chromisms, such as solvatochromism, thermochromism, mechanochromism, vapochromism, halochromism, and amphoteric electrochromisms, which are caused by the conformational change between folded and twisted conformers or by controlling the energy difference between the HOMO of the donor moiety and the LUMO of the acceptor moiety. The small difference between the HOMO energy level of naphthoxide moiety and the LUMO energy level of acridinium moiety, and their weak interaction are crucial for NIR absorption and large dipole moment in the twisted conformer. The drastic change in the ratio of folded and twisted conformers by changing the polarity of solvents, the detection of CO2, and the disappearance of NIR absorption by electrochemical oxidation and reduction are noteworthy for this new type of organic dye.</description>
      <author>Akihiro Shimizu, Y. Misaki, Chihiro Kondo, Ayane Kayama, Takashi Hirose, Hiroyasu Sato, Ryo Shintani</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soil smoldering in temperate forests: a neglected contributor to fire carbon emissions revealed by atmospheric mixing ratios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-22-213-2025</link>
      <description>Lilian Vallet, Charbel Abdallah, Thomas Lauvaux, Lilian Joly, Michel Ramonet, Philippe Ciais, Morgan Lopez, Ir&#232;ne Xu&#233;ref-R&#233;my, Florent Mouillot, Biogeosciences. 22(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406337752

                Abstract. Fire is regarded as an essential climate variable, emitting greenhouse gases in the combustion process. Current global assessments of fire emissions traditionally rely on coarse remotely sensed burned-area data, along with biome-specific combustion completeness and emission factors (EFs). However, large uncertainties persist regarding burned areas, biomass affected, and emission factors. Recent increases in resolution have improved previous estimates of burned areas and aboveground biomass while increasing the information content used to derive emission factors, complemented by airborne sensors deployed in the tropics. To date, temperate forests, characterized by a lower fire incidence and stricter aerial surveillance restrictions near wildfires, have received less attention. In this study, we leveraged the distinctive fire season of 2022, which impacted western European temperate forests, to investigate fire emissions monitored by the atmospheric tower network. We examined the role of soil smoldering combustion responsible for higher carbon emissions, locally reported by firefighters but not accounted for in temperate fire emission budgets. We assessed the CO/CO2 ratio released by major fires in the Mediterranean, Atlantic pine, and Atlantic temperate forests of France. Our findings revealed low modified combustion efficiency (MCE) for the two Atlantic temperate regions, supporting the assumption of heavy smoldering combustion. This type of combustion was associated with specific fire characteristics, such as long-lasting thermal fire signals, and affected ecosystems encompassing needle leaf species, peatlands, and superficial lignite deposits in the soils. Thanks to high-resolution data (approximately 10 m) on burned areas, tree biomass, peatlands, and soil organic matter (SOM), we proposed a revised combustion emission framework consistent with the observed MCEs. Our estimates revealed that 6.15 Mt CO2 (&#177;2.65) was emitted, with belowground stock accounting for 51.75 % (&#177;16.05). Additionally, we calculated a total emission of 1.14 Mt CO (&#177;0.61), with 84.85 % (&#177;3.75) originating from belowground combustion. As a result, the carbon emissions from the 2022 fires in France amounted to 7.95 MtCO2-eq (&#177;3.62). These values exceed by 2-fold the Global Fire Assimilation System (GFAS) estimates for the country, reaching 4.18 MtCO2-eq (CO and CO2). Fires represent 1.97 % (&#177;0.89) of the country's annual carbon footprint, corresponding to a reduction of 30 % in the forest carbon sink this year. Consequently, we conclude that current European fire emission estimates should be revised to account for soil combustion in temperate forests. We also recommend the use of atmospheric mixing ratios as an effective monitoring system of prolonged soil fires that have the potential to re-ignite in the following weeks.</description>
      <author>Lilian Vallet, Charbel Abdallah, Thomas Lauvaux, Lilian Joly, Michel Ramonet, Philippe Ciais, Morgan Lopez, Ir&#232;ne Xu&#233;ref-R&#233;my, Florent Mouillot</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-22-213-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telehealth &#8211; Environment Friendly Way to Take Care of IBD Patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202501.0616.v1</link>
      <description>Srdjan Markovi&#263;, Djordje Kralj, Tamara Kne&#382;evi&#263; Ivanovski, Petar Svorcan, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406184574

                Background/Objectives On March 11, 2020, our hospital adapted to the COVID-19 pandemic by becoming a temporary COVID facility, leading to the suspension or delegation of non-COVID services. Among the international IBD community, there were significant concerns regarding the neglect of immunocompromised IBD patients and their increased vulnerability to COVID-19. To address these challenges, the COVID-19 ECCO Taskforce recommended the implementation of telehealth. Following this recommendation, our hospital&amp;#039;s IT department integrated audiovisual hardware and software solutions to facilitate virtual consultations. This approach enabled patients and their local physicians to receive formal reports comparable to those issued during standard in-person care. Methods We retrospectively analyzed data from patients diagnosed with Crohn&#8217;s disease and ulcerative colitis who participated in telemedicine consultations. Average distances and time saved were calculated using Google Maps, while carbon emissions and carbon footprint reductions were determined using tools from CarbonFootprint.com and CO2Meter.com. Results Between August 11, 2021, and June 15, 2023, 107 telehealth consultations were completed. Patients benefited from reduced travel distances, with an average saving of 168.28 km per consultation and a total reduction of 18,006 km. Travel time savings averaged 2 hours and 22 minutes per consultation, amounting to a total of 252 hours saved. The reduction in carbon emissions was calculated at 3.26 tons, equivalent to the annual absorption capacity of 109 fully grown trees, considering an individual tree absorbs approximately 21.77 kg of CO2 annually. These findings underscore telemedicine&#8217;s role in reducing environmental impact while enhancing patient convenience. Conclusions The adoption of telehealth has successfully optimized outpatient clinic operations, maintaining high-quality patient outcomes while contributing to environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>Srdjan Markovi&#263;, Djordje Kralj, Tamara Kne&#382;evi&#263; Ivanovski, Petar Svorcan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202501.0616.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adoption of Electric Vehicles and Forecasting Air Emissions in the Metropolitan Area of Mexico City by 2050</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/wevj16010033</link>
      <description>Rodolfo Sosa Echeverr&#237;a, Graciela Velasco Herrera, Pablo S&#225;nchez &#193;lvarez, E. Hern&#225;ndez, Gilberto Fuentes Garc&#237;a, V&#237;ctor Manuel Velasco Herrera, Rogelio Gonz&#225;lez Oropeza, W. Vicente, Jaime Gandarilla Ibarra, Rodrigo Rivera Rivera, World Electric Vehicle Journal. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406242815

                Densely populated urban megacities, such as the Metropolitan Area of Mexico City, face the ongoing deterioration of air quality. Emissions from industrail factories and internal combustion vehicles are the main sources of pollutants. We have evaluated different transition trends from internal combustion engine vehicles as bus, truck and van, and motorcycle to electric vehicles through 2050. The total vehicle growth follows a second-degree polynomial trend. Bus growth exhibits a linear trend. Truck and van growth display a second-degree polynomial trend. Motorcycle growth also follows a second-degree polynomial trend. We found that the most significant reductions in transportation emissions are observed in CO2, followed by NOx, volatile organic compound (VOC), and particulate matter, with light and heavy vehicles being the primary contributors to total emissions. Mexico City serves as a pilot laboratory where both the challenges and potential solutions to an issue affecting millions of citizens can be observed. If proven effective and practical, these solutions could be applied to other megacities.</description>
      <author>Rodolfo Sosa Echeverr&#237;a, Graciela Velasco Herrera, Pablo S&#225;nchez &#193;lvarez, E. Hern&#225;ndez, Gilberto Fuentes Garc&#237;a, V&#237;ctor Manuel Velasco Herrera, Rogelio Gonz&#225;lez Oropeza, W. Vicente, Jaime Gandarilla Ibarra, Rodrigo Rivera Rivera</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/wevj16010033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Metal-Free Coal-Based Carbon Aerogel Catalyst for Oxygen Reduction to Produce Hydrogen Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03929</link>
      <description>Lingman Xia, Mingsheng Luo, Changke Shao, Yang Zhi, Huanqiao Song, Rehab O. Abdel Rahman, Ziyuan Li, Xing Cui, Wenshuai Yang, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406276876

                In this study, a highly efficient metal-free catalyst derived supported on coal-based carbon aerogel was successfully synthesized for the two-electron transfer oxygen reduction reaction (2e&#8211; ORR) to produce hydrogen peroxide (H2O2). The catalyst, with its high specific surface area and hierarchical porous structure, demonstrated exceptional selectivity for H2O2 under alkaline conditions. By optimization of the synthesis and drying conditions, particularly through the use of supercritical drying technology, the physicochemical properties and selectivity of the catalyst were significantly enhanced. Notably, the coal-based carbon gel obtained through supercritical drying with CO2 exhibited the superior specific surface area over 1311 m2&#183;g&#8211;1. The H2O2 selectivity over 95% at a potential of 0.5 V vs SHE was obtained using the catalyst material synthesized from this study. It was also revealed that the high selectivity was attributed to the layered edge active sites, which are rich in carbonyl (C=O) and carboxyl (COOH) groups. In situ FTIR and Raman spectroscopic analyses confirmed the two-electron-transfer ORR reaction mechanism from this study.</description>
      <author>Lingman Xia, Mingsheng Luo, Changke Shao, Yang Zhi, Huanqiao Song, Rehab O. Abdel Rahman, Ziyuan Li, Xing Cui, Wenshuai Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Technologies for Resource Recovery from Waste: A Case Study for Better Integrating Environmental and Economic Issues</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003561040-4</link>
      <description>Alfredo &#193;vila Galarza, Claudia Yazm&#237;n Ortega Montoya, Norma Lilia L&#243;pez-D&#237;az, Any Lucely Sierra-Negrette, Apple Academic Press eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406198611

                The current linear mode of production and consumption generates high environmental impacts at its final stage. In Mexico, urban waste is managed by local authorities, which is a relevant challenge considering the continuous increase of waste generation, the low efficiency in waste collection, and the high investment needed for a proper final disposal. Organic waste in Mexico is estimated at 56,427 TPD. Anaerobic decomposition of municipal solid waste generates mainly methane, a toxic gas that pollutes the air and has a global warming potential of 22 CO2 eq. At disposal sites, it is important to manage waste properly to control, manage, exploit, and/or mitigate GHG emissions. The use of biogas for power generation can be an alternative to valorize it, reducing GHG emissions to meet the international GHG reduction commitments, considering the importance of this sector in the national emissions inventory. This 50chapter presents an overview of the problem of air emissions related to the waste sector in Mexico and the challenges related with biogas management faced by Mexican municipalities throughout the case study of the generation and energy potential of biogas in San Luis Potos&#237;, a Mexican municipality, analyzing social, legal, and technological barriers obstructing progress and proposing proper solutions.</description>
      <author>Alfredo &#193;vila Galarza, Claudia Yazm&#237;n Ortega Montoya, Norma Lilia L&#243;pez-D&#237;az, Any Lucely Sierra-Negrette</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003561040-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali-Activated Mineral Residues in Construction: Case Studies on Bauxite Residue and Steel Slag Pavement Tiles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18020257</link>
      <description>Lubica Kriskov&#225;, Vilma Ducman, Mojca Loncnar, An&#382;e Tesovnik, Gorazd &#381;ibret, Dimitra Skentzou, Costa Georgopoulos, Materials. 18(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406222396

                This research aimed to investigate the potential of using alkali activation technology to valorize steel slag and bauxite residue for the production of high-performance pavement blocks. By utilizing these industrial by-products, the study seeks to reduce their environmental impact and support the development of sustainable construction materials. Lab-scale testing showed that bauxite pavers showed a decrease in mechanical strength with increasing replacement of ordinary Portland cement. Partial replacement up to 20% still exceeded 30 MPa in compressive strength. Steel slag-based pavers achieved the 30 MPa threshold required for the application with selected mix designs. Pilot-scale production-optimized formulations and standards testing, including freeze&#8211;thaw resistance, confirmed the technical viability of these products. Life cycle analysis indicated a 25&#8211;27% reduction in CO2 emissions for slag-based tiles compared to traditional concrete tiles. Moreover, using industrial residue reduced mineral resource depletion. This study examined the properties of the resulting alkali-activated binders, their ecological benefits, and their performance compared to conventional materials. Through a comprehensive analysis of these applications, our research promotes the circular economy and the advancement of sustainable construction products.</description>
      <author>Lubica Kriskov&#225;, Vilma Ducman, Mojca Loncnar, An&#382;e Tesovnik, Gorazd &#381;ibret, Dimitra Skentzou, Costa Georgopoulos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18020257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flame Retardancy and Heat Shielding in Green Polypropylene Composites Using Biohybrid Fibers and Agro-Waste Fillers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01733</link>
      <description>Thanh Mai Nguyen Tran, M. N. Prabhakar, Lee Dong Woo, Song Jung-il, ACS Applied Bio Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406252855

                The current work presents the flame-retardant performance of hybrid polypropylene composites, reinforced with specific short woven flax fabrics (SWFs), short basalt fibers (BFs), and rice husk powder (RHP), using polypropylene grafted maleic anhydride (MAPP) as the coupling agent. Horizontal burning test (HBT), microcalorimeter test (MCT), and cone calorimeter test (CCT) were conducted on these composites. The formulations used were 25% SWF/PP, 25% SWF/20% BF/PP, and 25% SWF/20% BF/PP with 6% RHP and 25% SWF/20% BF/PP with varying RHP contents (6, 12, and 18%) in combination with 6% MAPP. A peak heat release rate (pHRR) reduction of 14.42% was recorded in microcalorimeter test results. However, cone calorimeter test results indicated a reduction of 80.95% in pHRR and 23.84% in total heat release rate (THR). Furthermore, the emissions of CO and CO2 were reduced by 68 and 67%, respectively, in the 25SWF/20BF/PP.6MAPP-18RHP composite compared to pure PP, indicating an overall improvement in combustion efficiency. Fire performance index (FPI) also improved remarkably: FPI increased by 130% and fire growth index (FGI) improved by 81.34%. Moreover, the horizontal burning test showed an improved performance, with the burning rate further reduced by 11.10% compared to that of the 25% SWF/PP composite. These results highlight the synergy among natural fibers, agro-waste fillers, and MAPP in improving flame retardancy of polypropylene composites, and hence their potential application in automobiles and construction, where the demand for fire safety is very high.</description>
      <author>Thanh Mai Nguyen Tran, M. N. Prabhakar, Lee Dong Woo, Song Jung-il</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planet 2050 and the Future of Manufacturing: Data-Driven Approaches to Sustainable Production in Large Vehicle Manufacturing Plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5023000</link>
      <description>Shakir Syed, SSRN Electronic Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406209158

                This paper explores the future of manufacturing plants in large vehicle manufacturing through the lens of a single large European vehicle manufacturing complex. An example of a plant that originally massmanufactured a single line of products, the complex is currently navigating a shift to more complex mixed model production and the production of electric vehicle powertrains. Using innovative datasets generated through a year-long stakeholder co-design process, a diverse set of partners collectively formed a project to design new, data-driven approaches to the challenge. The project collected and explored diverse data sources, including product bills of materials, facility layout data, current manufacturing system capabilities, energy usage and carbon generation, machine uptime and failures, factory control strategies, planning processes, and product quality data. The paper provides a summary of the explored data, key analyses, feedback from the stakeholders, early technical project interpretations, as well as broader project reflections and contextual descriptions of the factory-particularly of its goals and current challenges. The project supported stakeholders in exploring the potential of digital approaches to transform and facilitate the current manufacturing system's CO2 reduction pathway. The paper concludes by outlining several thematic issues facing large vehicle manufacturing plants.</description>
      <author>Shakir Syed</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5023000</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical to Experimental Investigation: A Waste Utilization Technique for Iron Recovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5089968</link>
      <description>Sonia Abid Bhatti, Xiuchen Qiao, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406213297

                Copper slag and tire char are both large-scale industrial solid wastes, which pose a huge threat to the environment if not treated appropriately. Copper slag has 41 wt.% iron content, which can meet the growing demand of iron and solve its handling problem. Tire char has 97 wt.% fixed carbon thus can be used as a reductant along with CaCO3 and Ca(OH)2 as additives in carbothermal reduction process. Results showed that 0.11 moles of CaCO3 and Ca(OH)2 at 900 oC for 60 minutes give 98.9% and 95.4% iron recovery respectively. Microstructural evaluation of the product demonstrated that fayalite was converted to metallic iron through tire char reductant, along with CO2 from CaCO3 and H2 from Ca(OH)2 also played their parts for the reducing, decomposing, grain growing processes and releasing of iron from complex iron-hosting mineral i.e., fayalite. Aspen plus simulation indicated 0.69 mole ratio of calcium salts recovers 99% Fe from copper slag which is quite similar to the experimental investigation. By offering a new and environmental friendly approach for detailed investigation of iron recovery from copper slag, this study provides a technical route for handling copper slag waste.</description>
      <author>Sonia Abid Bhatti, Xiuchen Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5089968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Performance of Fixed 3D-Printed and Dynamic Fabric Modules in a Second-Skin Fa&#231;ade System: A Residential Case Study in Southern Italy at Building and District Scales</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15020189</link>
      <description>Yorgos Spanodimitriou, Giovanni Ciampi, Luigi Tufano, Michelangelo Scorpio, Sergio Sibilio, Buildings. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406233165

                The building sector accounts for 30% of worldwide final energy usage and 26% of global energy-linked emissions. In construction, innovative materials and systems can offer flexible, lightweight, energy-efficient solutions to achieve more efficient buildings. This study addresses the energy analysis and environmental impacts of retrofitting residential buildings in Monterusciello, Italy, using an innovative second-skin fa&#231;ade system design that incorporates 3D-printed and fabric modules. The purpose is to enhance energy efficiency and reduce the environmental impact of residential buildings originally constructed with prefabricated elements that have degraded over time. This research employed TRNSYS modelling to simulate energy consumption and environmental impacts at the single-building and whole-district levels, analysing the system&#8217;s effectiveness in reducing cooling and heating demands and using different materials for optimal performance. The results show that retrofitting with the second-skin fa&#231;ade system significantly reduces cooling energy demand by 30.2% and thermal energy demand by 3.84%, reaching a primary energy saving of 16.4% and 285 tons of CO2 emissions reduction for the whole district. The results highlight the potential of second-skin fa&#231;ade systems in improving energy efficiency and environmental sustainability, suggesting future research directions in material innovation and adaptive system development for district-wide applications.</description>
      <author>Yorgos Spanodimitriou, Giovanni Ciampi, Luigi Tufano, Michelangelo Scorpio, Sergio Sibilio</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15020189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NADPH oxidase 2 small molecule inhibitors as a therapeutic strategy in the treatment of Alzheimer&#8217;s disease</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/alz.086492</link>
      <description>Jenna M Peretin, Christopher M. Dustin, Maria Eugenia Cifuentes-Pagano, Patrick J. Pagano, Alberto L. Vazquez, Alzheimer s &amp; Dementia. 20(S6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406224515

                Abstract Background Alzheimer&#8217;s disease (AD) is a progressive neurodegenerative disease associated with neuroinflammation and heightened production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) in the brain from overactive NADPH Oxidase 2 (NOX2). The current study examines whether administration of a novel, brain&#8208;penetrant NOX2 inhibitor (CPP11G &amp; CPP11H) reduces amyloid plaque load and improves AD&#8208;associated vascular dysfunction in a male APP&#8208;PS1 mouse model of AD. Method Intraperitoneal injections of CPP11G (n = 1) or CPP11H (n = 2) three times per week began at 9&#8208;10 months of age in the treatment APP&#8208;PS1 group (15 mg/kg). The control group of age&#8208;matched APP&#8208;PS1 mice received no treatment (n = 7). All mice were implanted with a 5mm cranial window for awake optical imaging at least 2 weeks prior to onset of treatment. Two&#8208;photon microscopy was performed to assess longitudinal changes in amyloid plaque deposition after weekly Methoxy&#8208;04 administration (1 mg/kg). Changes in plaque load were quantified weekly and averaged monthly. Additionally, wide&#8208;field optical imaging at 620nm was performed with a 90s, 8% CO2 hypercapnic challenge. This imaging wavelength is sensitive to changes in blood oxygenation (OIS&#8208;BOLD) to capture changes in vascular reactivity over time. Result Treatment with CPP11G/H shows a trend toward reduction in cortical plaque load when compared to an untreated cohort (Fig. 1). OIS&#8208;BOLD results for vascular reactivity studies show a slight trend of improved vascular function over time with CPP11G/H treatment (Fig. 2). Conclusion Our preliminary findings show a strong trend in amyloid plaque reduction with ongoing CPP11G/H treatment in older&#8208;aged AD mice and improved vascular function. Ongoing studies to increase the size of the treated cohort will reveal the reliability and statistical significance of CPP11G/H&#8217;s therapeutic benefits. We are also examining the impact of treatment on microglia activation and gliosis in APP&#8208;PS1::CX3CR1&#8208;GFP mice (Fig. 3).</description>
      <author>Jenna M Peretin, Christopher M. Dustin, Maria Eugenia Cifuentes-Pagano, Patrick J. Pagano, Alberto L. Vazquez</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/alz.086492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Carbon Footprint of Clothing Considering the Relationship Between Clothing Layering and Heating Usage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020470</link>
      <description>Toshiro Semba, Atsushi Inaba, Ryuzo Furukawa, Norihiro Itsubo, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406234276

                Approximately 20% of CO2 emissions from Japanese households are attributed to heating usage. Consequently, as part of its climate change policy, the Ministry of the Environment has promoted the &#8220;WARM BIZ&#8221; campaign, which encourages setting room temperatures to about 20 &#176;C during heating, through practices such as layering clothing. However, according to the Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) of clothing, the environmental impacts of clothing production, washing, and drying are significant. Therefore, it is essential to evaluate heating usage within the clothing lifecycle to assess the greenhouse gas (GHG) emission reduction effect of practicing WARM BIZ. In this study, we calculated the household heating energy consumption in four regions of Japan, and, by incorporating these data, estimated the GHG emissions over the clothing&#8217;s lifecycle, from production and use to disposal. The results showed that those practicing WARM BIZ had approximately 9 to 26% lower GHG emissions over the entire lifecycle than those who were not. Furthermore, by using the Predicted Mean Vote (PMV) index, it was shown that by adding a light long-sleeved shirt (0.18 clo), light long pants (0.18 clo), and a cardigan (0.37 clo) to the standard clothing scenario, the room temperature could be set 3.1 &#176;C lower than the current setting, potentially reducing GHG emissions over the entire lifecycle by approximately 18%.</description>
      <author>Toshiro Semba, Atsushi Inaba, Ryuzo Furukawa, Norihiro Itsubo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating climate-related financial policies&#8217; impact on decarbonization with machine learning methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-85127-7</link>
      <description>Paola D&#8217;Orazio, Anh-Duy Pham, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406272712

                Abstract This study examines how Climate-Related Financial Policies (CRFPs) support decarbonization and renewable energy transitions across 87 countries from 2000 to 2023. Using the Policy Sequencing Score (PSS) and a bindingness-weighted adoption indicator, it explores the relationships between CRFPs, CO2 emissions, and Renewable Energy Production (REP) across diverse economic and institutional contexts. Findings reveal significant variation in outcomes. Advanced economies and OECD countries leverage structured policies and robust institutions to achieve steady emissions reductions and REP growth, with diminishing returns at higher policy intensities. Emerging Markets and Developing Economies (EMDEs) face institutional and structural constraints but show strong responsiveness to targeted policies, particularly in Sub-Saharan Africa and South Asia, where renewable energy growth potential is notable. Regions such as Latin America and East Asia display mixed trends, reflecting unique challenges and opportunities. Binding policies prove essential for environmental outcomes, particularly in institutionalized settings, while EMDEs require capacity building and international cooperation to address barriers. This study highlights the importance of tailoring CRFPs to specific contexts, emphasizing policy sequencing, enforcement, and capacity building. By identifying global and regional variations, the findings provide actionable insights for aligning financial systems with climate goals, fostering a sustainable low-carbon transition, and addressing equity challenges.</description>
      <author>Paola D&#8217;Orazio, Anh-Duy Pham</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-85127-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the Carbon Reduction Potential of Urban Parks Under Extreme Heat Events Using Interpretable Machine Learning: A Case Study of Jinan, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos16010079</link>
      <description>Lemin Yu, Wenjun Li, C. Zheng, Xiaowen Lin, Atmosphere. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406343047

                Greenhouse gas emissions are primary drivers of climate change, and the intensification of extreme heat and urban heat island effects poses serious threats to urban ecosystems, public health, and energy consumption. This study systematically evaluated the carbon reduction potential of 369 urban parks in Jinan during extreme heat events using land surface temperature (LST) retrieval, combined with CatBoost + SHAP machine learning methods. Results indicate that the LST in Jinan ranged from 1.77 &#176;C to 59.44 &#176;C, and 278 parks exhibited significant cooling effects, collectively saving 2943 tons of CO2 per day&#8212;offsetting 11.28% of the city&#8217;s fossil fuel emissions. Small parks, such as community parks, demonstrated higher carbon-saving efficiency (CSE), while large ecological parks showed greater carbon-saving intensity (CSI). CSE was strongly correlated with vegetation coverage and surrounding population density, with efficiency increasing when the vegetation index was within 0.3&#8211;0.7 and population density ranged 0&#8211;5000 or 15,000&#8211;22,500 people. CSI was influenced by evapotranspiration and park geometric form, increasing significantly when the park area exceeded 250 hectares or evapotranspiration ranged 2.5&#8211;6.0. However, elevation and albedo negatively impacted both metrics, with the lowest CSI observed when elevation exceeded 150 m or albedo surpassed 18%.</description>
      <author>Lemin Yu, Wenjun Li, C. Zheng, Xiaowen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos16010079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stress Reduced Embedded Die Substrate Structure Fabricated for Heterogeneous Integration Using Selective Laser Ablation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4071/001c.116541</link>
      <description>Masamitsu Matsuura, Tanemasa Asano, Haruichi Kanaya, IMAPSource Proceedings. 2021(DPC)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406198274

                The demand for high-speed, multi-functionality, and miniaturization of devices increases with a general acceptance of mobile communication devices such as smartphones and smartwatches in the next-generation 5G and IoT era. Undoubtedly, the semiconductor package of the mobile communication devices needs to be downsized with keeping function. One of the solutions is embedded die substrate technology, which is able to integrate passive components and active components with the minimum volume in the same body to implement heterogeneous integration. However, in the conventional embedded die substrate, the embedded die is fully covered by the substrate materials. This fact results in the generation of significant residual stress in the embedded components. Accordingly, the stress-sensitive components such as micro electro mechanical systems (MEMS) sensor, bulk acoustic wave (BAW) resonator, and surface acoustic wave (SAW) filter are regarded unsuitable for embedding. In our previous study, we newly developed an embedded die substrate structure having a hollow chamber at both sides of the die to mitigate a severe limitation for the stress-sensitive devices [1]. Measurements of stress in a sensor chip embedded in substrate have indicated a significant reduction in stress achieved by the formation of the hollow chamber. The results have also suggested technology options for further reduction of stress. This paper will report the formation of slots in the resin material at the periphery of the die, which is newly developed for stress-free embedded die. The manufacturing flow of embedded die substrate with a hollow chamber starts from the formation of the cavity core frame using a conventional PCB process. The through-hole cavity is formed on an FR4 core frame by a router. The single-sided adhesive tacky tape, which enables to hold the die, is laminated by a roll laminator at the bottom side of the frame. The die is placed into the cavity with a face-down using a flip-chip bonder. After that, the cavity filling material is laminated by a vacuum laminator from the opposite side of the tacky tape. The die into the cavity is completely covered by filling material and proceed the cure at 190 &#176;C for 60 min. After die embedding, the thin layer of the filling material on the die is removed by CO2 laser ablation. After that, the tacky tape is peeled off at room temperature. Accordingly, both side of the die is exposed into the air, and the die is only held at the peripheral by the filling material. After embedding the die, a 6-um-thick copper redistribution (RDL) layer is formed by a semi-additive process (SAP) to connect the IO pads on the die. Then, the hollow chamber at both sides was formed by using cavity prepreg and FR4 core as a cap layer. Finally, laser via, 2nd copper RDL, solder mask, and singulation proceed, then the embedded die substrate is finalized. As a result, cavities are formed at the topside and bottom side of the die, and the die is mechanically held by the filling material only at the periphery. The above process was applied to embedding a piezo-resistance gauge chip, which is able to measure the stress and its distribution generated at the chip surface and evolution of the stress with the progress of the fabrication steps. After completing the packaging, the measurement was extended to the temperature dependency from -60&#176;C to 100&#176;C. The results clearly showed a significant reduction of residual die stress. They also revealed the effects of the material properties of the filling resin. However, even with low modulus filling material, the residual stress remained more than 22 MPa at 50&#176;C environments. To further reduce stress on the die for stress-free packaging, we newly introduce slits in the filling material at the periphery of the die. CO2 laser pulses were applied around the die to make a through-hole via or a through-hole slit in the filling material. We report a change in stress with the ratio of the slit from zero up to 80% as measured with the piezo-resistance gauge chip. Moreover, the effects of the position of the slit are discussed by taking stress concentration at the corner of the die into consideration. To summarize, this paper reports a newly developed fabrication process of embedded die substrate technology for mechanical stress-free packaging. The characteristic of the laser ablation is fully utilized to form a stress-releasing structure around the embedded die. This new technology will enable heterogeneous integration of stress-sensitive components in an embedded die substrate.</description>
      <author>Masamitsu Matsuura, Tanemasa Asano, Haruichi Kanaya</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4071/001c.116541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of arc quenching ability for SF6 replacements based on time-dependent Elenbaas&#8211;Heller and Boltzmann equations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0246444</link>
      <description>He Ren, Linlin Zhong, Journal of Applied Physics. 137(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406180448

                Sulfur hexafluoride (SF6), a widely used arc quenching medium in the power industry, has been designated as a greenhouse gas, necessitating its reduction and replacement. Identifying eco-friendly alternatives to SF6 is a complex and expensive process, particularly since these alternatives often consist of gas mixtures that may function at varying pressures. In this work, we propose an efficient method for evaluating the arc quenching performance of gases or gas mixtures using the time-dependent Elenbaas&#8211;Heller and Boltzmann equations, which circumvents the computational costs associated with traditional 2D or 3D magnetohydrodynamic arc models. We segment the arc quenching process into four distinct stages: the thermal recovery stage, pre-dielectric recovery stage, post-dielectric recovery stage, and residual-gas cooling stage. To quantitatively assess arc quenching performance, we introduce two key parameters: recovery rate and recovery strength. The recovery rate is defined as the harmonic mean of thermal, pre-dielectric, and post-dielectric recovery rates. The recovery strength is characterized by the harmonic mean of the average recovery voltage, maximum critical electric field strength, and room-temperature dielectric strength. Our method is validated using several SF6 alternatives, including SF6 mixtures, C4F8, C4F7N, C5F10O, and their mixtures with CO2, N2, and O2. The results demonstrate that the coupling of the time-dependent Elenbaas&#8211;Heller and Boltzmann equations well describes the arc decaying process. Moreover, the proposed recovery rate and recovery strength metrics effectively quantify the arc quenching ability, enabling a systematic and efficient evaluation of various gas mixtures for arc interruption performance.</description>
      <author>He Ren, Linlin Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0246444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Combined Effect of Mixed Multi-Microplastic Types on Growth and Yield of Tomato</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/microplastics4010005</link>
      <description>C. U. Emenike, Adeola Adelugba, Mason T. MacDonald, Samuel K. Asiedu, Raphael Ofoe, Lord Abbey, Microplastics. 4(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406184237

                Microplastics (MPs) are plastic particles ranging from 1000 to 5000 &#181;m in diameter, posing a growing environmental and health risk. Composting is an excellent way to add nutrient-rich humus to the soil to boost plant development, but it also pollutes agricultural soil with MPs. Previous research has shown that MPs can threaten plant development, production, and quality, hence they must be studied. This study examined how a mixture of three MP types&#8212;polyethene (PE), polystyrene (PS), and polypropene (PP)&#8212;affected greenhouse tomato plant development. MP types were spiked at 1% w/w (MPs/soil) in tomato pots, whereas non-spiked growth medium was the control. Statistical analysis was conducted using an analysis of variance (ANOVA) and Tukey&#8217;s test (95% confidence) to compare treatments and controls. Soil spiked with MPs increased chlorophyll content (SPAD), transpiration rate, photosynthetic rate, and stomata conductance by 5.16%, 16.71%, 25.81%, and 20.75%, respectively, compared to the control but decreased sub-stomata CO2 concentration by 3.23%. However, MPs did not significantly affect tomato plant morpho-physiological features (p &gt; 0.05). Biochemical analysis of tomato fruits showed significant (p &lt; 0.05) reduction effects of MPs on carotenoid, total flavonoid, and sugar but increased protein, ascorbate, and peroxidase activity. However, there was no significant difference (p &gt; 0.05) in the effects of the combined MPs on total phenolic content. These data imply that whereas MPs did not influence tomato plant physiological and morphological properties, tomato fruit biochemistry was reduced. This raise concerns that an increase in MPs in soils may reduce antioxidant content and negatively affect human health contributing to a decrease in food security.</description>
      <author>C. U. Emenike, Adeola Adelugba, Mason T. MacDonald, Samuel K. Asiedu, Raphael Ofoe, Lord Abbey</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/microplastics4010005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evidence of the Functioning of the &#171;Green&#187; Economy (Case of the USA, Sweden, Costa Rica and Ukraine)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32983/2222-4459-2024-11-36-45</link>
      <description>Olena &#1040;. Shuba, Iryna L. Didorchuk, Serhii D. Velihodskyi, Business Inform. 11(562)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406292836

                The purpose of the article is to analyze the experience of the functioning of the green economy in individual countries of the world. On the example of the USA, Sweden, Costa Rica and Ukraine, the existing global trends in the field of green economy were considered. In the United States, during the study period (1990&#8211;2022), the share of renewable sources increased from 11.8% to 21.5%. In Sweden, more than 50% of energy is produced from renewable energy sources, and the country&#8217;s government aims to completely abandon nuclear energy by 2040 and switch to 100% renewable energy generation. The largest share of energy production in Costa Rica comes from low-carbon energy sources. A significant problem in the field of the green economy of Costa Rica can be defined as the situation with plastic waste. From 1991 to 2022, Ukraine managed to reduce CO2 emissions by almost 80%; the production of energy from renewable sources increased (in 2021, 14% of production). The efficiency of waste processing was at a low level even before the war: as of 2021, only 7% of all waste was recycled. The war disrupted Ukraine&#8217;s existing plans to develop a green economy; the energy infrastructure, including the green components, was damaged. However, Ukraine has prospects for the development of a green economy, given that the recovery and reconstruction of the country will take place with the choice of environmental alternatives. In addition, potential accession to the European Union will require compliance with the current EU regulations in the field of emission reduction and improvement of recycling systems. The prospects for the development of the green economy in the world depend on the action of interrelated factors, including: the development of the energy sector, since renewable energy sources are one of the main priorities for most countries; the emergence of new technologies and the constant improvement of existing ones for the purpose of sorting and processing of secondary raw materials; the incentive policy on the part of the State, which includes legislation, regulations, directives, standards related to various aspects of the development of the green economy. Thus, it can be noted that the world has formed a trend of purposeful policy to support the development of the green economy.</description>
      <author>Olena &#1040;. Shuba, Iryna L. Didorchuk, Serhii D. Velihodskyi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32983/2222-4459-2024-11-36-45</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Implementation of a Distributed IoT System for Monitoring of Gases Emitted by Vehicles That Use Biofuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202501.0505.v1</link>
      <description>Camilo Caraveo, J. A. Suastegui, Leticia Cervantes, Juan Antonio Ruiz-Ochoa, Samantha Jim&#233;nez, Armando P&#233;rez-S&#225;nchez, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406185000

                The global consumption of fossil fuels such as diesel and gasoline represent a considerable per-centage of global emissions, it is important to know for sure the percentage and type of gas emitted, there are many alternative energies that mitigate the production of emissions in different sectors such as the transport sector and the energy sector. The percentage use of hydrogen mixed with gasoline in internal combustion engines is a viable alternative because it helps the com-bustion process, but it is necessary to know the behavior of the engine and determine the carbon footprint, to quantify the benefit of these actions it is necessary to design and implement a network of low-cost sensors that monitor the emissions produced during the combustion processes and provide reliable data that can be used to make a statistical comparison between vehicles. This research proposes two software systems of an architecture (client-server) working in a synchro-nized manner in order to collect and store information in a database. The first software works as the client and runs on an IoT development board called ESP32 in conjunction with esp32 ttgo and communication between both devices is done through the esp now protocol, this software estab-lishes the connection with the physical sensors to detect and collect gas information, the data is sent wirelessly to the web server, the second software works as a server in addition to providing a graphical interface for user control and data visualization from a ground station. The tests were carried out using 100% Mexican gasoline (G100) and a mixture of hydrogen fuel with gasoline (GH) for the hydrogen cell a concentration of 0.0211 ml / gal of electrolytes (80 ml) was used, the same route and vehicle were used at an average acceleration of 40 and 60 km / h, the data obtained are taken every 30 seconds, the process was repeated 3 times and an average emission reduction of 5% and 10% of CO and CO2 respectively was obtained with GH fuel.</description>
      <author>Camilo Caraveo, J. A. Suastegui, Leticia Cervantes, Juan Antonio Ruiz-Ochoa, Samantha Jim&#233;nez, Armando P&#233;rez-S&#225;nchez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202501.0505.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Assessment of the Strategies for Energy Transition in Kenya as a Climate Change Mitigation Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47772/ijriss.2024.8120172</link>
      <description>Bertha Othoche, International Journal of Research and Innovation in Social Science. VIII(XII)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406219453

                Climate change is a global issue affecting communities in different parts of the world. Climate change is associated with extreme weather and climate patterns that affect the general health of the environment and humanity. The causes of climate change are both natural and anthropogenic. The human induced climate change has accelerated the emission of greenhouse gases that in turn cause global warming and climate change. The international community have initiated various interventions to minimize emission of greenhouse gases in order to maintain a healthier environment for sustainable development. One such initiative and/or interventions is the energy transition strategy that involves transition from a purely fossil fuel based to renewable energy-based economy. This paper therefore looks at the energy transition in Kenya. Specifically, the paper covers energy demand and supply, Mt CO2 emission; energy transitions process; constraints and opportunities. Kenya is going through a transition period in the energy sector and at the same time the country is striving to industrialize by the year 2023 being guided by the Country&#8217;s 2010 Constitution and the Vision 2030 which aims at transforming the country into a middle level economy. It is important that as the country strives to industrialize, the energy that drives the economy should be clean to enhance cleaner energy production. The country is a signatory to the landmark agreement of COP21 held in Paris, France in 2015. The country committed to observe the requirements of the Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) to ensure the reduction of emission of greenhouse gases and has put in place various institutional and legal frameworks towards this end. One of the most recent frameworks is the Climate Change Amendment Act, 2023. The main objective of the study is to assess the energy transition process and associated challenges. The study uses an exploratory design and employed descriptive statistics in data analysis. Data was presented in the form of tables, graphs, and themes. The result indicates that energy transition in Kenya is ongoing through specific processes and technologies. The results also confirm existing challenges and recommends sustained effort for sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Bertha Othoche</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47772/ijriss.2024.8120172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Catalyst Surfaces at Work: Introducing Mixed Isotope Operando Infrared Spectroscopy (MIOIRS)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06308</link>
      <description>Matteo Monai, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406170106

                This Perspective focuses on the characterization of supported metal catalysts by operando and CO infrared (IR) spectroscopy. CO IR spectroscopy is a powerful technique for probing catalyst surfaces and is used to identify single-atom catalysts, estimate metal surface availability to the gas phase, and measure catalyst Lewis acidity. However, the interpretation of CO IR spectra on metal surfaces is not trivial and is influenced by dipole&#8211;dipole interactions among CO molecules at medium to high coverage. Such a phenomenon results in spectral distortions, such as intensity transfer among IR bands, the appearance of spurious bands, and shifts in band position. Dipole&#8211;dipole interactions were widely investigated and understood from the 1950s to 1990s, but the implications for operando spectroscopy have been seemingly overlooked in the literature, with a few exceptions. Inspired by seminal studies in the field, I propose here the use of mixed isotopic streams, such as diluted 13CO in 12CO, to reduce dipole coupling effects and retrieve more information from operando IR spectra in reactions involving CO, such as CO oxidation or hydrogenation reactions. Similarly, mixed 13CO2/12CO2 streams may be applied in CO2 hydrogenation, where adsorbed CO is commonly observed. The proposed name of the technique is Mixed Isotope Operando IR Spectroscopy, MIOIRS. In this Perspective, I will first summarize the nature of dipole&#8211;dipole interactions in adsorbed CO layers and their effects on CO IR spectra. Then, I will briefly describe how diluted isotopic mixtures of CO can partially break the coupling among adsorbates and reduce spectral distortion. In both sections, I will give a few showcases of the implications of vibrational coupling in the characterization of heterogeneous catalysts. Finally, I will discuss the possible implications of MIOIRS for the detection and quantification of defect and surface sites on metal nanoparticles, the characterization of bimetallic nanoparticles surfaces, and the kinetics of CO intermediates adsorbed on different active sites. Notably, MIOIRS may be expanded to other reactions in which adsorbates have strong permanent dipoles, such as in self-catalytic reduction for NOx abatement.</description>
      <author>Matteo Monai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering quality education through sustainable and equitable electricity access in African schools</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.12.005</link>
      <description>Magda Moner&#8208;Girona, Fernando Fahl, Georgia Kakoulaki, Dohyung Kim, Iyke Maduako, S. Szab&#243;, Godwell Nhamo, Benjamin K. Sovacool, Daniel J. Weiss, Joule. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406270132

                Context &amp; scaleAlthough most people born this century will be educated in African schools, these schools often lack basic infrastructure, such as electricity and/or lighting. In the face of a rapidly growing school-age population in Africa, the electrification of educational facilities is not just an infrastructural challenge but also a pivotal investment in the continent's future workforce. This study reveals a stark reality: a third of Africa's school-aged children are nearer to schools without electricity, impacting educational quality and access. By mapping over half a million schools across the continent, this research underscores the transformative potential of decentralized solar photovoltaic (PV) systems. Not only could solar PV reduce travel times for millions of students, but it also promises the improvement of reliable services and a significant reduction in CO2 emissions. The strategic electrification of schools could catalyze a myriad of co-benefits, including enhancing educational outcomes, economic prosperity, and environmental sustainability. All this contributes to the achievement of multiple Sustainable Development Goals across the continent.Highlights&#8226;Comprehensive data of over half a million geolocated schools in Africa provided&#8226;PV systems offer clean, reliable, and cost-effective electricity access in schools&#8226;2 billion EUR investment needed to bring electricity to schools&#8226;Electricity can provide e-cooking, and internet services, and reduce travel time by 45 minSummaryAfrica's schools will educate the majority of the 21st century's working population, influencing the global economy. Through combined spatial analysis techniques on over 500,000 schools, we estimate a 2 billion EUR cost to power unelectrified schools with decentralized solar photovoltaic systems. Given the positive effect on children's food security and the growing need for digitalization, ensuring clean electricity access includes both electricity demand for internet connectivity and electric cooking. Our analysis reveals that 32% of African school-aged children live near unelectrified schools, with the nearest electrified school often too far away. The electrification of these facilities would reduce education-seeking trips by an average 45 min by motorized transport or 6 h on foot. This significant time savings, combined with the broader benefits of decentralized energy, can significantly enhance educational access, economic development, and environmental sustainability in Africa.Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Magda Moner&#8208;Girona, Fernando Fahl, Georgia Kakoulaki, Dohyung Kim, Iyke Maduako, S. Szab&#243;, Godwell Nhamo, Benjamin K. Sovacool, Daniel J. Weiss</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.12.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements and Prospects in Personalized Navigation Systems for Knee Arthroplasty: A Literature Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37647/2786-7595-2024-122-3-32-40</link>
      <description>O.&#1052;. Sulyma, V.S. Chornyi, Ye.V. Kozik, TERRA ORTHOPAEDICA. None(3(122))] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406176191

                Introduction. Traditional methods of knee arthroplasty are based on mechanical alignment, which ensures long-term component survival but does not always meet patients&#8217; functional needs. Recent studies indicate that personalized alignment approaches, such as kinematic and functional alignment, can improve functional outcomes and reduce complication rates. These methods consider the natural axes of movement and the anatomy of the knee joint, contributing to the restoration of joint anatomy and function. Individualized navigation systems represent a modern approach to knee arthroplasty using three-dimensional preoperative models based on CT or MRI. This method improves the accuracy of fitting the prosthesis components, considering the patient&#8217;s individual anatomical features and biomechanical parameters. Objective. The objective of this literature review is to analyze the literature on using advanced navigation systems and evaluate their effectiveness, advantages, and prospects in personalizing knee joint arthroplasty. Material and Methods. Using PubMed, Scopus, and Web of Science databases, we reviewed 22 scientific studies on various navigation systems for knee joint arthroplasty. Studies were selected based on patient numbers, statistical significance, clear inclusion and exclusion criteria, and availability of objective treatment outcome data. This allowed for a detailed analysis and comparison of different navigation methods. Results. Total knee arthroplasty (TKA) is one of the most effective surgical treatments for knee osteoarthritis. However, the accuracy of prosthesis implantation remains a critical factor for the long-term success of the surgery. Deviations in placement can lead to increased wear of components and a higher risk of complications. Traditionally, standard tools and techniques based on anatomical landmarks are used for prosthesis placement. In recent years, individualized navigation systems (INS) based on preoperative three-dimensional modeling of the patient&#8217;s individual anatomy have been introduced. INS aim to improve the accuracy of knee joint component placement, reduce time of surgery, and lower the risk of complications. Conclusions. The use of patient-specific surgical instruments and resection tools in primary and revision knee joint arthroplasty improves surgical and rehabilitation outcomes. This development allows for a 30% improvement in implant positioning accuracy and a 10% reduction in CO2 emissions. Standardizing research methods and increasing surgeon experience may contribute to a better understanding of the long-term benefits of individualized navigation systems in knee joint arthroplasty. Despite the identified advantages of INS, further research is needed to determine the long-term clinical outcomes and cost-effectiveness of these systems. The application of INS is especially important in cases of significant deformities and bone defects.</description>
      <author>O.&#1052;. Sulyma, V.S. Chornyi, Ye.V. Kozik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37647/2786-7595-2024-122-3-32-40</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the 10th Year of &lt;i&gt;ACS Energy Letters&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409</link>
      <description>Prashant V. Kamat, ACS Energy Letters. 10(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406248189

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. ACS Energy LettersVol 10/Issue 1Article This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse EditorialJanuary 10, 2025Celebrating the 10th Year of ACS Energy LettersClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Prashant V. Kamat*Prashant V. KamatUniversity of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, Indiana 46556, United States*[email protected]More by Prashant V. Kamathttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-2465-6819Open PDFACS Energy LettersCite this: ACS Energy Lett. 2025, 10, 1, 569&#8211;570Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409Published January 10, 2025 Publication History Received 10 December 2024Accepted 10 December 2024Published online 10 January 2025Published in issue 10 January 2025editorialCopyright &#169; 2025 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS PublicationsCopyright &#169; 2025 American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.BatteriesChemical engineering and industrial chemistryEnergy storageSolar cellsSolar energyIt is with delight that we embark on the tenth year of ACS Energy Letters. Since the launch of the journal in 2016, we have built an enthusiastic energy community of authors, reviewers and readers. Their continued support has helped us to build a top-tier journal to disseminate new advances in energy research and discuss important scientific issues from the laboratory to the real world.We are pleased to engage with the passionate members of the scientific community who have made impressive progress in recent years to address clean energy challenges. The desire to reduce the carbon footprint has led to many innovative strategies to adopt renewable energy technologies. For example, perovskite solar cells, which showed an increase in efficiency from 14.1% in 2013 to 26.7% in 2024, are now being targeted for large-scale panel production. Si-perovskite-based tandem solar cells have made significant strides, reaching a record efficiency of 34.6%. Similarly, storage batteries have emerged from table-top devices to grid storage, and electrocatalysis is driving CO2 reduction on a pilot plant scale. The next phase of energy research is likely to be dominated with topics such as device stability of solar cells, display devices and electrolyzers, for long-term operation, fast charging of storage batteries, and recycling strategies for solar cells and storage batteries. Fundamental studies exploring properties of new materials for energy conversion and storage, and a better understanding of interfacial charge transfer processes in various devices (e.g., solar cells, storage batteries and LEDs), will also see a major growth in research.The growth of ACS Energy Letters during its first ten years can be seen from the increase in number of published articles as well as their growing impact (Figure 1). In addition to Letters, Perspectives and Reviews, we regularly publish Viewpoints and Energy Focus articles. These features offer our authors a unique opportunity to engage in scientific discussions. We also regularly feature Collections that compile key papers on an emerging topic. Each year, we also highlight contributions of women scientists along with their inspiring thoughts. Having anchored with these popular features during this early period, we plan to grow in the coming years by attracting new authors and readers.Figure 1Figure 1. Growth of ACS Energy Letters as seen from the published articles (all types) and citations. (* indicates incomplete data of 2024). Source: Web of Science, Clarivate Analytics, December 10, 2024.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideThe success of the journal stems from our Editorial Advisory Board members, who regularly provide feedback to our editorial team. Special thanks to EAB members Leif Hammarstr&#246;m, Uppsala University, Sweden, Dongling Ma, Institut National de la Recherche Scientifique, Canada, Bryan D. McCloskey, University of California Berkeley, USA, Iv&#225;n Mora Ser&#243;, Universitat Jaume I, Spain, Edward (Ted) Sargent, Northwestern University, USA, and Yi-Jun Xu, Fuzhou University, China, who have completed their terms. We welcome new EAB members, Juan-Pablo Correa-Baena, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, USA, Satish A. Patil, Solid State and Structural Chemistry Unit, Indian Institute of Science, India, Lorenzo Malavasi, Chemistry Department, University of Pavia, Italy, Ji-Hyun Jang, School of Energy and Chemical Engineering, UNIST, Republic of Korea, Partha P. Mukherjee, School of Mechanical Engineering, Purdue University, USA, Lakshminarayana Polavarapu, Department of Physical Chemistry, University of Vigo, Spain, Venkataraman Thangadurai, School of Chemistry, University of St Andrews, United Kingdom, and Ranjani Viswanatha, International Centre for Materials Science and New Chemistry Unit, Jawaharlal Nehru Centre for Advanced Scientific Research, India. By having a good mix of senior and younger scientists from around the globe on our EAB board, we are able to seek a wide range of views on the journal's progress.I also take the opportunity to thank Rapha&#235;le Cl&#233;ment, University of California Santa Barbara, USA, who has completed her term as a Topic Editor. Her expertise in storage batteries helped us to publish several outstanding papers. Dinesh Kabra, Physics Department, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, India, and Ya You, International School of Materials Science and Engineering and School of Materials Science and Microelectronics, Wuhan University of Technology, China, will now join our editorial team as Topic Editors. Filippo De Angelis, University of Perugia, Italy, and Yang-Kook Sun, Hanyang University, Republic of Korea, will now serve as Executive Editors. They will take additional responsibilities to manage the editorial manuscript flow and engage in improving the invited content of the journal. Together our editorial team will continue to work with our authors and reviewers to maintain high-quality topical content in the journal.As part of our 10th year celebration, we will publish several exciting features throughout the year. Two such Energy Focus features published in this issue include, (i) Women Scientists at the Forefront of Energy Research: Part 7 and (ii) A Conversation with Ib Chorkendorff.On behalf of our entire editorial team, I would like to wish everyone a happy new year!Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorPrashant V. Kamat, Editor-in-Chief, ACS Energy Letters, University of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, Indiana 46556, United States, https://orcid.org/0000-0002-2465-6819, Email: [email protected]NotesViews expressed in this editorial are those of the author and not necessarily the views of the ACS.Cited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferences Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsACS Energy LettersCite this: ACS Energy Lett. 2025, 10, 1, 569&#8211;570Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409Published January 10, 2025 Publication History Received 10 December 2024Accepted 10 December 2024Published online 10 January 2025Published in issue 10 January 2025Copyright &#169; 2025 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesFigure 1Figure 1. Growth of ACS Energy Letters as seen from the published articles (all types) and citations. (* indicates incomplete data of 2024). Source: Web of Science, Clarivate Analytics, December 10, 2024.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideThis publication has no References.</description>
      <author>Prashant V. Kamat</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of micro-scale characteristics of shale reservoirs on gasdepletion behavior: A microscale discrete model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2025.02.06</link>
      <description>Wangxing Cheng, Y. Jay Guo, Guanglei Cui, Derek Elsworth, Yuling Tan, Zhejun Pan, ADVANCES IN GEO-ENERGY RESEARCH. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406336208

                Shale gas has become increasingly significant in the global energy supply. Mineral heterogeneity in shales importantly impacts gas transport within the shale matrix and therefore the depletion history curve. A microscale discrete coupling model is introduced to clarify mass transfer and mechanical interactions, as well as their impact on gas transport properties, ranging from individual mineral through ensemble field scale. The model uses a mineral morphology thin-section obtained through tescan integrated mineral analyzer with the mechanical parameters, controlling both elastic and viscosity behavior of each mineral, achieved through nanoindentation. A coupled model for poromechanical evolution is proposed and solved using COMSOL. The applicability of the model results are validated against field data using a dimensionless approach. This confirms that in the early stages of gas depletion, gas is primarily liberated from inorganic minerals, whereas in later stages, it is predominantly sourced from adsorbed gas from the organic matter. Over time, the permeability of the inorganic minerals decreases, and a higher Young's modulus of the minerals results in a greater ultimate permeability ratio. Evolution of the effective diffusion coefficient for the organic matter is controlled by multiple components. A negative correlation exists between mineral grain size and the creep effects, indicating that larger grain sizes result in smaller creep magnitudes during gas production. The Young's modulus of inorganic matter is inversely correlated with the diffusion coefficient, while an increase in the Young's modulus in the organic matter corresponds to a higher diffusion coefficient. The proposed model complements the traditional continuum dual-medium method and provides a clearer understanding of the interactions between minerals during gas depletion behavior. Document Type: Original article Cited as: Cheng, W., Guo, Y., Cui, G., Elsworth, D., Tan, Y., Pan, Z. Impact of micro-scale characteristics of shale reservoirs on gas depletion behavior: A microscale discrete model. Advances in Geo-Energy Research, 2025, 15(2): 143-157. https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2025.02.06 References Abdallah, Y., Vandamme, M., Chateau, C., et al. Linking elastic properties of various carbonate rocks to their microstructure by coupling nanoindentation and SEM-EDS. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2023, 170: 105456. Abedi, S., Slim, M., Ulm, F.-J. Nanomechanics of organic-rich shales: The role of thermal maturity and organic matter content on texture. Acta Geotechnica, 2016, 11(4): 775-787. Aguilera, R. Incorporating capillary pressure, pore throat aperture radii, height above free-water table, and Winland r35 values on Pickett plots. AAPG Bulletin, 2002, 86(4): 605-624. Al Ismail, M. I., Zoback, M. D. Effects of rock mineralogy and pore structure on stress-dependent permeability of shale samples. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society A, 2016, 374(2078): 20150428. Ambrose, R. J., Hartman, R. C., Diaz-Campos, M., et al. New pore-scale considerations for shale gas in place calculations. Paper SPE 131772 Presented at the SPE Unconventional Gas Conference, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA, 23-25, February, 2010. Chalmers, G. R., Ross, D. J., Bustin, R. M. Geological controls on matrix permeability of Devonian Gas Shales in the Horn River and Liard basins, northeastern British Columbia, Canada. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2012, 103: 120-131. Chen, D., Pan, Z., Ye, Z. Dependence of gas shale fracture permeability on effective stress and reservoir pressure: Model match and insights. Fuel, 2015a, 139: 383-392. Chen, F., Duan, Y., Wang, K., et al. A novel pressure transient response model considering multiple migration mechanisms in shale gas reservoir. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2015b, 22: 321-334. Chen, T., Feng, X.-T., Cui, G., et al. Experimental study of permeability change of organic-rich gas shales under high effective stress. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2019, 64: 1-14. Coq Germanicus, R., Mercier, D., Agrebi, F., et al. Quantitative mapping of high modulus materials at the nanoscale: Comparative study between atomic force microscopy and nanoindentation. Journal of Microscopy, 2020, 280(1): 51-62. Cui, G., Liu, J., Wei, M., et al. Evolution of permeability during the process of shale gas extraction. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2018a, 49: 94-109. Cui, G., Liu, J., Wei, M., et al. Why shale permeability changes under variable effective stresses: New insights. Fuel, 2018b, 213: 55-71. Cui, G., Tan, Y., Chen, T., et al. Multidomain two-phase f low model to study the impacts of hydraulic fracturing on shale gas production. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2020a, 34(4): 4273-4288. Cui, G., Feng, X., Pan, Z., et al. Impact of shale matrix mechanical interactions on gas transport during production. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering, 2020b, 184: 106524. Day-Stirrat, R. J., Dutton, S. P., Milliken, K. L., et al. Fabric anisotropy induced by primary depositional variations in the silt: Clay ratio in two fine-grained slope fan complexes: Texas Gulf Coast and northern North Sea. Sedimentary Geology, 2010, 226(1-4): 42-53. Eliyahu, M., Emmanuel, S., Day-Stirrat, R. J., et al. Mechanical properties of organic matter in shales mapped at the nanometer scale. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 2015, 59: 294-304. Feng, X., Yang, C., He, B., et al. Artificial intelligence technology in rock mechanics and rock engineering. Deep Resources Engineering, 2024, 1(2): 100008. Gao, Z., Fan, Y., Xuan, Q., et al. A review of shale pore structure evolution characteristics with increasing thermal maturities. Advances in Geo-Energy Research, 2020, 4(3): 247-259. Geng, L., Li, G., Zitha, P., et al. A diffusion-viscous flow model for simulating shale gas transport in nano-pores. Fuel, 2016, 181: 887-894. Javadpour, F. Nanopores and apparent permeability of gas flow in mudrocks (shales and siltstone). Journal of Canadian Petroleum Technology, 2009, 48(8): 16-21. Jin, Z., Li, W., Jin, C., et al. Anisotropic elastic, strength, and fracture properties of Marcellus shale. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2018, 109: 124-137. Li, S., Dong, M., Li, Z. Measurement and revised interpretation of gas flow behavior in tight reservoir cores. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering, 2009, 65(1-2): 81-88. Li, W., Wang, X., Cheng, J. Measurement of the anisotropic elastic properties of shale: uncertainty analysis and water effect. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 2019, 78: 6075-6087. Liu, J., Chen, Z., Elsworth, D., et al. Evaluation of stress-controlled coal swelling processes. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2010a, 83(4): 446-455. Liu, J., Chen, Z., Elsworth, D., et al. Linking gas-sorption induced changes in coal permeability to directional strains through a modulus reduction ratio. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2010b, 83(1): 21-30. Liu, X., Chen, L., Sheng, J., et al. A Non-Equilibrium multiphysics model for coal seam gas extraction. Fuel, 2023a, 331: 125942. Liu, Y., Burch, A. C., Bennett, K. C., et al. Bridging nanoindentation and triaxial creep tests on a shale. Acta Geotechnica, 2023b, 18(12): 6475-6487. Loucks, R. G., Reed, R. M., Ruppel, S. C., et al. Morphology, genesis, and distribution of nanometer-scale pores in siliceous mudstones of the mississippian barnett shale. Journal of Sedimentary Research, 2009, 79(12): 848-861. Monteiro, P. J., Rycroft, C. H., Barenblatt, G. I. A mathematical model of fluid and gas flow in nanoporous media. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of USA, 2012, 109(50): 20309-20313. Oliver, W. C., Pharr G. M. An improved technique for determining hardness and elastic modulus using load and displacement sensing indentation experiments. Journal of Materials Research, 1992, 7(6): 1564-1583. Palmer, I., Mansoori, J. How permeability depends on stress and pore pressure in coalbeds: A new model. SPE Reservoir Evaluation &amp; Engineering, 1998, 1(6): 539-544. Peng, Y., Liu, J., Pan, Z., et al. A sequential model of shale gas transport under the influence of fully coupled multiple processes. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2015, 27: 808-821. Qu, H., Pan, Z., Peng, Y., et al. Controls on matrix permeability of shale samples from Longmaxi and Niutitang formations, China. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2016, 33: 599-610. Schwartz, B., Elsworth, D., Marone, C. Relationships between mechanical and transport properties in Marcellus shale. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2019a, 119: 205-210. Schwartz, B., Huffman, K., Thornton, D., et al. The effects of mineral distribution, pore geometry, and pore density on permeability evolution in gas shales. Fuel, 2019b, 257: 116005. Shi, R., Liu, J., Wang, X., et al. A critical analysis of shale laboratory permeability evolution data. Energy, 2021, 236: 121405. Tahmasebi, P., Javadpour, F., Enayati, S. F. Digital rock techniques to study shale permeability: A mini-review. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2020, 34(12): 15672-15685. Tian, H., Pan, L., Xiao, X., et al. A preliminary study on the pore characterization of Lower Silurian black shales in the Chuandong Thrust Fold Belt, southwestern China using low pressure N2 adsorption and FE-SEM methods. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 2013, 48: 8-19. Wang, L., Liu, B., Bai, L., et al. Pore evolution modeling in natural lacustrine shale influenced by mineral composition: Implications for shale oil exploration and CO2 storage. Advances in Geo-Energy Research, 2024a, 13(3): 218-230. Wang, S., Wu, Z., Chen, J., et al. Study of the effect of mineral components on the permeability impairment rate and stress sensitivity factor of shale. Geofluids, 2022, 2022(1): 4407252. Wang, W., Chen, T., Cui, G., et al. New approach for predicting time-dependent deformation of shale rock: a modified fractional-order creep constitutive model. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 2024b, 83(6): 1-21. Wang, Y., Dong, D., Yang, H., et al. Quantitative characterization of reservoir space in the Lower Silurian Longmaxi Shale, southern Sichuan, China. Science China Earth Sciences, 2013, 57: 313-322. Xie, J., Xiong, W., Tan, Y., et al. Effects of Anisotropic Permeability Evolution on Shale Gas Production: An Internal Swelling Factor Model. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2022, 36(2): 771-785. Yang, C., Xiong, Y., Wang, J., et al. Mechanical characterization of shale matrix minerals using phase-positioned nanoindentation and nano-dynamic mechanical analysis. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2020, 229: 103571. Yang, F., Ning, Z., Liu, H. Fractal characteristics of shales from a shale gas reservoir in the Sichuan Basin, China. Fuel, 2014, 115: 378-384. Yang, F., Xu, S., Hao, F., et al. Petrophysical characteristics of shales with different lithofacies in Jiaoshiba area, Sichuan Basin, China: Implications for shale gas accumulation mechanism. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 2019, 109: 394-407. Yang, R., Liu, X., Yu, R., et al. Long short-term memory suggests a model for predicting shale gas production. Applied Energy, 2022, 322: 119415. Yuan, Y., Rezaee, R., Verrall, M., et al. Pore characterization and clay bound water assessment in shale with a combination of NMR and low-pressure nitrogen gas adsorption. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2018, 194: 11-21. Zhang, H., Liu, J., Elsworth, D. How sorption-induced matrix deformation affects gas flow in coal seams: A new FE model. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2008, 45(8): 1226-1236. Zhang, L., Li, D., Li, L., et al. Development of a new compositional model with multi-component sorption isotherm and slip flow in tight gas reservoirs. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2014, 21: 1061-1072. Zhang, T., Li, X., Shi, J., et al. An apparent liquid permeability model of dual-wettability nanoporous media: A case study of shale. Chemical Engineering Science, 2018, 187: 280-291. Zhang, W., Zhang, D., Zhao, J. Experimental investigation of water sensitivity effects on microscale mechanical behavior of shale. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2021, 145: 104837. Zhao, P., Cai, J., Huang, Z., et al. Estimating permeability of shale-gas reservoirs from porosity and rock compositions. Geophysics, 2018, 83(5): MR283-MR294. Zhu, X., Cai, J., Wang, G., et al. Role of organo-clay composites in hydrocarbon generation of shale. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2018, 192: 83-90. DOI: https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2025.02.06</description>
      <author>Wangxing Cheng, Y. Jay Guo, Guanglei Cui, Derek Elsworth, Yuling Tan, Zhejun Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2025.02.06</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
