<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:41:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic sponges for wastewater treatment, carbon dioxide reduction, and hydrogen production: a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10311-024-01696-5</link>
      <description>Akash Balakrishnan, Meenu Mariam Jacob, Mahendra Chinthala, Nanditha Dayanandan, M. N. Ponnuswamy, Dai&#8208;Viet N. Vo, Environmental Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391881021

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akash Balakrishnan, Meenu Mariam Jacob, Mahendra Chinthala, Nanditha Dayanandan, M. N. Ponnuswamy, Dai&#8208;Viet N. Vo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10311-024-01696-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benzyl alcohol promoted electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide and C2 production by Cu2O/Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149800</link>
      <description>Qianqian Wang, Xinfa Wei, Yan Li, Juanjuan Luo, Lisong Chen, Jianlin Shi, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391896197

                Oxide-derived copper (OD-Cu)-based materials containing Cu&#948;+ (0 &lt; &#948; &#8804; 1) have been considered as promising electrocatalysts for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (ECO2RR) to produce valuable C2 products, which, however, suffer from poor stability, mainly due to the inevitable reduction of Cu&#948;+. We report here that the benzyl alcohol (BA) introduced in catholyte presents a markedly positive effect on the durability and C2 selectivity enhancement of ECO2RR when OD-Cu-based material is adopted as cathode electrocatalyst. The critical evidence of ECO2RR intermediates has been provided by in situ Raman and FTIR spectroscopy, which reveals the surface mechanisms of BA-assisted ECO2RR over OD-Cu catalysts. On the one hand, the introduction of BA increases the CO2 supply for ECO2RR by slowing down its neutralizing reaction, which results in the increased intermediate species coverage on the catalytic surface therefore the delayed self-reduction of Cu&#948;+; On the other hand, the interaction between BA and the intermediate species *CO during ECO2RR brings an enhanced selectivity of C2 products (FE C2 = 85.5 % at &#8722;1.38 V vs RHE). Besides, an energy-savings and economic electrolyzer can be achieved by coupling anodic BA oxidation reaction to benzoic acid and ECO2RR to C2 products with much lowered cell voltages.</description>
      <author>Qianqian Wang, Xinfa Wei, Yan Li, Juanjuan Luo, Lisong Chen, Jianlin Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar fuels design: Porous cathodes modeling for electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction in aqueous electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26442</link>
      <description>Iva Fernandes, Duarte J. Antunes, Rodrigo Martins, Manuel J. Mendes, Ana S. Reis Machado, Heliyon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391912845

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Iva Fernandes, Duarte J. Antunes, Rodrigo Martins, Manuel J. Mendes, Ana S. Reis Machado</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategies to Improve the Activity of Silver&#8208;loaded Calcium Titanate Crystal Photocatalyst for Photocatalytic Reduction of Carbon Dioxide with Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301736</link>
      <description>Hongxuan Qiu, Akira Yamamoto, Hisao Yoshida, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391932224

                The rapid increase of carbon dioxide (CO2) in the atmosphere has sparked a global enthusiasm for carbon recycling. Photocatalytic CO2 reduction with water into carbon&#8208;containing products has attracted much attention since it can convert solar energy to the chemical potential of the products and CO2 to valuable compounds at the same time. One of the main products in the photocatalytic reaction system is carbon monoxide (CO), a useful compound for the one&#8208;carbon chemistry and related ones. The current shortage of this system is the low production efficiency, demanding us to improve the activity of the photocatalyst. In this perspective article, by taking a calcium titanate (CaTiO3, CTO) photocatalyst with silver cocatalyst (Ag/CTO) and so on as examples that can promote the selective photocatalytic CO2 reduction with water, we shortly review some strategies to improve the photocatalytic activity such as fabrication of well&#8208;structured crystal photocatalysts, development of the surface property and cocatalyst, improvement of surface CO2 adsorption, and improvement of photoabsorption. These concepts will be widely applied and contribute to further development of photocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Hongxuan Qiu, Akira Yamamoto, Hisao Yoshida</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of single-atom alloy catalysts in electrochemical conversion of carbon dioxide: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119910</link>
      <description>Jingnan Wang, Keli Zhao, Yi Ding, Yongan Yang, Xi Wu, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933654

                Atomic-scale understanding of C-C coupling in the electrocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable C2 chemicals remains elusive. Herein, we selected Group VIII and IB transition metals as active sites incorporated into the Cu(1 0 0) surface to construct single-atom alloy catalysts. The stability, selectivity, and activity of a series of catalysts were calculated using density functional theory. Fe, Co, Ni, Ru/Cu(1 0 0) exhibit the potential as candidates to generate C2 products and suppress the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The reaction proceeds through the reduction of CO2 to key intermediates *CO and *CHO, which undergoes C-C coupling to generate *CO-CHO, subsequently undergoing different protonation processes to yield diverse C2 products. The rate-determining step for Fe, Co, Ni, and Ru/Cu(1 0 0), is the hydrogenation of *CO, with a comparable energy barrier of 0.8 eV. Moreover, Fe and Co/Cu(1 0 0) favor the formation of C2H4 as the primary product, while Ni and Ru/Cu(1 0 0) predominantly produce CH3COOH.</description>
      <author>Jingnan Wang, Keli Zhao, Yi Ding, Yongan Yang, Xi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative life cycle analysis on ethylene production from electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141348</link>
      <description>Taemin Kim, Pahola Thathiana Benavides, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391934036

                Ethylene is one of the largest greenhouse gas emitters and the most diversly used commodity chemicals globally. Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to ethylene received great attention from the research society to decarbonize the ethylene production. In this study, a life-cycle analysis is conducted using the Greenhouse Gases, Regulated Emissions, and Energy use in Technologies (GREET) model on the three electrocatalytic CO2-reduction pathways (or &#8220;e-ethylene&#8221; pathways): i) cascade conversion via carbon monoxide intermediate; ii) single-step conversion in membrane electrode assembly (MEA); and iii) single-step conversion in alkaline flow cell. The results showed that the electricity consumption is the lowest for the cascade pathway (164 MJ/kg), thus resulting in the lowest cradle-to-gate carbon intensity [18 kgCO2e/kg with United States (US) average grid)] among the three pathways followed by the single-step MEA (32 kgCO2e/kg) and then by the single-step alkaline (56 kgCO2e/kg). However, all three e-ethylene pathways were significantly more carbon-intensive than their fossil-based counterpart (1.1 kgCO2e/kg) due to their excessive energy consumption with the current state of technology. With renewable electricity, all three pathways yielded negative carbon intensity: from &#8722;3.1 kgCO2e/kg to &#8722;1.6 kgCO2e/kg depending on the source of CO2. The threshold carbon intensity of electricity (TCIE), defined as the upper bound of the carbon intensity of electricity to achieve lower carbon intensity for e-ethylene compared to fossil-based ethylene, is calculated for both current and future state of e-ethylene technologies. The cascade pathway had the highest TCIE out of the three e-ethylene pathways for both current (92 gCO2e/kWh) and future (124 gCO2e/kWh) state of technologies. However, the carbon intensity of average US grid (i.e., 467 and 303 gCO2e/kWh for current and future projections) were higher than the TCIEs of the corresponding timeline. Thus, reducing electricity requirement for e-ethylene pathways and bringing low-carbon generation mix in the United States (US) grid faster than the current projection are both essential to decarbonize ethylene and its downstream chemicals/polymers.</description>
      <author>Taemin Kim, Pahola Thathiana Benavides</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances of 2D metal-organic frameworks for electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2024.100043</link>
      <description>Xingcheng Ma, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Xing Wang, Materials Today Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391969766

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingcheng Ma, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Xing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2024.100043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting hydrophilic cupric oxide electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction to methanol via interfacial engineering modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.128</link>
      <description>Xianan Du, Bo Gao, Chunhui Xiao, Hongyang Zhao, Zhongxiao Song, Ki Tae Nam, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391980122

                Copper-based catalysts have been extensively investigated in electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction to promote carbon products generated by requiring multiple electron transfer. However, hydrophilic electrodes are unfavourable for CO2 mass transfer and preferentially hydrogen (H2) evolution in electrochemical CO2 reduction. In this paper, a hydrophilic cupric oxide (CuO) electrode with a grassy morphology was prepared. CuO-derived Cu was confirmed as the active site for electrochemical CO2 reduction through wettability modulation. To enhance the intrinsic catalytic activity, a metal-oxide heterogeneous interface was created by engineering modulation at the interface, involving the loading of palladium (Pd) on CuO (CuO/Pd). Both the electrochemically active area and the electron transfer rate were enhanced by Pd loading, and significantly the reduced work function further facilitated the electron transfer between the electrode surface and the electrolyte. Consequently, the CuO/Pd electrode exhibited excellent excellent performance in electrochemical CO2 reduction, achieving a 54 % Faraday efficiency at &#8722;0.65 V for methanol (CH3OH). The metal-oxide interfacial effect potentially improves the intrinsic catalytic activity of hydrophilic CuO electrodes in electrochemical CO2 reduction, providing a conducive pathway for optimizing hydrophilic oxide electrodes in this process.</description>
      <author>Xianan Du, Bo Gao, Chunhui Xiao, Hongyang Zhao, Zhongxiao Song, Ki Tae Nam</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction and Formic Acid Oxidation by Formal Nickel(I) Complexes of Di&#8208;isopropylphenyl Bis&#8208;iminoacenaphthene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400168</link>
      <description>Vera V. Khrizanforova, Robert R. Fayzullin, Sergey Kartashov, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;, Mikhail Khrizanforov, Tatyana Gerasimova, Yulia H. Budnikova, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391996987

                Processing CO2 into value&#8208;added chemicals and fuels stands as one of the most crucial tasks in addressing the global challenge of the greenhouse effect. In this study, we focused on the complex (dpp&#8208;bian)NiBr2 (where dpp&#8208;bian is di&#8208;isopropylphenyl bis&#8208;iminoacenaphthene) as a precatalyst for the electrochemical reduction of CO2 into CH4 as the sole product. Cyclic voltammetry results indicate that the realization of a catalytically effective pattern requires the three&#8208;electron reduction of (dpp&#8208;bian)NiBr2. The chemically reduced complexes [K(THF)6]+[(dpp&#8208;bian)Ni(COD)]&#8211; and [K(THF)6]+[(dpp&#8208;bian)2Ni]&#8211; were synthesized and structurally characterized. Analyzing the data from the electron paramagnetic resonance study of the complexes in a solution, along with quantum&#8208;chemical calculations, reveals that the spin density is predominantly localized at their metal centers. The superposition of trajectory maps of the electron density gradient field and the one&#8208;electron electrostatic force field, along with the atomic charges, discloses that, within the first coordination sphere, the interatomic charge transfer occurs from the metal atom to the ligand atoms and that the complex anions can thus be formally described by the general formulas (dpp&#8208;bian)2&#8211;Ni+(COD) and (dpp&#8208;bian)2&#8211;Ni+. It was shown that the reduced nickel complexes can be oxidized by formic acid; resulting from this reaction, the two&#8208;electron and two&#8208;proton addition product dpp&#8208;bian&#8208;2H is formed.</description>
      <author>Vera V. Khrizanforova, Robert R. Fayzullin, Sergey Kartashov, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;, Mikhail Khrizanforov, Tatyana Gerasimova, Yulia H. Budnikova</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu2O/SiC photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide to methanol using visible light on InTaO4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108235</link>
      <description>Babalola Aisosa Oni, Samuel Eshorame Sanni, Olusegun Stanley Tomomewo, Shree Om Bade, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 174(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392042616

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Babalola Aisosa Oni, Samuel Eshorame Sanni, Olusegun Stanley Tomomewo, Shree Om Bade</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide Lingual Tonsil Reduction for Obstructive Sleep Apnea: A Feasibility Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.23937/2572-4053.1510043</link>
      <description>Fontenot Andee, Chuan Liu, Dewan Karuna, Journal of sleep disorders and management. 9(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391907254

                Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) is characterized by frequent episodes of upper airway collapse during sleep. The lingual tonsil, when hypertrophic, can contribute to airway obstruction. The purpose of this study was to establish the utility and safety of the carbon dioxide (CO2) laser for tonsillar reduction in the management of OSA.</description>
      <author>Fontenot Andee, Chuan Liu, Dewan Karuna</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.23937/2572-4053.1510043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research of the Impact of Hydrogen Metallurgy Technology on the Reduction of the Chinese Steel Industry&#8217;s Carbon Dioxide Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16051814</link>
      <description>Fang Wan, Jizu Li, Yaling Han, Xilong Yao, Sustainability. 16(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392043913

                The steel industry, which relies heavily on primary energy, is one of the industries with the highest CO2 emissions in China. It is urgent for the industry to identify ways to embark on the path to &#8220;green steel&#8221;. Hydrogen metallurgy technology uses hydrogen as a reducing agent, and its use is an important way to reduce CO2 emissions from long-term steelmaking and ensure the green and sustainable development of the steel industry. Previous research has demonstrated the feasibility and emission reduction effects of hydrogen metallurgy technology; however, further research is needed to dynamically analyze the overall impact of the large-scale development of hydrogen metallurgy technology on future CO2 emissions from the steel industry. This article selects the integrated MARKAL-EFOM system (TIMES) model as its analysis model, constructs a China steel industry hydrogen metallurgy model (TIMES-CSHM), and analyzes the resulting impact of hydrogen metallurgy technology on CO2 emissions. The results indicate that in the business-as-usual scenario (BAU scenario), applying hydrogen metallurgy technology in the period from 2020 to 2050 is expected to reduce emissions by 203 million tons, and make an average 39.85% contribution to reducing the steel industry&#8217;s CO2 emissions. In the carbon emission reduction scenario, applying hydrogen metallurgy technology in the period from 2020 to 2050 is expected to reduce emissions by 353 million tons, contributing an average of 41.32% to steel industry CO2 reduction. This study provides an assessment of how hydrogen metallurgy can reduce CO2 emissions in the steel industry, and also provides a reference for the development of hydrogen metallurgy technology.</description>
      <author>Fang Wan, Jizu Li, Yaling Han, Xilong Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16051814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gallium Nitride&#8208;Based Artificial Photosynthesis Integrated Devices for Solar Hydrogen Generation and Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119600862.ch11</link>
      <description>Baowen Zhou, Peng Zhou, Dong Wu, Zetian Mi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391875089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baowen Zhou, Peng Zhou, Dong Wu, Zetian Mi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119600862.ch11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability Assessment Of Carbon Dioxide Emission Reduction From Energy Use In Cement Production Via Life Cycle Assessment And Ahp</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46799/ajesh.v3i2.240</link>
      <description>Fatimatuz Zahro, Irwan Bagyo, Feni Eka Juliani, Asian Journal of Engineering Social and Health. 3(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391915352

                The cement industry in supporting sustainable development is faced with the challenge of reducing energy consumption, natural resources and emissions generated from its production activities. PT X is one of the cement industries in Indonesia that has a production design capacity of 2.6 million tons/year. PT X's cement production activities use several fossil fuel energy sources and alternative fuels that can produce carbon dioxide emissions that are wasted into the environment. This study aims to identify process units that produce significant impacts to determine alternative environmental improvement scenarios. The method used is Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) as a tool for calculating potential environmental impacts, and AHP as an alternative selection of environmental improvement program scenarios. The scope of the LCA study carried out with the scope of "Cradle to Gate" includes the stages of the raw material extraction process, the production process to the distribution of cement. The resulting potential environmental impact is a total Global Warming Potential (GWP) of 0.20543 tons CO2 eq/ton. The largest potential impact comes from the kiln unit of 0.20221 tons CO2 eq/ton or an impact contribution of 98.43%. Based on the environmental impacts generated, there are 4 alternative programs that can be used to reduce the environmental impacts generated. The selection of alternative program scenarios is based on 3 criteria based on 3 types of respondents. Alternatif program yang memiliki nilai prioritas tertinggi yaitu alternatif program 1 dengan sebesar 35,5%, 38,1%, dan 23,4%.</description>
      <author>Fatimatuz Zahro, Irwan Bagyo, Feni Eka Juliani</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46799/ajesh.v3i2.240</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction by Urea Hangman Mn Terpyridine species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202304218</link>
      <description>Minghong Li, Fang Huang, Ping Zhang, Ying Xiong, Yaping Zhang, F&#277;i Li, Cheng Huang Lin, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391881952

                Based on our previous study in chemical subtleties of the proton tunneling distance for metal hydride formation (PTD&#8208;MH) to regulate the selectivity of CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), we have developed a family of Mn terpyridine derivatives, in which urea groups functioning as multipoint hydrogen&#8208;bonding hangman to accelerate the reaction rate. We found that such changes to the second coordination sphere significantly increased the turnover frequency (TOF) for CO2 reduction to ca. 360 s&#8208;1 with this family of molecular catalysts while maintaining high selectivity (ca. 100% &#177; 3) for CO even in the presence of a large amount of phenol as proton source. Notably, the compounds studied in this manuscript all exhibit large value for CO as that achieved by Fe porphyrins derivates, while saving up to 0.55 V in overpotential with respect to the latter.</description>
      <author>Minghong Li, Fang Huang, Ping Zhang, Ying Xiong, Yaping Zhang, F&#277;i Li, Cheng Huang Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202304218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photobreeding oxygen vacancy facilitates phtocatalytic reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126842</link>
      <description>Shuai Li, Yanfeng Zhang, Lei Zhang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391940930

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Li, Yanfeng Zhang, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The implementation of intelligent edification to improve the energy efficiency and CO2 emission&#8217;s reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/c358072.2023.10436172</link>
      <description>Surichaqui Alvarez Sebastian Amulek, Castro Casas Alexis Del Piero, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392008284

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Surichaqui Alvarez Sebastian Amulek, Castro Casas Alexis Del Piero</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/c358072.2023.10436172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Cu-Ligand Interaction for Efficient CO2 Reduction towards Multi-carbon Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc05972c</link>
      <description>Jingyi Chen, Fan Li, Yan Zhao, Haozhou Yang, Di Wang, Bihao Hu, Shibo Xi, Lei Wang, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391967024

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction (CO2R) to valuable products provides a promising strategy to enable CO2 utilization sustainably. Here, we report the strategy of using Cu-DAT (3,5-diamino-1,2,4-triazole) as catalyst precursors for efficient...</description>
      <author>Jingyi Chen, Fan Li, Yan Zhao, Haozhou Yang, Di Wang, Bihao Hu, Shibo Xi, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc05972c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effects of Silica&#8208;Supported Iron&#8210;Cobalt Catalysts for CO2 Reduction to Prebiotic Organics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301218</link>
      <description>Kendra Solveig Belthle, William Martin, Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391926511

                To test the ability of geochemical surfaces in serpentinizing hydrothermal systems to catalyze reactions from which metabolism arose, we investigated H2&#8208;dependent CO2 reduction toward metabolic intermediates over silica&#8208;supported Co&#8210;Fe catalysts. Supported catalysts converted CO2 to various products at 180 &#176;C and 2.0 MPa. The liquid product phase included formate, acetate, and ethanol, while the gaseous product phase consisted of CH4, CO, methanol, and C2&#8210;C7 linear hydrocarbons. The 1/1 ratio CoFe alloy with the same composition as the natural mineral wairauite yielded the highest concentrations of formate (6.0 mM) and acetate (0.8 mM), which are key intermediates in the acetyl&#8208;coenzyme A (acetyl&#8208;CoA) pathway of CO2 fixation. While Co&#8208;rich catalysts were proficient at hydrogenation, yielding mostly CH4, Fe&#8208;rich catalysts favored the formation of CO and methanol. Mechanistic studies indicated intermediate hydrogenation and C&#8210;C coupling activities of alloyed CoFe, in contrast to physical mixtures of both metals. Co in the active site of Co&#8210;Fe catalysts performed a similar reaction as tetrapyrrole&#8208;coordinated Co in the corrinoid iron&#8208;sulfur (CoFeS) methyl transferase in the acetyl&#8208;CoA pathway. In a temperature range characteristic for deeper regions of serpentinizing systems, oxygenate product formation was favored at lower, more biocompatible temperatures.</description>
      <author>Kendra Solveig Belthle, William Martin, Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low&#8208;coordination Nanocrystalline Copper&#8208;based Catalysts through Theory&#8208;guided Electrochemical Restructuring for Selective CO2 Reduction to Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202319936</link>
      <description>Wensheng Fang, Ruihu Lu, Fu-Min Li, Dan Wu, Kaihang Yue, Cong He, Yu Mao, Wei Guo, Bao Yu Xia, Fei Song, Takeshi Yao, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391944406

                Revealing the dynamic reconstruction process and tailoring advanced copper (Cu) catalysts is of paramount significance for promoting the conversion of CO2 into ethylene (C2H4), paving the way for carbon neutralization and facilitating renewable energy storage. In this study, we initially employed density functional theory (DFT) and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations to elucidate the restructuring behavior of a catalyst under electrochemical conditions and delineated its restructuring patterns. Leveraging insights into this restructuring behavior, we devised an efficient, low&#8208;coordination copper&#8208;based catalyst. The resulting synthesized catalyst demonstrated an impressive Faradaic efficiency (FE) exceeding 70% for ethylene generation at a current density of 800 mA cm&#8208;2. Furthermore, it showed robust stability, maintaining consistent performance for 230 hours at a cell voltage of 3.5 V in a full&#8208;cell system. Our research not only deepens the understanding of the active sites involved in designing efficient carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) catalysts but also advances CO2 electrolysis technologies for industrial application.</description>
      <author>Wensheng Fang, Ruihu Lu, Fu-Min Li, Dan Wu, Kaihang Yue, Cong He, Yu Mao, Wei Guo, Bao Yu Xia, Fei Song, Takeshi Yao, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202319936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low&#8208;coordination Nanocrystalline Copper&#8208;based Catalysts through Theory&#8208;guided Electrochemical Restructuring for Selective CO2 Reduction to Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202319936</link>
      <description>Wensheng Fang, Ruihu Lu, Fu-Min Li, Dan Wu, Kaihang Yue, Cong He, Yu Mao, Wei Guo, Bao Yu Xia, Fei Song, Takeshi Yao, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391926647

                Revealing the dynamic reconstruction process and tailoring advanced copper (Cu) catalysts is of paramount significance for promoting the conversion of CO2 into ethylene (C2H4), paving the way for carbon neutralization and facilitating renewable energy storage. In this study, we initially employed density functional theory (DFT) and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations to elucidate the restructuring behavior of a catalyst under electrochemical conditions and delineated its restructuring patterns. Leveraging insights into this restructuring behavior, we devised an efficient, low&#8208;coordination copper&#8208;based catalyst. The resulting synthesized catalyst demonstrated an impressive Faradaic efficiency (FE) exceeding 70% for ethylene generation at a current density of 800 mA cm&#8208;2. Furthermore, it showed robust stability, maintaining consistent performance for 230 hours at a cell voltage of 3.5 V in a full&#8208;cell system. Our research not only deepens the understanding of the active sites involved in designing efficient carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) catalysts but also advances CO2 electrolysis technologies for industrial application.</description>
      <author>Wensheng Fang, Ruihu Lu, Fu-Min Li, Dan Wu, Kaihang Yue, Cong He, Yu Mao, Wei Guo, Bao Yu Xia, Fei Song, Takeshi Yao, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202319936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A robust and high performance copper silicide catalyst for electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ma00633f</link>
      <description>Vladislav D&#345;&#305;&#769;nek, Pavel Dytrych, Radek Fajg&#1072;r, Mariana Klementov&#225;, Jaroslav Kup&#269;&#305;&#769;k, Jarom&#305;&#769;r Kope&#269;ek, Petr Svora, Martin Ko&#353;tejn, V&#283;ra Jandov&#225;, Karel Soukup, Radim Ber&#225;nek, Materials advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391935036

                A copper-based catalyst CuxSi (3&lt;x&lt;5) was prepared using chemical vapor deposition (CVD) of butylsilane (BuSiH3) on copper substrates. By varying the precursor flow...</description>
      <author>Vladislav D&#345;&#305;&#769;nek, Pavel Dytrych, Radek Fajg&#1072;r, Mariana Klementov&#225;, Jaroslav Kup&#269;&#305;&#769;k, Jarom&#305;&#769;r Kope&#269;ek, Petr Svora, Martin Ko&#353;tejn, V&#283;ra Jandov&#225;, Karel Soukup, Radim Ber&#225;nek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ma00633f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of CO2 in the Presence of Light via Excited-state Hydride Transfer Reaction in a NADPH-inspired Derivative</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cp05635j</link>
      <description>Bojana Ostoji&#263;, Branislav Stankovi&#263;, Dragana &#272;or&#273;evi&#263;, Peter Schwerdtfeger, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392006911

                The photo-catalytic reduction of CO2 into chemical feedstocks using solar energy has attracted vast interest in environmental science because of global warming. Based on our previous study on the CO2...</description>
      <author>Bojana Ostoji&#263;, Branislav Stankovi&#263;, Dragana &#272;or&#273;evi&#263;, Peter Schwerdtfeger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cp05635j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pre-treatment through reductive calcination for CO2 mineralization and selective battery metal extraction from laterites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126818</link>
      <description>Fei Wang, David Dreisinger, Yuchang Xiao, Separation and Purification Technology. 340(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391980124

                The world needs an increasing supply of nickel and cobalt production as battery materials for sustainable development. However, the complexity of laterite deposits and the need to control CO2 emissions challenge the enhanced global supply from laterites. This work investigates the effects of calcination as a pre-treatment for selective battery metal extraction from both limonite laterite and saprolite laterite together with concurrent achievement of CO2 mineralization. Calcination under a reducing atmosphere of CO-N2 or CO-CO2 gas mixtures can significantly enhance the extraction of critical metals from both limonite and saprolite laterites. With calcination, the hydrated silicate minerals and ferric oxides converted to reactive olivine and ferrous oxide. The calcines thus can participate in the CO2 mineralization process to stabilize CO2 as mineral carbonates and release nickel and cobalt arising from the CO2 mineral carbonation into solution as complex ions with a ligand (such as sodium nitrilotriacetate, NTA). The optimum calcination conditions are 20 &#8764; 30 % CO in CO-CO2 gas mixture at 700 &#176;C. Beyond the optimum range results in the inadequate conversion of ferric to ferrous at too low CO concentration or over calcination of ferric to metallic iron at too high CO concentration. At the optimum conditions, the nickel &amp; cobalt extraction and CO2 mineralization can reach 90 %, 93 %, and 39 % from laterite. Each tonne saprolite with the pre-treatment of calcination can recover 20.5 kg nickel, 0.59 kg cobalt, and simultaneously sequester 142 kg CO2 as stable mineral carbonates. The pre-treatment through slightly reductive calcination enables the robust suitability of the developed process for all layers of laterites for both critical battery metal recovery and carbon mineralization.</description>
      <author>Fei Wang, David Dreisinger, Yuchang Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional N-doped carbon nanosheets loading heterostructured Ni/Ni3ZnC0.7 nanoparticles for Selective and Efficient CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr05771b</link>
      <description>Li Liao, Chunguang Jia, She&#8208;Huang Wu, Shansheng Yu, Zhenhai Wen, Suqin Ci, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391934877

                Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2RR) has emerged as a promising approach for converting CO2 into valuable chemicals and fuels to achieve a sustainable carbon cycle. However, the development of efficient electrocatalysts...</description>
      <author>Li Liao, Chunguang Jia, She&#8208;Huang Wu, Shansheng Yu, Zhenhai Wen, Suqin Ci</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr05771b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Extent of the Impact of Acetic Acid as Halite Precipitation Reduction Agent for Enhancing CO2 Injectivity in Deep Saline Aquifers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/217884-ms</link>
      <description>Victor Darkwah-Owusu, Muhammad Aslam Md Yusof, Yen Adams Sokama&#8208;Neuyam, Bennet Nii Tackie-Otoo, Joshua Nsiah Turkson, Sunil Kwon, Jang Hyun Lee, Ingebret Fjelde, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391874794

                Abstract CO2 sequestration in deep saline aquifers is vital to reduce the global carbon footprint. However, this effort can be hampered due to salt precipitation during CO2 injection, which clogs flow pathways leading to a significant reduction in CO2 injectivity. While freshwater has traditionally been employed as the primary solution to dissolve the precipitated salt, the salt tends to re-precipitate upon CO2 reinjection post-treatment, exacerbating the injectivity damage. The project was divided into two stages: (1) simulating salt precipitation scenarios with varying brine salinities to mimic formation damage during CO2 injection in saline aquifers, and (2) critically assessing the impact and effectiveness of acetic acid as a mitigation fluid under different injection scenarios through core-flooding experiments. The results were compared with freshwater and low salinity water (LSW). Mineralogical and petrographical assessments were carried out on the core samples to characterize the Berea sandstone cores. The core flooding experiments were conducted at 60 &#176;C and 1600 psi for CO2 injection, freshwater, LSW and acetic acid flooding. The experimental results revealed significant reductions in permeability (37% -75% impairment) and porosity (18% to 33%) due to salt precipitation. Among the treatments, LSW exhibited the lowest efficacy, followed by freshwater, possibly due to clay swelling, fines migration, and capillary trapping effects causing pore throat blockages. In contrast to freshwater and LSW, acetic acid treatment demonstrated improved injectivity, showing a high dissolution potential with up to a 137% increase compared to initial permeability. This study provides a preliminary assessment of the potential of acetic acid for CO2 injectivity enhancement and recommends further investigations on the effects of acetic acid and brine concentrations on the process.</description>
      <author>Victor Darkwah-Owusu, Muhammad Aslam Md Yusof, Yen Adams Sokama&#8208;Neuyam, Bennet Nii Tackie-Otoo, Joshua Nsiah Turkson, Sunil Kwon, Jang Hyun Lee, Ingebret Fjelde</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/217884-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-controlled exposure of active sites on Pd1Ag14 nanoclusters surface to boost electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc00152d</link>
      <description>Along Ma, Yong Ren, Yu Zuo, Jiawei Wang, Shan Huang, Xiaoshuang Ma, Shuxin Wang, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391932115

                Advancing catalyst design requires meticulous control of nanocatalyst selectivity at the atomic level. Here, we synthesized two Pd1Ag14 nanoclusters: Pd1Ag14(PPh3)8(SPh(CF3)2)6 and Pd1Ag14(P(Ph-p-OMe)3)7(SPh)6, each with well-defined structures. Notably, in Pd1Ag14(P(Ph-p-OMe)3)7(SPh)6, the...</description>
      <author>Along Ma, Yong Ren, Yu Zuo, Jiawei Wang, Shan Huang, Xiaoshuang Ma, Shuxin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc00152d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Phase Mixing Degree in Promoting C&#8208;C Coupling in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Reaction on Cu&#8208;based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202400952</link>
      <description>Yinuo Wang, Fei Yang, Hongming Xu, Juhee Jang, Ernest Pahuyo Delmo, Xiaoyi Qiu, Zhehan Ying, Ping Gao, Shangqian Zhu, Meng Gu, Minhua Shao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391926316

                Cu&#8208;based catalysts have been identified as the most promising candidates for generation of C2+ products in electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction. Defect engineering in catalysts is a widely employed strategy for promoting C&#8208;C coupling on Cu. However, comprehensive understanding of defect structure&#8208;to&#8208;activity relationship has not been obtained. In this study, controllable defects generation is achieved, which leads to a series of Cu&#8208;based catalysts with various phase mixing degrees. It is observed that the Faradaic efficiency toward C2+ products increases with the phase mixing degree, reaching 81% at maximum. In&#8208;situ infrared absorption spectroscopy reveals that the catalysts with higher phase mixing degree tend to form *CO more easily and possess higher retention of *CO under high overpotential window, thereby promoting C&#8208;C coupling. This work sheds new light on the relationship between defects and C&#8208;C coupling, and the rational developed of more advanced Cu&#8208;base catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yinuo Wang, Fei Yang, Hongming Xu, Juhee Jang, Ernest Pahuyo Delmo, Xiaoyi Qiu, Zhehan Ying, Ping Gao, Shangqian Zhu, Meng Gu, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202400952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Phase Mixing Degree in Promoting C&#8208;C Coupling in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Reaction on Cu&#8208;based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202400952</link>
      <description>Yinuo Wang, Fei Yang, Hongming Xu, Juhee Jang, Ernest Pahuyo Delmo, Xiaoyi Qiu, Zhehan Ying, Ping Gao, Shangqian Zhu, Meng Gu, Minhua Shao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391942916

                Cu&#8208;based catalysts have been identified as the most promising candidates for generation of C2+ products in electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction. Defect engineering in catalysts is a widely employed strategy for promoting C&#8208;C coupling on Cu. However, comprehensive understanding of defect structure&#8208;to&#8208;activity relationship has not been obtained. In this study, controllable defects generation is achieved, which leads to a series of Cu&#8208;based catalysts with various phase mixing degrees. It is observed that the Faradaic efficiency toward C2+ products increases with the phase mixing degree, reaching 81% at maximum. In&#8208;situ infrared absorption spectroscopy reveals that the catalysts with higher phase mixing degree tend to form *CO more easily and possess higher retention of *CO under high overpotential window, thereby promoting C&#8208;C coupling. This work sheds new light on the relationship between defects and C&#8208;C coupling, and the rational developed of more advanced Cu&#8208;base catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yinuo Wang, Fei Yang, Hongming Xu, Juhee Jang, Ernest Pahuyo Delmo, Xiaoyi Qiu, Zhehan Ying, Ping Gao, Shangqian Zhu, Meng Gu, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202400952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A robust Ni single-atom catalyst for industrial current and exceptional selectivity in electrochemical CO2 reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta07216a</link>
      <description>Zhicheng Liu, Longsheng Cao, Manli Wang, Yun Zhao, Ming Hou, Zhigang Shao, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392018860

                While achieving a Faradaic efficiency (FE) over 90% in the electroreduction of CO2 to CO with single transition metal atom anchored on nitrogen-doped carbon (M-N-C) catalyst is indeed notable, the...</description>
      <author>Zhicheng Liu, Longsheng Cao, Manli Wang, Yun Zhao, Ming Hou, Zhigang Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta07216a</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
