<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 01:16:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Self-assembly of Nanomaterials in Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/2025.20219</link>
      <description>Yi Lu, Applied and Computational Engineering. 127(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406247492

                The rapid development of nanomaterial self-assembly technology has greatly favored the field of electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) and allowed for better control of catalyst structure and composition. Various self-assembly methods, such as DNA-directed assembly, matrix-assisted technology and solvent evaporation, have been used to improve catalytic efficiency and selectivity. Various newly created self-assembled catalysts have also contributed to the development of CO2RR, such as metal oxide catalysts, organic polymers and frameworks, organometallic frameworks and hybrid systems. This paper explored the application of the self-assembled nanocatalysts in CO2RR through a literature review and case studies, with an emphasis on how these methods can reduce CO2 to valuable products such as CO, methane and C2 compounds. The main results highlight the impact of self-assembled structures on improving reaction kinetics and product selectivity. The paper finds that self-assembly technologies and self-assembly nanocatalysts offer potential breakthroughs in improving CO reduction efficiency and contribute to the development of carbon capture and conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Yi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/2025.20219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper/metal oxide heterostructures for electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03057-1</link>
      <description>Jinsheng Yan, Fangmu Wang, Shuai Yin, Jing Zhang, Wei Jiang, Guigao Liu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406307837

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinsheng Yan, Fangmu Wang, Shuai Yin, Jing Zhang, Wei Jiang, Guigao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03057-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper&#8208;Catalysed Electrochemical CO2 Methanation via the Alloying of Single Cobalt Atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417008</link>
      <description>Jiawei Li, Miaojin Wei, Bifa Ji, Sunpei Hu, Jing Xue, Donghao Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yifan Ye, Jilong Xu, Jie Zeng, Ruquan Ye, Yongping Zheng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406319031

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) to methane (CH4) presents a promising solution for mitigating CO2 emissions while producing valuable chemical feedstocks. Although single&#8208;atom catalysts have shown potential in selectively converting CO2 to CH4, their limited active sites often hinder the realization of high current densities, posing a selectivity&#8208;activity dilemma. In this study, we developed a single&#8208;atom cobalt (Co) doped copper catalyst (Co1Cu) that achieved a CH4 Faradaic efficiency exceeding 60% with a partial current density of &#8208;482.7 mA cm&#8208;2. Mechanistic investigations revealed that the incorporation of single Co atoms enhances the activation and dissociation of H2O molecules, thereby lowering the energy barrier for the hydrogenation of *CO intermediates. In situ spectroscopic experiments and density functional theory simulations further demonstrated that the modulation of the *CO adsorption configuration, with stronger bridge&#8208;binding, favours deep reduction to CH4 over the C&#8208;C coupling or CO desorption pathways. Our findings underscore the potential of Co1Cu catalysts in overcoming the selectivity&#8208;activity trade&#8208;off, paving the way for efficient and scalable CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Jiawei Li, Miaojin Wei, Bifa Ji, Sunpei Hu, Jing Xue, Donghao Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yifan Ye, Jilong Xu, Jie Zeng, Ruquan Ye, Yongping Zheng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Cu Active Centers: Local Structure and Mechanism Modulation for Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423092</link>
      <description>Xupeng Qin, Qizheng An, Jing Shang, Xiuxiu Zhang, Qinghua Liu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406247059

                Abstract Reducing carbon dioxide &#65288;CO 2 &#65289;to high&#8208;value products using green renewable energy is a promising approach for addressing energy and greenhouse effect issues. Consequently, electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) technology has become a current research hotspot. Since the discovery of the high activity and selectivity of copper in the CO 2 RR, atomically dispersed Cu catalysts have garnered widespread attention due to their efficient atom utilization, unique electronic structure, and outstanding catalytic performance. However, a great challenge remains in providing rational catalyst design principles to achieve the regulation of product distribution. A clear understanding of catalytic materials and an in&#8208;depth interpretation of the mechanism as well as the elucidation of the design strategy and research progress toward different products are the keys to building the understanding for solving the above problem. Therefore, this review starts with the introduction of advanced characterization techniques to reveal catalyst structure and reaction mechanisms. Then, various optimization strategies and the applications of atomically dispersed Cu catalysts in producing various high&#8208;value targeted products are summarized and discussed. Finally, the perspectives on atomically dispersed Cu catalysts in the CO 2 RR field toward future development are offered.</description>
      <author>Xupeng Qin, Qizheng An, Jing Shang, Xiuxiu Zhang, Qinghua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partial oxidation of methane based on optimized gas flow with efficient thermal recirculation and carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144732</link>
      <description>Huaming Dai, Chongxue Zou, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406272835

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huaming Dai, Chongxue Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Implications of Autonomous Vehicles : A Case Study on Autzu&#8217;s Ridesharing Model and CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32628/ijsrst251217</link>
      <description>Jiri Jilek, International Journal of Scientific Research in Science and Technology. 12(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406380419

                Regarding the environmental impact of Ridesharing integrated with AVs, this paper examines the work done to identify substantial CO2 reductions possible with AV use. Drawing on the trends in the shift to AV and on the adoption of EVs, the paper estimates the potential green effects of swapping ICE vehicles for autonomous electric ones. We also discuss updates in AVs, infrastructure issues, solar power options for charging stations, future forecasts of global CO2 emissions, and the felt shortcomings of this study. The study shows that although AVs may hold the key to the dramatic reduction in emission levels, their potential is only as good as the infrastructure and policies in place, as well as a few technological constraints.</description>
      <author>Jiri Jilek</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32628/ijsrst251217</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Metal Oxides Stabilize Cu Oxidation States for Electrocatalytical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402510</link>
      <description>Yu Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yuan Ji, Xu Li, Qiu Jiang, Chuan Xia, Tingting Zheng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406331856

                Modulating the oxidation state of copper (Cu) is crucial for enhancing the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), particularly for facilitating deep reductions to produce methane (CH4) or multi-carbon (C2+) products. However, Cu&#948;+ sites are thermodynamically unstable, fluctuating their oxidation states under reaction conditions, which complicates their functionality. Incorporating interfacial metal oxides has emerged as an effective strategy for stabilizing these oxidation states. This review provides an in-depth examination of the reaction mechanisms occurring at oxide-modified Cu&#948;+ sites, offering a comprehensive understanding of their behavior. We explore how Cu/metal oxide interfaces stabilize Cu oxidation states, showing that oxides-modified Cu catalysts often enhance selectivity for C2+ or CH4 products by stabilizing Cu+ or Cu2+ sites. In addition, we discuss innovative strategies for the rational design of efficient Cu catalytic sites tailored for specific deep CO2RR products. The review concludes with an outlook on current challenges and future directions, offering new insights into the rational design of selective and efficient CO2RR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yu Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yuan Ji, Xu Li, Qiu Jiang, Chuan Xia, Tingting Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peaks and pitfalls of electrocatalytic descriptor models at the example of CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5559232/v1</link>
      <description>Jihun Oh, Beom-Il Kim, Sheng Han, Suneon Wang, Stefan Ringe, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406380210

                Abstract Electrocatalysis advances rely on the development of efficient catalysts. Systematic material design hinges on identifying activity and selectivity descriptors. While adsorption energy descriptors have helped predict new materials, they are typically based on pure metals, uncertain of their applicability to complex materials like alloys. Here, we systematically analyze the validity of descriptor models for the electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR). For this, we prepare gold, silver, and palladium alloys of variable composition and confirm experimentally the continuous variation of the d-band center (i.e. the CO adsorption energy) and work function (i.e. the potential of zero charge). Our results indicate that while the d-band center is the decisive factor for CO production, it, along with the work function, fails to fully explain the production of HCOO&#8722; and H2. Designing a copper-like alloy based on the matching of these descriptor values showed no formation of C2 products (as commonly expected for copper). This breakdown of the descriptor model is explained from first-principles calculations by the heterogeneity of the surface leading to different deactivation pathways for C2 product formation. Our results highlight the problems in transferring conventional descriptor models to more complex, heterogeneous materials motivating future developments.</description>
      <author>Jihun Oh, Beom-Il Kim, Sheng Han, Suneon Wang, Stefan Ringe</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5559232/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare-earth neodymium single atom catalyst for efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2025.115199</link>
      <description>Tonglin Yang, Fangqi Yang, Fan Yang, Yang Ding, Fa Cao, Quan Zhang, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406269651

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tonglin Yang, Fangqi Yang, Fan Yang, Yang Ding, Fa Cao, Quan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2025.115199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic reduction of imines with silylformates: Formation of silyl carbamates through CO2 insertion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403907</link>
      <description>Thibault Cantat, Neethu Thyagarajan, Ruqaya Buhaibeh, Emmanuel Nicolas, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406377564

                Silylformates are emerging surrogates of hydrosilanes, able to reduce carbonyl groups in transfer hydrosilylation reactions, with the concomitant release of CO2. In this work, a new reactivity is revealed for silylformates, in the presence of imines. Using ruthenium catalysts, and lithium iodide as a co-catalyst, imines are shown to undergo hydrocarboxysilylation by formal insertion of CO2 to the N-Si bond of silyl amine to yield silyl carbamates in excellent yields.</description>
      <author>Thibault Cantat, Neethu Thyagarajan, Ruqaya Buhaibeh, Emmanuel Nicolas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DISPLACE Post-Combustion Carbon Capture Technology Integration in a Steel Plant for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144739</link>
      <description>Nicola Zecca, Leonie L&#252;cking, Dora-Andreea Chis&#259;li&#539;&#259;, Jurriaan Boon, H.A.J. van Dijk, Johannis A.Z. Pieterse, Antonio Giuffrida, Giampaolo Manzolini, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406240280

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicola Zecca, Leonie L&#252;cking, Dora-Andreea Chis&#259;li&#539;&#259;, Jurriaan Boon, H.A.J. van Dijk, Johannis A.Z. Pieterse, Antonio Giuffrida, Giampaolo Manzolini</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrochemical Co2 Reduction to Formate Using 2d Sno2 Gas Diffusion Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5096454</link>
      <description>Osmando F. Lopes, Cau&#234; A. Martins, Rafael A.C. Souza, Gon&#231;alves J. Marrenjo, David Patrun, Shifaa M. Siribbal, Antonio Ot&#225;vio T. Patroc&#237;nio, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406379158

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Osmando F. Lopes, Cau&#234; A. Martins, Rafael A.C. Souza, Gon&#231;alves J. Marrenjo, David Patrun, Shifaa M. Siribbal, Antonio Ot&#225;vio T. Patroc&#237;nio</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5096454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon-Enhanced CO2 Reduction to Liquid Fuel via Modified UiO-66 Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010070</link>
      <description>Alaa Elsafi Ahmed, Zeineb Theihmed, Aldana Ali H. A. Alyafei, Alaa Alkhateeb, Ahmed Abotaleb, Muhammad Anwar, Kamal H. Mrou&#233;, Brahim A&#239;ssa, Alessandro Sinopoli, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406375856

                Metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) have emerged as versatile materials with remarkably high surface areas and tunable properties, attracting significant attention for various applications. In this work, the modification of a UiO-66 MOF with metal nanoparticles (NPs) is investigated for the purpose of enhancing its photocatalytic activity for CO2 reduction to liquid fuels. Several NPs (Au, Cu, Ag, Pd, Pt, and Ni) were loaded into the UiO-66 framework and employed as photocatalysts. The synergistic effects of plasmonic resonance and MOF characteristics were investigated to improve photocatalytic performance. The synthesized materials were characterized by X-ray powder diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), confirming the successful integration of metal NPs onto the UiO-66 framework. Morphological analysis revealed distinct distributions and sizes of NPs on the UiO-66 surface for different metals. Photocatalytic CO2 reduction experiments demonstrated enhanced activity of plasmonic MOFs, yielding methanol and ethanol. The findings revealed by this study provide valuable insights into tailoring MOFs for improved photocatalytic applications through the incorporation of plasmonic metal nanoparticles.</description>
      <author>Alaa Elsafi Ahmed, Zeineb Theihmed, Aldana Ali H. A. Alyafei, Alaa Alkhateeb, Ahmed Abotaleb, Muhammad Anwar, Kamal H. Mrou&#233;, Brahim A&#239;ssa, Alessandro Sinopoli</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabricating an ohmic junction of Ag/CdS for highly efficient multi-electron reduction of CO2 to CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105807</link>
      <description>Chaoqiang Li, Xiangyu Xu, Aizhong Jia, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406282833

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoqiang Li, Xiangyu Xu, Aizhong Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the role of oxygen vacancies in CO2 photothermal catalytic reduction to methanol over 2D Bi2WO6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3199-9</link>
      <description>Hongxia Fan, Tao Liu, Liang-Fen Zhen, Antony Rajendran, Jie Feng, Wenying Li, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406320460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongxia Fan, Tao Liu, Liang-Fen Zhen, Antony Rajendran, Jie Feng, Wenying Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3199-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Digital Economy, R&amp;amp;D Investments, and CO2 Emissions: Unraveling Reduction Potentials in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/rsee2010004</link>
      <description>Yuexin Zhao, Peng Wang, Regional science and environmental economics. 2(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406324801

                This study explores the relationships between the digital economy, R&amp;D investment, and carbon emissions, as well as the mediating role of financial technology (fintech). Despite a growing body of research, the impact of the digital economy on carbon emissions remains contested, partly due to the limited scope and inconsistent measures in existing studies. Additionally, while R&amp;D is a pivotal driver of modern development, its potential quadratic effects on carbon emissions in China remain unexplored. By employing a comprehensive Digital Economy Index and analyzing panel data from 2011 to 2020 across Chinese regions, this study provides new insights into how digitalization and innovation influence carbon emissions. The findings reveal a positive linear correlation between the digital economy and CO2 emissions over the last decade. Moreover, R&amp;D investments exhibit an inverse U-shaped relationship with emissions, acting as an effective factor in reducing CO2 emissions. Notably, the turning point of this relationship occurs in Quadrant I, where most regions are clustered, indicating substantial efficiency gains from early-stage R&amp;D investments and their significant potential to enhance sustainable development. Furthermore, fintech emerges as a significant mediator in the R&amp;D&#8211;emissions dynamic, underscoring its critical role in this context.</description>
      <author>Yuexin Zhao, Peng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/rsee2010004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolating and stabilizing active copper species in layered double hydroxide to enhance electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115959</link>
      <description>Mingzhu Yue, Wenfu Xie, Ziyi Zhong, Min Li, Tianyu Zhang, Mingfei Shao, Hao Li, Qiang Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406309936

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingzhu Yue, Wenfu Xie, Ziyi Zhong, Min Li, Tianyu Zhang, Mingfei Shao, Hao Li, Qiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the cobalt phthalocyanine molecules by introducing adjacent cubic molybdenum carbide nanoparticles for accelerated proton transfer towards efficient CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwaf010</link>
      <description>Yunxiang Lin, Shaocong Wang, Hengjie Liu, Xue Liu, Li Yang, Xiaozhi Su, Lei Shan, Xiyu Li, Li Song, National Science Review. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406275274

                Abstract Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an important application that can considerably mitigate environmental and energy crises. However, the slow proton-coupled electron transfer process continues to limit overall catalytic performance. Fine-tuning the reaction microenvironment by accurately constructing the local structure of catalysts provides a novel approach to enhancing reaction kinetics. Here, cubic-phase &#945;-MoC1&#8722;x nanoparticles were incorporated into a carbon matrix and coupled with cobalt phthalocyanine molecules (&#945;-MoC1&#8722;x&#8211;CoPc@C) for the co-reduction of CO2 and H2O, achieving an impressive Faradaic efficiency for CO close to 100%. Through a combination of in-situ spectroscopies, electrochemical measurements, and theoretical simulations, it is demonstrated that &#945;-MoC1&#8722;x nanoparticles and CoPc molecules with the optimized local configuration serve as the active centers for H2O activation and CO2 reduction, respectively. The interfacial water molecules were rearranged, forming a dense hydrogen bond network on the catalyst surface. This optimized microenvironment at the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface synergistically enhanced water dissociation, accelerated proton transfer, and improved the overall performance of CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Yunxiang Lin, Shaocong Wang, Hengjie Liu, Xue Liu, Li Yang, Xiaozhi Su, Lei Shan, Xiyu Li, Li Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwaf010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the co-utilization of methanol and CO2 into 1-butanol by equipping synergistic reductive glycine pathway in Butyribacterium methylotrophicum</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2025.132071</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Shengji Li, Chenxi Ma, Rui Zhang, Jialun Qin, Kequan Chen, Xin Wang, Bioresource Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406308731

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Shengji Li, Chenxi Ma, Rui Zhang, Jialun Qin, Kequan Chen, Xin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2025.132071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Heterostructured Ti-MOF/g-C3N4 driven light assisted reductive carboxylation of aryl aldehydes with CO2 under ambient conditions&#8221; [J. Catal. 417 (2023) 116&#8211;128]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115944</link>
      <description>Sakshi Bhatt, Sandhya Saini, B. Moses Abraham, Anil Malik, Arghya Sen, Suman L. Jain, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406380802

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sakshi Bhatt, Sandhya Saini, B. Moses Abraham, Anil Malik, Arghya Sen, Suman L. Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115944</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide (CO2 ) emissions and mitigation efforts based on Bogor City's green open space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33751/injast.v5i2.8513</link>
      <description>Annisa Choerinita Kusuma Wardhani, Rita Retnowati, Yossa Istiadi, Indonesian Journal of Applied Environmental Studies. 5(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406276672

                One of the risks associated with climate change is carbon dioxide (CO2) emission, which can negatively affect human health and the ecosystem. The CO2 emission can lead to a decline in urban area quality that surpasses the environment's carrying capacity. This research aimed to investigate the relationship between CO2 Emissions from Transportation (X1), Household (X2), and Business Sector (X3) with the CO2 reduction of green open space (Y). The hypothesis is that there is a negative correlation between CO2 emissions from transportation, households, and businesses and CO2 reduction from green open spaces. A quantitative research design was adopted using the Slovin formula and cluster random sampling. The Normality and Homogeneity Tests are used to analyze research data. The study yielded the following results: first, the coefficient of determination (r2) = 0.003 indicates a relationship between CO2 emissions from transportation with CO2 reduction from green open space, with a 0.3% contribution. The second finding is that there is a 0.1% contribution from CO2 reduction from green open space to the CO2 emissions of households, as indicated by the coefficient of determination (r2) = 0.001. Third, a correlation of 0.1% between CO2 reduction from green open space and CO2 emissions from the Business Sector is indicated by the coefficient of determination (r2) = 0.001. Thus, using the regression equation Y = 2320.432 &#8211; 0.16X1 &#8211; 0,25 X2 &#8211; 0,007 X3, there is an overall significant relationship between CO2 emissions from transportation, CO2 emissions from households, and CO2 emissions from the business sector with the reduction of CO2 from green open space.</description>
      <author>Annisa Choerinita Kusuma Wardhani, Rita Retnowati, Yossa Istiadi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33751/injast.v5i2.8513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 injection modeling in a reservoir: Phase transition study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55592/cilamce.v6i06.8248</link>
      <description>Rafael de Lima Omena, Jonathan da Cunha Teixeira, Moacyr Roberto Cuc&#234; Nobre, Bernardo Jos&#233; Lucas Ferro Moreira, Matheus Santos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406372091

                The study explores the phase transition of carbon dioxide from liquid to gas after injection and storage in a confined aquifer at a temperature of 30&#176;C. By utilizing a compositional isotropic model and data from the NIST webbook (Linstrom and Mallard, 2024), the simulation analyzes, using compositional mesh model in tNavigator software (by Rock Flow Dynamics), the behavior of CO2 within a confined aquifer, seeking to identify the phase transition of the fluid. The effects of capillarity are neglected, and the main parameters of the reservoir are a pressure of 65 bar at the wellhead and a constant temperature of 31&#176;C throughout the aquifer to evaluate the phase transition close to the supercritical point of CO2. The analysis reveals that the drastic pressure reduction within the confined aquifer leads to the formation of free gas within the reservoir after the closure of injection wells, which becomes a problem, as occurred in the Ordos CCS Project in China, allowing fluid backflow during non-injection (CAI, Yuna et al.). The results showed that the closer the temperature approaches the supercritical point of CO2, the greater the probability of free gas formation within the reservoir. Therefore, the conclusions emphasize the impact of the pressure reduction on the stability of CO2, which will undergo a phase transition from the liquid to the gaseous state, so that free gas is generated within the reservoir. In this way, it is highlighted the importance of understanding phase transition in CO2 injection processes for effective carbon capture and storage strategies.</description>
      <author>Rafael de Lima Omena, Jonathan da Cunha Teixeira, Moacyr Roberto Cuc&#234; Nobre, Bernardo Jos&#233; Lucas Ferro Moreira, Matheus Santos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55592/cilamce.v6i06.8248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Interconnections Among Environmental Degradation, Energy Consumption, Information and Communication Technology, and Total Factor Productivity in Iran</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5829/ijee.2025.16.03.12</link>
      <description>, Iranica Journal of Energy and Environment. 16(03)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406367433

                Information and Communication Technology (ICT) is recognized as a critical driver of economic development in the modern era, significantly enhancing the productivity of production factors. However, the widespread adoption of ICT, particularly in countries reliant on fossil fuels, may contribute to increased greenhouse gas emissions, including carbon dioxide (CO2). So, this study investigates the interconnections among ICT, CO2, renewable energy, and Total Factor Productivity (TFP) in Iran. This descriptive-analytical and applied study used time series data from the World Bank and Iran Statistics Center from 2000 to 2023. This study, the Autoregressive Distributed Lag (ARDL) model to evaluate the long-term and short-term dynamic, unit root tests and diagnostic tests CUSUM and CUSUMQ and Canonical Co-Integrating Regression (CCR) Dynamic least squares (DOLS), and fully modified least squares (FMOLS) have been used to validate the results of ADRL estimates. The results of the ARDL estimation method showed that in the long run, TFP and economic growth on carbon dioxide had a coefficient of 0.07 and 0.14, respectively. Renewable energy consumption with a coefficient of -0.0808 had a significant negative role in reducing carbon dioxide. The coefficient of -0.286 obtained for the ICT variable at 95% indicates a reduction in carbon dioxide in parallel with the development of ICT. CUSUM and CUSUMQ confirmed the stability of the parameters, and CCR, DOLS, and FMOLS regressions confirmed the results of the ADRL model. The study recommends adopting green technologies and effective energy policies to balance productivity gains with environmental protection.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5829/ijee.2025.16.03.12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper&#8208;Catalysed Electrochemical CO2 Methanation via the Alloying of Single Cobalt Atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417008</link>
      <description>Jiawei Li, Miaojin Wei, Bifa Ji, Sunpei Hu, Jing Xue, Donghao Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yifan Ye, Jilong Xu, Jie Zeng, Ruquan Ye, Yongping Zheng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406339255

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) to methane (CH4) presents a promising solution for mitigating CO2 emissions while producing valuable chemical feedstocks. Although single&#8208;atom catalysts have shown potential in selectively converting CO2 to CH4, their limited active sites often hinder the realization of high current densities, posing a selectivity&#8208;activity dilemma. In this study, we developed a single&#8208;atom cobalt (Co) doped copper catalyst (Co1Cu) that achieved a CH4 Faradaic efficiency exceeding 60% with a partial current density of &#8208;482.7 mA cm&#8208;2. Mechanistic investigations revealed that the incorporation of single Co atoms enhances the activation and dissociation of H2O molecules, thereby lowering the energy barrier for the hydrogenation of *CO intermediates. In situ spectroscopic experiments and density functional theory simulations further demonstrated that the modulation of the *CO adsorption configuration, with stronger bridge&#8208;binding, favours deep reduction to CH4 over the C&#8208;C coupling or CO desorption pathways. Our findings underscore the potential of Co1Cu catalysts in overcoming the selectivity&#8208;activity trade&#8208;off, paving the way for efficient and scalable CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Jiawei Li, Miaojin Wei, Bifa Ji, Sunpei Hu, Jing Xue, Donghao Zhao, H. Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Yifan Ye, Jilong Xu, Jie Zeng, Ruquan Ye, Yongping Zheng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Methanol on Pt(111) Modified with a Pd Monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05442</link>
      <description>Aleksandra Wawrzyniak, Marc T. M. Koper, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406259351

                Electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO2) conversion to value-added, highly reduced chemicals such as methanol (CH3OH) is a promising possibility for producing renewable fuel and simultaneous CO2 recycling. However, this process remains a challenge, with only a few selective electrocatalysts known. Here, we present a study of a palladium monolayer on a platinum (111) single crystal (PdML/Pt(111)) as an electrocatalyst for CO2 conversion to CH3OH. A custom-made setup was employed in order to detect and quantify gaseous and liquid CO2 reduction products in sufficient concentrations despite the limitations of working with a single-crystalline electrode. Under ambient reaction conditions, a Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 1.5% at &#8722;0.9 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) was obtained while using CO2 as the reactant. Other reaction intermediates, carbon monoxide (CO) and formaldehyde (HCHO) were subsequently used as reactants, leading to FEs of 1.8 and 2.5%, respectively, whereas formic acid is not reduced. The corresponding mechanism concluded from our work is compared to the literature. The electrocatalyst introduced here, with a highly well-defined structure for CO2 conversion to CH3OH, opens up possibilities for further catalytic explorations.</description>
      <author>Aleksandra Wawrzyniak, Marc T. M. Koper</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Approach to CO2 Emissions Analysis in High-Human-Development-Index Countries Using Statistical and Time Series Approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020603</link>
      <description>Hamed Khosravi, Ahmed Shoyeb Raihan, Farzana Islam, Ashish D. Nimbarte, Imtiaz Ahmed, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406363296

                Reducing carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions is vital at both global and national levels, given their significant role in exacerbating climate change. CO2 emissions, stemming from a variety of industrial and economic activities, are major contributors to the greenhouse effect and global warming, posing substantial obstacles in addressing climate issues. It is imperative to forecast CO2 emissions trends and classify countries based on their emission patterns to effectively mitigate worldwide carbon emissions. This paper presents an in-depth comparative study on the determinants of CO2 emissions in twenty countries with high Human Development Index (HDI), exploring factors related to economy, environment, energy use, and renewable resources over a span of 25 years. The study unfolds in two distinct phases: initially, statistical techniques such as Ordinary Least Squares (OLS), fixed effects, and random effects models are applied to pinpoint significant determinants of CO2 emissions. Following this, the study leverages supervised and unsupervised time series approaches to further scrutinize and understand the factors influencing CO2 emissions. Seasonal AutoRegressive Integrated Moving Average with eXogenous variables (SARIMAX), a statistical time series forecasting model, is first used to predict emission trends from historical data, offering practical insights for policy formulation. Subsequently, Dynamic Time Warping (DTW), an unsupervised time series clustering approach, is used to group countries by similar emission patterns. The dual-phase approach utilized in this study significantly improves the accuracy of CO2 emissions predictions while also providing a deeper insight into global emission trends. By adopting this thorough analytical framework, nations can develop more focused and effective carbon reduction policies, playing a vital role in the global initiative to combat climate change.</description>
      <author>Hamed Khosravi, Ahmed Shoyeb Raihan, Farzana Islam, Ashish D. Nimbarte, Imtiaz Ahmed</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Trading as a New Paradigm for Indonesia's Polluter Pays Principle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15294/jllr.vol5i1.2090</link>
      <description>Erwin Syahruddin, Rahmat Saputra, Andre Cardenas, Alizah Ali, Journal of Law and Legal Reform. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406375602

                Climate change is driven by a combination of natural fluctuations and human activities, particularly the widespread use of fossil fuels (such as coal, oil, and natural gas) and alterations in land use practices such as logging, farming, and clearing land for agriculture. This global phenomenon encompasses various end-of-use activities, including agriculture, forestry, and consumerism. An inherent challenge in the global carbon dioxide (CO2) trading landscape lies in the competition between developed and developing countries, stemming from inconsistent CO2 prices. This competition manifests in three primary areas. Firstly, in the context of internationally transmitted mitigation outcomes, involving international trade aimed at surpassing Nationally Determined Contributions (NDC) targets. Secondly, it pertains to sustainable development mechanisms, specifically the use of carbon offsets derived from projects implemented by both public and private entities worldwide. The third aspect revolves around non-market approaches, encompassing emission reduction through mitigation and adaptation efforts, financial support, technology transfer, and capacity building, which may involve tools like carbon taxes and Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM). This research adopts a legal norm perspective, delving into methods that investigate, describe, synthesize, interpret, evaluate, and analyze positive approaches. The findings signify a paradigm shift aligning with the "polluter pays principle," recognizing that entities and individuals responsible for environmental pollution should bear the associated costs. In the quest for a new paradigm of sustainable development, a carbon market ecosystem assumes a pivotal role. This ecosystem contributes to enhancing sustainability by curbing greenhouse gas emissions and offering economic incentives to address climate change. It acts as a cornerstone in constructing a fresh paradigm for potential development.</description>
      <author>Erwin Syahruddin, Rahmat Saputra, Andre Cardenas, Alizah Ali</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15294/jllr.vol5i1.2090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manure Management as a Potential Mitigation Tool to Eliminate Greenhouse Gas Emissions in Livestock Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020586</link>
      <description>George Symeon, Konstantina Akamati, Vassilios Dotas, Despoina Karatosidi, Iosif Bizelis, George P. Laliotis, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406376406

                Climate change is a contemporary global challenge that requires comprehensive solutions to mitigate its adverse effects. All human activities contribute to climate change, mainly through atmospheric emissions of greenhouse gases (GHGs), such as nitrous oxide (N2O), carbon dioxide (CO2), and methane (CH4). While most of these emissions are primarily due to fossil fuel use, agriculture and livestock production also contribute to a significant share of approximately 12% of global emissions. Most processes that are implemented within an animal husbandry unit are associated with greenhouse gas emissions, including manure management. This review explores the interconnection between climate change and manure management practices, highlighting the potential for sustainable approaches to mitigating GHG emissions. The key strategies for manure management, such as anaerobic digestion, nutrient management, composting, manure separation and treatment, and improved storage and handling, are discussed, as they are implemented in different livestock production systems (ruminants, poultry, and pigs). Despite the technological progress, there is still a place for further improving manure management approaches, especially in non-ruminant species leading to a higher mitigation potential and a reduction in greenhouse gases emissions. Moreover, policy support and incentives for sustainable practices are crucial for widespread adoption.</description>
      <author>George Symeon, Konstantina Akamati, Vassilios Dotas, Despoina Karatosidi, Iosif Bizelis, George P. Laliotis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Effects of Salinity, Redox State, Soil Type, and Colloidal Size Fractionation on Greenhouse Gas Production in Coastal Wetland Soils</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.170158332.29336750/v2</link>
      <description>Nicholas Ward, Madison Bowe, Katherine A. Muller, Xingyuan Chen, Qian Zhao, Rosalie Chu, Zezhen Cheng, Thomas Wietsma, Ravi Kukkadapu, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406255924

                Coastal wetlands, including freshwater systems near large lakes, rapidly bury carbon, but less is known about how they transport carbon either to marine and lake environments or to the atmosphere as greenhouse gases (GHGs) such as carbon dioxide and methane. This study examines how GHG production and organic matter (OM) mobility in coastal wetland soils vary with the availability of oxygen and other terminal electron acceptors. We also evaluated how OM and redox-sensitive species varied across different size fractions: particulates (0.45&#8211;1&#956;m), fine colloids (0.1&#8211;0.45&#956;m), and nano particulates plus truly soluble (&lt;0.1&#956;m; NP+S) during 21-day aerobic and anaerobic slurry incubations. Soils were collected from the center of a freshwater coastal wetland (FW-C) in Lake Erie, the upland-wetland edge of the same wetland (FW-E), and the center of a saline coastal wetland (SW-C) in the Pacific Northwest, USA. Anaerobic methane production for FW-E soils were 47 and 27,537 times greater than FW-C and SW-C soils, respectively. High Fe2+ and dissolved sulfate concentrations in FW-C and SW-C soils suggest that iron and/or sulfate reduction inhibited methanogenesis. Aerobic CO2 production was highest for both freshwater soils, which had a higher proportion of OM in the NP+S fraction (64&#177;28% and 70&#177;10% for FW-C and FW-E, respectively) and organic C:N ratios reflective of microbial detritus (5.3&#177;5.3 and 5.3&#177;7.0 for FW-E and FW-C, respectively) compared to SW-C, which had a higher fraction of particulate (58&#177;9%) and fine colloidal (19&#177;7%) OM and organic C:N ratios reflective of vegetation detritus (11.4 &#177; 1.7). The variability in GHG production and shifts in OM size fractionation and composition observed across freshwater and saline soils collected within individual and across different sites reinforce the high spatial variability in the processes controlling OM stability, mobility, and bioavailability in coastal wetland soils.</description>
      <author>Nicholas Ward, Madison Bowe, Katherine A. Muller, Xingyuan Chen, Qian Zhao, Rosalie Chu, Zezhen Cheng, Thomas Wietsma, Ravi Kukkadapu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.170158332.29336750/v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Cyclizative Carboxylation of Alkene-Tethered Aryl Isocyanides with Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.orglett.4c04426</link>
      <description>Haitao Liu, Meng Guo, Mengying Jia, Jianwei Zhang, Xianxiu Xu, Organic Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406307963

                Herein, we present an unprecedented electrochemical reductive cyclizative carboxylation of o-vinylphenyl isocyanides with carbon dioxide achieved without the use of metal catalysts. This protocol demonstrates a broad substrate scope and good functional group tolerance, facilitating the rapid assembly of 2-oxoindolin-3-acetic acids in good to high yields with excellent regioselectivity. Furthermore, these structural motifs may have potential applications in formal synthesis of bioactive natural products.</description>
      <author>Haitao Liu, Meng Guo, Mengying Jia, Jianwei Zhang, Xianxiu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.orglett.4c04426</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Environmental Contaminants and the Impact of Green Technologies on Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33002/jelp040309</link>
      <description>Awodezi Henry, Ikechukwu Kwubosu, Journal of Environmental Law &amp; Policy. 04(03)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406334151

                Environment has been defined as the natural world in which living things dwell and grow. There are certain factors which often pose challenges to the environment and are capable of interrupting capacity building as well as sustainability. This research evaluates such factors as environmental contaminants which include any chemical, biological, or radiological substance or matter that hurts air, water, soil or living organisms. However, with the advancement of green technologies on the environment, there is a revolutionary change with regards to clean energy production, solar power, reduction of emissions of carbon dioxide, use of alternative fuels and other technologies that are less harmful to the environment than fossil fuels. This research focuses on clean energy production such as solar energy and other technologies that serve the best purpose of reducing emissions of carbon dioxide usually generated by vehicles, motorcycles and fuel power generators majorly in the cities, particularly in the industrial environments. These emissions from vehicle engines, power generators, gas flaring and other environmental contaminants are very dangerous to human health. Many, who have ingested these emissions, have serious interference with their bodies&#8217; internal functioning, causing diseases like cancer, itching in the eyes and respiratory disorders like asthma. The pressing need to explore green technologies for sustainability becomes imperative and this gave rise to this research. To achieve this aim, this research adopts the doctrinal research methodology in examining the natural environmental contaminants and the impact of green technologies on climate change. On this premise, this research recommends tremendous exploration of green technologies as a recipe for a sustainable environment.</description>
      <author>Awodezi Henry, Ikechukwu Kwubosu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33002/jelp040309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Opportunities to Incentivize Low-Carbon Regeneration of Buildings in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095964</link>
      <description>Valeri&#1110; Deshko, Anatolijs Borodi&#326;ecs, Nadia Buyak, Inna Bilous, Olena Naumchuk, Iryna Sukhodub, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406313146

                Given the consequences of military actions in Ukraine and global and national goals to achieve decarbonization across all sectors of the economy, the authors evaluate opportunities for low-carbon recovery of the construction sector. In particular, an analysis of the impact of providing a highly energy-efficient building thermal envelope and its heat supply using renewable energy sources during the modernization of the existing administrative building in Ukraine to the level of the requirements of the European Union was carried out. This analysis considered economic, technical, and environmental factors. Thus, the authors present the results of dynamic modeling of the building's energy consumption at different levels of building insulation and make a payback forecast for improving the thermal envelope and using various sources of heat supply (including using a heat pump and a pellet boiler). To assess emissions reduction of the proposed building modernization options, an analysis of the existing national methods of calculating carbon dioxide emissions was carried out, and the option of a combination of a heat pump and photovoltaic panels was considered.</description>
      <author>Valeri&#1110; Deshko, Anatolijs Borodi&#326;ecs, Nadia Buyak, Inna Bilous, Olena Naumchuk, Iryna Sukhodub</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095964</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Study of Steel Furnaces and boilers Emissions with and without Emission Control System (ECS)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.57041/vol76iss03pp348-351</link>
      <description>Imran Sheikh, Nafeesa Naz, Fiaz Hussa&#305;n, Maryam Arshad, Mohammad Firoz Alam, Rizwan Haider, Tahira Yaqoob, Pakistan Journal of Science. 76(03)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406377219

                In this study, emissions from boilers and steel furnaces with and without emission control systems (ECS), more especially wet scrubbers, were assessed. The concentrations of PM, SO&#8322;, and NO&#8339; were determined using an isokinetic assembly for particulate matter (PM) monitoring and a flue gas analyzer for CO, NOX and SO&#8322; monitoring. The efficacy of the wet scrubber in capturing airborne particles was demonstrated by the remarkable 70% reduction in PM emissions observed in the steel furnace findings. There was no discernible change in CO2 levels, and emissions of SOx and NOx were reduced by 15% and 16%, respectively, but CO emissions only dropped by 3.31%. With a reduction of 70.22% in SOx emissions, the wet scrubber proved to be the most efficient in lowering emissions of NOx (30.79%) and PM (27.75%) in the context of boilers. CO2 levels marginally increased while CO emissions declined by 17.75%. In general, the wet scrubber demonstrated significant efficacy in mitigating pollutants, including PM and SOx; however, its influence on CO and CO2 was restricted.</description>
      <author>Imran Sheikh, Nafeesa Naz, Fiaz Hussa&#305;n, Maryam Arshad, Mohammad Firoz Alam, Rizwan Haider, Tahira Yaqoob</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.57041/vol76iss03pp348-351</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-tin bimetallic aerogel alloy for the electroreduction of CO2 to formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04703f</link>
      <description>Bo Ren, Jing Shao, Hongji Li, Qingming Xu, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406239696

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) enables the conversion of CO2 into various value-added hydrocarbons, with formate formate garnering significant interest due to its high energy density and efficient conversion...</description>
      <author>Bo Ren, Jing Shao, Hongji Li, Qingming Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04703f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semipermanent Continuous Formic Acid Production from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by Controlling Ion Transport Using Boron-Doped Diamond Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06705</link>
      <description>Shingo Araki, Yasuaki Einaga, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406259126

                Boron-doped diamond (BDD) is an excellent functional electrode material used as a working electrode in the electrochemical reduction of CO2. Formic acid production with approximately 100% Faradaic efficiency has been achieved via CO2 reduction using BDD electrodes. In this study, we investigated the production performance stability during long-term electrolysis by focusing on ion transport in the electrolyte during electrolysis. Initially, we investigated the behavior of potassium ions (K+) and pH during long-term electrolysis in detail. A relationship was observed between the change in ion concentrations and formic acid production, crucial in formic acid production. Based on this knowledge, we successfully achieved stable formic acid production for an extremely long time (1264 h) by controlling ion transport. In addition to utilizing the durability of BDD electrodes as stable electrode materials, controlling ion transport has paved the way for the industrialization of formic acid production via CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Shingo Araki, Yasuaki Einaga</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide to formate using a robust metal-independent &lt;i&gt;Thiobacillus&lt;/i&gt; formate dehydrogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/10242422.2025.2450363</link>
      <description>Daan M. van Vliet, Lorenzo C. Schwerdtfeger, August E. Frissen, Rick H. A. M. van de Vondervoort, Mattijs K. Julsing, Carmen G. Boeriu, Tom A. Ewing, Biocatalysis and Biotransformation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406275958

                The capture and utilization of CO2 from industrial off-gases to produce commodity chemicals has the potential to make an important contribution to the transition to a circular economy. Formate, and its conjugate formic acid, is a potential sustainable platform chemical that can be produced from CO2. Electrochemical reduction of CO2 to formate is a promising route, but biocatalysis with formate dehydrogenase (FDH) as biocatalyst may offer advantages for industrial implementation such as mild conditions, high product selectivity, and less expensive down-stream processing. Here, we investigated the potential of a metal-independent Thiobacillus FDH (TsFDH) as a biocatalyst for the production of formate from CO2-rich industrial offgases. An excellent stability was demonstrated, also in the presence of potential off-gas impurities. A formate titer of 14 mM could be achieved at pH 6.5 and 37 &#176;C, with an initial specific productivity of 0.37 mmol g&#8722;1FDH h&#8722;1. TsFDH compares favorably to metal-dependent FDHs with respect to stability, O2-sensitivity and activity at low pH values, but unfavorably in terms of CO2 reduction activity, hampering its potential as industrial biocatalyst. Specific rates could be significantly improved by further reaction engineering, and possibly also by enzyme engineering.</description>
      <author>Daan M. van Vliet, Lorenzo C. Schwerdtfeger, August E. Frissen, Rick H. A. M. van de Vondervoort, Mattijs K. Julsing, Carmen G. Boeriu, Tom A. Ewing</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/10242422.2025.2450363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzy multi-objective optimization model to design a sustainable closed-loop manufacturing system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.2591</link>
      <description>Sajida Kousar, A U Alvi, Nasreen Kausar, Harish Garg, Seifedine Kadry, Jung-Eun Kim, PeerJ Computer Science. 11(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406302170

                Republicans and Democrats practically everywhere have been demonstrating concerns about environmental conservation to achieve sustainable development goals (SDGs) since the turn of the century. To promote fuel (energy) savings and a reduction in the amount of carbon dioxide CO 2 emissions in several enterprises, actions have been taken based on the concepts described. This study proposes an environmentally friendly manufacturing system designed to minimize environmental impacts. Specifically, it aims to develop a sustainable manufacturing process that accounts for energy consumption and CO 2 emissions from direct and indirect energy sources. A multi-objective mathematical model has been formulated, incorporating financial and environmental constraints, to minimize overall costs, energy consumption, and CO 2 emissions within the manufacturing framework. The input model parameters for real-world situations are generally unpredictable, so a fuzzy multi-objective model will be developed as a way to handle it. The validity of the proposed ecological industrial design will be tested using a scenario-based approach. Results demonstrate the high reliability, applicability, and effectiveness of the proposed network when analyzed using the developed techniques.</description>
      <author>Sajida Kousar, A U Alvi, Nasreen Kausar, Harish Garg, Seifedine Kadry, Jung-Eun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.2591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health system and environmental factors affecting global progress towards achieving End TB targets between 2015 and 2020</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7189/jogh.15.04004</link>
      <description>Haileab Fekadu Wolde, Archie C. A. Clements, Kefyalew Addis Alene, Journal of Global Health. 15(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406245452

                Health system and environmental factors play a significant role in achieving the World Health Organization (WHO) End Tuberculosis (TB) targets. However, quantitative measures are scarce or non-existent at a global level. We aimed to measure the progress made towards meeting the global End TB milestones from 2015 to 2020 and identify health system and environmental factors contributing to the success. We obtained data from ten different online data repositories and used principal component analysis to create domain-specific health system performance measures. We used radar charts and dumbbell plots to show the country's progress in ending TB with their health systems. Lastly, we used a linear regression model to identify key health systems and environmental predictors of the percent reduction in TB incidence and mortality. There was a high variation in TB incidence and mortality reduction between countries and WHO regions. Of all countries included, 75 (39.3%) achieved more than a 20% reduction in TB incidence between 2015 and 2020. However, only 31 (16.2%) reached a 35% reduction in TB mortality. The European Region achieved the highest incidence reduction, exceeding the 2020 milestone with a 25% reduction. The African Region also made notable progress, achieving an 18% mortality reduction despite its relatively poor health systems. Health system factors, such as TB financing, TB-specific health service delivery, access to medicine, and governance, were significantly associated with TB mortality reduction between 2015 and 2020. Environmental factors, such as average annual temperature and air particulate matter concentration, were found to have a significant negative effect on TB incidence and mortality reduction. Weak health systems were identified as major barriers to achieving the End TB milestones in most high-burden countries. Hence, strengthening health systems with a special focus on TB financing, service delivery, and access to medicine in these countries should be prioritised to achieve global TB mortality reduction targets. Countries should follow WHO's air quality guidelines and rapidly reduce carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emissions to mitigate the impact of environmental factors.</description>
      <author>Haileab Fekadu Wolde, Archie C. A. Clements, Kefyalew Addis Alene</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7189/jogh.15.04004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Uniformity Properties and Corrosion Resistance of Zinc&#8211;Nickel Composite Coating Enhanced by Nano-SiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings15010071</link>
      <description>Sujie Chang, Yuanhao Wang, Jianpeng Wang, Zerui Hao, Yang Yang, Y.Y. Wang, Xinyi Wang, Fan Cao, Lei Shi, Coatings. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406242903

                In this study, pre-treated low-carbon steel substrates were electroplated with Zinc&#8211;Nickel (ZN) alloy composite coatings enhanced by the incorporation of nano-silicon dioxide (SiO2) particles in an alkaline solution. ZN deposits with varying concentrations of nano-SiO2&#8212;specifically, 1, 2, 3, 5, and 10 wt%&#8212;were achieved by adjusting the ratio between the nano-SiO2 and ZN alloy electroplating solutions. The influence of the nano-SiO2 content on both the quality of the coating and its corrosion behavior was investigated in detail. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy-dispersive spectroscopy (EDS), and an atomic force microscope (AFM) were utilized to assess the surface, cross-section structure, elemental composition, and thickness of the coatings. Notably, the addition of nano-SiO2 improved the microstructure of the coating, leading to a reduction in grain size as well as enhancements in uniformity and density while revealing that co-deposition reached an optimal concentration at 3 wt% nano-SiO2. The corrosion behavior of coated specimens was evaluated through electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) and polarization techniques within a 3.5 wt% NaCl solution serving as a corrosive medium. Specifically, for typical prepared coatings, the corrosion current density decreased from 1.410 &#215; 10&#8722;4 A&#183;cm&#8722;2 to 5.762 &#215; 10&#8722;6 A&#183;cm&#8722;2, which is a remarkable reduction by one to two orders of magnitude relative to the SiO2-free coatings mentioned previously. These findings provide a straightforward approach for selecting 3 wt% nano-SiO2 as an effective additive in ZN composite coatings.</description>
      <author>Sujie Chang, Yuanhao Wang, Jianpeng Wang, Zerui Hao, Yang Yang, Y.Y. Wang, Xinyi Wang, Fan Cao, Lei Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings15010071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antibacterial Efficacy Comparison of Electrolytic and Reductive Silver Nanoparticles Against Propionibacterium acnes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/antibiotics14010086</link>
      <description>Suparno Suparno, Rita Prasetyowati, Khafidh Nur Aziz, Aulia Rahma, Endang Sri Lestari, Siti Chaerani Nabiilah, Delia Grace, Antibiotics. 14(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406373888

                Background: The aim of this study was to develop an electrolysis system to produce silver nanoparticles free from toxic gases, as the most common reduction and electrolysis techniques produce nitrogen dioxide (NO2) as a byproduct, which is harmful to human health. The new electrolysis system used two identical silver plate electrodes, replacing silver and carbon rods, and used water as the electrolyte instead of silver nitrate (AgNO3) solution since AgNO3 is the source of NO2. Methods: The electrolytic silver nanoparticles (ESNs) produced by the new system were characterized and compared with reductive silver nanoparticles (RSNs). Using UV&#8211;Visible spectrophotometry, absorption peaks were found at 425 nm (ESN) and 437 nm (RSN). Using dynamic light scattering, the particle diameters were measured at 40.3 nm and 39.9 nm for ESNs at concentrations of 10 ppm and 30 ppm, respectively, and 74.0 nm and 74.6 nm for RSNs at concentrations of 10 ppm and 30 ppm, respectively. Antibacterial activity against Propionibacterium acnes (P. acnes) was assessed using the Kirby&#8211;Bauer method. Results: It was found that the efficacy of ESNs and RSNs was relatively lower than that of 5% chloramphenicol because it was measured in different concentration units (ESNs and RSNs in ppm and chloramphenicol in %). Using the calibration curve, the efficacy of 5% chloramphenicol was comparable to that of 0.005% ESN. It was also found that P. acnes developed a strong resistance to chloramphenicol and showed no resistance to ESNs. Conclusions: This finding underlines the tremendous potential of ESNs as a future antibiotic raw material.</description>
      <author>Suparno Suparno, Rita Prasetyowati, Khafidh Nur Aziz, Aulia Rahma, Endang Sri Lestari, Siti Chaerani Nabiilah, Delia Grace</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/antibiotics14010086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Waste to Resource: Evaluation of the Technical and Environmental Performance of Concrete Blocks Made from Iron Ore Tailings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020552</link>
      <description>Luciana Chaves Weba, J&#250;lia Maria Medalha Resende Oliveira, Alexandra Do Nascimento Souza, Lu&#237;s Antunes, Jos&#233; Maria Franco de Carvalho, Wanna Carvalho Fontes, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406304604

                This study investigates the use of iron ore tailings (IOTs) as recycled aggregates in segmental blocks, focusing on technical performance, CO2 emissions, and embodied energy using the cradle-to-gate approach. IOTs replaced fine aggregates in concrete at 25%, 50%, and 75% by volume, achieving compressive strengths of 16.23 MPa, 10.02 MPa, and 3.93 MPa, respectively. Raw material production accounted for 98% of CO2 emissions and 86% of embodied energy. Producing blocks at mining sites offered limited environmental benefits due to longer transport distances. Despite this, the results showed a 6% reduction in CO2 emissions and a 35% improvement in mechanical&#8211;environmental performance (CO2 emissions weighted by compressive strength) compared to traditional concrete. These findings underscore the potential of IOT-based concrete for segmental block production.</description>
      <author>Luciana Chaves Weba, J&#250;lia Maria Medalha Resende Oliveira, Alexandra Do Nascimento Souza, Lu&#237;s Antunes, Jos&#233; Maria Franco de Carvalho, Wanna Carvalho Fontes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Electrolysis Using Metal-Supported Solid Oxide Cells with Infiltrated Pr0.5Sr0.4Mn0.2Fe0.8O3-&#948; Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/adaa23</link>
      <description>Boxun Hu, Ka-Young Park, Asia Sarycheva, Robert Kostecki, Fanglin Chen, Mike C Tucker, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406363877

                Abstract Electrochemical conversion of CO2 to CO is demonstrated with symmetric-structured metal supported solid oxide cells (MS-SOC). Perovskite Pr0.5Sr0.4Mn0.2Fe0.8O3-&#948; (PSMF) and Pr6O11 catalysts were infiltrated into the MS-SOC cathode and anode, using 3 cycles with firing at 850&#61616;C and 8 cycles with firing at 800&#61616;C, respectively. Upon reduction during operation, the perovskite PSMF was transformed to Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper structure with a highly efficient electrocatalytic activity. The impact of operating temperature (600-800&#61616;C) and overpotential (0-1.8 V) on the CO2 conversion was investigated. The highest CO2 conversion of 57.2% was achieved at 750&#61616;C and 1.8 V. During extended operation for 150 h at 750&#61616;C and 1.2V, a cell demonstrated relatively stable performance, with initial current density of 535 mA cm-2 and CO2 conversion of 23%. Degradation mechanisms were studied by posttest characterization.</description>
      <author>Boxun Hu, Ka-Young Park, Asia Sarycheva, Robert Kostecki, Fanglin Chen, Mike C Tucker</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/adaa23</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;&#916;&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inversion setup for estimating European fossil CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-397-2025</link>
      <description>Carlos G&#243;mez-Ortiz, Guillaume Monteil, Sourish Basu, Marko Scholze, Atmospheric chemistry and physics. 25(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333402

                Abstract. Independent estimation and verification of fossil CO2 emissions on a regional and national scale are crucial for evaluating the fossil CO2 emissions and reductions reported by countries as part of their nationally determined contributions (NDCs). Top-down methods, such as the assimilation of in situ and satellite observations of different tracers (e.g., CO2, CO, &#916;14CO2, XCO2), have been increasingly used for this purpose. In this paper, we use the Lund University Modular Inversion Algorithm (LUMIA) to estimate fossil CO2 emissions and natural fluxes by simultaneously inverting in situ synthetic observations of CO2 and &#916;14CO2 over Europe. We evaluate the inversion system by conducting a series of observing system simulation experiments (OSSEs). We find that in regions with a dense sampling network, such as western/central Europe, adding &#916;14CO2 observations in an experiment where the prior fossil CO2 and biosphere fluxes are set to zero allows LUMIA to recover the time series of both categories. This reduces the prior-to-truth root mean square error (RMSE) from 1.26 to 0.12 TgC d&#8722;1 in fossil CO2 and from 0.97 to 0.17 TgC d&#8722;1 in biosphere fluxes, reflecting the true total CO2 budget by 91 %. In a second set of experiments using realistic prior fluxes, we find that in addition to retrieving the time series of the optimized fluxes, we are able to recover the true regional fossil CO2 budget in western/central Europe by 95 % and in Germany by 97 %. In all experiments, regions with low sampling coverage, such as southern Europe and the British Isles, show poorly resolved posterior fossil CO2 emissions. Although the posterior biosphere fluxes in these regions follow the seasonal patterns of the true fluxes, a significant bias remains, making it impossible to close the total CO2 budget. We find that the prior uncertainty of fossil CO2 emissions does not significantly impact the posterior estimates, showing similar results in regions with good sampling coverage like western/central Europe and northern Europe. Finally, having a good prior estimate of the terrestrial isotopic disequilibrium is important to avoid introducing additional noise into the posterior fossil CO2 fluxes.</description>
      <author>Carlos G&#243;mez-Ortiz, Guillaume Monteil, Sourish Basu, Marko Scholze</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-397-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Modeling and Experimental Investigation of CO2-Hydrocarbon System Within Cross-Scale Porous Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020277</link>
      <description>Feiyu Chen, Linghui Sun, Bowen Li, Xiuxiu Pan, Siyu Jian, Xu Huo, Zhirong Zhang, Chun Feng, Molecules. 30(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333918

                CO2 flooding plays a crucial role in enhancing oil recovery and achieving carbon reduction targets, particularly in unconventional reservoirs with complex pore structures. The phase behavior of CO2 and hydrocarbons at different scales significantly affects oil recovery efficiency, yet its underlying mechanisms remain insufficiently understood. This study improves existing thermodynamic models by introducing Helmholtz free energy as a convergence criterion and incorporating adsorption effects in micro- and nano-scale pores. This study refines existing thermodynamic models by incorporating Helmholtz free energy as a convergence criterion, offering a more accurate representation of confined phase behavior. Unlike conventional Gibbs free energy-based models, this approach effectively accounts for confinement-induced deviations in phase equilibrium, ensuring improved predictive accuracy for nanoscale reservoirs. Additionally, adsorption effects in micro- and nano-scale pores are explicitly integrated to enhance model reliability. A multi-scale thermodynamic model for CO2-hydrocarbon systems is developed and validated through physical simulations. Key findings indicate that as the scale decreases from bulk to 10 nm, the bubble point pressure shows a deviation of 5% to 23%, while the density of confined fluids increases by approximately 2%. The results also reveal that smaller pores restrict gas expansion, leading to an enhanced CO2 solubility effect and stronger phase mixing behavior. Through phase diagram analysis, density expansion, multi-stage contact, and differential separation simulations, we further clarify how confinement influences CO2 injection efficiency. These findings provide new insights into phase behavior changes in confined porous media, improving the accuracy of CO2 flooding predictions. The proposed model offers a more precise framework for evaluating phase transitions in unconventional reservoirs, aiding in the optimization of CO2-based enhanced oil recovery strategies.</description>
      <author>Feiyu Chen, Linghui Sun, Bowen Li, Xiuxiu Pan, Siyu Jian, Xu Huo, Zhirong Zhang, Chun Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence and Mechanism of Structural Characteristics of Limestone on Quicklime Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min15010072</link>
      <description>Zehao Yang, Jing Wu, Zhiqin Huang, Yong Zhu, Weikang Liang, Minjie Zhu, Minerals. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406376026

                Quicklime (CaO) is extensively used in metallurgy, chemical engineering, materials science, and greenhouse gas reduction due to its high reactivity, low energy consumption, and environmental benefits. It is considered as one of the most promising raw materials for nanomaterial synthesis and carbon dioxide capture. Previous studies have predominantly focused on the impact of limestone composition and calcination condition. Recent research, however, suggests that the structural characteristics of limestone also play a crucial role in determining the reactivity of quicklime. This study investigates the effect of limestone structure on quicklime reactivity and provides a mechanistic analysis. Three types of limestone with varying structures&#8212;clastic-structured, transitional-crystalline-structured, and crystalline-structured&#8212;were selected for experiments under different calcination times. The results indicate that quicklime produced from clastic-structured limestone exhibits the highest reactivity. The observed differences in quicklime reactivity can primarily be attributed to the following factors: (1) Clastic-structured limestone possesses larger pore volume and specific surface area, which enhance heat conduction and ensure the uniform decomposition of calcite across various regions. (2) The rock-forming calcite particles are fine and small, allowing for the simultaneous decomposition of the outer shell, middle, and core during heating. This prevents &#8220;overburning&#8221; of the shell or &#8220;underfiring&#8221; of the core, thereby improving the overall reactivity. Based on these findings, we propose that fine-grained, high-purity clastic-structured limestone is more favorable for producing high-activity quicklime.</description>
      <author>Zehao Yang, Jing Wu, Zhiqin Huang, Yong Zhu, Weikang Liang, Minjie Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/min15010072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Lattice Oxygen of Bi2O3 by Interstitial Insertion of Indium for Efficient Formic Acid Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423658</link>
      <description>Junjie Wang, Wu Tang, Zhaozhao Zhu, Yingxi Lin, Lei Zhao, Haiyuan Chen, Xueqiang Qi, Xiaobin Niu, Rui Wu, Jun Song Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333304

                Bismuth oxide (Bi2O3) emerges as a potent catalyst for converting CO2 to formic acid (HCOOH), leveraging its abundant lattice oxygen and the high activity of its Bi&#8208;O bonds. Yet, its durability is usually impeded by the loss of lattice oxygen causing structure alteration and destabilized active bonds. Herein, we report an innovative approach via the interstitial incorporation of indium (In) into the Bi2O3, significantly enhancing bond stability and preserving lattice oxygen. The optimized In&#8208;Bi2O3&#8208;100 catalyst achieves over 90% Faradaic efficiency for HCOOH production across a wide potential range, in both H&#8208;cells and flow cells, maintaining robust stability after 100 hours of continuous operation. In&#8208;situ surface&#8208;enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy and theoretical calculations reveal that the interstitial In doping precisely tunes the adsorption of CO2* and OCHO* intermediate, facilitating rapid conversion. Further in&#8208;situ Raman spectroscopy confirms the role of In bolstering the oxidized structure's stability within Bi2O3, critical for sustaining lattice oxygen during electrochemical CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Junjie Wang, Wu Tang, Zhaozhao Zhu, Yingxi Lin, Lei Zhao, Haiyuan Chen, Xueqiang Qi, Xiaobin Niu, Rui Wu, Jun Song Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Lattice Oxygen of Bi2O3 by Interstitial Insertion of Indium for Efficient Formic Acid Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423658</link>
      <description>Junjie Wang, Wu Tang, Zhaozhao Zhu, Yingxi Lin, Lei Zhao, Haiyuan Chen, Xueqiang Qi, Xiaobin Niu, Rui Wu, Jun Song Chen, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333687

                Bismuth oxide (Bi2O3) emerges as a potent catalyst for converting CO2 to formic acid (HCOOH), leveraging its abundant lattice oxygen and the high activity of its Bi-O bonds. Yet, its durability is usually impeded by the loss of lattice oxygen causing structure alteration and destabilized active bonds. Herein, we report an innovative approach via the interstitial incorporation of indium (In) into the Bi2O3, significantly enhancing bond stability and preserving lattice oxygen. The optimized In-Bi2O3-100 catalyst achieves over 90% Faradaic efficiency for HCOOH production across a wide potential range, in both H-cells and flow cells, maintaining robust stability after 100 hours of continuous operation. In-situ surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy and theoretical calculations reveal that the interstitial In doping precisely tunes the adsorption of CO2* and OCHO* intermediate, facilitating rapid conversion. Further in-situ Raman spectroscopy confirms the role of In bolstering the oxidized structure's stability within Bi2O3, critical for sustaining lattice oxygen during electrochemical CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Junjie Wang, Wu Tang, Zhaozhao Zhu, Yingxi Lin, Lei Zhao, Haiyuan Chen, Xueqiang Qi, Xiaobin Niu, Rui Wu, Jun Song Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studies of the expansion mechanism on different pellets under hydrogen-rich reducing atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00084433.2024.2447644</link>
      <description>Shuo Wang, Fengman Shen, Xiaobo Zhang, Haiyan Zheng, Xin Jiang, Qiangjian Gao, Canadian Metallurgical Quarterly. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406297394

                In response to the need to develop green low-carbon iron smelting technology, blast furnace hydrogen reduction technology is of great significance for reducing CO2 emissions from the ironmaking system. This study focuses on the change in swelling behaviour of different types of pellets during the blast furnace hydrogen smelting process. It analyses the reduction swelling index (RSI/%) and compression strength before and after reduction at 900&#176;C in a variety of reduction gas atmospheres, among other indices. The results show that under the condition of ore grade, the reduction expansion rate of pellet increases with the increase of grade. With the increase of basicity (R) (0 &#8764; 0.25) and the Mg-Al ratio (M/A) (0.4 &#8764; 1.4), the reduction in expansion of the pellet shows an upward trend. However, the RSI/% shows a downward trend with the increase of the synergistic effect of ore silicon and aluminium (S + A). The compression strength after reduction increases to different degrees with the increase of the proportion of hydrogen in the reduction atmosphere; the maximum increase was about 0.591 KN. SEM-EDS detection was carried out on pellet in different reduction atmospheres, and the structure and component changes of various regions during the reduction process were analysed.</description>
      <author>Shuo Wang, Fengman Shen, Xiaobo Zhang, Haiyan Zheng, Xin Jiang, Qiangjian Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00084433.2024.2447644</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Specific Activity during Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction through Homogeneous Deposition of Gold Nanoparticles on Gas Diffusion Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02254</link>
      <description>Takuya Yamada, Kazuyuki Iwase, Naoto Todoroki, Itaru Honma, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406308799

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) has attracted attention as a promising strategy for converting CO2 into value-added products. Gas diffusion electrodes (GDEs) loaded with metallic nanoparticles as electrocatalysts are expected to efficiently reduce CO2 due to the high specific surface area of such particles and the superior mass transport characteristics of GDEs. In the present study, GDEs loaded with homogeneous layers of gold (Au) nanoparticles were fabricated using a radio frequency sputtering technique that had a low deposition rate. This allowed for precise control of the catalyst loading. The Au-loaded GDEs exhibited a significantly higher CO production efficiency compared with the electrodes fabricated by conventional deposition methods using dispersed Au nanoparticles. Additionally, a Au-loaded GDE having a catalytic layer thickness of 10 nm demonstrated a mass-based CO production activity of 1882 A g&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.85 V. This is the highest value yet reported. This work confirmed that the uniform deposition of metallic nanoparticles provides enhanced catalyst utilization. The results of this research provide important insights into the design of efficient CO2RR electrodes and highlight the potential of radio frequency sputtering to fabricate high-performance CO2RR electrodes as an approach to realizing carbon-neutral technologies.</description>
      <author>Takuya Yamada, Kazuyuki Iwase, Naoto Todoroki, Itaru Honma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24&#8208;Epibrassinolide Improves Potato (&lt;i&gt;Solanum tuberosum&lt;/i&gt; L.) Tolerance to Alkaline Salt Stress by Regulating Antioxidant Defence and Photosynthetic Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jac.70022</link>
      <description>Yong Wang, Ruyan Zhang, Xingxing Wang, Shujuan Jiao, Weina Zhang, Yichen Kang, Ming Li, Jiali Xie, Xinyu Yang, Yuhui Liu, Shuhao Qin, Journal of Agronomy and Crop Science. 211(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406250805

                ABSTRACT Alkaline salt stress, as a more diverse stress, severely affects the growth and development of potato ( Solanum tuberosum L.) and leads to yield reduction. Brassinosteroids have been shown to regulate plant growth and play an essential role under environmental stress. However, the physiological responses by which brassinosteroids confer alkaline salt stress tolerance in potato remain unclear. We used potato &#8216; Atlantic &#8217; as experimental material. The effects of 0.01, 0.1, 1 and 10 &#956;mol&#183;L &#8722;1 of 24&#8208;epibrassinolide (EBR) on the physiological and photosynthetic characteristics of potato under alkaline salt stress (300 mmol&#183;L &#8722;1 NaHCO 3 ) were studied. The results showed that exogenous EBR increased the antioxidant enzyme activities, increased the content of osmoregulatory substances and decreased the production of peroxidation products in potato leaves under alkaline salt stress. EBR treatment improved the photosynthetic characteristics by accumulating more photosynthetic pigments. This was manifested by an increase in net photosynthetic rate, transpiration rate and stomatal conductance, and a decrease in intercellular carbon dioxide concentration. In addition, exogenous EBR increased the maximal quantum yield of photosystem II photochemistry and the effective PSII quantum yield of potato PSII under alkaline salt stress and ultimately increased yield. Potato tuber yield was significantly increased by 27.31% and 29.17% in T4 treatment compared to T1 in 2022 and 2023, respectively. Cluster and correlation analyses further demonstrated the beneficial effects of exogenous EBR on physiology, photosynthetic characteristics and potato yield under alkaline salt stress. In conclusion, exogenous EBR can enhance the tolerance of potato to alkaline salt stress by improving the antioxidant system and photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Yong Wang, Ruyan Zhang, Xingxing Wang, Shujuan Jiao, Weina Zhang, Yichen Kang, Ming Li, Jiali Xie, Xinyu Yang, Yuhui Liu, Shuhao Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jac.70022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A photosynthesis&#8208;derived bionic system for sustainable biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414981</link>
      <description>Na Chen, Ruichen Shen, Tianpei He, Na Du, Jing Xi, Yangbing Yang, Lilei Yu, Quan Yuan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406319475

                &#8220;Cell factory&#8221; strategy based on microbial anabolism pathways offers an intriguing alternative to relieve the dependence on fossil fuels, which are recognized as the main sources of CO2 emission. Typically, anabolism of intracellular substance in cell factory requires the consumption of sufficient reduced nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NADPH) and adenosine triphosphate (ATP). However, it is of great challenge to modify the natural limited anabolism and to increase the insufficient level of NADPH and ATP to optimum concentrations without causing metabolic imbalance. Inspired by the natural photosynthesis process in which NADPH and ATP can both be produced through the coupled electron&#8208;proton transfer processes driven by sunlight, herein we designed a light&#8208;driven bionic system composed of three modules including photo&#8208;induced electron module, electron transfer channel module and proton gradient module. The proposed strategy of light&#8208;driven bionic system enables for achieving simultaneous and controllable supplies of NADPH and ATP, thus facilitating both highly efficient CO2 fixation and biomanufacturing. The proposed light&#8208;driven bionic system design strategy in this work might pave new sustainable ways for reducing power and energy regeneration to optimize microbial metabolism, offering intriguing alternatives for CO2 emission reduction and high value&#8208;added chemical biomanufacturing.</description>
      <author>Na Chen, Ruichen Shen, Tianpei He, Na Du, Jing Xi, Yangbing Yang, Lilei Yu, Quan Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A photosynthesis&#8208;derived bionic system for sustainable biosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414981</link>
      <description>Na Chen, Ruichen Shen, Tianpei He, Na Du, Jing Xi, Yangbing Yang, Lilei Yu, Quan Yuan, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406319476

                "Cell factory" strategy based on microbial anabolism pathways offers an intriguing alternative to relieve the dependence on fossil fuels, which are recognized as the main sources of CO2 emission. Typically, anabolism of intracellular substance in cell factory requires the consumption of sufficient reduced nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NADPH) and adenosine triphosphate (ATP). However, it is of great challenge to modify the natural limited anabolism and to increase the insufficient level of NADPH and ATP to optimum concentrations without causing metabolic imbalance. Inspired by the natural photosynthesis process in which NADPH and ATP can both be produced through the coupled electron-proton transfer processes driven by sunlight, herein we designed a light-driven bionic system composed of three modules including photo-induced electron module, electron transfer channel module and proton gradient module. The proposed strategy of light-driven bionic system enables for achieving simultaneous and controllable supplies of NADPH and ATP, thus facilitating both highly efficient CO2 fixation and biomanufacturing. The proposed light-driven bionic system design strategy in this work might pave new sustainable ways for reducing power and energy regeneration to optimize microbial metabolism, offering intriguing alternatives for CO2 emission reduction and high value-added chemical biomanufacturing.</description>
      <author>Na Chen, Ruichen Shen, Tianpei He, Na Du, Jing Xi, Yangbing Yang, Lilei Yu, Quan Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of low frequency vibration to the turning of ultra-high molecular weight polyethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/20550340.2025.2449631</link>
      <description>Jack Rooke, R.D. Bonnell, Emily Pickford, Adam Brown, David Curtis, Advanced Manufacturing Polymer &amp; Composites Science. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406242955

                Medical implant manufacturing is a growing sector and therefore requires improved manufacturing practices. In the case of total hip arthroplasty, the most challenging component to meet the ISO standard (ISO 7206-2:2011) is the acetabular liner, often made from ultra-high molecular weight polyethylene (UHMWPE). UHMWPE machining is associated with several manufacturing challenges, including swarf control. This research used low frequency vibration (LFV), an intermittent cutting process and supercritical CO2 (scCO2) to aid chip segmentation and prevent swarf nesting. Machining trials have demonstrated a significant reduction in swarf nesting relative to a traditional process (91% reduction from LFV and 98% reduction when using LFV and scCO2). The surface roughness (*Ra_Symbol*) also had an indirect improvement from using LFV (53% reduction on the inner hemisphere), leading to all parts meeting the roughness requirement of ISO 7206-2:2011. The results have demonstrated machinability benefits for UHMWPE, reducing the operator intervention required and component scrap rates.</description>
      <author>Jack Rooke, R.D. Bonnell, Emily Pickford, Adam Brown, David Curtis</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/20550340.2025.2449631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the role of production capacity in mitigating carbon emissions: a case study of Algeria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34140/bjbv7n1-008</link>
      <description>Bouazza Elamine Zemr&#305;, Mohammed Fouad Gassem, Brazilian Journal of Business. 7(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406314937

                This study examines the relationship between productive capacity and CO2 emissions in Algeria, addressing the pressing challenge of sustainable development in the context of climate change. The aim is to explore how enhancing production capacity can influence environmental outcomes, particularly in terms of carbon emissions. To achieve this, the study employs an Auto Regressive Distributed Lag (ARDL) model, with results validated through an Error Correction Model (ECM), using data from 1990 to 2023. The findings reveal that improvements in productive capacity contribute to a long-term reduction in CO2 emissions per capita. However, an increase in energy consumption has the potential to undermine these gains, underlining the need for greater energy efficiency. Key policy recommendations suggest prioritizing investments in energy-efficient technologies, thereby enhancing Algeria&#8217;s productive capacity while minimizing environmental impact. This framework provides a valuable pathway for aligning economic growth with sustainable environmental practices, offering actionable insights for policymakers aiming to balance development with climate goals.</description>
      <author>Bouazza Elamine Zemr&#305;, Mohammed Fouad Gassem</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34140/bjbv7n1-008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASSESSING THE PUBLIC PERCEPTION AND TARGETED IMPLEMENTATION OF ELECTRIC MOTORCYCLES IN DENPASAR CITY RELATED TO EMISSION REDUCTION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24843/ejes.2024.v18.i02.p10</link>
      <description>Otniel Stefen Adi Prasetyo, Qomariatus Sholihah, &#1045;driana Pang&#1077;stuti, Takahiro Osawa, Rio Aldi Prasetyo, ECOTROPHIC Jurnal Ilmu Lingkungan (Journal of Environmental Science). 18(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406320273

                Using an electric motorcycles can contribute to decreasing emissions in the transportation sector. Government policies and various socialization programs have supported the development of electric vehicles. This research was conducted to determine the public perception and implementation of electric motorcycles in Denpasar City. The public perception was obtained through questionnaires and in-depth interviews with related key persons. The statistical analysis of the questionnaire indicated a good category with a score of 3.43. The level of community acceptance was influenced by quieter and environmentally friendly technology, electricity tax subsidies, and lower electric fuel costs. The interview with community and government representatives reinforced the public acceptance finding affected by the intensive public outreach program and a vehicle installment payment scheme. As the result, The implementation target was rated optimistic, with a potential CO2 emission reduction of up to 32,641 tons/year in 2026. All the efforts to implement electric motorcycles in Denpasar City by the goverments have met the requirements to achieve acceptance of perceptions in the people of Denpasar City. This thing&#8217;s very important to reaching out the scenario of reducing CO2 emissions by 2026. In addition, it is important to have a more study regarding to the sustainability of the electric motorcycles ecosystem, such as the availability of data sources update from related agencies that show efforts to improve infrastructure by producers, the number of charging station and selling stations, as well as opportunities for domestic production and incentive policies. Keywords: Electric Motorcycles; Emission; Implementation Targets; Level of Acceptance; Public Perception</description>
      <author>Otniel Stefen Adi Prasetyo, Qomariatus Sholihah, &#1045;driana Pang&#1077;stuti, Takahiro Osawa, Rio Aldi Prasetyo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24843/ejes.2024.v18.i02.p10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Design of Ice Thermal Energy Storage Unit Integrated into a Marine Air Conditioning System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095963</link>
      <description>Yang Yu, Wenbin Cui, Chong Zhang, Hong&#8208;Rui Fan, Yi Wei, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406313107

                Greenhouse gas emission from ships is currently one of the environmental issues for the shipping industry. Considering the marine air conditioning system consumes much energy on board ships, and to improve its efficiency and thus reduce CO2 emission, an ice thermal energy storage (ICE-TES) unit was designed and integrated into a marine air conditioning system on a real ship. Four cases distinguished with the shaved peak value of cooling load as 4%, 8%, 12%, and 16% were analyzed, and with the increasing shaving percent the integration of ICE-TES unit could reduce more electricity consumed for air cooling, and a upmost reduction of 1.49% was achieved (saved fuel by 33.99 kg/day). Furthermore, the rated power of compressor was optimized subsequently, the corresponding average COP of the system was enhanced from 2.36 to 2.45, and the saving in electricity consumption was promoted to 5.23% (saved fuel by 95.53 kg/day). Environmental analysis showed that CO2 emission was reduced by up to 2.84%, and the payback period for the optimized system could be shortened to 2.50 years. Thus this study proves the feasibility of the integration of ICE-TES unit with central air conditioning systems specifically for marine applications.</description>
      <author>Yang Yu, Wenbin Cui, Chong Zhang, Hong&#8208;Rui Fan, Yi Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Evaluation of Ceiling Cooling with PCM in the Hot-Dry Climate of Yazd, Iran: An Experimental Analysis of Energy, Environmental, and Economic Impacts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15020198</link>
      <description>Mehran Rabani, Mina Alafzadeh, Mehrdad Rabani, Buildings. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406334922

                The present study investigates experimental cooling from the ceiling using phase change materials (PCMs) in Yazd, a city characterized by a hot and dry climate. A one-fourth scale model of a real room, measuring 4 m &#215; 3 m &#215; 3 m, was employed for the analysis. To evaluate system performance and the impact of PCM on energy consumption reduction, three configurations were considered: a simple PCM system, a PCM system with a fan (PCM-F), and a PCM system with a mini cooler (PCM-C). Additionally, to assess the influence of window configurations on ventilation, temperature, and comfort conditions within the model, three scenarios were examined: two open windows, one open window, and no windows. The economic analysis compared the two systems with the fan and mini cooler against a full mechanical cooling system without PCMs. Furthermore, CO2 emissions and environmental impacts associated with the systems were also evaluated. The results indicate that the presence of PCMs in the ceiling, due to heat absorption during phase change, leads to a temperature reduction of 5 to 10 &#176;C in the ceiling and a 3.2 &#176;C reduction in the average room temperature compared to the scenario without PCMs. The findings demonstrate that ceiling cooling with PCMs significantly contributes to energy consumption reduction during peak hours of cooling demand. Specifically, the PCM-F system results in a 92% reduction, and the PCM-C system leads to a 71% reduction in total cost compared to the reference mechanical cooling system. Additionally, the PCM-F system achieves approximately a 36% reduction, and the PCM-C system results in a 34% reduction in environmental impact relative to the reference full mechanical cooling system.</description>
      <author>Mehran Rabani, Mina Alafzadeh, Mehrdad Rabani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15020198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seismic and ultrasonic frequency measurements on partially saturated rocks under X-ray</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/gji/ggaf017</link>
      <description>K. S. Mews, Serhii Lozovyi, Geophysical Journal International. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406358697

                Summary Low-frequency laboratory measurements provide direct access to the elastic properties of samples within the seismic frequency band, offering calibration data for seismic survey analysis. Additionally, &#194;&#181;CT imaging can quantify actual saturations and provides insights into phase distributions at the pore scale. To conduct laboratory triaxial measurements at seismic frequencies while simultaneously imaging the rock interior, we developed an X-ray transparent low-frequency apparatus. Our apparatus determines rock mechanical properties at seismic frequencies (0.5&#226;&amp;#x80;&amp;#x93;150 Hz) and strain amplitudes (10&#8722;7&#226;&amp;#x80;&amp;#x93;10&#8722;5), measuring Young&#226;&amp;#x80;&amp;#x99;s modulus, Poisson&#226;&amp;#x80;&amp;#x99;s ratio, and attenuation. In addition P- and S-wave velocities at ultrasonic frequencies are measured. We conducted imbibition-drainage experiments to assess the effect of saturation and patch size on seismic and ultrasonic elastic properties in sandstone. Additional tests with liquid and gaseous CO2 reveal the impact of partial CO2-gas saturation. The imbibition-drainage experiment demonstrated that P-wave velocity at ultrasonic frequencies was elevated during drainage and reduced during imbibition. Drainage caused patchy saturation, while imbibition resulted in uniform saturation. This implies that ultrasonic measurements, with wavelengths comparable to the pore fluid patch size, are likely influenced by scattering. In contrast, low-frequency measurements, where the wavelength surpasses the patch size, capture effective medium properties and therefore are not affected by scattering effects. The results of the CO2 test suggest that low-frequency measurements can detect even low gas saturations (4% gaseous CO2). In contrast, ultrasonic velocity measurements primarily reflect the response of the fully saturated sample at low gas saturations and do not indicate a reduction in velocity. Identifying fluid-solid interactions and estimating saturation via &#194;&#181;CT imaging is crucial, especially with minimal gas presence. Our combined approach allows precise determination of elastic properties at seismic frequencies and shows the importance of low-frequency over ultrasonic measurements.</description>
      <author>K. S. Mews, Serhii Lozovyi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/gji/ggaf017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphitic Carbon Nitride: Achieving Superlow Friction and Wear on Engineering Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00696</link>
      <description>Lin Li, Tao Lin, Jie Sun, Hanjun Gong, Yun Bai, Kai Gao, ACS Applied Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406254470

                Graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) is a typical two-dimensional (2D) material acclaimed for its layered structure and electronic properties, showcasing promise across various domains such as catalysis, CO2 reduction, and lubrication. In this study, g-C3N4 is synthesized as an oil-based nanoadditive within oleic acid (OA), exhibiting superlow friction coefficient (COF) within steel/steel contacts under high pressure. When dispersed g-C3N4 in OA at a concentration of 0.25 wt %, the COF is reduced from 0.077 to 0.022 compared to the base oil. The amino groups in g-C3N4 promote the formation of continuous friction films, creating a composite tribofilm made of carbon layers, carbon nitride, and iron oxides. This tribofilm effectively prevents direct contact between tribopairs, leading to significant friction reduction and enhanced antiwear properties. These findings offer insights into the design of lubricant additives for base oils and highlight the promising potential of carbon nitride in lubrication and tribology applications.</description>
      <author>Lin Li, Tao Lin, Jie Sun, Hanjun Gong, Yun Bai, Kai Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fueling Climate Solutions: A Federal Clean Fuel Standard (Cfs) for the USA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095478</link>
      <description>Cato Sandford, Chris Malins, Maria Cecilia P. Moura, J. L. Martin, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406306068

                A clean fuel standard (CFS) is a regulatory instrument that aims to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from the use of transportation fuel. It establishes a lifecycle emissions benchmark (the 'compliance schedule') against which fuels may be rewarded or penalized. This paper explains the CFS mechanism and examines the prospects for a national CFS in the USA that covers road and aviation segments. We introduce the CFS Scenario Compliance Model (CSCM), and two ambitious scenarios of transportation decarbonization which are consistent with an economy that reaches net zero emissions in 2050. Our 'High-ZEV' scenario is characterized by rapid transition of the vehicle fleet, while the 'High-Liquid' scenario emphasizes rapid scale-up of next-generation fuel production. These scenarios achieve a 87-94% reduction in road transportation carbon intensity by 2050. In addition, we model an ~84% reduction for aviation fuel (this includes carbon removals, but excludes the climate impact of aviation's non-CO2 emissions). Policy considerations for the design of a national CFS in the USA include the ambition of target-setting, investment support, and use of feedstock caps to mitigate sustainability risks. Cross-sectoral linkages mean that target-setting in transportation policy should be coupled with transitions towards renewable electricity and climate-efficient farming practices.</description>
      <author>Cato Sandford, Chris Malins, Maria Cecilia P. Moura, J. L. Martin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An analysis of the transport impact of finish building on-ramps and off-ramps from the Dnipro embankment to the Darnytskyi Bridge in Kyiv</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56318/as/2.2024.172</link>
      <description>Dmytro Bespalov, Volodymyr Tarasiuk, Mykola Osetrin, Maksym Dorosh, Oleksii Pryimachenko, Architectural studies. 10(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406314881

                This study was aimed at assessing the effectiveness of design solutions for the development of Kyiv&#8217;s transport infrastructure based on transport modelling and analysis of possible socio-economic effects. To do this, a four-step algorithm for modelling transport demand was used, based on data from sociological surveys, territory plans, and forecasts for 2030. The results of the study showed significant changes in the functioning of the Kyiv transport network as a result of the implementation of the proposed design solutions. The transport modelling helped to estimate quantitative indicators such as traffic volumes on major highways, as well as qualitative changes such as reduced congestion, shorter travel times, and cost savings. One of the key results was that the opening of new exits and entrances to the Darnytskyi Bridge on the left bank contributed to a slight increase in bridge capacity, but the biggest effect was seen on the approaches to the bridge. The additional approaches have increased traffic volumes, which indicates improved transport accessibility for drivers using this transport hub. The results related to environmental performance were also important. The reduction in congestion resulted in a reduction in CO2 emissions, which is a significant contribution to improving the environmental situation in the city. In terms of cost-effectiveness, the results demonstrated significant savings in transport losses, confirming that the implementation of the proposed measures has a positive impact on transport infrastructure, as well as reducing financial losses associated with travel. Thus, the results of the study confirmed that the proposed design solutions have a positive impact on the development of the transport network, increasing capacity and reducing negative environmental impact, which opens up opportunities for creating a more efficient transport system that meets the requirements of sustainable development and improves the overall quality of life of Kyiv residents</description>
      <author>Dmytro Bespalov, Volodymyr Tarasiuk, Mykola Osetrin, Maksym Dorosh, Oleksii Pryimachenko</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56318/as/2.2024.172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soil smoldering in temperate forests: a neglected contributor to fire carbon emissions revealed by atmospheric mixing ratios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-22-213-2025</link>
      <description>Lilian Vallet, Charbel Abdallah, Thomas Lauvaux, Lilian Joly, Michel Ramonet, Philippe Ciais, Morgan Lopez, Ir&#232;ne Xu&#233;ref-R&#233;my, Florent Mouillot, Biogeosciences. 22(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406337752

                Abstract. Fire is regarded as an essential climate variable, emitting greenhouse gases in the combustion process. Current global assessments of fire emissions traditionally rely on coarse remotely sensed burned-area data, along with biome-specific combustion completeness and emission factors (EFs). However, large uncertainties persist regarding burned areas, biomass affected, and emission factors. Recent increases in resolution have improved previous estimates of burned areas and aboveground biomass while increasing the information content used to derive emission factors, complemented by airborne sensors deployed in the tropics. To date, temperate forests, characterized by a lower fire incidence and stricter aerial surveillance restrictions near wildfires, have received less attention. In this study, we leveraged the distinctive fire season of 2022, which impacted western European temperate forests, to investigate fire emissions monitored by the atmospheric tower network. We examined the role of soil smoldering combustion responsible for higher carbon emissions, locally reported by firefighters but not accounted for in temperate fire emission budgets. We assessed the CO/CO2 ratio released by major fires in the Mediterranean, Atlantic pine, and Atlantic temperate forests of France. Our findings revealed low modified combustion efficiency (MCE) for the two Atlantic temperate regions, supporting the assumption of heavy smoldering combustion. This type of combustion was associated with specific fire characteristics, such as long-lasting thermal fire signals, and affected ecosystems encompassing needle leaf species, peatlands, and superficial lignite deposits in the soils. Thanks to high-resolution data (approximately 10 m) on burned areas, tree biomass, peatlands, and soil organic matter (SOM), we proposed a revised combustion emission framework consistent with the observed MCEs. Our estimates revealed that 6.15 Mt CO2 (&#177;2.65) was emitted, with belowground stock accounting for 51.75 % (&#177;16.05). Additionally, we calculated a total emission of 1.14 Mt CO (&#177;0.61), with 84.85 % (&#177;3.75) originating from belowground combustion. As a result, the carbon emissions from the 2022 fires in France amounted to 7.95 MtCO2-eq (&#177;3.62). These values exceed by 2-fold the Global Fire Assimilation System (GFAS) estimates for the country, reaching 4.18 MtCO2-eq (CO and CO2). Fires represent 1.97 % (&#177;0.89) of the country's annual carbon footprint, corresponding to a reduction of 30 % in the forest carbon sink this year. Consequently, we conclude that current European fire emission estimates should be revised to account for soil combustion in temperate forests. We also recommend the use of atmospheric mixing ratios as an effective monitoring system of prolonged soil fires that have the potential to re-ignite in the following weeks.</description>
      <author>Lilian Vallet, Charbel Abdallah, Thomas Lauvaux, Lilian Joly, Michel Ramonet, Philippe Ciais, Morgan Lopez, Ir&#232;ne Xu&#233;ref-R&#233;my, Florent Mouillot</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-22-213-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adoption of Electric Vehicles and Forecasting Air Emissions in the Metropolitan Area of Mexico City by 2050</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/wevj16010033</link>
      <description>Rodolfo Sosa Echeverr&#237;a, Graciela Velasco Herrera, Pablo S&#225;nchez &#193;lvarez, E. Hern&#225;ndez, Gilberto Fuentes Garc&#237;a, V&#237;ctor Manuel Velasco Herrera, Rogelio Gonz&#225;lez Oropeza, W. Vicente, Jaime Gandarilla Ibarra, Rodrigo Rivera Rivera, World Electric Vehicle Journal. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406242815

                Densely populated urban megacities, such as the Metropolitan Area of Mexico City, face the ongoing deterioration of air quality. Emissions from industrail factories and internal combustion vehicles are the main sources of pollutants. We have evaluated different transition trends from internal combustion engine vehicles as bus, truck and van, and motorcycle to electric vehicles through 2050. The total vehicle growth follows a second-degree polynomial trend. Bus growth exhibits a linear trend. Truck and van growth display a second-degree polynomial trend. Motorcycle growth also follows a second-degree polynomial trend. We found that the most significant reductions in transportation emissions are observed in CO2, followed by NOx, volatile organic compound (VOC), and particulate matter, with light and heavy vehicles being the primary contributors to total emissions. Mexico City serves as a pilot laboratory where both the challenges and potential solutions to an issue affecting millions of citizens can be observed. If proven effective and practical, these solutions could be applied to other megacities.</description>
      <author>Rodolfo Sosa Echeverr&#237;a, Graciela Velasco Herrera, Pablo S&#225;nchez &#193;lvarez, E. Hern&#225;ndez, Gilberto Fuentes Garc&#237;a, V&#237;ctor Manuel Velasco Herrera, Rogelio Gonz&#225;lez Oropeza, W. Vicente, Jaime Gandarilla Ibarra, Rodrigo Rivera Rivera</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/wevj16010033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Metal-Free Coal-Based Carbon Aerogel Catalyst for Oxygen Reduction to Produce Hydrogen Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03929</link>
      <description>Lingman Xia, Mingsheng Luo, Changke Shao, Yang Zhi, Huanqiao Song, Rehab O. Abdel Rahman, Ziyuan Li, Xing Cui, Wenshuai Yang, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406276876

                In this study, a highly efficient metal-free catalyst derived supported on coal-based carbon aerogel was successfully synthesized for the two-electron transfer oxygen reduction reaction (2e&#8211; ORR) to produce hydrogen peroxide (H2O2). The catalyst, with its high specific surface area and hierarchical porous structure, demonstrated exceptional selectivity for H2O2 under alkaline conditions. By optimization of the synthesis and drying conditions, particularly through the use of supercritical drying technology, the physicochemical properties and selectivity of the catalyst were significantly enhanced. Notably, the coal-based carbon gel obtained through supercritical drying with CO2 exhibited the superior specific surface area over 1311 m2&#183;g&#8211;1. The H2O2 selectivity over 95% at a potential of 0.5 V vs SHE was obtained using the catalyst material synthesized from this study. It was also revealed that the high selectivity was attributed to the layered edge active sites, which are rich in carbonyl (C=O) and carboxyl (COOH) groups. In situ FTIR and Raman spectroscopic analyses confirmed the two-electron-transfer ORR reaction mechanism from this study.</description>
      <author>Lingman Xia, Mingsheng Luo, Changke Shao, Yang Zhi, Huanqiao Song, Rehab O. Abdel Rahman, Ziyuan Li, Xing Cui, Wenshuai Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flame Retardancy and Heat Shielding in Green Polypropylene Composites Using Biohybrid Fibers and Agro-Waste Fillers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01733</link>
      <description>Thanh Mai Nguyen Tran, M. N. Prabhakar, Lee Dong Woo, Song Jung-il, ACS Applied Bio Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406252855

                The current work presents the flame-retardant performance of hybrid polypropylene composites, reinforced with specific short woven flax fabrics (SWFs), short basalt fibers (BFs), and rice husk powder (RHP), using polypropylene grafted maleic anhydride (MAPP) as the coupling agent. Horizontal burning test (HBT), microcalorimeter test (MCT), and cone calorimeter test (CCT) were conducted on these composites. The formulations used were 25% SWF/PP, 25% SWF/20% BF/PP, and 25% SWF/20% BF/PP with 6% RHP and 25% SWF/20% BF/PP with varying RHP contents (6, 12, and 18%) in combination with 6% MAPP. A peak heat release rate (pHRR) reduction of 14.42% was recorded in microcalorimeter test results. However, cone calorimeter test results indicated a reduction of 80.95% in pHRR and 23.84% in total heat release rate (THR). Furthermore, the emissions of CO and CO2 were reduced by 68 and 67%, respectively, in the 25SWF/20BF/PP.6MAPP-18RHP composite compared to pure PP, indicating an overall improvement in combustion efficiency. Fire performance index (FPI) also improved remarkably: FPI increased by 130% and fire growth index (FGI) improved by 81.34%. Moreover, the horizontal burning test showed an improved performance, with the burning rate further reduced by 11.10% compared to that of the 25% SWF/PP composite. These results highlight the synergy among natural fibers, agro-waste fillers, and MAPP in improving flame retardancy of polypropylene composites, and hence their potential application in automobiles and construction, where the demand for fire safety is very high.</description>
      <author>Thanh Mai Nguyen Tran, M. N. Prabhakar, Lee Dong Woo, Song Jung-il</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating climate-related financial policies&#8217; impact on decarbonization with machine learning methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-85127-7</link>
      <description>Paola D&#8217;Orazio, Anh-Duy Pham, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406272712

                Abstract This study examines how Climate-Related Financial Policies (CRFPs) support decarbonization and renewable energy transitions across 87 countries from 2000 to 2023. Using the Policy Sequencing Score (PSS) and a bindingness-weighted adoption indicator, it explores the relationships between CRFPs, CO2 emissions, and Renewable Energy Production (REP) across diverse economic and institutional contexts. Findings reveal significant variation in outcomes. Advanced economies and OECD countries leverage structured policies and robust institutions to achieve steady emissions reductions and REP growth, with diminishing returns at higher policy intensities. Emerging Markets and Developing Economies (EMDEs) face institutional and structural constraints but show strong responsiveness to targeted policies, particularly in Sub-Saharan Africa and South Asia, where renewable energy growth potential is notable. Regions such as Latin America and East Asia display mixed trends, reflecting unique challenges and opportunities. Binding policies prove essential for environmental outcomes, particularly in institutionalized settings, while EMDEs require capacity building and international cooperation to address barriers. This study highlights the importance of tailoring CRFPs to specific contexts, emphasizing policy sequencing, enforcement, and capacity building. By identifying global and regional variations, the findings provide actionable insights for aligning financial systems with climate goals, fostering a sustainable low-carbon transition, and addressing equity challenges.</description>
      <author>Paola D&#8217;Orazio, Anh-Duy Pham</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-85127-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the Carbon Reduction Potential of Urban Parks Under Extreme Heat Events Using Interpretable Machine Learning: A Case Study of Jinan, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos16010079</link>
      <description>Lemin Yu, Wenjun Li, C. Zheng, Xiaowen Lin, Atmosphere. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406343047

                Greenhouse gas emissions are primary drivers of climate change, and the intensification of extreme heat and urban heat island effects poses serious threats to urban ecosystems, public health, and energy consumption. This study systematically evaluated the carbon reduction potential of 369 urban parks in Jinan during extreme heat events using land surface temperature (LST) retrieval, combined with CatBoost + SHAP machine learning methods. Results indicate that the LST in Jinan ranged from 1.77 &#176;C to 59.44 &#176;C, and 278 parks exhibited significant cooling effects, collectively saving 2943 tons of CO2 per day&#8212;offsetting 11.28% of the city&#8217;s fossil fuel emissions. Small parks, such as community parks, demonstrated higher carbon-saving efficiency (CSE), while large ecological parks showed greater carbon-saving intensity (CSI). CSE was strongly correlated with vegetation coverage and surrounding population density, with efficiency increasing when the vegetation index was within 0.3&#8211;0.7 and population density ranged 0&#8211;5000 or 15,000&#8211;22,500 people. CSI was influenced by evapotranspiration and park geometric form, increasing significantly when the park area exceeded 250 hectares or evapotranspiration ranged 2.5&#8211;6.0. However, elevation and albedo negatively impacted both metrics, with the lowest CSI observed when elevation exceeded 150 m or albedo surpassed 18%.</description>
      <author>Lemin Yu, Wenjun Li, C. Zheng, Xiaowen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos16010079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phytotoxic Effects of Polystyrene Microplastics on Growth Morphology, Photosynthesis, Gaseous Exchange and Oxidative Stress of Wheat Vary with Concentration and Shape</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics13010057</link>
      <description>Komal Riaz, Tahira Yasmeen, Kotb A. Attia, Itoh Kimiko, Muhammad Arif, Toxics. 13(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406382893

                Microplastics pose a serious ecological threat to agricultural soils, as they are very persistent in nature. Microplastics can enter the soil system in different ways and present different shapes and concentrations. However, little is known about how plants react to microplastics with different concentrations and shapes. To this end, we conducted a factorial pot experiment with wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) in which we mixed polystyrene (PS) in different shapes (bead, fiber and powder) with soil at concentrations of 0, 1, 3 and 5%. Although all shapes of PS significantly reduced morphological growth traits, PS in powder shape was the microplastic that reduced plant height (by 58&#8211;60%), fresh biomass (by 54&#8211;55%) and dry biomass (by 61&#8211;62%) the most, especially at the 3% and 5% concentrations compared with 0% PS. Similar negative effects were also observed for root length and fresh root weight at the 3% and 5% concentrations, regardless of shape. A concentration-dependent reduction in the leaf area index (LAI) was also observed. Interestingly, increasing the PS concentration tended to up-regulate the activity of antioxidant enzymes for all shapes, indicating potential complexity and a highly time-dependent response related to various reactive oxygen species (ROS). Importantly, PS at the 5% concentration caused a significant reduction in chlorophyll pigmentation and photosynthetic rate. For the transpiration rate, stomatal conductance and intercellular CO2 concentration, the negative effects of PS on wheat plants increased with the increase in microplastic concentration for all shapes of PS. Overall, we concluded that PS microplastics at higher concentrations are potentially more devastating to the physiological growth and biochemical attributes of wheat, as evidenced by the negative effects on photosynthetic pigments and gas exchange parameters for all shapes. We recommend further research experiments not only on translocation but also on tissue-specific retention of different sizes in crops to fully understand their impact on food safety.</description>
      <author>Komal Riaz, Tahira Yasmeen, Kotb A. Attia, Itoh Kimiko, Muhammad Arif</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics13010057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evidence of the Functioning of the &#171;Green&#187; Economy (Case of the USA, Sweden, Costa Rica and Ukraine)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32983/2222-4459-2024-11-36-45</link>
      <description>Olena &#1040;. Shuba, Iryna L. Didorchuk, Serhii D. Velihodskyi, Business Inform. 11(562)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406292836

                The purpose of the article is to analyze the experience of the functioning of the green economy in individual countries of the world. On the example of the USA, Sweden, Costa Rica and Ukraine, the existing global trends in the field of green economy were considered. In the United States, during the study period (1990&#8211;2022), the share of renewable sources increased from 11.8% to 21.5%. In Sweden, more than 50% of energy is produced from renewable energy sources, and the country&#8217;s government aims to completely abandon nuclear energy by 2040 and switch to 100% renewable energy generation. The largest share of energy production in Costa Rica comes from low-carbon energy sources. A significant problem in the field of the green economy of Costa Rica can be defined as the situation with plastic waste. From 1991 to 2022, Ukraine managed to reduce CO2 emissions by almost 80%; the production of energy from renewable sources increased (in 2021, 14% of production). The efficiency of waste processing was at a low level even before the war: as of 2021, only 7% of all waste was recycled. The war disrupted Ukraine&#8217;s existing plans to develop a green economy; the energy infrastructure, including the green components, was damaged. However, Ukraine has prospects for the development of a green economy, given that the recovery and reconstruction of the country will take place with the choice of environmental alternatives. In addition, potential accession to the European Union will require compliance with the current EU regulations in the field of emission reduction and improvement of recycling systems. The prospects for the development of the green economy in the world depend on the action of interrelated factors, including: the development of the energy sector, since renewable energy sources are one of the main priorities for most countries; the emergence of new technologies and the constant improvement of existing ones for the purpose of sorting and processing of secondary raw materials; the incentive policy on the part of the State, which includes legislation, regulations, directives, standards related to various aspects of the development of the green economy. Thus, it can be noted that the world has formed a trend of purposeful policy to support the development of the green economy.</description>
      <author>Olena &#1040;. Shuba, Iryna L. Didorchuk, Serhii D. Velihodskyi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32983/2222-4459-2024-11-36-45</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering quality education through sustainable and equitable electricity access in African schools</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.12.005</link>
      <description>Magda Moner&#8208;Girona, Fernando Fahl, Georgia Kakoulaki, Dohyung Kim, Iyke Maduako, S. Szab&#243;, Godwell Nhamo, Benjamin K. Sovacool, Daniel J. Weiss, Joule. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406270132

                Context &amp; scaleAlthough most people born this century will be educated in African schools, these schools often lack basic infrastructure, such as electricity and/or lighting. In the face of a rapidly growing school-age population in Africa, the electrification of educational facilities is not just an infrastructural challenge but also a pivotal investment in the continent's future workforce. This study reveals a stark reality: a third of Africa's school-aged children are nearer to schools without electricity, impacting educational quality and access. By mapping over half a million schools across the continent, this research underscores the transformative potential of decentralized solar photovoltaic (PV) systems. Not only could solar PV reduce travel times for millions of students, but it also promises the improvement of reliable services and a significant reduction in CO2 emissions. The strategic electrification of schools could catalyze a myriad of co-benefits, including enhancing educational outcomes, economic prosperity, and environmental sustainability. All this contributes to the achievement of multiple Sustainable Development Goals across the continent.Highlights&#8226;Comprehensive data of over half a million geolocated schools in Africa provided&#8226;PV systems offer clean, reliable, and cost-effective electricity access in schools&#8226;2 billion EUR investment needed to bring electricity to schools&#8226;Electricity can provide e-cooking, and internet services, and reduce travel time by 45 minSummaryAfrica's schools will educate the majority of the 21st century's working population, influencing the global economy. Through combined spatial analysis techniques on over 500,000 schools, we estimate a 2 billion EUR cost to power unelectrified schools with decentralized solar photovoltaic systems. Given the positive effect on children's food security and the growing need for digitalization, ensuring clean electricity access includes both electricity demand for internet connectivity and electric cooking. Our analysis reveals that 32% of African school-aged children live near unelectrified schools, with the nearest electrified school often too far away. The electrification of these facilities would reduce education-seeking trips by an average 45 min by motorized transport or 6 h on foot. This significant time savings, combined with the broader benefits of decentralized energy, can significantly enhance educational access, economic development, and environmental sustainability in Africa.Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Magda Moner&#8208;Girona, Fernando Fahl, Georgia Kakoulaki, Dohyung Kim, Iyke Maduako, S. Szab&#243;, Godwell Nhamo, Benjamin K. Sovacool, Daniel J. Weiss</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.12.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the 10th Year of &lt;i&gt;ACS Energy Letters&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409</link>
      <description>Prashant V. Kamat, ACS Energy Letters. 10(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406248189

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. ACS Energy LettersVol 10/Issue 1Article This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse EditorialJanuary 10, 2025Celebrating the 10th Year of ACS Energy LettersClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Prashant V. Kamat*Prashant V. KamatUniversity of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, Indiana 46556, United States*[email protected]More by Prashant V. Kamathttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-2465-6819Open PDFACS Energy LettersCite this: ACS Energy Lett. 2025, 10, 1, 569&#8211;570Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409Published January 10, 2025 Publication History Received 10 December 2024Accepted 10 December 2024Published online 10 January 2025Published in issue 10 January 2025editorialCopyright &#169; 2025 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS PublicationsCopyright &#169; 2025 American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.BatteriesChemical engineering and industrial chemistryEnergy storageSolar cellsSolar energyIt is with delight that we embark on the tenth year of ACS Energy Letters. Since the launch of the journal in 2016, we have built an enthusiastic energy community of authors, reviewers and readers. Their continued support has helped us to build a top-tier journal to disseminate new advances in energy research and discuss important scientific issues from the laboratory to the real world.We are pleased to engage with the passionate members of the scientific community who have made impressive progress in recent years to address clean energy challenges. The desire to reduce the carbon footprint has led to many innovative strategies to adopt renewable energy technologies. For example, perovskite solar cells, which showed an increase in efficiency from 14.1% in 2013 to 26.7% in 2024, are now being targeted for large-scale panel production. Si-perovskite-based tandem solar cells have made significant strides, reaching a record efficiency of 34.6%. Similarly, storage batteries have emerged from table-top devices to grid storage, and electrocatalysis is driving CO2 reduction on a pilot plant scale. The next phase of energy research is likely to be dominated with topics such as device stability of solar cells, display devices and electrolyzers, for long-term operation, fast charging of storage batteries, and recycling strategies for solar cells and storage batteries. Fundamental studies exploring properties of new materials for energy conversion and storage, and a better understanding of interfacial charge transfer processes in various devices (e.g., solar cells, storage batteries and LEDs), will also see a major growth in research.The growth of ACS Energy Letters during its first ten years can be seen from the increase in number of published articles as well as their growing impact (Figure 1). In addition to Letters, Perspectives and Reviews, we regularly publish Viewpoints and Energy Focus articles. These features offer our authors a unique opportunity to engage in scientific discussions. We also regularly feature Collections that compile key papers on an emerging topic. Each year, we also highlight contributions of women scientists along with their inspiring thoughts. Having anchored with these popular features during this early period, we plan to grow in the coming years by attracting new authors and readers.Figure 1Figure 1. Growth of ACS Energy Letters as seen from the published articles (all types) and citations. (* indicates incomplete data of 2024). Source: Web of Science, Clarivate Analytics, December 10, 2024.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideThe success of the journal stems from our Editorial Advisory Board members, who regularly provide feedback to our editorial team. Special thanks to EAB members Leif Hammarstr&#246;m, Uppsala University, Sweden, Dongling Ma, Institut National de la Recherche Scientifique, Canada, Bryan D. McCloskey, University of California Berkeley, USA, Iv&#225;n Mora Ser&#243;, Universitat Jaume I, Spain, Edward (Ted) Sargent, Northwestern University, USA, and Yi-Jun Xu, Fuzhou University, China, who have completed their terms. We welcome new EAB members, Juan-Pablo Correa-Baena, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, USA, Satish A. Patil, Solid State and Structural Chemistry Unit, Indian Institute of Science, India, Lorenzo Malavasi, Chemistry Department, University of Pavia, Italy, Ji-Hyun Jang, School of Energy and Chemical Engineering, UNIST, Republic of Korea, Partha P. Mukherjee, School of Mechanical Engineering, Purdue University, USA, Lakshminarayana Polavarapu, Department of Physical Chemistry, University of Vigo, Spain, Venkataraman Thangadurai, School of Chemistry, University of St Andrews, United Kingdom, and Ranjani Viswanatha, International Centre for Materials Science and New Chemistry Unit, Jawaharlal Nehru Centre for Advanced Scientific Research, India. By having a good mix of senior and younger scientists from around the globe on our EAB board, we are able to seek a wide range of views on the journal's progress.I also take the opportunity to thank Rapha&#235;le Cl&#233;ment, University of California Santa Barbara, USA, who has completed her term as a Topic Editor. Her expertise in storage batteries helped us to publish several outstanding papers. Dinesh Kabra, Physics Department, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, India, and Ya You, International School of Materials Science and Engineering and School of Materials Science and Microelectronics, Wuhan University of Technology, China, will now join our editorial team as Topic Editors. Filippo De Angelis, University of Perugia, Italy, and Yang-Kook Sun, Hanyang University, Republic of Korea, will now serve as Executive Editors. They will take additional responsibilities to manage the editorial manuscript flow and engage in improving the invited content of the journal. Together our editorial team will continue to work with our authors and reviewers to maintain high-quality topical content in the journal.As part of our 10th year celebration, we will publish several exciting features throughout the year. Two such Energy Focus features published in this issue include, (i) Women Scientists at the Forefront of Energy Research: Part 7 and (ii) A Conversation with Ib Chorkendorff.On behalf of our entire editorial team, I would like to wish everyone a happy new year!Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorPrashant V. Kamat, Editor-in-Chief, ACS Energy Letters, University of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, Indiana 46556, United States, https://orcid.org/0000-0002-2465-6819, Email: [email protected]NotesViews expressed in this editorial are those of the author and not necessarily the views of the ACS.Cited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferences Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsACS Energy LettersCite this: ACS Energy Lett. 2025, 10, 1, 569&#8211;570Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409Published January 10, 2025 Publication History Received 10 December 2024Accepted 10 December 2024Published online 10 January 2025Published in issue 10 January 2025Copyright &#169; 2025 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesFigure 1Figure 1. Growth of ACS Energy Letters as seen from the published articles (all types) and citations. (* indicates incomplete data of 2024). Source: Web of Science, Clarivate Analytics, December 10, 2024.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideThis publication has no References.</description>
      <author>Prashant V. Kamat</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of micro-scale characteristics of shale reservoirs on gasdepletion behavior: A microscale discrete model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2025.02.06</link>
      <description>Wangxing Cheng, Y. Jay Guo, Guanglei Cui, Derek Elsworth, Yuling Tan, Zhejun Pan, ADVANCES IN GEO-ENERGY RESEARCH. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406336208

                Shale gas has become increasingly significant in the global energy supply. Mineral heterogeneity in shales importantly impacts gas transport within the shale matrix and therefore the depletion history curve. A microscale discrete coupling model is introduced to clarify mass transfer and mechanical interactions, as well as their impact on gas transport properties, ranging from individual mineral through ensemble field scale. The model uses a mineral morphology thin-section obtained through tescan integrated mineral analyzer with the mechanical parameters, controlling both elastic and viscosity behavior of each mineral, achieved through nanoindentation. A coupled model for poromechanical evolution is proposed and solved using COMSOL. The applicability of the model results are validated against field data using a dimensionless approach. This confirms that in the early stages of gas depletion, gas is primarily liberated from inorganic minerals, whereas in later stages, it is predominantly sourced from adsorbed gas from the organic matter. Over time, the permeability of the inorganic minerals decreases, and a higher Young's modulus of the minerals results in a greater ultimate permeability ratio. Evolution of the effective diffusion coefficient for the organic matter is controlled by multiple components. A negative correlation exists between mineral grain size and the creep effects, indicating that larger grain sizes result in smaller creep magnitudes during gas production. The Young's modulus of inorganic matter is inversely correlated with the diffusion coefficient, while an increase in the Young's modulus in the organic matter corresponds to a higher diffusion coefficient. The proposed model complements the traditional continuum dual-medium method and provides a clearer understanding of the interactions between minerals during gas depletion behavior. Document Type: Original article Cited as: Cheng, W., Guo, Y., Cui, G., Elsworth, D., Tan, Y., Pan, Z. Impact of micro-scale characteristics of shale reservoirs on gas depletion behavior: A microscale discrete model. Advances in Geo-Energy Research, 2025, 15(2): 143-157. https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2025.02.06 References Abdallah, Y., Vandamme, M., Chateau, C., et al. Linking elastic properties of various carbonate rocks to their microstructure by coupling nanoindentation and SEM-EDS. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2023, 170: 105456. Abedi, S., Slim, M., Ulm, F.-J. Nanomechanics of organic-rich shales: The role of thermal maturity and organic matter content on texture. Acta Geotechnica, 2016, 11(4): 775-787. Aguilera, R. Incorporating capillary pressure, pore throat aperture radii, height above free-water table, and Winland r35 values on Pickett plots. AAPG Bulletin, 2002, 86(4): 605-624. Al Ismail, M. I., Zoback, M. D. Effects of rock mineralogy and pore structure on stress-dependent permeability of shale samples. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society A, 2016, 374(2078): 20150428. Ambrose, R. J., Hartman, R. C., Diaz-Campos, M., et al. New pore-scale considerations for shale gas in place calculations. Paper SPE 131772 Presented at the SPE Unconventional Gas Conference, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA, 23-25, February, 2010. Chalmers, G. R., Ross, D. J., Bustin, R. M. Geological controls on matrix permeability of Devonian Gas Shales in the Horn River and Liard basins, northeastern British Columbia, Canada. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2012, 103: 120-131. Chen, D., Pan, Z., Ye, Z. Dependence of gas shale fracture permeability on effective stress and reservoir pressure: Model match and insights. Fuel, 2015a, 139: 383-392. Chen, F., Duan, Y., Wang, K., et al. A novel pressure transient response model considering multiple migration mechanisms in shale gas reservoir. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2015b, 22: 321-334. Chen, T., Feng, X.-T., Cui, G., et al. Experimental study of permeability change of organic-rich gas shales under high effective stress. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2019, 64: 1-14. Coq Germanicus, R., Mercier, D., Agrebi, F., et al. Quantitative mapping of high modulus materials at the nanoscale: Comparative study between atomic force microscopy and nanoindentation. Journal of Microscopy, 2020, 280(1): 51-62. Cui, G., Liu, J., Wei, M., et al. Evolution of permeability during the process of shale gas extraction. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2018a, 49: 94-109. Cui, G., Liu, J., Wei, M., et al. Why shale permeability changes under variable effective stresses: New insights. Fuel, 2018b, 213: 55-71. Cui, G., Tan, Y., Chen, T., et al. Multidomain two-phase f low model to study the impacts of hydraulic fracturing on shale gas production. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2020a, 34(4): 4273-4288. Cui, G., Feng, X., Pan, Z., et al. Impact of shale matrix mechanical interactions on gas transport during production. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering, 2020b, 184: 106524. Day-Stirrat, R. J., Dutton, S. P., Milliken, K. L., et al. Fabric anisotropy induced by primary depositional variations in the silt: Clay ratio in two fine-grained slope fan complexes: Texas Gulf Coast and northern North Sea. Sedimentary Geology, 2010, 226(1-4): 42-53. Eliyahu, M., Emmanuel, S., Day-Stirrat, R. J., et al. Mechanical properties of organic matter in shales mapped at the nanometer scale. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 2015, 59: 294-304. Feng, X., Yang, C., He, B., et al. Artificial intelligence technology in rock mechanics and rock engineering. Deep Resources Engineering, 2024, 1(2): 100008. Gao, Z., Fan, Y., Xuan, Q., et al. A review of shale pore structure evolution characteristics with increasing thermal maturities. Advances in Geo-Energy Research, 2020, 4(3): 247-259. Geng, L., Li, G., Zitha, P., et al. A diffusion-viscous flow model for simulating shale gas transport in nano-pores. Fuel, 2016, 181: 887-894. Javadpour, F. Nanopores and apparent permeability of gas flow in mudrocks (shales and siltstone). Journal of Canadian Petroleum Technology, 2009, 48(8): 16-21. Jin, Z., Li, W., Jin, C., et al. Anisotropic elastic, strength, and fracture properties of Marcellus shale. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2018, 109: 124-137. Li, S., Dong, M., Li, Z. Measurement and revised interpretation of gas flow behavior in tight reservoir cores. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering, 2009, 65(1-2): 81-88. Li, W., Wang, X., Cheng, J. Measurement of the anisotropic elastic properties of shale: uncertainty analysis and water effect. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 2019, 78: 6075-6087. Liu, J., Chen, Z., Elsworth, D., et al. Evaluation of stress-controlled coal swelling processes. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2010a, 83(4): 446-455. Liu, J., Chen, Z., Elsworth, D., et al. Linking gas-sorption induced changes in coal permeability to directional strains through a modulus reduction ratio. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2010b, 83(1): 21-30. Liu, X., Chen, L., Sheng, J., et al. A Non-Equilibrium multiphysics model for coal seam gas extraction. Fuel, 2023a, 331: 125942. Liu, Y., Burch, A. C., Bennett, K. C., et al. Bridging nanoindentation and triaxial creep tests on a shale. Acta Geotechnica, 2023b, 18(12): 6475-6487. Loucks, R. G., Reed, R. M., Ruppel, S. C., et al. Morphology, genesis, and distribution of nanometer-scale pores in siliceous mudstones of the mississippian barnett shale. Journal of Sedimentary Research, 2009, 79(12): 848-861. Monteiro, P. J., Rycroft, C. H., Barenblatt, G. I. A mathematical model of fluid and gas flow in nanoporous media. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of USA, 2012, 109(50): 20309-20313. Oliver, W. C., Pharr G. M. An improved technique for determining hardness and elastic modulus using load and displacement sensing indentation experiments. Journal of Materials Research, 1992, 7(6): 1564-1583. Palmer, I., Mansoori, J. How permeability depends on stress and pore pressure in coalbeds: A new model. SPE Reservoir Evaluation &amp; Engineering, 1998, 1(6): 539-544. Peng, Y., Liu, J., Pan, Z., et al. A sequential model of shale gas transport under the influence of fully coupled multiple processes. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2015, 27: 808-821. Qu, H., Pan, Z., Peng, Y., et al. Controls on matrix permeability of shale samples from Longmaxi and Niutitang formations, China. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2016, 33: 599-610. Schwartz, B., Elsworth, D., Marone, C. Relationships between mechanical and transport properties in Marcellus shale. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2019a, 119: 205-210. Schwartz, B., Huffman, K., Thornton, D., et al. The effects of mineral distribution, pore geometry, and pore density on permeability evolution in gas shales. Fuel, 2019b, 257: 116005. Shi, R., Liu, J., Wang, X., et al. A critical analysis of shale laboratory permeability evolution data. Energy, 2021, 236: 121405. Tahmasebi, P., Javadpour, F., Enayati, S. F. Digital rock techniques to study shale permeability: A mini-review. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2020, 34(12): 15672-15685. Tian, H., Pan, L., Xiao, X., et al. A preliminary study on the pore characterization of Lower Silurian black shales in the Chuandong Thrust Fold Belt, southwestern China using low pressure N2 adsorption and FE-SEM methods. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 2013, 48: 8-19. Wang, L., Liu, B., Bai, L., et al. Pore evolution modeling in natural lacustrine shale influenced by mineral composition: Implications for shale oil exploration and CO2 storage. Advances in Geo-Energy Research, 2024a, 13(3): 218-230. Wang, S., Wu, Z., Chen, J., et al. Study of the effect of mineral components on the permeability impairment rate and stress sensitivity factor of shale. Geofluids, 2022, 2022(1): 4407252. Wang, W., Chen, T., Cui, G., et al. New approach for predicting time-dependent deformation of shale rock: a modified fractional-order creep constitutive model. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 2024b, 83(6): 1-21. Wang, Y., Dong, D., Yang, H., et al. Quantitative characterization of reservoir space in the Lower Silurian Longmaxi Shale, southern Sichuan, China. Science China Earth Sciences, 2013, 57: 313-322. Xie, J., Xiong, W., Tan, Y., et al. Effects of Anisotropic Permeability Evolution on Shale Gas Production: An Internal Swelling Factor Model. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2022, 36(2): 771-785. Yang, C., Xiong, Y., Wang, J., et al. Mechanical characterization of shale matrix minerals using phase-positioned nanoindentation and nano-dynamic mechanical analysis. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2020, 229: 103571. Yang, F., Ning, Z., Liu, H. Fractal characteristics of shales from a shale gas reservoir in the Sichuan Basin, China. Fuel, 2014, 115: 378-384. Yang, F., Xu, S., Hao, F., et al. Petrophysical characteristics of shales with different lithofacies in Jiaoshiba area, Sichuan Basin, China: Implications for shale gas accumulation mechanism. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 2019, 109: 394-407. Yang, R., Liu, X., Yu, R., et al. Long short-term memory suggests a model for predicting shale gas production. Applied Energy, 2022, 322: 119415. Yuan, Y., Rezaee, R., Verrall, M., et al. Pore characterization and clay bound water assessment in shale with a combination of NMR and low-pressure nitrogen gas adsorption. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2018, 194: 11-21. Zhang, H., Liu, J., Elsworth, D. How sorption-induced matrix deformation affects gas flow in coal seams: A new FE model. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2008, 45(8): 1226-1236. Zhang, L., Li, D., Li, L., et al. Development of a new compositional model with multi-component sorption isotherm and slip flow in tight gas reservoirs. Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering, 2014, 21: 1061-1072. Zhang, T., Li, X., Shi, J., et al. An apparent liquid permeability model of dual-wettability nanoporous media: A case study of shale. Chemical Engineering Science, 2018, 187: 280-291. Zhang, W., Zhang, D., Zhao, J. Experimental investigation of water sensitivity effects on microscale mechanical behavior of shale. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 2021, 145: 104837. Zhao, P., Cai, J., Huang, Z., et al. Estimating permeability of shale-gas reservoirs from porosity and rock compositions. Geophysics, 2018, 83(5): MR283-MR294. Zhu, X., Cai, J., Wang, G., et al. Role of organo-clay composites in hydrocarbon generation of shale. International Journal of Coal Geology, 2018, 192: 83-90. DOI: https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2025.02.06</description>
      <author>Wangxing Cheng, Y. Jay Guo, Guanglei Cui, Derek Elsworth, Yuling Tan, Zhejun Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46690/ager.2025.02.06</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
