<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:50:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium carbide sealed cadmium sulfide quantum dots on carbon, oxygen-doped boron nitride for enhanced and durable photochemical carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.139</link>
      <description>Zhangfeng Shen, Yang Yang, LI Yu-ji, Xiaohua Cheng, Huayang Zhang, Xuhui Zou, Ming Qiu, Hong Huang, Hongge Pan, Qineng Xia, Ge Zhang, Yongyong Cao, Jing Gao, Yangang Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393131989

                Despite great efforts that have been made, photocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction still faces enormous challenges due to the sluggish kinetics or disadvantageous thermodynamics. Herein, cadmium sulfide quantum dots (CdS QDs) were loaded onto carbon, oxygen-doped boron nitride (BN) and encapsulated by titanium carbide (Ti3C2, MXene) layers to construct a ternary composite. The uniform distribution of CdS QDs and the tight interfacial interaction among the three components could be achieved by adjusting the loading amounts of CdS QDs and MXene. The ternary 100MX/CQ/BN sample gave a productive rate of 2.45 and 0.44 &#956;mol g-1 h&#8722;1 for carbon monoxide (CO) and methane (CH4), respectively. This CO yield is 1.93 and 6.13 times higher than that of CdS QDs/BN and BN counterparts. The photocatalytic durability of the ternary composite is significantly improved compared with CdS QDs/BN because MXene can protect CdS from photocorrosion. The characterization results demonstrate that the excellent CO2 adsorption and activation capabilities of BN, the visible light absorption of CdS QDs, the good conductivity of MXene and the well-matched energy band alignment jointly promote the photocatalytic performance of the ternary catalyst.</description>
      <author>Zhangfeng Shen, Yang Yang, LI Yu-ji, Xiaohua Cheng, Huayang Zhang, Xuhui Zou, Ming Qiu, Hong Huang, Hongge Pan, Qineng Xia, Ge Zhang, Yongyong Cao, Jing Gao, Yangang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction via DNA-Directed Catalyst Immobilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.3c00823</link>
      <description>Gang Fan, Nathan Corbin, Minju Chung, Thomas M. Gill, Evan G. Moore, Amruta A. Karbelkar, Ariel L. Furst, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393150984

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gang Fan, Nathan Corbin, Minju Chung, Thomas M. Gill, Evan G. Moore, Amruta A. Karbelkar, Ariel L. Furst</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.3c00823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineered &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; Whole Cell-Mediated Electro-Biocatalysis for Carbon Dioxide to Formic Acid Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08129</link>
      <description>Hongbo Shi, Meng-Xi Fu, Shu Yuan, Yao Lu, Yang Zhuan, Chao Ye, Lunguang Yao, Chuang Xue, Cun-Duo Tang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393164149

                The conversion of CO2 into a valuable chemical fuel could help reduce its effect on global warming. However, the utilization of CO2 by biological transformations is challenging because of the lack of enzymes exhibiting high catalytic activity toward CO2 reduction. In this work, three NAD+/W-containing formate dehydrogenases (FDHs) were discovered, expressed, and characterized. In addition, we used PbFDH, which displays high catalytic activity toward CO2 reduction, as a biocatalyst to convert CO2 to formic acid through whole-cell biocatalysis and electro-biocatalysis. The specific activities of DaFDH, PbFDH, and CsFDH increased by 68.1, 100.0, and 18.7 times, respectively, compared with that of ClFDH reported with high catalytic efficiency. Furthermore, this paper presents a preliminary discussion of the catalytic mechanism of FDHs for CO2 reduction based on their structures. The yield of formic acid obtained from CO2 reduction using electro-biocatalysis under aerobic conditions reaches up to 4.1 mmol/L/h, without any cofactor NADH and hydrogen gas. This study also demonstrates and compares the performances of NAD+/W-containing and NAD+-dependent FDHs in whole-cell biocatalysis and electro-biocatalysis. The findings of this study provide a meaningful foundation for the conversion of CO2 into a value-added chemical fuel.</description>
      <author>Hongbo Shi, Meng-Xi Fu, Shu Yuan, Yao Lu, Yang Zhuan, Chao Ye, Lunguang Yao, Chuang Xue, Cun-Duo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas Diffusion Electrodes (GDEs) for Carbon Dioxide (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) Reduction in Microfluidic Cells: Towards a Fluid Dynamics Assisted Rational Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad377f</link>
      <description>Melanie Colet-Lagrille, Sergio Gonz&#225;lez-Poggini, Carol Salazar-Espinoza, Benito S&#225;nchez, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393164782

                Abstract The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) for the generation of multicarbon (C2+) products with high commercial value &#8211; e.g., ethanol and ethylene &#8211; is gaining growing interest due to the successful implementation of laboratory scale technologies that can reach high current densities (&gt;500 mA cm-2) and Faradaic efficiencies (&gt;60%), using a simplified approach in terms of configuration and cost. This is the case of microfluidic cells, low-temperature electrochemical flow systems which optimal operation sustains on the enhancement of the mass and charge transfer phenomena taking place at the gas diffusion electrode (GDE) | aqueous electrolyte interface where CO2 molecules are selectively transformed at the surface of the catalyst layer. &amp;#xD;This work presents an up-to-date overview of materials and operational conditions for microfluidic-type systems, providing significant enlightenment on the effects that the phenomena occurring at the GDE | electrolyte interface have over the CO2 reduction reaction kinetics towards the generation of C2+ products. It is shown that the integration of computational methods (particularly, density functional theory and computational fluid dynamics) to conventional experimental approaches is an effective strategy to elucidate the reactions mechanisms and mass/charge transfer trends determining the enhanced design of GDEs and the GDE | electrolyte interface.</description>
      <author>Melanie Colet-Lagrille, Sergio Gonz&#225;lez-Poggini, Carol Salazar-Espinoza, Benito S&#225;nchez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad377f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical Catalytic Co2 Reduction Enhanced by In-Doped Gan and Combined with Vibration Energy Harvester Driving Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4772115</link>
      <description>Mingxiang Zhang, Li Wen, Shanghao Gu, Weihan Xu, Zhouguang Lu, Fei Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393143337

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingxiang Zhang, Li Wen, Shanghao Gu, Weihan Xu, Zhouguang Lu, Fei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4772115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-dopant and O-vacancy of mesoporous ZnO nanosheets induce high efficiency and selectivity of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coco.2024.101890</link>
      <description>Ying Wang, Youngeun Kang, Yuanxin Miao, Min Jia, S. Alice Long, Lipeng Diao, Lijie Zhang, Daohao Li, Guanglei Wu, Composites Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393166182

                Surface engineering can adjust the electronic properties of catalysts, thereby boosting their electrocatalytic performances. Herein, S-doped and O-vacant mesoporous ZnO nanosheets (ZnO-VO-S) were synthesized through the plasma-treatment method, exhibiting highly electrocatalytic selectivity and activity in the conversion of CO2 to CO. Synchrotron X-ray absorption fine structure (XAFS) investigations were used to further clarify the valence state and local coordination structure of Zn, concretely affirming the reduced electron density of Zn in ZnO-VO-S. Specifically, at &#8722;1.1 V vs. RHE, the as-prepared ZnO-VO-S demonstrated a high Faradaic efficiency of 90%. Experiments and density functional theory (DFT) suggest that the electron deficiency of Zn caused by the introduction of S dopant and O vacancy, reduces the energy barrier of CO2 to CO by improving the adsorption behavior of the intermediate *COOH.</description>
      <author>Ying Wang, Youngeun Kang, Yuanxin Miao, Min Jia, S. Alice Long, Lipeng Diao, Lijie Zhang, Daohao Li, Guanglei Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coco.2024.101890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The carbon emission reduction effect of renewable resource utilization: From the perspective of green innovation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apr.2024.102121</link>
      <description>Jin-Long Xiao, Siying Chen, Jingwei Han, Zhongfu Tan, Shengjing Mu, Jiayi Wang, Atmospheric Pollution Research. 15(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393135358

                In the face of pressing global challenges posed by climate change, resource constraints, and environmental pollution, understanding the role of renewable resource utilization in carbon emission reduction has become paramount. This study aims to investigate this relationship, particularly within the context of the dual carbon goals, which emphasizes both carbon peak and carbon neutrality. Focusing on the national "urban mineral" demonstration bases as a case study, this research employs the directional distance function incorporating non-expected output alongside the Malmquist index to assess the dynamic changes in urban carbon dioxide emission performance. A multi-period difference-in-difference model is utilized to examine the impact of these demonstration bases on CO2 emissions. The Baseline results reveal that renewable resource utilization significantly enhances carbon emission performance. The channel analysis indicate that the establishment of national "urban mineral" demonstration bases positively influences carbon emission performance through three primary pathways: green technology agglomeration, green technology spillover, and energy structure optimization. Based on these findings, this study advocates for policies that promote renewable resource utilization and carbon emission reduction. Specifically, it highlights the need for increased investment in green technology innovation and diffusion, as well as the optimization of energy structures to mitigate carbon emissions. These findings provide valuable policy implications for governments and stakeholders seeking to reduce carbon emissions and promote sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Jin-Long Xiao, Siying Chen, Jingwei Han, Zhongfu Tan, Shengjing Mu, Jiayi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apr.2024.102121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Influence of Supercritical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with High Temperature and Pressure on Pore-Throat Structure and Minerals of Shale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c09698</link>
      <description>Xiangzeng Wang, Xin Sun, Xing Min Guo, Liange Zheng, Ping Luo, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393156566

                Injection of carbon dioxide offers substantial social and economic advantages for reduction of carbon emission reduction. Utilizing CO2 in shale formations can significantly enhance the extraction of shale oil or gas. Conducting fundamental research on how CO2 affects shale rock's physical properties is crucial for enhancing its porosity and permeability. Particularly for deep shale layers, the effects of supercritical CO2 on shale physical properties should be investigated at a high temperature and pressure, differing from the standard conditions applied in shallower layers. A study examined the impact of supercritical CO2 under such conditions on the pore-throat structure and mineral composition of the shale. The experimental parameters included immersing shale rock in supercritical CO2 at pressures ranging from 10 to 70 MPa and temperatures between 55 and 95 &#176;C. This study evaluated changes in mineral composition, pore-throat structure (using scanning electron microscopy and nitrogen adsorption tests), and the porosity and permeability of the shale rocks. Findings indicated that the dissolution of CO2 altered the relative content of certain minerals. The average quartz content rose and, potassium feldspar and the average contents of plagioclase declined conversely. When increasing the pressure, an increase in the relative content of I/S mixed layer and a decrease in illite content were observed and kaolinite content experienced minor changes. When increasing the temperature, kaolinite, I/S mixed layer, and chlorite all exhibited a decreasing trend with increasing temperature, while the relative contents of illite increased. Some of the pores become rounded in a high-magnification view under the impact of CO2 dissolution. Additionally, the Brunauer&#8211;Emmett&#8211;Teller specific surface area, pore volume, porosity, and permeability generally improved with increasing pressure and temperature. With the temperature and pressure of CO2 increased, the curves of nitrogen absorption had moved first upward and then downward. However, under specific CO2 conditions, the permeability enhancement effect could diminish or even negatively impact the shale's permeability. These findings underscore the need to optimize supercritical CO2 injection parameters under high-temperature and high-pressure conditions. This research aims to provide theoretical guidance for the efficient use of CO2 in deep shale applications to increase the shale gas output.</description>
      <author>Xiangzeng Wang, Xin Sun, Xing Min Guo, Liange Zheng, Ping Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c09698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel combined process for enhancing soluble salt recovery and reducing pollutant diffusion in municipal solid waste incineration fly ash</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141892</link>
      <description>Xin Huang, Lei Wang, Xiaotao Bi, Dahai Yan, Jonathan W C Wong, Yuezhao Zhu, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393131722

                There is a limited body of research on the recovery of soluble salts from fly ash from municipal solid wastes (MSWI-FA), with challenges stemming from the effective management of residual heavy metals and dioxins. In this investigation, we propose using water-washing treatment for fly ash dechlorination and using CO2 aeration carbonation combined with ceramic membrane filtration to recover soluble salt resources from fly ash. This study investigated the impact of combined processes on fly ash soluble salt recovery, carbon dioxide capture and sequestration, heavy metal removal, and dioxin diffusion reduction. The findings revealed that the combined process can significantly enhance the rate of carbonation and the removal of heavy metals. Specifically, the removal rates of Pb and Zn reach 100%. The resulting CaCO3 precipitation particle size is smaller, averaging only approximately 4 &#956;m, with greater surface porosity, higher heavy metal and dioxin content, and dioxin toxic equivalents as high as 8.11 ng TEQ/kg. Moreover, the dioxin content in the recovered mixed salt decreased, and its dioxin toxic equivalent was only 3.228.11 ng TEQ/kg. Consequently, the combined process of CO2 aeration combined with ceramic membrane filtration was used in conjunction to significantly reduce pollutants (heavy metals and dioxins) in the MSWI-FA recovered salt. This approach enhances the recyclable resource utilization of MSWI-FA and reduces the risk of pollution dispersal during MSWI-FA disposal and resource utilization.</description>
      <author>Xin Huang, Lei Wang, Xiaotao Bi, Dahai Yan, Jonathan W C Wong, Yuezhao Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Study of the Effect of Molecular Collision Frequency and Adsorption Capacity on Gas Seepage Flux in Coal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/219733-pa</link>
      <description>Gao Yang, Qingchun Yu, Spe Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393165922

                Summary The differences in the transport behavior and adsorption capacity of different gases in coal play crucial roles in the evolution of coal permeability. Previous studies of coreflooding experiments failed to explain the mechanism of gas flow and have attributed the variation in gas seepage flux (flow rate) at the beginning of the experiment to the change in effective stress, while the differences in the microscopic properties of different gases, such as molar mass, molecular diameter, mean molecular free path, and molecular collision frequency, were ignored. To research the effect of these gas properties on seepage flux while circumventing the effective stress, coreflooding experiments with helium (He), argon (Ar), nitrogen (N2), methane (CH4), and carbon dioxide (CO2) were designed. The results show that the gas transport velocity in coal is affected by the combination of molecular collision frequency and dynamic viscosity, and the transport velocities follow the order of &#957; (CH4) &amp;gt; &#957; (He) &amp;gt; &#957; (N2) &amp;gt; &#957; (CO2) &amp;gt; &#957; (Ar). A permeability equation corrected by the molecular collision frequency is proposed to eliminate differences in the permeabilities measured with different gases. The adsorption of different gases on the coal matrix causes different degrees of swelling, and the adsorption-induced swelling strains follow the order of &#949; (CO2) &amp;gt; &#949; (CH4) &amp;gt; &#949; (N2) &amp;gt; &#949; (Ar) &amp;gt; &#949; (He). The reduction in seepage flux and irreversible alterations in pore structure caused by adsorption-induced swelling are positively correlated with their adsorption capacities. The gas seepage fluxes after adsorption equilibrium of coal follow the order of Q (He) &amp;gt; Q (CH4) &amp;gt;Q (N2) &amp;gt; Q (Ar) &amp;gt; Q (CO2). Like supercritical CO2 (ScCO2), conventional CO2 can also dissolve the organic matter in coal. The organic molecules close to the walls of the cleats along the direction of gas flow are preferentially dissolved by CO2, and the gas seepage flux increases when the dissolution effect on the cleat width is greater than that on adsorption swelling.</description>
      <author>Gao Yang, Qingchun Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/219733-pa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Synthetic Fuel Co-firing of Heavy Fuel Oil for Marine User</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1299/jsmepes.2023.27.d226</link>
      <description>Ken-ichi Sakurai, Masaya Terada, Doryoku, Enerugi Gijutsu Shinpojiumu koen ronbunshu. 2023.27(0)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393134423

                Ships are required to improve their environmental performance, and fuel consumption regulations such as the EEXI regulations require the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions. These regulations require the same environmental performance from ships currently in service as from newbuildings, and conventional ships in service are reducing their maximum power output to reduce carbon dioxide emissions. Therefore, we investigated the effects of co-firing C fuel oil and synthetic fuel. Under the condition of 30[%] synthetic fuel blending, the engine speed was 265[rpm] at low speed, and the ignition time was 1[deg. In the presentation, combustion analysis will be presented along with exhaust gas characteristics.</description>
      <author>Ken-ichi Sakurai, Masaya Terada</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1299/jsmepes.2023.27.d226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/cen-10209-reactions</link>
      <description>, C&amp;EN Global Enterprise. 102(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393162112

                CLIMATE CHANGE Reactions ShareShare onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InRedditEmail C&amp;EN, 2024, 102 (9), p 3March 25, 2024Cite this:C&amp;EN 102, 9, 3Letters to the editorCarbon capture from fermentation processesTwo items in the Feb. 12/19, 2024, issue (the letter "Direct Air Capture," page 5, and the article "Researchers Caution about Reliance on CO2 Removal," page 17) discuss some economic and sustainability issues related to the reduction of atmospheric carbon dioxide, which is needed to achieve goals on mitigating global warming. Ultimately, multiple approaches will be required. One approach that I hear little about is the capture and reuse of CO2 generated as a by-product of fermentation processes, including the anaerobic digestion of food and sewage waste. The CO2 is derived from various forms of biomass and generated in enclosed spaces at higher concentrations than air, which should make capture more efficient. I believe that the CO2 produced is typically just vented into the air.Anaerobic digestion facilities are already separating the digestion-generated CO2 from the biogas before the methane is used to generate renewable electricity. More CO2 could be captured from the flue gas. The Quantum Biopower anaerobic digestion facility where I send my food waste processes about 36,000 metric tons (t) of material annually and has reported that it avoids roughly 4,500 t of CO2 emissions annually. I've read that anaerobic digestion of sewage sludge at Boston's regional sewage treatment facility on Deer Island produces about 5 million ft3 (about 142,000 m3) of biogas daily, which I calculate as resulting in over 10 times as much CO2 (from the biogas and burning of methane) as the total CO2 produced from the Quantum Biopower facility. Scaling such facilities widely and capturing and using the generated CO2 in the production of, for example, aviation and other transportation fuels could significantly contribute to reducing fossil CO2 emissions and eventually to reducing atmospheric CO2 levels.William C. HorneBranford, ConnecticutSafety in imagesI read with interest the article by Geoffrey Kamadi "C&amp;EN Talks with Stephen Cochrane, Antibiotics Researcher" (C&amp;EN, Feb. 12/19, 2024, page 26). It looks like Dr. Cochrane is in a lab without his personal protective equipment (PPE). I recommend that future publications respect lab safety protocols by either showing people in lab with their PPE or adding a qualifying statement that all chemicals, etc. have been removed&#8212;as is done in the current American Chemical Society RAMP (recognize hazards, assess risks, minimize risks, and prepare for emergencies) lab safety videos. C&amp;EN should set the correct example. We faculty have enough trouble getting students to comply with lab safety regulations. C&amp;EN's support is requested. Thank you!Ruth Ann Cook MurphyAustin, TexasDownload PDF</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/cen-10209-reactions</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamically Efficient, Low-Emission Gas-to-Wire for Carbon Dioxide-Rich Natural Gas: Exhaust Gas Recycle and Rankine Cycle Intensifications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040639</link>
      <description>Israel Bernardo S. Poblete, Jos&#233; Luiz de Medeiros, Of&#233;lia de Queiroz Fernandes Ara&#250;jo, Processes. 12(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393141920

                Onshore gas-to-wire is considered for 6.5 MMSm3/d of natural gas, with 44% mol carbon dioxide coming from offshore deep-water oil and gas fields. Base-case GTW-CONV is a conventional natural gas combined cycle, with a single-pressure Rankine cycle and 100% carbon dioxide emissions. The second variant, GTW-CCS, results from GTW-CONV with the addition of post-combustion aqueous monoethanolamine carbon capture, coupled to carbon dioxide dispatch to enhance oil recovery. Despite investment and power penalties, GTW-CCS generates both environmental and economic benefits due to carbon dioxide&#8217;s monetization for enhanced oil production. The third variant, GTW-CCS-EGR, adds two intensification layers over GTW-CCS, as follows: exhaust gas recycle and a triple-pressure Rankine cycle. Exhaust gas recycle is a beneficial intensification for carbon capture, bringing a 60% flue gas reduction (reduces column&#8217;s diameters) and a more than 100% increase in flue gas carbon dioxide content (increases driving force, reducing column&#8217;s height). GTW-CONV, GTW-CCS, and GTW-CCS-EGR were analyzed on techno-economic and environment&#8211;thermodynamic grounds. GTW-CCS-EGR&#8217;s thermodynamic analysis unveils 807 MW lost work (79.8%) in the combined cycle, followed by the post-combustion capture unit with 113 MW lost work (11.2%). GTW-CCS-EGR achieved a 35.34% thermodynamic efficiency, while GTW-CONV attained a 50.5% thermodynamic efficiency and 56% greater electricity exportation. Although carbon capture and storage imposes a 35.9% energy penalty, GTW-CCS-EGR reached a superior net value of 1816 MMUSD thanks to intensification and carbon dioxide monetization, avoiding 505.8 t/h of carbon emissions (emission factor 0.084 tCO2/MWh), while GTW-CONV entails 0.642 tCO2/MWh.</description>
      <author>Israel Bernardo S. Poblete, Jos&#233; Luiz de Medeiros, Of&#233;lia de Queiroz Fernandes Ara&#250;jo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040639</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Climate Change in the Thermosphere under Varying Solar Activity Conditions.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.171136724.40231179/v1</link>
      <description>Matthew K. Brown, Hugh G. Lewis, A. J. Kavanagh, Ingrid Cnossen, Sean Elvidge, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393156922

                Increasing carbon dioxide concentrations in the mesosphere and lower thermosphere are increasing radiative cooling in the upper atmosphere, leading to thermospheric contraction and decreased neutral mass densities at fixed altitudes. Previous studies of the historic neutral density trend have shown a dependence upon solar activity, with larger F10.7 values resulting in lower neutral density reductions. To investigate the impact on the future thermosphere, the Whole Atmosphere Community Climate Model with ionosphere and thermosphere extension (WACCM-X) has been used to simulate the thermosphere under increasing carbon dioxide concentrations and varying solar activity conditions. These neutral density reductions have then been mapped onto the Shared Socioeconomic Pathways (SSPs) published by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). The neutral density reductions can also be used as a scaling factor, allowing commonly used empirical models to account for CO$_2$ trends. Under the&#8220;best case&#8217; SSP1-2.6 scenario, neutral densities reductions at 400 km altitude peak (when CO$_2$ = 474 ppm) at a reduction of 13 to 30\% (under high and low solar activity respectively) compared to the year 2000. Higher CO$_2$ concentrations lead to greater density reductions, with the largest modelled concentration of 890 ppm resulting in a 50 to 77 \% reduction at 400 km, under high and low solar activity respectively.</description>
      <author>Matthew K. Brown, Hugh G. Lewis, A. J. Kavanagh, Ingrid Cnossen, Sean Elvidge</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.171136724.40231179/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of Water-Amine Combined Process for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Extraction from Biogas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2478/rtuect-2024-0012</link>
      <description>H.V. Zhuk, Yu.V. Ivanov, &#1051;.&#1056;. &#1054;&#1085;&#1086;&#1087;&#1072;, Serhii Krushnevych, Mekhrzad Soltanibereshne, Environmental and Climate Technologies. 28(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393143820

                Abstract The EU countries are implementing biomethane production projects from biogas, supplying it to the natural gas distribution grid, or using it as motor fuel. It is also extremely relevant for Ukraine, supposing the problems with gas import due to Russian aggression. Biogas production from landfills, agriculture waste, and sewage is already implemented in Ukraine, so the next step must be biomethane production on an industrial scale and the selection of biogas separation technology is important. Using 11 years of industrial experience in biogas production from landfills, wide experience of the different methane-containing gases separations, and small companies&#8217; industrial possibilities, the most applicable separation technologies for Ukraine were selected: amine, water, and combined water amine carbon dioxide separation. These technologies had compared using computer simulation with real landfill biogas flow rate debt. Results of a software simulation of the most applicable water-amine absorption technology were verified using a laboratory setup. For carbon dioxide concentration in biogas at 32&#8211;42 % vol., the specific energy consumption when using water absorption is on average 2 times less compared to amine absorption, but at the same time, the loss of methane due to its solubility in water during water absorption amounted to 7.1&#8211;7.6 %, with practically no losses in amine absorption, and minor losses at 0.17&#8211;2.8 % in combined water-amine technology. The energy consumption of combined water-amine absorption is comparable to that of water absorption due to: a) reduction of heat losses for the regeneration process of saturated amine absorbent, as part of carbon dioxide has already been removed with water technology; b) using the methane excess to compensate power consumption of the biogas compressor during the preliminary water absorption of carbon dioxide and/or to compensate heat costs of the saturated amine absorbent regeneration</description>
      <author>H.V. Zhuk, Yu.V. Ivanov, &#1051;.&#1056;. &#1054;&#1085;&#1086;&#1087;&#1072;, Serhii Krushnevych, Mekhrzad Soltanibereshne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2478/rtuect-2024-0012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Carbon Emissions during Slurry Shield Tunneling for Sustainable Management Utilizing a Hybrid Life-Cycle Assessment Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16072702</link>
      <description>Xiang Qian Shi, Lei Kou, Hao Liang, Yibo Wang, Wuxue Li, Sustainability. 16(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393142649

                The construction sector is one of the principal contributors to carbon dioxide emissions (CDEs) and has a vital role to play in responding to the issue of long-term environmental sustainability. This research proposes a process-based hybrid life-cycle assessment (LCA) method depending on a process-based LCA and an input&#8211;output LCA. The process-based hybrid LCA model provides a supplementary method to quickly estimate carbon emissions that are not considered in the system boundary due to the limitation of inventory data. The proposed hybrid method was applied to a carbon emissions assessment in a slurry shield tunnel. The results suggest that 93.88% of emissions are from materials. Of the materials contribution, 55.9% comes from steel and 34.55% arises from concrete. It has also been found that emissions during the tunneling stage are negatively correlated with the efficiency of tunnel construction. Recommendations for carbon emissions reductions in tunnel construction are provided for promoting sustainable transportation and management.</description>
      <author>Xiang Qian Shi, Lei Kou, Hao Liang, Yibo Wang, Wuxue Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16072702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Electrocatalyst Produced by Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Mediated In Situ Deposition for Diluted CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Multicarbon Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00279</link>
      <description>Qiankang Zhang, Zhanbo Si, Ying Zhang, Yilin Deng, Xiaojie She, Qing Yu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393157892

                Pure CO2 is commonly used in most of the current studies for electrochemical CO2 reduction which will need a further cost of gas purification and separation. However, the limited works on diluted CO2 reduction are focused on CO or CH4 production other than C2 products. In this work, copper electrocatalysts were prepared by Cu2(OH)2CO3-mediated in situ deposition for diluted CO2 reduction to multicarbon products. Using in situ Raman spectroscopy, constant amounts of CO and OH* were observed on the catalyst surface, which could effectively suppress the high kinetics of hydrogen evolution and promote C&#8211;C coupling, especially under the condition of diluted CO2 reduction. The optimized Cu catalyst achieves a C2 Faradaic efficiency as high as 60.72% in the presence of merely 25% CO2, which is almost equivalent to that observed with pure CO2.</description>
      <author>Qiankang Zhang, Zhanbo Si, Ying Zhang, Yilin Deng, Xiaojie She, Qing Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#27703;&#35069;&#27083;&#36896;&#29289;&#12395;&#12424;&#12427;&#27969;&#12428;&#12398;&#21046;&#24481;&#12395;&#38306;&#12377;&#12427;&#30740;&#31350;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1299/jsmemecj.2023.s054p-05</link>
      <description>Shota KAWASUMI, Satoshi Ogata, Manaya KOMORI, Nenji Taikai. 2023(0)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393134379

                In recent years, environmental issues such as carbon dioxide emissions have become a concern, and flow separation control such as vortex generators (hereinafter referred to as "VG") have attracted attention. However, VG has the disadvantage that the drag coefficient is reduced at low Reynolds numbers, but at higher Reynolds numbers, VG conversely becomes a drag. Therefore, we decided to compensate for this shortcoming by creating VG with ice. Specifically, the procedure is to produce ice at low Reynolds numbers and melt ice at high Reynolds numbers. In addition, previous studies have used the technique of freezing water droplets, which has the disadvantage that the height of the droplets is limited by gravity. We proposed a method in which a tube is filled with water, frozen in a cooling device, and pushed out with a syringe like a tokoroten, which does not limit the height of the tube. The following results were obtained by forming a VG with an object that reproduced ice and checking the change in drag coefficient. (1) It was confirmed that a rectangular VG shape reduces drag more than a cylindrical one. (2) The maximum drag reduction of about 8% was observed at a flow velocity of 2m/s with a VG breadth of 5mm and a height of 6mm. (3) The maximum drag reduction of about 17% was observed at a flow velocity of 5m/s with a VG breadth of 5mm and a height of 3mm.</description>
      <author>Shota KAWASUMI, Satoshi Ogata, Manaya KOMORI</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1299/jsmemecj.2023.s054p-05</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel technology for synergistic SO2 reduction during the carbonation process via a CaO-Char mixed system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150678</link>
      <description>Menghan Zhang, Huichao Chen, Cai Liang, Lunbo Duan, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393132238

                A novel method to effectively achieve synergistic SO2 reduction during the carbonation process by the as-designed CaO-biochar system is developed. Coconut shells and calcined-limestone were used as biochar and calcium sources (denoted as CSC and LS), respectively. The introduced reductant creates the reduction condition making the Ca-based sulfation suppressed and the desulfurization prefers to undertake the reduction pathway during the simultaneous CO2/SO2 removal process. The competition of SO2 and CO2 for the calcium active sites is weakened, effectively alleviating the negative effect of SO2 presence on CO2 carbonation and generating valuable sulfur-product. With the mass ratio of LS and CSC is 3, the carbonation conversion of the LS-CSC(1:3) is 34% higher than that of the LS and the reduced-sulfur ratio of the system reaches about 85% indicating an effective CO2 capture synergistic SO2 reduction. The CO produced via the Boudouard reaction between CO2 and char is sufficient to play an important role in SO2 reduction, which effectively promotes the decarboxylation process in the reduction of SO2. It also facilitates the sulfur transfer from the reduced intermediate on the solid phase to the gas phase as a form of COS, promoting the reduction of SO2 through the Claus reaction.</description>
      <author>Menghan Zhang, Huichao Chen, Cai Liang, Lunbo Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Exceptional CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Selectivity at Neutral Conditions: A First-Principles Study on Chlorinated Single Iron Doped Graphitic Carbon Nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07748</link>
      <description>Renna Shakir, Hannu Pekka Komsa, Karan Kumar Paswan, A. Sinha, J. Karthikeyan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393161959

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2RR) to useful fuels and chemicals using renewable energy sources presents a promising strategy for addressing energy security and environmental challenges. Single-metal atom catalysts have emerged as appealing alternatives due to their high efficiency in overcoming limitations associated with traditional metal nanocatalysts. This comprehensive study focuses on fine-tuning chlorinated single-atom-based active sites on a graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) monolayer to achieve absolute selectivity for HCOOH. Previous research has demonstrated that halogenation significantly suppresses the hydrogen evolution reaction, which competes with the CO2RR. To achieve selectivity for a single product among all reduced products, the chemical environment of the catalyst was tuned to neutral conditions. Our results indicate that the catalyst exhibited higher selectivity for HCOOH, with a significantly low onset potential and a wide potential range where HCOOH selectivity was maintained at the FeCl site at pH 7 compared to the acidic region. These findings highlight the FeCl active site of FeCl-decorated g-C3N4 as a highly efficient and selective electrocatalyst for the CO2RR. The insights gained from our study offer valuable directions for designing new CO2RR catalysts with improved selectivity and efficiencies.</description>
      <author>Renna Shakir, Hannu Pekka Komsa, Karan Kumar Paswan, A. Sinha, J. Karthikeyan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the electroreduction of CO2 to liquid products via nanostructure engineering of Cu2O catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115458</link>
      <description>Fubin Yang, Tao Yang, Jing Li, Pengfei Li, Quan Zhang, Huihui Lin, Luyan Wu, Journal of Catalysis. 432(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393175738

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 presents a promising pathway for storing intermittent renewable energy in the form of chemical bonds, thereby mitigating CO2 emissions and enabling the production of sustainable fuels. In this work, we demonstrate nanoscale engineering of oxygen vacancy and morphology simultaneously on Cu2O catalysts for electrochemical reduction of CO2 to liquid products (formate and ethanol). By comparing the performance of cube- and tetrakaidecahedron-like Cu2O catalysts, we have demonstrated that the flower-like Cu2O catalyst, enclosed with rich oxygen vacancy defects, exhibited superior performance in the reduction of CO2 to liquid products. Moreover, the synergetic role of Cu+ also contributed to the enhanced activity by promoting CO2 adsorption and facilitating C&#8211;C coupling. As a result, the peak Faradaic efficiency (FE) for liquid products of 95.5 % was obtained, associated with a high ethanol FE of 52.6 % and formation rate of 23.8 &#956;mol h&#8722;1 cm&#8722;2 within a H-cell. Furthermore, within a flow cell configuration, we have observed a significant improvement in the generation of formate, maintaining FE values above 70 % even under high current densities of up to 400 mA cm&#8722;2. In-situ Raman spectroscopic measurements allow us to identify and track key intermediates involved in the CO2 reduction to formate and ethanol. This detailed understanding of the reaction pathways adds to our fundamental knowledge and provides valuable insights for the development of morphology-controlled electrocatalysts targeting efficient conversion of CO2 into liquid products.</description>
      <author>Fubin Yang, Tao Yang, Jing Li, Pengfei Li, Quan Zhang, Huihui Lin, Luyan Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115458</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deposition and release behavior of H2S during chemical looping hydrogen production process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150621</link>
      <description>Yusan Turap, Zhe Zhang, Yongkang Wang, Yidi Wang, Zhentong Wang, Wei Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393131905

                Chemical looping hydrogen production process is a promising technology for producing low-carbon hydrogen from various fossil and biogenic energy sources. However, the typical contaminant in feedstock, hydrogen sulfide, has a potential influence on the process. Herein, this study investigated the influence of hydrogen sulfide on the chemical looping hydrogen production process. Results show that the presence of hydrogen sulfide in the fuel reduces the reaction performance of the oxygen carrier because sulfur is deposited in the oxygen carrier during the reduction stage to produce iron sulfide species (FeS2, Fe7S8 and FeS). Then the iron sulfide is converted to hydrogen sulfide and sulfur dioxide during the hydrogen production and air oxidation stage, respectively. H2 production temperature is an important factor in controlling the production of hydrogen sulfide, which will not be produced at temperature below 710 &#176;C. In addition, the air oxidation regeneration step ensures that sulfur does not accumulate in the oxygen carrier, thus improving the cycle stability of the oxygen carrier.</description>
      <author>Yusan Turap, Zhe Zhang, Yongkang Wang, Yidi Wang, Zhentong Wang, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150621</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Cu incorporation on activated carbon for CO2 adsorption and electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133784</link>
      <description>Lee-Lee Chang, Chechia Hu, Chun-Chieh Huang, Vlastimil Mat&#283;jka, Kuo&#8208;Lun Tung, Colloids and Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393130226

                Electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) have emerged as promising approaches toward a sustainable and green society. In this study, potassium citrate-derived activated carbon (ACK) was synthesized and incorporated with copper (Cu) for electrocatalytic reduction under CO2 and N2 flows. The ACK sample exhibited high CO2 adsorption properties to generate different carbonate species and served as an electrocatalyst after Cu incorporation. To understand the competitive reactions of HER and CO2RR, different reaction conditions were applied. Under a CO2 flow, the Cu-ACK sample revealed a high and long-term current density of 0.9 V, and the products were determined to be H2 (2.642 mmol) as major product, and CH3COOH, and C2H5OH as minor products. A reaction mechanism was proposed to elucidate the reaction path for the electrocatalytic CO2 RR and HER.</description>
      <author>Lee-Lee Chang, Chechia Hu, Chun-Chieh Huang, Vlastimil Mat&#283;jka, Kuo&#8208;Lun Tung</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Green Infrastructure Investment on Urban Carbon Emissions in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16072668</link>
      <description>James H. Sang, Lingying Pan, Sustainability. 16(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393142915

                Given the increasingly severe global climate change, the reduction in urban greenhouse gas emissions has become the common goal of all nations. As a widely concerned sustainable development strategy, green infrastructure investment (GII) aims to reduce urban carbon emissions, improve the efficiency of resource utilization, and improve environmental quality. However, the construction cycle of green infrastructure is long, and the construction process itself may produce carbon emissions; so, the final effect of GII on urban carbon emissions is unclear, which deserves our in-depth study. Further, is this effect having a time-lag effect? Is there only a simple linear relationship between GII and urban carbon emissions? Based on panel data from 235 Chinese cities from 2006 to 2019, this study conducted an econometric regression analysis using time-lag-effect and threshold-effect models. The results showed the following: (1) GII had a negative inhibitory effect on urban CO2 emissions. Adding one unit to the GII could reduce urban CO2 emissions by 0.032 units. (2) GII exhibited a time-lag effect on urban CO2 emissions, and the greatest reduction in CO2 emissions occurred in the third lag period. (3) GII had a threshold effect on urban CO2 emissions based on technological progress (TP). This paper used the static and dynamic panel threshold models to research separately, and obtained the corresponding regression results. In the static panel, the double threshold values for TP were 3.9120 and 6.8035. At different TP levels, GII had an inhibitory effect on CO2 emissions, but the coefficients were different. However, in the dynamic panel, the threshold value was 3.666. The threshold changed over time and the effect of GII on CO2 emissions shifted from facilitation to inhibition.</description>
      <author>James H. Sang, Lingying Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16072668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are electricity generation effective on carbon neutrality in the global south? Evidence from sectoral CO2 emissions by daily data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.171911</link>
      <description>Mustafa Tevfik Kartal, U&#287;ur Korkut Pata, Dilvin Ta&#351;k&#305;n, Science of The Total Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393129349

                In light of the efforts to ensure carbon neutrality by combating climate-related problems, the study investigates the effectiveness of electricity generation (EG) from the main renewable sources (hydro-HEG, solar-SEG, and wind-WEG). In this context, the study examines the countries of the Global South (i.e., Brazil, China, and India), considers EG at a disaggregated level and sectoral CO2 emissions, applies nonlinear methods, and uses daily data between January 2, 2019 and December 31, 2022. The results demonstrate that (i) disaggregated EG sources have a stronger (weaker) time and frequency dependency on sectoral CO2 emissions in China (Brazil and India); (ii) HEG has a stimulating impact on sectoral CO2 emissions in all countries; (iii) SEG has an increasing impact on sectoral CO2 emissions in Brazil and China, while it provides a decrease in sectoral CO2 emissions in India; (iv) WEG upsurges sectoral CO2 emissions in China, while it achieves a CO2 reduction in Brazil and India; (v) disaggregated level EG has a causal impact on sectoral CO2 emissions across all quantiles except some lower, middle, and higher quantiles. The study adds scientific value to existing knowledge by analyzing for the first time which EG sources are effective in reducing daily CO2 emissions in the Global South. Based on the outcomes, the study demonstrates that WEG is the best EG source for Brazil, that SEG and WEG are optimal EG sources for India, and that China cannot benefit from the EG sources considered. In this way, the study provides fresh insights for the countries of the Global South and underlines the crucial role of renewable EG in ensuring carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Mustafa Tevfik Kartal, U&#287;ur Korkut Pata, Dilvin Ta&#351;k&#305;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.171911</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Electric Field Promotes Interfacial Adsorption and Activation of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for C&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; Products over a Wide Potential Window</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01190</link>
      <description>Xin Zhao, Qingguo Feng, Mengjie Liu, Yuchao Wang, Wei Liu, Danni Deng, Jiabi Jiang, Xinran Zheng, Longsheng Zhan, Jinxian Wang, Zheng He, Yu Bai, Yingbi Chen, Xiang Xiong, Yongpeng Lei, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393129964

                The unsatisfactory adsorption and activation of CO2 suppress electrochemical reduction over a wide potential window. Herein, the built-in electric field (BIEF) at the CeO2/In2O3 n&#8211;n heterostructure realizes the C1 (CO and HCOO&#8211;) selectivity over 90.0% in a broad range of potentials from &#8722;0.7 to &#8722;1.1 V with a maximum value of 98.7 &#177; 0.3% at &#8722;0.8 V. In addition, the C1 current density (&#8722;1.1 V) of the CeO2/In2O3 heterostructure with a BIEF is about 2.0- and 3.2-fold that of In2O3 and a physically mixed sample, respectively. The experimental and theoretical calculation results indicate that the introduction of CeO2 triggered the charge redistribution and formed the BIEF at the interfaces, which enhanced the interfacial adsorption and activation of CO2 at low overpotentials. Furthermore, the promoting effect was also extended to CeO2/In2S3. This work gives a deep understanding of BIEF engineering for highly efficient CO2 electroreduction over a wide potential window.</description>
      <author>Xin Zhao, Qingguo Feng, Mengjie Liu, Yuchao Wang, Wei Liu, Danni Deng, Jiabi Jiang, Xinran Zheng, Longsheng Zhan, Jinxian Wang, Zheng He, Yu Bai, Yingbi Chen, Xiang Xiong, Yongpeng Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01190</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
