<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:42:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Formate Synthesis: Integrating Ethylene Glycol Oxidation with Carbon Dioxide Electrocatalysis Using Redox-Stabilized Earth-Abundant Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08233</link>
      <description>Ifra Bashir, James McGettrick, Moritz F. Kuehnel, Bilal Sarfraz, Sidra Arshad, Ali Rauf, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392579512

                Carbon dioxide electroreduction (CO2ER) coupled with water oxidation (oxygen evolution reaction, OER) presents a promising solution for effectively mitigating global warming. However, this process is compromised by the sluggish OER, which yields only undesirable O2. Here, we couple selective CO2ER with partial ethylene glycol oxidation (EGO) to concurrently produce formate in both half-reactions. The enhancement of active sites and optimization of formate selectivity are the principal objectives during the design of both electrodes. For CO2ER, redox stabilization of Sn-based cathodes is investigated via Pb doping, thus ultimately improving the Faradaic efficiency from 68% to &#8764;89%. To replace OER with EGO, we employed CuO@Ni(OH)2 on copper foam, reducing the applied potential by 200 mV at 50 mA/cm2. Finally, an EGO-coupled CO2 electrolyzer achieves 10 mA/cm2 at an overall cell voltage 180 mV lower than that of a conventional CO2 electrolyzer. This study showcases the integration of divergent electrochemical processes for concurrent electrosynthesis without precious metals to achieve cost-effective and sustainable formate production from CO2 and plastic waste.</description>
      <author>Ifra Bashir, James McGettrick, Moritz F. Kuehnel, Bilal Sarfraz, Sidra Arshad, Ali Rauf</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Roughness of Copper Working Electrode Through Electroless Deposition for Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4753683</link>
      <description>Yu&#8208;Hsu Chang, Watsananan T. Thienprasert, N. Manjula, Ninie Suhana Abdul Manan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392621229

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Yu&#8208;Hsu Chang, Watsananan T. Thienprasert, N. Manjula, Ninie Suhana Abdul Manan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4753683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioinspired Binickel Catalyst for Carbon Dioxide Reduction: The Importance of Metal&#8211;ligand Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00047</link>
      <description>Yao Xiao, Fusheng Xie, Zhang Hong-tao, Ming&#8208;Tian Zhang, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392638780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Xiao, Fusheng Xie, Zhang Hong-tao, Ming&#8208;Tian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated screening of gas diffusion electrodes for carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-m8dtd</link>
      <description>Ryan J. R. Jones, Ying&#8208;Chih Lai, Dan Guevarra, Kevin Kan, Joel A. Haber, John M. Gregoire, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392649765

                The electrochemical conversion of carbon dioxide to chemicals and fuels is expected to be a key sustainability technology. Electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction technologies are challenged by several factors, including the limited solubility of carbon dioxide in aqueous electrolyte as well as the difficulty in utilizing polymer electrolytes. These considerations have driven systems designs to incorporate gas diffusion electrodes (GDEs) to bring the electrocatalyst in contact with both a gaseous reactant/product stream as well as a liquid electrolyte. GDE optimization typically results from manual tuning by select experts. Automated preparation and operation of GDE cells could be a watershed for the systematic study of, and ultimately the development of a materials acceleration platform (MAP) for, catalyst discovery and system optimization. Toward this end, we present the automated GDE (AutoGDE) testing system. Given a catalyst-coated GDE, AutoGDE automates the insertion of the GDE into an electrochemical cell, the liquid and gas handling, the quantification of gaseous reaction products via online mass spectroscopy, and the archiving of the liquid electrolyte for subsequent analysis.</description>
      <author>Ryan J. R. Jones, Ying&#8208;Chih Lai, Dan Guevarra, Kevin Kan, Joel A. Haber, John M. Gregoire</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-m8dtd</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic promotion for the performance of photocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction by vacancy engineering and N-doped carbon nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127063</link>
      <description>Min Wang, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Fanlin Kong, Baolin Liu, Zhende Wu, Yali Cao, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392659274

                The structural devise of photocatalytic materials are closely related to the separation of photogenerated carriers and the transport of charge, which is crucial to enhance the performance of photocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). Here, a photocatalyst (CdS-SV@Co@NCNT) has been successfully prepared by growing cadmium sulfide nanoparticles with sulfur vacancies on N-doped carbon nanotubes through a simple solvothermal method. The intrinsic electronic structure is regulated by sulfur vacancies to promote photocatalytic activity. Meanwhile, a larger specific surface area of Co@NCNT could expose more reaction sites and shorten the transfer distance of photogenerated carriers. Furthermore, the combination with Co@NCNT could effectively suppress the photocorrosion of CdS. The possible photocatalytic CO2RR path is further speculated by in-situ infrared test results, in which CO2 molecules adsorbed on sulfur vacancies preferentially generate important intermediate COOH*, which is then reduced to CO and CH4. Therefore, it exhibits a high CO yield of 263.3 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1 and trace of CH4 while showing excellent stability. This research provides a novel idea for designing the photocatalysts with highly active and stability for CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Min Wang, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Fanlin Kong, Baolin Liu, Zhende Wu, Yali Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scale-Up Study of Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction Process Through Data-Driven Modelling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4755410</link>
      <description>G.Q. Zhang, Xiaoteng Liu, Hanhui Lei, Yucheng Wang, Denise Bildan, Xing Liu, Xiangqun Zhuge, Zhihong Luo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392666560

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>G.Q. Zhang, Xiaoteng Liu, Hanhui Lei, Yucheng Wang, Denise Bildan, Xing Liu, Xiangqun Zhuge, Zhihong Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4755410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 nm Tin Oxide Cluster for the Electrochemical Conversion of Carbon Dioxide to Formate at Low Overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/1367542</link>
      <description>Hyungrae Kim, Kang-Hyuk Lee, Chan Woo Lee, International Journal of Energy Research. 2024(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392683413

                Due to its cost-effectiveness and high product selectivity, tin oxide has been regarded as a promising catalyst for the electrochemical conversion of CO2 to formate. However, formate production is hindered by the high overpotential; there is a need to reduce the overpotential to enhance energy efficiency and lower electricity cost for the implementation of carbon utilization technology. Here, we report a facile synthesis method for 1 nm-sized SnO2 cluster catalysts, which can be used for CO2-to-formate conversion. SnO2 clusters were prepared through impregnation of porous carbon with a tin precursor solution. The SnO2 clusters showed a low overpotential, generating a current density of 10 mA cm-2 at a potential of -0.34 V vs. RHE in 1 M KOH. They also achieved high Faradaic efficiencies of 90.5% and 81.5% at 200 and 300 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. Their electrocatalytic performance was strongly dependent on the annealing conditions, which affected the particle size, electrochemical active surface area, and metal oxidation state. This paper presents a versatile method for synthesizing metal oxide cluster catalysts, apart from providing insights into the catalytic activity for the electrochemical conversion of CO2 to formate.</description>
      <author>Hyungrae Kim, Kang-Hyuk Lee, Chan Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/1367542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functionalization of copper for enhanced electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide via ultrashort pulse laser surface processing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3000983</link>
      <description>Graham Kaufman, Ahmed El&#8208;Harairy, Suchit Sarin, Siamak Nejati, Jeffrey E. Shield, Craig Zuhlke, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392692145

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Graham Kaufman, Ahmed El&#8208;Harairy, Suchit Sarin, Siamak Nejati, Jeffrey E. Shield, Craig Zuhlke</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3000983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size&#8208;Dependent Carbon Dioxide Reduction Activity of Copper Nanoparticle and Nanocluster Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202300575</link>
      <description>Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Tomoshige Okada, Kana Takemae, Shiho Tomihari, Yuichi Negishi, ChemNanoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392699583

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction reaction (CRR, which can convert CO2 into useful compounds at room temperature and ambient pressure by using electricity derived from renewable energy source), has been attracting attention in recent years. This is because it can convert CO2 into useful compounds, which is pertinent to establishing a next&#8208;generation recycling&#8208;oriented energy society. However, further improvement of the electrocatalyst is required to improve its activity, selectivity, and durability. Among these, copper (Cu) can synthesize various hydrocarbons from CO2 and has been the most studied electrocatalyst for the CRR over many years. In particular, regarding ligand&#8208;protected Cu particles for the CRR, the size, shape, and ligands of Cu particles prepared by chemical reduction can be precisely controlled. In this review, we summarize previous research on the size&#8208;dependence of the CRR by using Cu particles (nanoparticles and nanoclusters) prepared by liquid&#8208;phase reduction, and discuss the current status of these studies for researchers on the electrochemical CRR.</description>
      <author>Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Tomoshige Okada, Kana Takemae, Shiho Tomihari, Yuichi Negishi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202300575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Status, Challenges, and Future Prospects of Carbon Dioxide Reduction Technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04591</link>
      <description>Hongtao Dang, Bin Guan, Junyan Chen, Zeren Ma, Yujun Chen, Jinhe Zhang, Zelong Guo, Lei Chen, Jingqiu Hu, Yi Chao, Shunyu Yao, Zhen Huang, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392705965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongtao Dang, Bin Guan, Junyan Chen, Zeren Ma, Yujun Chen, Jinhe Zhang, Zelong Guo, Lei Chen, Jingqiu Hu, Yi Chao, Shunyu Yao, Zhen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Electrocatalytic Redox-Active Sites in Three-Dimensional Bimetalloporphyrin-based Covalent Organic Framework for Enhancing Carbon Dioxide Reduction and Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00998c</link>
      <description>Jie Liu, Yan&#8208;Xi Tan, Jiaping Lin, Yangyang Feng, Xiang Zhang, Enle Zhou, Daqiang Yuan, Yaobing Wang, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392719172

                Constructing bifunctional covalent organic frameworks (COFs) electrocatalysts to mimic photosynthesis independent of natural sunlight is important for the CO2 recycling. We first construct 3D bifunctional Co/Ni-TPNB-COF containing Ni(II)-porphyrin and Co(II)-porphyrin...</description>
      <author>Jie Liu, Yan&#8208;Xi Tan, Jiaping Lin, Yangyang Feng, Xiang Zhang, Enle Zhou, Daqiang Yuan, Yaobing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00998c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two&#8208;Dimensional Crystalline Electrocatalysts for Efficient Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400009</link>
      <description>Lu Dai, Jie Zong, Lisha Liang, Pengfei Li, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392749022

                Abstract The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (eCO 2 RR) can achieve carbon recycling through renewable electrical energy. Before releasing the full potential of eCO 2 RR, the electrocatalysts still need improvement in terms of catalytic activity, selectivity, and durability. Two&#8208;dimensional (2D) crystalline materials show a high aspect ratio with well&#8208;defined crystal structures, which are promising electrocatalysts for eCO 2 RR. In this review, we briefly discuss the typical 2D electrocatalysts for eCO 2 RR. Subsequently, we provide a summary of the different strategies to improve the catalytic performance of 2D crystalline electrocatalysts for creating and modulating active sites. Finally, we end this review with the current challenges and future opportunities of 2D crystalline materials in the eCO 2 RR.</description>
      <author>Lu Dai, Jie Zong, Lisha Liang, Pengfei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quadruple transition metal dichalcogenide for variously synergetic electron behaviors during photocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159887</link>
      <description>Pei Liu, Hongyu Chen, Caiyuan Zhao, Deng Long, Weijia Chen, Miao L&#252;, Xin Yi Chen, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392752845

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pei Liu, Hongyu Chen, Caiyuan Zhao, Deng Long, Weijia Chen, Miao L&#252;, Xin Yi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Cu2O/SiC photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide to methanol using visible light on lnTaO4&#8221; [Mater. Sci. Semicond. Process. 174 (2024) 108235]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108313</link>
      <description>Babalola Aisosa Oni, Samuel Eshorame Sanni, Olusegun Stanley Tomomewo, Shree Om Bade, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392768040

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Babalola Aisosa Oni, Samuel Eshorame Sanni, Olusegun Stanley Tomomewo, Shree Om Bade</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Production of Ethylene and Hydrogen Peroxide from Paired Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction and Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304247</link>
      <description>Sotirios Mavrikis, Mich&#233;l K. Nieuwoudt, Maximilian G&#246;ltz, Sophie Ehles, Andreas K&#246;rner, Andreas Hutzler, Emeric Fossy, Andreas Zervas, Oshioriamhe Brai, Moritz Wegener, Florian Doerrfuss, Peter Bouwman, Stefan Rosiwal, Ling Wang, Carlos Ponce de Le&#243;n, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392807699

                Abstract Paired electrolysis offers an auspicious strategy for the generation of high&#8208;value chemicals, at both the anode and cathode, in an integrated electrochemical reactor. Through efficient electron utilization, routine product misuse at overlooked electrodes can be prevented. Here, an original paired electrosynthetic system is reported that can convert CO 2 to ethylene (C 2 H 4 ) at the cathode, and water to hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) at the anode under a single pass of electric charge. Amongst various investigated copper (Cu) nanomorphologies, the bespoke mixed Cu nanowire/nanoparticle catalyst recorded a peak C 2 H 4 Faraday efficiency ( FE ) of 60% following 370 h of electrolysis at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 , while the tailored boron&#8208;doped diamond (BDD) anode accumulated an unprecedented &#8776;1% w/w of H 2 O 2 in 4 m K 2 CO 3 upon applying 300 mA cm &#8722;2 for 10 h. When paired, the dual C 2 H 4 &#8208;H 2 O 2 electrochemical cell attains a combined FE of 120% for 50 h at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 , a combined energy efficiency (EE) of 69%, and a 50% decrease in the overall electrical energy consumption (EEC) compared to the individual electrosynthesis of C 2 H 4 and H 2 O 2 .</description>
      <author>Sotirios Mavrikis, Mich&#233;l K. Nieuwoudt, Maximilian G&#246;ltz, Sophie Ehles, Andreas K&#246;rner, Andreas Hutzler, Emeric Fossy, Andreas Zervas, Oshioriamhe Brai, Moritz Wegener, Florian Doerrfuss, Peter Bouwman, Stefan Rosiwal, Ling Wang, Carlos Ponce de Le&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of nanocomposites based on graphitic carbon nitride, titanium dioxide and boron nitride for the photo-production of H2 and the photo-reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4392773243</link>
      <description>Leila Hammoud, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392773243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leila Hammoud</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4392773243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distribution of Carbon Dioxide Emissions and Potential Consequences for Their Reduction in Louisiana</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31390/gradschool_theses.5821</link>
      <description>Mohammad I. Zia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392795875

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohammad I. Zia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31390/gradschool_theses.5821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Carbon Dioxide on Bromantane Syntesis by Reductive Amination without an External Hydrogen Source</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32931/io2307a</link>
      <description>D. Kletnov, Klim O. Biriukov, &#1040;. &#1045;. &#1053;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1083;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, Oleg I. Afanasyev, Denis Chusov, &#1048;&#1053;&#1069;&#1054;&#1057; OPEN. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392658822

                The effect of carbon dioxide on the reaction of bromantane synthesis by reductive amination using carbon monoxide as a reducing agent has been studied. A nonlinear dependence of the yield of the target product on the ratio of gases was observed. It was found that, depending on the conditions, carbon dioxide could both decrease and increase the yield of bromantane.</description>
      <author>D. Kletnov, Klim O. Biriukov, &#1040;. &#1045;. &#1053;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1083;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, Oleg I. Afanasyev, Denis Chusov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32931/io2307a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-purpose afforestation scenarios under climate change for carbon dioxide reduction&amp;amp;#160;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-egu24-19777</link>
      <description>Florian Kraxner, Dmitry Schepaschenko, Sabine Fuss, Andrey Krasovskiy, &#1040;. Shvidenko, Georg Kindermann, Hyun-Woo Jo, Woo&#8208;Kyun Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392645629

                This study aims at identifying the carbon dioxide reduction (CDR) potential of large-scale and multi-purpose afforestation/reforestation at the global level with special emphasis on the Mid-Latitude Region (MLR). Applying a combined remote sensing/GIS approach coupled with biophysical forest and disturbance modeling under various climate change scenarios, we identify potential afforestation locations, inter-alia on abandoned agricultural land and on areas burnt from wild land fires. With the help of IIASA&amp;#8217;s biophysical global forestry model (G4M), we calculate the associated land-based CDR potentials through carbon sequestration in afforested biomass and through climate risk-resilient and sustainable forest management dedicated to the supply of bioenergy plants coupled with carbon capture and storage (BECCS) facilities. Finally, three promising scenarios have been identified including I) afforestation; II) reforestation; and III) BECCS. In all scenarios, priority is put on sustainable forest management and nature/biodiversity conservation. Forest modeling results have been combined with recent data sets which have been overlayed in order to provide a unique basis to estimate the land-based CDR technologies&amp;#8217; potential to mitigate climate change and contribute to reaching the goals of the Paris Agreement. In the case of afforestation, preliminary results indicate a total potential afforestation area greater than 1 billion ha. &amp;#160;The largest area potential for afforestation have been identified in the USA. Given the higher productivity (combined with large area available), Brazil is the country with the highest total CDR potential of close to 500 MtC/yr.</description>
      <author>Florian Kraxner, Dmitry Schepaschenko, Sabine Fuss, Andrey Krasovskiy, &#1040;. Shvidenko, Georg Kindermann, Hyun-Woo Jo, Woo&#8208;Kyun Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-egu24-19777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous ZnSnOx Hollow Spheres Enable Highly Efficient CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301694</link>
      <description>Hanjun Li, Yao Chen, Honggang Huang, Zhenxiang Cheng, Shuxing Bai, Feili Lai, Nan Zhang, Tianxi Liu, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392697772

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) adsorption and electron transport play an important role in CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Herein, we have demonstrated a new class of diverse hollow ZnSnOx (ZSO) through the amorphization of hydroxides to enhance CO2 adsorption and accelerate electron transport. The amorphization is occurred by calcination process, as indicated by Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy and Raman spectra. In particular, the ZnSnOx hollow spheres (ZSO HSs) achieve a high Faradaic efficiency (FE) of HCOOH up to 92.7% at best, outperforming the commercial ZSO (Comm. ZSO, 83.9%). ZSO HSs also exhibit durable stability with negligible activity decay after 10 h of successive electrolysis. In&#8208;situ attenuated total reflectance infrared absorption spectroscopy further reveals strong adsorption of CO2 and rapid intermediate configuration transformation in amorphous ZSO HSs. This work demonstrates the practical application of ZSO for CO2RR and provides a new insight to create efficient CO2RR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hanjun Li, Yao Chen, Honggang Huang, Zhenxiang Cheng, Shuxing Bai, Feili Lai, Nan Zhang, Tianxi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study of layered double hydroxides for the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4392773097</link>
      <description>A. Tarhini, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392773097

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Tarhini</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4392773097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte effect in electrochemical reduction of CO2 on Cu electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.367</link>
      <description>Amanda C. Garcia, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392704869

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amanda C. Garcia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction-transport kinetics in the electrochemical reduction of CO2 on copper catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.418</link>
      <description>Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392704678

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of International Cooperation and Logistics Networks on CO2 Emission Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18104/kalc.2023.38.4.181</link>
      <description>Ming Song, Korean Academy Of International Commerce. 38(4)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392735268

                Purpose: This study analyzes the causal relationships between CO2 emissions and ODA, logistics, renewable energy, economic growth, and industrialization.
 Research design, data, and methodology: From 2006 to 2019, panel data related to CO2 emissions, ODA, logistics networks, renewable energy, economic growth, and industrialization were collected from a total of 84 countries. To analyze this model, panel unit root tests and panel co-integration tests were performed to confirm the stability and long-term causal relationships in the data. Subsequently, panel FMOLS and panel DOLS were used to identify variables affecting carbon dioxide, and pairwise panel Granger causality analysis was used to analyze causality between these variables.
 Results: According to panel FMOLS and panel DOLS analysis, ODA and renewable energy reduce CO2 emissions, but economic growth increases CO2 emissions.
 Conclusions: As a result of panel FMOLS and panel DOLS analysis, economic growth was identified as a factor in increasing CO2 emissions, and international development cooperation and renewable energy were identified as factors in reducing CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Ming Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18104/kalc.2023.38.4.181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuSnBi Catalyst Grown on Copper Foam by Co-Electrodeposition for Efficient Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14030191</link>
      <description>Hangxin Xie, Li Lv, Yuan Sun, Chunlai Wang, Jialin Xu, Min Tang, Catalysts. 14(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392648975

                Effective electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide to formate under mild conditions helps mitigate the energy crisis but requires the use of high-performance catalysts. The addition of a third metal to the binary metal catalyst may further promote the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide to formate. Herein, we provided a co-electrodeposition method to grow CuSnBi catalysts on pretreated copper foam and discussed the effects of both pH value and molar ratio of metal ions (Cu2+, Sn2+, and Bi3+) in the electrodeposition solution on the electrocatalytic performance of CO2 to HCOO&#8722;. When the pH value of the electrodeposition solution was 8.5 and the molar ratio of Cu2+, Sn2+, and Bi3+ was 1:1:1, the electrode showed the highest FEHCOO&#8722; of 91.79% and the formate partial current density of 36.6 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;1.12 VRHE. Furthermore, the electrode kept stable for 20 h at &#8722;1.12 VRHE, and FEHCOO&#8722; was always beyond 85% during the electrolysis process, which is excellent compared to the previously reported ternary metal catalytic electrodes. This work highlights the vital impact of changes (pH value and molar ratio of metal ions) in electrodeposition liquid on catalytic electrodes and their catalytic performance, and refreshing the electrolyte is essential to maintain the activity and selectivity during the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to HCOO&#8722;.</description>
      <author>Hangxin Xie, Li Lv, Yuan Sun, Chunlai Wang, Jialin Xu, Min Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14030191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Prospects of Urea Manufacturing via Electrochemical Co-reduction of CO2 and Nitrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101479</link>
      <description>Qinglan Zhao, Ye Zhang, Dapeng Cao, Minhua Shao, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392767741

                Electrochemical co-reduction of CO2 and nitrates presents a promising alternative for urea production. However, the current electrochemical synthesis of urea faces challenges related to low selectivity and production rates. The development of high-efficiency electrocatalysts is the key to performance improvement of urea electrosynthesis. This minireview primarily focuses on the rational design of catalysts, starting with a mechanistic overview. In addition, the advancement of electrolyzers for urea electrochemical synthesis is also discussed aiming to articulate guiding principles of achieving high-rate production reaching industrial relevant level in the future.</description>
      <author>Qinglan Zhao, Ye Zhang, Dapeng Cao, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Strain in Electrocatalytic Materials for CO2 Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00514g</link>
      <description>Junshan Lin, Ning Zhang, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392813161

                The electrocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable carbon-based compounds has attracted considerable attention. In the quest for efficient electrocatalysts, strain engineering, characterized by localized relative deformation, emerges as...</description>
      <author>Junshan Lin, Ning Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00514g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Effects of Ligands on Gold Nanoparticles for the Selective Reduction of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.082</link>
      <description>&#193;lvaro Lozano Roche, Asia Porceddu, Laia Franc&#225;s, Jordi Garc&#305;&#769;a-Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392704565

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#193;lvaro Lozano Roche, Asia Porceddu, Laia Franc&#225;s, Jordi Garc&#305;&#769;a-Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Evolution of Single Atom Catalysts during CO2 Electrocatalytic Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.233</link>
      <description>Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392704879

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Design of Electro-Organocatalysts and Transition Metal Sulfides for the Electrochemical Reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31390/gradschool_dissertations.6240</link>
      <description>Foroogh Khezeli, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392691393

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction (ECO2RR) has emerged as a promising approach for generating carbon-neutral liquid fuels by utilizing excess renewable electricity to convert CO2. This thesis aims to employ atomistic simulations by using Density Functional Theory (DFT) to investigate the mechanistic details of how transition metal sulfides and electro-organocatalysts can enhance the activity and selectivity towards desired products, including those containing C-H bonds and molecules with C-C bonds. For this project, three different electrocatalysts were designed computationally.</description>
      <author>Foroogh Khezeli</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31390/gradschool_dissertations.6240</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
