<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 01:19:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Annealing Conditions on the Catalytic Performance of Anodized Tin Oxide for Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15020121</link>
      <description>Nicol&#242; B. D. Monti, Juqin Zeng, Micaela Castellino, Samuele Porro, Mitra Bagheri, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Angelica Chiodoni, Katarzyna Bejtka, Nanomaterials. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406470739

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) to value-added products has garnered significant interest as a sustainable solution to mitigate CO2 emissions and harness renewable energy sources. Among CO2RR products, formic acid/formate (HCOOH/HCOO&#8722;) is particularly attractive due to its industrial relevance, high energy density, and potential candidate as a liquid hydrogen carrier. This study investigates the influence of the initial oxidation state of tin on CO2RR performance using nanostructured SnOx catalysts. A simple, quick, scalable, and cost-effective synthesis strategy was employed to fabricate SnOx catalysts with controlled oxidation states while maintaining consistent morphology and particle size. The catalysts were characterized using SEM, TEM, XRD, Raman, and XPS to correlate structure and surface properties with catalytic performance. Electrochemical measurements revealed that SnOx catalysts annealed in air at 525 &#176;C exhibited the highest formate selectivity and current density, attributed to the optimized oxidation state and the presence of oxygen vacancies. Flow cell tests further demonstrated enhanced performance under practical conditions, achieving stable formate production with high faradaic efficiency over prolonged operation. These findings highlight the critical role of tin oxidation states and surface defects in tuning CO2RR performance, offering valuable insights for the design of efficient catalysts for CO2 electroreduction to formate.</description>
      <author>Nicol&#242; B. D. Monti, Juqin Zeng, Micaela Castellino, Samuele Porro, Mitra Bagheri, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Angelica Chiodoni, Katarzyna Bejtka</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15020121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction Behaviors of Tin Oxides and Oxyhydroxides Itself during Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide in an Aqueous Solution under Neutral Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k</link>
      <description>Etsushi Tsuji, Kaede Ohwan, Tomoki Ishikawa, Yuki Hirata, Hiroyuki Okada, Satoshi Suganuma, Naonobu Katada, RSC Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406529537

                It is well known that tin oxides and oxyhydroxides show high selectivity for electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) to form HCOOH in aqueous solutions. The tin oxides and oxyhydroxides are...</description>
      <author>Etsushi Tsuji, Kaede Ohwan, Tomoki Ishikawa, Yuki Hirata, Hiroyuki Okada, Satoshi Suganuma, Naonobu Katada</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multifunctions of carbon dots in CeO2/Cu2O complex catalyst for the regulation of carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02744b</link>
      <description>Yan Xiong, Jiacheng Li, Honglin Si, Haojie Xu, Hui Huang, Yang Liu, Zhenhui Kang, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406534805

                For electrocatalytic reactions, the charge transfer is a very complex process and also closely related to the chemical reaction process. Herein, taking the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) as an example,...</description>
      <author>Yan Xiong, Jiacheng Li, Honglin Si, Haojie Xu, Hui Huang, Yang Liu, Zhenhui Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02744b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst design for the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide: from copper nanoparticles to copper single atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.69</link>
      <description>Qianwen Li, Jingjing Jiang, Shanshan Jiang, Di Liu, Donghao Xu, Yongjia Chen, Dunru Zhu, Xiangwen Liu, Microstructures. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406549799

                Carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) is an efficacious method to mitigate carbon emissions and simultaneously convert CO2 into high-value carbon products. The efficiency of CO2RR depends on the development of highly active and selective catalysts. Copper (Cu)-based catalysts can effectively reduce CO2 to hydrocarbons and oxygen-containing compounds because of their unique geometric and electronic structures. Most importantly, Cu can reduce CO2 to multiple carbon products (C2+). Therefore, this review aims to outline recent research progress in Cu-based catalysts for CO2RR. After introducing the mechanism of this electroreduction reaction, we summarize the influence of the size, morphology, and coordination environment of single component Cu-based catalysts on their performance, especially the performance control of catalysts that contain nano Cu or Cu single-atom sites. Then, the synergistic regulation strategies of doping other metals into Cu-based catalysts are summarized. Finally, the research on the supports used for Cu-based catalysts is reviewed. The prospects and challenges of Cu-based catalysts are discussed.</description>
      <author>Qianwen Li, Jingjing Jiang, Shanshan Jiang, Di Liu, Donghao Xu, Yongjia Chen, Dunru Zhu, Xiangwen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.69</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reliable and accessible methods for urea quantification in co-reduction of carbon-dioxide- and nitrogen-containing species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101234</link>
      <description>Yan Zhang, Gefei Huang, Haichuan Zhang, Xiaoyi Qiu, Guimei Liu, Yinuo Wang, Juhee Jang, Yian Wang, Zidong Wei, Zongwei Cai, Minhua Shao, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406564021

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Zhang, Gefei Huang, Haichuan Zhang, Xiaoyi Qiu, Guimei Liu, Yinuo Wang, Juhee Jang, Yian Wang, Zidong Wei, Zongwei Cai, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Reduction Behaviors of Tin Oxides and Oxyhydroxides Itself during Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide in an Aqueous Solution under Neutral Conditions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406566426

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Reduction Behaviors of Tin Oxides and Oxyhydroxides Itself during Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide in an Aqueous Solution under Neutral Conditions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406566508

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptor for electro-oxidation of glycerol with high-efficiency bifunctional Cu-N single atom catalyst and coupled with hydrogen evolution/carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.122</link>
      <description>Mingyue Lv, Hao Sun, Hui Wang, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406569196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyue Lv, Hao Sun, Hui Wang, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst Ink Preparation Matters for Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400665</link>
      <description>Miao Wang, Junmei Chen, Bihao Hu, Yukun Xiao, Lei Chen, Jingyi Chen, Lei Wang, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406617533

                Abstract Electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction (CO 2 R) offers a promising pathway for closing the carbon cycle. Metallic Cu&#8208;based catalysts are the only materials capable of converting CO 2 to C 2+ products with significant selectivity and activity. Achieving industrially relevant current densities in CO 2 R requires the use of gas diffusion electrodes (GDEs), making the structure and properties of the catalyst layer (CL) on GDEs critical to the CO 2 R performance of Cu catalysts. However, limited research has explored how catalyst ink composition affects CL features and, consequently, CO 2 R performance under operating conditions. In this study, we investigate the influence of catalyst ink composition on CL structure and morphology, and how these properties affect CO 2 R performance. We find that the water content in the ink modifies active site density, thickness, and porosity of the CL, as well as the state of the Nafion binder, thereby altering the microenvironment of the active sites during CO 2 R, including local CO 2 concentration and pH. Our results reveal a strong correlation between CO 2 R performance and the structural characteristics of the CL. Specifically, optimizing the ethanol&#8208;to&#8208;water ratio in the catalyst ink enhances C 2+ product selectivity and current density to 75 % and 450 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. This approach provides a simple yet effective strategy to improve CO 2 R activity and selectivity under practical conditions.</description>
      <author>Miao Wang, Junmei Chen, Bihao Hu, Yukun Xiao, Lei Chen, Jingyi Chen, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Electrocatalysts for Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202560603011</link>
      <description>Xiaojie Deng, Ziyun Huang, Xiaowen Wu, E3S Web of Conferences. 606(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406630799

                With the progress of science and technology and the economy, realizing &#8220;sustainable development&#8221; has become the common development goal of many countries and regions in the world today. Carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) is widely used as an important carbon resource, which aggravates the problem of global warming. electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide reduction reaction (ECO 2 RR) is a key technology for converting CO 2 into useful carbon-based products (such as C 2 H 4 , CO, CH 3 OH). Thereby increasing the economic and commercial value of clean energy worldwide. In this paper, different electrocatalysts commonly used in ECO 2 RR reactions were studied. By summarizing the definition, characteristics, deficiencies, and modification strategies of different electrocatalysts, different effects of different electrocatalysts on ECO 2 RR reaction were studied. This paper helps to make up for the shortage of different electrocatalysts in the literature review of ECO 2 RR reaction, promote the development of ECO 2 RR reaction electrocatalysts, and promote the progress of ECO 2 RR reaction. Let the ECO 2 RR reaction enable energy conservation and emission reduction, and provide more effective measures for the early realization of the &#8220;double carbon goal&#8221;. Due to the limited literature on electrocatalysts, the current research is not comprehensive. Future studies should summarize the characteristics of different electrocatalysts in ECO 2 RR reactions more comprehensively.</description>
      <author>Xiaojie Deng, Ziyun Huang, Xiaowen Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202560603011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin Palladium-loaded Cuprous oxide stabilises Copper(I) to facilitate electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.132</link>
      <description>Xiaoye Du, Jae Hyun Kim, Bo Gao, Dan Qian, Chunhui Xiao, Shujiang Ding, Zhongxiao Song, Ki Tae Nam, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406632722

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoye Du, Jae Hyun Kim, Bo Gao, Dan Qian, Chunhui Xiao, Shujiang Ding, Zhongxiao Song, Ki Tae Nam</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Reduction Behaviors of Tin Oxides and Oxyhydroxides Itself during Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide in an Aqueous Solution under Neutral Conditions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Etsushi Tsuji, Kaede Ohwan, Tomoki Ishikawa, Yuki Hirata, Hiroyuki Okada, Satoshi Suganuma, Naonobu Katada, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406566318

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Etsushi Tsuji, Kaede Ohwan, Tomoki Ishikawa, Yuki Hirata, Hiroyuki Okada, Satoshi Suganuma, Naonobu Katada</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Reduction Behaviors of Tin Oxides and Oxyhydroxides Itself during Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide in an Aqueous Solution under Neutral Conditions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406566397

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Reduction Behaviors of Tin Oxides and Oxyhydroxides Itself during Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide in an Aqueous Solution under Neutral Conditions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406566513

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Reduction Behaviors of Tin Oxides and Oxyhydroxides Itself during Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide in an Aqueous Solution under Neutral Conditions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406566586

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Reduction Behaviors of Tin Oxides and Oxyhydroxides Itself during Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide in an Aqueous Solution under Neutral Conditions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406566587

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Reduction Behaviors of Tin Oxides and Oxyhydroxides Itself during Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide in an Aqueous Solution under Neutral Conditions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406566609

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00476k/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of carbon monoxide from the photodegradation of terrestrial dissolved organic carbon in natural waters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/0967-0653(93)95813-l</link>
      <description>, Oceanographic literature review. 40(8)] 1993. https://openalex.org/W4406493734

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 1993 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/0967-0653(93)95813-l</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic modelling and simulation of bioanode and biocathode in a bioelectrochemical cell for carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3384/ecp212.039</link>
      <description>Vafa Ahmadi, Nabin Aryal, Link&#246;ping electronic conference proceedings. 211(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406475077

                Bioelectrochemical systems (BESs) have garnered extensive research attention for their biosynthesis and environmental remediation applications. One of the challenges to upscaling BES for carbon dioxide (CO2) methanation is energy-efficient process development. Investigations are ongoing to determine the relationship between the yield of electroactive microorganisms, the key candidates for electrochemical reactions with external electricity input. Consequently, simulating processes, particularly with biocathode for biosynthesis and bioanode for remediation, gives crucial insights for designing efficient BESs. The framework for establishing Nernst-Monod equations for modeling BES, starts from bioanode, where anode respiring bacteria (ARB) oxidize organic carbon compounds to CO2, and generate the proton (H+). In this work, kinetic modeling was applied to calculate the biomass yield of ARBs corresponding to the applied anodic voltage. The generated CO2 and H+ from the anode determined the biomass yield of electroactive methanogens and acetogens on the cathode. Two biofilm models were established for anodic and cathodic biofilm growth in the Aquasim simulation tool. Results showed that the concentration of organic carbon compound (acetate) available for ARB, had a significant impact on the biofilm thickness and biomass concentration on the biofilm, especially at +0.3 V. The optimum anode voltage which released the highest CO2 and H+, was +0.3 V. The anodic and cathodic biofilm thickness reached 3 mm and 55 &#181;m, respectively, at +0.3 V and 10 g.L-1 acetate input to the anode chamber. Moreover, methanogens surpassed acetogens on the biocathode for CO2 reduction to methane rather than acetate. In addition, acetate consumption rate by ARB at anode was remarkably faster than acetate production at cathode.</description>
      <author>Vafa Ahmadi, Nabin Aryal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3384/ecp212.039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioenergetic Modeling of the Relationship Between Voltage and Electroactive Microbial Biomass Yield for Bioelectrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction to Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/fermentation11010040</link>
      <description>Vafa Ahmadi, Nabin Aryal, Fermentation. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406616659

                Optimal product synthesis in bioelectrochemical systems (BESs) requires a comprehensive understanding of the relationship between external voltage and microbial yield. While most studies assume constant growth yields or rely on empirical estimates, this study presents a novel thermodynamic model, linking anodic oxidation and cathodic carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction to methane (CH4) by growing microbial biofilm. Through integrating theoretical Gibbs free energy calculations, the model predicts electron and proton transfers for autotrophic methanogen and anode-respiring bacteria (ARB) growth, accounting for varying applied voltages and substrate concentrations. The findings identify an optimal applied cathodic potential of &#8722;0.3 V vs. the standard hydrogen electrode (SHE) for maximizing CH4 production under standard conditions (pH 7, 25 &#176;C, 1 atm) regardless of ohmic losses. The model bridges the stoichiometry of anodic and cathodic biofilms, addressing research gaps in simulating anodic and cathodic biofilm growth simultaneously. Additionally, sensitivity analyses reveal that lower substrate concentrations require more negative voltages than standard condition to stimulate microbial growth. The model was validated using experimental data, demonstrating reasonable predictions of biomass growth and CH4 yield under different operating voltages in a multi substrate system. The results show that higher voltage inputs increase biomass yield while reducing CH4 output due to non-optimal voltage. This validated model provides a tool for optimizing BES performance to enhance CH4 recovery and biofilm stability. These insights contribute to finding optimum voltage for the highest CH4 production for energy efficient CO2 reduction for scaling up BES technology.</description>
      <author>Vafa Ahmadi, Nabin Aryal</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/fermentation11010040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigation Strategies Based on Life Cycle Assessment for Carbon Dioxide Reduction in Asphalt Pavements: Systematic Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020695</link>
      <description>Diego Flores-Ruiz, Marco Montoya-Alcaraz, Leonel Garc&#237;a, &#769;Jos&#233; Manuel Guti&#233;rrez-Moreno, Julio Calder&#243;n-Ram&#237;rez, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406489020

                Expanding the road network is inevitable due to the accelerated economic growth of countries. However, the development of road infrastructure has generated considerable concern among society, governments, and environmental organizations. This concern mainly stems from the significant environmental effects and the omission of the sustainability of materials associated with road construction. Current literature suggests Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) as a solution to address greenhouse gas emissions and other environmental impacts of road infrastructure. This research uses the PRISMA-SCR methodology to identify strategies to mitigate environmental impact during the life cycle stages of asphalt pavements and emission-generating activities. This study identifies the critical life cycle stages responsible for the largest amount of emissions, highlighting &#8220;material extraction and production&#8221; and &#8220;transportation&#8221; as key areas of intervention. The results demonstrate how the incorporation of recycled materials (RAPs) and warm mix asphalts (WMAs) can reduce between 15% and 45% of total emissions. It is concluded that it is possible to develop asphalt pavement construction projects with a sustainability perspective, allowing not only to identify opportunities to optimize construction processes but also to establish a reference framework for transportation agencies to integrate more sustainable practices, including the reduction of emissions, the responsible use of non-renewable resources and proper waste management.</description>
      <author>Diego Flores-Ruiz, Marco Montoya-Alcaraz, Leonel Garc&#237;a, &#769;Jos&#233; Manuel Guti&#233;rrez-Moreno, Julio Calder&#243;n-Ram&#237;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated system for electrolyte recovery, product separation, and CO2 capture in CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56111-6</link>
      <description>Peng Wang, An Pei, Zhaoxi Chen, Pingyong Sun, Chengyi Hu, Xue Wang, Nanfeng Zheng, Guangxu Chen, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406468132

                Challenges in CO2 capture, CO2 crossover, product separation, and electrolyte recovery hinder electrocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2R). Here, we present an integrated electrochemical recovery and separation system (ERSS) with an ion separation module (ISM) between the anode and cathode of a water electrolysis system. During ERSS operation, protons from the anolyte flow through the anodic cation exchange membrane (CEM) into the ISM, acidifying the CO2R effluent electrolyte. Cations like K+ in the ISM flow through the cathodic CEM into the catholyte to balance the OH- ions from hydrogen evolution. ERSS recycles electrolyte-adsorbed CO2, recovers KOH with a 94.0% K+ yield, and achieves an 86.2% separation efficiency for CO2R products. The recovered KOH can capture CO2 from air or flue gas or be utilized as a CO2R electrolyte, closing the CO2 capture, conversion, and utilization loop. Compared to the conventional acid-base neutralization process, ERSS saves $119.76 per ton of KOH recovered and is applicable to other aqueous alkaline electrosynthesis reactions.</description>
      <author>Peng Wang, An Pei, Zhaoxi Chen, Pingyong Sun, Chengyi Hu, Xue Wang, Nanfeng Zheng, Guangxu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56111-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Water Content on Electrochemical CO2 Reduction in Acetonitrile Solution on Cu Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401332</link>
      <description>Connor Deacon-Price, N.Y. Chen, Ashique Lal, Pim Broersen, Evert Jan Meijer, Amanda C. Garcia, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406633235

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) on copper electrodes in acetonitrile (MeCN) solutions offers a promising route for converting CO2 into valuable products, but it competes with the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This study systematically explores the impact of varying water content in MeCN on the selectivity and efficiency of CO2RR and HER. Through cyclic voltammetry, we observe that increasing water content shifts onset potentials and Tafel slopes, indicating changes in reaction mechanisms and rate&#8208;determining steps. In dry MeCN, CO2RR is predominant due to high CO2 solubility and limited proton availability. As water content increases, HER kinetics improve significantly, eventually dominating the reaction at higher water concentrations. In situ FTIR spectroscopy and molecular dynamics simulations reveal that water preferentially adsorbs onto the copper electrode surface, enhancing the stabilization of reaction intermediates and facilitating HER. Additionally, the clustering of water in MeCN plays a crucial role in the observed reaction dynamics, with water clusters influencing the availability and reactivity of surface&#8208;bound species. These findings provide critical insights into optimizing electrochemical systems for selective CO2 reduction by controlling water content, offering a pathway for improved electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Connor Deacon-Price, N.Y. Chen, Ashique Lal, Pim Broersen, Evert Jan Meijer, Amanda C. Garcia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Approach to CO2 Emission Reduction in the Iron and Steel Industry: Research Status and Development Trends of Integrated Absorption-Mineralization Technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020702</link>
      <description>Chuanbo Zhang, Sihong Cheng, Yali Tong, Guoliang Li, Tao Yue, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406613800

                With the acceleration of global industrialization, the issue of carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions has become increasingly severe, highlighting the urgent need to develop effective CO2 capture and utilization technologies. CO2 absorption-mineralization technology, as an emerging method, can convert CO2 into solid minerals, achieving both long-term storage and emission reduction goals. This paper systematically reviews the latest research progress in CO2 absorption-mineralization technology, with a particular focus on its application potential and sustainability in the steel industry. Additionally, it summarizes the research status and optimization strategies of various monoamine and mixed amine absorbents and explores the main process technologies, reaction mechanisms, and key parameters of industrial CO2 mineralization. Through multiscale modeling analysis, the study delves into the reaction mechanisms and influencing factors of the mineralization process, providing theoretical support for the industrial application of the technology. The research indicates that CO2 absorption-mineralization technology not only effectively reduces greenhouse gas emissions but also offers raw materials for industries such as construction, thus promoting sustainable resource development. Although this technology shows good application prospects, it still faces key challenges in economic viability and technical feasibility during practical implementation. This paper aims to clarify the current research hotspots and challenges, providing theoretical and practical support for future large-scale application.</description>
      <author>Chuanbo Zhang, Sihong Cheng, Yali Tong, Guoliang Li, Tao Yue</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction with calix[8]arene/base metal platforms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2025.122554</link>
      <description>Rafael A. Castro-Blanco, Armando Berlanga&#8208;V&#225;zquez, Kitze Tzian, Marcos Flores&#8208;&#193;lamo, Iv&#225;n Castillo, Inorganica Chimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406486629

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rafael A. Castro-Blanco, Armando Berlanga&#8208;V&#225;zquez, Kitze Tzian, Marcos Flores&#8208;&#193;lamo, Iv&#225;n Castillo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2025.122554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of an Indium&#8208;based Coordination Polymer with Redox Non&#8208;Innocent Ligand for High&#8208;Efficient Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202500020</link>
      <description>Chang Liu, Linqin Wang, Hao Yang, Yunxuan Ding, Ziqi Zhao, Peili Zhang, Fei Li, Licheng Sun, Fusheng Li, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406593847

                Developing high&#8208;activity and long&#8208;term stable electrocatalysts for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) to valuable products is still a challenge. An in&#8208;depth understanding of reaction mechanisms and the structure&#8208;function relationship is required for the development of an advanced catalytic eCO2RR system. Herein, a coordination polymer of indium(III) and benzenehexathiol (BHT) was developed as an electrocatalyst (In&#8208;BHT) for eCO2RR to HCOO&#8722;, which displayed an outstanding catalytic performance over the entire pH range. However, experimental results revealed significantly different catalytic pathways in the acid and neutral/alkaline solutions, which are attributed to the influence of redox non&#8208;innocent ligands on the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS). In the acid solution, the RDS is the formation of *OCOH intermediate through the proton transfer that originates from H2O in the solution, leading to relatively sluggish kinetics. But in the neutral or alkaline solution, the thiolate groups could be protonated during the catalytic process, and such proton can attack on carbon of absorbed CO2 via an intramolecular proton transfer, promoting the formation of *OCHO intermediate, resulting in faster kinetics. Our findings revealed the pivotal roles of the redox non&#8208;innocent ligands of metal active sites for eCO2RR, providing a new idea for designing highly efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Chang Liu, Linqin Wang, Hao Yang, Yunxuan Ding, Ziqi Zhao, Peili Zhang, Fei Li, Licheng Sun, Fusheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202500020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction to liquid fuels: Mechanistic pathways and surface/interface engineering of catalysts and electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xinn.2025.100807</link>
      <description>Xueying Li, Woo-Jong Kang, Xinyi Fan, Xinyi Tan, Justus Masa, Alex W. Robertson, Yousung Jung, Buxing Han, John Texter, Yi-Wen Cheng, Bin Dai, Zhenyu Sun, The Innovation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406564174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xueying Li, Woo-Jong Kang, Xinyi Fan, Xinyi Tan, Justus Masa, Alex W. Robertson, Yousung Jung, Buxing Han, John Texter, Yi-Wen Cheng, Bin Dai, Zhenyu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xinn.2025.100807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposition of Ga-Sn thin liquid films from a deep eutectic solvent for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136232</link>
      <description>Yulan Xu, Minxian Wu, Xinlei Cheng, Shiying Wang, Dan Wang, Wenchang Wang, Naotoshi Mitsuzaki, Zhidong Chen, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406588483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yulan Xu, Minxian Wu, Xinlei Cheng, Shiying Wang, Dan Wang, Wenchang Wang, Naotoshi Mitsuzaki, Zhidong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strongly photosensitive metal-organic coordination polymers as photo-coupled electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction to formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159809</link>
      <description>Kai Cui, Pengbo Lyu, Zhao Zhang, Manchang Kou, Xinrui Yuan, Jiajia Suo, Xiaoliang Tang, Yu Tang, Weisheng Liu, Yuxi Xu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406642583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Cui, Pengbo Lyu, Zhao Zhang, Manchang Kou, Xinrui Yuan, Jiajia Suo, Xiaoliang Tang, Yu Tang, Weisheng Liu, Yuxi Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of the Hydrogen Content of CO2 Methanation Product Gas via Catalytic Ethanol Dehydration&#8211;Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04924-3</link>
      <description>Shimpei Norioka, Tomoki Uchiyama, Hirofumi Ohtsuka, Yoshiharu Uchimoto, Catalysis Letters. 155(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406549530

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shimpei Norioka, Tomoki Uchiyama, Hirofumi Ohtsuka, Yoshiharu Uchimoto</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04924-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZnIn2S4/g-C3N4 Binary Heterojunction Nanostructure for Enhancing Visible Light CO2 Reduction at the Reaction Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122380</link>
      <description>Jiyue Zhang, Yaru Lei, Jiaying Jiang, Shunzheng Zhao, Honghong Yi, Xiaolong Tang, Xiubing Huang, Yuansong Zhou, Fengyu Gao, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406549825

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiyue Zhang, Yaru Lei, Jiaying Jiang, Shunzheng Zhao, Honghong Yi, Xiaolong Tang, Xiubing Huang, Yuansong Zhou, Fengyu Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergetic Emission Reduction of VOCs and CO2 in the Automotive Coating Industry Using Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) Technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115534</link>
      <description>Wenjun Liang, Jinzhu Wang, Chenhang Zhang, Jia Liu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406602261

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjun Liang, Jinzhu Wang, Chenhang Zhang, Jia Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115534</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Contact, Open, Three-Dimensional, Real-Time Measurement of Plant CO2 Emission Reduction with a More Accurate Theory and Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/sslchinaifws64644.2024.10835339</link>
      <description>Wei Wei, Kuo&#8208;Hsing Cheng, Yangyang Liu, Qian Fang, Qian Li, Kuang Yuhan, You Wu, Yuxin Tong, Mingming Shi, Dong Zhenfen, Song Jinde, Jun Zou, Zhang Guo&#8208;Yi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406460455

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wei, Kuo&#8208;Hsing Cheng, Yangyang Liu, Qian Fang, Qian Li, Kuang Yuhan, You Wu, Yuxin Tong, Mingming Shi, Dong Zhenfen, Song Jinde, Jun Zou, Zhang Guo&#8208;Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/sslchinaifws64644.2024.10835339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuO and La0.75Sr0.25Cr0.5Mn0.5O3-&#948; nanoparticles modified Sr2Fe1.5Mo0.5O6-&#948; perovskite cathodes for CO2 reduction in solid oxide electrolysis cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178705</link>
      <description>Wanting Tan, Siliang Zhao, Hui Song, P. Hu, Jiabin Wang, Zhaoyu Qi, Wenjie Li, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406444790

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wanting Tan, Siliang Zhao, Hui Song, P. Hu, Jiabin Wang, Zhaoyu Qi, Wenjie Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating CO2 Reduction Selectivity over Multi-Metal Electrocatalysts Derived from 0D Alloyed Halide Perovskite Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110684</link>
      <description>Ming Zhou, Dianxing Ju, Wen&#8208;Kui Dong, Guangrui Xu, Xinfa Wei, Huifang Li, Jian Liu, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406596598

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming Zhou, Dianxing Ju, Wen&#8208;Kui Dong, Guangrui Xu, Xinfa Wei, Huifang Li, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly performance polybenzimidazole/zirconia composite membrane with loosened chain packing for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis and electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131675</link>
      <description>Xinyu Li, Zhi Qiu, Yanbin Yun, Min He, Lihua Wang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406450406

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyu Li, Zhi Qiu, Yanbin Yun, Min He, Lihua Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the in-situ engineered mixed metal oxides anchored on activated carbon cloth as a flexible electrode material for electrochemical reduction of CO2 into formic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01260</link>
      <description>Hemavathi Manjunath, Chob Singh, Allwin Sudhakaran, Rey Eliseo C. Torrejos, Mohd Nor Faiz Norrrahim, Akshaya K. Samal, Arvind H. Jadhav, Sustainable materials and technologies. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406570421

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hemavathi Manjunath, Chob Singh, Allwin Sudhakaran, Rey Eliseo C. Torrejos, Mohd Nor Faiz Norrrahim, Akshaya K. Samal, Arvind H. Jadhav</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixation Of Single Cobalt-Substituted Keggin Xw11co (X = Si, P, Co) Polyoxoanions into Zif-8 Cavities For Boosting Electrochemical Reduction of Co2 To Co Via A Synthetic Encapsulation Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5104659</link>
      <description>Can Li, Yan Zhang, Lei Shu, Yun&#8208;Lei Teng, Y WANG, Bao&#8208;Xia Dong, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406607351

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Can Li, Yan Zhang, Lei Shu, Yun&#8208;Lei Teng, Y WANG, Bao&#8208;Xia Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5104659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Tourism, Foreign Direct Investment, Trade, Economic Growth, and Renewable Energy on Carbon Emissions: The Case of Mediterranean Countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.70908/2232-6022/17.313-337</link>
      <description>Younesse El Menyari, International Journal of Euro-Mediterranean Studies. 17(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406530139

                In this study, we examine the influence of international tourism, trade, foreign direct investment, economic growth and renewable energy consumption on CO2 emissions in 17 Mediterranean countries, spanning the period 1995&#8211;2018, by using heterogeneous panel estimation techniques. The findings show that economic growth has a strong impact on carbon dioxide emissions. Our results are in favor of the existence of an inverted U-shaped Environmental Kuznets curve (EKC) in Mediterranean countries. In addition, the econometric results indicate that international tourism, trade openness, FDI, and renewable energy consumption have a negative impact on carbon dioxide emissions. Moreover, the Dumitrescu and Hurlin panel Granger causality test suggests that there is a two-way causality between CO2 emissions and the other variables explored (international tourism, openness, FDI, renewable energy consumption and real income) and a oneway causality running from renewable energy consumption and trade openness to real income. Therefore, the development of international trade in the field of renewable energies and the exploitation of theseenergies in the field of tourism and FDI can be favorable to economic growth and the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions.</description>
      <author>Younesse El Menyari</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.70908/2232-6022/17.313-337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ELECTRIFICATION OF A HEAVY-DUTY OFF-ROAD MATERIAL HANDLER: ENERGY SAVINGS AND EMISSION REDUCTIONS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37099/mtu.dc.etdr/1843</link>
      <description>Bryant Goodenough, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406456609

                Federal regulations are driving the adoption of electrification technologies to reduce carbon dioxide equivalent (CO2e) emissions, a metric that quantifies the global warming potential of various greenhouse gases in terms of carbon dioxide (CO2). Although no specific CO2 regulations exist for heavy-duty off-road machines, future reductions are likely, given stricter emissions standards for on-road vehicles. The heavy-duty off-road sector offers significant fuel-saving potential, as its focus has traditionally been on reliability and performance rather than fuel efficiency. This dissertation examines fuel and CO2e savings opportunities on a heavy-duty off-road material handler, the Pettibone Cary-Lift 204i, from stock configuration to simple modifications to a complete teardown and reconfiguration of the machine with a plug-in series hybrid architecture using electrified hydraulics.</description>
      <author>Bryant Goodenough</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37099/mtu.dc.etdr/1843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of gas impurities on CO2 storage in depleted oil field with carbonate reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31705/iserme.2024.40</link>
      <description>A. Muer, Yogarajah Elakneswaran, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406483725

                The carbon dioxide capture and storage (CCS) is considered as a promising technology for carbon dioxide emission reduction. High-purity CO2 mixture gas is separated from the flue gas and pumped into underground for a long-term storage. The impurities of gas can affect the trapping mechanisms. Various research studies about how impurity changes permeability were carried out. However, the effect of impurities in long-term trapping mechanisms is still unclear. This research studies the effects of H2S, SO2, and NO2 in CCS for a long-term period of 2000 years using a PHREEQC geochemical simulator. The simulation presents formation water and rock samples from the previous research and the mixture gas groups to emphasis the effect of each impurity. The simulation contains two parts: the equilibrium block and the kinetics block. The former is to simulate the reversible reaction between the pure phases and the aqueous phase, which is defined by the equilibrium constant and dependent on the temperature. The latter is to simulate how phases react by time defined by kinetics rate, which is defined by the Arrhenius equation and depends on the pH, temperature, surface area and other reaction condition constants. Firstly, the gas and formation water are input into the equilibrium block to get CO2 enriched solution and remaining gas components. Then, the remaining gas and solution and mineralogy are put into the kinetics block. Results indicate a shift from mineral trapping to solubility trapping in the presence of impurities, with a significant decrease in pH affecting CO2 storage ratios. Furthermore, the changes in each mineralogy and the effects of each impurity are discussed</description>
      <author>A. Muer, Yogarajah Elakneswaran</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31705/iserme.2024.40</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital finance, institutional quality, and carbon dioxide emissions in Africa</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/17565529.2025.2452435</link>
      <description>Emmanuel Konadu-Yiadom, Daniel Domeher, Kingsley Opoku Appiah, Joseph Magnus Frimpong, Climate and Development. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406489201

                The impact of digital finance on carbon dioxide emissions has generated conflicting findings, with some studies suggesting emissions reduction while others point to the contrary. To gain clarity amidst this contradictory evidence, examining the moderating role of institutional quality is crucial. This research delved into the intricate relationship between digital finance, institutional quality, and CO2 emissions across 45 African countries from 2004 to 2021. By employing the dynamic system-generalized method of moment (sys-GMM) technique, the study revealed a positive relationship between digital finance and CO2 emissions. However, a key discovery emerged as the analysis considered the moderating role of institutional quality. The results highlighted the significant decrease in CO2 emissions that results from the interaction between institutional quality and digital finance. Furthermore, there is a critical point at which well-established institutions start to offset the environmental consequences associated with digital finance. The positive impact of digital finance on emissions is mitigated when institutions reach a certain threshold level of quality.</description>
      <author>Emmanuel Konadu-Yiadom, Daniel Domeher, Kingsley Opoku Appiah, Joseph Magnus Frimpong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/17565529.2025.2452435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol by Cu Interacting with Isolated Zn Cations in Zincosilicate CIT-6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07496</link>
      <description>Yu Gao, Yonghui Fan, Hao Zhang, Peerapol Pornsetmetakul, Brahim Mezari, Jorden Wagemakers, M. Ramakrishnan, Konstantin Klementiev, Nikolay Kosinov, Emiel J. M. Hensen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406493338

                The catalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) to methanol over Cu/ZnO catalysts is expected to become valuable for recycling CO2. The nature of the Cu&#8211;Zn interplay remains a subject of intense debate due to many different Zn species encountered in Cu/ZnO catalysts. In this study, we designed a Cu&#8211;Zn catalyst by ion-exchanging Cu into CIT-6, a crystalline microporous zincosilicate with the BEA* topology. The catalyst exhibited high and stable CO2 hydrogenation rate to methanol. In contrast, its aluminosilicate counterparts Cu-Beta and CuZn-Beta mainly converted CO2 to CO. Operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy combined with X-ray diffraction confirmed the stability of Zn cations in the zincosilicate framework during reduction in H2 and reaction in CO2/H2. The active phase consisted of highly dispersed Cu particles. These particles located near isolated Zn2+ species represent a different type of active site for methanol synthesis than the active phases proposed for Cu&#8211;Zn catalysts, such as Cu&#8211;Zn alloy particles and Cu particles decorated with ZnOx. In situ IR spectroscopy showed the formation of Zn-formate species during CO2 hydrogenation, indicating that Zn2+ ions stabilize formate as a reaction intermediate in the hydrogenation of CO2 to methanol.</description>
      <author>Yu Gao, Yonghui Fan, Hao Zhang, Peerapol Pornsetmetakul, Brahim Mezari, Jorden Wagemakers, M. Ramakrishnan, Konstantin Klementiev, Nikolay Kosinov, Emiel J. M. Hensen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process simulation for biogas upgrading and biomethane recovery using biofilm-based reactors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3384/ecp212.037</link>
      <description>Vafa Ahmadi, Aryan Bhusal, Gamunu L Samarakoon Arachchige, Nabin Aryal, Link&#246;ping electronic conference proceedings. 211(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406473498

                Microbial biofilm matrices offer numerous benefits in bioprocessing and are crucial in various industrial and remediation processes. They facilitate electron exchange from solid surfaces when they interact with the environment. Emerging technologies such as biofilm-containing trickle bed reactors (TBR) and bioelectrochemical systems (BESs) for carbon dioxide (CO2) utilization, mostly rely on microbial biofilm matrices. Metabolic modeling of biofilm-based reactors enables detailed analysis of CO2 reduction within microorganisms, enhancing reactor efficiency. This study employed simulation models to analyze biomethane synthesis within TBR and BES systems. AQUASIM simulation tool was used for conducting the simulation. Parameters such as non-stoichiometric and stoichiometric ratios of substrates, hydraulic retention time (HRT), biofilm surface area, and applied voltage in BES were varied to evaluate methane (CH4) production and microbial biomass growth in TBR and BES. Results demonstrated that 1 day HRT resulted in methanation process failure due to biomass development problem in both TBR and BES. The substrate ratio 1:4 of CO2 to H2 increased CH4 production in the investigated reactors. In BES, in-situ CO2 and proton (H+) generation from oxidation reactions can increase CH4 production. Whereas in TBR, external H2 (hydrogen) should be supplied to consume higher amount of CO2. The lag phase in TBR was shorter than that in BES because of the greater surface area in TBR. In BES, higher voltage increased the current generation because of development of more biomass on the cathode. The simulation underlines the influence of different variables on biofilm-based reactors, offering critical insights for experimental process design.</description>
      <author>Vafa Ahmadi, Aryan Bhusal, Gamunu L Samarakoon Arachchige, Nabin Aryal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3384/ecp212.037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic relationships between environment-related technologies, agricultural value added, transport infrastructure and environmental emissions in the five most populous countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-86451-8</link>
      <description>Yinuo Wang, Arshad Ali, Zhaojie Chen, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406598000

                Densely populated countries have higher demand for agricultural products and greater use of fuel and vehicles, resulting in higher environmental emissions, so this study considers transportation infrastructure and the agricultural sector as the two major drivers of environmental degradation in the top five densely populated countries. In a baseline regression, this study first unveils the impact of investments in transportation infrastructure, agricultural value addition, and environment-related technologies on per capita CO2 emissions using CS-ARDL approach from 1990 to 2021 in the five most populous countries. Besides, this study also reveals the typical moderating effect of environment-related technologies in the link between transport infrastructure, agricultural value added and environmental hazards. The results of the baseline model indicate that transport infrastructure and agricultural value added can substantially contribute to per capita carbon emissions in both the short and long term. However, environment-related technologies significantly reduce environmental emissions in both the short and long term. Per capita GDP extensively promotes per capita carbon dioxide emissions, while per capita GDP2 substantially reduces per capita carbon dioxide emissions in the long term rather than the short term, thus authenticating the inverted U-shaped EKC hypothesis for the top five countries with the highest population density. The moderating effect of environment-related technologies shows that the application of environment-related technologies in both transportation and agriculture can alleviate environmental pollution. Finally, the threshold level of environment-related technologies shows that as environment-related technologies move from lower threshold levels (&#8804; &#8722; 1.05) to higher threshold levels (&gt; -1.05), agricultural value added and transportation infrastructure investment significantly improve the reduction of environmental contamination. The goal of environmental sustainability can be ensured by the adoption of environment-related technologies in agriculture and transportation sectors.</description>
      <author>Yinuo Wang, Arshad Ali, Zhaojie Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-86451-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of Characteristics, Methane Generated and Sustainability of Municipal Landfill Waste in Urban City, Thailand</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling10010015</link>
      <description>Yaowatat Boongla, Supachai Changphuek, Anuwat Saehuang, Recycling. 10(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406628754

                Many developed and developing countries are concerned about climate change and greenhouse gas (GHG) reduction, with landfills being a major contributor due to the presence of important GHGs such as carbon dioxide (CO2) and methane (CH4) in landfill emissions. The appropriate technology or suitable innovation could result in the extraction of significant amounts of energy from CH4 in landfills. This work used landfill gas emissions (LandGEM) software modeling to analyze the distribution patterns of the gas emissions of two urban landfills in Chonburi and Phuket Provinces, Thailand, from 2013 to 2023. The methane emissions from the Chonburi landfill were 1.063 &#215; 104 Mg/year, and they were 1.077 &#215; 103 Mg/year for the Phuket landfill, in 2023. According to estimates, the Chonburi landfill emitted 2.916 &#215; 104 Mg/year of CO2 in 2023, while Phuket emitted 2.955 &#215; 103 Mg/year. The Chonburi landfill generated 8.67 MWh/year and 195.74 MWh/year of electrical energy potential from CH4 in 2014 and 2023. In 2014 and 2023, the electrical energy potential from CH4 was 1.00 MWh/year and 19.83 MWh/year for the Phuket landfill. This study&#8217;s results show that landfills can produce CH4 and that it is possible to collect this gas and stop GHG emissions from entering the atmosphere. This would be beneficial for local authorities considering the potential of landfill gas.</description>
      <author>Yaowatat Boongla, Supachai Changphuek, Anuwat Saehuang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling10010015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing the efficiency of bioreactor operation for cultivation of methane-oxidizing bacteria under conditions of decreasing carbon dioxide concentration in the cultural liquid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32362/2410-6593-2024-19-6-508-516</link>
      <description>&#1042;. &#1052;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1095;&#1077;&#1090;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1048;. &#1057;. &#1043;&#1072;&#1075;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, D. V. Tolkin, V. V. Kochetkov, P. A. Nyunkov, Fine Chemical Technologies. 19(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406591087

                Objectives . The work set out to develop a bioreactor that incorporates a carbon dioxide removal unit within the apparatus gas phase, which is capable of operating without the need for supplementary compression apparatus. As part of testing the developed equipment in order to ascertain its capacity for enhanced biomass production, the principal fermentation system parameters that facilitate the optimal bioreactor productivity in conditions of carbon dioxide removal from the apparatus gas phase were identified. Methods . A series of tests were conducted on the fermentation unit with the objective of controlling the oxygen and carbon dioxide content in the gas phase of the bioreactor. This was achieved using an in-line gas analyzer fitted with electrochemical sensors. The oxygen and carbon dioxide content in the gas phase was determined by means of gas chromatography. The oxygen and natural gas flow rates were determined using a thermal electronic flow controller equipped with thermoresistive elements. The oxygen content of the cultural liquid was determined by means of an optical oxygen sensor with integrated transducer. The pH level in the bioreactor was monitored and maintained using an electrochemical pH sensor. Results . The efficacy of the newly devised jet-type bioreactor design, which permits the incorporation of a carbon dioxide removal unit into the fermentation system without requiring supplementary compression apparatus, was evaluated through experimentation. The system was tested with the carbon dioxide removal unit included in the design, resulting in a 64% increase in bioreactor productivity and a 18% reduction in oxygen consumption as a component of the gas supply. Conclusions . The operational parameters of a technological bioreactor that facilitate a stable continuous process of bacterial cultivation were identified.</description>
      <author>&#1042;. &#1052;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1095;&#1077;&#1090;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1048;. &#1057;. &#1043;&#1072;&#1075;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, D. V. Tolkin, V. V. Kochetkov, P. A. Nyunkov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32362/2410-6593-2024-19-6-508-516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical and Chemical Methods for Mitigating Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202560603001</link>
      <description>Yuhang Wu, E3S Web of Conferences. 606(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406630817

                The greenhouse effect caused by greenhouse gases, especially carbon dioxide emissions, has become a central issue in global environmental governance. Traditional emission reduction strategies, although effective, are difficult to meet global climate goals. In response, the scientific community has begun to explore new technologies for capturing, separating, storing and utilizing carbon dioxide through physical and chemical means. These technologies offer potential avenues for greenhouse gas (GHG) management, but still face technical, economic, and environmental challenges before large-scale application. This study systematically evaluates the progress of the application of these physical and chemical means in carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) treatment, and discusses in depth the technical bottlenecks and future improvement directions by analyzing the advantages and disadvantages of each technology. It is hoped that this study provides a valuable theoretical basis and practical reference for the development and application of future large-scale CO 2 abatement technologies.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202560603001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-induced Changes in the Electrocatalytic Activity of Atomically Precise Au&#8322;&#8325; Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc07181f</link>
      <description>Lipan Luo, Xia Zhou, Yuping Chen, Fang Sun, Likai Wang, Qing Tang, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406598092

                Atomically precise gold nanoclusters have shown great promise as model elctrocatalysts in pivotal electrocatalytic processes such as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). Although the influence...</description>
      <author>Lipan Luo, Xia Zhou, Yuping Chen, Fang Sun, Likai Wang, Qing Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc07181f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on carbon dioxide treatment and utilization technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202560603003</link>
      <description>K. Chen, E3S Web of Conferences. 606(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406630739

                This paper summarizes the various types of carbon dioxide treatment technology, the current situation, and the development trend, and describes the progress and challenges in the application of carbon dioxide treatment technology at the present stage. It is found that the focus of research and development should be on improving carbon capture efficiency and reducing carbon capture costs. CO 2 utilization technology is currently in the industrial demonstration stage, and breaking through the bottleneck of high temperature and high pressure environment, and searching for suitable catalysts to improve the carbon utilization efficiency are the key research directions in the next stage of CO 2 utilization technology. CO 2 treatment technology needs to overcome the challenges of economic profitability, technological innovation, cost reduction and efficiency enhancement, and policy subsidies and incentives. CO 2 bioprocessing technology will become a new mode of CO 2 treatment promotion in the future. This study is of reference significance for accurately grasping the research direction of CO 2 treatment technology, promoting the progress and innovation of CO 2 treatment technology, and accelerating the leapfrog development of CO 2 treatment technology.</description>
      <author>K. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202560603003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A low-carbon economic scheduling of power systems considering marginal carbon emission factor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2935/1/012027</link>
      <description>Wan-Sheng Su, Feixiong Chen, Zhenguo Shao, Tianhao Huang, Hongbin Wu, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2935(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406529064

                Abstract The energy sector contributes significantly to carbon dioxide emissions, and speeding up the shift to a low-carbon power system is essential for tackling global warming. This paper introduces a method for low-carbon economic scheduling that considers the marginal carbon emission factor to improve carbon reduction. First, the marginal carbon emission factor encourages users to adjust their energy plans. A demand response model for pre-scheduling and rescheduling within the grid is developed using price-based strategies. Second, a two-stage model is created to optimize low-carbon scheduling and minimize overall system costs. The method&#8217;s effectiveness is demonstrated using the IEEE39-node grid.</description>
      <author>Wan-Sheng Su, Feixiong Chen, Zhenguo Shao, Tianhao Huang, Hongbin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2935/1/012027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential therapeutic applications of medical gases in cancer treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4103/mgr.medgasres-d-24-00089</link>
      <description>Abbas Al Bazzal, Bassel H. Hoteit, Mariam Chokor, Abdallah Safawi, Zahraa Zibara, Fatima Rizk, Aya Kawssan, Naseeb Danaf, Layal Msheik, Hiba Hamdar, Medical Gas Research. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406598662

                Medical gases were primarily used for respiratory therapy and anesthesia, which showed promising potential in the cancer therapy. Several physiological and pathological processes were affected by the key gases, such as oxygen, carbon dioxide, nitric oxide, hydrogen sulfide, and carbon monoxide. Oxygen targets shrinking the tumor via hyperbaric oxygen therapy, and once combined with radiation therapy it enhances its effect. Nitric oxide has both anti- and pro-tumor effects depending on its level; at high doses, it triggers cell death while at low doses it supports cancer growth. The same concept is applied to hydrogen sulfide which promotes cancer growth by enhancing mitochondrial bioenergetics and supporting angiogenesis at low concentrations, while at high concentrations it induces cancer cell death while sparing normal cells. Furthermore, carbon dioxide helps induce apoptosis and improve oxygenation for cancer treatments by increasing the release of oxygen from hemoglobin. Moreover, high-dose carbon monoxide gas therapy has demonstrated significant tumor reductions in vivo and is supported by nanomedicine and specialized medicines to boost its delivery to tumor cells and the availability of hydrogen peroxide. Despite the promising potentials of these gases, several challenges remain. Gas concentrations should be regulated to balance pro-tumor and anti-tumor effects for gases such as nitric oxide and hydrogen sulfide. Furthermore, effective delivery systems, such as nanoparticles, should be developed for targeted therapy.</description>
      <author>Abbas Al Bazzal, Bassel H. Hoteit, Mariam Chokor, Abdallah Safawi, Zahraa Zibara, Fatima Rizk, Aya Kawssan, Naseeb Danaf, Layal Msheik, Hiba Hamdar</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4103/mgr.medgasres-d-24-00089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Ni&#8208;N&#8208;C Catalysts for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412162</link>
      <description>John Weiss, Yanghua He, David A. Cullen, Angelica Benavidez, Jeremy Jernigen, Hanguang Zhang, Luigi Osmieri, Piotr Zelenay, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406542585

                Abstract The atomic dispersion of nickel in Ni&#8208;N&#8208;C catalysts is key for the selective generation of carbon monoxide through the electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR). Herein, the study reports a highly selective, atomically dispersed Ni 1.0% &#8208;N&#8208;C catalyst with reduced Ni loading compared to previous reports. Extensive materials characterization fails to detect Ni crystalline phases, reveals the highest concentration of atomically dispersed Ni metal, and confirms the presence of the proposed Ni&#8208;N x active site at this reduced loading. The catalyst shows excellent activity and selectivity toward CO generation, with a faradaic efficiency for CO generation (FE CO ) of 97% and partial current density for CO (j co ) of &#8208;9.0 mA cm &#8722;2 at &#8208;0.9 V in an electrochemical H&#8208;type cell. CO 2 RR activity and selectivity are also studied by rotating disk electrode (RDE) measurements where transport limitations can be suppressed. It is expected that the utility of these Ni&#8208;N&#8208;C catalysts will lie with tandem CO 2 RR reaction schemes to multi&#8208;carbon (C 2+ ) products.</description>
      <author>John Weiss, Yanghua He, David A. Cullen, Angelica Benavidez, Jeremy Jernigen, Hanguang Zhang, Luigi Osmieri, Piotr Zelenay</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Enhanced Oil Recovery in Reservoirs with Advanced Wells: Simulations and Sensitivity Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3384/ecp212.020</link>
      <description>Isu Uchechukwu Agha, Nora C. I. S. Furuvik, Soheila Taghavi, Link&#246;ping electronic conference proceedings. 211(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406473132

                Injection of CO2 for enhanced oil recovery (CO2-EOR) is used in fields with high amount of residual oil. CO2-EOR refers to a technology where supercritical CO2 is injected into an oil reservoir to increase the oil production. Utilizing autonomous inflow control valves (AICVs) in CO2-EOR projects contributes to a better distribution of CO2 in the reservoir, reduction in production of water and CO2 mixture, and thereby increased storage capacity of CO2. The main objective of this study is modelling and simulation of oil production from an oil reservoir using CO2 water alternating gas (CO2 WAG) injection in combination with advanced wells that are completed with AICVs. The results from the simulations indicate that well completion with AICV can maintain good oil production while the production of water is decreased from 3e+06 m3 to 9.8e+04 m3 which corresponds to 97% reduction in water production. The sensitivity analysis of the simulation results affirms that permeability, well placement, and well spacing have impact on oil recovery and water production. The results indicate that permeability increase has a slight increment effect on oil recovery. The well spacing analysis shows that increasing the distance between the wells will increase the oil recovery and delay the water breakthrough. Lastly the well placement analysis shows that vertical injection of miscible CO2 produces more oil than horizontal injection of miscible CO2. AICVs restrict the production of mixture of CO2 and water, and thereby cause a better distribution of CO2 in the reservoir.</description>
      <author>Isu Uchechukwu Agha, Nora C. I. S. Furuvik, Soheila Taghavi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3384/ecp212.020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding How the Interfacial Properties of ALD&#8208;rafted In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Thin Films Promote Enhanced Formate Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404178</link>
      <description>J&#228;ri Van den Hoek, Femi Mathew, Lieven Hintjens, Brend de Coen, Eduardo Solano, Matthias Minjauw, Nick Daems, Daniel Choukroun, Christophe Detavernier, Jolien Dendooven, Tom Breugelmans, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406544511

                Abstract The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (eCO 2 R) to formate is a promising technology for CO 2 utilization and potential industrial application. Despite extensive research on catalyst layer design, interpreting performance is often hindered by the complexity of composite layers. In this study, plasma&#8208;enhanced and thermal Atomic Layer Deposition (ALD) are employed to fabricate In 2 S 3 thin films on gas diffusion electrodes, creating model catalyst layers without ionomers or binders. The uniform ALD films enables fine&#8208;tuning of hydrophobicity, underscoring its critical role at the triple&#8208;phase boundary (TPB) and enhancing formate production via eCO 2 R at high current densities. For example, a thermal ALD&#8208;deposited In 2 S 3 thin film (150 &#181;g cm &#8722;2 ) achieved a formate Faradaic efficiency of 93% at 1 A cm &#8722;2 . The system exhibits high selectivity, with minimal hydrogen evolution and carbon monoxide as the sole by&#8208;product, facilitating the determination of key electrokinetic parameters such as exchange and limiting current densities. Reaction kinetic modeling further clarified the influence of hydrophobicity on these parameters. This work provides valuable insights into the role of interfacial properties in electrocatalysis, advancing the development of efficient electrocatalysts and processes for industrial formate production.</description>
      <author>J&#228;ri Van den Hoek, Femi Mathew, Lieven Hintjens, Brend de Coen, Eduardo Solano, Matthias Minjauw, Nick Daems, Daniel Choukroun, Christophe Detavernier, Jolien Dendooven, Tom Breugelmans</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting C&#8208;O Bond Cleavage and Reverse Water&#8208;Gas Shift Activity via Enriched in&#8208;plane Sulfur Vacancies in Single&#8208;Layer Molybdenum Disulfide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422953</link>
      <description>Zhiyuan Zheng, Xin Shang, Weijue Wang, Xiaofeng Yang, Xiong Su, Yanqiang Huang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406555872

                The reduction of CO2 to CO provides a promising approach to the production of valuable chemicals through CO2 utilization. However, challenges persist with the rapid deactivation and insufficient activity of catalysts. Herein, we developed a soft&#8208;hard dual&#8208;template method to synthesize layered MoS2 using inexpensive and scalable templates, enabling facile regulation of sulfur vacancies by controlling the number of layers. The concentration of in&#8208;plane vacancies keeps increasing with the reduction of MoS2 layer number, contributing to 100% CO selectivity over single&#8208;layer MoS2 and a stable performance over 300&#8208;hour reaction at 600 &#176;C. The space&#8208;time&#8208;yield of CO reached 35.7 gCO gcat&#8208;1 h&#8208;1, outperforming most current catalysts. Multiple characterizations and theoretical calculations revealed that in&#8208;plane sulfur vacancy sites endowed enhanced production of CO via direct dissociation of CO2, showing an intrinsic activity of above 5.8 times higher than that of edge sulfur vacancy sites. The rate&#8208;limiting step was shifted from C&#8208;O cleavage in edge to sulfur vacancy regeneration in plane with a lower energy barrier. Our findings exemplified the specified design and synthesis of MoS2 for high&#8208;temperature CO2 reduction through the effective manipulation of distinct vacancy sites, shedding light on their potential industrial application.</description>
      <author>Zhiyuan Zheng, Xin Shang, Weijue Wang, Xiaofeng Yang, Xiong Su, Yanqiang Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting C&#8208;O Bond Cleavage and Reverse Water&#8208;Gas Shift Activity via Enriched in&#8208;plane Sulfur Vacancies in Single&#8208;Layer Molybdenum Disulfide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422953</link>
      <description>Zhiyuan Zheng, Xin Shang, Weijue Wang, Xiaofeng Yang, Xiong Su, Yanqiang Huang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406556056

                The reduction of CO2 to CO provides a promising approach to the production of valuable chemicals through CO2 utilization. However, challenges persist with the rapid deactivation and insufficient activity of catalysts. Herein, we developed a soft&#8208;hard dual&#8208;template method to synthesize layered MoS2 using inexpensive and scalable templates, enabling facile regulation of sulfur vacancies by controlling the number of layers. The concentration of in&#8208;plane vacancies keeps increasing with the reduction of MoS2 layer number, contributing to 100% CO selectivity over single&#8208;layer MoS2 and a stable performance over 300&#8208;hour reaction at 600 &#176;C. The space&#8208;time&#8208;yield of CO reached 35.7 gCO gcat&#8208;1 h&#8208;1, outperforming most current catalysts. Multiple characterizations and theoretical calculations revealed that in&#8208;plane sulfur vacancy sites endowed enhanced production of CO via direct dissociation of CO2, showing an intrinsic activity of above 5.8 times higher than that of edge sulfur vacancy sites. The rate&#8208;limiting step was shifted from C&#8208;O cleavage in edge to sulfur vacancy regeneration in plane with a lower energy barrier. Our findings exemplified the specified design and synthesis of MoS2 for high&#8208;temperature CO2 reduction through the effective manipulation of distinct vacancy sites, shedding light on their potential industrial application.</description>
      <author>Zhiyuan Zheng, Xin Shang, Weijue Wang, Xiaofeng Yang, Xiong Su, Yanqiang Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and Properties of Poly(Butylene Adipate&#8208;Co&#8208;Terephthalate)/Soybean Isolate Protein Composites With a Special Interface Structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/app.56738</link>
      <description>Yazhou Yi, Kui Jian, Yaqing Zhang, Ningning Wei, Mingtian Ren, Qiangxian Wu, Journal of Applied Polymer Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406543803

                ABSTRACT It will significantly reduce carbon dioxide emissions by incorporating natural polymers into eco&#8208;friendly composites. Improving compatibility in eco&#8208;friendly composites is essential for enhancing their mechanical properties for broad applications. In this study, we synthesized a unique structured polyurethane prepolymer (PBAPU) and utilized it as a compatibilizer. We then mixed varying amounts of PBAPU with PBAT and SPI to produce a series of PBAT/SPI composites and subsequently investigated their structure and properties. The PBAT/SPI composites, with the addition of 15% compatibilizer, saw their tensile elongation increase by 207% and their impact strength improve by 236%, showing that the addition of PBAPU enhanced the mechanical properties of the composites. Furthermore, the scanning electron microscopy images revealed a reduction in cracks and gaps at the PBAT/SPI interface, with a more uniform dispersion, indicating a significant enhancement in the compatibility of the composites. The strong urethane linkage interactions between the PBAPU interfacial layer and SPI, as well as the crystalline PBA&#8208;PBA interactions between the PBAPU interfacial layer and the PBAT matrix, are the reasons for the improved compatibility of the PBAT/SPI composites. Therefore, incorporating PBAPU with a special structure enhances the compatibility and performance of the PBAT/SPI composites.</description>
      <author>Yazhou Yi, Kui Jian, Yaqing Zhang, Ningning Wei, Mingtian Ren, Qiangxian Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/app.56738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoscale Cu&#8211;Ag Heterostructures for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06338</link>
      <description>Siying Zhang, Bowen Zhang, Shuaibing Yang, Tao Shao, Xiaohan Li, Rong Cao, Minna Cao, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406515584

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) to value-added chemicals represents a critical strategy for mitigating carbon emissions and promoting energy sustainability. This study focuses on enhancing the CO2 reduction performance of copper-based catalysts through silver doping, with the specific objective of improving C2+ product selectivity and suppressing C1 products. We report the delicate synthesis of three distinct CuAg Janus nanostructures using a coreduction method involving metal precursors for nucleation and growth. Compared to Cu NPs, CuAg Janus 1:0.02 exhibits significantly superior selectivity for both C2H4 (&#8764;50%) and multicarbon products (&#8764;70%) at &#8722;1.2 V vs RHE in CO2RR. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis reveals that the CuAg Janus nanostructure facilitates an electron transfer process, significantly influencing the catalytic activity and product selectivity of the CO2 reduction reaction. In-situ attenuated total reflectance Fourier transform infrared (ATR-FTIR) spectroscopy spectra indicate that CuAg Janus nanoparticles promote the formation of *CHO and *COCHO, which are key intermediates in the production of C2H4 and enhancement of C&#8211;C coupling. This study provides an effective strategy for designing advanced tandem catalysts, paving the way for the widespread application of the CO2RR in addressing environmental and energy challenges.</description>
      <author>Siying Zhang, Bowen Zhang, Shuaibing Yang, Tao Shao, Xiaohan Li, Rong Cao, Minna Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Confinement Effects on the Dynamical Aspects of CO Oxidation over Pt(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06593</link>
      <description>Nidhi Tiwari, Sandip Ghosh, Ashwani K. Tiwari, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406465179

                This study investigates the effects of two-dimensional (2D) confinement on CO oxidation reaction over Pt(111) surfaces, emphasizing the structural, electronic, and dynamical aspects of CO2 formation and desorption. Using pristine and single-defect hexagonal boron nitride (h-BN) and graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) as overlayers, we found that confinement by nitrogen-vacancy h-BN (NV) induces a significant reduction, greater than that of graphene (Gr), in the activation energy barrier for CO2 formation. The confinement effect on adsorption depends on the reference states chosen for adsorption energy calculations. Reference states, such as stable or original intersurface gaps, can yield either positive or negative confinement energy values, indicating adsorption weakening or strengthening, respectively. Importantly, adsorption weakening correlates better with barrier reduction. Post-transition-state dynamical simulations of CO2 desorption revealed pronounced vibrational oscillations. NV and Gr confinement led to complex vibrational features, indicating stronger interactions between CO2 and the 2D cover. This study highlights the profound impact of 2D confinement on catalytic processes, providing insights into how 2D materials modulate the electronic structure and vibrational dynamics of reactions. The findings could guide the design of efficient catalysts for industrial applications, particularly in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Nidhi Tiwari, Sandip Ghosh, Ashwani K. Tiwari</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;Cu&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&#8221; Site-Driven Selectivity Switch for Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18450</link>
      <description>Xinyue Ma, Jie Shao, Baoguang Mao, Fenghui Ye, Zichun Wang, Junjie Mao, Aibing Chen, Dan Wang, Lipeng Zhang, Hui Dong, Husitu Lin, Ning Li, Chuangang Hu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406606737

                The comprehensive understanding of the effect of the chemical environment surrounding active sites on the pathway for the electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (eCO2RR) is essential for the development of advanced catalysts for large-scale applications. Based on a series of model catalysts engineered by the coordination of copper ions with various isomers of phenylenediamine [i.e., o-phenylenediamine (oPD), m-phenylenediamine (mPD), and p-phenylenediamine (pPD)] featuring two amino groups in ortho-, meta-, and para-positions, the steric effects could significantly govern the selectivity of the "Cu&#8211;N" sites for eCO2RR. It was found the steric distance between adjacent copper and nitrogen active sites in Cu-oPD enhanced the C&#8211;C coupling of the *COOH intermediate, thereby resulting in increased selectivity for C2H4 production. In contrast, the weak van der Waals interactions arising from steric electrostatic effects surrounding the *CHO intermediate on Cu-pPD facilitated subsequent hydrogenation, leading to the preferential synthesis of CH4. However, Cu-mPD exhibited diminished eCO2RR activity due to a higher free energy associated with the rate-determining step, which primarily led to the formation of H2. This study underscores the significant role of a steric effect-driven selectivity switch for eCO2RR.</description>
      <author>Xinyue Ma, Jie Shao, Baoguang Mao, Fenghui Ye, Zichun Wang, Junjie Mao, Aibing Chen, Dan Wang, Lipeng Zhang, Hui Dong, Husitu Lin, Ning Li, Chuangang Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sun-simulated-driven production of high-purity methanol from carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56101-8</link>
      <description>Jiqing Jiao, Yanbin Ma, Xiaoqian Han, Awu Ergu, Chao Zhang, Pingping Chen, Wei Liu, Qiquan Luo, Zhaolin Shi, Han Xu, Chen Chen, Yaguang Li, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406614382

                CO2 conversion to CH3OH under mild conditions is of particular interest yet rather challenging. Both electro- and thermo-catalytic CO2 reduction to CH3OH can only produce CH3OH in low concentration (typically mixed with water), requiring energy-intensive purification processes. Here we design a sun-simulated-driven tandem catalytic system comprising CO2 electroreduction to syngas, and further photothermal conversion into high-purity CH3OH (volume fraction &gt; 97%). We construct a self-supporting electrocatalyst featuring dual active sites of Ni single atoms and encapsulated Co nanoparticles, which could produce syngas with a constant H2:CO ratio of ~2 via solar-powered CO2 electroreduction. The generated syngas is subsequently fed into the photothermal module, which could produce high-purity CH3OH under 1 sun-light irradiation, with a rate of 0.238 gCH3OH gcat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1. This work demonstrates a feasible and sustainable route for directly converting CO2 into high-purity CH3OH. CO2 conversion to CH3OH under mild conditions is of particular interest yet rather challenging. Here, the authors report a sun-simulated-driven tandem catalytic system comprising CO2 electroreduction to syngas, and further photothermal conversion into high-purity CH3OH (volume fraction &lt;97%).</description>
      <author>Jiqing Jiao, Yanbin Ma, Xiaoqian Han, Awu Ergu, Chao Zhang, Pingping Chen, Wei Liu, Qiquan Luo, Zhaolin Shi, Han Xu, Chen Chen, Yaguang Li, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56101-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Synergy of Pollution and Carbon Reduction by Green Fiscal Policy: A Quasi-Natural Experiment Utilizing a Pilot Program from China&#8217;s Comprehensive Demonstration Cities of Energy Conservation and Emission Reduction Fiscal Policy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020667</link>
      <description>Lei Xu, Shiguang Peng, Le Wang, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406469851

                Using data from 2003 to 2019 for China&#8217;s 257 cities, this quantitative research utilizes the difference-in-differences approach to evaluate the synergy of the Comprehensive Demonstration Cities of Energy Conservation and Emission Reduction Fiscal Policy on pollution and carbon reduction. The primary results are as follows. The policy successfully reduces total emissions of industrial SO2, industrial wastewater, and CO2, thus achieving the desired synergistic effect of pollution and carbon reduction. Facilitating green technological innovation and promoting industrial upgrading are the transmission mechanisms through which the synergistic effect of the policy operates. The negative effect of the policy on the total emissions of industrial SO2 and CO2 is greater in the eastern area than in the mid-western area and the impact of the policy on decreasing the total emissions of industrial SO2 is more pronounced in non-resource-based cities compared to resource-based cities. This study provides an empirical reference for green fiscal policy with respect to reducing air pollution, wastewater pollution, and greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
      <author>Lei Xu, Shiguang Peng, Le Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multienzymatic Platform for Coupling a CCU Strategy to Waste Valorization: CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from the Iron and Steel Industry and Crude Glycerol from Biodiesel Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c04908</link>
      <description>S. Rodriguez, Gregorio &#193;lvaro, Marina Guill&#233;n, Oscar Romero, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406532671

                Ongoing climate crisis demands the development of carbon capture and utilization (CCU) technologies that emphasize simplicity, eco-sustainability, and cost-effectiveness. Enzymatic CO2 reduction emerges as an alternative to biotransforming this cheap raw material into high-value products under milder conditions. This work proposes a multienzymatic platform to reduce CO2 to formate by formate dehydrogenase (FDH) and oxidize glycerol to dihydroxyacetone (DHA) by glycerol dehydrogenase (GlyDH), allowing for efficient cofactor regeneration. Through studies such as pH operating range, enzyme stability, FDH/GlyDH ratio, and reaction medium engineering to achieve optimal soluble CO2 concentrations, the reaction with a gas mixture of 24% CO2 yielded 5.7 mM formate and 6 mM DHA after 30 h, achieving a 92.3% CO2 conversion. To evaluate the feasibility under industrially relevant conditions, a synthetic gas mixture mimicking the composition of the iron and steel industry off-gases (24.5% CO2) and crude glycerol (64% v/v) from biodiesel production was tested as substrates. The simultaneous production was successful, yielding 3.1 mM formate and 4.4 mM DHA. Formic acid was subsequently purified using liquid&#8211;liquid extraction, employing the green solvent 2-methyltetrahydrofuran (2-MTHF). For the first time to our knowledge, a CCU strategy has been successfully coupled with industrial waste valorization, obtaining two high-value molecules by means of a robust, profitable, and easily manageable multienzymatic system.</description>
      <author>S. Rodriguez, Gregorio &#193;lvaro, Marina Guill&#233;n, Oscar Romero</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c04908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 sequestration potential in Depleted Hydrocarbon fields &#8211; A geochemical approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.19280.1</link>
      <description>Eleni Gianni, Pavlos Tyrologou, Dounya Behnous, M&#225;rton P&#225;l Farkas, Paula Fern&#225;ndez&#8208;Canteli &#193;lvarez, Jes&#250;s Garc&#237;a-Crespo, Ricardo Chacartegui, Nikolaos Koukouzas, J&#250;lio Carneiro, Open Research Europe. 5(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406621451

                Background The CO2 emissions reduction is crucial for the energy transition. Thus, new technologies for CO2 capture and storage are under development, such as CEEGS 1,2 . Porous media and rock caverns are geological formations of high interest for such technology. Among them, depleted hydrocarbon fields (DHF) gain ground due to the experience of reservoir characterisation, sealing performance, storage operability, and already established infrastructure which critically decreases the cost. However, one of the major problems caused during CO2 storage in DHF is the interactions between the injected CO2 and the remaining fluids. Methods In this study, the potential CO2 storage in DHF was investigated. Marismas 3 was used as a hypothetical model area for the examination of CO2 interactions with a carbonate-silisiclastic reservoir. PHREEQC software 1  was used to investigate reservoir rock/water/remained gas (CH4) interactions followed by interactions taking place after the CO2 injection. Different scenarios were used for the CO2 concentration and behaviour in the reservoir. To make the system more complex and generic, the CMG-GEM software 3  was utilized to examine the long-term sequestration of CO2 through dissolution trapping, residual trapping, and lateral migration in a reservoir analogue to the Marismas field, but at higher depth, compatible with the CEEGS technology. Results During the CO2 injection, carbonic acid was formed, causing a dissolution of several minerals, leading to siderite and clay minerals precipitation (e.g. kaolinite, Ca-montmorillonite, and illite), which may cause problems to the permeability of the system. The colloidal nature of siderite and the Ca-montmorillonite swelling properties are of high concern for pore throat clogging. However, the other newly formed mineralogical phases are not threatening the reservoir quality. CMG-GEM validated the critical phase of CO2 plume establishment. Conclusions The proposed DHF is promising for real-world underground applications fitting to CEEGS technology.</description>
      <author>Eleni Gianni, Pavlos Tyrologou, Dounya Behnous, M&#225;rton P&#225;l Farkas, Paula Fern&#225;ndez&#8208;Canteli &#193;lvarez, Jes&#250;s Garc&#237;a-Crespo, Ricardo Chacartegui, Nikolaos Koukouzas, J&#250;lio Carneiro</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.19280.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvent Mediated Interfacial Microenvironment Design for High&#8208;Performance Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409186</link>
      <description>Jiping Sun, Bichao Wu, Zhixing Wang, Huajun Guo, Guochun Yan, Hui Duan, Guangchao Li, Jiexi Wang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406466729

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction (CO2RR) in membrane electrode assembly (MEA) represents a viable strategy for converting CO2 into value-added multi-carbon (C2+) compounds. Therefore, the microstructure of the catalyst layer (CL) affects local gas transport, charge conduction, and proton supply at three-phase interfaces, which is significantly determined by the solvent environment. However, the microenvironment of the CLs and the mechanism of the solvent effect on C2+ selectivity remains elusive. Herein, a tailored interfacial structure is designed by introducing a solvent-mediated catalyst-ionomer-solvent microenvironment. The acetone surface promotion strategy is beneficial for the unfolded ionomers to uniformly coat the catalysts, which contributes to enhancing interfacial hydrophobicity and inhibiting hydrogen evolution. Furthermore, molecular dynamics (MD) simulation and in situ ATR-SEIRAS are employed to elucidate the appropriate interfacial network with a balanced distribution of CO2 and H2O. The uniform and continuous network in acetone is advantageous for CO2-to-C2+. The optimized structure favors the production of C2+ products in Cu-based MEA, exhibiting a high C2+ faradaic efficiency (FE) of 80.27% at 400 mA cm-2.</description>
      <author>Jiping Sun, Bichao Wu, Zhixing Wang, Huajun Guo, Guochun Yan, Hui Duan, Guangchao Li, Jiexi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Framework for History Matching CO2 Storage with 4D Seismic
  and Monitoring Well Data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.01575</link>
      <description>Nanzhe Wang, Louis J. Durlofsky, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406444272

                Geological carbon storage entails the injection of megatonnes of supercritical CO2 into subsurface formations. The properties of these formations are usually highly uncertain, which makes design and optimization of large-scale storage operations challenging. In this paper we introduce a history matching strategy that enables the calibration of formation properties based on early-time observations. Early-time assessments are essential to assure the operation is performing as planned. Our framework involves two fit-for-purpose deep learning surrogate models that provide predictions for in-situ monitoring well data and interpreted time-lapse (4D) seismic saturation data. These two types of data are at very different scales of resolution, so it is appropriate to construct separate, specialized deep learning networks for their prediction. This approach results in a workflow that is more straightforward to design and more efficient to train than a single surrogate that provides global high-fidelity predictions. The deep learning models are integrated into a hierarchical Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) history matching procedure. History matching is performed on a synthetic case with and without 4D seismic data, which allows us to quantify the impact of 4D seismic on uncertainty reduction. The use of both data types is shown to provide substantial uncertainty reduction in key geomodel parameters and to enable accurate predictions of CO2 plume dynamics. The overall history matching framework developed in this study represents an efficient way to integrate multiple data types and to assess the impact of each on uncertainty reduction and performance predictions.</description>
      <author>Nanzhe Wang, Louis J. Durlofsky</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.01575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Synthesis of Cellulose Acetate Mixed Matrix Membranes: Structure&#8211;Function Characterization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07538</link>
      <description>Andrea Torre-Celeizabal, Francesca Russo, Francesco Galiano, Alberto Figoli, Clara Casado&#8208;Coterillo, A. Garea, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406463550

                Although membrane technology is widely used in different gas separation applications, membrane manufacturers need to reduce the environmental impact during the membrane fabrication process within the framework of the circular economy by replacing toxic solvents, oil-based polymers, and such by more sustainable alternatives. These include environmentally friendly materials, such as biopolymers, green solvents, and surfactant free porous fillers. This work promotes the use of environmentally sustainable and low toxic alternatives, introducing the novel application of cellulose acetate (CA) as a biopolymer in combination with dimethyl carbonate (DMC) as a greener solvent and different inorganic fillers (Zeolite-A, ETS-10, AM-4 and ZIF-8) prepared without the use of toxic solvents or reactants. Hansen Solubility Parameters were used to confirm the polymer&#8211;solvent affinity. Pure CA and mixed matrix membranes were characterized regarding their hydrophilicity by water uptake and contact angle measurements, thermal stability by TGA, mechanical resistance, ATR-FTIR and scanning electron microscopy before evaluating the gas separation performance by single gas permeability of N2, CH4, and CO2. Conditioning of the CA membranes is observed causing reduction of the CO2 permeability values from 12,600 Barrer for the fresh 0.5 wt % ETS-10/CA membrane to 740 Barrer for the 0.5 wt % ZIF-8/CA membranes, corresponding to 24% and 4.2% reductions in CO2/CH4 selectivity and 30% and 24% increase in CO2/N2 selectivity for the same membranes. The structure&#8211;relationship was evaluated by phenomenological models which are useful at low filler loading considering flux direction and particle shape and size but still fail to explain the interactions between the DMC green solvent and CA matrix and fillers that are influencing gas transport performance different than other CA membranes.</description>
      <author>Andrea Torre-Celeizabal, Francesca Russo, Francesco Galiano, Alberto Figoli, Clara Casado&#8208;Coterillo, A. Garea</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07538</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expression of concern: Photo-induced reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; using a magnetically separable Ru-CoPc@TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; catalyst under visible light irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90225d</link>
      <description>Pawan Kumar, Reshu Chauhan, Bir Sain, Suman L. Jain, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406534334

                Expression of Concern for 'Photo-induced reduction of CO2 using a magnetically separable Ru-CoPc@TiO2@SiO2@Fe3O4 catalyst under visible light irradiation' by Pawan Kumar et al., Dalton Trans., 2015, 44, 4546-4553, https://doi.org/10.1039/C4DT02461C.</description>
      <author>Pawan Kumar, Reshu Chauhan, Bir Sain, Suman L. Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90225d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Atom&#8208;Scale Cascade Catalysis via Multi&#8208;Active Site Collaboration for Ampere&#8208;Level CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412658</link>
      <description>Cheng&#8208;Hao Jin, Lin Yue, Yanan Wang, Jingbo Shi, Li Ren, Yijiang Liu, Zongye Yue, Kunyue Leng, Yafei Zhao, Yi Wang, Xiao Han, Yunteng Qu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406482743

                Electrochemical reduction of CO2 to value-added multicarbon (C2+) productions offers an attractive route for renewable energy storage and CO2 utilization, but it remains challenging to achieve high C2+ selectivity at industrial-level current density. Herein, a Mo1Cu single-atom alloy (SAA) catalyst is reported that displays a remarkable C2+ Faradaic efficiency of 86.4% under 0.80 A cm-2. Furthermore, the C2+ partial current density over Mo1Cu reaches 1.33 A cm-2 with a Faradaic efficiency surpasses 74.3%. The combination of operando spectroscopy and density functional theory (DFT) indicates the as-prepared Mo1Cu SAA catalyst enables atom-scale cascade catalysis via multi-active site collaboration. The introduced Mo sites promote the H2O dissociation to fabricate active *H, meanwhile, the Cu sites (Cu0) far from Mo atom are active sites for the CO2 activation toward CO. Further, CO and *H are captured by the adjacent Cu sites (Cu&amp;+) near Mo atom, accelerating CO conversion and C&#9472;C coupling process. Our findings benefit the design of tandem electrocatalysts at atomic scale for transforming CO2 to multicarbon products under a high conversion rate.</description>
      <author>Cheng&#8208;Hao Jin, Lin Yue, Yanan Wang, Jingbo Shi, Li Ren, Yijiang Liu, Zongye Yue, Kunyue Leng, Yafei Zhao, Yi Wang, Xiao Han, Yunteng Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USING ION BEAM IRRADIATION METHOD TO CHANGE THE ATOMIC STRUCTURES OF MATERIALS TO ENHANCE THEIR ABILITY TO TRAP CARBON DIOXIDE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33564/ijeast.2024.v09i06.004</link>
      <description>Farzan Saleem Butt, Shaheen Irfan, International Journal of Engineering Applied Sciences and Technology. 09(06)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406484342

                The reduction of atmospheric CO2 requires thought-provoking ideas that would help reduce the concentration level in the atmosphere. In this study, the authors suggest the atomic modification of zeolite materials through controlled electron and ion beam damage to increase their carbon capture capacities. Zeolite samples were synthesized by hydrothermal method and subsequently, two different types of electron beam irradiation were performed on the samples. In the inert gas medium, zeolite samples were irradiated to restrict the structural degradation. In contrast, the vacuum medium which had a raster magnet was the other type which allowed a wide dispersion of the electron beam. The absorbed keratins ranged from 500 kGy to 1000 kGy, and the progression encouraged structural changes in the zeolites to increase the CO&#8322; adsorption uptake. The results have shown that lewis acid zeolite shows increased uptake of CO2 forming an exceptionally high adsorbed volume of 87.86 cm&#179;/g at 500 kGy. The generation of modified zeolites has made it possible to use the innovative Carbfix technique which incorporates the dissolved CO&#178; in water and then pumps it into the basalt layers and harnesses the natural occurrence of minerals to fix the CO2. The methods of modified samples were examined by PXRD, FE-TEM and FE-SEM techniques, TGA and spectrometric methods.</description>
      <author>Farzan Saleem Butt, Shaheen Irfan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33564/ijeast.2024.v09i06.004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Tantalate by a Sodium&#8208;Driven Flux&#8208;Mediated Synthesis for Photoelectrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401432</link>
      <description>Ariadne K&#246;che, Kootak Hong, Sehun Seo, Finn Babbe, Hyeongyu Gim, Keon&#8208;Han Kim, Hojoong Choi, Yoonsung Jung, Inhyeok Oh, Gnanavel Vaidhyanathan Krishnamurthy, M. St&#246;rmer, Sanghan Lee, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kim, Alexis T. Bell, Sherdil Khan, Carolin M. Sutter&#8208;Fella, Francesca M. Toma, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406482172

                Copper-tantalate, Cu2Ta4O11 (CTO), shows significant promise as an efficient photocathode for multi-carbon compounds (C2+) production through photoelectrochemical (PEC) CO2 reduction, owing to its suitable energy bands and catalytic surface. However, synthesizing CTO poses a significant challenge due to its metastable nature and thermal instability. In this study, this challenge is addressed by employing a flux-mediated synthesis technique using a sodium-based flux to create sodium-doped CTO (Na-CTO) thin films, providing enhanced nucleation and stabilization for the CTO phase. To evaluate the PEC performance and catalytic properties of the films, copper(II) oxide (CuO) at the Na-CTO surface is selectively etched. The etched Na-CTO shows a lower dark current, with decreased contribution from photocorrosion, unlike the non-etched Na-CTO which has remaining CuO on the surface. Furthermore, Na-CTO exhibits 7.3-fold ethylene selectivity over hydrogen, thus highlighting its promising potential as a photocathode for C2+ production through PEC CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Ariadne K&#246;che, Kootak Hong, Sehun Seo, Finn Babbe, Hyeongyu Gim, Keon&#8208;Han Kim, Hojoong Choi, Yoonsung Jung, Inhyeok Oh, Gnanavel Vaidhyanathan Krishnamurthy, M. St&#246;rmer, Sanghan Lee, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kim, Alexis T. Bell, Sherdil Khan, Carolin M. Sutter&#8208;Fella, Francesca M. Toma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Modeling of Energy, Exergy, Exergoeconomic, Economic and Environmental Indices of a CO2 Transcritical Vapor Compression Refrigeration System with Hybrid Triply Periodic Minimal Surface Heat Exchangers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202501.1200.v1</link>
      <description>Kabo Letlhare-Wastikc, Xinle Yang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406545666

                Thermodynamic equipment efficiency continues to be a topical area of research, especially at the advent of 3D printing of compact heat exchangers (HX). The innovative equipment should address wholistic efficiency concerns (thermodynamic, sustainable, economic). This study dynamically simulated a CO2 (R744) transcritical vapor compression refrigeration system fitted with novel hy-brid Triply Periodic Minimal Surface heat exchangers and compared with it to a tubular HX system on energy, exergy, exergoeconomic, economic and environmental performance. The models were run in MATLAB, which called their Simulink dynamic simulations. Key findings were; improved heat transfer effectiveness due to the material&#8217;s intricate shape, exergy efficiency is 5.79% better, initial investment savings is 16.49%, CO2 penalty cost rate reduction of 15.04%, and overall exergy cost rate reduction of 40.83%. The implications of these findings are that the proposed HX achieves more surface area and less material volume for heat transfer equivalent to a bigger pipe HX, hence more economic at less environmental impact and reduced irreversibilities.</description>
      <author>Kabo Letlhare-Wastikc, Xinle Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202501.1200.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solution of the Capacity-Constrained Vehicle Routing Problem Considering Carbon Footprint Within the Scope of Sustainable Logistics with Genetic Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020727</link>
      <description>Bedrettin T&#252;rker Palamut&#231;uo&#287;lu, Selin &#199;avu&#351;o&#287;lu, Ahmet Yavuz &#199;AMLI, Florina Oana V&#238;rl&#259;nu&#539;&#259;, Silviu Bacalum, Deniz Z&#252;ng&#252;n, Florentina Moisescu, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615094

                One of the important problems of sustainable logistics is routing vehicles in a sustainable manner, the green vehicle routing problem, or vehicle routing problems which aim to reduce CO2 emissions. In the literature research, it was seen that these problems were solved with heuristic, metaheuristic, or hyper-heuristic methods and hybrid approaches since they are in the NP-hard class. This work presents a parallel multi-process genetic algorithm that incorporates problem-specific genetic operators to minimize CO2 emissions in the capacity-constrained vehicle routing problem. Unlike previous research, the algorithm combines parallel computing with tailored genetic operators in order to enhance the diversity of solutions and speed up convergence. Genetic algorithm models were developed to minimize total distance, CO2 emissions, and both objectives simultaneously. Two genetic algorithm models were developed to minimize total distance and CO2 emissions. Experimental results using the reference CVRP examples such as A-n32-k5 and B-n44-k7 show that the proposed approach reduces CO2 emissions by 1.2% more than hybrid artificial bee colony optimization, 1.3% more than ant colony optimization, and 4% more than the traditional genetic algorithm. Experimental results using benchmark CVRP instances demonstrate that the proposed approach outperforms hybrid artificial bee colony optimization, ant colony optimization, and traditional genetic algorithms for most of the test cases. This is done by exploiting multi-core processors, and the parallel architecture has improved computational efficiency; the modules compare and update solutions against the global optimum. Results obtained show that prioritizing CO2 emissions as the only objective yields better results compared to multi-objective models. This study makes two significant contributions to the literature: (1) it introduces a novel parallel genetic algorithm framework optimized for CO2 emission reduction, and (2) it provides empirical evidence underscoring the advantages of emission-focused optimization in CVRP.</description>
      <author>Bedrettin T&#252;rker Palamut&#231;uo&#287;lu, Selin &#199;avu&#351;o&#287;lu, Ahmet Yavuz &#199;AMLI, Florina Oana V&#238;rl&#259;nu&#539;&#259;, Silviu Bacalum, Deniz Z&#252;ng&#252;n, Florentina Moisescu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion to Dimethyl Ether on Cu/ZnO/Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-ZSM-5 Tandem Catalysts in a Double-Bed Reactor: Tuning the ZSM-5 Catalyst Acidity and Porosity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04512</link>
      <description>Assem T. Mohamed, Yahia H. Ahmad, Abdul Hakeem Anwer, Ahmed M. Soliman, Mohamed Ali H. Saad, Mohamed Kheireddine Aroua, Siham Y. Al-Qaradawi, Abdelbaki Benamor, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406473900

                This research evaluated the effectiveness of thermally and microwave-assisted alkali-treated HZSM-5 zeolites with varying silica/alumina ratios in catalyzing the direct one-step synthesis of dimethyl ether (DME) from CO2. The reactions were carried out in a dual-bed reactor configuration. A primary catalyst, consisting of Cu/ZnO/Al2O3 (CZA) with a formulation of 10 wt % alumina, 30 wt % Zinc, and 60 wt % Copper, was used to convert CO2 to methanol. Subsequently, zeolite or modified zeolite was utilized as a secondary catalyst for the dehydration of methanol to DME. The catalysts were extensively characterized using various advanced analytical techniques, including transmission electron microscopy (TEM), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), nitrogen physisorption analysis, X-ray diffraction (XRD), ammonia temperature-programmed desorption (NH3-TPD), and hydrogen temperature-programmed reduction (H2-TPR). The CO2 hydrogenation study was carried out at a pressure of 40 bar and a temperature of 250 &#176;C. The results demonstrated that alkali treatment had minimal impact on the crystallinity of the zeolites, but it greatly improved their textural properties. Moreover, the alkali modification enhanced the stability of catalysts and increased their selectivity for DME production.</description>
      <author>Assem T. Mohamed, Yahia H. Ahmad, Abdul Hakeem Anwer, Ahmed M. Soliman, Mohamed Ali H. Saad, Mohamed Kheireddine Aroua, Siham Y. Al-Qaradawi, Abdelbaki Benamor</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electroreduction-Driven Formation and Connectivity of Polyoxometalate Coordination Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04891</link>
      <description>Haeun Chang, Linfeng Chen, Erika Samo&#318;ov&#225;, Y. K. Pan, Kody A. Acosta, Carl E. Lemmon, Milan Gembick&#253;, Francesco Paesani, Alina M. Schimpf, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406495684

                We present the synthesis of metal oxide coordination networks based on Preyssler-type polyoxoanions ([NaP5W30O110]14- and [NaP5MoW29O110]14-) bridged with metal-aquo complexes ([M(H2O)n]m+, Mm+ = Co2+, Ni2+, Zn2+, Y3+), induced by electrochemical reduction. Networks bridged with first-row transition metals are isostructural with a previously reported Co-bridged structure, while the Y3+-bridged structure is new. All networks feature an uncommon binding motif of the metal cation to the oxygen atoms at cap positions, which we hypothesize is due to increased electron density at the cap upon reduction. Oxidation of a Zn2+-bridged network resulted in a new structure in which Zn2+-Ocap bonds are lost, indicating the importance of reduction in the connectivity of these polyoxometalate-based coordination networks.</description>
      <author>Haeun Chang, Linfeng Chen, Erika Samo&#318;ov&#225;, Y. K. Pan, Kody A. Acosta, Carl E. Lemmon, Milan Gembick&#253;, Francesco Paesani, Alina M. Schimpf</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical Foam Injection Molding of Cellulose Fiber Reinforced Polypropylene by Using CO2: Parameter Variation and Comparison to Chemical Foam Injection Molding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jcs9010050</link>
      <description>Claudia Pretschuh, Matthias Mihalic, Christian Sponner, Thomas Lummerstorfer, Andreas Steurer, Christoph Unterweger, Journal of Composites Science. 9(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406613162

                The use of cellulose fiber-filled polypropylene (PP) composites in combination with foam injection molding has enabled the lightweight design of injection-molded parts. The study provides achievements for the physical foam injection molding (MuCell&#174;) process of PP&#8211;cellulose fiber compounds by using CO2 as the direct foaming agent, including a comparison of MuCell&#174; foaming with N2 and a comparison to a chemical foaming process. Weight and density reductions, foam structure and specific mechanical properties are highly dependent on the applied processing parameters. The maximum weight reduction reached values of up to 16%, and density reduction even reached 33% in relation to the compact plates. The extent of weight and density reduction could be adjusted, among other factors, by a reduction in the shot volume. Setting the density reduction to 22% allowed for simultaneously decreasing weight while sustaining the specific flexural properties and limiting the loss of specific impact strength. By using optimized FIM parameters, the mechanical performance could be improved, with specific modulus values even outperforming the compact reference sample. This presents a significant benefit for the preparation of lightweight products and sets the basis for further optimization and modeling studies.</description>
      <author>Claudia Pretschuh, Matthias Mihalic, Christian Sponner, Thomas Lummerstorfer, Andreas Steurer, Christoph Unterweger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jcs9010050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JWPE 3-Minute Pitch "My Life in Water" event winning presentations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.fdbzpl</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406622802

                The Winners of the JWPE 3-Minute Pitch: "My Life in Water" event will each present a 15 minute talk about their research topic. The JWPE 3-Minute Pitch "My Life in Water" event, was a global initiative dedicated to celebrating outstanding PhD research in water processing and engineering. This initiative aims to support emerging researchers by providing a platform within the Journal of Water Process Engineering for them to showcase their work. Participants faced the challenge of distilling their research into a compelling three-minute presentation, using language accessible to a non-specialist audience. Congratulations to our winners and presnsters for this webinar: 1st place: Ms. Hanwei Yu, University of Technology Sydney, Australia for her presentation on Extracting Lithium from Water for a Sustainable Future 2nd place: Ms. Mbokazi Ngayeka, Nelson Mandela University, South Africa for her presentation on Synthesis of composite track-etched membranes for metal recovery in mine wastewater 3rd place: Ms. Jin Du, Tsinghua University, China for her presentation on Simultaneous CO2 reduction and Wastewater Treatment via Bioelectrochemical System Lithium Recovery from Aqueous Resources Using Capacitive Deionization (CDI) The increasing demand for lithium, driven by its vital role in energy storage technologies, underscores the need for efficient and sustainable recovery methods. Capacitive deionization (CDI) has emerged as a promising technology for lithium recovery from aqueous resources, such as seawater desalination brine, due to its low energy consumption, operational simplicity, and high adsorption efficiency. However, the selective recovery of lithium remains challenging due to the presence of massive competing ions. This presentation highlights my PhD research on enhancing lithium selectivity in CDI through three innovative strategies: employing nanomaterials with subnano-scale channels to leverage the size sieving effect, introducing functional groups with strong cation affinities, and utilizing lithium-ion sieves that exploit the material's memory effect. Experimental findings, detailed mechanism analyses, and potential applications for sustainable resource recovery will be discussed, paving the way for environmentally friendly lithium extraction solutions. Synthesis of composite track-etched membranes for metal recovery in mine wastewater Track-etched membranes (TEM) offer distinct advantages over conventional membranes and other solid supports due to their precisely determined structure and the fact that their pores sizes and thickness can be varied in a controllable manner. Composite membranes were fabricated by combining the products of ion-tracking and electrospinning processes. Swift heavy ions generated from a cyclotron were used to irradiate polyethylene terephthalate (PET) polymer film to create latent tracks which were then chemically etched in an alkaline solution, to produce tracks on the membrane. Magnetron sputtering was then used to deposit titanium (Ti) on the membrane to produce PET-TM. Ligand functionalized polyacrylonitrile nanofibres (PAN-nfs), polysulfone (PSN-nfs) and polystyrene (PSRN-nfs) were directly electrospun on the Ti coated PET-TEM using an electrospinning process creating the composite membrane. These track-etched membranes with specific pore sizes were functionalized with various ligands for scavenging Pt, Rh and Ir metal anions from mine waste water. The track-etched membrane, the nanofibres and the composite membrane were characterised using SEM, TEM, TGA, ATR-FTIR and adsorption/desorption of nitrogen techniques. Mean pore size and pore size distribution was determined using electrical conductivity and small angle X-ray scattering techniques. The results confirmed the fabrication of nanofibers-coated track-etched composite membranes. Filtration studies were conducted to assess the efficiency of the uptake of the platinum group metals and invariably separate Pt, Rh and Ir from mine wastewater. Microbial Electrosynthesis Systems for Efficient CO2 Reduction and Acetate Production Microbial electrosynthesis (MES), coupling the electrochemical process with bio-technology, is green and specific for CO2 reduction, for which the microbial cells as the biocatalyst attached on the cathode are self-sustaining, stable, and inexpensive to develop and maintain. The MES system is a hybrid of a bioreactor and an electrochemical reactor, which requires thorough understanding across its various aspects such as reactor optimization, electrode design, and process control. In this study, the preferred inorganic carbon form (gaseous CO2 or dissolved bicarbonate) for the MES system was discussed, highlighting the importance of CO2 supplying strategy to the start-up and steady operation of the MES system. The system performance and microbial communities suggested that feeding more gaseous CO2 would aid in microbial CO2 electroreduction. Furthermore, a facile and promising electrode modification strategy was developed for MES system with Fe-Mn bimetallic oxides, increasing the acetate production rate from 28 to 78 g/(m2&#183;d). The underlying mechanisms were also highlighted, in particular the contributions of Mn and Fe individually and their synergistic effect on the microbial CO2 electroreduction, as well as the functional microbial species and the electron transfer pathways involved. Overall, this presentation will provide effective strategies and mechanistic insights for efficient and sustainable conversion of CO2 to valuable platform organic chemicals, bringing the world closer to achieving carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.fdbzpl</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Temperature and Ageing on LFP Electric Vehicle Batteries: A Comprehensive Modelling Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30939/ijastech..1519778</link>
      <description>Benan Serarslan, International Journal of Automotive Science And Technology. 9(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406601479

                For several years now, electric cars (E-cars) have increasingly come into the public spotlight. This technology aims to provide alternatives to conventional vehicles with internal combustion engines while creating independence from politically unstable oil-producing countries. Another significant reason for this trend is the reduction of CO2 emissions to counteract the associated climate change. When powered by renewable energy sources such as wind or solar energy, E-cars theoretically avoid most of the CO2 emissions. However, from a consumer perspective, E-cars currently have two main disadvantages, such as high acquisition costs and limited range. Due to these two factors, it became imperative to be able to get accurate information about the batteries&#8217; state, age, and range. Therefore, this article presents the main influential factors on vehicle range and a comprehensive study of different types of state of art modeling methods. The methodologies with their challenges and the necessity of using the relevant modeling methodology are described. Furthermore, experimental findings after 365 days are presented, using 60 Ah battery cells, to investigate different kinds of aging influence with various parameters like ambient temperature, charging current and depth of discharge.</description>
      <author>Benan Serarslan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30939/ijastech..1519778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cumulative Energy Demand and Greenhouse Gas Emissions from Potato and Tomato Production in Southeast Brazil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy15010235</link>
      <description>Breno de Jesus Pereira, Newton La Scala, Arthur Bernardes Cec&#237;lio Filho, Agronomy. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406627125

                Knowing the energy balance in agricultural systems is essential for a holistic understanding of sustainability, productivity and economic return. The aim of this study was to estimate the cumulative energy demand (CED), greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions and carbon footprint in industrial potato and tomato production systems in the Southeast region of Brazil, identifying mitigation strategies in different scenarios. The Life Cycle Analysis methodology was used, and two functional units were defined: one hectare of cultivation and one kilogram of vegetable produced. The CEDs for tomato and potato production were 59,553.56 MJ ha&#8211;1 (or 0.54 MJ kg&#8211;1) and 57,992.02 MJ ha&#8211;1 (or 1.45 MJ kg&#8211;1), respectively. The GHG emissions were 5425.13 kg CO2 eq ha&#8211;1 for potato production and 5270.9 kg CO2 eq ha&#8211;1 for tomato production, resulting in carbon footprints of 0.135 and 0.042 kg CO2 eq kg&#8211;1, respectively. Fertilizers, diesel and pesticides were the main contributors to CED and GHG emissions. Thus, in order to achieve greater sustainability in the production of these vegetables and mitigate the impacts on the environment generated by the high demand for energy and GHG emissions, it is necessary to replace synthetic fertilizers with organic sources, chemical pesticides with biological pesticides, diesel with biodiesel or the use of electric vehicles and tractors, resulting in reductions of up to 39 and 52% in the GHG emissions for potatoes and tomatoes, respectively.</description>
      <author>Breno de Jesus Pereira, Newton La Scala, Arthur Bernardes Cec&#237;lio Filho</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy15010235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supercritical fluid extrusion of pea flour and pea protein concentrate: Effects on off&#8208;flavor removal and sensory improvement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1750-3841.70004</link>
      <description>Aamir Iqbal, Abdul Fateh Hosseini, Syed S. H. Rizvi, Journal of Food Science. 90(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406614647

                Abstract This study was intended to provide a novel process that fills a knowledge gap in relation to the enhancement of pulses utilization. The primary goal was to develop an experimental framework for using a high&#8208;pressure supercritical fluid extruder (SCFX) as a continuous bioreactor to produce off&#8208;flavor reduced and functionally superior pulse flours and protein concentrates in a single step. The current study focused on using SCFX processing to remove off&#8208;flavor from pulse flour and protein concentrates, enhancing the quality, acceptability, and marketability of pulse&#8208;based products. Supercritical carbon dioxide (SC&#8208;CO 2 ), a well&#8208;known green solvent, was employed in combination with an extrusion system to achieve off&#8208;flavor reduction at larger scale. Using various methods such as headspace solid&#8208;phase microextraction&#8208;gas chromatography mass&#8208;spectroscopy (HS&#8208;SPME&#8208;GC&#8208;MS) and sensory evaluation, this study demonstrated that SCFX significantly reduced the off&#8208;flavor in pea flour (PF) and pea protein concentrate (PPC). HS&#8208;SPME&#8208;GC&#8208;MS analyses identified major off&#8208;flavor compounds in unextruded PF and PPC, including 1&#8208;hexanol, 1&#8208;octanol, 1&#8208;nonanol, nonanal, and 2&#8208;alkyl methoxypyrazines. Following SCFX treatment, all these compounds except nonanal were removed. Total off&#8208;flavor compound concentration dropped from 923 to 126.5 ng/g in PF, and from 571.7 to 65.9 ng/g in pea protein concentrate PPC after SCFX treatment. Sensory evaluation corroborated these HS&#8208;SPME&#8208;GC&#8208;MS findings, showing that over 80% of the participants could accurately distinguish the extruded samples from the unextruded ones, perceiving the treated samples as having the least beany flavor. These findings highlight the efficacy of SCFX processing in enhancing the sensory profile of pulse&#8208;based products by removing off&#8208;flavor compounds.</description>
      <author>Aamir Iqbal, Abdul Fateh Hosseini, Syed S. H. Rizvi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1750-3841.70004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Carbon Dioxide Therapy on Skin Wound Healing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines13010228</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Prazeres, Ana Lima, G. Ribeiro, Biomedicines. 13(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406618679

                Promoting rapid healing is a concern in skin wound treatment, as the increased pain and the loss of functional ability when wounds become chronic create a complex problem to manage. This scoping review aimed to explore the literature and synthesize existing knowledge on the therapeutic use of CO2 in treating cutaneous wounds. The literature was selected using previously defined inclusion and exclusion criteria, and 22 articles were selected for data extraction. The most researched type of injury was chronic wounds located on the extremities of the limbs. Carboxytherapy was performed in five different ways: subcutaneous, intradermal, or intralesional injections; in hot water baths with temperatures ranging from 30 to 42 &#176;C; transcutaneous application; intra-abdominal insufflation; and a paste for transcutaneous local application. The main effects of CO2 therapy described were as follows: improved blood flow and local oxygenation, reduction of the inflammatory process, increased collagen production, and improved clinical aspects of wounds, with faster healing. Carboxytherapy can be considered a good alternative for treating skin wounds, although further studies should be pursued to elucidate its molecular mechanisms and enhance its efficacy.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Prazeres, Ana Lima, G. Ribeiro</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines13010228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of Binder Materials for Ag-Based Gas Diffusion Electrodes for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03279</link>
      <description>Prasad Gonugunta, Khatereh Roohi, Mohammad Soleimani, Prasaanth Ravi Anusuyadevi, Peyman Taheri, Mahinder Ramdin, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406529578

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction (CO2R) to chemicals and fuels has made tremendous progress since the introduction of gas diffusion electrodes (GDEs) to overcome mass-transfer limitations and enable industrial-scale current densities. The advancement in the field, however, has come with new challenges that are related to the stability and degradation of the GDE due to flooding issues, which currently hinder the scale-up. Here, we investigated the effect of six different binding materials (Nafion, polytetrafluoroethylene, Fumion, Pention, poly(vinyl alcohol), and polypyrrole) on the stability and performance of Ag-based GDEs for CO2R to CO in alkaline media. All binders show a decrease in the Faraday efficiency (FE) of CO and increase in hydrogen evolution reaction over time. The most hydrophilic GDE based on polypyrrole can uphold a higher FE of CO for longer times, which is contrary to a common belief that low wettability is required for long-term stability. By using a range of tools (SEM&#8211;EDX, SEM&#8211;FIB, X-ray diffraction, and contact angle measurements) for the postelectrolysis characterization of the GDEs, we show that the performance loss is related to flooding, bi(carbonate) precipitation, and catalyst agglomeration. These results contribute to a better understanding of the stability issues in GDE-based CO2 electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Prasad Gonugunta, Khatereh Roohi, Mohammad Soleimani, Prasaanth Ravi Anusuyadevi, Peyman Taheri, Mahinder Ramdin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stand-Alone Sponge-Shaped Mesoporous AuPt Alloy Nanosponges as Visible Photocatalyst for the Selective Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06023</link>
      <description>Harshitha Rajashekhar, Damini Vrushabendrakumar, Kazi M. Alam, Navneet Kumar, John Garcia, Karthik Shankar, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406602263

                Bulk Au is chemically inert and a relatively poor catalyst while Pt is catalytically active. Nanostructured Au is an effective photocatalyst due to hot electrons generated by interband- and intraband damping of surface plasmons. A bimetallic, mesoporous AuPt catalyst with a large specific surface area is highly desirable due to the combination of hot carrier and catalytic promoter effects together with a large number of active reaction sites. Sponge-shaped AuPt alloy nanoparticles were grown by spontaneous thermal dewetting of ultrathin AuPtAg films followed by dealloying through removal of Ag. Selective etching of silver from AuPtAg alloy precursors formed a porous AuPt sheet-like nanostructure with mesopores with an average size of 3.72 nm. Under AM1.5G one sun illumination, the AuPt nanosponge acted as a stand-alone photocatalyst for CO2 reduction by evolving CO at a rate of 1010 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 with 100% selectivity. Scavenger experiments confirmed photogenerated electrons to be the driving force for chemical transformation as opposed to holes. AuPt nanosponge significantly outperformed bare Au nanosponge in both visible light-stimulated CO2 photoreduction and photooxidative degradation of methylene blue dye, which is attributed to a non-negligible photoinduced electron transfer from Au to Pt followed by electron transfer to reactants.</description>
      <author>Harshitha Rajashekhar, Damini Vrushabendrakumar, Kazi M. Alam, Navneet Kumar, John Garcia, Karthik Shankar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Emission Accounting and LMDI Factor Analysis of Fossil Energy in Henan Province</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/df58c541</link>
      <description>Yishao Shi, Jun Ma, Frontiers in Business Economics and Management. 18(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406642336

                The cultivation of fossil energy consumption in Henan Province between 2005 and 2022 is key to formulate carbon reduction strategies. This study uses the Logarithmic Mean Divisia Index (LMDI) method to decompose the factors of carbon emissions. The total carbon emissions from fossil energy in Henan Province amounted to 3.075 billion tons of CO2, showing an initial increase followed by a decrease, with fluctuations ranging from 125.59 million tons to 209.98 million tons. The LMDI analysis results show that the total effect of fossil energy carbon emissions fluctuated over time. From 2006 to 2011, the total effect was 84.39 million tons. From 2012 to 2019, it was -56.70 million tons. rom 2020 to 2022, it was 14.93 million tons. The greatest positive impact is the economic factor, accounting for 52.36% of the total effect. The greatest negative impact is the technological factor, accounting for 46.32%.Based on this, the study proposes the following carbon reduction strategies: adjusting the energy structure, fostering green technological innovation, and enhancing energy consumption management.</description>
      <author>Yishao Shi, Jun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/df58c541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of labour and nature within just transition strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4337/9781035300907.00051</link>
      <description>Nora R&#228;thzel, Dimitris Stevis, Edward Elgar Publishing eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406525082

                The term through which to speak about trade union's environmental policies these days is Just Transition. As with any term that enters the public discourse, the more it is used, the less it means. We will first outline the major turning points of the history of the idea of just transition (avant la lettre) in trade unions across the globe. In a second part we discuss some of the environmental policies of trade unions in the global north and south which go beyond ideas of a "technological fix" and the reduction of CO2 emissions only including problems of water, soil and biodiversity. The third part provides a critical assessment of these policies arguing that given the limits of natural resources, policies need to provide an alternative to green growth and include shop floor in the development of just transition strategies.</description>
      <author>Nora R&#228;thzel, Dimitris Stevis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4337/9781035300907.00051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comment on egusphere-2024-3721</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3721-rc1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406490195

                Abstract. Developing effective global strategies for climate mitigation requires an independent assessment of green-house gas emission inventory at the urban scale. In the framework of the Dutch Ruisdael Observatory infrastructure project, we have enhanced the Dutch Large-Eddy Simulation (DALES) model to simulate carbon dioxide (CO2) plume emission and three-dimensional dispersion within the turbulent boundary layer. The unique ability to explicitly resolve turbulent structures at the hectometer resolution (100 m) makes DALES particularly suitable for detailed realistic simulations of both singular high-emitting point sources and urban emissions, aligning with the goals of Ruisdael Observatory. The model setup involves a high-resolution simulation (100 m &#215; 100 m) covering the main urban area of the Netherlands (51.5&#176;&#8211;52.5&#176; N, 3.75&#176;&#8211;6.45&#176; E). The model integrates meteorological forcing from the HARMONIE-AROME weather forecasting model, background CO2 levels from the CAMS reanalysis, as well as point source emissions and downscaled area emissions derived from 1 km &#215; 1 km emission inventory from the national registry. The latter are prepared using a sector-specific downscaling workflow, covering major emission categories. Biogenic CO2 exchanges from grasslands and forests are interactively included in the hectometer calculations within the heterogeneous land-surface model of DALES. Our evaluation strategy is twofold, comparing DALES simulations with: (i) the state-of-the art LOTOS-EUROS model simulations and (ii) in-situ Cabauw tower measurements and Ruisdael surface observations of the urban background in the Rotterdam area at Westmaas and Slufter. Our comprehensive statistical analysis confirmed the effectiveness of DALES in modeling the urban-scale CO2 emission distribution and plume dispersion under turbulent conditions, but also revealed potential limitations and areas for further improvement. Thus, our new model framework provides valuable insights into emission transport and dispersion of CO2, in support of emission uncertainty reduction using atmospheric measurements and the development of effective climate policies.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3721-rc1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comment on egusphere-2024-3721</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3721-rc2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406501414

                Abstract. Developing effective global strategies for climate mitigation requires an independent assessment of green-house gas emission inventory at the urban scale. In the framework of the Dutch Ruisdael Observatory infrastructure project, we have enhanced the Dutch Large-Eddy Simulation (DALES) model to simulate carbon dioxide (CO2) plume emission and three-dimensional dispersion within the turbulent boundary layer. The unique ability to explicitly resolve turbulent structures at the hectometer resolution (100 m) makes DALES particularly suitable for detailed realistic simulations of both singular high-emitting point sources and urban emissions, aligning with the goals of Ruisdael Observatory. The model setup involves a high-resolution simulation (100 m &#215; 100 m) covering the main urban area of the Netherlands (51.5&#176;&#8211;52.5&#176; N, 3.75&#176;&#8211;6.45&#176; E). The model integrates meteorological forcing from the HARMONIE-AROME weather forecasting model, background CO2 levels from the CAMS reanalysis, as well as point source emissions and downscaled area emissions derived from 1 km &#215; 1 km emission inventory from the national registry. The latter are prepared using a sector-specific downscaling workflow, covering major emission categories. Biogenic CO2 exchanges from grasslands and forests are interactively included in the hectometer calculations within the heterogeneous land-surface model of DALES. Our evaluation strategy is twofold, comparing DALES simulations with: (i) the state-of-the art LOTOS-EUROS model simulations and (ii) in-situ Cabauw tower measurements and Ruisdael surface observations of the urban background in the Rotterdam area at Westmaas and Slufter. Our comprehensive statistical analysis confirmed the effectiveness of DALES in modeling the urban-scale CO2 emission distribution and plume dispersion under turbulent conditions, but also revealed potential limitations and areas for further improvement. Thus, our new model framework provides valuable insights into emission transport and dispersion of CO2, in support of emission uncertainty reduction using atmospheric measurements and the development of effective climate policies.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3721-rc2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic&#8211;Energy&#8211;Environmental Optimization of a Multi-Energy System in a University District</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en18020413</link>
      <description>L. Bacci, Enrico Dal Cin, Gianluca Carraro, Sergio Rech, Andrea Lazzaretto, Energies. 18(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615387

                The integration of energy generation and consumption is one of the most effective ways to reduce energy-system-related waste, costs, and emissions in cities. This paper considers a university district consisting of 32 buildings where electrical demand is currently met by the national grid, and 31% of thermal demand is supplied by a centralized heating station through a district heating network; the remainder is covered by small, dedicated boilers. Starting from the present system, the goal is to identify &#8220;retrofit&#8221; design solutions to reduce cost, environmental impact, and the primary energy consumption of the district. To this end, three new configurations of the multi-energy system (MES) of the district are proposed considering (i) the installation of new energy conversion and storage units, (ii) the enlargement of the existing district heating network, and (iii) the inclusion of new branches of the electrical and heating network. The configurations differ in increasing levels of integration through the energy networks. The results show that the installation of cogeneration engines leads to significant benefits in both economic (up to &#8722;12.3% of total annual costs) and energy (up to &#8722;10.2% of the primary energy consumption) terms; these benefits increase as the level of integration increases. On the other hand, the limited availability of space for photovoltaics results in increased CO2 emissions when only total cost minimization is considered. However, by accepting a cost increase of 8.4% over the least expensive solution, a significant reduction in CO2 (&#8722;23.9%) can be achieved while still keeping total costs lower than the existing MES.</description>
      <author>L. Bacci, Enrico Dal Cin, Gianluca Carraro, Sergio Rech, Andrea Lazzaretto</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en18020413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential of Rice Straw as a Carbon Source in Organic Rice Farming and its Effect on Global Warming Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58297/hnzh8897</link>
      <description>Surekha Kuchi, M Pragnya, Kumar RM, P. Brajendra, Sundaram RM, Journal of Rice Research. 17(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406625542

                The potential benefits of rice straw in organic farming in terms of rice productivity, soil organic carbon (SOC) stocks, carbon sequestration rate (CSR) and global warming potential (GWP) were studied for five years covering 10 wet (kharif) and dry (rabi) seasons with a wide seasonal temperature range (28-31 C and 30-40 C during wet and dry seasons, respectively). Field experiments were conducted at the ICAR-IIRR, Hyderabad, in a black clayey vertisol. The organic sources used were rice straw + green manure in kharif and rice straw + poultry manure in rabi. Organic system resulted in initial yield reduction by 15-20 % than inorganic system and yields stabilized after two and five years in wet and dry seasons, respectively, with improved soil health parameters. The SOC stocks were higher with organics by 34-43 % compared to inorganics after five years of study. The CSR was also positive with organics (0.97 and 0.57 t/ha/ year during wet and dry seasons, respectively) compared to inorganics (-021 and -0.33 t/ha/year during wet and dry seasons, respectively) which recorded negative C sequestration rate. Organics recorded favourable C sequestration even under dry situations which is more desirable to mitigate the adverse effects of global warming to certain extent by reducing CO2 emissions. The global warming potential under organic system was 20 % higher than in conventional system with increased CO2 and CH4 and reduced N2O emissions. Since GWP was higher with rice straw, mixing of straw with other potential organics in proper proportions reduce the GWP in addition to carbon sequestration in organic rice cultivation.</description>
      <author>Surekha Kuchi, M Pragnya, Kumar RM, P. Brajendra, Sundaram RM</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58297/hnzh8897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy and climate policy implications on the deployment of low-carbon ammonia technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56006-6</link>
      <description>Chi Kong Chyong, Eduardo Italiani, Nikolaos Kazantzis, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406529630

                The economic feasibility of low-carbon ammonia production pathways, such as steam methane reforming with carbon capture and storage, biomass gasification, and electrolysis, is assessed under various policy frameworks, including subsidies, carbon pricing, and renewable hydrogen regulations. Here, we show that employing a stochastic techno-economic analysis at the plant level and a net present value approach under the US Inflation Reduction Act reveals that carbon capture and biomass pathways demonstrate strong economic potential due to cost-effectiveness and minimal public support needs. Conversely, the electrolytic pathway faces significant economic challenges due to higher costs and lower efficiency. We conclude that efficient decarbonization of ammonia production requires adapting the Haber-Bosch process for variable bioenergy quality, ensuring safe CO2 transport and storage, advancing research to lower costs and improve efficiency in renewable energy and storage technologies, as well as creating a technologically neutral policy framework.</description>
      <author>Chi Kong Chyong, Eduardo Italiani, Nikolaos Kazantzis</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56006-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avalia&#231;&#227;o de concretos produzidos com variadas areias de minera&#231;&#227;o: em busca de dosagens de alto desempenho e sustent&#225;veis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.19180/1809-2667.v26n22024.23416</link>
      <description>Carlos Augusto De Melo BARBOSA, Mariana Figueira Lacerda Menezes, V&#233;rtices. 26(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406587467

                The sand from the processing of iron ore has been widely used in civil construction in Brazil, especially in the states of Minas Gerais, Esp&#237;rito Santo and S&#227;o Paulo. It is used as fine aggregate in the production of mortars, cement products and concrete. With the possibility of producing new sand in several iron ore mines in the state of Minas Gerais, the present study aimed to develop and analyze concrete dosages with various ore sands and sands present in the industrial market in the Belo Horizonte region. The replacement of natural river sand with mining sand in concrete dosages was evaluated and the Abrams curves were analyzed for the various dosages developed. It was possible to observe a performance gain in the dosages carried out with ore sands, with a reduction of up to 7% in cement consumption in the mixes. Thus, it can be concluded that the use of mining sand in the production of concrete is efficient, with technical and productive gains, promoting sustainable construction, reducing CO2 and promoting the circular economy in the construction chain.</description>
      <author>Carlos Augusto De Melo BARBOSA, Mariana Figueira Lacerda Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.19180/1809-2667.v26n22024.23416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental investigation of bluff body geometry effects on nitrogen oxides emissions from Cambridge stratified burner</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-86198-2</link>
      <description>Mahmood Nahvi, Kiumars Mazaheri, Mohammad Zabetian Targhi, Fatemeh Eskandari, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406475665

                In this study, a series of experiments are done to analyze the effect of bluff body geometry on the NOx reduction of a natural gas-air stratified swirl burner. The stratified burner of Cambridge University is chosen to study the mentioned geometrical effect, and the geometry modification of bluff body is used as a simple method for NOx reduction, which can be easily applied to the systems using these burners, including gas turbines. The bluff body geometrical change to an annular bluff body is inspired by the fact that the areas in which the edge of the bluff body is in contact with the unburned flow have lower temperatures, which can drastically affect combustion parameters, especially emissions. This new geometry is called the Annular Bluff body Stratified Burner, ABSB. The comparison of the mentioned burners is made for three equivalence ratios, &#1060;, stratification cases: premixed, moderately stratified, and highly stratified with a global equivalence ratio of 0.75, in the conditions of atmospheric pressure and the temperature of the inlet mixture of 26 degrees of Celsius. Flame spectroscopy compares the chemiluminescence intensities of OH*, CH*, C2*, H2O*, and CO2*. Digital image processing, flame edge detection, and exhaust gas analysis are also utilized to measure flames' general dimensions and emissions. According to experiments, for ABSB cases, a general decrease of about 14% in Nitrogen Oxides, especially NO and NO2, and an increase of about 17% in Carbon Monoxide are observed. Besides, the average bluff body temperature dropped by about 20% in ABSB for all three stratification cases.</description>
      <author>Mahmood Nahvi, Kiumars Mazaheri, Mohammad Zabetian Targhi, Fatemeh Eskandari</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-86198-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using satellite-based sun-induced chlorophyll fluorescence and spectral reflectance for improving terrestrial CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; flux estimates of India</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2752-664x/adabed</link>
      <description>Aparnna Ravi, Dhanyalekshmi Pillai, Christoph Gerbig, Stephen Sitch, S&#246;nke Zaehle, Vishnu Thilakan, Chandra Shekhar Jha, Thara Anna Mathew, Environmental Research Ecology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406607516

                Abstract Significant uncertainties in terrestrial carbon fluxes exist in regions with limited ground-based observations, impacting our understanding of ecosystem carbon dynamics and emission reduction needs. This is particularly true for areas with sparse measurement networks, like India. To address this, we explore the potential of satellite measurements from various missions such as Sentinel-5 Precursor (S5P) and the Orbiting Carbon Observatory-2 (OCO-2) to improve terrestrial biosphere CO2 fluxes of India. We follow a data-driven approach, which simulates spatial and temporal distributions of Gross Primary Productivity (GPP), Net Ecosystem Exchange (NEE), and ecosystem Respiration (Reco). We improve these model predictions by additionally using satellite-based Solar Induced chlorophyll Fluorescence (SIF), Soil Temperature (ST), and Soil Moisture (SM) specific to the vegetation classes of the domain. Different model refinements were performed to present the improved hourly distributions of terrestrial biospheric CO2 fluxes on a 0.1&#9702;&#215;0.1&#9702; grid from 2012 to 2020. Among them, the best-performing model simulations show reasonable agreement with eddy covariance observations for 2012 - 2018. For example, our best NEE and GPP predictions are highly correlated with observations with squared correlation coefficient (R2) values of 0.68 (NEE) and 0.74 (GPP) at the monthly scale for 2018. Based on our improved estimations, the annual NEE and GPP show values within the range from -0.38 Pg C yr-1 to -0.53 Pg C yr-1 (land C sink) and 3.39 Pg C yr-1 to 3.88 Pg C yr-1, respectively over India for 2012 - 2020. Our novel approach and findings highlight the potential of satellite-based SIF measurements to detail the ecosystem-scale vegetation responses across various biomes in India. The use of satellite observations, as demonstrated in this study, offers a scalable solution for regions lacking sufficient ground-based observations to estimate biospheric carbon fluxes reliably.</description>
      <author>Aparnna Ravi, Dhanyalekshmi Pillai, Christoph Gerbig, Stephen Sitch, S&#246;nke Zaehle, Vishnu Thilakan, Chandra Shekhar Jha, Thara Anna Mathew</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2752-664x/adabed</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of COVID-19 on the Yearly Concentration Reduction of Three Criteria Air Pollutants and Meteorological Parameters&#8217; Effects on Aerosol Dispersion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46488/nept.2024.v24is1.004</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Manuel Vassallo, Ahmed N. Bdour, Nature Environment and Pollution Technology. 24(S1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406532221

                The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the reduction percentage in the yearly concentrations of sulfur dioxide (SO2), nitrogen dioxide (NO2), and CO before and after COVID-19 in Amman, the capital city of Jordan, which has the highest population and traffic densities, and Zarqa, an industrial area with 55% of different types of industries. Additionally, this study examines the effect of metrological parameters such as temperature, humidity, and wind speed on air pollutant dispersion, particularly particulate matter 10 (PM10), which is considered uncontrollable. Furthermore, this study highlights the critical environmental and health effects of air pollution. The Ministry of Environment measured the yearly concentration of air pollutants (SO2, NO2, CO, and PM10) in three areas (Amman, Zarqa, and Irbid) in 12 stations in nearby industrial, urban, and traffic areas using the nitric oxide (NO) NO2 chemiluminescence analyzer Model 42i, hydrogen sulfide (H2S) and SO2 analyzer model 450iQ, and PM10 Peta Attenuation analyzer. The few air pollution studies in Jordan have primarily focused on average yearly concentrations of SO2, NO2, CO, and PM10 without considering the monthly or daily variations that greatly concern health and the environment. The results of the present study reveal that during the COVID-19 pandemic, there was a significant decrease in the annual concentrations of H2S, SO2, and NO2 as the reduction percentage in Amman 70, 58, 87% respectively, and in Zarqa 36, 62, 72% respectively. However, there is a slight reduction in CO and PM10 with 39 and 18% at Amman and 19% and 40% at Zarqa. This decrease is attributed to the reduction of primary sources of air pollutants, which are linked to the reductions in traffic volume and industrial activities during the lockdown. Furthermore, the results show that the Jordanian government has implemented regulations to address air pollution in residential areas. These regulations aim to prevent the burning of trees and smoking. The government is also adopting new transportation technologies to reduce the impact of CO2 and other pollutants produced by diesel and gasoline vehicles. The use of green fuels like synthetic natural gas, green methanol, or ammonia, as well as the increasing use of electric cars, are being encouraged. Implementing the bus rapid transit system, which started in 2021 and includes linked lines in the east and west areas of Jordan, has reduced the number of cars used and solved the main issues in crowded regions. Overall, the country has taken significant steps to address and control air pollution.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Manuel Vassallo, Ahmed N. Bdour</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46488/nept.2024.v24is1.004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential for reducing urban emissions with Semarang City pedestrian paths</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202560503016</link>
      <description>Kirana Prasetya Azizah, Bagus Hario Setiadji, Haryono Setiyo Huboyo, Andy Fefta Wijaya, E3S Web of Conferences. 605(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406488539

                Semarang City, as one of the big cities in Indonesia, faces significant challenges related to greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, most of which come from the transportation sector. These emissions contribute to climate change and the decline in air quality in the city. This study explores the potential for reducing GHG emissions through the development of pedestrian paths in Semarang. By analyzing transportation emission data and the coverage of existing pedestrian paths, this study assesses the effectiveness of pedestrian path development in reducing emissions and improving urban quality of life. The methodology used includes GHG emission analysis, assessment of the area and coverage of pedestrian paths, and emission reduction projection models based on user survey data. Currently, only around 20% of the total roads in Semarang City have been built for pedestrian paths. By expanding and improving the quality of pedestrian paths, the potential for reducing CO2 emissions can reach 11% of total transportation emissions. This study suggests further development of pedestrian paths by considering factors such as comfort, accessibility, and connectivity to public transportation. This development not only has the potential to reduce GHG emissions but also increasing the resilience of cities to global climate change.</description>
      <author>Kirana Prasetya Azizah, Bagus Hario Setiadji, Haryono Setiyo Huboyo, Andy Fefta Wijaya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202560503016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Literature Review of Laser Assisted Periodontal Therapy Efficacy and Safety</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32592/3dj.13.1.17</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406626784

                This study aims to compare previous studies using lasers to evaluate the efficacy and safety of laser therapy adjacent to traditional methods. PubMed and Cochrane search engines were used to identify previous studies of laser assisted periodontal therapy. 29 articles were selected after applying specific keywords, additional filters, inclusion and exclusion criteria between the years 2018 and 2024 out of 107,255 articles. The results have indicated the efficacy of Nd:YAG, diode and CO2 laser for frenectomy.A single study using Er:YAG showed a decrease in operation and bleeding time. Er:YAG, Er, Cr:YSGG and diode have shown an efficacy for second-stage surgery of submerged implants. 2780 nm Er,Cr:YSGG used for crown lengthening surgery have shown a stable height increase after surgery unlike the conventional group. Nd;YAG showed a significant difference while Er,Cr:YSGG haven&#8217;t in gingivectomy and osteotomy. Significant improved healing was shown using a ER:YAG and 660,940 and 980 nm diode for regenerative surgical therapy. Laser techniques using a 2940 nm Er:YAG and 980 nm Diode laser were efficient for gingival depigmentation. 1064 nm Nd:YAG showed a significant difference while 810 nm diode, PDT and Er:YAG laser haven&#8217;t in comparison with the traditional method in reduction of bacteria. Studies reported a significant reduction in the average dental pain range using 808, 940, 980 nm diode and 2780 nm Er,Cr:YSGG laser. laser assisted treatments in variety of peridontal therapies was efficient and safe considering the wavelength and type of laser for each therapy</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32592/3dj.13.1.17</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;Caking&#8221; Process in Green Cement Composites under the Impact of Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.23947/2949-1835-2024-3-4-74-81</link>
      <description>Aleksandr Khalyushev, E. A. Kolesnichenko, Modern Trends in Construction Urban and Territorial Planning. 3(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406473825

                Introduction. The problems of resource and energy saving during production of cements and concretes on their basis are of great importance in the world. An important trend in solving these problems is the development of green cements, which contain various mineral additives of natural and anthropogenic origin. The advantages of the green cements compared to the clinker-based cements are revealed from both the environmental point of view &#8212; reduction of carbon dioxide emissions into the atmosphere, use of the industrial by-products, and the technical point of view &#8212; improvement of the technological properties of concrete mixes, improvement of the physical, mechanical and operational properties of con[1]cretes. At the same time, replacement of the clinker component in Portland cement by the mineral components leads to the change of the physical and mechanical properties of cement, including that taking place during the &#8220;caking&#8221; process in conditions of interaction with the environment. The research presented in the paper aims at studying the effect of long-term storage of plain cements and green cement composites in conditions of free interaction with the environment on the physical and mechanical properties of the cement stone. Materials and Methods. Various types of cements were used in the experiments. Green cement composites were obtained in the laboratory by intergrinding with the slag and fly-ash respectively. To improve the grinding process and inhibit the sorption process, a grinding intensifying agent was added into the composition of green cement composites. The impact of the environment on the cement sorption process was assessed by measuring indirect parameters: specific surface area, angle of natural repose, bulk density and cement stone compressive strength. Results. The obtained results indicate that the specific surface area of cement samples stored in the open air for 30 days reduces significantly due to the &#8220;caking&#8221; process, on average by 25% in type I cements, whereas in green cement composites this process is less intense and amounts to 15%. A similar consistent pattern is observed when measuring the angle of repose and bulk density. The decrease in the angle of repose and high values of bulk density for type I cement are related to the active sorption of moisture from the environment, which leads to the formation of hydrate &#8220;bridges&#8221; upon interaction of particles. Compared to the control samples, the compressive strength in the cement stone samples tested at the age of 28 days of curing decreases on average by 25&#8211;30% in type I cements and by a less extent of 15&#8211;20% in green cement composites. Discussion and Conclusion. When storing different types of cement in conditions of free interaction with the environment, moisture is sorbed and the hydrate &#8220;bridges&#8221; are formed on the surface of the particles. This process goes more intensely in type I cement due to the highly active surfaces of its particles, which hydrate faster, resulting in a decrease of cement activity by 30%. At the same time, the green cement composites lose their activity less significantly &#8211; by 20%. This consistent pattern can be explained by the less active surfaces of the particles of mineral additives included into the composition, as well as by addition of a grinding intensifying agent into a composition.</description>
      <author>Aleksandr Khalyushev, E. A. Kolesnichenko</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.23947/2949-1835-2024-3-4-74-81</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LOW CARBON DEVELOPMENT STRATEGY ON LAND USE SECTOR IN CILIWUNG MIDDLE-STREAM WATERSHED</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59465/ijfr.2015.2.1.55-69</link>
      <description>Gamma Nur Merrillia Sularso, Rudy P. Tambunan, Andreo Wahyudi Atmoko, Indonesian Journal of Forestry Research. 2(1)] 2015. https://openalex.org/W4406605741

                The second (2nd) and third (3rd) segment of Ciliwung middle-stream watershed land use have changed drastically over the past two decades. The second (2nd) and third (3rd) segment of Ciliwung middle-stream watershed land use have changed drastically over the past two decades. This paper analyses the land use change from 1989-2012 and its impact on decreasing carbon stock or increasing CO2 eq emission, as well as to establish projected Reference Level (RL) to 2020. Best RL projection was used to establish the Low Carbon Development Strategy (LCDS) in both segments. The land use changing from 1989-2012 indicated a reduction of green space area by 2,575.57 ha whereas the non-green space area increased by 2,575.57 ha. These changes decreases the carbon stock by 26,900 ton C and released CO eq emission by about 98,723 ton CO2eq. Population growth, demand on land and land constraints were found to be the driving factors of land use changes in this area. Reference Level 2020 was established based on business as usual (BAU) and forward looking (FL) scenarios. The projection showed that FL was the best scenario which estimated carbon storage at 217,610 ton C in 2020. Low carbon development strategy directed to the area of green space added up to 20% carbon storage through the implementation of the strategy based on green space and non-green space which covered the areas from protection, supervision, extension or awareness and law enforcement.</description>
      <author>Gamma Nur Merrillia Sularso, Rudy P. Tambunan, Andreo Wahyudi Atmoko</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59465/ijfr.2015.2.1.55-69</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen Electrochemical Reduction Reaction Pathways Evidenced by Online Electrochemical Mass Spectrometry and Isotope Labeling on the MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00135</link>
      <description>Rodrigo Gomes de Araujo, Joelma Perez, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406530056

                The electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) for ammonia production is a promising method for mitigating CO2 emissions. In this study, we investigate the NRR in alkaline media using both labeled and unlabeled compounds on MoS2 electrodes, employing online electrochemical mass spectrometry (OLEMS) and UV-vis spectroscopy to identify gaseous and solution-phase products, respectively. Notably, OLEMS results reveal the detection of N2H+ and N2H2+ species as intermediates of the NRR, following the observation of N2 consumption at &#8722;0.4 V vs. RHE and the onset of NH3 production around &#8722;0.5 V vs. RHE. However, N2H3+ and N2H4+ species were not observed. UV-vis spectroscopy confirmed the production of NH3. The N2 molecule first adsorbs onto the catalyst surface, leading to two consecutive protonation steps and the formation of N2H and N2H2 intermediates at potentials below &#8722;0.4 V. N2H2 is identified as the predominant intermediate in ammonia production. For the first time, this study, utilizing isotope labeling and OLEMS, has enabled the identification of key NRR intermediates, the correlation of NH3 production with N2 consumption as a function of applied potential, and has provided crucial insights into this important reaction. A comprehensive understanding of the NRR mechanism will facilitate the development of high-performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Rodrigo Gomes de Araujo, Joelma Perez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Transformation and Degradation of Cu Oxide Nanocatalysts during Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14720</link>
      <description>Soo Hong Lee, Jaime E. Avil&#233;s Acosta, Daewon Lee, David M. Larson, Hui Li, Junjie Chen, Jin&#8208;Young Lee, Ezgi Erdem, Dong Un Lee, S. Blair, Alessandro Gallo, Haimei Zheng, Adam C. Nielander, Christopher J. Tassone, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Walter S. Drisdell, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406474470

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) holds enormous potential as a carbon-neutral route to the sustainable production of fuels and platform chemicals. The durability for long-term operation is currently inadequate for commercialization, however, and the underlying deactivation process remains elusive. A fundamental understanding of the degradation mechanism of electrocatalysts, which can dictate the overall device performance, is needed. In this work, we report the structural dynamics and degradation pathway of Cu oxide nanoparticles (CuOx NPs) during the CO2RR by using in situ small-angle X-ray scattering (SAXS) and X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS). The in situ SAXS reveals a reduction in the size of NPs when subjected to a potential at which no reaction products are detected. At potentials where the CO2RR starts to occur, CuOx NPs are agglomerated through a particle migration and coalescence process in the early stage of the reaction, followed by Ostwald ripening (OR) as the dominant degradation mechanism for the remainder of the reaction. As the applied potential becomes more negative, the OR process becomes more dominant, and for the most negative applied potential, OR dominates for the entire reaction time. The morphological changes are linked to a gradual decrease in the formation rate for multicarbon products (C2H4 and ethanol). Other reaction parameters, including reaction intermediates and local high pH, induce changes in the agglomeration process and final morphology of the CuOx NPs electrode, supported by post-mortem ex situ microscopic analysis. The in situ XAS analysis suggests that the CuOx NPs reduced into the metallic state before the structural transformation was observed. The introduction of high surface area carbon supports with ionomer coating mitigates the degree of structural transformation and detachment of the CuOx NPs electrode. These findings show the dynamic nature of Cu nanocatalysts during the CO2RR and can serve as a rational guideline toward a stable catalyst system under electrochemical conditions.</description>
      <author>Soo Hong Lee, Jaime E. Avil&#233;s Acosta, Daewon Lee, David M. Larson, Hui Li, Junjie Chen, Jin&#8208;Young Lee, Ezgi Erdem, Dong Un Lee, S. Blair, Alessandro Gallo, Haimei Zheng, Adam C. Nielander, Christopher J. Tassone, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Walter S. Drisdell</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14720</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Industrial Energy Supply Systems with Integrated Renewable Energy, CCUS, and Energy Storage: A Comprehensive Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020712</link>
      <description>Liujian Yang, Xingyu Wu, Beijia Huang, Zeqiu Li, Sustainability. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406614236

                With the increasing emphasis on emission reduction targets, the low-carbon sustainable transformation of industrial energy supply systems is crucial. Addressing the urgent issue of reducing industrial carbon emissions, this study presents an integrated industrial energy supply system (IRE-CCUS-BESS-SPS) that incorporates renewable energy; calcium-based carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS); and battery energy storage systems (BESSs) to improve energy efficiency and sustainability. The system model is designed to achieve a cost-effective and environmentally low-impact energy supply, validated through Aspen Plus V11.0 and Matlab R2019b simulations. The system&#8217;s performance is evaluated using a 4E index system encompassing economy, environment, energy, and exergy. The findings indicate that the system&#8217;s lifetime net present value (NPV) is positive, with a payback period of 6.09 years. Despite a 12.9% increase in the overall economic cost, carbon emissions are significantly reduced by 59.78%. The energy supply composition includes 48.60% from fuel oil and 22.10% from biomass, with an additional 270.04 kW of heat provided by waste heat boilers. The equalization costs for CO2 removal (LCCR) and methanation (LCOM) are 122.95 CNY/t and 10908.35 CNY/t, respectively, both exceeding current carbon emission trading costs and methane prices. This research offers a robust framework for designing sustainable industrial energy systems that integrate renewable energy, CCUS, and energy storage technologies for low-carbon operations. The analysis also suggests that government policies, such as direct financial subsidies or tax relief, are effective in accelerating the adoption of CCUS technology.</description>
      <author>Liujian Yang, Xingyu Wu, Beijia Huang, Zeqiu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17020712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration, Stability, and Doping of Mono-Elemental and Binary Transition Metal Dichalcogenide Van der Waals Solids for Electronics and Sensing Devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12794/metadc1944314</link>
      <description>Ravindra K. Mehta, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4406492875

                In this work, we have explored 2D semiconducting transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs), black phosphorus (BP), and graphene for various applications using liquid and mechanical exfoliation routes. The topical areas of interest that motivate our work include considering factors such as device integration, stability, doping, and the effect of gasses to modulate the electronic transport characteristics of the underlying 2D materials. In the first area, we have integrated solution-processed transparent conducting oxides (TCOs), specifically indium-doped tin oxide (ITO) with BP, which is a commonly used TCO for solar cell devices. Here we have found surface treatment of glass substrates with a plasma before spin-coating the solution-processed ITO, to be effective in improving coverage and uniformity of the ITO film by promoting wettability and film adhesion. The maximum transmittance obtained was measured to be ~75% in the visible region, while electrical measurements made on BP/ITO heterostructures showed improved transport characteristics compared to the bare ITO film. Within the integration realm, inkjet-printing of BP and MoS2 p-n hetero-junctions on standard ITO glass substrates in a vertical architecture was also demonstrated. To address the issue of stability which some 2D materials such as BP face, we experimented with ionic liquids (ILs) to passivation the hydrophilic surface of BP to minimize its oxidative degradation. The enhanced stability of BP was inferred through Raman spectroscopy and scanning probe microscopy techniques, where no observable changes in the A1g and A2g Raman vibrational modes were observed for the BP films passivated with ILs over time under ambient conditions. On the other hand, a blue-shift in these Raman modes was evident for unpassivated samples. Atomic force microscopy measurements on the unpassivated samples clearly revealed the difference in surface characteristics through localized regions of degradation that intensified with time which was absent in IL passivated BP samples. The electronic device measurements for IL coated BP devices showed a more stabilized Ids&#8722;Vds characteristic in the 5.4 K to 335 K temperature range. Prototypical demonstrations of stabilized ILs/BP devices at ambient printed on flexible polyimide substrates were also successfully made. At the same time, doping is one of the essential steps required for the modulation of carrier density and electronic transport in electronic and optoelectronic devices, which is the third topical area we have addressed in this work with semiconducting TMDs. Of the conventional approaches used to dope 3D semiconductors, ion-implantation is commonly adopted but given the ultra-thin nature of 2D materials, this approach is not feasible as it causes severe damage to the delicate crystalline lattice of ultra-thin 2D membranes. Instead, we have used plasma-based doping routes with UV-ozone treatement and solution processing using 1,2 dichloroethane, to characterize the temperature-dependent two-terminal and three-terminal electronic and optoelectronic transport of mechanically exfoliated 2D MoS2 and WSe2. A significant difference was seen in the optoelectronic properties between the two dopants, owing to differences in their respective doping mechanisms and the intrinsic structural attributes of the exfoliated flakes. A significant reduction in barrier height was evident after doping using both techniques in MoS2, while an increase in barrier height after soaking in 1,2 dichloroethane was seen in WSe2. Lastly, in the fourth topical area for sensing devices, we have studied the effect of gas-flow in inkjet-printed and spin-coated graphene and MoS2 to modulate the electronic transport for the 2D materials since their increased surface area is an ideal platform to observe interactions with external stimuli, in this case, in-coming gas species. Here, the chamber pressure and change in current with flow of gas was measured in the steady-state, as well as time-dependent dynamic transport toward nitrogen and carbon dioxide. We observed significant differences in the electrical response of mono-elemental graphene and binary MoS2, owing to differences in microstructure and joule heating response to the ambient gas. In conclusion, the findings obtained from our work will provide an important framework to help guide strategies in further improving integration schemes, stability, doping and sensing behavior driven by the unique structural attributes inherent to 2D materials for high-performance devices in the future.</description>
      <author>Ravindra K. Mehta</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12794/metadc1944314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing biochar's impact on greenhouse gas emissions, microbial biomass, and enzyme activities in agricultural soils through meta-analysis and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2025.178541</link>
      <description>Jinze Bai, Bruno Rafael de Almeida Moreira, Yuxin Bai, Cresha Gracy Nadar, Yongzhong Feng, Sudhir Yadav, The Science of The Total Environment. 963(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406517528

                The role of biochar in reducing greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions and improving soil health is a topic of extensive research, yet its effects remain debated. Conflicting evidence exists regarding biochar's impact on soil microbial-mediated emissions with respect to different GHGs. This study systematically examines these divergent perspectives, aiming to investigate biochar's influence on GHG emissions and soil health in agricultural soils. The meta-analysis includes 2594 paired observations from 157 studies conducted between 2000 and 2024. It was found that biochar increased the presence of amoA and nosZ genes by 39.4 % and 41.7 %, respectively, while reducing the abundance of the nirS gene by 17.8 %. This led to a 13.1 % decrease in N2O emissions. Nitrous emissions were positively associated with mean annual temperature and biochar's pyrolysis temperature and dosage while inversely related to soil pH, nitrogen fertilisation rate, and biochar pH and carbon content. Biochar also regulated enzyme activity related to the nutrient cycle and increased microbial biomass carbon, nitrogen, and phosphorus by 16.6 %, 23.9 %, and 50.2 %, respectively, leading to changes in microbial community diversity. These changes contributed to a reduction in CO2 and CH4 emissions, particularly when biochar and nitrogen fertiliser were applied at doses below 21.4 t ha-1 and 242.5 kg ha-1, as predicted by machine learning models. This study offers an overview of the positive impact of biochar amendments on soil GHG emissions mitigation. The key predictive factors identified could help optimise biochar production and targeted amendments, potentially improving soil health and achieving carbon neutrality in agroecosystems.</description>
      <author>Jinze Bai, Bruno Rafael de Almeida Moreira, Yuxin Bai, Cresha Gracy Nadar, Yongzhong Feng, Sudhir Yadav</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2025.178541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of lemongrass and oregano essential oils and their combination on &lt;i&gt;in vitro&lt;/i&gt; ruminal fermentation and greenhouse gas emissions in total mixed ration for dairy cows</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/1828051x.2025.2450509</link>
      <description>Sara Glorio Patrucco, Alessandro Lotto, Martina Dorigo, Rita Fornaciari, Antonio Sagliano, Nicola Martinelli, Alessandra Cosani, Khalil Abid, Salvatore Barbera, Hatsumi Kaihara, Sonia Tassone, Italian Journal of Animal Science. 24(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406589720

                Ruminants play a crucial role in the food chain, but are also considered contributors of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions . Essential oils (EOs) are emerging as natural feed additives in ruminants' nutrition to enhance animal health, performance and reduce environmental footprint. Among EOs, lemongrass (Cymbopogon winterianus) and oregano (Origanum vulgare) EOs (LEO and OEO) have attracted attention as modulators of ruminal fermentations, but their role needs to be clarified. The experiment was designed using a randomised setup to assess the effects of LEO and OEO on in vitro ruminal fermentation and GHGs, using total mixed ration (TMR) as substrate (incubation time 24h). Experimental treatments included (doses as % of TMR on DM basis): 1) control only TMR (0% EOs) 2) 0.07% LEO 3) 0.07% OEO 4) 0.035% LEO + 0.035% OEO 5) 0.07% LEO + 0.07% OEO. Each treatment was repeated three times in two experimental runs. Only EO combinations reduced total gas (&#8722;9%, p=0.001). All EOs decreased CO2 emissions by &#8722;5 to &#8722;12% with no significant differences between treatments (p&lt;0.001), although anti-methanogenic effects were not observed (p=0.192). Volatile fatty acids were slightly affected only by EOs blend at the highest dose, resulting in a reduction of propionate (&#8722;1.3%, p=0.02), an increase in acetate:propionate (+0.16%, p=0.04) and isovalerate (+0.7%, p=0.03). LEO reduced pH (&#8722;0.6%, p=0.004), while OEO increased oxidation capacity (+4.2%, p=0.004), but both parameters remained within physiological ranges. Canonical discriminant analysis confirmed distinct EOs effects, highlighting their potential as natural additives for improving ruminal fermentation and mitigating ruminant environmental footprint.</description>
      <author>Sara Glorio Patrucco, Alessandro Lotto, Martina Dorigo, Rita Fornaciari, Antonio Sagliano, Nicola Martinelli, Alessandra Cosani, Khalil Abid, Salvatore Barbera, Hatsumi Kaihara, Sonia Tassone</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/1828051x.2025.2450509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biochar and bentonite application improves aeolian sandy soil health and enhances soil carbon sequestration and emission reduction potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-86636-1</link>
      <description>Liang Weijing, Tang Jiaxi, Li Yu, Song Sizhu, Xiaoyu Jiang, Hao Liyu, Tao Shuyu, He Miaomiao, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406488018

                Aeolian sandy soil is barren and readily leads to low fertilizer utilization rates and yields. Therefore, it is imperative to improve the water and fertilizer retention capacity of these soils. In this paper, three kinds of biochar (rice husk, corn stalk, and bamboo charcoal) and bentonite were used as amendments in the first year of the experiment. In the second year, only corn stalk biochar was applied. The effects of biochar and bentonite on the physicochemical and biological characteristics of aeolian sandy soil and corn agronomic traits were studied through a 2-year field experiment, and the carbon sequestration and emission reduction potential of biochar in aeolian sandy soil were explored. The results showed that the input of biochar and bentonite effectively improved water content and reduced soil bulk density. Compared with the same treatment in the first year, the content of water-stable aggregates with particle sizes greater than 0.25 mm, mean weight diameter and geometric mean diameter of the corn stalk biochar mixed with bentonite treatment significantly increased in the second year. Biochar and bentonite significantly increased the soil organic matter content, pH, cation exchange capacity (CEC) and available nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium contents, and CEC increased by 150.4%. Soil available phosphorus increased 2.6 times compared with that of the fertilizer treatment. Soil alkali-hydrolyzable nitrogen content increased by 211.5%, respectively. The plant height, leaf area index and ground dry matter mass also increased significantly, and the corn yield increased by 36.6% in response to the mixed application of 1.9 t/hm2 corn stalk biochar and 12 t/hm2 bentonite. The contents of urease, sucrase and catalase increased first and then decreased with crop growth through the jointing, silking and maturity stages. The microbial carbon content increased 2.4 times in the second year when corn stalk biochar was applied compared with that in the first year. The carbon sequestration potential of biochar application was equivalent to offsetting CO2 emissions by approximately 100 million tons per year of the study.</description>
      <author>Liang Weijing, Tang Jiaxi, Li Yu, Song Sizhu, Xiaoyu Jiang, Hao Liyu, Tao Shuyu, He Miaomiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-86636-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A GIS-Based Estimation of Bioenergy Potential from Cereal and Legume Straw Biomasses in Alentejo, Portugal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app15020868</link>
      <description>Abel Rodrigues, Alexandre Gon&#231;alves, Benvindo Ma&#231;&#227;s, A.M. Cordeiro, Paulo Brito, Applied Sciences. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406489209

                Portugal exhibits a large deficit in cereals with an import/export ratio of about 18%. Alentejo is a southern vast plain region, which is the largest cereal producer in the country, with about 80% of the total cereal area. The region also shows a huge local energy deficit with a ratio of about 17% between spent and produced energy. In this context, this work used GIS modeling based on available digital geographical information on soil and topographic conditions in Alentejo for estimating optimal production areas of four main classes of cereal and legume classes, which were wheat, barley, oat/lupin, and triticale/broad bean. The estimated areas were validated by 199 sample points in the field and allowed to quantify a potential of bioenergy production from straw biomasses based on yields of biomass net calorific values of 18 MJkg&#8722;1 and yields of 6, 9, 6, and 9 tons/ha for the four classes in the order indicated. The estimated areas allocated to the cereal and legume classes covered approximately four municipalities in the region. The total modeled area in Alentejo for the four cultivation classes was 44,980 ha. The results showed that even if 50% of the estimated total straw biomass produced was used for animal feed, the estimated bioenergy production of the remaining half biomass would be of about 2940 TJy&#8722;1, or about 12.5% of the actual regional energy production, which is an energy amount able to supply 35 organic Rankine cycle (ORC) 2.5 MW cogeneration units and 347 boilers with 125 kW thermal power, delivering renewable electricity to the grid, and heating facilities as diverse as buildings, nursing homes, or horticultural greenhouses. More than 160 kton of CO2 fossil emissions would also be avoided, delivering a contribution to mitigating effects of climate change. By contributing to the reduction of the large cereal dependence and the carbon emissions of the country, the proposed strategy would contribute to increasing the decentralized bioenergy production for applications in buildings and local facilities, significantly boosting the socio-economic dynamics of rural areas involved.</description>
      <author>Abel Rodrigues, Alexandre Gon&#231;alves, Benvindo Ma&#231;&#227;s, A.M. Cordeiro, Paulo Brito</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app15020868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Short Autobiography of Jens K. N&#248;rskov</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08365</link>
      <description>Jens K. N&#248;rskov, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. 129(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406474324

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. The Journal of Physical Chemistry CVol 129/Issue 2Article This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse Special Issue PrefaceJanuary 16, 2025Short Autobiography of Jens K. N&#248;rskovClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Jens K. N&#248;rskov*Jens K. N&#248;rskovDepartment of Physics, Technical University of Denmark, Kongens Lyngby, DK-2800 Denmark*[email protected]More by Jens K. N&#248;rskovOpen PDFThe Journal of Physical Chemistry CCite this: J. Phys. Chem. C 2025, 129, 2, 1027&#8211;1028Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08365https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08365Published January 16, 2025 Publication History Received 10 December 2024Published online 16 January 2025Published in issue 16 January 2025introductionCopyright &#169; Published 2025 by American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS PublicationsCopyright &#169; Published 2025 by American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.Activation energyAdsorptionCatalystsEnergyTransfer reactionsSpecial IssuePublished as part of The Journal of Physical Chemistry C special issue "Jens K. N&#248;rskov Festschrift".I received a PhD in physics from &#197;rhus University, Denmark, under the inspiring supervision of Bengt Lundqvist. After postdoc experiences at &#197;rhus University, IBM Yorktown Heights Research Laboratories, and the Nordic Institute for Theoretical Physics in Copenhagen, I found it hard to find a faculty position in Denmark in the early 1980s. There simply were no openings. Fortunately, I was offered a position at the Haldor Tops&#248;e Research Laboratories&#9472;strongly supported by Haldor Tops&#248;e, Henrik Tops&#248;e, and Bjerne Clausen. The involvement with the Tops&#248;e company, one of the world's largest suppliers of catalysts and technology for the chemical and energy industry, influenced my career in many ways. Most importantly, it became clear to me that a theory of heterogeneous catalysis was essential to further advance this important area of science and technology. I kept that focus when starting an academic career, and kept the association with the Tops&#248;e company, now serving on its Board of Directors.In the late 80s the Danish government started to realize that they were about to lose a whole generation of scientists and instituted some special professorships with applicants competing in all fields and at all universities in the country. That got me started at the Technical University of Denmark building up a research group with the funding that came with the professorship. The focus was on understanding surface reactivity as well as impurities in bulk metals.The impurity work started an extremely fruitful collaboration with Flemming Besenbacher at &#197;rhus University that continued for the next decades. With Besenbacher, I founded the Center for Atomic- scale Materials Physics with large-scale funding from the first round of grants from the Danish National Research Foundation. Here my group established the beginning of an understanding of the surface chemical bond. It started with simple models like the effective medium theory. Later, as more accurate density functional calculations became possible, it formed the foundation of the d-band model, or Hammer&#8211;N&#248;rskov model, of chemisorption. The model allowed an understanding of trends in bond energies of adsorbates on transition metal surfaces including variations from metal to metal, the effect of alloying, the effect of structure and defects, and the effect of strain. The interplay with the experimental groups of Flemming Besenbacher, Ib Chorkendorff and Anders Nilsson became extremely important in supporting the theory efforts.Combining DFT calculations of trends in adsorption energies and transition state energies of elemental surface processes with microkinetic modeling opened the possibility of calculating trends in full catalytic rates, for the first time. This also opened the possibility of making predictions for new catalysts, several of which were synthesized and tested in the groups of Claus Hviid Christensen and of Ib Chorkendorff.I established a Center for Atomic-scale Materials Design with Karsten Jacobsen, Kristian Thygesen, Thomas Bligaard, and Jan Rossmeisl in the late 2000s with funding from the Lundbeck Foundation. An important new effort was aimed at an understanding electrocatalysis. The theory of electrocatalysis was not nearly as developed as the theory of heterogeneous catalysis in terms of a quantitative description of processes and trends in reactivity. One aspect that makes the theoretical description of adsorption and reaction processes at the solid&#8211;liquid interface extremely demanding is the description of the solvated reactants. We developed the so-called computational hydrogen electrode, which opened up for a description of thermo-chemical trends in electrocatalysis. Our first application provided an understanding of trends in reactivity of different catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) providing insights into why Pt is the best elemental electrocatalyst for the cathode process in fuel cells, and how it can be made even better by alloying.The discovery of scaling relations between adsorption energies of different intermediates and between transition energies and adsorption energies opened the possibility of reducing the enormous complexity associated with the calculation of trends for full catalytic rates. We found that many adsorption energies of CHx species scaled and it took us some time to understand the physical basis for this amazing effect well enough to publish the result. Later, we found that this is extremely general. The fact that many activation energies scale with reaction energies, known as Br&#248;nsted&#8211;Evans&#8211;Polanyi relations, have been realized for many years. The scaling we discovered of adsorbed species is considerably more general than that. First, it includes scaling between adsorption energies of intermediates, and therefore transition state energies not only scale with reaction energies but with any chosen representative adsorption energy. This gives an enormous simplification.Moving to Stanford and SLAC in 2010, DOE funding to a new Catalysis center, SUNCAT, allowed a large expansion of the theory efforts, and Thomas Bligaard, Frank Abild Petersen, Felix Studt, and Alexandra Vojvodic moved along to SLAC to form the core theory group in this center. The Center also included a number of outstanding experimentalists, in particular Anders Nilsson, Tom Jaramillo, Matteo Cargnello, Stacey Bent, and Zhenan Bao.A systematic theory of transition metal catalysis was developed in those years. We showed that the scaling relations are extremely general for many surfaces and reactions, and eventually you can plot the rate as a function of a few adsorption energies, or descriptors, for any reaction in a volcano plot directly identifying the optimum catalyst. Sabatier had postulated such a relationship between a bond energy and the rate many years before. The scaling relations directly showed that a single or a few bond energies can in fact be used as a descriptor, it defined what the descriptor should be, and most importantly, it made volcano relations quantitative, allowing its use to search for new catalysts. Many reactions were analyzed including hydrogenation reactions and methane activation reactions.Another development that accelerated considerably during the time at Stanford was the description of electrochemical processes for energy conversion, including models of activation energies in electrocatalysis. This included the oxygen evolution reaction, the CO and CO2 reduction reactions and the N2 reduction reaction. For the latter we developed an understanding of the requirements for a high ammonia selectivity, something that laid the foundation for the thinking in the experimental groups we worked with (Ib Chorkendorff at DTU and Tom Jaramillo and Matteo Cargnello at Stanford).In 2018 I moved back to DTU in a Villum Kann Rasmussen Chair and with good funding from the Villum Foundation. I also took on the position as Chair of the Danish National Research Foundation. The work on electrochemical ammonia synthesis became a cornerstone. Additional work on thermal ammonia synthesis resulted in the discovery of a new promotion mechanism. Surfaces with a spin moment bind adsorbates weaker than the non spin polarized surface of the same metal, and certain adsorbates quench the spin in their vicinity and thus act as promotors by lowering the energy of transition state of important elementary steps. Experimental work in the Chorkendorff and Kibsgaard groups validated the effect for several ammonia synthesis catalysts. Another new effort was in translating the theory we developed to understand trends in heterogeneous catalysis to homogeneous catalysts. All of this work continues ....In all my career I have been fortunate to have worked with outstanding students and postdocs as well as some of the best scientists in the field. I have mentioned some of the colleagues in the above but it would be completely impossible to do all students and postdocs justice in this short piece. Let me just thank everyone profoundly. The picture above, taken at a conference celebrating my 70th birthday, shows many of the students and postdocs I have worked with over the years.Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorJens K. N&#248;rskov - Department of Physics, Technical University of Denmark, Kongens Lyngby, DK-2800 Denmark; Email: [email protected]NotesViews expressed in this preface are those of the author and not necessarily the views of the ACS.Cited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferences Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsThe Journal of Physical Chemistry CCite this: J. Phys. Chem. C 2025, 129, 2, 1027&#8211;1028Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08365Published January 16, 2025 Publication History Received 10 December 2024Published online 16 January 2025Published in issue 16 January 2025Copyright &#169; Published 2025 by American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesThis publication has no figures.This publication has no References.</description>
      <author>Jens K. N&#248;rskov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08365</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
