<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 01:07:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Utilization of carbon dioxide using electrochemical reduction: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205367</link>
      <description>Mansoor Al-Shamari, Ahmed Refaat Khodary, Dong Suk Han, Iqbal M. Mujtaba, Nejat Rahmanian, Gas science and engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399208285

                This article explores the electro-chemical Carbon dioxide Reduction Cell (eCO2RC), delving into fundamental principles, methods, applications, and the latest approaches for converting CO2 emissions into valuable products. Product outcomes depend on electron exchange and electrode surface attributes used in the CO2 reduction. The study focuses on C1 and C2 products, emphasizing the necessity for selective materials and catalysts to enhance product recovery while minimizing energy consumption. Converting eCO2 into valuable products is seen as a crucial method for transforming waste into value, addressing the challenge of mitigating global warming through gas emission reduction.</description>
      <author>Mansoor Al-Shamari, Ahmed Refaat Khodary, Dong Suk Han, Iqbal M. Mujtaba, Nejat Rahmanian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decorated and sculpted zeolitic imidazolate frameworks for electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction to formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118400</link>
      <description>Yanhong Zou, Yayu Guan, Yuyu Liu, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399258271

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanhong Zou, Yayu Guan, Yuyu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ construction of iron-modified nickel nanoparticles assisted by hexamethylenetetramine with the internal and external collaboration for highly selective electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.224</link>
      <description>Hongyu Chen, Zhaojie Wang, Hongzhi Cui, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Jun Guo, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Binbin Wei, Xiaoqing Lu, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399222860

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) electroreduction provides a sustainable route for realizing carbon neutrality and energy supply. Up to now, challenges remain in employing abundant and inexpensive nickel materials as candidates for CO2 reduction due to their low activity and favorable hydrogen evolution. Here, the representative iron-modified nickel nanoparticles embedded in nitrogen-doped carbon (Ni1-Fe0.125-NC) with the porous botryoid morphology were successfully developed. Hexamethylenetetramine is used as nitrogen-doped carbon source. The collaboration of internal lattice expansion with electron effect and external confinement effect with size effect endows the significant enhancement in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction. The optimized Ni1-Fe0.125-NC exhibits broad potential ranges for continuous carbon monoxide (CO) production. A superb CO Faradaic efficiency (FECO) of 85.0 % realized at &#8722;1.1 V maintains a longtime durability over 35 h, which exceeds many state-of-the-art metal catalysts. Theoretical calculations further confirm that electron redistribution promotes the desorption of CO in the process for favorable CO production. This work opens a new avenue to design efficient nickel-based materials by considering the intrinsic structure and external confinement for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Hongyu Chen, Zhaojie Wang, Hongzhi Cui, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Jun Guo, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Binbin Wei, Xiaoqing Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of Tin and Zinc Gas Diffusion Electrodes for Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46488/nept.2024.v23i02.038</link>
      <description>R. M. H. H. Jayarathne, Abdul Rahim Nihmiya, A.H.L.R. Nilmini, P. K. D. D. P. Pitigala, Nature, Environment and Pollution Technology/Nature, environment and pollution technology. 23(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399290554

                This study explores the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) using tin (Sn) and zinc (Zn) catalyst-loaded gas diffusion electrodes (GDEs). The research explores the influence of electrolytic potential and catalyst loading on the efficiency of CO2 conversion to valuable chemicals, specifically formic acid and carbon monoxide. The best Sn loading for Sn-loaded GDEs, according to the morphological study, is 7 mg.cm-2, which results in higher current density (0.33 mA.cm-2) and current efficiency (36%). An electrolytic potential of -1.3 V Vs. Ag/AgCl is identified as optimal for Sn GDEs, offering a balance between high current efficiency (35%) and controlled current density. For Zn-loaded GDEs, an optimal loading of 5 mg.cm&#178;- yields the highest current efficiency of 19.4% and a peak current density of 0.28 mA.cm&#178;- at an electrolytic potential of -1.55 V Vs. Ag/AgCl, in addition to highlighting the crucial role that catalyst loading and electrolytic potential play in enhancing CO2 reduction efficiency, this research offers insightful information for environmentally friendly CO2 conversion technology.</description>
      <author>R. M. H. H. Jayarathne, Abdul Rahim Nihmiya, A.H.L.R. Nilmini, P. K. D. D. P. Pitigala</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46488/nept.2024.v23i02.038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Accumulation and Stability Enhancement Effects Triggered by Built&#8208;in Electric Field of SnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/LaOCl Nanofibers Boost Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402654</link>
      <description>Hanjun Li, Honggang Huang, Wenshuai Huang, X.B. Zhang, Guangtong Hai, Feili Lai, Zhu Tong, Shuxing Bai, Nan Zhang, Tianxi Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399305728

                Abstract Constructing a built&#8208;in interfacial electric field (BIEF) is an effective approach to enhance the electrocatalysts performance, but it has been rarely demonstrated for electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) to date. Herein, for the first time, SnO 2 /LaOCl nanofibers (NFs) with BIEF is created by electrospinning, exhibiting a high Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 100% C 1 product (CO and HCOOH) at &#8722;0.9&#8211;&#8722;1.1 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) and a maximum FE HCOOH of 90.1% at &#8722;1.2 V RHE in H&#8208;cell, superior to the commercial SnO 2 nanoparticles (NPs) and LaOCl NFs. SnO 2 /LaOCl NFs also exhibit outstanding stability, maintaining negligible activity degradation even after 10 h of electrolysis. Moreover, their current density and FE HCOOH are almost 400 mA cm &#8722;2 at &#8722;2.31 V and 83.4% in flow&#8208;cell. The satisfactory CO 2 RR performance of SnO 2 /LaOCl NFs with BIEF can be ascribed to tight interface of coupling SnO 2 NPs and LaOCl NFs, which can induce charge redistribution, rich active sites, enhanced CO 2 adsorption, as well as optimized Gibbs free energy of *OCHO. The work reveals that the BIEF will trigger interfacial accumulation and stability enhancement effects in promoting CO 2 RR activity and stability of SnO 2 &#8208;based materials, providing a novel approach to develop stable and efficient CO 2 RR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hanjun Li, Honggang Huang, Wenshuai Huang, X.B. Zhang, Guangtong Hai, Feili Lai, Zhu Tong, Shuxing Bai, Nan Zhang, Tianxi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured Cobalt/Copper Catalysts for Efficient Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00909f</link>
      <description>Sharon Abner, Aicheng Chen, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399310990

                The search for an efficient and stable catalyst for the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to value-added chemicals is especially critical for dropping atmospheric CO2 concentration. In this study, self-supported cobalt/copper...</description>
      <author>Sharon Abner, Aicheng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00909f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metrics for quantifying the efficiency of atmospheric CO2 reduction by marine carbon dioxide removal (mCDR)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.171742811.17141982/v1</link>
      <description>K. Yamamoto, Tim DeVries, David A. Siegel, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399285203

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Yamamoto, Tim DeVries, David A. Siegel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.171742811.17141982/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Carbon Dioxide Emissions of IT Hardware</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-61069-1_17</link>
      <description>Kamil Hudaszek, Iwona Chomiak-Orsa, Saeed Abdullah M. AL-Dobai, IFIP advances in information and communication technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399259054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kamil Hudaszek, Iwona Chomiak-Orsa, Saeed Abdullah M. AL-Dobai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-61069-1_17</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barium titanate photocatalysts with silver-manganese dual cocatalyst for carbon dioxide reduction with water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01147c</link>
      <description>Shuwei Liu, Hongxuan Qiu, Akira Yamamoto, Hisao Yoshida, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239862

                Photocatalytic CO 2 reduction with water as an electron donor has attracted a lot of attention. Titanates with suitable cocatalysts are promising photocatalyst candidates for the reaction. Here, several barium titanates...</description>
      <author>Shuwei Liu, Hongxuan Qiu, Akira Yamamoto, Hisao Yoshida</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01147c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 reduction and hydrogenation assisted by microwaves</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4399313681</link>
      <description>Loren Acher, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric C. Meunier, A. Kaddouri, T. Caillot, Thamara Laredo, J. Gana, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399313681

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Loren Acher, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric C. Meunier, A. Kaddouri, T. Caillot, Thamara Laredo, J. Gana</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4399313681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured Mnmoo4 as a Trifunctional Electrocatalyst for Overall Water Splitting and Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853666</link>
      <description>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399337243

                Electrochemical water splitting and CO2 reduction are important processes to produce hydrogen and low&#8211;carbon fuels as renewable energy sources. Here, nanostructured MnMoO4, prepared by the reflux precipitation method, was investigated as a trifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions. Using a combination of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results, a direct band gap of 3.05 eV was obtained experimentally for the prepared MnMoO4. An overpotential of 0.36 V at a current density of 5 mA cm-2 and a Tafel slope of 58 mV dec-1 were obtained for the oxygen evolution reaction. At a current density of 3 mA cm-2, overpotentials of 0.39 V and 0.58 V were achieved in the absence and presence of CO2 bubbling into a 0.1 M KOH solution, respectively, emphasizing the poisoning effect of CO2 reduction intermediates for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Based on the obtained results, MnMoO4 could be a promising electrocatalyst for water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions.</description>
      <author>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking microwave-induced CO2 plasma splitting against electrochemical CO2 reduction for a comparison of promising technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102825</link>
      <description>A. Hecimovic, Matthew T. Mayer, L.G.J. de Haart, S. K. Gupta, C. Kiefer, Alexander Navarrete, Andreas Schulz, U. Fantz, Journal of CO2 utilization. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399217262

                Plasma conversion technology is an emerging technique under development to activate, convert or valorize gas molecules such as CO2, N2, CH4, NH3 and others. A large-scale application beyond the lab-scale demonstrator unit requires assessment of the efficiency of this new technology. The straightforward approach for assessment of the efficiency is benchmarking with the other well-established technologies of similar technology readiness level (TRL). In this paper we present a benchmarking of the atmospheric pressure microwave-induced CO2 plasma splitting with electrochemical CO2 conversion, via both low-temperature and high-temperature electrolysis. An additional step of oxygen removal in case of the plasma reactor is implemented due to the difference in the output stream of the plasma (gas mixture containing CO2, CO, and O2) and the electrochemical reactor (typical gas mixture on cathode containing CO2 and CO). For the benchmarking, a comprehensive set of comparison parameters that are applicable for both the plasma and the electrochemical route is identified and grouped in three comparison categories: performance, interfaces, and economics. The comparison of these parameters demonstrates that in terms of the electric power consumption (EPC; power required for production of one Nm3CO) plasma conversion technology (&#8764;20 kWh/Nm3CO) is in the ballpark with the other two electrochemical technologies (&#8764;4&#8211;20 kWh/Nm3CO). The key features of the plasma conversion technology are relatively large conversion (up to 56%) and moderate energy efficiencies (up to 27%). Also, CO2 gas of reduced purity of only 98% can be used without decrease of the performance, and CO output values are currently at 3.5 slm (standard litre per minute). Fast on/off response time of order of minutes, and no need for the hot standby indicate that the plasma conversion is particularly suitable for use of intermittent renewable energy sources. The aspects that require further development include optimization of the process towards lower EPCtotal values, improved oxygen gas separation, and reliable ignition of the plasma.</description>
      <author>A. Hecimovic, Matthew T. Mayer, L.G.J. de Haart, S. K. Gupta, C. Kiefer, Alexander Navarrete, Andreas Schulz, U. Fantz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioinspired bimetallic catalysts for CO2 reduction beyond C1 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101148692</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399349336

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101148692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformation of Bi4Cl2S5 into sub-10 nm Bi2O2CO3 nanowires for electrochemical reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160453</link>
      <description>Xiao-Han Wang, Qian Zhang, Chunxiu Wang, Yujie Wang, Ruize Yin, Qiuhua Deng, Jianhui Jiang, Chunyan Liu, Jia Huo, Li Zheng, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399303492

                The development of highly efficient catalysts for the selective electrochemical reduction reaction of CO2 (eCO2RR) to high-valued formate remains a challenge in achieving carbon neutrality and renewable energy conversion. In this study, ultrathin Bi4Cl2S5 nanowires, synthesized using different branched-chain thiols as sulfur sources, were reported for the first time as precatalysts for eCO2RR to formate. Systematic material characterization demonstrated that Bi4Cl2S5 can undergo in-situ evolution into Bi2O2CO3 nanowires, serving as the genuine electrocatalyst for eCO2RR. Through the fine-tuning of ligands during the synthesis of Bi4Cl2S5 nanowires, the optimized Bi4Cl2S5-derived Bi2O2CO3 nanowires exhibited a maximum formate Faradaic efficiency (FEformate) of 95.3 % in eCO2RR using a traditional H-cell, surpassing other prepared samples. Furthermore, an FEformate of over 92.9 % was achieved in a wide potential window of 500 mV, and high performance was maintained over 20 h. This outstanding performance is attributed to the high intrinsic activity, accelerated charge transfer, and the large electrochemical active surface area associated with the characteristic sub-10 nm diameter nanowire structure. Moreover, density function theory calculations further revealed that Bi2O2CO3 can reduce the energy barriers for the formation of *OCHO intermediate and bolster formate production. Our work provides a novel synthesis strategy for excellent Bi-based catalysts in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Xiao-Han Wang, Qian Zhang, Chunxiu Wang, Yujie Wang, Ruize Yin, Qiuhua Deng, Jianhui Jiang, Chunyan Liu, Jia Huo, Li Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160453</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening of Defective BC3-Supported Single-Atom Catalysts for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01217h</link>
      <description>Renyi Li, Caimu Wang, Yaozhong Liu, C. Suo, Danyang Zhang, Zaibin Jiao, Wei Guo, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399349369

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) driven by renewable electricity offers a green and sustainable technology for synthesizing chemicals and managing global carbon balance. However, developing electrocatalysts with high activity and...</description>
      <author>Renyi Li, Caimu Wang, Yaozhong Liu, C. Suo, Danyang Zhang, Zaibin Jiao, Wei Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01217h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Intrinsic Activity Barriers of Bilayer Metal Oxides for Catalytic Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4851392</link>
      <description>Hui Xu, Hao Song, Chen Bi, Ganghua Zhou, Lan Xiang, Kang Zhong, Weiyi Jiang, Jinman Yang, Wenlong Shen, Naiying Hao, Xianglin Zhu, Xingwang Zhu, Xiaozhi Wang, Hui Xu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399277272

                The photocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction is severely limited by sluggish charge kinetics. To address this issue, a strategy utilizing non-metal-doped layered double hydroxide (LDH) has been developed to control the electronic structure of spindle-shaped nanoflowers, resulting in efficient photocatalytic CO2 reduction. The results demonstrate that the designed catalyst yields 263.16 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 for the photoreduction of CO2 to CO. Furthermore, the in situ FT-IR analysis demonstrate that the specific S-ligand (S-bridge) facilitates CO2 activation, ensuring the continuous production of *COOH. The hydrothermal-assisted ionic liquid method proposed in this study offers guidance for modifying catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hui Xu, Hao Song, Chen Bi, Ganghua Zhou, Lan Xiang, Kang Zhong, Weiyi Jiang, Jinman Yang, Wenlong Shen, Naiying Hao, Xianglin Zhu, Xingwang Zhu, Xiaozhi Wang, Hui Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4851392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modification of the CuO electronic structure for enhanced selective electrochemical CO2 reduction to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6708-0</link>
      <description>Xiang&#8208;Ping Wu, Zhuang Tong, Yunliang Liu, Yaxi Li, Yuanyuan Cheng, Jingwen Yu, Peng Cao, Chunqiang Zhuang, Qiuzhong Shi, Naiyun Liu, Fei Liu, Hongyu Liang, Haitao Li, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399266746

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang&#8208;Ping Wu, Zhuang Tong, Yunliang Liu, Yaxi Li, Yuanyuan Cheng, Jingwen Yu, Peng Cao, Chunqiang Zhuang, Qiuzhong Shi, Naiyun Liu, Fei Liu, Hongyu Liang, Haitao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6708-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concentrated solar CO2 reduction in H2O vapour with &amp;gt;1% energy conversion efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49003-8</link>
      <description>Yifei Ren, Yiwei Fu, Naixu Li, You Chen, Jie Huang, Kai Huang, Zhenkun Sun, Jiancheng Zhou, Yitao Si, Yuanhao Zhu, Wenshuai Chen, Lunbo Duan, Maochang Liu, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399261170

                H</description>
      <author>Yifei Ren, Yiwei Fu, Naixu Li, You Chen, Jie Huang, Kai Huang, Zhenkun Sun, Jiancheng Zhou, Yitao Si, Yuanhao Zhu, Wenshuai Chen, Lunbo Duan, Maochang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49003-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The comparative performance study of the EF7 downsized engines; fuel economy besides CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55670/fpll.futech.3.3.4</link>
      <description>Mohammad Mostafa Namar, Omid Jahanian, Kamyar Nikzadfar, Rouzbeh Shafaghat, Future technology. 3(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399278756

                Engine downsizing is considered a strategic idea in fuel economy enhancement as well as reduction. It is defined in the literature as the decrease in engine geometrical dimensions besides its performance being fixed. In this research, the Iranian gasoline-fueled national engine, EF7, has been investigated for 25% downsizing. After introducing the gasoline-fueled and CNG-fueled versions of downsized engines, their performance, besides release rates are studied in detail. A one-dimensional engine simulator coupled with a 3D-CFD model is developed to carry out such an investigation, an experimental test setup is provided to evaluate the accuracy of the provided numerical model, as well. The first version of presented downsized engines, called EF7, is a 3-cylinder engine with the same geometrical characteristics as the base engine, which is equipped with a turbo-charger and dual CVVT technologies. The EF7 is then introduced by fuel shifting to CNG as the second version of downsized engines, and finally, increasing the compression ratio, the EF7 is presented as the third version of studied-downsized engines. The results show almost the same rate of BSFC besides a 3.4% reduction in concentration for EF7, 20.6% fuel economy enhancement, besides 20.8% reduction in the specific release rate for EF7, and 28.8% fuel economy enhancement, besides 25.3% reduction in the specific release rate for EF7 in comparison with the base engine.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Mostafa Namar, Omid Jahanian, Kamyar Nikzadfar, Rouzbeh Shafaghat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55670/fpll.futech.3.3.4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Reduction of Co2 to Co Over Alumina-Supported Catalysts of Group 5 Transition Metal Carbides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4850293</link>
      <description>Narc&#305;&#769;s Homs, Arturo Pajares, Pilar Ram&#305;&#769;rez de la Piscina, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399209323

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Narc&#305;&#769;s Homs, Arturo Pajares, Pilar Ram&#305;&#769;rez de la Piscina</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4850293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering MXene-based Photocatalyst for Efficient NADH Regeneration and Photoenzymatic CO2 Reduction without Electron Mediator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124257</link>
      <description>Ping Wei, Yue Zhang, Jinfeng Dong, Yuan&#8208;Cheng Cao, Simon Ming&#8208;Yuen Lee, Wen&#8208;Yong Lou, Chao Peng, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399253435

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ping Wei, Yue Zhang, Jinfeng Dong, Yuan&#8208;Cheng Cao, Simon Ming&#8208;Yuen Lee, Wen&#8208;Yong Lou, Chao Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Atoms Immobilization on MXene-Metal-Organic Polyhedra Assemblies for Selective Reduction of CO2 to Formic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101151123</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399350957

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101151123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous two-dimensional CuSe@BiOI isotype heterojunction with highly exposed (1 0 2) facets for efficient photoelectrocatalytic CO2 reduction and photodetection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152773</link>
      <description>X. G. Gong, Shuai Fan, Qu Yang, Jingliang Yang, Y Chen, Xiaosi Qi, Hui Shen, Dan Ren, Mingkui Wang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399273856

                Using photoelectrochemical technology to construct efficient photoelectric materials has aroused extensive research interest. In this study, we propose a two-dimensional porous CuSe@BiOI isotype heterojunction photocathode for CO2 reduction to formic acid. The heterojunction was constructed by the epitaxial growth of high-quality oriented BiOI nanosheets onto the porous CuSe framework. The CuSe framework as a template to ensure the formation of the (1 0 2) facets of BiOI and the isotropic charge transport characteristics of the (1 0 2) surface greatly improve the efficiency of charge separation and transfer. This CuSe@BiOI isotype heterojunction electrode can efficiently reduce CO2 to formic acid with a selectivity of up to 80.5 % in 0.5 M potassium bicarbonate aqueous solution. Meanwhile, the performance of the photodetector based on CuSe@BiOI heterostructure is 6.97 &#215; 1011 Jones and a response rate of 87.13 mA W&#8722;1. This finding provides a new approach to designing stable heterojunction photoelectrocatalysts with isotropy</description>
      <author>X. G. Gong, Shuai Fan, Qu Yang, Jingliang Yang, Y Chen, Xiaosi Qi, Hui Shen, Dan Ren, Mingkui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical CO2 Reduction with Surface Immobilized Mn-NHC Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101152972</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4399404585

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101152972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast reduction of Atlantic SST threatens Europe-wide gross primary productivity under positive and negative CO2 emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-024-00674-6</link>
      <description>Young&#8208;Min Yang, Jongsoo Shin, So&#8208;Won Park, Jae&#8208;Heung Park, Soon&#8208;Il An, Jong&#8208;Seong Kug, Sang&#8208;Wook Yeh, June&#8208;Yi Lee, Bin Wang, Tim Li, Nari Im, npj climate and atmospheric science. 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399256438

                Abstract Climate change mitigation through negative CO 2 emissions has been recognized as a crucial strategy to combat global warming. However, its potential effects on terrestrial productivity and agricultural activities remain uncertain. In this study, we utilized large ensemble simulations with an Earth system model of full complexity to investigate the response of Gross Primary Production (GPP) to CO 2 forcings. Our findings reveal a significant asymmetry in the GPP response to CO 2 ramp-up and symmetric ramp-down model experiments, especially in Europe, suggesting that GPP declines rapidly as CO 2 levels decrease. Remarkably, during the CO 2 removal period, the North Atlantic Sea surface temperature experienced cooling due to a delayed recovery of the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation (AMOC). This cooling led to precipitation and soil moisture deficits, resulting in a rapid reduction in GPP. This asymmetry in GPP response holds consistent across multi-model simulations. These results underscore the potential implications of delayed recovery in ocean circulation, which could unexpectedly accelerate terrestrial GPP reduction. These insights are crucial for policymakers, aiding them in projecting agricultural activity and formulating targeted GPP control policies specific to the European region.</description>
      <author>Young&#8208;Min Yang, Jongsoo Shin, So&#8208;Won Park, Jae&#8208;Heung Park, Soon&#8208;Il An, Jong&#8208;Seong Kug, Sang&#8208;Wook Yeh, June&#8208;Yi Lee, Bin Wang, Tim Li, Nari Im</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-024-00674-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and fabrication of Zr-based MOF photocatalyst with functionalized moieties for CO2 reduction and coupling selective oxidation of benzyl alcohol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119826</link>
      <description>Yun Xu, Linli Zhu, Zhouwei Lv, Yunfei Zhang, Ti-Fang Miao, Qinghua Deng, Yunjian Wang, Zhiqiang Liang, Xianliang Fu, Longfeng Li, Applied catalysis. A, General. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399264873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yun Xu, Linli Zhu, Zhouwei Lv, Yunfei Zhang, Ti-Fang Miao, Qinghua Deng, Yunjian Wang, Zhiqiang Liang, Xianliang Fu, Longfeng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel bipolar Membrane-Electrode Assembly designs for Simultaneous CO2 Capture and Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101153662</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4399412451

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101153662</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycling Electronic Waste to Catalyse H2 Production and CO2 Reduction Using Recovered Metals: A Step towards Circular Economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101152892</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4399406096

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101152892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability in Vietnam: Examining Economic Growth, Energy, Innovation, Agriculture, and Forests' Impact on CO2 Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.wds.2024.100164</link>
      <description>Asif Raihan, Md Hasan, Liton Chandra Voumik, Dulal Chandra Pattak, Salma Akter, Mohammad Ridwan, World development sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399199744

                Global warming, induced by human-generated greenhouse gases, especially carbon dioxide (CO2), threatens the planet's ecology, economic development, and long-term viability in unparalleled ways. Vietnam's utilization of energy and CO2 emanations are on the increase as a consequence of the country's increasing economic and improving agricultural practices. Governments seeking to accomplish an equilibrium between combating climate change and sustainable development would benefit from a deeper understanding of Vietnam's climate change vulnerability. A better understanding of the trade-off between pollution and economic growth is crucial if Vietnam is to slow the rate at which its environment is being damaged. So, the current study empirically examined the connections between GDP development, energy consumption, technical advancement, agricultural output, forest region, and carbon dioxide emissions in Vietnam. This study collected annual data from 1990 to 2020 and analyzed it using the Dynamic Ordinary Least Squares method. Based on the projection, Vietnam experiences a direct correlation between energy consumption and CO2 emissions. This implies that an increase in energy consumption and economic growth corresponds to a corresponding emission of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere. Nevertheless, it is essential to acknowledge that this pattern might be alleviated by means of technological innovations, increased agricultural output, and initiatives to broaden forested regions. A negative correlation exists between these variables and CO2 emissions; technological innovations, more sustainable agricultural methods, and forest preservation initiatives may contribute to the gradual reduction of CO2 emissions. Therefore, environmental sustainability could be achieved through reduced emissions if the policies advocated in this article were implemented. Some of these policies include using renewable energy sources, encouraging innovations in technology, encouraging climate-conscious agriculture, and encouraging careful forest management.</description>
      <author>Asif Raihan, Md Hasan, Liton Chandra Voumik, Dulal Chandra Pattak, Salma Akter, Mohammad Ridwan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.wds.2024.100164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Technology and a Convert&#1077;r for Neutralizing Greenhouse Gases Emitted from Automobiles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54338/27382656-2024.6-001</link>
      <description>Yeghiazar Vardanyan, V. M. Harutyunyan, Karapet Mosikyan, Vladimir Sahidovich Koichev, Journal of architectural and engineering research. 6(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399325246

                The article touches upon the issues of global warming associated with carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions into the atmosphere from vehicle internal combustion engines (ICE). To neutralize existing greenhouse gases emitted by ICE, in particular CO2, the interaction of the latter with various chemicals has been studied. The dynamics of exhaust gas emissions from ICE cylinders were observed. The experimental research was conducted to develop a greenhouse gas neutralization technology. Carbon dioxide neutralization converter with three neutralization batteries and a homogenization device is presented. This converter can guarantee CO2 neutralization of up to 92%. The formation of CO2 in the cylinders of modern petrol engines is due to the final combustion of the air-petrol fuel mixture. The combustion of the latter in the cylinder can be heterogeneous and diffusive. In addition, CO2 is generated in large quantities during diffusion combustion. The most effective method of diffusive combustion was chosen by the constructors of modern ICE, which is the formation of an artificial turbulent gas-dynamic condition for the fuel mixture due to the increase in the temperature of the air adsorbed in the cylinder, which ensures the engine's thermal energy efficiency coefficient of up to 35%. The CO2 volume in the exhaust gases of such engines reaches up to 16%. Thus, considering the perfection of modern ICE design for providing a high-efficiency reaction for the hydrocarbon oxidation in the fuel mixture in the combustion chamber, it becomes apparent that the presence of about 16% CO2 in the fractional composition of emitted dissolved gases is a serious problem in terms of increasing the volume of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere. Therefore, the goal of this article is to develop a reduction technology.</description>
      <author>Yeghiazar Vardanyan, V. M. Harutyunyan, Karapet Mosikyan, Vladimir Sahidovich Koichev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54338/27382656-2024.6-001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techno-economic Analysis of Water-based CO2 Capture Method Based on Adiabatic Compressed Air Energy Storage: Comparison with Monoethanolamine-based CO2 Capture Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142790</link>
      <description>Longxiang Chen, Liugan Zhang, Wei Guo, Huiqin Lian, Yongwei Wang, Kai Ye, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399298264

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) capture and storage is considered an effective measure to mitigate climate change, used to reduce CO2 emissions from industrial sectors, especially for coal-fired power plants. In our previous work, a novel water-based CO2 capture (WCC) method based on adiabatic compressed air energy storage (A-CAES) was developed. This method is simple and environmentally friendly. However, unlike the widely used monoethanolamine (MEA)-based CO2 capture (MCC) technology, which consumes low-grade thermal energy, the WCC technology consumes high-grade electrical energy. Therefore, in this work, a comprehensive techno-economic analysis of the WCC technology is conducted and compared with the MCC technology from the perspective of carbon emission reduction. A universal economic assessment criterion of CO2 capture cost based on electricity prices is proposed, and the techno-economic analysis is based on the cost in 2022 USD ($). The result shows that the CO2 capture cost of the WCC system ranges from 53.74 to 71.70 $/tonne CO2 due to the different factors considered in computational models, taking 63.57%&#8764;84.81% of the MCC system under the same capture rate (85%). The dynamic payback period of the WCC system ranges from 7.14 years to 20.52 years, while the MCC system failed to recover capital throughout the entire lifecycle. Moreover, the CO2 capture cost of the WCC system can be reduced to below carbon tax (43 $/tonne CO2) when the CO2 concentration in the feed flue gas is above 18 vol%, achieving positive benefits with no carbon trading required, which means the WCC system can achieve positive profitability for higher CO2 concentration emission sectors. The results provide significant guidance for developing and promoting the WCC technology.</description>
      <author>Longxiang Chen, Liugan Zhang, Wei Guo, Huiqin Lian, Yongwei Wang, Kai Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142790</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Niobium-Modified HZSM-5 Zeolite Catalyzes Low-Energy Regeneration of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Captured Amine Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00200</link>
      <description>Yingyang Song, Junyu Lang, Qingrui Zeng, Jin Cheng, Mingce Long, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399299969

                Monoethanolamine (MEA)-based carbon dioxide absorption is one of the effective carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS) technologies but is significantly restricted by the high energy consumption in the regeneration of rich amine solution. Solid acid catalysts have the potential to reduce energy consumption, while the exploration of highly active catalysts with abundant Bro&#823;nsted and Lewis acid sites remains needing. We developed an efficient solid acid catalyst, niobium-modified HZSM-5 (Nb/HZ), to facilitate CO2 desorption from the CO2-captured MEA solutions. The Nb/HZ catalysts with various niobium loadings were synthesized by using an impregnation method. HZSM-5 retained its pore structure and large surface area after niobium incorporation. The catalyst with 4% Nb (4.0-Nb/HZ) has the highest activity and stability, with 61% increase in the desorption rate, 50% increase in the desorbed CO2 amount, and 37% reduction of relative heat duty. According to theoretic calculations and experimental analyses, the Nb/HZ catalyst provides abundant Bro&#823;nsted and Lewis acid sites to facilitate carbamate adsorption, proton transfer, and carbamate breakdown, thus reducing the activation energy for CO2 desorption. This work provides a valuable solid acid catalyst for amine-based CO2 capture and also brings insights for the development of a novel solid acid for diverse catalysis.</description>
      <author>Yingyang Song, Junyu Lang, Qingrui Zeng, Jin Cheng, Mingce Long</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a Highly Stable Methane Reforming Catalyst Via Lattice Metal Ion Reduction Accompanying Support Phase Transition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854274</link>
      <description>Libo Han, Hui Yang, Xiaolei Fu, Ruijue Hu, Haiquan Su, Lili Wan, Yiyi Su, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399338171

                Dry reforming of methane (DRM) is one of the most important technologies for converting carbon dioxide and methane into syngas. ZrO2-supported Ni catalysts have shown promising potential for DRM. However, their catalytic stability remains a challenge due to sintering and coking. In this work, a feasible strategy for the preparation of a highly stable ZrO2-supported Ni catalyst, Ni/ZrO2-Mt, was reported. The key points for the preparation of Ni/ZrO2-Mt were the replacement of Zr4+ in the metastable tetragonal ZrO2 with lattice Ni2+, followed by the reduction of lattice Ni2+ into metallic Ni and the phase transformation of ZrO2 support from the metastable tetragonal phase to the monoclinic phase. Compared with the catalyst Ni/ZrO2-Mn (no phase transition and lattice Ni2+ reduction), Ni/ZrO2-Mt could run stably for 800 h without deactivation, with both CO2 and CH4 conversions maintaining 96%. Corresponding to its high stability, the Ni/ZrO2-Mt displayed excellent resistance to sintering and coking, which was attributed to the enhanced metal-support interaction arising from the reduction of lattice Ni2+ and the transformation of the support phase. The proposed catalyst synthetic strategy provided an optional method for preparing highly stable catalysts.</description>
      <author>Libo Han, Hui Yang, Xiaolei Fu, Ruijue Hu, Haiquan Su, Lili Wan, Yiyi Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Research on Regulated and Unregulated Emissions from E20-Fuelled Vehicles and Hybrid Electric Vehicles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15060669</link>
      <description>Tao Qiu, Yaohua Zhao, Yan Lei, Z.H. Chen, Dong-Dong Guo, Fulu Shi, Tao Wang, Atmosphere. 15(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399285602

                Ethanol as a renewable fuel has been applied in fuel vehicles (FVs), and it is promising in hybrid electric vehicles (HEVs). This work aims to investigate the emission characteristics of ethanol applied in both FVs and plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEVs). The paper conducted a real-road test of an internal combustion FV and PHEV, respectively, based on the world light vehicle test cycle (WLTC) by using gasoline and regular gasoline under different temperature conditions. The use of E10 and E20 in FVs has been effective in reducing the conventional emissions of the vehicles. At 23 &#176;C, E10 and E20 reduced the conventional emissions including carbon monoxide (CO), total hydrocarbon compound (THC), non-methane hydrocarbon compound (NMHC), particulate matter (PM), and particulate number (PN) by 15.40&#8211;31.11% and 11.00&#8211;44.13% respectively. At 6 &#176;C, E10 and E20 reduced conventional emissions including THC, CO, and PM by 2.15&#8211;8.61% and 11.02&#8211;13.34%, respectively. However, nitrogen oxide (NOX) emissions increased to varying degrees. The reduction trend of non-conventional emissions including methane (CH4), nitrous oxide (N2O), and carbon dioxide (CO2) from FVs fueled with E10 and E20 is not significant for vehicles. Overall, the emission reduction effect of E20 is better than that of E10, and the emission reduction effect of ethanol gasoline on vehicle emissions is reduced at low temperatures. Lower ambient temperatures increase vehicle emissions in the low-speed segment but decrease vehicle emissions in the ultra-high-speed segment. HEV emissions of THC, CO, PN, and PM are reduced by 25.28%, 12.72%, 77.34%, and 64.59%, respectively, for E20 compared to gasoline, and the use of E20 in HEVs contributes to the reduction of overall vehicle emissions.</description>
      <author>Tao Qiu, Yaohua Zhao, Yan Lei, Z.H. Chen, Dong-Dong Guo, Fulu Shi, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15060669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel wastewater recovery process for sustainable sodium carbonate production with CO2 and SOx utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102824</link>
      <description>Jongmin Choi, Jonghun Lim, Yurim Kim, Seongbin Ga, Junghwan Kim, Journal of CO2 utilization. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239965

                Ammonia-soda process, which produce soda ash, emits flue gas containing a large amount of CO2 and SOx. The wastewater discharged from the ammonia-soda process contains cations, such as Na+ and Ca2+, which can be recovered and reacted with a CO2 and SOx. In this study, we designed a CO2 and SOx utilization process for the sustainable production of sodium carbonate using wastewater recovery system, extracting Na+ and Ca2+. The proposed process involved the following steps: (1) metal-ion separation, which produces NaOH and Ca(OH)2; (2) capture and utilization of SOx using Ca(OH)2; and (3) capture and utilization of CO2 using NaOH and Ca(OH)2, respectively. The economic feasibility of the proposed process was verified by comparing its total annualized cost (TAC) with those of conventional processes. Approximately 99% of SOx was captured to produce high-purity desulfurized gypsum, and 99% of CO2 was captured to be transformed into CaCO3. To confirm the CO2 reduction of the process, the carbon dioxide equivalent (CO2e) was calculated by evaluating the amount of greenhouse gases. The CO2e decreased to 71.4% compared with that of the conventional process. The TAC of the proposed process decreased by 10.67% and 19.63% compared with that of the ammonia-soda and Hou processes, respectively. Thus, this study proposes an industrially potential process design for sustainable sodium carbonate production by utilizing CO2 and SOx with wastewater recycling, without additional reactants, making it more economically viable.</description>
      <author>Jongmin Choi, Jonghun Lim, Yurim Kim, Seongbin Ga, Junghwan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicted C&#8211;N Coupling Performance of Lateral Heterostructure Interfaces between Two Types of Layered Materials for Electrochemical Synthesis of Acetamide and Ammonia Via Coreduction of Co2 and N2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4851398</link>
      <description>Yi Xiao, Tianhang Zhou, Chen Shen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399277334

                Currently, carbon dioxide reduction (CO2RR) can convert CO2 into many high-value hydrocarbon chemicals via electrochemical processes, contributing to achieving energy conservation and emission reduction. Importantly, this method also guides the electrocatalytic synthesis of organonitrogen chemicals via C&#8211;C and C&#8211;N coupling, such as acetamide synthesis during the coelectroreduction of CO2 and N2. Herein, we utilized density functional theory calculations to predict the C&#8211;N coupling performance of *CCO and NH3 for acetamide synthesis on lateral heterostructure (LHS) interfaces of two types of layered materials: Type-A includes NbS2/MoS2, NbS2/TaS2, NbS2/WS2, MoS2/TaS2, and TaS2/WS2; Type-B contains LHS NbS2/AlN, NbS2/GaN, NbS2/ZnO, MoS2/AlN, MoS2/GaN, MoS2/ZnO, TaS2/AlN, TaS2/GaN, TaS2/ZnO, and WS2/AlN, WS2/GaN, WS2/ZnO. However, achieving simultaneous C&#8211;C coupling and C&#8211;N coupling remains a great challenge in designing catalysts. To address this, we systemically investigated these LHS catalysts, evaluating factors such as adsorption stability, electroconductivity, catalytic activity, selectivity, and electronic properties. Our findings suggest that MoS2/WS2 and NbS2/ZnO may be potential catalysts, facilitating acetamide synthesis from CO2 and N2 reduction with low limiting potentials of &#8722;1.11 and &#8722;0.97 V, respectively. The reaction pathway of CO2RR involves the formation of CO, C&#8211;C coupling via keto&#8722;enol tautomerism to form ketene (*CCO), N2 reduction, and C&#8211;N coupling between NH3 and *CCO to produce *CC(OH)NH2, finally resulting in acetamide production. Most of these LHS junction catalysts exhibit metallic and semiconductor electronic states, except for MoS2/GaN, which possesses a large band gap of up to 3.73 eV. Furthermore, our analysis indicates that NbS2/AlN, NbS2/GaN, TaS2/ZnO, WS2/AlN, and WS2/ZnO effectively suppress competing byproducts, ensuring the formation of *CCO and promoting nucleophilic reactions leading to *CC(OH)NH2 during *CC(OH)NH2. This strategic approach enables the synthesis of organonitrogen chemicals via C&#8211;N coupling in the coreduction of CO2 and NOx, expanding the scope of hydrocarbon products derived from CO2RR. The LHS catalysts identified in this study may be employed to form amide chemicals.</description>
      <author>Yi Xiao, Tianhang Zhou, Chen Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4851398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxide&#8208;Encapsulated Silver Electrocatalysts for Selective and Stable Syngas Production from Reactive Carbon Capture Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202404758</link>
      <description>Zhexi Lin, N Blake, Xueqi Pang, Zhirui He, Gholamreza Mirshekari, Oyinkansola Romiluyi, Yoon Jun Son, Saurabh Kabra, Daniel V. Esposito, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239756

                Electrolysis of bicarbonate&#8208;containing CO2 capture solutions is a promising approach towards achieving low&#8208;cost carbon&#8208;neutral chemicals production. However, the parasitic bicarbonate&#8208;mediated hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and electrode instability in the presence of trace impurities remain major obstacles to overcome. This work demonstrates that the combined use of titanium dioxide (TiO2) overlayers with the chelating agent ethylene diamine tetra&#8208;acetic acid (EDTA) significantly enhances the selectivity and stability of Ag&#8208;based electrocatalysts for bicarbonate electrolysis. The amorphous TiO2 overlayers suppress the HER by over 50% at potentials more negative than &#8208;0.7 V vs. RHE, increasing the CO faradaic efficiency (FE) by 33% (relative). In situ surface&#8208;enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) measurements reveal the absence of near&#8208;surface bicarbonate species and an abundance of CO2 reduction intermediates at the Ag|TiO2 buried interface, suggesting that the overlayers suppress HER by blocking bicarbonate ions from reaching the buried active sites. In accelerated degradation tests with 5 ppm of Fe(III) impurity, the addition of EDTA allows stable CO production with &gt;47% FE, while the electrodes rapidly deactivate in the absence of EDTA. This work highlights the use of TiO2 overlayers for enhancing the CO:H2 ratio while simultaneously protecting electrocatalysts from impurities likely to be present in &#8220;open&#8221; carbon capture systems.</description>
      <author>Zhexi Lin, N Blake, Xueqi Pang, Zhirui He, Gholamreza Mirshekari, Oyinkansola Romiluyi, Yoon Jun Son, Saurabh Kabra, Daniel V. Esposito</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202404758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxide&#8208;Encapsulated Silver Electrocatalysts for Selective and Stable Syngas Production from Reactive Carbon Capture Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202404758</link>
      <description>Zhexi Lin, N Blake, Xueqi Pang, Zhirui He, Gholamreza Mirshekari, Oyinkansola Romiluyi, Yoon Jun Son, Saurabh Kabra, Daniel V. Esposito, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239529

                Electrolysis of bicarbonate&#8208;containing CO2 capture solutions is a promising approach towards achieving low&#8208;cost carbon&#8208;neutral chemicals production. However, the parasitic bicarbonate&#8208;mediated hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and electrode instability in the presence of trace impurities remain major obstacles to overcome. This work demonstrates that the combined use of titanium dioxide (TiO2) overlayers with the chelating agent ethylene diamine tetra&#8208;acetic acid (EDTA) significantly enhances the selectivity and stability of Ag&#8208;based electrocatalysts for bicarbonate electrolysis. The amorphous TiO2 overlayers suppress the HER by over 50% at potentials more negative than &#8208;0.7 V vs. RHE, increasing the CO faradaic efficiency (FE) by 33% (relative). In situ surface&#8208;enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) measurements reveal the absence of near&#8208;surface bicarbonate species and an abundance of CO2 reduction intermediates at the Ag|TiO2 buried interface, suggesting that the overlayers suppress HER by blocking bicarbonate ions from reaching the buried active sites. In accelerated degradation tests with 5 ppm of Fe(III) impurity, the addition of EDTA allows stable CO production with &gt;47% FE, while the electrodes rapidly deactivate in the absence of EDTA. This work highlights the use of TiO2 overlayers for enhancing the CO:H2 ratio while simultaneously protecting electrocatalysts from impurities likely to be present in &#8220;open&#8221; carbon capture systems.</description>
      <author>Zhexi Lin, N Blake, Xueqi Pang, Zhirui He, Gholamreza Mirshekari, Oyinkansola Romiluyi, Yoon Jun Son, Saurabh Kabra, Daniel V. Esposito</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202404758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additive effects of basalt enhanced weathering and biochar co-application on carbon sequestration, soil nutrient status and plant performance in a mesocosm experiment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apgeochem.2024.106054</link>
      <description>Nicolas Honvault, Marie-Laure Tiouchichine, Joana Sauze, Cl&#233;ment Piel, Damien Landais, S&#233;bastien Devidal, Emmanuel Gritti, Delphine Bosch, Alexandru Milcu, Applied geochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399245414

                Co-deployment of a portfolio of carbon removal technologies is anticipated in order to remove several gigatons of carbon dioxide from the atmosphere and meet climate targets. However, co-application effects between carbon removal technologies have rarely been examined, despite multiple recent perspectives suggesting potential synergies between basalt enhanced weathering and biochar application. To study the co-application effects of basalt for enhanced weathering and biochar on carbon sequestration, along with related co-benefits and risks, we conducted a fully replicated factorial mesocosm experiment with wheat. Basalt applied alone (74 t ha-1) resulted in an estimated carbon sequestration potential of 1.13 t of equivalent CO2 ha-1 over the course of approximately 6 months. Co-application with biochar (12 t ha-1) did not significantly increase estimated carbon sequestration potential. Total alkalinity fluxes and isotopic evidence indicated nearly exactly additive effects of basalt and biochar co-applied, with no significant interaction effect. Biochar carbon sequestration, approximately 32 t of equivalent CO2 ha-1 in our experiment, was unaffected by basalt addition during our experiment. Co-benefits of basalt and biochar on plant biomass as well as nutrient uptake and availability similarly mostly showed additive tendencies when co-applied. Nonetheless, a few synergistic tendencies were observed when co-applied for plant potassium and magnesium uptake as well as soil calcium availability. Soil calcium availability increased by 126% compared to expected effects based on separate application. Finally, we did not observe a reduction in the increased uptake of potentially harmful trace elements released from basalt when co-applied with biochar. Overall, our results support the co-application of basalt for enhanced weathering and biochar, with additive effects on carbon sequestration and additive, if not synergistic, effects on associated co-benefits.</description>
      <author>Nicolas Honvault, Marie-Laure Tiouchichine, Joana Sauze, Cl&#233;ment Piel, Damien Landais, S&#233;bastien Devidal, Emmanuel Gritti, Delphine Bosch, Alexandru Milcu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apgeochem.2024.106054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biogas upgrading to biomethane with zeolite membranes: separation performance and economic analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cherd.2024.05.042</link>
      <description>Pasquale F. Zito, Giuseppe Barbieri, Adele Brunetti, Process safety and environmental protection/Transactions of the Institution of Chemical Engineers. Part B, Process safety and environmental protection/Chemical engineering research and design/Chemical engineering research &amp; design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399242618

                Biogas represents an important renewable source alternative to fossil fuels, which can significantly contribute to the reduction of global warming and the gradual decarbonisation. In this work, the purification of CH4 and CO2 from a biogas mixture was investigated using DD3R zeolite membrane modules, as a possible solution to replace the traditional techniques at higher environmental impact (i.e., solvent absorption and cryogenic distillation). Multistage membrane configurations operating at 25&#176;C and 30 bar were proposed and explored to get highly pure biomethane (concentration of 98%) and carbon dioxide (concentration of 99.5%), imposing a recovery of both the species higher than 90%. Then, an economic analysis was carried out, evaluating the economic potential of each configuration as a function of several parameters, such as membrane module cost, biomethane selling price, CO2 permeance, CO2/CH4 selectivity, feed flow rate and pressure. The multistage schemes were found to be promising in a wide range of zeolite membrane module cost (i.e., up to 2000 $/m2), providing positive values of the economic potential, due to the good recovery of both the components, which produced high revenues. The increment of the CO2 permeance and, especially, of the feed flow rate (i.e., plant size) allowed for a more profitable process. In particular, if feed flow rate increased from 100 to 1000 Nm3/h, the economic potential would grow of about 12 times, from 113 to 1370 thousand dollars per year. Hence, this preliminary economic assessment showed that zeolite membranes can be successfully used in biogas treatment to get pure CH4 and CO2. Such an analysis can be applied to any membrane materials, once permeance and selectivity are fixed.</description>
      <author>Pasquale F. Zito, Giuseppe Barbieri, Adele Brunetti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cherd.2024.05.042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Framework for Sustainability Analysis of Construction Projects to Achieve Net-Zero Emission Goal by 2050</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1972-3_7</link>
      <description>Mohammad Masfiqul Alam Bhuiyan, Mohammad Rabiul Karim, Ahmed Hammad, Lecture notes in civil engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399210908

                Many regard the construction industry as a non-sustainable sector due to its energy-intensive activities, coupled with greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions and low productivity. According to a recent United Nations Environment Program report, building and construction account for 36% of global energy use and 37% of energy-related carbon dioxide (CO2) and greenhouse gas emissions. Concerning the current emerging rules and regulations related to sustainability, Canada has introduced the 2030 emission reduction plan, which aims to achieve clean air and a strong economy. The 2030 plan is a detailed road map that outlines a sector-by-sector path for Canada to reach its emissions reduction target of 40% below 2005 levels by 2030 and net-zero emissions by 2050, and it is intended to be continuously updated. The construction industry is also involved in the 2030 emission reduction plan, as it has a prominent role in generating emissions during the life cycle of its projects. Therefore, the construction industry has no option but to shift gradually toward achieving sustainability. The core concept of sustainable construction is to maximize value and minimize harm by achieving a balance between social, economic, technical, and environmental aspects, commonly known as the pillars of sustainability. In general, the integration of sustainability in any construction project remains a complex and open issue due to the involvement of a large number of factors influencing the decision. This paper analyzed significant factors causing greenhouse gas emissions considering the project's complete life cycle and developed a framework to suggest action plans to reduce those gradually. The outcome is expected to enhance interdisciplinary collaboration among researchers, industry practitioners and policymakers to integrate the information available to support decision-making to achieve net-zero GHG emissions targets in construction.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Masfiqul Alam Bhuiyan, Mohammad Rabiul Karim, Ahmed Hammad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1972-3_7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a novel sustainable concrete from waste coconut shell with alccofine supplements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13167/2024.28.11</link>
      <description>Ramaiah Prakash, Sundaresan Srividhya, Viswanathan Gowrishankar, Sachin Kumar, Advances in civil and architectural engineering. 15(28)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399291746

                The infrastructure of a country depends significantly on cement concrete as the primary construction material. The aggregate comprises a significant proportion of the overall volume of concrete. However, the ongoing extraction of granite rock to obtain coarse aggregate contributes to the escalating need for natural resources among future generations. Due to its high carbon dioxide (CO2) footprint, the cement industry is a significant contributor to global warming. An appropriate reduction in the amount of cement in concrete without affecting its key properties can result in economical and sustainable development of the construction industry. In this investigation, agricultural waste coconut shell is considered as a substitute for conventional aggregate in concrete to produce lightweight coconut shell concrete. The alccofine-1203 contains ultrafine particles with a distinctive composition that enhances the pozzolanic and hydration process in concrete. Alccofine ranging from 5 % to 15 % were added to cement. The results demonstrated that the 10 % alccofine enhanced the fresh and mechanical properties of the lightweight coconut shell concrete. Using a combination of coconut shell and alccofine in concrete would be the most environmentally sustainable option in the construction industry.</description>
      <author>Ramaiah Prakash, Sundaresan Srividhya, Viswanathan Gowrishankar, Sachin Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13167/2024.28.11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Post-Heat Behavior of Cement Mortar Containing Mechanically Modified Ground Coal Bottom Ash</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56294/sctconf2024813</link>
      <description>Mohammad I. Al Biajawi, Rahimah Embong, Khairunisa Muthusamy, Haneen Abdel Jabar, Nahla Hilal, Fadzli Mohamed Nazri, Salud, Ciencia y Tecnolog&#237;a - Serie de Conferencias. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399213652

                Coal is widely recognized as a significant and essential fuel source due to its capacity to undergo combustion and produce heat in many different regions worldwide. Over the course of many decades, there has been a notable rise in power usage among individuals, thus resulting in an upsurge in the utilization of coal. The growth of mankind has a parallel rising trajectory with the utilization of cement in the building industry, as well as a corresponding rise in cement manufacturing. These two phenomena significantly contribute to the escalation of carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions and the improper disposal of coal ash, both of which pose significant environmental hazards. Coal-fired thermal power plants generate many waste products from industry, including coal-bottom ash (CBA), which may be effectively used in the production of mortar or concrete. This practice not only promotes the adoption of sustainable construction materials but also encourages the utilization of these wastes. In contrast, it is worth noting that cement manufacture yields a significant quantity of carbon dioxide emissions, so exerting a detrimental influence on the ecosystem. The reduction of environmental deterioration may be achieved by substituting cement with waste products. The substitution of Portland cement with reutilized coal combustion products has the potential to provide significant environmental and infrastructural advantages. This study presents an experimental investigation into the post-heat performance of cement mortars including ground coal bottom ash (CBA). To achieve this objective, an investigation was conducted to assess the strength qualities, residual strength, and mass losses of mortar specimens. These specimens comprised varying proportions (10%, 20%, 30%, and 40%) of CBA as a substitute for cement. To perform the heating procedure, samples were subjected to temperatures of 200&#176;C, 400&#176;C, and 600&#176;C, which corresponded to room temperatures. The findings indicate that the use of ground CBA up to a proportion of 20% yields mortar with the maximum value of compressive strength compared with the control sample. The use of a substantial amount of ground CBA has been shown to produce the most significant reduction in mass and decrease in strength when subjected to high temperatures. As a result, the residual strength of concrete experiences a decrease of 33.65% when exposed to a temperature of 600&#176;C in conventional concrete while for CBA in concrete decreases around 40.9% . In general, the integration of ground CBA alternatives as an alternative to cement would result in a decrease in the need for the manufacture of cement and the environmental pollution associated with CBA discharge.</description>
      <author>Mohammad I. Al Biajawi, Rahimah Embong, Khairunisa Muthusamy, Haneen Abdel Jabar, Nahla Hilal, Fadzli Mohamed Nazri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56294/sctconf2024813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficacy of Salvia officinalis Shrub as a Sustainable Feed Additive for Reducing Ruminal Methane Production and Enhancing Fermentation in Ruminants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ani14111648</link>
      <description>Ahmed E. Kholif, Md. Atiar Rahman, S. A. H. A. El-Nor, Tarek A. Morsy, Gouda A. Gouda, Mahmoud Fahmy, Mireille Chahine, Animals. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399217455

                The objective of this study was to evaluate the effects of the inclusion of dried Salvia officinalis (SO) shrub leaves on nutrient degradability, ruminal in vitro fermentation, gas production (GP), methane (CH4), and carbon dioxide (CO2) productions. Dried and ground SO shrub leaves were included at 0% (control), 0.5%, 1%, 1.5%, and 2% DM of a diet consisting of (per kg DM) 500 g concentrate feed mixture, 400 g berseem hay, and 100 g rice straw. The diet was incubated for 48 h. The asymptotic GP and the rate of GP changed linearly and quadratically (p &lt; 0.01), with the highest GP observed at 1% inclusion of SO and then decreasing thereafter with greater inclusion (i.e., 1.5% and 2%), while CH4 production and its rate decreased linearly (p &lt; 0.01) with all levels of SO inclusion. A linear increase in CO2 production and its rate was also found with an increasing level of SO inclusion in the diet (p &lt; 0.05). Furthermore, the degradability of DM, NDF, and the concentration of total short-chain fatty acids and acetate changed linearly and quadratically, with the greatest being found at 1% SO inclusion and then steadily declining after (p &lt; 0.01) with the 1.5% and 2% inclusion levels. Meanwhile, the propionate, NH3-N, and microbial crude protein levels showed similar trends, with the plateau found at 1% inclusion of SO, where there was no change in butyrate concentration. Moreover, the pH, metabolizable energy, and partitioning factor (PF24) also changed linearly and quadratically (p &lt; 0.05), where the pH and PF24 were considerably reduced and ME increased with a 1% inclusion of SO (p &lt; 0.05). In summary, SO at 1% inclusion in the diet showed the potential to improve gas production kinetics, nutrient degradability, and the ruminal fermentation profile, with a more significant reduction in ruminal CH4 production suggesting that SO at 1% could be included in the ruminant diet to reduce their carbon footprint and increase the production performance.</description>
      <author>Ahmed E. Kholif, Md. Atiar Rahman, S. A. H. A. El-Nor, Tarek A. Morsy, Gouda A. Gouda, Mahmoud Fahmy, Mireille Chahine</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ani14111648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the China-Europe Railway Express reduce carbon dioxide emissions? New mechanism of manufacturing industry substitution effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eap.2024.05.023</link>
      <description>Peiming He, Xueying Tian, Jiaming Zhang, Sijun Yu, Shiyu Li, Chuan Lin, Chen Li-tai, Qian Liu, Economic analysis and policy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399207787

                The China-Europe Railway Express (CRE) has attracted and fostered low-carbon, export-oriented manufacturing industry; thus, it could reduce carbon dioxide emissions through manufacturing industry substitution effect. To verify this new mechanism, this study focuses on a specific case, namely, Chongqing's electronic and telecommunications equipment (ETE) manufacturing industry, as this sector is a low-carbon industry promoted by the CRE. This study proposes a novel detour estimation strategy for causal identification of the environmental externality of CRE on carbon dioxide emissions. The results show that the CRE could contribute to an increase of 567.06 billion yuan in ETE exports from Chongqing to Europe and a consequent reduction of 17.10 million tons of carbon dioxide between 2011 and 2021. This study provides new insights into the environmental externality of CRE and the mechanism of manufacturing industry substitution effect, contributing to the understanding of the relationship between transportation and carbon dioxide emissions.</description>
      <author>Peiming He, Xueying Tian, Jiaming Zhang, Sijun Yu, Shiyu Li, Chuan Lin, Chen Li-tai, Qian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eap.2024.05.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deployment of carbon removal technologies could reduce the rapid and potentially disruptive pace of decarbonization in South Africa&#8217;s climate ambitions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142753</link>
      <description>Sandylove Afrane, Jeffrey Dankwa Ampah, Zhao Jinjuan, Pingjian Yang, Jian Lin Chen, Guozhu Mao, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301369

                As a developing country, South Africa faces the risk of having to undertake disruptive actions to meet its internationally pledged emission reduction targets. It has become necessary to find alternative measures for South Africa to meet its climate targets without such a disruptive and aggressive transformation of its energy sector. To truly reach net-zero CO2 emissions, South Africa must ensure that residual emissions from its recalcitrant sectors are equally compensated by carbon dioxide removal (CDR). Given the potential for CDR technologies to delay the need for rapid emissions cuts, we leverage this characteristic to explore their role in helping South Africa achieve its climate targets on time, but through a less disruptive and overly aggressive pace of energy system decarbonization. Using an integrated assessment model, we show that while reaching its emission reduction targets, the presence of novel CDR (nCDR) could significantly reduce South Africa's mitigation costs, from $190-590/tCO2 without nCDR to $155-240/tCO2 with nCDR by 2050. Furthermore, the availability of nCDR may allow for a less aggressive expansion of renewable and nuclear power generation, saving about 35-55TWh/yr by 2050 compared to scenarios without nCDR. Importantly, we reveal that nCDR could help avoid the asset stranding of up to 4-6 GW and $15-25 billion in associated costs between 2016 and 2050. However, this comes at the cost of higher residual greenhouse gas emissions, as the continued reliance on fossil fuels under nCDR availability would likely lead to the perpetuation of some emissions. Overall, South Africa's priority must remain on decarbonization, especially in sectors where fuel switching and energy efficiency are feasible. Nonetheless, the complementary role of nCDR must not be underestimated, and South Africa should begin investing in these emerging technologies to support its ambitious net-zero goal.</description>
      <author>Sandylove Afrane, Jeffrey Dankwa Ampah, Zhao Jinjuan, Pingjian Yang, Jian Lin Chen, Guozhu Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142753</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capturing carbon dioxide from air with charged-sorbents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-024-07449-2</link>
      <description>Huaiguang Li, Mary E. Zick, Teedhat Trisukhon, Matteo Signorile, Xinyu Liu, Helen Eastmond, Shivani Sharma, Tristan Spreng, Jack A. Taylor, Jamie W. Gittins, Cavan Farrow, Seng Lim, Valentina Crocell&#224;, Phillip J. Milner, Alexander C. Forse, Nature. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399366349

                Abstract Emissions reduction and greenhouse gas removal from the atmosphere are both necessary to achieve net-zero emissions and limit climate change 1 . There is thus a need for improved sorbents for the capture of carbon dioxide from the atmosphere, a process known as direct air capture. In particular, low-cost materials that can be regenerated at low temperatures would overcome the limitations of current technologies. In this work, we introduce a new class of designer sorbent materials known as &#8216;charged-sorbents&#8217;. These materials are prepared through a battery-like charging process that accumulates ions in the pores of low-cost activated carbons, with the inserted ions then serving as sites for carbon dioxide adsorption. We use our charging process to accumulate reactive hydroxide ions in the pores of a carbon electrode, and find that the resulting sorbent material can rapidly capture carbon dioxide from ambient air by means of (bi)carbonate formation. Unlike traditional bulk carbonates, charged-sorbent regeneration can be achieved at low temperatures (90&#8211;100 &#176;C) and the sorbent&#8217;s conductive nature permits direct Joule heating regeneration 2,3 using renewable electricity. Given their highly tailorable pore environments and low cost, we anticipate that charged-sorbents will find numerous potential applications in chemical separations, catalysis and beyond.</description>
      <author>Huaiguang Li, Mary E. Zick, Teedhat Trisukhon, Matteo Signorile, Xinyu Liu, Helen Eastmond, Shivani Sharma, Tristan Spreng, Jack A. Taylor, Jamie W. Gittins, Cavan Farrow, Seng Lim, Valentina Crocell&#224;, Phillip J. Milner, Alexander C. Forse</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-024-07449-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Low Carbon Energy Policy in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52819/jnes.2023.35.3.59</link>
      <description>Yang Yue, Do Il Choi, Bugbang gyeongje yeon'gu. 35(3)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4399247712

                This study aimed to examine the actual effects of policies by applying a quasi-experimental methodology to the second phase of China&#8217;s low-carbon pilot city project. Particularly, we tried to investigate whether a significant reduction in particulate matter and carbon emissions occurred through the implementation of the policy. Analyzing 31 cities in China from 2008 to 2018, the study revealed a significant decrease in both particulate matter and carbon dioxide emissions in the pilot cities compared to non-pilot cities post-policy implementation. Further categorization of cities into groups based on a GDP of over 90,000 yuan and cities with a secondary industry contribution exceeding 50% indicated that the pilot city initiatives had the most substantial effects in these areas. Additionally, deriving insights from the analysis of factors influencing particulate matter and carbon emissions, the study drew policy implications. These findings underscore the significant practical impact of municipally-led, city-specific approaches in China&#8217;s environmental policies.</description>
      <author>Yang Yue, Do Il Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52819/jnes.2023.35.3.59</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Spatial Pattern Optimization Path of Urban Building Carbon Emission based on Low-Carbon Cities Analytical Framework: A Case Study of Xi'an, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scs.2024.105551</link>
      <description>Liang Chen, Huan Huang, Haonan Yang, Yi Xiao, Panyu Tang, Shiyu Liu, Ming Chang, Sustainable cities and society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399274907

                Reducing carbon dioxide emissions has become a prominent issue in city construction. Here, with the objective of spatial pattern optimization, we propose a comprehensive evaluation framework for low-carbon cities. To shed further light on the mechanism by which green finance facilitates the low-carbon transformation of the economy, we chose Xi'an as a study area, used the system dynamics model, simulated the relationship between different factors in the development of low-carbon cities, and provided guidance for spatial planning of low-carbon cities. Through systematic analysis of results, we found that with the progress of urbanization and the improvement of people's living standards, the carbon emissions from urban buildings in Xi'an will increase annually and reach 2.47 million tons by 2030. In scenario 1, the faster pace of urbanization raises carbon emissions from urban buildings by 3%, to 2.5543 million tons from the base. In contrast, in Scenario 2, the reduction in urbanization rate results in a decrease in urban building carbon emissions to 2.4243 million tons, a reduction of 2.26% compared to the baseline scenario. Thus it can be seen that diverse modifications of parameters exert distinct effects on the ultimate carbon emissions from urban buildings.</description>
      <author>Liang Chen, Huan Huang, Haonan Yang, Yi Xiao, Panyu Tang, Shiyu Liu, Ming Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scs.2024.105551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimentally assessing the uncertainty of forecasts of geological carbon storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104162</link>
      <description>Jan M. Nordbotten, Martin A. Fern&#248;, Bernd Flemisch, Rub&#233;n Juanes, Magne J&#248;rgensen, International journal of greenhouse gas control. 135(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399303982

                Geological storage of carbon dioxide is a cornerstone in almost every realistic emissions reduction scenario outlined by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. Our ability to accurately forecast storage efficacy is, however, mostly unknown due to the long timescales involved (hundreds to thousands of years). To study perceived forecast accuracy, we designed a double-blind forecasting study. As ground truth, we constructed a laboratory-scale carbon storage operation, retaining the essential physical processes active on the field scale, within a time span of five days. Separately, academic groups with experience in carbon storage research were invited to forecast key carbon storage efficacy metrics. The participating groups submitted forecasts in two stages: First independently without any cross-group interaction, then finally after workshops designed to share and assimilate understanding between the forecast groups. Their confidence in reported forecasts was monitored throughout the forecasting study. Our results show that participating groups provided forecasts that appear bias-free with respect to carbon storage as a technology, yet the forecast intervals are too narrow to capture the ground truth (overconfidence bias). When asked to qualitatively self-assess their forecast uncertainty (and later when asked to provide an external assessment of other forecast groups), the assessment of the participants indicated an understanding that the forecast intervals (both their own and those of others) were too narrow. However, the participants did not display an understanding of how poorly the forecast intervals calibrated to the ground truth. The quantitative uncertainty assessments contrast the qualitative comments supplied by the participants, which indicate an acute awareness of the challenges associated with assessing the uncertainty of forecasts for complex systems such as the geological storage of carbon dioxide.</description>
      <author>Jan M. Nordbotten, Martin A. Fern&#248;, Bernd Flemisch, Rub&#233;n Juanes, Magne J&#248;rgensen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scanning Bubble Electrochemical Microscopy: Mapping of Electrocatalytic Activity with Low-Solubility Reactants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c00917</link>
      <description>J.F. Monteiro, Kim McKelvey, Analytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399359847

                Determining electrocatalytic activity for reactions that involve reactants with limited solubility presents a significant challenge due to the reduced mass-transport to the electrocatalyst surface. This limitation is seen in important reactions such as the oxygen reduction reaction, nitrogen reduction reaction, and carbon dioxide reduction reaction. We introduce a new approach, which we call scanning bubble electrochemical microscopy, to enable the detection and high-resolution mapping of electrocatalytic activity with low-solubility reactants at high mass-transport rates. Using a scanning probe approach, a dual-barreled nanopipette is used to precisely deliver the gas-phase reactant within micrometers of an electrocatalyst surface, which results in high mass-transport rates at the electrocatalyst surface directly under the probe. We demonstrate the scanning bubble electrochemical microscopy approach by mapping the oxygen reduction reaction on model platinum microelectrode surfaces. We anticipate that scanning bubble electrochemical microscopy will provide an effective tool for measuring the electrocatalytic activity of reactants that have limited solubility.</description>
      <author>J.F. Monteiro, Kim McKelvey</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c00917</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring technology of near-surface atmospheric carbon dioxide concentration in multiple regions based on unmanned aerial vehicle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3032121</link>
      <description>Huimin Wang, Lei Yu, Yu Liu, Yanan Wang, Kailei Xu, Xingcheng Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399280286

                Due to the unclear distribution of near-surface atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) in small areas, by choosing Yulin City and Xi'an City as the research areas and applying Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) to carry out atmospheric CO2 concentration monitoring at multiple carbon monitoring points, this study explores the impact of ground object type, height and time on atmospheric CO2 concentration. Regarding the temporal variation, the atmospheric CO2 concentration of the vegetation-covered area in the afternoon is lower than that in the morning in summer, and only the evergreen vegetation-covered area in winter has similar characteristics as that in summer. The near-surface atmospheric CO2 concentration in the vegetated area changes greatly in summer and winter. For the characteristics of vertical distribution of CO2, the CO2 concentration gradually decreases with increasing altitude. In summer, the CO2 concentration in areas affected by human activities decreases rapidly from 0 to 50 meters and decreases slowly from 50 to 150 meters. The CO2 concentration in vegetation-covered areas decreases slightly from 0 to 150 meters. In winter, the areas affected by human activities and the vegetation-covered areas both decrease rapidly from 0&#8211;20 meters and relatively slowly from 20 meters to 100 meters. The experimental results indicate that using UAVs can accurately monitor the atmospheric CO2 concentration near the surface of typical land features in small areas. UAVs can form air-space-ground carbon monitoring networks with satellites and ground observation points, which is of great significance for quantitative analysis of carbon reduction paths to achieve peak carbon dioxide emission and carbon neutralization.</description>
      <author>Huimin Wang, Lei Yu, Yu Liu, Yanan Wang, Kailei Xu, Xingcheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3032121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct use of low-concentration CO2 in the synthesis of dialkyl carbonates, carbamate acid esters, and urea derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102814</link>
      <description>Katsuhiko Takeuchi, Hiroki Koizumi, Haruki Nagae, Kazuhiro Matsumoto, Norihisa Fukaya, Kazuhiko Sat&#333;, Junho Choi, Journal of CO2 utilization. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399236708

                The CO2 in thermal power plant and factory exhaust gases and the air must be addressed because all have low-concentration CO2. However, applying low-concentration CO2 to developed reactions that use high-purity CO2, energy- and cost-intensive pretreatments, such as CO2 purification, concentration, and compression, are required. Thus, a technology that directly converts low-concentration CO2 into useful chemicals without these pretreatment processes is attractive for energy saving and cost reduction. Such technology has been achieved in the fields of methane and methanol synthesis via the hydrogen reduction of CO2. Recently, the concept of directly using low-concentration CO2 has been applied to the synthesis of high value-added chemicals without hydrogen reduction. The synthesis of useful chemicals from CO2 without hydrogen reduction is a technology that will be put into practical use without waiting for the widespread use of green hydrogen. Thus, this review introduces the technology for the direct synthesis of useful chemicals, such as dialkyl carbonates (DRCs), carbamic acid esters (CAEs), and urea derivatives from low-concentration CO2 contained in exhaust gas or air, without hydrogen reduction. DRCs, CAEs, and urea derivatives are synthesized via the non-hydrogen reduction route of CO2. They are expected to contribute to long-term, large-volume CO2 fixation because they are raw materials of functional polymers, which have long-material-life and large market potential. Details on how to synthesize these compounds directly from low-concentration CO2 are presented, focusing on the efforts to devise CO2 capture processes, reactants, and catalysts.</description>
      <author>Katsuhiko Takeuchi, Hiroki Koizumi, Haruki Nagae, Kazuhiro Matsumoto, Norihisa Fukaya, Kazuhiko Sat&#333;, Junho Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Have Land Use Carbon Emissions Changed in the Past and Future Under Multiple Scenarios? -Based on Carbon Emissions Fair Model and Plus Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4851326</link>
      <description>Tianqi Rong, Mingzhou Qin, Pengyan Zhang, Yinghui Chang, Zhenyue Liu, Z.J. Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399277193

                With the increase of carbon dioxide concentration, global warming has become increasingly serious, and has posed a serious threat to human survival and the ecological environment. The land use carbon emissions (LUCE) are only second to those caused by fossil fuel combustion. The affected area of the lower Yellow River (ALYR) is an essential grain producing area in China. Studying its LUCE and future development has practical significance for the low-carbon development and food security of the basin. We analyzed the characteristics and drivers of LUCE in the ALYR from 2000 &#8722; 2018 and simulated the LUCE under different scenarios in 2030. The LUCE in the ALYR were in a continuous growth trend, with a growth rate of 27.94%, and the economic efficiency and ecological carrying capacity remained stable. The built-up land area and the proportion of secondary industry in GDP can promote the LUCE, while the per capita GDP has a suppressive effect. The LUCE will decrease in 2030, with the least LUCE under the cultivated land protection scenario. The results show that it is necessary to control the built-up land and increase the area of ecological land in order to achieve carbon emission reduction. This study analyzed the LUCE in the ALYR from the different periods, providing a theoretical reference for promoting sustainable development of the basin and scientific land use management.</description>
      <author>Tianqi Rong, Mingzhou Qin, Pengyan Zhang, Yinghui Chang, Zhenyue Liu, Z.J. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4851326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A snapshot of fundamental geological knowledge to deal with climate change</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7186/bgsm77202401</link>
      <description>Joy Jacqueline Pereira, Buletin Persatuan Geologi Malaysia. 77(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399303012

                The 28th meeting of the Conference of the Parties (COP 28) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, concluded in December 2023. The meeting discussed the overarching goal of the legally binding Paris Agreement to limit &#8220;global average temperature to well below 2 &#176;C above pre-industrial levels and pursuing efforts to limit the temperature increase to 1.5 &#176;C above pre-industrial levels&#8221;. The COP 28 recognised recent findings of Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) that &#8220;limiting global warming to 1.5 &#176;C with no or limited overshoot requires deep, rapid and sustained reductions in global greenhouse gas emissions of 43% by 2030 and 60% by 2035 relative to the 2019 level, and reaching net zero carbon dioxide emissions by 2050&#8221;.</description>
      <author>Joy Jacqueline Pereira</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7186/bgsm77202401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The structure of carbon dioxide at the air&#8208;water interface and its chemical implications.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400825</link>
      <description>Marilia T. C. Martins&#8208;Costa, Manuel F. Ruiz&#8208;L&#243;pez, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399360917

                The efficient reduction of CO2 into valuable products is a challenging task in an international context marked by the climate change crisis and the need to move away from fossil fuels. Recently, the use of water microdroplets has emerged as an interesting reaction media where many redox processes which do not occur in conventional solutions take place spontaneously. Indeed, several experimental studies in microdroplets have already been devoted to study the reduction of CO2 with promising results. The increased reactivity in microdroplets is thought to be linked to unique electrostatic solvation effects at the air&#8208;water interface. In the present work, we report a theoretical investigation on this issue for CO2 using first&#8208;principles molecular dynamics simulations. We show that CO2 is stabilized at the interface, where it can accumulate, and that compared to bulk water solution, its electron capture ability is larger. Our results suggests that reduction of CO2 might be easier in interface&#8208;rich systems such as water microdroplets, which is in line with early experimental data and indicate directions for future laboratory studies. The effect of other relevant factors which could play a role in CO2 reduction potential is discussed.</description>
      <author>Marilia T. C. Martins&#8208;Costa, Manuel F. Ruiz&#8208;L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of Carbon Quantum Dots/Alq3 Layer for NO2 Gas Sensor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30723/ijp.v22i1.1214</link>
      <description>N. Ahmed, Omar Adnan, Iraqi journal of physics. 22(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399261167

                The gas sensors were prepared using carbon quantum dots (CQDs) using an electrochemical method after mixing the CQDs with Tris (8-hydroxyquinoline) aluminum (III) (Alq3) polymer. A spin coating technique was used to deposit CQDs/Alq3 composite film on glass substrates with a ratio of 1:1. The CQDs/Alq3 gas sensor showed a sensitivity of about 24&#1642; at a temperature of 300 &#8451;, and this was calculated after measuring the change in the resistance of the samples with a response time of 2 and 8sec recovery time. The sensor showed a good response for nitrogen dioxide (NO2) gas. However, the sensitivity, response time, and recovery time for the CQDs gas sensor when exposed to NO2 gas at 300 &#176;C were 78%, 4s, and 129s, respectively. The results showed that the best sensor CQDs/Alq3 led to a reduction in the recovery time, which shows the importance of the Alq3 polymer in improving the properties of the gas sensor.</description>
      <author>N. Ahmed, Omar Adnan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30723/ijp.v22i1.1214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The lubricity of gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4445568/v1</link>
      <description>Jie Zhang, Janet Wong, Hugh Spikes, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399238332

                Abstract A sealed reciprocating tribometer has been used to study the influence of different gaseous environments on the friction and wear properties of AISI52100 bearing steel at atmospheric pressure and 25&#176;C. Helium, argon, hydrogen, carbon dioxide and nitrogen all give high friction and wear, suggestive of very little, if any tribofilm formation under the conditions studied. Dry air and oxygen also give high friction, slightly lower than the inert gases, but produce extremely high wear, much higher than the inert gases. This is characteristic of the phenomenon of &#8220;oxidational wear&#8221;. The two gases ammonia and carbon monoxide give relatively low friction and wear, and XPS analysis indicates that this is due to the formation of adsorbed ammonia/nitride and carbonate films respectively. For the hydrocarbon gases studied, two factors appear to control friction and wear, degree of unsaturation and molecular weight. For the saturated hydrocarbons, methane and ethane give high friction and wear but propane and butane give low friction after a period of rubbing that decreases with molecular weight. The unsaturated hydrocarbons all give an immediate reduction in friction with correspondingly low wear. Raman analysis shows that all the hydrocarbons that reduce friction and wear form a carbonaceous tribofilm of the rubbed surfaces.</description>
      <author>Jie Zhang, Janet Wong, Hugh Spikes</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4445568/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise&#8217;s strategies to improve financial capital under a climate change scenario &#8211; evidence of the leading country</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44168-024-00121-5</link>
      <description>Nguyen Quang-Loc, Minh&#8208;Hoang Nguyen, Viet&#8208;Phuong La, M. Ishaq Bhatti, Quan&#8208;Hoang Vuong, npj climate action. 3(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399300488

                Abstract Climate change poses manifold consequences to the world&#8217;s ecosystems and human well-being. Greenhouse gas emissions reduction and climate-friendly technological innovations at the corporate level are considered effective measures to mitigate climate change. Using the Bayesian Mindsponge Framework (BMF) to analyze 178 enterprises listed in the Standard and Poor&#8217;s 500 companies from 2016 to 2021, this paper examines how companies&#8217; climate risk-mitigating efforts can affect their market value. We found that emitted carbon dioxide negatively affects the stock price. Meanwhile, companies&#8217; income and climate risk-mitigating efforts, including producing eco-friendly products, using renewable energy, and environmental investments, are positively associated with their share value. However, the effects of these efforts are conditional on the companies&#8217; income. Based on these findings, we suggest that building an eco-surplus culture among investors and improving their climate change knowledge can be a promising approach to promoting a corporation&#8217;s mitigation efforts.</description>
      <author>Nguyen Quang-Loc, Minh&#8208;Hoang Nguyen, Viet&#8208;Phuong La, M. Ishaq Bhatti, Quan&#8208;Hoang Vuong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44168-024-00121-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocarrier Tunneling Triggering CO2 Photocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02313g</link>
      <description>Xian Yan, Meng Yuan, Yanbin Yuan, Peng Su, Qing Chen, Fang&#8208;Xing Xiao, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399294753

                Solar CO2 reduction to renewable hydrocarbon fuels offers a promising pathway to carbon neutrality, but it is retarded by tough CO2 activation, complicated mechanism, sluggish charge transport kinetics and scarcity...</description>
      <author>Xian Yan, Meng Yuan, Yanbin Yuan, Peng Su, Qing Chen, Fang&#8208;Xing Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02313g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Synthesis of Magnesium Single Atom Catalyst from Spinacia oleracea-Chlorophyll Extracts for Sustainable Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc01422g</link>
      <description>Kanhai Kumar, P. Tripathi, Gokul Raj, Dova Kalyan, Demudu Babu Gorle, Nikhil George Mohan, Surendra Kumar Makineni, Kothandaraman Ramanujam, Abhishek K. Singh, Karuna Kar Nanda, Green chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399266957

                Single atom-based catalysts (SACs), due to their exceptional electrocatalytic behavior, have been explored for numerous applications such as oxygen reduction reaction, thermo-catalytic CO2 reduction, and other catalytic activities. Ammonia is...</description>
      <author>Kanhai Kumar, P. Tripathi, Gokul Raj, Dova Kalyan, Demudu Babu Gorle, Nikhil George Mohan, Surendra Kumar Makineni, Kothandaraman Ramanujam, Abhishek K. Singh, Karuna Kar Nanda</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc01422g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the environmental and downstream human health impacts of decentralizing cancer care.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2024.42.16_suppl.1522</link>
      <description>Andrew Hantel, Colin Cernik, Thomas Walsh, Hajime Uno, Dalia Larios, Jonathan E. Slutzman, Gregory A. Abel, Journal of clinical oncology. 42(16_suppl)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399324775

                1522 Background: Greenhouse gas emissions from healthcare are substantial and harm persons with cancer. Emissions from outpatient cancer care visits are not well described, nor are the downstream reduction in human harms that could be obtained through visit &#8220;decentralization&#8221; (telemedicine and local care when possible). Methods: This life-cycle assessment (LCA)-based study evaluated changes in emissions and downstream health harms associated with (1) telemedicine visits using retrospective observational analysis and (2) fully decentralized visits using counterfactual modeling. The retrospective observational cohort included persons receiving cancer care at Dana-Farber Cancer Institute (DFCI) and 20 affiliated facilities between 5/2015-12/2020. The main outcome was the adjusted per visit-day difference in emissions (in kilograms carbon dioxide equivalents: kgCO 2 e) between two periods: an in-person care period (5/2015-2/2020; &#8220;Pre&#8221;) and a telemedicine period (3/2020-12/2020; &#8220;Post&#8221;). Mixed effects log-linear model assessed emissions changes adjusted for age, sex, race, ethnicity, and cancer type, with random effects on person. The counterfactual model assessed emissions changes between actual in-person visits during the Pre period and a counterfactual with maximal decentralization. Visit-day eligibility for decentralization was obtained by categorizing appointments (e.g., clinician visit, infusion) as DFCI required, local care possible, or telemedicine possible. This cohort was matched to a national population diagnosed with cancer over the same period (Cancer in North America [CiNA] dataset) using mixed-effects linear modeling, through which annual changes in disability-adjusted life-years (DALY) from clinician visit decentralization were estimated using Eckelman&#8217;s mortality cost of carbon conversion. Results: There were123,890 unique patients in the DFCI cohort seen over 1.6 million visit-days (Pre N=110,180, Post N=61,691) at a median of 6 visit-days per patient (IQR 2, 15). An estimated 72,554,006 kgCO 2 e were within scope of the LCA emitted during the study period. In mixed-effects log-linear regression, the adjusted mean absolute reduction in per visit-day emissions between Pre and Post periods was 36.4 kgCO 2 e (95%CI 36.2,36.6), or a reduction of 81.3% (95%CI 80.8,81.7) compared to the baseline model. In the counterfactual decentralized care model of the Pre period, there was a relative emissions reduction of 33.1% (95%CI 32.9,33.3). When demographically matched to 10.3 million persons in the CiNA dataset, decentralized care would have reduced national emissions by 75.3 million kgCO 2 e annually; this corresponds to an estimated annual reduction of 15.0-47.7 DALYs. Conclusions: Employing decentralization through telemedicine and local care can substantially reduce emissions during cancer care delivery; this corresponds to a small reduction in human mortality.</description>
      <author>Andrew Hantel, Colin Cernik, Thomas Walsh, Hajime Uno, Dalia Larios, Jonathan E. Slutzman, Gregory A. Abel</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2024.42.16_suppl.1522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O Interaction with High-Rank Coal on Mechanical Properties and Acoustic Emission Characteristics under Confining Pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c02599</link>
      <description>Yi Jiang, Jienan Pan, Zhenzhi Wang, Nannan Cheng, Lei Zhang, Xianglong Wang, Weiqing Liu, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399293489

                The adsorption of CO2 by coal leads to changes in its mechanical properties, particularly when considering supercritical CO2 and water with supercritical CO2 adsorption. This is strongly linked to the efficiency of CO2-enhanced coalbed methane (CO2-ECBM) extraction and the safety of CO2 geological storage. This study focuses on 3# coal from the Datong Mine in Gaoping City, Shanxi Province. The high-rank coal's mechanical properties, including the triaxial compressive strength and elastic modulus, were examined under the combined effects of CO2 injection pressure, CO2 injection time, and moisture content. The triaxial compressive strength and elastic modulus of the coal showed a decrease following CO2 injection. Increasing the CO2 injection pressure, prolonging the CO2 injection time, and increasing the moisture content were favorable for coal softening. In particular, the triaxial compressive strength and elastic modulus of the coal sample after 144 h of water and supercritical CO2 softening decreased by 67.67 and 64.15%, respectively. Injecting CO2 into coal changed its failure mode. The dry raw coal sample exhibited a brittle shear failure mode, while the coal samples showed transitional shear failure after injecting 6 MPa CO2 and 8 MPa CO2 and ductile nondilatant barreling failure after injecting water and 8 MPa CO2 (with a moisture content of 3.02%). Moreover, the cumulative acoustic emission energy of the coal samples followed a similar trend to the decrease in mechanical properties under different conditions. The physical and chemical interactions among coal, CO2, and water caused the softening of coal; these included the generation of the swelling stress, the dissolution of minerals by carbonate solutions, the reduction in surface energy of coal owing to CO2 adsorption, and the extraction and plasticization reactions of organic matter in coal. The research results are of great significance for further understanding CO2-ECBM and CO2 geological sequestration.</description>
      <author>Yi Jiang, Jienan Pan, Zhenzhi Wang, Nannan Cheng, Lei Zhang, Xianglong Wang, Weiqing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c02599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk-based MMV for Efficient, Long-Term Storage of CO2: Lessons Learnt from Quest</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3997/2214-4609.2024101844</link>
      <description>Sara Minisini, Marcella Dean, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399244822

                Summary CCS facilities need to demonstrate that the injected CO2 will be safely and permanently contained during the full life-cycle of CO2 storage operations, from the injection to post-closure. This presentation will outline fundamentals of risk-based Measurement, Monitoring and Verification (MMV), followed by insights and learnings from the Quest operational MMV programme. Further, a brief overview of cost reduction opportunities and new monitoring technology developments will be shared.</description>
      <author>Sara Minisini, Marcella Dean</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3997/2214-4609.2024101844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Environmental and Downstream Human Health Impacts of Decentralizing Cancer Care</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoncol.2024.2744</link>
      <description>Andrew Hantel, Colin Cernik, Thomas Walsh, Hajime Uno, Dalia Larios, Jonathan E. Slutzman, Gregory A. Abel, JAMA oncology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399287407

                Importance Greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from health care are substantial and disproportionately harm persons with cancer. Emissions from a central component of oncology care, outpatient clinician visits, are not well described, nor are the reductions in emissions and human harms that could be obtained through decentralizing this aspect of cancer care (ie, telemedicine and local clinician care when possible). Objective To assess potential reductions in GHG emissions and downstream health harms associated with telemedicine and fully decentralized cancer care. Design, Setting, and Participants This population-based cohort study and counterfactual analyses using life cycle assessment methods analyzed persons receiving cancer care at Dana-Farber Cancer Institute between May 2015 and December 2020 as well as persons diagnosed with cancer over the same period from the Cancer in North America (CiNA) public dataset. Data were analyzed from October 2023 to April 2024. Main Outcomes and Measures The adjusted per&#8211;visit day difference in GHG emissions in kilograms of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) equivalents between 2 periods: an in-person care model period (May 2015 to February 2020; preperiod) and a telemedicine period (March to December 2020; postperiod), and the annual decrease in disability-adjusted life-years in a counterfactual model where care during the preperiod was maximally decentralized nationwide. Results Of 123 890 included patients, 73 988 (59.7%) were female, and the median (IQR) age at first diagnosis was 59 (48-68) years. Patients were seen over 1.6 million visit days. In mixed-effects log-linear regression, the mean absolute reduction in per&#8211;visit day CO 2 equivalent emissions between the preperiod and postperiod was 36.4 kg (95% CI, 36.2-36.6), a reduction of 81.3% (95% CI, 80.8-81.7) compared with the baseline model. In a counterfactual decentralized care model of the preperiod, there was a relative emissions reduction of 33.1% (95% CI, 32.9-33.3). When demographically matched to 10.3 million persons in the CiNA dataset, decentralized care would have reduced national emissions by 75.3 million kg of CO 2 equivalents annually; this corresponded to an estimated annual reduction of 15.0 to 47.7 disability-adjusted life-years. Conclusions and Relevance This cohort study found that using decentralization through telemedicine and local care may substantially reduce cancer care&#8217;s GHG emissions; this corresponds to small reductions in human mortality.</description>
      <author>Andrew Hantel, Colin Cernik, Thomas Walsh, Hajime Uno, Dalia Larios, Jonathan E. Slutzman, Gregory A. Abel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoncol.2024.2744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Dual-Atom Catalysts for Sustainable Ammonia Production from Nitrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00171k</link>
      <description>Sreekuttan M. Unni, P. H. Ashida, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399264487

                The traditional Haber-Bosch process, which is essential for global food supply, is both energy- and capital-intensive, leading to high levels of CO2 emissions and negative environmental consequences. Electrochemical nitrogen reduction...</description>
      <author>Sreekuttan M. Unni, P. H. Ashida</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00171k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The artificial neural network-based two-phase equilibrium calculation framework for fast compositional reservoir simulation of CO2 EOR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fluid.2024.114151</link>
      <description>Liang-nan Li, Hongbin Jing, Jianqiao Liu, Huanquan Pan, Zhengbao Fang, Tie Kuang, Yubo Lan, Jianchun Guo, Fluid phase equilibria. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399243635

                Injecting CO2 into the reservoir is an essential method for Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage (CCUS) and enhanced oil recovery (EOR). However, due to the complex phase behavior between CO2 and hydrocarbons, the reservoir simulation of the injection process becomes time-consuming. To expedite phase equilibrium calculations (PECs) involved in CO2-EOR, we have developed an artificial neural network (ANN)-based PECs framework comprising the 1P-stability and 2P-flash models, which replaced traditional single-phase stability analysis and two-phase flash calculations. Additionally, We proposed a straightforward method for generating training points tailored to CO2-EOR production characteristics. Specific settings are placed on the two models to ensure a 100% correct solution, including predefining criteria to filter the stability model output and utilizing the flash model output as the standard algorithm initial value. We have enhanced the ANN-based models to integrate seamlessly with the compositional simulator. Four published fluids were selected to test this framework by implementing the standalone PECs, and one fluid was used for the simulation of CO2-EOR. The ANN-based framework can save up to 80% of time on phase equilibrium calculations, resulting in a 40% reduction in simulation time compared to the conventional algorithm. In summary, the newly developed ANN-based PECs framework shows great potential to accelerate the reservoir simulation for CO2-EOR, which helps design the program of CCUS by injecting CO2 into the reservoir.</description>
      <author>Liang-nan Li, Hongbin Jing, Jianqiao Liu, Huanquan Pan, Zhengbao Fang, Tie Kuang, Yubo Lan, Jianchun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fluid.2024.114151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulated radiocarbon cycle revisited by considering the bipolar seesaw and benthic 14C data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.epsl.2024.118801</link>
      <description>Peter K&#246;hler, Luke C Skinner, Florian Adolphi, Earth and planetary science letters. 640(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399215466

                Carbon cycle models used to calculate the marine reservoir age of the non-polar surface ocean (called Marine20) out of IntCal20, the compilation of atmospheric &#916;14C, have so far neglected a key aspect of the millennial-scale variability connected with the thermal bipolar seesaw: changes in the strength of the Atlantic meridional overturning circulation (AMOC) related to Dansgaard/Oeschger and Heinrich events. Here we implement such AMOC changes in the carbon cycle box model BICYCLE-SE to investigate how model performance over the last 55 kyr is affected, in particular with respect to available 14C and CO2 data. Constraints from deep ocean 14C data suggest that the AMOC in the model during Heinrich stadial 1 needs to be highly reduced or even completely shutdown. Ocean circulation and sea ice coverage combined are the processes that almost completely explain the simulated changes in deep ocean 14C age, and these are also responsible for a glacial drawdown of &#8764;60 ppm of atmospheric CO2. We find that the implementation of abrupt reductions in AMOC during Greenland stadials in the model setup that was previously used for the calculation of Marine20 leads to differences of less than &#177;100 14C yrs. The representation of AMOC changes therefore appears to be of minor importance for deriving non-polar mean ocean radiocarbon calibration products such as Marine20, where atmospheric carbon cycle variables are forced by reconstructions. However, simulated atmospheric CO2 exhibits minima during AMOC reductions in Heinrich stadials, in disagreement with ice core data. This mismatch supports previous suggestions that millennial-scale changes in CO2 were probably not driven directly by the AMOC, but rather by biological and physical processes in the Southern Ocean and by contributions from variable land carbon storage.</description>
      <author>Peter K&#246;hler, Luke C Skinner, Florian Adolphi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.epsl.2024.118801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selection of sheep skin bacteria to reduce blood-feeding by biting midges under laboratory conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.30.596646</link>
      <description>Paula S. Brok, S Jost, Niels O. Verhulst, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399260347

                Biting midges of the genus Culicoides (Diptera: Ceratopogonidae) are of huge veterinary importance, mainly as vectors of pathogens, such as Bluetongue virus. Currently, there are no effective methods to protect animals against biting midges since insecticides have limited or short-lived efficacy. Biting midges are attracted to hosts by carbon dioxide and by their body odours, which are mainly produced by skin bacteria. In humans, it has been shown that differences in attractiveness between individuals to mosquitoes is mediated by these skin bacterial volatiles. This opens the possibility to protect individuals from biting insects by supplementing their skin microbiome with probiotics. In this study, we investigated this approach by culturing sheep skin bacteria on different media and assessed their effects against field-caught Culicoides (overwhelmingly Obsoletus group species) as well as laboratory-reared Culicoides nubeculosus (Meigen). Aerococcus urinaeeequi, Bacillus safensis, Bacillus subtilis, Jeotgalicoccus psychrophilus, Micrococcus sp. and Staphylococcus equorum were selected to be tested in a dual-choice Y-tube olfactometer, assessing their behavioural effects towards biting midges. We revealed an avoidance effect towards laboratory-reared C. nubeculosus when testing B. safensis (P &#8804; 0.001) and B. subtilis (P &#8804; 0.001). Bacillus safensis (P = 0.006) and Micrococcus sp. (P &#8804; 0.001) yielded significant repellent potential towards field-caught Culicoides. These two candidates were subsequently tested in a membrane blood feeding assay. When the bacterial species B. safensis was applied to the membrane, a feeding reduction of 83 % was observed with field-caught Culicoides.</description>
      <author>Paula S. Brok, S Jost, Niels O. Verhulst</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.30.596646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microscopic Seepage Mechanism of Nanofluids Assistant Co2 Aerosol Foam System Flooding after Water Flooding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4852409</link>
      <description>Xiangyu Wang, Chenwei Liu, Jiacheng Nie, Chenru Zhou, Chuixiu Huang, &#1051;&#1080;&#1085;&#1075; &#1051;&#1086;&#1085;&#1075;, Mingzhong Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399311111

                CO2 foam (CF) flooding is an effective method for enhancing oil recovery (EOR) in late-stage water drive reservoirs. However, inadequate mixing of CO2 and foaming agent solution during the injection process leads to the formation of uneven and unstable foam, thereby limited the efficient development of water drive reservoirs. Herein, we report a novel CO2 aerosol foam system (CAFS) generated by a custom-built aerosol foam generator. The CAFS development performance was systematically analyzed after water flooding and investigate the affecting factors about gas-liquid ratio, pre-injection volume, and solution concentration using flooding experiments. Evaluation parameters such as recovery, water cut, differential pressure, and resistance coefficient are employed. Additionally, we examine the microscopic EOR mechanism of CAFS through visualized microscopic flooding experiments. The results reveal that CAFS exhibits better development performance compared to conventional CF flooding. This improvement is attributed to enhanced rock wettability by hydrophobic nanoparticles and the high resistance coefficient of aerosol foam, both of which contribute significantly to the superior oil production performance of CAFS. Microscopic experiments demonstrate that CO2 aerosol generates more uniform foam and effectively expands the sweep area through trapping effects, superimposed Jamin effects, and squeezing occupation in pore throats. Moreover, the emulsification capability of nanofluid-SDS solution and viscosity reduction of oil due to dissolved CO2 after foam breakdown in the matrix further facilitate oil recovery, where the remained oil is recovered as foamy oil driven by the subsequently injected fluid.</description>
      <author>Xiangyu Wang, Chenwei Liu, Jiacheng Nie, Chenru Zhou, Chuixiu Huang, &#1051;&#1080;&#1085;&#1075; &#1051;&#1086;&#1085;&#1075;, Mingzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4852409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Analyzable Solutions for Left-Turn-Centered Congestion Problems in Urban Grid Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114777</link>
      <description>Taraneh Ardalan, Denis Sarazhinsky, Nemanja Dobrota, Aleksandar Stevanovic, Sustainability. 16(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399321298

                Traffic congestion caused by left-turning vehicles in a coordinated corridor is a multifaceted problem requiring tailored solutions. This study explores the impact of shared left-turn lanes within one-way couplets, particularly during peak hours, where high left-turn volumes, limited side street storage, and the overlapped green time between pedestrians and left-turners contribute to queue spillbacks, coordination interruption, and network congestion. The focus of this paper is on the solutions that can be easily analyzed by practitioners, here called &#8220;analyzable solutions&#8221;. This approach stands in contrast to solutions derived from &#8220;non-transparent&#8221; optimization tools, which do not allow for a clear assessment of the solution&#8217;s adequacy or the ability to predict its impact in real-world applications. This paper investigates the effects of employing two analyzable signal timing strategies: Lagging Pedestrian (LagPed) phasing and Left-Turn Progression (LTP) offsets. Using high-fidelity microsimulation, the authors evaluated different scenarios, assessing pedestrian delays, queue lengths, travel time index, area average travel time index, and environmental impacts such as Fuel Consumption (FC) and CO2 emissions. The effectiveness of the proposed strategies was comprehensively evaluated against the base case scenario, demonstrating considerable improvements in various performance measures, including approximately a 5% reduction in FC and CO2 emissions. Implementation of the LTP strategy alone yields substantial reductions in delays, the number of stops, the queue length for left-turning vehicles, travel times for all road users, and ultimately FC and CO2 emissions. This study offers innovative approach to addressing the complex and multifaceted problem of left-turn-centered congestion in urban grid networks using efficient and down-to-earth analyzable solutions.</description>
      <author>Taraneh Ardalan, Denis Sarazhinsky, Nemanja Dobrota, Aleksandar Stevanovic</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delayed effects of air pollution on public bike-sharing system use in Seoul, South Korea: A time series analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2024.117030</link>
      <description>Eun&#8208;Hye Yoo, John &#919;. Roberts, Young-Joo Suh, Social science &amp; medicine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399209089

                As a complementary means to urban public transit systems, public bike-sharing provides a green and active mode of sustainable mobility, while reducing carbon-dioxide emissions and promoting health. There has been increasing interest in factors affecting bike-sharing usage, but little is known about the effect of ambient air pollution. To assess the short-term impact of daily exposure to multiple air pollutants (PM2.5, PM10, NO2, and O3) on the public bike-sharing system (PBS) usage in Seoul, South Korea (2018--2021), we applied a quasi-Poisson generalized linear model combined with a distributed lag nonlinear model (DLNM). The model was adjusted for day of the week, holiday, temperature, relative humidity, and long-term trend. We also conducted stratification analyses to examine the effect modification by age group, seasonality, and COVID-19. We found that there was a negative association between daily ambient air pollution and the PBS usage level at a single lag day 1 (i.e., air quality a day before the event) across all four pollutants. Our results suggest that days with high levels of air pollutants (at 95th percentile) are associated with 0.91% (0.86% to 0.96%) for PM2.5, 0.89% (0.85% to 0.94%) for PM10, 0.87% (0.82% to 0.91%) for O3, 0.92% (0.87% to 0.98%) for NO2, reductions in cycling behavior in the next day compared to days with low levels of pollutants (at 25th percentile). No evidence of effect modification was found by seasonality, age nor the COVID-19 pandemic for any of the four pollutants. Our findings suggest that high concentrations of ambient air pollution are associated with decreased rates of PBS usage on the subsequent day regardless of the type of air pollutant measured.</description>
      <author>Eun&#8208;Hye Yoo, John &#919;. Roberts, Young-Joo Suh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2024.117030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy prediction for future energy supply in electrical vehicles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-23814-7.00006-7</link>
      <description>S. Syed Rafiammal, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399224875

                The carbon dioxide emission due to fuel-based vehicle transportation was greatly reduced by the usage of electric vehicles (EVs). The energy management of battery systems in EV plays a vital role in the development of modern vehicles. The consumption of energy by EVs depends on vehicle parameters and path details. By monitoring these parameters, the energy prediction models are developed to predict future energy consumption, which increases the vehicle performance, and to avoid driver's range anxiety problems. Artificial intelligence (AI) helps to develop sophisticated energy prediction models in EV systems. The machine learning (ML) algorithms are harnessed to predict future energy requirements based on the vehicle's prior details. Recurrent neural network algorithms and sequence-based ML algorithms are effectively forecasting required energy in EV models. In this proposed work, a sequence-based hybrid deep ML algorithm is employed because of its ability to intricate relationships within the dataset. Long-short-term memory and gated recurrent unit algorithms are bootstrap aggregated to make a hybrid bagging deep ML model. The model is developed using an EV model BMWi3 driving trips dataset. The EV dataset is preprocessed using the dimensionality reduction method. The random forest-based feature selection algorithm is used to achieve dimensionality reduction. The details of the EV vehicle's battery current, battery voltage, driving velocity, electric motor torque, elevation of the road, throttle, environmental temperature, and battery state of charge are selected as important features to model the dataset for AI model training. The model is validated by a fivefold cross-validation method. The results reveal that the predicted energy consumption values are nearly equal to the original energy consumed values. The performance of the proposed model is evaluated by mean square error (MSE) and mean absolute error (MAE). The MSE of the proposed prediction algorithm is achieved as 0.20%, and the MAE is achieved as 0.4%. The results show that the proposed model can be implemented in hardware for the design of an effective energy management system in modern EVs to retrieve the issue of driver anxiety and improve performance.</description>
      <author>S. Syed Rafiammal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-23814-7.00006-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pilot-scale study on combustion characteristics, slagging characteristics and flue gas composition of coal oilfield wastewater slurry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.123572</link>
      <description>Yang Xiang, Yumeng Zhang, Jianbin Wang, Wanqin Jin, Xiaodan Gao, Junhai Wen, Jian Zhong Liu, Bo Wang, Applied thermal engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399207392

                As the volume of oil extraction continues to rise, the issue of oilfield wastewater treatment has become increasingly urgent. Traditional water treatment technologies struggle to effectively and economically eliminate the pollution caused by oilfield wastewater, as well as efficiently utilize its various components. This study proposes the utilization of oilfield wastewater for the preparation of coal water slurry, and the combustion experiments of coal oilfield wastewater slurry (COWS) and original coal water slurry (CWS) under various working conditions are conducted on a pilot-scale horizontal furnace. The investigation focused on the combustion characteristics, slagging characteristics and flue gas composition, as these indicators directly impact the industrial application of such slurry fuel. The combustion characteristics results reveal that both COWS and CWS demonstrate stable ignition and combustion across all working conditions, with combustion efficiency exceeding 99.69%, and the incorporation of oilfield wastewater promotes volatiles precipitation and combustion. The slagging characteristics results indicate that the flame temperature within the furnace is critical in determining slagging occurrence, and the incorporation of oilfield wastewater increases the likelihood of slagging. The flue gas composition measurement results indicate that the incorporation of oilfield wastewater slightly elevates carbon monoxide (CO) levels, albeit within a low concentration range. Additionally, oilfield wastewater demonstrates a modest reduction in sulfur dioxide (SO2) and nitrogen oxide (NOx) emissions. These test results underscore that incorporating oilfield wastewater into the preparation of fuel coal water slurry not only facilitates thorough treatment of oilfield wastewater, but also enhance the combustion performance of slurry fuel within the furnace, thereby offering significant industrial application potential.</description>
      <author>Yang Xiang, Yumeng Zhang, Jianbin Wang, Wanqin Jin, Xiaodan Gao, Junhai Wen, Jian Zhong Liu, Bo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.123572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjusting the phase transition time node of a solid&#8211;liquid biphasic solvent based on 2-amino-2-methyl-1-propanol for efficient CO2 capture: Insight into the regulatory effect of aminoethylethanolamine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128149</link>
      <description>Xiaobin Zhou, Ting Zou, Wei Wang, Zhifang Tu, Yinming Fan, Jianwen Wei, Lei Liao, Zongqiang Zhu, Yinian Zhu, Dunqiu Wang, Guohua Jing, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399243375

                Solid-liquid biphasic solvents (SLBSs) hold promise as energy-efficient candidates for CO2 capture. Nevertheless, the premature phase transition of current SLBSs leads to inopportune solid precipitation, posing operational challenges for the CO2 capture system. This study proposed a promising strategy that using aminoethylethanolamine (AEEA) as a regulator to fine-tune the phase transition time node of the 2-amino-2-methyl-1-propanol (AMP)/N-methylpyrrolidone (NMP) SLBS, enabling the phase transition to occur precisely as desired. Experimental results showed that the AEEA/AMP/NMP (A/A/N) SLBS exhibited tunable phase transition time nodes, modulated by the concentration of AEEA. Specifically, with the addition of 0.2 mol&#183;L&#8722;1 AEEA, the CO2 loading associated with the phase transition increased significantly, from 0.19 to 0.54 mol&#183;mol&#8722;1, approaching the saturation loading of 0.57 mol&#183;mol&#8722;1. The delayed phase transition would facilitate the CO2 absorption operation. The regulatory mechanism of AEEA on the phase transition were thoroughly studied via 13C NMR and quantum calculations. AMP reacted with CO2 to produce AMPCOO&#8722; and AMPH+, which had a significantly stronger affinity for each other than for the solvent NMP, mediated by strong hydrogen bond interactions. Consequently, the continuous and fast aggregation of AMPCOO&#8722; and AMPH+ caused their swift precipitation from NMP. With the introduction of AEEA, the derived product AEEAH+(S)COO&#8211;(P) acted as a bridge-builder, connecting AMPCOO&#8722; or AMPH+ and NMP via hydrogen bonds, increasing the solubility of the AMP-derived products in NMP, thus effectively delaying the phase transition. Thermodynamic analysis revealed that the A/A/N SLBS exhibited a total regeneration energy consumption of 1.94 GJ&#183;ton&#8722;1 CO2, representing a significant reduction of 48.9 % compared to that of 30 wt% MEA. This study provided a novel idea for designing SLBSs with controllable phase transition behavior, and offered a promising A/A/N SLBS for energy-efficient CO2 capture.</description>
      <author>Xiaobin Zhou, Ting Zou, Wei Wang, Zhifang Tu, Yinming Fan, Jianwen Wei, Lei Liao, Zongqiang Zhu, Yinian Zhu, Dunqiu Wang, Guohua Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core-in-shell, glucose-templated, ZrO2-stabilized calcium/copper-based pellets with robust CO2 capture performance for Ca/Cu process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128241</link>
      <description>Jian Chen, Weimin Xia, Huiping Tang, Anqi Huang, Changqiang Huang, Y. Li, Yuxin Jiang, Zhicheng Wang, Yu Gu, Bin Qi, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399207529

                Calcium/copper-based pellets are crucial to the advancement of the Ca/Cu process, as CuO reduction provides the heat necessary for CaCO3 calcination. Yet, a significant challenge lies in preserving their CO2 capture performance, which tends to deteriorate rapidly. Thus in this study, we proposed a two-stage method to synthesize core-in-shell, glucose-templated, ZrO2-stabilized calcium/copper-based pellets that are highly efficient at capturing CO2. The designed pellets featured a core concentrated with CaO and CuO, surrounded by an outer shell of ZrO2. Initially, different particle size ranges of unstabilized calcium/copper-based pellets were fabricated, including 200&#8211;470, 210&#8211;600, 400&#8211;890, and 800&#8211;1090 &#956;m. A minor improvement in CO2 capture performance was observed with decreasing particle sizes, ranging from 0.16 to 0.20 gCO2/gmaterial. However, a noticeable decline in CO2 capture performance was observed in these unstabilized calcium/copper-based pellets during cycling. To address this issue, these pellets were then coated with a ZrO2 shell. The core-in-shell, ZrO2-stabilized calcium/copper-based pellets possessed much-improved CO2 sorption stability, mainly due to that the ZrO2 shell mitigated the degradation of the pore structure resulting from sintering during cycling. Finally, glucose was incorporated as a pore-forming material into the core-in-shell, ZrO2-stabilized calcium/copper-based pellets, improving the pore structure and further boosting their reactivity. The incorporation of glucose proved to be beneficial, resulting in enhanced capacity and stability for CO2 sorption for the core-in-shell, glucose-templated, ZrO2-stabilized calcium/copper-based pellets. The best-performing sample, i.e., calcium/copper-based pellets with the simultaneous coating of a ZrO2 shell and the incorporation of glucose, demonstrated a sorption capacity of 0.26 gCO2/gmaterial in the initial cycle. This capacity decreased to 0.18 gCO2/gmaterial in the tenth cycle, retaining 70 % of its initial reactivity.</description>
      <author>Jian Chen, Weimin Xia, Huiping Tang, Anqi Huang, Changqiang Huang, Y. Li, Yuxin Jiang, Zhicheng Wang, Yu Gu, Bin Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of microstructure evolution and redox behavior of Ni-GDC cermet by cyclic re-oxidation in CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.478</link>
      <description>Yang Sun, Yanan Hou, Xiaofeng Guo, Huiying Qi, Ding Rong Ou, Peng Qiu, Tonghuan Zhang, Di Liu, Shuna Han, Baofeng Tu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399321601

                The microstructure and reactivity of Ni-GDC cermet under cyclic oxidation in CO2 conditions were investigated using temperature-programmed reduction (TPR), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). The XRD results revealed that NiO was formed during the re-oxidation process in CO2. SEM and TPR results demonstrated that nanostructured NiO aggregates were formed on the surface of the sample after being re-oxidized at 400 &#176;C for 1200 min, resulting in an &#945; peak with high reduction activity and a conversion of only 16% from Ni to NiO. In contrast, the samples re-oxidized at 600 &#176;C for 600 min and 800 &#176;C for 240 min were completely oxidized, resulting in reconstructed and sintered NiO with larger particle size, and a &#946; peak with lower reactivity and a conversion of 100%. Redox cycling was further conducted on completely oxidized samples, which showed a decrease in &#946; peak temperature from the first to seventh cycle. The migration and redistribution of sintered NiO towards the exterior were confirmed by comparing SEM images after the first and fourth cycles, which favored an increase in the reactive area. Therefore, this study reveals that lower re-oxidation temperatures (&#8804;400 &#176;C) and an appropriate increase in redox cycles are beneficial for forming surficial nanostructures while hindering the formation of large sintered NiO particles.</description>
      <author>Yang Sun, Yanan Hou, Xiaofeng Guo, Huiying Qi, Ding Rong Ou, Peng Qiu, Tonghuan Zhang, Di Liu, Shuna Han, Baofeng Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Offshore wind energy potential in Shandong Sea of China revealed by ERA5 reanalysis data and remote sensing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142745</link>
      <description>Longxing Liu, Mengquan Wu, Yunfei Mao, Longxiao Zheng, Min Xue, Bing Lei, Feng Liang, Jiayan Liu, Bowen Liu, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399215205

                The scale of offshore wind energy has been rapidly growing worldwide in recent years. Accurate assessment of the offshore wind energy potential and emission reduction benefits is essential to realize the ambitious targets for future installations. In this study, the Shandong Sea of China was selected as a case study, and the long-term offshore wind energy potential was assessed using ERA5 reanalysis data for the last 30 years, including the spatio-temporal variation and the technical potential of wind resources. An innovative approach to evaluate the technical potential of installed offshore wind farms based on deep learning, satellite images and ERA5 reanalysis data was proposed and applied to the Shandong Sea. The results show that (1) the highest offshore wind energy potential is observed in the northeast sea of Weihai; (2) the inter-annual variation of wind resources is relatively modest, with a pronounced monthly variability. The richest wind resources are found in the spring; (3) the electricity generation of wind resources is 12.66&#8764;30.53 GWh/year, equivalent to a reduction of 9.35&#8764;22.55 Kt of CO2 emissions; (4) as of 2023, there were 12 OWFs including 633 offshore wind turbines in Shandong Sea, generating 14,218 GWh/year of clean electricity and reducing 10,505 Kt/year of CO2 emissions. The method proposed in this study is applicable to both small- and large-scale areas and allows for an accurate assessment of the electricity generation from installed offshore wind farms.</description>
      <author>Longxing Liu, Mengquan Wu, Yunfei Mao, Longxiao Zheng, Min Xue, Bing Lei, Feng Liang, Jiayan Liu, Bowen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering Geometric Reconstruction of Bismuth with Accelerated Dynamics for CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407665</link>
      <description>Xiaowen Wang, Yangyang Zhang, Wei Shao, Yifan Li, Feng Yan, Zhifeng Dai, Yanxu Chen, Xianwei Meng, Jianghai Xia, Genqiang Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399361569

                Bismuth&#8208;based materials have emerged as promising catalysts in the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to formate. However, the reasons for the reconstruction of Bi&#8208;based precursors to form bismuth nanosheets are still puzzling, especially the formation of defective bismuth sites. Herein, we prepare bismuth nanosheets with vacancy&#8208;rich defects (V&#8208;Bi NS) by rapidly reconstructing Bi19Cl3S27 under negative potential. Theoretical analysis reveals that the introduction of chlorine induces the generation of intrinsic electric field in the precursor, thereby increasing the electron transfer rate and further promoting the metallization of trivalent bismuth. Meanwhile, in situ Raman and ex situ XRD tests verify that Bi19Cl3S27 has a faster reconstruction rate than Bi2S3. The formed V&#8208;Bi NS exhibits up to 96% HCOO&#8208; Faraday efficiency and 400 mA cm&#8208;2 HCOO&#8208; partial current densities, and its ECSA normalized formate current density and yield are 2.2 times higher than those of intact bismuth nanosheets (I&#8208;Bi NS). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that bismuth vacancies with electron&#8208;rich aggregation reduce the activation energy of CO2 to *CO2&#8208; radicals and stabilize the adsorption of the key intermediate *OCHO, thus facilitating the reaction kinetics of formate production.</description>
      <author>Xiaowen Wang, Yangyang Zhang, Wei Shao, Yifan Li, Feng Yan, Zhifeng Dai, Yanxu Chen, Xianwei Meng, Jianghai Xia, Genqiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Experimental Method to Simulate Reduction Behavior of Burden in Blast Furnace Shaft</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854358</link>
      <description>Wang Guang, Weiwei Xu, Qianyu Yi, Bin-bin Lyu, Qingguo Xue, Jingsong Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399344749

                In order to evaluate the effects of CO and H2 for the gas-solid reaction behavior of the ferrous burden and coke in blast furnace shaft, a near-steady-state simulation test method of the blast furnace shaft was designed. The reduction behavior of the ferrous burden, carbon solution loss reaction under different temperatures and atmospheres, and the effect of hydrogen enrichment on the CO gas utilization ratio were investigated. The results show that above 830&#176;C, the reduction degrees of different ferrous burden structures under H2 atmosphere are higher than that under CO atmosphere. Better reduction degradation behavior could be obtained under the hydrogen-rich atmosphere. The H2O generated under H2 atmosphere could promote the carbon solution loss reaction. The solution loss ratio reaching the maximum at 950&#176;C. Under hydrogen-rich atmosphere, CO gas utilization ratio increased with the increased of H2 concentration due to the effects of the products H2O and CO2.</description>
      <author>Wang Guang, Weiwei Xu, Qianyu Yi, Bin-bin Lyu, Qingguo Xue, Jingsong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Intraday Impacts of Wind Energy on Wholesale Electricity Prices and Carbon Emissions in Great Britain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4852343</link>
      <description>Huang Xiao, Xiaoyi Mu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399310636

                This paper studies the intra-day impacts of wind power on wholesale electricity prices and carbon emissions in Great Britain. Exploiting hourly variations across years from 2008 to 2019, we differentiate the longer-term impact of wind power, largely due to capacity increases, and the short-term impact driven by weather conditions. The results show that the expansion of wind energy significantly decreases wholesale electricity prices in most hours, although the effect is not uniform. The prices decrease more during peak hours than during off-peak hours, with no significant effect during the ramping-up and ramping-down hours. However, over the sample period, the negative effects of wind expansion and load reduction on wholesale electricity prices are more than offset by the increases in carbon and fuel prices. Wind expansion, load reduction, and increases in carbon prices all contributed to the significant reduction in CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Huang Xiao, Xiaoyi Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4852343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Single&#8208;Atom Sites with the Irving&#8208;Williams Series for the Simultaneous Co&#8208;photocatalytic CO2 Reduction and CH3CHO Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407975</link>
      <description>Jian Li, Mingliang Du, Zhongke Wu, X. W. Zhang, Wenjuan Xue, Hongliang Huang, Chongli Zhong, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399238736

                The bonding effects between 3d transition&#8208;metal single sites and supports originate from crystal field stabilization energy (CFSE). The 3d transition&#8208;metal atoms of the spontaneous geometrical distortions, that is the Jahn&#8208;Teller effect, can alter CFSE, thereby leading to the Irving&#8208;Williams series. However, engineering single&#8208;atom sites (SASs) using the Irving&#8208;Williams series as an ideal guideline has not been reported to date. Herein, alkynyl&#8208;linked covalent phenanthroline frameworks (CPFs) with phenanthroline units are developed to anchor the desired 3d single metal ions from d5 to d10 (Mn2+, Fe3+, Co2+, Ni2+, Cu2+, and Zn2+). The Irving&#8208;Williams series was employed to accurately predict the bonding effects between 3d transition&#8208;metal atoms and phenanthroline units. To verify this, theoretical calculations and experimental results reveal that Cu&#8208;SASs/CPFs exhibits higher stability and faster charge&#8208;transfer efficiency, far surpassing other metal&#8208;SASs/CPFs. As expected, Cu&#8208;SASs/CPFs demonstrates a high photoreduction of CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO activity (~30.3 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8208;1&#183;h&#8208;1) and an exceptional photooxidation of CH3CHO&#8208;to&#8208;CH3COOH activity (~24.7 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8208;1&#183;h&#8208;1). Interestingly, the generated *O2&#8208; is derived from the process of CO2 reduction, thereby triggering a CH3CHO oxidation reaction. This work provides a novel design concept for designing SASs by the Irving&#8208;Williams to regulate the catalytic performances.</description>
      <author>Jian Li, Mingliang Du, Zhongke Wu, X. W. Zhang, Wenjuan Xue, Hongliang Huang, Chongli Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic and Environmental Benefit Analysis between Crumb Rubber Concrete and Ordinary Portland Cement Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114758</link>
      <description>Xiong Guang-jing, Safat Al&#8208;Deen, Xiao Guan, Qing Qin, Chenghua Zhang, Sustainability. 16(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399302741

                Although manifold empirical studies have identified the mechanical properties of crumb rubber concrete (CRC), a comparative analysis of economic and environmental benefits between CRC and ordinary Portland cement concrete (OPCC) is not explored. In this paper, a quantitative meta-analysis between CRC and OPCC is conducted to explore optimized design strength, and a comparative analysis of the economic and environmental benefits of the two materials is undertaken. Considering cost price as the economic index and CO2 emissions per cubic meter of concrete as the environmental index in the materialization stage, CRC and OPCC were compared with different mix designs to achieve grades of similar strengths. Upon replacing less than 20% of natural fine aggregates in concrete with crumb rubber, while retaining the cement content, an increase of 6% in the cost price was achieved for CRC with 30&#8211;40 MPa strength grade. Apart from the aspect of mining and transportation of natural aggregates, the reduction of CO2 emissions by means of CRC adoption was verified in the treatment process of waste tire incineration. The results show that CO2 emissions from CRC decreased by 15&#8211;17% when compared with OPCC for 30~40 MPa grade concrete. The research conclusion can serve as a theoretical basis for the engineering application of CRC with the same strength, and make certain contributions to the industrial application of crumb rubber aggregates and the sustainable treatment of waste tires.</description>
      <author>Xiong Guang-jing, Safat Al&#8208;Deen, Xiao Guan, Qing Qin, Chenghua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Promotion and Ni+Co Loading Effects of &#947;-Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported Ni&#8211;Co Catalysts for the Flue Gas Reforming of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01317</link>
      <description>Satyam Gupta, Saumya Tiwari, Vaibhav K. Arghode, Goutam Deo, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399299595

                In this study, we synthesize a series of active Ni3Co&#8211;Al2O3 catalysts, calcined at 850 &#176;C for 5 h, to examine the effects of (i) substituting Ni with Co on the catalytic performance of the Ni&#8211;Al2O3 catalyst and (ii) the total metal amount on the catalytic activity of Ni3Co&#8211;Al for the flue gas reforming of methane (FGRM) reaction at 600 &#176;C. We maintain high calcination temperatures to ensure strong alloy&#8211;support interactions. We also synthesize a Co&#8211;Al2O3 catalyst and use the data of a previously synthesized Ni&#8211;Al2O3 catalyst to analyze the effect of cobalt promotion. In the Ni3Co&#8211;Al catalysts, we maintain the Ni/Co ratio to be 3 and increase the Ni+Co amount from 5 to 25 wt % to examine the effect of total metal loading. The H2-reduction profiles reveal that the temperature where the consumption of H2 was maximum, Tmax temperature, is a function of the total metal loading. Comparison of the catalytic activities appears to suggest that in situ reduction of the catalyst at Tmax was better than the reduction at higher temperatures, since a larger number of surface active sites are available. The CH4 and CO2 conversions and H2 and CO yields increase when nickel is substituted with cobalt due to Ni&#8211;Co nanoalloy formation. However, the dispersion of the nanoalloy varies with the metal loading, and the optimum dispersion is when Ni+Co = 10 wt %. This 10Ni3Co&#8211;Al catalyst exhibits optimum CH4 (89%) and CO2 (30%) conversions and H2 (79%) and CO (46%) yields for the FGRM reaction at 600 &#176;C for a GHSV of 120,000 mL g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1. The conversions, yields, and particle size of the alloy of this 10Ni3Co&#8211;Al catalyst do not change significantly, and an insignificant amount of carbon is formed during 24 h of operation. Thus, after using a promoter, it is necessary to optimize the loading of the active phase to obtain the best catalyst for FGRM.</description>
      <author>Satyam Gupta, Saumya Tiwari, Vaibhav K. Arghode, Goutam Deo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating the Energy Demand and Carbon Emission Reduction Potential of Singapore&#8217;s Future Road Transport Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114754</link>
      <description>Shiddalingeshwar Channabasappa Devihosur, Anurag Chidire, Tobias Massier, Thomas Hamacher, Sustainability. 16(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399290302

                About 20% of the world&#8217;s CO2 emissions originate from transport. Many countries are committed to decarbonizing their transport sector. Singapore pledged to electrify a whole host of its land transportation fleet, which includes private cars, public buses, ride-hail vehicles, and motorcycles. This paper proposes a simple empirical framework to estimate the future energy demand after 100% electrification has been realized for nine selected road transport vehicle sub-classes and to calculate the carbon emission reduction potential based on various scenarios. The present energy demand for each vehicle sub-class is first calculated based on parameters like petrol and diesel consumption, heat value and density of petrol and diesel, population of vehicle type, and average mileage per vehicle sub-class. Several scenarios are presented, and an analysis is carried out to derive a range of emission factors which are used to estimate the carbon emission reduction potential. Relative to the present day, the future energy demand estimates reveal an overall reduction of 73.60%. Full electrification and a &#8220;clean&#8221; power generation mix could lead to an emission reduction as high as 93.64% across all vehicles sub-classes, with private cars having the highest reduction potential.</description>
      <author>Shiddalingeshwar Channabasappa Devihosur, Anurag Chidire, Tobias Massier, Thomas Hamacher</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Enhanced Electrochemical Co2 Conversion: The Role of 3d Porous Biocl with Defects and Ctab-Mediated Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4852638</link>
      <description>Natarajan Thiyagarajan, Sankar Arumugam, Yi&#8208;Fang Tsai, Steve S.&#8208;F. Yu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399311475

                A 3D flower-like structure composed of porous bismuth oxychloride (p-BiOCl) nanosheets was synthesized through a hydrothermal process utilizing Bi(NO3)2, cetyltrimethylammonium bromide (CTAB) and LiCl. Powder X-ray diffraction (PXRD) studies confirmed the successful formation of the p-BiOCl. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and transmission electron microscopy (TEM) were exploited to identify the nanosheet structure. The catalyst appeared as reduced Bi0 nanosheets at an applied cathodic potential of - 0.92 V (vs. RHE (reversible hydrogen electrode)). The maintenance of Bi nanosheet structures, controlled by the cationic surfactant of CTAB, resulted in enhanced electrochemical activity with a favorable Tafel slope and lower charge resistance. Defects of under-coordinated Bi sites and oxygen vacancy with interconnected 3D structures possess abundant active sites that further assist the activity. In 1.0 and 2.0 M KHCO3 electrolytes, the catalyst achieved a maximum current density of - 80 and 100 mA/cm2, respectively, at - 0.92 V (vs. RHE) with Faradaic efficiency &gt; 99% for converting CO2 to formate in H-cell electrolyzers. The substantial H/D kinetic isotope effect revealed from H2O versus D2O electrolytes, and the feature of bicarbonate concentration-dependent performance provided the mechanistic insights that bicarbonate intermediates are in equilibrium with CO2, activated by water, in the aqueous environment, together with the effects of electrode surface modulated by CTAB, are essential for the efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction to formate.</description>
      <author>Natarajan Thiyagarajan, Sankar Arumugam, Yi&#8208;Fang Tsai, Steve S.&#8208;F. Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4852638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Single&#8208;Atom Sites with the Irving&#8208;Williams Series for the Simultaneous Co&#8208;photocatalytic CO2 Reduction and CH3CHO Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407975</link>
      <description>Jian Li, Mingliang Du, Zhongke Wu, X. W. Zhang, Wenjuan Xue, Hongliang Huang, Chongli Zhong, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399238808

                The bonding effects between 3d transition&#8208;metal single sites and supports originate from crystal field stabilization energy (CFSE). The 3d transition&#8208;metal atoms of the spontaneous geometrical distortions, that is the Jahn&#8208;Teller effect, can alter CFSE, thereby leading to the Irving&#8208;Williams series. However, engineering single&#8208;atom sites (SASs) using the Irving&#8208;Williams series as an ideal guideline has not been reported to date. Herein, alkynyl&#8208;linked covalent phenanthroline frameworks (CPFs) with phenanthroline units are developed to anchor the desired 3d single metal ions from d5 to d10 (Mn2+, Fe3+, Co2+, Ni2+, Cu2+, and Zn2+). The Irving&#8208;Williams series was employed to accurately predict the bonding effects between 3d transition&#8208;metal atoms and phenanthroline units. To verify this, theoretical calculations and experimental results reveal that Cu&#8208;SASs/CPFs exhibits higher stability and faster charge&#8208;transfer efficiency, far surpassing other metal&#8208;SASs/CPFs. As expected, Cu&#8208;SASs/CPFs demonstrates a high photoreduction of CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO activity (~30.3 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8208;1&#183;h&#8208;1) and an exceptional photooxidation of CH3CHO&#8208;to&#8208;CH3COOH activity (~24.7 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8208;1&#183;h&#8208;1). Interestingly, the generated *O2&#8208; is derived from the process of CO2 reduction, thereby triggering a CH3CHO oxidation reaction. This work provides a novel design concept for designing SASs by the Irving&#8208;Williams to regulate the catalytic performances.</description>
      <author>Jian Li, Mingliang Du, Zhongke Wu, X. W. Zhang, Wenjuan Xue, Hongliang Huang, Chongli Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic sanctions, energy consumption, and CO2 emissions in Iran: a system dynamics model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/01442872.2024.2358842</link>
      <description>Hamid Balali, Mohammad Reza Farzanegan, Omid Zamani, Mostafa Baniasadi, Policy studies. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399297736

                Economic sanctions have the potential to affect environmental factors through various channels, including income reduction and constraints on accessing finance and environmentally friendly technologies. This study aims to simulate the energy and environmental consequences resulting from international sanctions in Iran. To achieve this, we develop a System Dynamics model integrating a spectrum of variables spanning economic, social, and environmental dimensions, for the period from 2008 to 2028. Our simulation outcomes indicate that by 2028, sanctions are anticipated to precipitate a notable upsurge in CO2 emissions, ranging from 12.5% to 30% compared to the baseline scenario. The magnitude of this escalation hinges on a variety of factors, including energy intensity and scenarios related to economic growth. According to our findings, prolonging international sanctions could be a major barrier to improving energy intensity and lowering CO2 emissions. Given the potential environmental consequences of sanctions, international communities, particularly sanctioning countries, should consider the environmental impacts of sanctions in their policy-making decisions in order to reduce emissions damage.</description>
      <author>Hamid Balali, Mohammad Reza Farzanegan, Omid Zamani, Mostafa Baniasadi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/01442872.2024.2358842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Sustainable Mobility: Assessing the Benefits and Implications of Internal Combustion Engine Vehicle Bans and Battery Electric Vehicle Uptake in Qatar</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15060677</link>
      <description>Abdulla Alishaq, Daniel Mehlig, Atmosphere. 15(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399285817

                The global shift towards sustainable transportation, primarily through vehicle electrification, is critical in addressing climate change. Qatar presents a knowledge gap with specific challenges and opportunities in this transition. This study calculates the potential reduction in CO2-eq, NOx, and PM2.5 emissions resulting from substituting Internal Combustion Engine Vehicles (ICEVs) with Battery Electric Vehicles (BEVs) in Qatar, considering ICEV ban scenarios in 2030, 2035, and 2040, alongside five policy pathways. A Vehicle Stock Model (VSM) simulates Qatar&#8217;s fleet evolution from 2022 to 2050, focusing on the vehicle&#8217;s operational phase. An ICEV ban in 2030 would result in a 34% cumulative emission reduction in road transport between 2022 and 2050 compared with the Business-as-Usual (BAU) scenario. For NOx and PM2.5, cumulative emissions for the 2030 ICEV ban pathways are approximately 20% and 9% lower, respectively, compared with BAU. This study underscores the necessity of localising environmental strategies to meet Qatar&#8217;s specific needs and climate commitments, where results indicate significant emission reductions are possible through BEVs.</description>
      <author>Abdulla Alishaq, Daniel Mehlig</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15060677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Toll Collection (Etc) Deployment on Highways: Global Patterns, Estimated Gains from the Case of Vietnam, and Policy Discussion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853522</link>
      <description>Vu Ming M. Khuong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399337342

                This paper examines the transformative shift towards Electronic Toll Collection (ETC) systems in highway management, focusing on their patterns and realized gains. By analyzing the global landscape of ETC deployment and delving deeply into the case of Vietnam, it provides practical policy insights for developing countries in this strategically urgent transition.A distinctive feature of this paper is its detailed examination of Vietnam's transition from manual toll collection (MTC) to ETC, highlighting substantial gains in emissions reduction, efficiency improvement, and savings in time and costs. In 2023, the first year of Vietnam's full ETC implementation, the estimated gains included a reduction in the consumption of 60,816 tons of gasoline and diesel, 192 tons of CO2-equivalent emissions, and 37.3 million hours in manpower time, with the total monetary equivalent value in cost savings amounting to $442 million. For the next seven years, 2024-2030, as Vietnam continues to rapidly expand highway networks, these respective figures are projected to amount to 597,862 tons of gasoline and diesel, 1,886,106 tons of CO2-equivalent emissions, 917.1 million hours, and $4.352 billion.Through policy discussion, the paper emphasizes the importance of ETC in boosting productivity and sustainable development, reducing pollution, and fostering advancement towards a smart economy and society. It underscores the critical role of government leadership and private sector engagement in successful ETC deployment.Additionally, the estimation results highlight the critical urgency and enormous benefits of making major investments and leveraging digital transformation in toll facilities such as metros, tunnels, and skyways to reduce heavy traffic congestion in megacities and inter-city roads, where millions of people and vehicles could save hours of waiting time in travel.</description>
      <author>Vu Ming M. Khuong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D nanomaterials for removal of gas molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-12-820643-0.00020-1</link>
      <description>A. B. Samui, S. Shamshath Begum, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399243890

                The physicochemical properties of any material undergo drastic change during reduction of size of particles, particularly at the nanometer region. A large number of possibilities open up in several fields of research and technology. The special properties of nanomaterials made it suitable for different applications. One of the significant challenges faced by the world is the environmental pollution due to released gases from industries, household, and other sources in the form of gas, liquid, and the dispersed materials. Nanomaterials, having high surface area, adjustable properties, particularly those having porosity, are known to adsorb a variety of gaseous substances. Discovery of single-layer graphene at the University of Manchester in 2004 has triggered intense interests in 2D materials in broad fields of science such as chemistry, physics, and material science. Unique properties of 2D materials such as infinitesimal thickness, molecular sieving ability along with good thermal and chemical stability make them ideal building blocks for developing the new generation of high-performance gas and liquid separation membranes. Beyond graphene and its derivatives, abundant 2D nanomaterials such as metal-organic frameworks, transitional metal dichalcogenides, covalent organic frameworks, hexagonal boron nitride (h-BN), and MXenes have been discovered during recent past. The chapter will discuss various aspects of the removal of gas including the underlying mechanisms. As an example, h-BN adsorbs CO2 very loosely. Interestingly, DFT calculation results indicate that the injection of extra electron into the h-BN nanoadsorbent dramatically increases the adsorption of CO2 via a charge-induced chemisorption interaction. When the extra charge is released, there is a spontaneous release of CO2.</description>
      <author>A. B. Samui, S. Shamshath Begum</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-12-820643-0.00020-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-MOF-74-Derived CuO-400 Material for CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14060361</link>
      <description>Hua Liu, Yali Wang, Lijun Chen, Menghan Li, Jiaxing Lu, Huan Wang, Catalysts. 14(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399209511

                This study proposes a straightforward strategy utilizing metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) to obtain efficient electrocatalysts for synthesizing C2 products (C2H4 and C2H5OH) via a CO2 reduction reaction. Cu-MOF-74 was chosen as the precursor, while copper oxide nanoparticles were obtained through a calcination method. During the calcination process, by controlling the calcination conditions, the porous structure of the MOF framework was successfully retained, leading to CuO-400 with a high catalytic activity and C2 production efficiency. Compared to CuO-n formed by the calcination of Cu(NO3)2, CuO-400 derived from MOFs exhibits a 1.6 times higher C2 activity as an electrocatalytic material at &#8722;1.15 V vs. RHE.</description>
      <author>Hua Liu, Yali Wang, Lijun Chen, Menghan Li, Jiaxing Lu, Huan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14060361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic performance and control analysis of supercritical CO2 brayton cycle for solid oxide fuel cell waste heat recovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.123556</link>
      <description>Jiancong Chen, Song Tan, E Jiaqiang, Gaoliang Liao, Feng Zhang, Applied thermal engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399220591

                Due to the high-temperature operation of solid oxide fuel cell, recovering its exhaust waste heat is worthwhile. The supercritical CO2 cycle features low compression power consumption and high thermal efficiency, making it a promising power cycle. Therefore, this paper adopts the supercritical CO2 recompression cycle as the bottom cycle, combined with solid oxide fuel cell to form a joint system, further improving energy utilization. Given the long temperature response time of the solid oxide fuel cell and the variability of its exhaust waste heat with load changes, this paper innovatively proposes establishing an integrated dynamic model of the joint system, instead of directly providing heat source flow and temperature changes as in traditional research, to more accurately study the dynamic response of the cycle during solid oxide fuel cell startup and load variations. Based on this, a control strategy utilizing inventory control is proposed, and the feasibility of the control effect is verified. The research results indicate that the uncontrolled cycle may lead to safety issues with a significant increase in turbine inlet temperature when solid oxide fuel cell load increases. Under the control strategy, the turbine inlet temperature and main compressor inlet temperature are rapidly stabilized at the target values. The controlled cycle achieves higher efficiency compared to the uncontrolled cycle, particularly prominent during solid oxide fuel cell load reduction, with an efficiency increase of approximately 5.23%.</description>
      <author>Jiancong Chen, Song Tan, E Jiaqiang, Gaoliang Liao, Feng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.123556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Few-Layer-Graphene Based Smart Concrete: A New Paradigm in Construction Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1972-3_45</link>
      <description>Salvatore Polverino, Antonio Esa&#250; Del R&#237;o Castillo, Francesco Bonaccorso, Lecture notes in civil engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399210765

                In recent years, the construction industry has been increasingly focused on finding solutions to improve infrastructure and building performance while fulfilling environmental requirements. One area of focus is the production of cementitious composites, which currently produce high CO2 emissions. However, there are adaptable strategies for decarbonising the cement sector, including nanomaterials like graphene and graphene-related materials (GRM). GRM enhances the lifespan and adds innovative properties to cementitious composites. This study pioneers the application of few-layer graphene (FLG) in cementitious composites, resulting in a notable 94% reduction in electrical resistance and a 55% increase in thermal conductivity. This novel approach can significantly elevate the multifunctionality and performance attributes of cementitious materials, furthering sustainable construction practices.</description>
      <author>Salvatore Polverino, Antonio Esa&#250; Del R&#237;o Castillo, Francesco Bonaccorso</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1972-3_45</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymer-Assisted WAG Injection Improves CO2 Flow Properties in Porous Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/0624-0083-jpt</link>
      <description>Chris Carpenter, Journal of petroleum technology. 76(06)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399269512

                _ This article, written by JPT Technology Editor Chris Carpenter, contains highlights of paper SPE 215024, &#8220;Polymer-Assisted Water-Alternating-Gas for Improving CO2 Flow Properties in Porous Media,&#8221; by Mohsen M. Yegane, SPE, Delft University of Technology and the Dutch Polymer Institute; Thijs van Wieren, SPE, Delft University of Technology; and Ali Fadili, Shell, et al. The paper has not been peer reviewed. _ CO2 flow in porous media is vital for both enhanced oil recovery and underground carbon storage. For improving CO2 mobility control and improved reservoir sweep efficiency, water-alternating-gas (WAG) injection often has been applied. The effectiveness of WAG diminishes, however, because of the presence of microscale reservoir heterogeneity that results in an early breakthrough of gas. In the complete paper, the authors propose polymer-assisted WAG (PA-WAG) as an alternative method to reduce gas mobility and the mobility of the aqueous phase, consequently improving the performance of WAG. In this method, high-molecular-weight water-soluble polymers are added to the water slug. Introduction Recently, PA-WAG has received attention as a method to mitigate early gas breakthrough and gravity segregation during WAG injection. However, the flow mechanisms in PA-WAG injection in porous media remain poorly understood. In particular, no experimental study exists to the authors&#8217; knowledge that demonstrates in-situ visualization and discusses how PA-WAG can improve the gravity override and early gas breakthrough of WAG. The objective of this study is to demonstrate experimentally the feasibility of PA-WAG by conducting a series of X-ray computed tomography (CT) -aided coreflood experiments. To this end, coreflood experiments in Bentheimer cores using different injection schemes (CO2 and polymer injection, WAG injection, and PA-WAG injection) were conducted. The aim of CT scanning during the coreflood experiments was to map the phase saturations at different times of injection. Using dual-energy CT scanning, a reduction in gravity override could be visualized, and the CO2 breakthrough was delayed when PA-WAG was used. Experiments Table 1 of the complete paper presents the various chemical components that were used in this study. The coreflood experiments were performed using Bentheimer sandstone cores. Bentheimer cores have high permeabilities and a homogeneous mineralogy. The porosity of the core samples was measured using CT scanning. To introduce the aqueous phases into the core, a dual-cylinder pump was used. The core, core holder, and heating sleeve were placed in a fixed horizontal position on the CT bench because vertical scanning led to undesirable artifacts and yielded no meaningful insights. Fraction-collector sampling was used to collect effluents at the outlet at various time intervals. CO2 was injected into the system by a mass-flow controller sourced from a dedicated CO2 supply. The pump indirectly introduced both the oleic phase during primary drainage stages and the polymer solution used for secondary or tertiary recovery by means of a transfer vessel. The pressure drop across various sections of the core was measured using four pressure transducers. Pressure and temperature measurements were recorded at 10-second intervals. Four coreflood experiments were conducted in this study. As mentioned, all experiments were performed at pressures and temperatures of 20&#177;1 bar and 40&#177;1&#176;C.</description>
      <author>Chris Carpenter</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/0624-0083-jpt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Green Transition and the Italian Labour Market</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4849356</link>
      <description>Gaetano Basso, Fabrizio Colonna, Domenico Depalo, Graziella Mendicino, Social Science Research Network. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399310513

                The paper discusses the role of labour in the transition to a net zero economy and provides an analysis for Italy over the period 2011-2021. First, we observe that the emissions generated from production activities declined over this period. We estimate that the contribution of employment reallocation across sectors was modest, while that of sectoral efficiency &#8211; particularly the shift in the energy mix towards cleaner sources &#8211; was decisive. Second, we show that the share of employment in the environmental goods and services sector was small in 2020 and has remained broadly stable since 2014. Our results suggest that, so far, labour has not played a prominent role in the green transition. However, this trend could change in the near future, as CO2 emission reduction targets take on an increasingly key role in production activities.</description>
      <author>Gaetano Basso, Fabrizio Colonna, Domenico Depalo, Graziella Mendicino</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4849356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycling various slag into cement clinker</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-21536-0.00025-3</link>
      <description>Kai Wu, Kai Yang, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399225069

                Slag is a significant by-product generated in large quantities during metallurgical processes involved in the production of ferrous and nonferrous metals. Due to the chemical compositions and processing feature, various slags can be recycled into cement clinker in large quantities. This chapter reviews several types of slag and their contribution to the sustainable development of cement industry. The processing of cement clinker made with various slag is discussed, and the factors influencing clinker feature are presented. The effect of slag on the clinker mineralogical compositions, hydration feature, and mechanical properties is thereafter assessed. Since there are various elements presented in the slag, which could exert a detrimental effect on the cement properties, the stabilization mechanism and efficiency is discussed. With the industrialization and increased requirement for CO2 reduction, recycling various slags into cement clinker would be the route one must take for both metallurgical and cement field.</description>
      <author>Kai Wu, Kai Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-21536-0.00025-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generic Buffers: A Flexibility Modeling Approach for Predictive Control of an Industrial Steam Network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4852110</link>
      <description>Rom&#225;n Cant&#250; Rodr&#237;guez, Brida V. Mbuwir, Carlo Manna, Geert Deconinck, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399310507

                Steam networks offer a practical solution to increase flexibility in energy-intensive industries, thanks to their potential for electrification and integration of various energy sources. However, effectively using this flexibility requires models that accurately represent system constraints and dynamics for control. While first-principle models provide accuracy, their complexity can hinder practical control applications. This paper proposes a data-driven model using generic buffers to model the intrinsic flexibility and dynamics of a steam network in order to efficiently leverage the available flexibility through model predictive control. Our simulations show significant weekly reductions in CO2 emissions (between 3120 and 7990 tCO2) with an emissions-oriented controller, and in costs (between 0.448 and 1.419 million EUR) with a cost-oriented controller, compared to a pressure-regulating PI controller.</description>
      <author>Rom&#225;n Cant&#250; Rodr&#237;guez, Brida V. Mbuwir, Carlo Manna, Geert Deconinck</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4852110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shedding Light on Solar Olefin Synthesis: Advances and Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01608</link>
      <description>Zhe Lu, Lu Wang, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399275451

                Light olefins, crucial feedstocks in the chemical industry, are projected to reach a market size of USD 475.8 million by 2027. Traditional methods for producing light olefins, such as cracking and the Fischer&#8211;Tropsch process, are energy-intensive and heavily reliant on fossil fuels. These production methods contribute significantly to environmental issues, emitting approximately 400 million tons of CO2 annually. Integrating solar energy into the olefin synthesis process presents a promising avenue for enhancing sustainability and efficiency. Recent research reveals the potential of utilizing solar energy to activate light-alkanes and COx, enabling solar olefin production via dehydrogenation, hydrogenation, and reduction reactions. This review overviews recent advancements and evaluates the prospects of solar energy utilization in olefin synthesis, emphasizing innovative approaches and their potential implications.</description>
      <author>Zhe Lu, Lu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of quality and quantity of crop residues on organic carbon dynamics and microbial activity in soil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25252/se/2024/243394</link>
      <description>Tahseen Afzal, Abdul Wakeel, Sardar Alam Cheema, Javed Iqbal, Muhammad Sanaullah, Soil &amp; environment. 43(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399264841

                An incubation study investigated the decomposition patterns, microbial activities, soil aggregates distribution, and soil organic carbon (SOC) contents, using four crop residues; wheat (Triticum aestivum L.), rice (Oryza sativa L.), cotton (Gossypium hirsutum L.), and maize (Zea mays L.), at low and high rates (10 and 20 g kg&#8211;1). An average increase of about 35% in cumulative C-CO2 emissions and 26% in soil microbial biomass carbon (MBC) was observed at high residue rates as compared to low rates. A positive and strong correlation (0.96) was found between C-CO2 emissions and MBC, and the effect of residue quality on decomposition was found to be less at high rates. The relative reduction in C-CO2 emissions by adding rice residues may be due to their high silica content. Differences in extracellular enzyme activities (EEA) with different residues indicated the effect of residue quality on microbial activities. Cotton residues increased &#946;-glucosidase and chitinase activities by 41 and 38%, respectively, at high rates than at low rates. High maize residues also markedly increased chitinase activity by 41%, implying higher N cycling and fungal prevalence. Acid phosphatase activity was found to increase by about 25 to 32% with high rice and wheat residues, respectively. Higher EEA at high residues input likely reflected the microbial nutritional limitations. Crop residues raised SOC content from 0.7 under control to 1.0% at low residues input but not at high input. Increased macro-aggregates fraction at high residues input may be attributed to higher microbial activities. In summary, high residues input can minimize residue biochemical quality&#8217;s effect on decomposition, with no further increase in SOC content. While a positive effect on the soil MBC, but not on the SOC content, was observed at high residue input, suggesting moderation in the additions of organic amendments is key for SOC buildup. Crop residues, added at 10 g kg&#8211;1, may help maintain a positive SOC balance in the arid agroecosystems by moderating higher microbial activities and soil respiration.</description>
      <author>Tahseen Afzal, Abdul Wakeel, Sardar Alam Cheema, Javed Iqbal, Muhammad Sanaullah</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25252/se/2024/243394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combined Effect of Sulfur and Lithium on Intensification of Portland Cement Clinker Burning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1972-3_24</link>
      <description>Theodor Stan&#283;k, Eva Barton&#237;&#269;kov&#225;, Ingrid Khongov&#225;, Ane&#382;ka Zezulov&#225;, Jakub Palov&#269;&#237;k, Alexandra Rybov&#225;, Ji&#345;&#237; M&#225;silko, Martin Boh&#225;&#269;, Lecture notes in civil engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399210741

                Lithium significantly reduces the temperature of clinker melt formation and its viscosity, and sulfur promotes the formation of monoclinic alite modification M1, which guarantees higher mechanical strength of cement compared to cement with M3 modification. By a suitable combination of both dopants, it is possible to reduce the burning temperature of clinker by 100 &#8211; 150 &#8451; and, as it was found, to increase the mechanical strength of the cement prepared from this clinker. The initial strengths of this cement show an increase of up to 100% compared to the conventional cement CEM I. Lowering the burning temperature of the clinker would lead to a reduction in the energy demand of the production of the main intermediate product for cement production. At the same time, it is also one of the possibilities to reduce CO2 emissions in cement production, which is one of the current priority goals. X-ray diffraction analysis, optical microscopy, electron microscopy and microanalysis were used for the research.</description>
      <author>Theodor Stan&#283;k, Eva Barton&#237;&#269;kov&#225;, Ingrid Khongov&#225;, Ane&#382;ka Zezulov&#225;, Jakub Palov&#269;&#237;k, Alexandra Rybov&#225;, Ji&#345;&#237; M&#225;silko, Martin Boh&#225;&#269;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1972-3_24</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESEARCH PATTERNS AND TRENDS OF CARBON EMISSION FROM INLAND WATERS AT A GLOBAL SCALE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30638/eemj.2024.065</link>
      <description>Yifei Zhao, Jie Yuan, Environmental Engineering and Management Journal. 23(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399350219

                This paper presents a bibliometric analysis of the publications on carbon emission from inland waters (CEW) in the past 10 years (2011)(2012)(2013)(2014)(2015)(2016)(2017)(2018)(2019)(2020).The study in this paper utilizes the Scopus database, which enables the retrieval of 6303 related documents.The findings of the study showed that the amount of CEW research has consistently increased over the years, and is expected to grow rapidly in the future.China and USA are the top publishing sources on CEW worldwide, with the Chinese Academy of Sciences being the top leading institution.The research in this field has focused on the CO2 source identification, the impact of environmental factors on CEW, the reduction of carbon emissions, as well as the energy usage performance and efficiency.This comprehensive study not only enhances the understanding of current CEW research among scholars and managers but also provides a historical reference for future research.</description>
      <author>Yifei Zhao, Jie Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30638/eemj.2024.065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First Emission Map of China's National Parks: Emissions from National Parks Have Significantly Different Patterns and Require Attention</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854205</link>
      <description>Shan Yang, Huan Xu, Zhicong Zhao, Fangyi Wang, Qibo Sun, Jiale Tang, Jia He, Zhong Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399345351

                National parks act as significant carbon reserves and sinks, yet their ability to offset carbon emissions is under threat, underscoring the need for stringent greenhouse gas emission control and reduction measures. Previous research has lacked detailed spatial inventories of greenhouse gas emissions from all national park sources at a national level, impeding the development of precise carbon management strategies. In this study, we conducted a uniform analysis of greenhouse gas emissions across all five national parks in China for the year 2020 at a national scale. It quantitatively assesses the spatial distribution and characteristics of emission sources, revealing that in 2020, China's national parks released a total of 6.79 million tonnes of greenhouse gas, predominantly CO2. The majority of emissions stemmed from residential and animal husbandry activities, with emission levels demonstrating spatial coherence&#8212;areas with high emissions were clustered together, and similarly for low-emission areas. Although the emissions per unit area in most national parks were significantly lower than the national average, emission hotspots in the Three-River-Source National Park were 1.78 times above the national average. The study emphasizes the importance of employing emission maps for devising effective greenhouse gas control and reduction strategies, aiming to enhance the carbon-neutral potential of national parks.</description>
      <author>Shan Yang, Huan Xu, Zhicong Zhao, Fangyi Wang, Qibo Sun, Jiale Tang, Jia He, Zhong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum in Frustrated Lewis Pair Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405207</link>
      <description>Felix Kr&#228;mer, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399294160

                Abstract: This review article describes the development of the use of aluminum compounds in the chemistry of frustrated Lewis pairs (FLPs) over the last 14 years. It also discusses the synthesis, reactivity and catalytic applications of intermolecular, intramolecular and so&#8208;called hidden FLPs with phosphorus, nitrogen and carbon Lewis bases. The intrinsically higher acidity of aluminum compounds compared to their boron analogs opens up different reaction pathways. The results are presented in a more or less chronological order. It is shown that Al FLPs react with a variety of polar and non&#8208;polar substrates and form both stable adducts and reversibly activate bonds. Consequently, some catalytic applications of the title compounds were presented such as dimerization of alkynes, hydrogenation of tert&#8209;butyl ethylene and imines, C&#8211;F bond activation, reduction of CO2, dehydrogenation of amine borane and transfer of ammonia. In addition, various Al FLPs were used as initiators in polymerization reactions.</description>
      <author>Felix Kr&#228;mer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405207</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physiological and growth responses of lettuce plants submitted of 2,4-D simulated drift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14295/cs.v15.4083</link>
      <description>Roberta Bianchin Rebesquini, Nat&#225;lia Teixeira Schwab, Camila Peligrinotti Tarouco, Ja&#237;ne Rubert, Paola Ana Buffon, Aline Sielo Holkem, Andr&#233; da Rosa Ulguim, Comunicata Scientiae. 15(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399297521

                Pesticide drift is due to the transport of the active ingredient to areas not targeted by spraying, causing negative effects on the sensitive crops&#8217; development. The aim of this study was to evaluate lettuce response to simulated 2,4-D drift. Experiments were conducted in the greenhouse, in a randomized complete block design with four replications. The treatments consisted of nine different doses of the 2,4-D herbicide, which are: 0; 1.56; 3.125; 6.20; 12.5; 25; 50; 75; and 100% from the recommended dose (670 g a.a. ha-1). The application occurred when the lettuce plants had four to six true leaves. The analyzed variables were visual injury (phytotoxicity), development parameter (phyllochron), growth (rosette diameter and dry mass of the aerial part), and photosynthetic parameters (gas exchange). The lettuce crop showed high sensitivity to the 2,4-D herbicide, with the lowest dose resulting in significant phytotoxic damage to plants, and from 12.5% of the recommended 2,4-D dose, visual injuries were greater than 90%. The plants&#180; development and growth were negatively affected by the increased drift doses, culminating in enhanced phyllochron and reduction in rosette diameter and dry mass of the aerial part. The gas exchange of the crop was affected from 6.20% of the recommended dose, causing a reduction in the CO2 assimilation rate, stomatal conductance, transpiration rate and rubisco carboxylation efficiency.</description>
      <author>Roberta Bianchin Rebesquini, Nat&#225;lia Teixeira Schwab, Camila Peligrinotti Tarouco, Ja&#237;ne Rubert, Paola Ana Buffon, Aline Sielo Holkem, Andr&#233; da Rosa Ulguim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14295/cs.v15.4083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum in Frustrated Lewis Pair Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405207</link>
      <description>Felix Kr&#228;mer, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399294126

                Abstract: This review article describes the development of the use of aluminum compounds in the chemistry of frustrated Lewis pairs (FLPs) over the last 14 years. It also discusses the synthesis, reactivity and catalytic applications of intermolecular, intramolecular and so&#8208;called hidden FLPs with phosphorus, nitrogen and carbon Lewis bases. The intrinsically higher acidity of aluminum compounds compared to their boron analogs opens up different reaction pathways. The results are presented in a more or less chronological order. It is shown that Al FLPs react with a variety of polar and non&#8208;polar substrates and form both stable adducts and reversibly activate bonds. Consequently, some catalytic applications of the title compounds were presented such as dimerization of alkynes, hydrogenation of tert&#8209;butyl ethylene and imines, C&#8211;F bond activation, reduction of CO2, dehydrogenation of amine borane and transfer of ammonia. In addition, various Al FLPs were used as initiators in polymerization reactions.</description>
      <author>Felix Kr&#228;mer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405207</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antimicrobial Assay of Metal Ions Using Yeast and Its Relevance to Food Preservation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsfoodscitech.4c00079</link>
      <description>Zhiguo Cao, Muhammad Shahidul Islam, Jared Sisler, Kam Chiu Tam, ACS food science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399320958

                The increasing occurrence of antimicrobial resistance in recent years has spurred research to produce new antimicrobial compounds. However, there is currently a lack of a rapid, simple, and quantitative assay to determine the antimicrobial characteristics of new antimicrobial compounds. In this study, we demonstrated that a simple water displacement apparatus can be used to determine the effects of various metal ions on the cell viability of a model organism Saccharomyces cerevisiae (S. cerevisiae) by monitoring the volume of CO2 (VCO2) released. Analysis on the effect of different metal ions on S. cerevisiae demonstrated a linear relationship between VCO2 and the reduction potentials and a linear&#8211;logarithmic relationship between VCO2 and the metal/ligand binding constant indicating this measurement's accuracy and quantitative nature. Due to its speed, simplicity, and accuracy, this water displacement method has the potential to be used as a pre-screening method to facilitate the rapid quantification and development of more effective antimicrobial agents for various applications including antimicrobial food preservation and packaging.</description>
      <author>Zhiguo Cao, Muhammad Shahidul Islam, Jared Sisler, Kam Chiu Tam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsfoodscitech.4c00079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current State of Research in Defined Area from Energy Efficiency Point of View</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-658-44193-7_3</link>
      <description>Jana Karras, Schriftenreihe des Instituts f&#252;r Klimaschutz, Energie und Mobilit&#228;t. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399309000

                This chapter examines the dynamics of energy poverty and efficiency in low-income households, particularly in the contexts of Germany and Sweden. It explores the intricacies of the landlord-tenant dilemma and the impact of energy efficiency modernisation on vulnerable social groups. The research addresses the absence of a uniform legal definition of low-income households in Germany, emphasizing the socio-cultural subsistence level and the relativity of poverty. The study highlights the critical role of energy efficiency in reducing energy poverty and contributing to CO2 reduction and climate change policies. The complex phenomenon of energy poverty is examined through various lenses, including the socio-economic, legal, and housing market perspectives. Significantly, the study provides insights into the energy poverty situation in Germany and Sweden. It reviews the performance of these countries in population-based and expenditure-based indicators of energy poverty, comparing them with the EU average. The research underscores the need for effective policies to address the challenges of energy poverty, particularly in rented housing, to achieve climate goals and EU obligations.</description>
      <author>Jana Karras</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-658-44193-7_3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Reactive Sites for Electrocatalytic Conversion of Nitrate to High Value-Added Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854058</link>
      <description>Yan Yu-feng, Pengfei Guo, Xin Xu, Zhongyan Zhang, Huan Lou, Fanfei Sun, Meiqin Shi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399342907

                CuZn catalysts with various structures were synthesized for electrocatalyzing NO3- and CO2. Among them, CuZn supported on nitrogen-doped carbon exhibited the capability for directly producing urea, while after treated at higher temperature it presents the highest yield of ammonia. XAFS analysis revealed in the optimized sample, Zn existed as the single atom and Cu contained Cu-O(N) and Cu-Cu coordination structures. The Cu-O(N) species promoted the C-N coupling, while the Cu-Cu component played a crucial role in the reduction of nitrate to ammonia. Cu&#948;+ (1&lt;&#948;&lt;2) in the catalyst contributed to the C-N coupling. In addition, in-situ XAFS data indicated that under the optimal potential of -0.89 V, the valence state of Cu&#948;+ decreased slightly but remained within the range of 1&lt;&#948;&lt;2. After 8-hour stability test, the catalyst maintained a stable coordination structure. This study reveals that the Cu coordination environment is a crucial parameter for selectively producing ammonia or urea.</description>
      <author>Yan Yu-feng, Pengfei Guo, Xin Xu, Zhongyan Zhang, Huan Lou, Fanfei Sun, Meiqin Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4854058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-High-Performance Fiber Reinforced Concrete with UAE Red Dune Sand - Some Initial Results</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1972-3_80</link>
      <description>Man T. Bui, Nader Jaber, Ramzi Jaber, Firozsha Patel, Mariam Jamal, Lecture notes in civil engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399210425

                Using local materials is important for reduction of cost and CO2 emission. Dune sand is prevalent in Middle East but has not been widely used in concrete products. In UAE, for construction purposes, quartz sand, which was not available locally, was imported from the neighbour and European countries at relatively high cost. In this paper, we present our early results of our trials using UAE local dune sand to replace quartz sand for UHPC reinforced fibre. Natural dune sand was used directly without any pre-treatment. The dune sand is charaterised as reddish round to subrounded fine sand with 99% particles passing sieve 0.5mm. The chemical analysis results show that the silica content of the dune sand is 67%. Our initial compressive and flexural test results have shown that dune sand is highly suitable for UHPC hence normal concrete. The compressive strength and flexural strength are sufficient, suitable more many applications, suggesting that it can replace quart sand in concrete.</description>
      <author>Man T. Bui, Nader Jaber, Ramzi Jaber, Firozsha Patel, Mariam Jamal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1972-3_80</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon performance analysis of upgraded wastewater treatment plants in key control areas of the Ziya River Basin in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121304</link>
      <description>Jiahao Liu, Zhongqian Wang, Tonggang Zhang, Rui Li, Weiguang He, Xianjing Kong, Yaolong Shi, Jinxin Xie, Journal of environmental management. 362(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399293826

                Wastewater treatment plants (WWTPs) are one of the largest sources of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, and they are also one of the largest energy consumption industries in urban systems. With the progression of upgrading and standard-rising, WWTPs both directly and indirectly increase carbon emissions from the increased investments in facilities and usages in electricity as well as chemical agents. Here, we collected operational data from 15 WWTPs in the key control areas of the Ziya River Basin in North China and accounted for the changes in carbon performance at different technical upgrade methods. Results showed that the average carbon emission performance increased by 0.487 kg CO2/m3 after the upgrade. Carbon emissions from electricity consumption, chemical usage, biochemical process and sludge treatment accounted for 42%, 17%, 24%, and 17% of the total improvement in carbon emission performance, respectively. Reducing energy consumption, regulating chemical use and sludge comprehensive utilization are the key to carbon emission reduction. It further proposes that the development of wastewater treatment discharge standards should fully consider the comprehensive utilization of water quality classification. Regions with favorable natural conditions should make full use of their advantages by adopting economically feasible, low-energy-consuming technologies such as constructed wetlands, which offer carbon sequestration and landscaping benefits. This study provides guidance on the selection of technological pathways for pollution reduction and carbon mitigation in the wastewater treatment industry and on achieving sustainable water resource utilization.</description>
      <author>Jiahao Liu, Zhongqian Wang, Tonggang Zhang, Rui Li, Weiguang He, Xianjing Kong, Yaolong Shi, Jinxin Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energetic, Exergetic, and Techno-Economic Analysis of A Bioenergy with Carbon Capture and Utilization Process via Integrated Torrefaction&#8211;CLC&#8211;Methanation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17112690</link>
      <description>Enrico Alberto Cutillo, Claudio Tregambi, Piero Bareschino, Erasmo Mancusi, Gaetano Continillo, Francesco Pepe, Energies. 17(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399300368

                Bioenergy with carbon capture and storage (BECCS) or utilization (BECCU) allows net zero or negative carbon emissions and can be a breakthrough technology for climate change mitigation. This work consists of an energetic, exergetic, and economic analysis of an integrated process based on chemical looping combustion of solar-torrefied agro-industrial residues, followed by methanation of the concentrated CO2 stream with green H2. Four agro-industrial residues and four Italian site locations are considered. Depending on the considered biomass, the integrated plant processes about 18&#8211;93 kg h&#8722;1 of raw biomass and produces 55&#8211;70 t y&#8722;1 of synthetic methane. Global exergetic efficiencies ranged within 45&#8211;60% and 67&#8211;77% when neglecting and considering, respectively, the valorization of torgas. Sugar beet pulp and grape marc required a non-negligible input exergy flow for the torrefaction, due to the high moisture content of the raw biomasses. However, for these biomasses, the water released during drying/torrefaction and CO2 methanation could be recycled to the electrolyzer to eliminate external water consumption, thus allowing for a more sustainable use of water resources. For olive stones and hemp hurd, this water recycling brings, instead, a reduction of approximately 65% in water needs. A round-trip electric efficiency of 28% was estimated assuming an electric conversion efficiency of 40%. According to the economic analysis, the total plant costs ranged within 3&#8211;5 M&#8364; depending on the biomass and site location considered. The levelized cost of methane (LCOM) ranged within 4.3&#8211;8.9 &#8364; kgCH4&#8722;1 but, if implementing strategies to avoid the use of a large temporary H2 storage vessel, can be decreased to 2.6&#8211;5.3 &#8364; kgCH4&#8722;1. Lower values are obtained when considering hemp hurd and grape marc as raw biomasses, and when locating the PV field in the south of Italy. Even in the best scenario, values of LCOM are out of the market if compared to current natural gas prices, but they might become competitive with the introduction of a carbon tax or through government incentives for the purchase of the PV field and/or electrolyzer.</description>
      <author>Enrico Alberto Cutillo, Claudio Tregambi, Piero Bareschino, Erasmo Mancusi, Gaetano Continillo, Francesco Pepe</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17112690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circular Economy Approach: Recycling Toner Waste in Cement-Based Construction Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114707</link>
      <description>R.J. Ring, Gisela Cordoba, Natalia Delbianco, Carla Priano, Viviana F&#225;tima Rahhal, Sustainability. 16(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399208932

                Based on a waste generated survey by companies in the area of the city of Bahia Blanca (Argentina), the possibility of incorporating part of them in a Portland cement matrix was examined. Among the waste is toner (TW), which is obtained from cartridges used in photocopiers, laser printers, and faxes. This paper aims to analyze the physical and mechanical properties of cement pastes and mortars using toner as a Portland cement replacement compared to a reference sample without toner. The mixes were made with 2.5, 5, 10, and 15 wt.% replacement of cement by toner, and it was measured the flow, normal consistency, setting time, calorimetry, and Frattini test in pastes and mechanical strengths in mortars employing standardized tests. Also, an analysis of the leachate in the curing water was carried out after 56 days to look for contaminating materials. The replacement of up to 5% cement with toner did not produce substantial alterations in the final setting time or mechanical properties. No heavy metals were found in the leachate, so TW can be immobilized in a cementitious matrix as it does not cause leaching above the established limits. Therefore, TW from a local industry can be used in construction materials and could contribute to a reduction of up to 14% of CO2 emissions with a cement replacement of 15% in cement-based materials.</description>
      <author>R.J. Ring, Gisela Cordoba, Natalia Delbianco, Carla Priano, Viviana F&#225;tima Rahhal</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature based bipolar plate forming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1757-899x/1307/1/012032</link>
      <description>D. Meelkop, Hans-Karl Janssen, C. Brecher, IOP conference series. Materials science and engineering. 1307(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399212068

                Abstract By the end of the 1990s, the global peak of energy supply from oil and gas deposits had already been reached. Since then, there has been a clear trend towards the development of new, more sustainable ways of supplying energy. To realize this reduction, a holistic and rapid restructuring of the energy supply towards CO2-free and renewable energy production, storage and processing across all areas of life is necessary. The development and implementation of a functioning hydrogen economy can be crucial with respect to the goal of climate neutrality. The scale-up and commercialization of technologies for the cost-effective production and use of hydrogen carry significant importance. Accordingly, innovative production technologies and process chains must be developed to be able to manufacture fuel cells reliably in high volumes and at optimized costs. In this context, BPPs in the PEM-FC are responsible for about 80 % of the total weight, just over 50 % of the system volume, and up to 40 % of the total cost. Current research approaches in the field of BPP forming focus mainly on the optimization of a pre-selected production technology. Thereby, the possibility of combining different forming technologies to represent a holistic process chain is mostly disregarded. This research gap is to be closed by the developments within the scope of this work. The bipolar plate is not to be regarded as a coherent component, but as a composition of different geometric features.</description>
      <author>D. Meelkop, Hans-Karl Janssen, C. Brecher</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1757-899x/1307/1/012032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porphyrin Aggregation under Homogeneous Conditions Inhibits Electrocatalysis: A Case Study on CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c00121</link>
      <description>Kaitlin Branch, Erin R. Johnson, Eva M. Nichols, ACS central science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399299373

                Metalloporphyrins are widely used as homogeneous electrocatalysts for transformations relevant to clean energy and sustainable organic synthesis. Metalloporphyrins are well-known to aggregate due to &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking, but surprisingly, the influence of aggregation on homogeneous electrocatalytic performance has not been investigated previously. Herein, we present three structurally related iron meso-phenylporphyrins whose aggregation properties are different in commonly used N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF) electrolyte. Both spectroscopy and light scattering provide evidence of extensive porphyrin aggregation under conventional electrocatalytic conditions. Using the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to CO as a test reaction, cyclic voltammetry reveals an inverse dependence of the kinetics on the catalyst concentration. The inhibition extends to bulk performance, where up to 75% of the catalyst at 1 mM is inactive compared to at 0.25 mM. We additionally report how aggregation is perturbed by organic additives, axial ligands, and redox state. Periodic boundary calculations provide additional insights into aggregate stability as a function of metalloporphyrin structure. Finally, we generalize the aggregation phenomenon by surveying metalloporphyrins with different metals and substituents. This study demonstrates that homogeneous metalloporphyrins can aggregate severely in well-solubilizing organic electrolytes, that aggregation can be easily modulated through experimental conditions, and that the extent of aggregation must be considered for accurate catalytic benchmarking.</description>
      <author>Kaitlin Branch, Erin R. Johnson, Eva M. Nichols</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c00121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of the Impact of Driver Behavior on the Carbon Footprint in Morocco's Transportation Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.procs.2024.05.060</link>
      <description>Laila Benabbou, Mimoun Benali, Ghada Moufdi, Hicham SADOK, Procedia computer science. 236(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399249653

                With population growth, industrial expansion, and increased energy demand intensifying pollution, Morocco is suffering from a shortage of fossil fuels, urgently calling for climate intervention to stimulate the imperative reduction of its carbon footprint. Indeed, the country has realized that it is time to monitor its environmental indicators such as energy consumption, accounting, and carbon footprint to comply with global efforts to reduce carbon footprint and aim for energy efficiency while preserving and optimizing its energy resources. Much attention has been focused on the transportation sector, the second-largest global polluter, which will be the subject of our analysis. Our case study will focus on the evaluation of three vehicles to examine the influence of driver behavior on energy consumption and carbon footprint. Data collection was carried out using UPLOGISTIX, a solution developed by our hosting entity, which aims to present calculations of environmental measures to display the results and ultimately provide recommendations for reducing its carbon footprint. An approach has been proposed to achieve the set objectives. The results of our analysis highlight the existence of a significant relationship between behavioral barriers and energy consumption. Indeed, the behavior of a reckless driver, characterized by abrupt braking, rapid accelerations, and other factors, leads to an actual energy consumption that exceeds recommended standards. This excessive consumption results in a considerable production of CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Laila Benabbou, Mimoun Benali, Ghada Moufdi, Hicham SADOK</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.procs.2024.05.060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation, Structure and Reactivity of a Beryllium(0) Complex with Mg&#948;+ &#822;&#822; Be&#948;&#713; Bond Polarization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408422</link>
      <description>Chantsalmaa Berthold, Johannes M&#228;urer, Lukas Klerner, Sjoerd Harder, Magnus R. Buchner, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399241000

                Attempts to create a novel Mg&#8208;Be bond by reaction of [(DIPePBDI*)MgNa]2 with Be[N(SiMe3)2]2 failed; DIPePBDI* = HC[(tBu)C=N(DIPeP)]2, DIPeP = 2,6&#8208;Et2C&#8208;phenyl. Even at elevated temperatures, no conversion was observed. This is likely caused by strong steric shielding of the Be center. A similar reaction with the more open Cp*BeCl gave in quantitative yield (DIPePBDI)MgBeCp* (1). The crystal structure shows a Mg&#8208;Be bond of 2.469(4) &#197;. Homolytic cleavage of the Mg&#8208;Be bond requires &#916;H = 69.6 kcal mol&#713;1 (cf. CpBe&#8208;BeCp 69.0 kcal mol&#713;1 and (DIPPBDI)Mg&#8208;Mg(DIPPBDI) 55.8 kcal mol&#713;1). Natural&#8208;Population&#8208;Analysis (NPA) shows fragment charges: (DIPePBDI*)Mg +0.27 / BeCp* &#8208;0.27. The very low NPA charge on Be (+0.62) compared to Mg (+1.21) and the strongly upfield 9Be NMR signal at &#8208;23.7 ppm are in line with considerable electron density on Be and the formal oxidation state assignment of MgII&#8208;Be0. Despite this Mg&#948;+&#8208;Be&#948;&#713; polarity, 1 is extremely thermally stable and unreactive towards H2, CO, N2, cyclohexene and carbodiimide. It reacted with benzophenone, azobenzene, phenyl acetylene, CO2 and CS2. Reaction with 1&#8208;adamantyl azide led to reductive coupling and formation of an N6&#8208;chain. The azide reagent also inserted in the Cp*&#8208;Be bond. The inertness of 1 is likely due to bulky ligands protecting the Mg&#8208;Be unit.</description>
      <author>Chantsalmaa Berthold, Johannes M&#228;urer, Lukas Klerner, Sjoerd Harder, Magnus R. Buchner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Consumption Analysis and Management Strategies for the Dairy Farm in India Towards Sustainable Development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/03772063.2024.2359006</link>
      <description>Michael C.P. Sing, M. Marsaline Beno, IETE journal of research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399297329

                Environmental pollution and the rapid decline in the availability of fossil fuels are the major concerns of the electric power industry in recent years. Effective utilization of electrical energy is the need of the hour in building the nation towards sustainable development. This study presents the energy consumption analysis and management performed in a diary firm located in Tamil Nadu, India. Initially, the energy usage of the firm is estimated based on its electricity bills, meter readings, and survey followed by detailed energy consumption analysis and evaluation. The study employs guidelines provided by the Indian Bureau of Energy Efficiency for energy management. The detailed analysis performed finds scopes for improvement in efficient energy usage. Numerical analysis shows that implementation of proposed action plans that include installation of automatic power factor correction, replacement of overheating equipment, and replacement of lighting systems with energy-efficient lighting would save annual energy of 123.96 kWh which in turn results in the reduction of annual CO2 emission by 117.76 tonnes. Furthermore, this paper also proposes a novel optimal process scheduling which optimally schedules different processes in the firm without affecting productivity. This makes an additional savings of INR 4,23,360 per annum in the energy cost by minimizing the maximum demand of the firm with zero investment. A comparison of the proposed approach with existing methodologies available in the literature shows the effectiveness of the proposed technique.</description>
      <author>Michael C.P. Sing, M. Marsaline Beno</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/03772063.2024.2359006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling of carbon flows in the value chain of packaging plastics in the context of sustainable carbon management</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.spc.2024.06.002</link>
      <description>Stijn Van der Perre, Oleksii Mynko, Kevin M. Van Geem, Tomas Wyns, Sustainable production and consumption. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399303979

                The low share of plastic recycling means significant losses for the economy as well as for the environment, especially for plastic packaging materials since they are the largest end-use market for plastics and characterized by a typical short first-use cycle. The main polymers used in packaging applications are basic polymers, such as PE, PP, PS and PET, which consist mainly of fossil carbon locked up in polymer form. This study attempts to map carbon flows across the packaging plastics value chain with the goal to optimize carbon fixation in relevant polymers over multiple life cycles and minimize carbon loss to the atmosphere via CO2 emissions. Evaluating these carbon balances in the production, consumption and end-of-life treatment phase of these polymers provides more insight in the carbon losses during their life cycle. Three case studies were considered; (1) a baseline route (BASE), representing the current linear plastics economy model which is benchmarked with two theoretical sustainable scenarios: (2) an electrified (ELEC) and (3) a biobased (BIO) route. Specific parameters and assumptions in these three cases were adapted, such as feedstock type, recycling rate, type of recycling etc. Improved recycling rates and advanced recycling methods were applied in the sustainable cases and had a positive effect on carbon retention in products. Allowing a numerical comparison, a method was developed to quantify this carbon retention via the half lifetime of carbon in materials over multiple life cycles. The half lifetime evolved from 0.3 year in the BASE route to 2.0 and 2.6 years in the BIO and ELEC route, respectively. However, even these sustainable, optimized routes remained insufficient to embed carbon in plastic products for many years without too much carbon loss. It is inevitable that an enhanced (carbon) circularity in these routes comes by a certain energy cost; about 46 GJ more energy was required per extra recycled ton carbon in the ELEC route (compared to BASE). But at the same time this intensified carbon conservation leads to a CO2 emission reduction potential of 80 %. The present work illustrates the potential of chemical recycling, and carbon capture and utilization (CCU) techniques for end-of-life treatment of plastic packaging products, but additional process development and process intensification in all facets of the value chain are needed to minimize carbon leakage over multiple lifecycles. Hence, waste management policy could be an important instrument to support further enhancement in plastics circularity.</description>
      <author>Stijn Van der Perre, Oleksii Mynko, Kevin M. Van Geem, Tomas Wyns</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.spc.2024.06.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation, Structure and Reactivity of a Beryllium(0) Complex with Mg&#948;+ &#822;&#822; Be&#948;&#713; Bond Polarization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408422</link>
      <description>Chantsalmaa Berthold, Johannes M&#228;urer, Lukas Klerner, Sjoerd Harder, Magnus R. Buchner, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399238722

                Attempts to create a novel Mg&#8208;Be bond by reaction of [(DIPePBDI*)MgNa]2 with Be[N(SiMe3)2]2 failed; DIPePBDI* = HC[(tBu)C=N(DIPeP)]2, DIPeP = 2,6&#8208;Et2C&#8208;phenyl. Even at elevated temperatures, no conversion was observed. This is likely caused by strong steric shielding of the Be center. A similar reaction with the more open Cp*BeCl gave in quantitative yield (DIPePBDI)MgBeCp* (1). The crystal structure shows a Mg&#8208;Be bond of 2.469(4) &#197;. Homolytic cleavage of the Mg&#8208;Be bond requires &#916;H = 69.6 kcal mol&#713;1 (cf. CpBe&#8208;BeCp 69.0 kcal mol&#713;1 and (DIPPBDI)Mg&#8208;Mg(DIPPBDI) 55.8 kcal mol&#713;1). Natural&#8208;Population&#8208;Analysis (NPA) shows fragment charges: (DIPePBDI*)Mg +0.27 / BeCp* &#8208;0.27. The very low NPA charge on Be (+0.62) compared to Mg (+1.21) and the strongly upfield 9Be NMR signal at &#8208;23.7 ppm are in line with considerable electron density on Be and the formal oxidation state assignment of MgII&#8208;Be0. Despite this Mg&#948;+&#8208;Be&#948;&#713; polarity, 1 is extremely thermally stable and unreactive towards H2, CO, N2, cyclohexene and carbodiimide. It reacted with benzophenone, azobenzene, phenyl acetylene, CO2 and CS2. Reaction with 1&#8208;adamantyl azide led to reductive coupling and formation of an N6&#8208;chain. The azide reagent also inserted in the Cp*&#8208;Be bond. The inertness of 1 is likely due to bulky ligands protecting the Mg&#8208;Be unit.</description>
      <author>Chantsalmaa Berthold, Johannes M&#228;urer, Lukas Klerner, Sjoerd Harder, Magnus R. Buchner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-volume fly ash self-compacting concrete for coastal constructions: A sustainable development solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54772/jomc.v14i01.704</link>
      <description>C. Hung, Journal of materials and construction. 14(01)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399294155

                This article presents the research results on the effectiveness of applying high-volume fly ash self-compacting concrete (SCC) in constructing environmentally influenced structures along the coast of Vietnam. SCC is designed with fly ash replacing 70% and 80% of cement. Technical criteria evaluated include workability, compressive strength, chloride ion permeability, water absorption, and dry bulk density of SCC. Additionally, the energy consumption, environmental emissions, and production costs of high-volume fly ash SCC are also assessed. The results show that SCC with 70% and 80% fly ash replacement by weight meets construction requirements, with compressive strengths at 28 days reaching 25.1 MPa and 21.2 MPa, and at 90 days reaching 49.4 MPa and 28.3 MPa respectively; chloride ion permeability is very low, electrical resistivity at 28 days is 690C and 539C; water absorption at 28 days is approximately 2.3% and 2.6%; dry bulk density at 28 days is 2239 kg/m3 and 2225 kg/m3. Compared to conventional concrete with equivalent compressive strengths of 20 MPa and 25 MPa (BT200, BT250), using high-volume fly ash SCC with 70% and 80% fly ash replacement results in energy consumption reduction by 45.28% and 53.45% respectively; CO2, NOx, SOx emissions are reduced by (52.41%, 54.26%, 53.95%) and (62.21%, 64.33%, 64.13%); material production costs decrease by 15.14% and 17.16% respectively. Utilizing high-volume fly ash SCC as a solution for coastal constructions proves to be technically feasible, cost-effective, environmentally friendly, and sustainable.</description>
      <author>C. Hung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54772/jomc.v14i01.704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the spatiotemporal heterogeneity, sectoral contributions and drivers of provincial CO2 emissions in China from 2019 to 2022</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.05.041</link>
      <description>Hanyu Zhang, Weidong Guo, Siwen Wang, Zhiliang Yao, Ling Lv, Yan Teng, Xin Li, Xianbao Shen, Journal of Environmental Sciences/Journal of environmental sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399208776

                CO2 emissions (CEs) pose a growing threat to environmental changes and global warming, attracting extensive attention. Here, we leveraged near-real-time monitoring data spanning 2019 to 2022 to investigate spatiotemporal heterogeneity, sectoral contributions, provincial spatial correlation, and driving factors influencing CEs at the provincial level in China. Our analysis, integrating Moran's Index analysis, Spearman correlation analysis, and the Geographically Weighted Regression model, unveiled China's consistent world-leading CEs, surpassing 10,000 Mt over the study period. Spatially, CEs exhibited a heterogeneous distribution, with markedly higher emissions in eastern and northern regions compared to western and southern areas. Temporally, CEs displayed significant fluctuations, peaking in the fourth quarter before declining in subsequent quarters. Chinese New Year and COVID-19 had the biggest effects on CEs, with average daily reductions of -20.8 % and -18.9 %, respectively, compared to the four-year average and the same period in 2019. Sectoral analysis highlighted the power and industry sectors as primary contributors to CEs in China, jointly accounting for 37.9 %-40.2 % and 43.5 %-46.4 % of total CEs, respectively. Spatial clustering analysis identified a distinct High-High agglomeration region, predominantly encompassing provinces such as Inner Mongolia, Shandong and Jiangsu. Furthermore, total energy consumption and electricity consumption emerged as significant drivers of CEs, exhibiting correlation coefficients exceeding 0.9, followed by exhaust emissions, population size, and gross domestic product. Moreover, the influence of drivers on provincial CEs exhibited notable spatial heterogeneity, with regression coefficients displaying a decreasing gradient from north to south. These findings provide scientific and technological support to realize the provincial dual-carbon goals in China.</description>
      <author>Hanyu Zhang, Weidong Guo, Siwen Wang, Zhiliang Yao, Ling Lv, Yan Teng, Xin Li, Xianbao Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.05.041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Generation Graphenes in Cement-Based Materials: Production, Property Enhancement, and Life Cycle Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c01924</link>
      <description>Sahil Surehali, Sayee Srikarah Volaity, Aude Simon, Ranjith Divigalpitiya, Aditya Kumar, Narayanan Neithalath, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399303643

                Several studies have explored the use of graphene to improve the properties of cement-based materials. However, most commercially available graphenes are expensive, not amenable to mass production, and have high embodied energy and emissions, making their use in concrete less attractive, despite the beneficial mechanical property attributes. This paper discusses the use of two novel graphene types, fractal graphene (FG) and reactive graphene (RG), obtained through a cost-effective and scalable detonation synthesis, in cement-based materials. FG and RG are sheets containing 6&#8211;10 layers, with lateral dimensions of 20&#8211;50 nm and a z-axis thickness of &lt;5 nm. RG is functionalized with carboxylic groups. An ultrasonication process is employed to ensure dispersion of graphene particles in aqueous solutions. Both FG and RG, when added at very small dosages (&#8804;0.04% by mass of cement), enhance the compressive strength of cement mortars by &gt;70% at early ages and up to 20% at later ages. The beneficial effect of functionalization results in better performance for RG-modified mixtures, even at dosages as low as 0.02%. Concomitant enhancements in heat of hydration, hydrate formation, and rheological response are observed. A significant reduction in porosity and critical pore size (by 50% or more) promises significantly improved concrete durability, and thus reduced life-cycle costs. A comparative life cycle analysis (LCA) is used to show that FG- and RG-modified mortars have normalized (by the 28 d strength) energy demand and global warming potential (GWP) that is up to 15% lower than those of conventional mortars. Overall, this study shows that FG and RG, manufactured through a scalable, cost-, energy-, and CO2-efficient detonation synthesis, can beneficially impact the engineering and environmental performance of concretes.</description>
      <author>Sahil Surehali, Sayee Srikarah Volaity, Aude Simon, Ranjith Divigalpitiya, Aditya Kumar, Narayanan Neithalath</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c01924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indicators of Global Climate Change 2023: annual update of key indicators of the state of the climate system and human influence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-16-2625-2024</link>
      <description>Piers M. Forster, Chris Smith, Tristram Walsh, William F. Lamb, Robin Lamboll, B. D. Hall, Mathias Hauser, Aur&#233;lien Ribes, Debbie Rosen, Nathan P. Gillett, Matthew D. Palmer, Joeri Rogelj, Karina von Schuckmann, Blair Trewin, Myles Allen, Robbie M. Andrew, Richard Betts, Alex Borger, Tim Boyer, Jiddu A. Broersma, Carlo Buontempo, Samantha Burgess, Chiara Cagnazzo, Lijing Cheng, Pierre Friedlingstein, Andrew Gettelman, Johannes G&#252;tschow, Masayoshi Ishii, Stuart Jenkins, Lan X, Colin Morice, Jens M&#252;hle, Christopher Kadow, John Kennedy, Rachel Killick, P. B. Krummel, Jan C. Minx, Gunnar Myhre, Vaishali Na&#239;k, Glen P. Peters, Anna Pirani, Julia Pongratz, Carl&#8208;Friedrich Schleussner, Sonia I. Seneviratne, Sophie Szopa, Peter Thorne, Mahesh Kovilakam, Elisa Majam&#228;ki, Jukka-Pekka Jalkanen, Margreet van Marle, Rachel Hoesly, Robert Rohde, Dominik L. Schumacher, Guido R. van der Werf, Russell S. Vose, Kirsten Zickfeld, Xuebin Zhang, Val&#233;rie Masson&#8208;Delmotte, Panmao Zhai, Earth system science data. 16(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399318659

                Abstract. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) assessments are the trusted source of scientific evidence for climate negotiations taking place under the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). Evidence-based decision-making needs to be informed by up-to-date and timely information on key indicators of the state of the climate system and of the human influence on the global climate system. However, successive IPCC reports are published at intervals of 5&#8211;10 years, creating potential for an information gap between report cycles. We follow methods as close as possible to those used in the IPCC Sixth Assessment Report (AR6) Working Group One (WGI) report. We compile monitoring datasets to produce estimates for key climate indicators related to forcing of the climate system: emissions of greenhouse gases and short-lived climate forcers, greenhouse gas concentrations, radiative forcing, the Earth's energy imbalance, surface temperature changes, warming attributed to human activities, the remaining carbon budget, and estimates of global temperature extremes. The purpose of this effort, grounded in an open-data, open-science approach, is to make annually updated reliable global climate indicators available in the public domain (https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.11388387, Smith et al., 2024a). As they are traceable to IPCC report methods, they can be trusted by all parties involved in UNFCCC negotiations and help convey wider understanding of the latest knowledge of the climate system and its direction of travel. The indicators show that, for the 2014&#8211;2023 decade average, observed warming was 1.19 [1.06 to 1.30] &#176;C, of which 1.19 [1.0 to 1.4] &#176;C was human-induced. For the single-year average, human-induced warming reached 1.31 [1.1 to 1.7] &#176;C in 2023 relative to 1850&#8211;1900. The best estimate is below the 2023-observed warming record of 1.43 [1.32 to 1.53] &#176;C, indicating a substantial contribution of internal variability in the 2023 record. Human-induced warming has been increasing at a rate that is unprecedented in the instrumental record, reaching 0.26 [0.2&#8211;0.4] &#176;C per decade over 2014&#8211;2023. This high rate of warming is caused by a combination of net greenhouse gas emissions being at a persistent high of 53&#177;5.4 Gt CO2e yr&#8722;1 over the last decade, as well as reductions in the strength of aerosol cooling. Despite this, there is evidence that the rate of increase in CO2 emissions over the last decade has slowed compared to the 2000s, and depending on societal choices, a continued series of these annual updates over the critical 2020s decade could track a change of direction for some of the indicators presented here.</description>
      <author>Piers M. Forster, Chris Smith, Tristram Walsh, William F. Lamb, Robin Lamboll, B. D. Hall, Mathias Hauser, Aur&#233;lien Ribes, Debbie Rosen, Nathan P. Gillett, Matthew D. Palmer, Joeri Rogelj, Karina von Schuckmann, Blair Trewin, Myles Allen, Robbie M. Andrew, Richard Betts, Alex Borger, Tim Boyer, Jiddu A. Broersma, Carlo Buontempo, Samantha Burgess, Chiara Cagnazzo, Lijing Cheng, Pierre Friedlingstein, Andrew Gettelman, Johannes G&#252;tschow, Masayoshi Ishii, Stuart Jenkins, Lan X, Colin Morice, Jens M&#252;hle, Christopher Kadow, John Kennedy, Rachel Killick, P. B. Krummel, Jan C. Minx, Gunnar Myhre, Vaishali Na&#239;k, Glen P. Peters, Anna Pirani, Julia Pongratz, Carl&#8208;Friedrich Schleussner, Sonia I. Seneviratne, Sophie Szopa, Peter Thorne, Mahesh Kovilakam, Elisa Majam&#228;ki, Jukka-Pekka Jalkanen, Margreet van Marle, Rachel Hoesly, Robert Rohde, Dominik L. Schumacher, Guido R. van der Werf, Russell S. Vose, Kirsten Zickfeld, Xuebin Zhang, Val&#233;rie Masson&#8208;Delmotte, Panmao Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-16-2625-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interventions for postburn pruritus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.cd013468.pub2</link>
      <description>Sarthak Sinha, Vincent Gabriel, Rohit Arora, Wisoo Shin, J Scott, Shyla K Bharadia, Myriam Verly, Waleed Rahmani, Duncan Nickerson, Frankie O. G. Fraulin, Pallab Chatterjee, Rajeev Ahuja, Jeff Biernaskie, Cochrane library. 2024(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399365486

                Background Postburn pruritus (itch) is a common and distressing symptom experienced on healing or healed burn or donor site wounds. Topical, systemic, and physical treatments are available to control postburn pruritus; however, it remains unclear how effective these are. Objectives To assess the effects of interventions for treating postburn pruritus in any care setting. Search methods In September 2022, we searched the Cochrane Wounds Specialised Register, the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL), Ovid MEDLINE (including In&#8208;Process &amp; Other Non&#8208;Indexed Citations), Ovid Embase, and EBSCO CINAHL Plus. We also searched clinical trials registries and scanned references of relevant publications to identify eligible trials. There were no restrictions with respect to language, publication date, or study setting. Selection criteria Randomised controlled trials (RCTs) that enrolled people with postburn pruritus to compare an intervention for postburn pruritus with any other intervention, placebo or sham intervention, or no intervention. Data collection and analysis We used the standard methodological procedures expected by Cochrane. We used GRADE to assess the certainty of the evidence. Main results We included 25 RCTs assessing 21 interventions with 1166 randomised participants. These 21 interventions can be grouped into six categories: neuromodulatory agents (such as doxepin, gabapentin, pregabalin, ondansetron), topical therapies (such as CQ&#8208;01 hydrogel, silicone gel, enalapril ointment, Provase moisturiser, beeswax and herbal oil cream), physical modalities (such as massage therapy, therapeutic touch, extracorporeal shock wave therapy, enhanced education about silicone gel sheeting), laser scar revision (pulsed dye laser, pulsed high&#8208;intensity laser, fractional CO2 laser), electrical stimulation (transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation, transcranial direct current stimulation), and other therapies (cetirizine/cimetidine combination, lemon balm tea). Most RCTs were conducted at academic hospitals and were at a high risk of performance, attrition, and detection bias. While 24 out of 25 included studies reported change in burn&#8208;related pruritus, secondary outcomes such as cost&#8208;effectiveness, pain, patient perception, wound healing, and participant health&#8208;related quality of life were not reported or were reported incompletely. Neuromodulatory agents versus antihistamines or placebo There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that doxepin cream may reduce burn&#8208;related pruritus compared with oral antihistamine (mean difference (MD) &#8208;2.60 on a 0 to 10 visual analogue scale (VAS), 95% confidence interval (CI) &#8208;3.79 to &#8208;1.42; 2 studies, 49 participants). A change of 2 points represents a minimal clinically important difference (MCID). Due to very low&#8208;certainty evidence, it is uncertain whether doxepin cream impacts the incidence of somnolence as an adverse event compared to oral antihistamine (risk ratio (RR) 0.64, 95% CI 0.32 to 1.25; 1 study, 24 participants). No data were reported on pain in the included study. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that gabapentin may reduce burn&#8208;related pruritus compared with cetirizine (MD &#8208;2.40 VAS, 95% CI &#8208;4.14 to &#8208;0.66; 1 study, 40 participants). A change of 2 points represents a MCID. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that gabapentin reduces the incidence of somnolence compared to cetirizine (RR 0.02, 95% CI 0.00 to 0.38; 1 study, 40 participants). No data were reported on pain in the included study. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that pregabalin may result in a reduction in burn&#8208;related pruritus intensity compared with cetirizine with pheniramine maleate (MD &#8208;0.80 VAS, 95% CI &#8208;1.24 to &#8208;0.36; 1 study, 40 participants). A change of 2 points represents a MCID. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that pregabalin reduces the incidence of somnolence compared to cetirizine (RR 0.04, 95% CI 0.00 to 0.69; 1 study, 40 participants). No data were reported on pain in the included study. There is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence that ondansetron probably results in a reduction in burn&#8208;related pruritus intensity compared with diphenhydramine (MD &#8208;0.76 on a 0 to 10 numeric analogue scale (NAS), 95% CI &#8208;1.50 to &#8208;0.02; 1 study, 38 participants). A change of 2 points represents a MCID. No data were reported on pain and adverse events in the included study. Topical therapies versus relevant comparators There is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence that enalapril ointment probably decreases mean burn&#8208;related pruritus compared with placebo control (MD &#8208;0.70 on a 0 to 4 scoring table for itching, 95% CI &#8208;1.04 to &#8208;0.36; 1 study, 60 participants). No data were reported on pain and adverse events in the included study. Physical modalities versus relevant comparators Compared with standard care, there is low&#8208;certainty evidence that massage may reduce burn&#8208;related pruritus (standardised mean difference (SMD) &#8208;0.86, 95% CI &#8208;1.45 to &#8208;0.27; 2 studies, 166 participants) and pain (SMD &#8208;1.32, 95% CI &#8208;1.66 to &#8208;0.98). These SMDs equate to a 4.60&#8208;point reduction in pruritus and a 3.74&#8208;point reduction in pain on a 10&#8208;point VAS. A change of 2 VAS points in itch represents a MCID. No data were reported on adverse events in the included studies. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that extracorporeal shock wave therapy (ESWT) may reduce burn&#8208;related pruritus compared with sham stimulation (SMD &#8208;1.20, 95% CI &#8208;1.65 to &#8208;0.75; 2 studies, 91 participants). This equates to a 5.93&#8208;point reduction in pruritus on a 22&#8208;point 12&#8208;item Pruritus Severity Scale. There is low&#8208;certainty evidence that ESWT may reduce pain compared with sham stimulation (MD 2.96 on a 0 to 25 pressure pain threshold (PPT), 95% CI 1.76 to 4.16; 1 study, 45 participants). No data were reported on adverse events in the included studies. Laser scar revision versus untreated or placebo controls There is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence that pulsed high&#8208;intensity laser probably results in a reduction in burn&#8208;related pruritus intensity compared with placebo laser (MD &#8208;0.51 on a 0 to 1 Itch Severity Scale (ISS), 95% CI &#8208;0.64 to &#8208;0.38; 1 study, 49 participants). There is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence that pulsed high&#8208;intensity laser probably reduces pain compared with placebo laser (MD &#8208;3.23 VAS, 95% CI &#8208;5.41 to &#8208;1.05; 1 study, 49 participants). No data were reported on adverse events in the included studies. Authors' conclusions There is moderate to low&#8208;certainty evidence on the effects of 21 interventions. Most studies were small and at a high risk of bias related to blinding and incomplete outcome data. Where there is moderate&#8208;certainty evidence, practitioners should consider the applicability of the evidence for their patients.</description>
      <author>Sarthak Sinha, Vincent Gabriel, Rohit Arora, Wisoo Shin, J Scott, Shyla K Bharadia, Myriam Verly, Waleed Rahmani, Duncan Nickerson, Frankie O. G. Fraulin, Pallab Chatterjee, Rajeev Ahuja, Jeff Biernaskie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.cd013468.pub2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;One for all, all for one&#8217;: A tale from the formative years of Scandinavian exercise physiology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1113/ep091943</link>
      <description>Ronan M. G. Berg, Experimental physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399353119

                In Scandinavia, we have a proud tradition of exercise physiology. The period from 1910 to 1920, during which August Krogh (1874&#8211;1949) and Johannes Lindhard (1870&#8211;1947) provided measurements on cardiorespiratory function and metabolism during exercise in humans, can certainly be considered its birth, at least from a merely Danish perspective. However, it is in my opinion the decades that followed the establishment of the Rockefeller Institute in Copenhagen in 1928 that comprise the formative years of Scandinavian exercise physiology. This institute, established with funds secured by August Krogh after he became a Nobel laureate, offered advanced research and teaching facilities in areas such as zoophysiology, medical physiology, gymnastics theory, biochemistry and biophysics (Asmussen, 1987). Krogh was instrumental in its design, ensuring the inclusion of facilities for Lindhard's Gymnastics Theory Laboratory on the first floor of the north wing, strategically located above his own Zoophysiological Laboratory to facilitate interaction and collaboration. It was in this environment, and under the guidance of both Lindhard and Krogh, that three scientists emerged as seminal figures in Scandinavian exercise physiology: Erik Hohw&#252; Christensen (1904&#8211;1996), Marius Nielsen (1903&#8211;2000) and Erling Asmussen (1907&#8211;1991), fondly referred to by Krogh as 'The Three Musketeers' (Schmidt-Nielsen, 1995). The tales of these three scientists are many, and their efforts to evolve and promote exercise physiology, scientifically, pedagogically and organisationally, are certainly reminiscent of the noble characters' fight for justice in Alexandre Dumas's novel. I will try to refrain from digressing too much into the swashbuckler genre here, but Dumas's sentiment that 'the merit of all things lies in their difficulty' seems to resonate well with their scientific endeavours, as they repeatedly tackled scientific challenges that appeared insurmountable, either conceptually or methodologically (Asmussen, 1987; &#197;strand, 1991). However, because a comprehensive account of their collective contributions would merit a whole monograph in its own right, I will only recapitulate one important aspect of their work from the formative years of Scandinavian exercise physiology here: the adaptative resetting of homeostasis across organ systems during exercise. Erik Hohw&#252; Christensen, universally known as 'Hohw&#252;', was still an undergraduate student in natural history, chemistry, geography and geology when he joined Lindhard at the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory, shortly after the Rockefeller Institute had been inaugurated in 1928. Under Lindhard's supervision, he engaged in a series of studies that followed up on Krogh and Lindhard's work from the preceding decade that demonstrated extremely rapid cardiovascular and gas exchange kinetics following exercise onset. Initially, his efforts were focused on enhancing the functionality of Krogh's bicycle ergometer (Krogh, 1913) and refining Krogh and Lindhard's nitrous oxide rebreathing technique developed for the measurement of cardiac output (Krogh &amp; Lindhard, 1912). While doing this, Hohw&#252; ensured an unprecedented standardisation of experimental conditions, exercising stringent control over variables such as diet, meal timings and rest periods prior to measurements. As an alternative to the nitrous oxide rebreathing technique, Hohw&#252; adapted the relatively new acetylene rebreathing method for measurements during exercise (Christensen, 1931a, 1932a), and soon Hohw&#252; expanded from mere methodologically based studies to mechanistic studies that focused not only on cardiac output, but also on blood glucose, respiration and thermoregulation (Christensen, 1931b, 1931c, 1931d, 1931e, 1932b). However, while Krogh and Lindhard's studies had mostly focused on exercise at moderate intensity in moderately fit men approaching middle age (themselves), Hohw&#252; continued the longstanding Scandinavian tradition of self-experimentation within physiology, to conduct studies at (near-)maximal intensity in highly fit, young athletes, that is, himself and three fellow students that he knew from his dormitory, including Marius Nielsen. All these experiments were meticulously carried out using Krogh's now-optimised bicycle ergometer, ensuring well-defined workloads. Most critically, and unlike other contemporary studies that typically captured measurements during transitional states&#8212;such as at the onset of exercise, immediately following exertion or during short breaks&#8212;Hohw&#252;'s work was characterised by extended continuous exercise sessions that facilitated the acquisition of steady state measurements, to compare and distinguish the physiological changes that take place during rest, exercise at well-defined intensities, and recovery. Hohw&#252; graduated in 1931, majoring in gymnastic theory, and defended his doctoral thesis based on the abovementioned studies later the same year. Marius Nielsen also graduated in 1931, majoring in natural history, and soon began conducting his experiments at the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory, focusing on the work of breathing during exercise (Nielsen, 1936a). Soon, an opportunity arose that would prove pivotal to their continued work. Since World War I, there had been an extraordinary surge in enthusiasm for sports, fuelled by the belief in athleticism as a crucial factor for health. However, some critics questioned whether these efforts genuinely contributed to improving health, highlighting the lack of clear evidence on whether athletic sports had a positive or negative impact on the body. The ambiguity surrounding the physiological effects of strenuous exercise and the safe limits of such exertion prompted the League of Nations' Health Organization to convene a meeting in Copenhagen in January 1931. Here, it was acknowledged that the specific changes occurring in the body under extreme athletic strain remained largely unexplored. To address this, experts at the meeting recommended that the Health Organization initiate a comprehensive study into various physiological responses to maximum muscular effort. Krogh and Lindhard, who attended the meeting, proposed a 2-year research programme to investigate these phenomena and subsequently received funding to continue Hohw&#252; and Nielsen's research. The preliminary results were presented to the Health Organization in Geneva in 1934, encompassing a comprehensive 32-page report (Christensen et al., 1934), which is also an early account of the oxygen transport cascade, highlighting the convective and diffusive steps for oxygen transport from ambient air to working muscle in relation to exercise performance. The funding from the League of Nations' Health Organization enabled Krogh to hire both Hohw&#252; and Nielsen as research assistants at the Zoophysiological Laboratory. Nielsen utilised this opportunity to also focus on the chemical regulation of ventilation (Nielsen, 1936b). These studies were not particularly focused on exercise as such, but exercise was used along with hypobaric hypoxia and experimentally induced metabolic acidosis (by orally administered ammonium chloride) as a means for uncovering the mechanisms regulating ventilation in humans. Specifically, Nielsen aimed to determine whether CO2 or H+ was the primary chemical stimulus that increased the 'excitability' of the respiratory centre to enhance breathing in these different conditions, a matter of great controversy during those years. During exercise, it was believed that either the increased CO2 or H+ production in the contracting skeletal muscle (and other working tissues) could increase P aC O 2 ${{P}_{{\mathrm{aC}}{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ and/or reduce arterial pH, which would then increase ventilation. Lindhard and Krogh, in particular, had both placed their bets on P aC O 2 ${{P}_{{\mathrm{aC}}{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ , but much to Nielsen's surprise, he found that both P aC O 2 ${{P}_{{\mathrm{aC}}{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ and arterial pH remained relatively constant during the prolonged strenuous exercise sessions to which he subjected Hohw&#252; and his fellow students. When Nielsen presented this to Krogh, admitting that he did not understand how to grasp these findings, Krogh replied, 'No, I don't understand that either! You must find out!' Krogh said this in such a compelling manner that it remained a source of inspiration for Nielsen for much of his future work (Schmidt-Nielsen, 1995). Nielsen defended his doctoral thesis on the regulation of respiration in 1936. While he did not succeed in conclusively determining whether CO&#8322; or H&#8314; was the primary stimulus governing the regulation of ventilation, much pointed towards CO2. However, the stimulus for the increased ventilation during any of the examined conditions was clearly not an increase in P aC O 2 ${{P}_{{\mathrm{aC}}{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ per se, but rather seemed to involve an altered sensitivity of the respiratory centre to CO&#8322; (Nielsen, 1936b). Curiously, Nielsen followed up with a study on thermoregulation during exercise, to challenge a common viewpoint that the increase in core temperature during exercise represents a failure of thermoregulation (Nielsen, 1938). Hohw&#252;'s previous study on core temperature during prolonged strenuous exercise, showing increases in temperature to levels that would be considered life-threatening in a clinical setting, had not done much to resolve this (Christensen, 1931c). In a room that was carefully thermoregulated to maintain consistent air temperature and humidity, the young scientists cycled vigorously at various intensities on Krogh's bicycle ergometer, which was suspended on a scale for the continuous measurement of weight loss due to perspiration, while rectal and skin temperatures were continuously measured (Nielsen, 1936a, 1936b). Rectal temperature increased proportionally with exercise intensity, independently of differences in the conditions for heat loss, while changes in skin temperature remained relatively minor (Nielsen, 1938). In fact, body temperature was kept within much narrower limits at a given exercise intensity than at rest. Nielsen could thus conclude that the rise in body temperature during exercise is a regulatory response and not the result of a failure in thermoregulation (Nielsen, 1938). Together, Nielsen's studies on ventilation and thermoregulation, conducted under carefully controlled conditions and at a well-defined steady state of exercise as established by Hohw&#252;, pointed towards highly regulated exercise adaptations. While all this was going on, Asmussen, who was slightly younger than Hohw&#252; and Nielsen, had started attending lectures at the Rockefeller Institute as a student of natural history. He became acquainted with Hohw&#252; who knew that Lindhard needed an assistant to develop a method for isolating frog skeletal muscle fibres. Asmussen thus joined the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory as an unpaid assistant, and soon he was able to isolate muscle fibres from the frog's semitendinosus muscle, which then allowed him to conduct a series of studies on isometric and isotonic contractions. He continued spending his afternoons and evenings doing this after he majored in gymnastic theory in 1931 while earning his livelihood as a secondary school teacher of natural history and physical education, and in 1933 he defended his doctoral thesis on this work. By 1935, Asmussen had finally landed a position as a full-time research assistant at the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory, this time with an actual salary, so that he could quit his job as a secondary school teacher and focus more wholly on his research. However, in the meantime, Lindhard had invited the renowned German neurophysiologist Fritz Buchtal (1907&#8211;2003) to join the laboratory, in part because of the increasing hostility towards the Jewish community in Germany. Buchtal's expertise naturally drove the focus at the laboratory more in the direction of electrophysiological studies of skeletal muscle, which prompted Asmussen to concentrate on the integrative physiology of the human body in response to exercise instead. Asmussen thus conducted a study on the cardiopulmonary response to static exercise by leg presses against an angle lever with considerable loads. The study showed that oxygen uptake, ventilation and cardiac output showed variable changes during exercise depending on the workload, but they all increased sharply immediately after, which was attributed to the mechanical constraint of blood flow by the actively engaged muscles (Asmussen &amp; Hansen, 1938). The thematic overlap between Hohw&#252; and Nielsen were obvious to anyone, and soon the three started working closely together. Thus, by 1936, the memorable trio had finally been formed! Initially, Hohw&#252;, Nielsen and Asmussen turned their attention towards matters deemed urgent at the time, in particular the mechanisms behind the increase in cardiac output during exercise. A prevalent theory suggested that vasodilatation in working muscle triggered a reduction in arterial blood pressure, which then led to an increase in cardiac output through baroreflex feedback. However, this could not explain the increase in stroke volume previously reported by Hohw&#252; (Christensen, 1931e), and furthermore, the arterial baroreflex feedback loop had not been conclusively demonstrated in humans, neither during postural changes nor during steady state exercise. Moreover, the existing studies often uncritically assumed that heart rate was an accurate reflection of cardiac output, a notion also inconsistent with Hohw&#252;'s earlier studies (Christensen, 1931d, 1931e). In the basement under the north wing of the Rockefeller Institute, the trio devised an experimental set-up allowing for the manipulation of blood volume distribution through pneumatic thigh cuff inflation and deflation and by the use of a tilt table (enabling upright, supine and head-down measurements), reconstructed from a resuscitation table previously designed by Krogh in one of his less successful scientific endeavours (Krogh, 1934). This set-up also permitted the measurement of oxygen uptake, cardiac output (by Hohw&#252;'s modified acetylene rebreathing technique), and blood volume changes through water displacement plethysmography. They mostly used exercise protocols that involved rhythmic arm extensions against an elastic resistance, or by employing Krogh's bicycle ergometer. The routine was such that, after completing their teaching duties around 10 a.m., The Three Musketeers would commence the day's experiments, during which they took turns serving as experimental subjects. Following lunch, they dedicated time to analysing the data obtained. The set-up and measurements were continually refined to achieve reproducible results; even so, one experimental day would generally yield only one measurement point for a given variable (Asmussen, 1987). Therefore, although their papers often report results from relatively few, in this case three subjects, these results are usually based on several months of daily experimentation. When it came to drafting manuscripts based on the the data, they would sit together at a desk in the late afternoons and evenings; Nielsen, having the neatest handwriting, would write with a pencil as they collectively formulated each sentence of the paper, while Hohw&#252;, who came from a Danish-minded family in Southern Jutland&#8212;a region that had not become part of Denmark until the Reunification in 1920&#8212;and had attended a German school, ensured that the paper's language, written in German, was impeccable (Asmussen, 1987). Krogh was a regular visitor, keen to showcase the experimental set-up to scientists from around the world, and in the evenings, he would often stop by to discuss results and ideas, contributing to further optimisation of the experiments (Asmussen, 1987; Schmidt-Nielsen, 1995). In their collaborative experiments conducted from 1936 and approximately 5 years forth, The Three Musketeers demonstrated that thigh cuff deflation in the sitting position and a postural change from supine to upright both result in blood displacement to the lower extremities with a concomitant increase in heart rate, and vice versa when moving from upright to the supine posture (Asmussen et al., 1938, 1939a). Despite a higher heart rate in the upright position, cardiac output was found to be lower due to a lower stroke volume than in the supine position, even though oxygen uptake was similar (Asmussen et al., 1939b). Additionally, superimposing arm exercise during postural changes while restricting venous return by thigh cuff inflation, caused heart rate to vary with posture in relation to differences in stroke volume, but it still increased with exercise in all postures (Asmussen &amp; Christensen, 1939; Asmussen et al., 1939c). The baroreflex feedback loop could thus be effectively demonstrated in humans, and it seemed to remain equally effective for regulating heart rate during exercise compared to rest. Hence, as Nielsen had demonstrated for ventilation and thermoregulation, the changes in cardiovascular function during exercise seemed to reflect highly regulated phenomena. In another study, about half of the working musculature was isolated from the rest of the circulation by thigh cuff inflation during exercise on Krogh's bicycle ergometer. Despite a significant reduction in oxygen uptake, cardiac output and heart rate were barely affected (Asmussen et al., 1940). This indicated that the determinant of the cardiac output increase during exercise was the workload. In a subsequent study, a similar increase in cardiac output was observed, both in the healthy state and in the case of impaired proprioceptive feedback due to posterior fascicle demyelination (neurosyphilis) when muscle contractions were induced by electrical stimulation (Asmussen et al., 1943a). Together these studies showed that during steady state light-to-moderate exercise, it was not vasodilatation in the working muscle nor cortical feed-forward impulses that accounted for the increase in cardiac output. Given that no substances produced in the muscles below the inflated cuffs could enter the main circulation while the nervous connections remained intact, a neural feedback mechanism related to the volume of involved musculature, but unrelated to proprioception, seemed to be at play. Following up on the studies from Nielsen's doctoral thesis, similar observations were made regarding the ventilatory response to exercise. Thus, during light and moderate exercise on Krogh's bicycle ergometer, the reduction in oxygen uptake evoked by thigh cuff inflation did not affect the ventilatory response to exercise (Asmussen, Hohw&#252; Christensen et al., 1943). Furthermore, a similar ventilatory response was observed during electrically induced muscle contractions, both in the healthy state and in the case of posterior fascicle demyelination (Asmussen et al., 1943b). Hence, the steady state ventilatory response to exercise also seemed to be triggered by a non-proprioceptive neural feedback mechanism. By the early 1940s, The Three Musketeers had thus demonstrated that ventilation, thermoregulation and cardiovascular function remain tightly regulated during exercise, involving feedback mechanisms originating within the working skeletal muscle that function to reset this regulation according to the given workload. However, they could not identify the exact stimulus that triggered this feedback mechanism. In 1941, that is, at the peak of The Three Musketeers' collaborative studies, Hohw&#252; decided to depart to Sweden to pursue a professorship at the Royal Gymnastic Central Institute (GCI) in Stockholm, thus marking the end of this formative period of Scandinavian exercise physiology. Apart from a brief leave of absence from GCI in the early 1960s, Hohw&#252; remained there until his retirement in 1970. However, to quote Dumas, 'Friendship is a sacred bond that cannot be broken by distance or time', and the trio remained in touch. Notably, Asmussen and Nielsen, who both became professors at the Gymnastics Theory Laboratory in 1961 and 1965, respectively, continued to investigate the elusive stimulus within working muscle that seemingly functioned to reset homeostatic regulation, initially naming it the 'work stimulus' (Asmussen &amp; Nielsen, 1958), but later using the term 'work factor' (Asmussen, 1965), thus aligning with the contemporary terminology in exercise endocrinology (Goldstein, 1965; Ingle, 1955). Later, Hohw&#252;'s students, notably Bengt Saltin (1935&#8211;2014), followed up on another series of Hohw&#252;'s early studies on skeletal muscle fuel utilization during exercise, thereby integrating glucose homeostasis into this paradigm. However, that is a different story for another time. When reflecting on the collaboration between The Three Musketeers within the context of Alexandre Dumas's 1842 novel, I have often wondered: who is who? One might liken Hohw&#252; to Athos, the noble and naturally leading figure. Nielsen could be compared to Aramis, the quieter and more thoughtful innovator. As for Asmussen, rather than resembling Porthos, the jovial and boisterous member, he might be better represented as D'Artagnan. Hence, during these formative years, the younger Asmussen grew to become Hohw&#252; and Nielsen's equal, and subsequently a driving force for their collaboration that served as the group's visionary (Saltin, 1991). This is well-exemplified by an opening talk of his at a symposium entitled 'Physiology of Muscular Exercise' held in Dallas in 1966, in which he compiled the results of The Three Musketeers to elegantly formulate the concept of adaptive resetting of homeostasis during exercise (Asmussen, 1967): 'For every state of physical exercise, there is a carefully controlled level of pulmonary function, ventilation, cardiac output and deep body temperature. These levels are maintained at least as precisely as the resting level, and the controlling feedback systems are the same in exercise as during rest; only the set-point has been changed.' At the present day, it is evident that this adaptive resetting of homeostasis during exercise should be considered a universal phenomenon involving myriad neural and non-neural mechanisms, encompassed by the evolving concept of interorgan crosstalk (Hargreaves, 2021; Severinsen &amp; Pedersen, 2020). Returning to the questions posed at The League of Nations meeting in 1931, it is thus clear that exercise is not merely a disturbance that organ systems must counteract, eliciting abnormal or extreme responses. Rather, every organ of the healthy body is 'designed' to accommodate to the steady state of exercise, both in its own right and through its interaction with other organs&#8212;'one for all, and all for one!' Sole author. The author has no conflict of interest to declare. None.</description>
      <author>Ronan M. G. Berg</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1113/ep091943</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
