<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 01:02:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>CuO (111) Microcrystalline Evoked Indium&#8211;Organic Framework for Efficient Electroreduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400441</link>
      <description>Honghao Huang, Kaihang Yue, Chaofan Liu, Ke Zhan, Hongliang Dong, Ya Yan, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394596322

                Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2RR) to formate is economically beneficial but suffers from poor selectivity and high overpotential. Herein, enriched microcrystalline copper oxide is introduced on the surface of indium-based metal-organic frameworks. Benefiting from the CuO (111) microcrystalline shell and formed catalytic active In-Cu interfaces, the obtained MIL-68(In)/CuO heterostructure display excellent CO2RR to formate with a Faradaic efficiency (FE) as high as 89.7% at low potential of only -0.7 V vs. RHE in a flow cell. Significantly, the membrane electrode assembly (MEA) cell based on MIL-68(In)/CuO exhibit a remarkable current density of 640.3 mA cm-2 at 3.1 V and can be stably operated for 180 h at 2.7 V with a current density of 200 mA cm-2. The ex/in situ electrochemical investigations reveal that the introduction of CuO increases the formation rate of the carbon dioxide reduction intermediate *HCOO- and inhibits the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction. This work not only provides an in-depth study of the mechanism of the CO2RR pathways on In/Cu composite catalyst but also offers an effective strategy for the interface design of electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction.</description>
      <author>Honghao Huang, Kaihang Yue, Chaofan Liu, Ke Zhan, Hongliang Dong, Ya Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-doped carbon-supported Cu&#8211;CuO nanoparticles for photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.optmat.2024.115360</link>
      <description>Yun Wang, Abulikemu Abulizi, Kenji Okitsu, Tie&#8208;Zhen Ren, Optical materials. 151(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394779173

                Value-added conversion of CO2 using solar energy is a sustainable strategy to address the energy crisis and environmental issues simultaneously. In this work, Cu&#8211;CuO/NC catalysts were successfully prepared by a sol-gel method, and the effects of Cu doping ratio and heat treatment temperature on the catalyst properties were investigated. The experimental results revealed that 7%CNC-600 &#176;C has the best photocatalytic reduction performance of CO2 to CH3OH within 8h, 812&#956;mol/gcat. The catalysts were also analyzed using techniques such as XRD, SEM, TEM, Raman spectroscopy, CO2-TPD, PL, etc. The superior catalytic activity mainly benefits from the electron capture properties of the metal and its synergistic effect with nitrogen-doped carbon, resulting in a significantly improved catalyst optical property, enhanced CO2 adsorption capacity, and improved separation efficiency of photoexcited charges. Furthermore, the combined DRS and VB-XPS results elucidate the photocatalytic reaction mechanism. This study could provide potential strategies for environmental purification and energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Yun Wang, Abulikemu Abulizi, Kenji Okitsu, Tie&#8208;Zhen Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.optmat.2024.115360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide on P/P+-Si Electrode Modified with Titanium Dioxide Film</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1996.6.52</link>
      <description>Peng Wei, Xueyong Qi, Yu Sung Chun, Yingyong huaxue. 13(6)] 1996. https://openalex.org/W4394630081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Wei, Xueyong Qi, Yu Sung Chun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 1996 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1996.6.52</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photostimulated catalytic reduction of CO2 with iron porphyrins</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4394738131</link>
      <description>Heng Rao, No host. None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4394738131

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Heng Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4394738131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Porous Catalysts for Electrochemical Reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00717d</link>
      <description>Shuanglong Lu, Hongyin Hu, Huimin Sun, Fulin Yang, Han Zhu, Mingliang Du, Yinghua Jin, Wei Zhang, Green chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394627887

                The electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) stands out as a highly promising approach to simultaneously resolve the elevated atmospheric CO2 concentration and its utilization to produce value-added products. One of...</description>
      <author>Shuanglong Lu, Hongyin Hu, Huimin Sun, Fulin Yang, Han Zhu, Mingliang Du, Yinghua Jin, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00717d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Carbon Emission Trading Policy Enhance the Synergistic Emission Reduction of Carbon Dioxide and Air Pollutants? A Comparative Study Considering Different Pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4788337</link>
      <description>Zhihao Chen, Yong He, Nuo Liao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394627001

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Zhihao Chen, Yong He, Nuo Liao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4788337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO2 to CO by Molecular Cobalt&#8211;Polypyridine Diamine Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081694</link>
      <description>Y. Yang, Fang Xie, Jiahui Chen, Si Qin, Na Qiang, Ming L&#252;, Zhongli Peng, Jing Yang, Guocong Liu, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394621485

                Cobalt complexes have previously been reported to exhibit high faradaic efficiency in reducing CO2 to CO. Herein, we synthesized capsule-like cobalt&#8211;polypyridine diamine complexes [Co(L1)](BF4)2 (1) and [Co(L2) (CH3CN)](BF4)2 (2) as catalysts for the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2. Under catalytic conditions, complexes 1 and 2 demonstrated the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to CO in the presence or absence of CH3OH as a proton source. Experimental and computational studies revealed that complexes 1 and 2 undergo two consecutive reversible one-electron reductions on the cobalt core, followed by the addition of CO2 to form a metallocarboxylate intermediate [CoII(L)&#8211;CO22&#8722;]0. This crucial reaction intermediate, which governs the catalytic cycle, was successfully detected using high resolution mass spectrometry (HRMS). In situ Fourier-transform infrared spectrometer (FTIR) analysis showed that methanol can enhance the rate of carbon&#8211;oxygen bond cleavage of the metallocarboxylate intermediate. DFT studies on [CoII(L)&#8211;CO22&#8722;]0 have suggested that the doubly reduced species attacks CO2 on the C atom through the dz2 orbital, while the interaction with CO2 is further stabilized by the &#960; interaction between the metal dxz or dxz orbital with p orbitals on the O atoms. Further reductions generate a metal carbonyl intermediate [CoI(L)&#8211;CO]+, which ultimately releases CO.</description>
      <author>Y. Yang, Fang Xie, Jiahui Chen, Si Qin, Na Qiang, Ming L&#252;, Zhongli Peng, Jing Yang, Guocong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretic Insight into CO2 Reduction at Active Sites of Molybdenum and Tungsten Enzymes: a &#960; Interaction between CO2 and Tungsten Bis-Dithiolene Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.1412.2655</link>
      <description>Ya Yan, Jing Gu, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2014. https://openalex.org/W4394639766

                Active sites of molybdenum and tungsten enzymes, particularly mononuclear tungsten formate dehydrogenase (FDH) have been theoretically investigated towards their interaction with CO2. Obvious &#960; interaction has been found between the 2e reduced metallodithiole moiety and the molecular CO2. This weak &#960; bonding is predicated both at gas phase, noted as -6.0 kcal/mol and aqueous solvation level, -3.6 kcal/mol. Such interaction is not only limited to CO2, but also to the CO2 reduced product, i.e. formate, in the form of anion- &#960; interaction, noted as -6.8 kcal/mol and -4.1 kcal/mol respectively in gas and aqueous solvation model. The Bailar twisted angles from 60o to 0o, governing structure preference of tungsten dithiolene from octahedron to triangle prism in their restricted structures, has been explored to evaluate such &#960; in-terrelations with CO2 and formate. An octahedral structure with 3 kcal/mol energy lower is preferred over the triangle prismatic when such interactions are concerned.</description>
      <author>Ya Yan, Jing Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.1412.2655</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 to Ethylene using Boosted Hydrophobicity of Polyvinyl Dichloride-Coated CuO Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174475</link>
      <description>Quhan Chen, Hongqing Zhu, Zhiqiang Guo, Zijun Yan, Gang Yang, Yan&#8208;Song Zheng, Yalan Xing, Hongfeng Yin, Tom Wu, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394600676

                Cu-based materials have gathered significant attention as efficient electrocatalysts for converting carbon dioxide (CO2) to ethylene. CuO electrode was coated with Polyvinyl dichloride (PVDC) to finely tune its surface hydrophobicity, thereby effectively suppressing the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) while promoting CO2 conversion to ethylene. PVDC modification on modulating proton transfer and enhancing the stability of the electrocatalysts was investigated systematically by varying the coating material, coating amount, and coating order. The CuO-PVDC electrode with a 50 &#956;g/cm2 PVDC coating demonstrated an optimal level of hydrophobicity where the water contact angle (WCA) increased from 94.8 &#176; to 122 &#176;) and led to highly efficient production of ethylene (FEethylene increased from 32.2% to 41.4%) at a low potential of -0.89 V vs. RHE, while effectively suppressing hydrogen evolution. Comparative tests and calculations revealed that PVDC modification balances proton transfer and CO2 availability. Hence, PVDC regulates the degree of reduction in CuO, leading to an increased proportion of Cu ions on the surface of the CuO-PVDC electrode, which facilitates the C-C coupling process exhibiting long-lasting hydrophobic properties without sacrificing conductivity, which is a promising strategy for mitigating the environmental impact of CO2 and their efficient conversion to produce valuable chemicals.</description>
      <author>Quhan Chen, Hongqing Zhu, Zhiqiang Guo, Zijun Yan, Gang Yang, Yan&#8208;Song Zheng, Yalan Xing, Hongfeng Yin, Tom Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Organic Frameworks for Artificial Photosynthetic Diluted CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100307</link>
      <description>Hong Dong, Fengming Zhang, Jiegou huaxue/Chinese journal of structural chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394761334

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong Dong, Fengming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel flexible aromatic Cu3 metal-organic &#960;-cluster for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104349</link>
      <description>Yayu Yan, Jiali Chen, Zirui Wang, Jun Fu, Haixia Zhang, Shumei Chen, Qiaohong Li, Jian Zhang, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394770127

                Producing Cn products through electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is of great significance in addressing the global warming crisis. Organic-inorganic hybrid catalysts, characterized by precise and controllable active sites and metal-ligand synergistic interactions, can enhance the reaction activity and stability of Cu-based catalysts. Herein, based on density functional theory (DFT), a novel flexible aromatic Cu3 metal-organic &#960;-cluster (Cu3-&#960; cluster) was constructed, consisting of triple-atom active centers and pentalyne ligands. During the catalytic CO2RR process, the adsorption of H can promote the activation of CO2, this converts the competing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) into promoting CO2RR. Enhanced aromaticity of its cluster core is credited with stabilizing the coadsorption of H and CO2 (H*+CO2*), consequently lowering the reaction free energy of the CO2 activation process. Research has shown that Cu3-&#960; cluster have high catalytic activity for electrocatalytic CO2 generation of C2H4. Considering the solvation effect, the limit potential of this reaction is -0.60 V. Furthermore, the reaction free energies suggest that the Cu3-&#960; cluster is more inclined to yield C2H4(g) products via COCO* coupling. Moreover, the high CO coverage at the triple-atom active centers not only makes it more challenging for this cluster to adsorb H, but also reduces the energy barrier of the COCO* coupling reaction.In the entire reaction pathway of C2H4(g), there exhibits dynamic self-adaptive behavior in the bond lengths and bond angles of the three Cu atoms in the cluster core, leading to fluctuations in aromaticity. The flexibility and aromaticity changes in this structure enable the Cu3-&#960; cluster to better stabilize intermediates. This work provides theoretical guidance for the application of metal-organic &#960;-clusters, accelerates the screening of catalysts for CO2RR, and provides powerful theoretical guidance for the structure-activity relationships between aromaticity and catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Yayu Yan, Jiali Chen, Zirui Wang, Jun Fu, Haixia Zhang, Shumei Chen, Qiaohong Li, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ/Operando Synchrotron Analytical Techniques for CO2/CO Reduction Reaction: From Atomic Scales to Mesoscales</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202404213</link>
      <description>Yi Xu, Bingbao Mei, Qiucheng Xu, Huai Qin Fu, Xin Yu Zhang, Peng Fei Liu, Zheng Jiang, Hua Gui Yang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394724017

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide/carbon monoxide reduction reaction (CO(2)RR) has emerged as a prospective and appealing strategy to realize carbon neutrality for manufacturing sustainable chemical products. Developing highly active electrocatalysts and stable devices has been demonstrated as effective approach to enhancing the conversion efficiency of CO(2)RR. In order to rationally design electrocatalysts and devices, a comprehensive understanding of the intrinsic structure evolution within catalysts and micro&#8208;environment change around electrode interface, particularly under operation conditions, is indispensable. Synchrotron radiation has been recognized as a versatile characterization platform, garnering widespread attention owing to its high brightness, elevated flux, excellent directivity, strong polarization and exceptional stability. This review systematically introduces the applications of synchrotron radiation technologies classified by radiation sources with varying wavelengths in CO(2)RR. By virtue of in situ/operando synchrotron analytical techniques, we also summarize relevant dynamic evolution processes from electronic structure, atomic configuration, molecular adsorption, crystal lattice and devices, spanning scales from the angstrom to the micrometer. The merits and limitations of diverse synchrotron characterization techniques are summarized, and their applicable scenarios in CO(2)RR are further presented. On the basis of the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art fourth&#8208;generation synchrotron facilities, a perspective for further deeper understanding of the CO(2)RR process using synchrotron analytical techniques is proposed.</description>
      <author>Yi Xu, Bingbao Mei, Qiucheng Xu, Huai Qin Fu, Xin Yu Zhang, Peng Fei Liu, Zheng Jiang, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202404213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ/Operando Synchrotron Analytical Techniques for CO2/CO Reduction Reaction: From Atomic Scales to Mesoscales</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202404213</link>
      <description>Yi Xu, Bingbao Mei, Qiucheng Xu, Huai Qin Fu, Xin Yu Zhang, Peng Fei Liu, Zheng Jiang, Hua Gui Yang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394724108

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide/carbon monoxide reduction reaction (CO(2)RR) has emerged as a prospective and appealing strategy to realize carbon neutrality for manufacturing sustainable chemical products. Developing highly active electrocatalysts and stable devices has been demonstrated as effective approach to enhancing the conversion efficiency of CO(2)RR. In order to rationally design electrocatalysts and devices, a comprehensive understanding of the intrinsic structure evolution within catalysts and micro&#8208;environment change around electrode interface, particularly under operation conditions, is indispensable. Synchrotron radiation has been recognized as a versatile characterization platform, garnering widespread attention owing to its high brightness, elevated flux, excellent directivity, strong polarization and exceptional stability. This review systematically introduces the applications of synchrotron radiation technologies classified by radiation sources with varying wavelengths in CO(2)RR. By virtue of in situ/operando synchrotron analytical techniques, we also summarize relevant dynamic evolution processes from electronic structure, atomic configuration, molecular adsorption, crystal lattice and devices, spanning scales from the angstrom to the micrometer. The merits and limitations of diverse synchrotron characterization techniques are summarized, and their applicable scenarios in CO(2)RR are further presented. On the basis of the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art fourth&#8208;generation synchrotron facilities, a perspective for further deeper understanding of the CO(2)RR process using synchrotron analytical techniques is proposed.</description>
      <author>Yi Xu, Bingbao Mei, Qiucheng Xu, Huai Qin Fu, Xin Yu Zhang, Peng Fei Liu, Zheng Jiang, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202404213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the local microenvironment on porous Cu nanosheets for enhancing electrocatalytic CO2 reduction selectivity to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01198h</link>
      <description>Ying Zhang, Qianqian Wang, Qi Song, Kaibin Li, Yaxin Zhou, Chenchen Zhang, Junjun Mao, Lei Yang, Chengsi Pan, Jiawei Zhang, Yongfa Zhu, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626437

                Local microenvironments of the ECO2RR play an important role in tuning the adsorption energy of crucial intermediates, which helps enhance ECO2RR selectivity. Different types of organic polymers were used in...</description>
      <author>Ying Zhang, Qianqian Wang, Qi Song, Kaibin Li, Yaxin Zhou, Chenchen Zhang, Junjun Mao, Lei Yang, Chengsi Pan, Jiawei Zhang, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01198h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does innovation facilitate meeting the CO2 emission reduction targets of China: A non-linear approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aglobe.2024.100079</link>
      <description>Yifan Wang, Nadia Doytch, Mohamed Elheddad, &#24799;&#31185; &#26446;, Ms. Ha Thi Kim Chi -, Asia and the global economy. 4(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394747159

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifan Wang, Nadia Doytch, Mohamed Elheddad, &#24799;&#31185; &#26446;, Ms. Ha Thi Kim Chi -</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aglobe.2024.100079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forming multiple C - C bonds upon electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 by molecular transition metal macrocycles</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4394790705</link>
      <description>Shaojun Dong, HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394790705

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaojun Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4394790705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing electrochemical CO2 reduction: Insights from operando Attenuated total reflectance surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101515</link>
      <description>Sojung Park, Wooyul Kim, Current opinion in electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394617577

                Cu-based electrodes have been at the forefront of research on the electrochemical reduction of CO2 for several decades owing to their ability to generate multi-carbon products. Various innovative approaches, including alloying, doping, and surface modification, have been used to develop catalysts with superior selectivity, activity, and durability. Despite these developments, the commercialization of Cu-based electrocatalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction remains elusive. This review provides comprehensive insights into catalyst design and discusses methodologies using in situ surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy for the validation of newly designed catalysts, particularly those developed considering the information presented herein.</description>
      <author>Sojung Park, Wooyul Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Sn-based nanocomposites using waste polyethylene terephthalate (PET) for the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11144-024-02623-z</link>
      <description>Shweta Shukla, Ramasamy Karvembu, Reaction kinetics, mechanisms and catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394619586

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shweta Shukla, Ramasamy Karvembu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11144-024-02623-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large CO2 reduction and enhanced thermal performance of agro-forestry, construction and demolition waste based fly ash bricks for sustainable construction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-59012-8</link>
      <description>Siddharth Singh, Soumitra Maiti, Ravindra Singh Bisht, Soraj Kumar Panigrahi, Sameer Yadav, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394689932

                The exhaust gases in production of burnt clay bricks is responsible for greenhouse gases (GHGs) emission which increase the carbon footprint in the ecosystem. Here, we report carbon emission and thermal performance based evaluation of 8 ft. &#215; 9 ft. &#215; 8 ft. building. The bricks used in building construction are manufactured from fly ash, agro-forestry wastes, construction &amp; demolition wastes (C&amp;D), ground granulated blast furnace slag (GGBFS) using NaOH as activator in order to provide compressive strength in the range of 3-6 MPa with ambient curing at 30 &#176;C for 28 days. Life cycle analysis (LCA) reveals the total CO2 emission for fly ash and burnt clay bricks estimated to be 43.28 gCO2 and 290 gCO2 per brick, respectively. Considering the current scenario, by replacing 1-2% of brunt clay bricks with agro-forestry waste, C&amp;D waste based fly ash bricks can potentially reduce 0.5-1.5 million tons of CO2 emission annually. The embodied energy calculation shows fly ash based bricks consumes 10-15 times less energy as compared to burnt clay bricks. Thermal paremeters viz., U-value (0.5-1.2 W/m2K), thermal conductivity (0.4-0.5 W/mK) show adequate insulation of agro-forestry waste based fly ash bricks highlighting its importance of thermal comfort, CO2 reduction along with sustainable and eco-friendly construction practices.</description>
      <author>Siddharth Singh, Soumitra Maiti, Ravindra Singh Bisht, Soraj Kumar Panigrahi, Sameer Yadav</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-59012-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile construction of double vacancy modified BiOBr/g-C3N4@Bi heterojunctions for effective photochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.138290</link>
      <description>Ziqiong Wang, Rui Du, Feng Chen, Yan Wang, Wanting Li, Jun Long, Yanmei Zhou, Ruifeng Chong, Ling Zhang, Journal of molecular structure. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394618522

                Three different heterojunctions, BiOBr/g-C3N4, Bi/g-C3N4, and BiOBr/g-C3N4@Bi modified with carbon vacancies and/or oxygen vacancies, were first synthesized via a facile solvothermal approach by adjusting the ratio of Bi(NO3)3 &#183; 5H2O with ethylene glycol (EG). The as-prepared heterojunctions were characterized by various modern analytical instruments, and their visible-light photocatalytic performance for CO2 conversion was evaluated. Our findings demonstrate that the ternary photocatalyst BiOBr/g-C3N4@Bi exhibits better activity toward visible-light-driven CO2 reduction than pristine g-C3N4 and its binary counterparts without hole scavengers, and its maximum CO yield (7.4 &#956;mol &#183; h&#8722;1 &#183; g&#8722;1) is approximately four 4 times that of pure g-C3N4. This is attributed to the VO and VC defects, which enhance the photon absorption capacity. On the other hand, the g-C3N4 matrix exhibits strong interfacial interactions with BiOBr and metallic Bi, leading to an increase in the separation efficiency of the photoinduced carriers. In other words, the strong interfacial interactions among g-C3N4, BiOBr and metallic Bi, the vacancy defects VO and VC, and the metallic Bi particles cooperate to significantly improve the separation and transportation of the photoexcited charge carriers, thereby augmenting the CO2 photoreduction activity of the BiOBr/g-C3N4@Bi ternary heterojunction in the absence of a sacrificial agent. This approach based on facile solvothermal treatment has promising potential in fabricating highly efficient photocatalysts suitable for visible-light-driven CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Ziqiong Wang, Rui Du, Feng Chen, Yan Wang, Wanting Li, Jun Long, Yanmei Zhou, Ruifeng Chong, Ling Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.138290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Nanosheet Ch3coo(Bio) Topotactically Converted into Nanocomposite of Bismuth Clusters and Bi2o2co3 for Highly Efficient Electrocatalytic Reduction of Co2 to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4788681</link>
      <description>Huawang Zhao, Chao Deng, Chao Qi, Zhenhong Xue, Kai Cui, Xiaomin Wu, Guohua Jing, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394627725

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Huawang Zhao, Chao Deng, Chao Qi, Zhenhong Xue, Kai Cui, Xiaomin Wu, Guohua Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4788681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly coordinated Ni-N5 sites for efficient electrocatalytic CO2 reduction toward CO with faradaic efficiency exceeding 99%</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115495</link>
      <description>Fengwei Zhang, J. Li, Yuxin Chen, Han Zhang, Jingjing Li, Peihao Liu, Yuewen Mu, Wenyan Zan, Zhenyu Sun, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394720601

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengwei Zhang, J. Li, Yuxin Chen, Han Zhang, Jingjing Li, Peihao Liu, Yuewen Mu, Wenyan Zan, Zhenyu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of booster refrigeration system with eco-friendly working fluid CO2/halogenated alkene (HA) mixture for supermarket application around the world: Energy conservation, cost saving, and emissions reduction potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131244</link>
      <description>Baomin Dai, Tianhao Wu, Shengchun Liu, Peng Zhang, Jianing Zhang, Rao Fu, Dabiao Wang, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394746982

                For the scope of commercial supermarkets, the demand for energy efficiency improvement and environmentally-friendly working fluid of the refrigeration system is necessary. In this study, supermarket booster refrigeration system by using eco-friendly working fluid CO2/halogenated alkene (HA) mixture is proposed, and the mixture used in systems with two evaporation temperatures and operating modes affected by ambient temperature are studied. The energy efficiency, economic performance and emission reduction potential of the whole life cycle are conducted to compare with the pure CO2 booster refrigeration system. Furthermore, the influence of climate condition is discussed when used in 40 typical cities around the world. The results show the coefficient of performance (COP) of booster refrigeration system can be significantly improved by using CO2/HA mixtures. As the ambient temperature is 33 &#176;C, the CO2/R1234yf (93/7) operates with the maximum COP of 1.367, which is 11.59% higher than that of pure CO2. Using CO2/HA mixtures in the booster refrigeration system can significantly improve the exergy efficiency of system. Moreover, the system using CO2/HA mixtures has higher annual performance factor and lower life cycle cost (LCC) than pure CO2. LCC of the system using CO2/R1234yf (94/6) is the lowest, and the reduction rate is 3.06&#8764;5.59%. Meanwhile, the life cycle carbon emissions of systems in different climatic regions using CO2/R1234yf can be reduced by 2.39&#8764;5.21%. The booster refrigeration system adopting CO2/HA mixtures is a promising alternative solution for commercial supermarket refrigeration and energy-saving.</description>
      <author>Baomin Dai, Tianhao Wu, Shengchun Liu, Peng Zhang, Jianing Zhang, Rao Fu, Dabiao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Template-free synthesis of hierarchical graphitic carbon nitride (H-gC3N4) embedded with NiO for water splitting and CO2 reduction with the role of hole scavenger: A comparative investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108379</link>
      <description>Beenish Tahir, Muhammad Nawaz Tahir, Naveen Kumar, Mohammad Siraj, Amanullah Fatehmulla, Materials science in semiconductor processing. 178(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394718289

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Beenish Tahir, Muhammad Nawaz Tahir, Naveen Kumar, Mohammad Siraj, Amanullah Fatehmulla</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically coupled CH4 and CO2 consumption driven by microbial processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47445-8</link>
      <description>Yue Zheng, H. X. Wang, Yan Liu, Peiyu Liu, Baoli Zhu, Yanning Zheng, Jinhua Li, Ludmila Chistoserdova, Zhiyong Jason Ren, Feng Zhao, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394683918

                The chemical transformations of methane (CH4) and carbon dioxide (CO2) greenhouse gases typically have high energy barriers. Here we present an approach of strategic coupling of CH4 oxidation and CO2 reduction in a switched microbial process governed by redox cycling of iron minerals under temperate conditions. The presence of iron minerals leads to an obvious enhancement of carbon fixation, with the minerals acting as the electron acceptor for CH4 oxidation and the electron donor for CO2 reduction, facilitated by changes in the mineral structure. The electron flow between the two functionally active microbial consortia is tracked through electrochemistry, and the energy metabolism in these consortia is predicted at the genetic level. This study offers a promising strategy for the removal of CH4 and CO2 in the natural environment and proposes an engineering technique for the utilization of major greenhouse gases.</description>
      <author>Yue Zheng, H. X. Wang, Yan Liu, Peiyu Liu, Baoli Zhu, Yanning Zheng, Jinhua Li, Ludmila Chistoserdova, Zhiyong Jason Ren, Feng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47445-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the nonlinear effect of digital technology development on CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sd.2964</link>
      <description>Aleksy Kwili&#324;ski, Sustainable development. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394766226

                Abstract Digital technology, including advancements in artificial intelligence, the Internet of Things, and data analytics, has the potential to revolutionize tackling the problem of carbon dioxide emissions and achieving sustainable development. The paper aims at checking the nature of the impact of digital technology development on carbon dioxide reduction for the EU countries in 2013&#8211;2020. The study applies the following methods: entropy methods, panel&#8208;corrected standard error, and feasible generalized least squares. The digital technology development index enabled the classification of all the EU countries into two distinct groups: High Digital Technology Development and Moderate/Lower Digital Technology Development. The findings confirm that digital technology development has a significant impact on decreasing carbon dioxide emissions. In the first stage, the growth of digital technology causes a faster decrease in carbon dioxide emissions. However, beyond a certain threshold, the further improvement of digital technology results in diminishing marginal benefits of CO2 emissions reduction. Thus, the EU government should catalyze the extension of digital technologies among all sectors and levels. In addition, it requires enhancing digital literacy of the society and local authorities.</description>
      <author>Aleksy Kwili&#324;ski</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sd.2964</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Assessment of CO2 Co-benefits of Air Pollution Control Policies in Taiyuan's 14th Five-Year Plan].</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202304046</link>
      <description>Tianlin Xiao, Yun Shu, Hui Li, Han Wang, Junhong Li, Qin Yan, Wenjie Zhang, Hua Jiang, PubMed. 45(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394739599

                To quantitatively evaluate the co-benefits of air pollution reduction and carbon dioxide reduction of Taiyuan's 14th Five-Year Plan air pollution prevention and control policies, this study used the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei Greenhouse Gas-Air Pollution Interaction and Synergy Model (GAINS-JJJ) to simulate and evaluate the emission reduction potential and CO2 co-benefit of 13 air pollution control measures. The emission reductions of PM2.5, PM10, SO2, NOx, VOCs, and NH3 in 2025 were 1.8 (5%, compared with that in the baseline scenario), 2.5 (2%), 3.7 (16%), 20.0 (27%), 13.6 (15%), and 0.0 kt (0%), respectively. The reduction in CO2 emissions was 9.0 Mt (13%), whereas CH4 emissions increased by 203.3 kt (25% increase relative to that in the baseline scenario). SO2, NOx, and VOCs emission reductions derived from the power, industrial combustion, and solvent use sectors. CO2 reduction occurred mainly in the industrial combustion sector, and CH4 emission increased mainly due to the increase in coal mining activity. The highest synergistic CO2 reductions were achieved by restricting energy consumption in the high energy-consuming and high-emitting sectors; prohibiting new capacity in the steel, coke, cement, and flat glass industries; and replacing coal-fired power generation with renewable energy. Furthermore, the CO2 reduction co-benefit was highest for VOCs. In addition, this study suggests that promoting the policy of terminal electrification and simultaneously increasing the share of clean energy and the ability to consume renewable energy generation in the power sector are the keys to decreasing the emissions in Taiyuan.</description>
      <author>Tianlin Xiao, Yun Shu, Hui Li, Han Wang, Junhong Li, Qin Yan, Wenjie Zhang, Hua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202304046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial effects of green innovation and carbon emission reduction in China: Mediating role of infrastructure and informatization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scs.2024.105426</link>
      <description>Qiufeng Zhang, Junfeng Li, Qingshen Kong, Yi Xiao, Sustainable cities and society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394602875

                Green innovation (GI) plays a vital role in mitigating urban carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions and fostering sustainable development in China. This study examines the impact of GI on CO2 emissions, underscoring its significance for environmental sustainability. The analysis of data from 253 Chinese cities from 2010 to 2020 shows a transition in GI from a "multipoint" sporadic pattern to a "clustered" aggregation, indicative of significant polarization. Concurrently, a converging trend in the CO2 emissions kernel density curve reflects the initial success of carbon reduction initiatives, demonstrating a notable "high in the north and low in the south" spatial disparity. Critically, the findings reveal that GI induces significant spatial spillover effects, reducing CO2 emissions not only locally but also in adjacent areas. The mediation analysis reveals that the level of infrastructure development acts as a masking factor, suggesting that despite infrastructure expansion potentially escalating CO2 emissions, alignment with GI principles steers its environmental impact towards a positive direction. Additionally, informatization's modest mediating role suggests that its enhancement, driven by GI, further mitigates CO2 emissions through improved resource efficiency. These insights highlight the importance of integrating GI into urban policy frameworks, emphasizing its role in environmental management and CO2 emission reduction.</description>
      <author>Qiufeng Zhang, Junfeng Li, Qingshen Kong, Yi Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scs.2024.105426</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Carbon Reserves with Zero Processing of Chernozem in the Conditions of the Forest-Steppe Zone of the Middle Volga Region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0002188123070086</link>
      <description>L. V. Orlova, &#1053;. &#1052;. &#1058;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1055;&#1083;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Eugene Balashov, Sofia Sushko, &#1048;. &#1053;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Sergey Orlov, E. V. Kruglov, Agrohimi&#226;. None(7)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394752901

                The transition from conventional soil treatment technology to zero treatment technology contributes to an increase in carbon sequestration (Sorg) in the form of carbon dioxide (CO2) from the atmosphere into the soil and, as a result, a reduction in the adverse effects of the greenhouse effect on the ecological state of the environment. The effectiveness of the application of zero tillage is to a greater or lesser extent due to specific agro-climatic conditions, crop rotation systems, fertilizers and plant protection, soil quality and stability. The influence of zero tillage on the dynamics of sorghum reserves and greenhouse gas emissions (CO2, N2O, CH4) in the agro-climatic conditions of crop production (LLC &#8220;Orlovka AIC&#8221;, Samara region) was investigated. The study was conducted on agrochernozem heavy loam in September&#8211;November 2021 in conditions of an abnormally arid growing season and high summer temperatures. On plots with zero tillage, plant residues were received: 268&#8211;1720 kg &#1057;/ha, 3&#8211;66 kg N, 0.2&#8211;7.7 kg P and 12&#8211;44 kg K/ha. Based on the results obtained, recommendations are proposed for further improving the efficiency of zero tillage technology due, firstly, to reducing its adverse effect on the density of soil composition, and, secondly, taking into account the influence of underlying parent rocks and relief on water erosion of soil and redistribution of granulometric fractions of soil in the agricultural landscape, which will allow using this technology according to principles of adaptive landscape farming.</description>
      <author>L. V. Orlova, &#1053;. &#1052;. &#1058;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1055;&#1083;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Eugene Balashov, Sofia Sushko, &#1048;. &#1053;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Sergey Orlov, E. V. Kruglov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0002188123070086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Mineral Fertilizers in Forests with Respect to Forest Carbon Budget</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0002188123090107</link>
      <description>Liudmila Mukhortova, Olga Martynenko, &#1042;. &#1053;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1090;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, Viktor Karminov, Dmitry Schepaschenko, Agrohimi&#226;. None(9)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394753136

                Carbon sequestration and conservation is one of the important ecosystem functions of the forest. The task of modern science is to explore the possibilities of enhancing this function in order to counter the increase in the concentration of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere. Sustainable and climate smart forestry, in particular the use of mineral fertilizers, are an effective way to increase the productivity of forests and enhance their carbon-sequestration capacity. This review aims to summarize the experience of using mineral fertilizers in boreal and temperate forests. It is concluded that fertilization should be selective, and it is most effective in combination with other forest management operations. A significant effect is observed on sites with medium-productivity conditions on sites with with sufficient, but not excessive moisture, at the age of the maximum current increment of biomass or commercial wood (40&#8211;70 years for coniferous species). The most common (inexpensive, but effective) are N-fertilizers, but it is necessary to control the content of other nutrients, in particular P, K and B. We have collected and published a database of long-term experiments on the application of mineral fertilizers. Experiments have shown that the absorption of 1 t of CO2-eq. requires from 5.6 to 10.3 kg (on average 7.2) of nitrogen. The results of a fertilizer application project should be compared against the baseline (without fertilizer application), and the difference can be counted in emission reduction units.</description>
      <author>Liudmila Mukhortova, Olga Martynenko, &#1042;. &#1053;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1090;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, Viktor Karminov, Dmitry Schepaschenko</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0002188123090107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Hydrogen to Decarbonize the Brick and Tile Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52825/isec.v1i.1155</link>
      <description>Stefan Wallat, Wolfgang Adler, Ekhard Rimpel, Rachel Giese, No host. 1(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394605059

                For a significant reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions, it is assumed that hydrogen (H2) will substitute natural gas in the upcoming years. Therefore, the operational limitations of the existing burner technology must be evaluated when the hydrogen content in the fuel is increased. To investigate the H2-readiness of typical burners, numerical simulations and experimental investigations were carried out in test facilities and in an industrial tunnel kiln system in the brick and tile industry. The results of the examination of the existing conventional burner for natural gas and an additive manufactured dual-fuel burner for natural gas and H2 will be presented. The investigations carried out so far suggest that it is possible to use H2 in addition to natural gas as a fuel gas for tunnel kilns in the brick and tile industry. Ongoing investigations by means of simulations and measurements of the industrial tunnel kiln will provide further insights into this.</description>
      <author>Stefan Wallat, Wolfgang Adler, Ekhard Rimpel, Rachel Giese</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52825/isec.v1i.1155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designed imidazolium-based ionic liquids to capture carbon dioxide from natural gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.124708</link>
      <description>Raghda A. El-Nagar, A. Elaraby, M.I. Nessim, Alaa Ghanem, Journal of molecular liquids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394603561

                Natural gas is considered one of the most appealing fossil fuels in the world's energy supply nowadays, and it is primarily recognized as a clean energy source. However, the removal of pollutants from NG, particularly carbon dioxide (CO2), requires complex treatment strategies, significantly influencing its production. Consequently, the appealing properties of ionic liquids (ILs) make them interesting eco-friendly candidates for capturing CO2 from natural gas. In this work, a series of novel functionalized ILs (IL-Br, IL-BF4, and IL-PF6) were synthesized and characterized via a variety of analysis tools, including FT-IR, NMR, and thermal gravimetric analysis. Highly efficient capture of CO2 from natural gas was investigated at ambient temperature and was successfully achieved with the synthesized ILs. IL-PF6 recorded the highest capture CO2 capacity from the natural gas stream, which reached up to 94 % in only 5 min as a retention time. The experimental results revealed that each gram of IL-PF6, IL-BF4, and IL-Br could capture 2.02, 1.23, and 1.18 mmol of CO2, respectively. The used ILs were reused three times without any significant reduction in their capturing performance, which enhances their potential for eco-friendly and cost-saving issues. The CO2 capture efficiency of the used ILs was verified theoretically using the DFT method and Monte Carlo simulations (MCs). The quantum study matches with the experimental results, which confirmed the CO2 capture efficiency in the order of IL-PF6 &gt; IL-BF4 &gt; IL-Br.</description>
      <author>Raghda A. El-Nagar, A. Elaraby, M.I. Nessim, Alaa Ghanem</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.124708</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4337/9781802209204.ch09</link>
      <description>Todd A. Eisenstadt, Edward Elgar Publishing eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394622430

                The most effective way of managing climate change is through mitigation&#8212; anthropogenic intervention to reduce the anthropogenic forcing of the climate system. Mitigation is almost universally measured by emissions reduction of the main greenhouse gas, carbon dioxide (CO2), and, to a lesser extent, other gases. This entry looks at mitigation efforts, which have mostly taken the form of international treaties, such as the Paris Agreement and strategies to reduce greenhouse gas sources and emissions and enhance greenhouse gas sinks. While the Paris Agreement has fallen short in efforts to prompt nations to reduce emissions, international treaties have been a useful tool in climate policy implementation as they leverage "shame" tactics if nations fail to comply. So far, nation-states, companies, leaders, and individual citizens and consumers have failed to achieve the collective action needed to prioritize mitigation.</description>
      <author>Todd A. Eisenstadt</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4337/9781802209204.ch09</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biogas Purification through the use of a Microalgae-Bacterial System in Semi-Industrial High Rate Algal Ponds.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3791/65968</link>
      <description>Mariana Vega Blanes, Isaac J. P&#233;rez-Hermosillo, Arnold Ram&#237;rez Rueda, Armando Gonz&#225;lez S&#225;nchez, PubMed. None(205)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394764306

                In recent years, a number of technologies have emerged to purify biogas into biomethane. This purification entails a reduction in the concentration of polluting gases such as carbon dioxide and hydrogen sulfide to increase the content of methane. In this study, we used a microalgal cultivation technology to treat and purify biogas produced from organic waste from the swine industry to obtain ready-to-use biomethane. For cultivation and purification, two 22.2 m3 open-pond photobioreactors coupled with an absorption-desorption column system were set up in San Juan de los Lagos, Mexico. Several recirculation liquid/biogas ratios (L/G) were tested to obtain the highest removal efficiencies; other parameters, such as pH, dissolved oxygen (DO), temperature, and biomass growth, were measured. The most efficient L/Gs were 1.6 and 2.5, resulting in a treated biogas effluent with a composition of 6.8%vol and 6.6%vol in CO2, respectively, and removal efficiencies for H2S up to 98.9%, as well as maintaining O2 contamination values of less than 2%vol. We found that pH greatly determines CO2 removal, more so than L/G, during cultivation because of its participation in the photosynthetic process of microalgae and its ability to vary pH when solubilized due to its acidic nature. DO, and temperature oscillated as expected from the light-dark natural cycles of photosynthesis and the time of day, respectively. Biomass growth varied with CO2 and nutrient feeding as well as reactor harvesting; however, the trend remained primed for growth.</description>
      <author>Mariana Vega Blanes, Isaac J. P&#233;rez-Hermosillo, Arnold Ram&#237;rez Rueda, Armando Gonz&#225;lez S&#225;nchez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3791/65968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Abiotic Pathway for Phosphine Synthesis over Acidic Dust in Venus' Atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1089/ast.2023.0046</link>
      <description>Klaudia Mr&#225;zikov&#225;, Anton&#237;n Kn&#237;&#382;ek, Homa Saeidfirozeh, Luk&#225;&#353; Petera, Svatopluk Civi&#353;, Franz Saija, Giuseppe Cassone, Paul B. Rimmer, Martin Ferus, Astrobiology. 24(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394728345

                Recent ground-based observations of Venus have detected a single spectral feature consistent with phosphine (PH3) in the middle atmosphere, a gas which has been suggested as a biosignature on rocky planets. The presence of PH3 in the oxidized atmosphere of Venus has not yet been explained by any abiotic process. However, state-of-the-art experimental and theoretical research published in previous works demonstrated a photochemical origin of another potential biosignature&#8212;the hydride methane&#8212;from carbon dioxide over acidic mineral surfaces on Mars. The production of methane includes formation of the HC &#183; O radical. Our density functional theory (DFT) calculations predict an energetically plausible reaction network leading to PH3, involving either HC &#183; O or H&#183; radicals. We suggest that, similarly to the photochemical formation of methane over acidic minerals already discussed for Mars, the origin of PH3 in Venus' atmosphere could be explained by radical chemistry starting with the reaction of &#183;PO with HC&#183;O, the latter being produced by reduction of CO2 over acidic dust in upper atmospheric layers of Venus by ultraviolet radiation. HPO, H2P&#183;O, and H3P&#183;OH have been identified as key intermediate species in our model pathway for phosphine synthesis.</description>
      <author>Klaudia Mr&#225;zikov&#225;, Anton&#237;n Kn&#237;&#382;ek, Homa Saeidfirozeh, Luk&#225;&#353; Petera, Svatopluk Civi&#353;, Franz Saija, Giuseppe Cassone, Paul B. Rimmer, Martin Ferus</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1089/ast.2023.0046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of surfactant on dynamics and gas-liquid mass transfer for single carbon dioxide bubbles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142148</link>
      <description>Guangyan Hu, Kuixin Cui, Shengming Jin, Kun Liu, Taiyu Wang, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394790751

                In carbonation reaction, the impact of surfactants on the movement and mass transfer behavior of carbon dioxide bubbles were crucial for the production of high-quality silicon dioxide products. The study employed the Matlab image processing system to investigate the shapes, motion velocities, and rise path of single carbon dioxide bubbles within varying concentrations of cetyltrimethyl ammonium bromide (CTAB) solutions. This exploration aimed to elucidate the effect of CTAB on the movement and mass transfer coefficient (MTRC) of single carbon dioxide bubbles. Alterations in the CTAB solution concentration and bubble sizes significantly influenced the mass transfer and movement characteristics of single carbon dioxide bubbles. The conclusion was drawn through the computation of the MTRC of single carbon dioxide bubbles in deionized water and CTAB solutions: the addition of CTAB significantly reduced the mass transfer efficiency of carbon dioxide in deionized water, with the MTRC of CTAB solutions decreasing as the solution concentration increased. Utilizing the stagnant cap model, it can be concluded that CTAB's reduction of the MTRC of carbon dioxide was attributed to the high viscosity of the medium, low bubble velocity, stable flow conditions, and intensified adsorption degree of CTAB molecules at the gas-liquid interface. According to the significant periodic trajectories of single carbon dioxide bubbles in the stable range, the correlation between the trajectories of compressible bubbles in surfactant solution and mass transfer in liquid phase was established, and the previous method based on rigid sphere model was modified. The paper proposed the mechanism of CTAB's influence on single carbon dioxide bubbles, offering crucial theoretical insights into the industrial application of surfactants in the carbonation process for producing silicon dioxide.</description>
      <author>Guangyan Hu, Kuixin Cui, Shengming Jin, Kun Liu, Taiyu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization Technique on Dynamics of Carbon Dioxide to Controlling Global Warming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4208405/v1</link>
      <description>Muhammad Abid, Mohsan Hassan, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394611144

                Abstract Background Carbon dioxide is increasing in the atmosphere day by day due to diverse sources increasing global warming. Meeting the energy demands of the expanding human population, large-scale carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) is produced. Effective reduction of CO 2 emissions from the energy sector and others through optimization is required to reduce global warming. Model: This paper presents a mathematical model that captures the dynamic relationship between carbon dioxide levels in the atmosphere, human population dynamics, energy use, and the progression of global warming as distinct sections. Real-time data from these sections are utilized to adjust model parameters. Methodology: Firstly, the stability analysis of the proposed model is examined to determine whether solutions remain bounded or converge to specific states on the equilibrium points. Secondly, sensitivity analysis of the model is investigated and determines the behavior of the dynamic system on changes in parameters. Lastly, the optimization technique is applied to the model to reduce global warming by optimizing the level of CO 2 emission from the energy sector. Results Through optimization, results show that global warming is majorly reduced when the CO 2 emission from the energy sector is reduced. Novelty: The thorough analysis and validation of the proposed model offer valuable insights for devising effective strategies to mitigate climate change.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Abid, Mohsan Hassan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4208405/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;NH&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt; &amp;lt;sub&amp;gt; &amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; &amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;and H&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt; &amp;lt;sub&amp;gt; &amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; &amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;Impact on Combustion and Emission Characteristics of i-C&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt; &amp;lt;sub&amp;gt; &amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;8&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; &amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;H&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt; &amp;lt;sub&amp;gt; &amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;18&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; &amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;Flame under Premixed and Diffusion Conditions&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-01-2370</link>
      <description>M. Zuhaib Akram, Haroon Rashid, Yangbo Deng, Muhammad Aziz, Qiao Zhu, M. Waqar Akram, SAE technical papers on CD-ROM/SAE technical paper series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394617166

                &lt;div class="section abstract"&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;Soot and carbon dioxide released from internal combustion engines became the key issues when using fossil fuels. Ammonia and hydrogen having zero-carbon species can reduce carbon-related emissions and enhance the reliance on renewable fuels. A comparative study of ammonia and hydrogen impact on combustion and emission characteristics of iso-octane flame was performed under different combustion conditions. Arrhenius equation, soot surface reactions, and modified kinetic mechanism were used to study the flame growth, soot nucleation, and surface growth rates. The results show that hydrogen increased the temperature about 20.74 K and 59.30 K, whereas ammonia reduced it about 82.17 K and 66.03 K at premixed and counterflow conditions, respectively. The flame speed of iso-octane was increased 43.83 cm/s by hydrogen and decreased 34.36 cm/s by ammonia. A reduction in CH&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O caused a reduction in CO and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions. Ammonia impact on CO reduction was stronger than hydrogen under premixed and counterflow flame conditions. In contrast, a higher reduction in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emission was noticed when adding hydrogen instead of ammonia adopting counterflow flame conditions. The diluted fuel reduced the fraction of small-chain hydrocarbon species in iso-octane combustion, resulting in a reduction of the soot precursors, soot particle number density, and soot volume fractions. NO emission decreased in premixed flame and increased in counterflow flame when adding hydrogen. Ammonia enhanced NO emissions, and its impact was greater on counterflow flame rather than premixed combustion. The current study suggested that ammonia dilution in iso-octane should be &#8804; 50% because a higher reduction in soot and carbon dioxide emissions can be achieved with a small reduction in burning velocity and increment in NO emission. However, the hydrogen contents &amp;gt; 50% in iso-octane fuel significantly reduced the emission and increased the burning velocity.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <author>M. Zuhaib Akram, Haroon Rashid, Yangbo Deng, Muhammad Aziz, Qiao Zhu, M. Waqar Akram</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-01-2370</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low oxidation state and hydrido group 2 complexes: synthesis and applications in the activation of gaseous substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00097h</link>
      <description>Matthew J. Evans, Cameron Jones, Chemical Society reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394696992

                Numerous industrial processes utilise gaseous chemical feedstocks to produce useful chemical products. Atmospheric and other small molecule gases, including anthropogenic waste products (e.g. carbon dioxide), can be viewed as sustainable building blocks to access value-added chemical commodities and materials. While transition metal complexes have been well documented in the reduction and transformation of these substrates, molecular complexes of the terrestrially abundant alkaline earth metals have also demonstrated promise with remarkable reactivity reported towards an array of industrially relevant gases over the past two decades. This review covers low oxidation state and hydrido group 2 complexes and their role in the reduction and transformation of a selection of important gaseous substrates towards value-added chemical products.</description>
      <author>Matthew J. Evans, Cameron Jones</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00097h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal dispatching of multi-community electric-thermal integrated energy systems considering wind and solar uncertainties based on hydraulic stability and energy sharing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118335</link>
      <description>Wenjia Ji, Shu-Guang Guo, Hongbin Sun, Deyou Liu, Energy conversion and management. 308(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394789468

                The multi-community integrated energy system holds significant potential in facilitating the decarbonization of energy distribution in the context of carbon neutrality. However, the literature review reveals the gaps in the comprehensive examination of hybrid energy sharing and hydraulic-thermal dynamic processes within the system, which can compromise the security and stability of the energy supply and lead to insufficient dispatch. To address these challenges, this research proposes a bi-level optimization framework for the day-ahead dispatch of the multi-community integrated energy system, novelly taking hydraulic stability and economic efficiency as optimization objectives. Hybrid energy sharing is considered as one of the processes of system operation rather than merely a constraint. To accurately capture the hydraulic and thermal dynamic characteristics, a dynamic-correction quasi-dynamic model is proposed for hydraulic-thermal coupling calculation in the heating networks. Additionally, Latin hypercube sampling and backward reduction are applied to address the uncertainty of renewable energy. The results show that the proposed optimization framework can achieve a 22.19 % reduction in operation costs and a 42.35 % reduction in carbon dioxide emissions. Furthermore, the maximum hydraulic steady time is significantly reduced from 360.02 s to 136.39 s, indicating effective suppression of extreme hydraulic instability conditions. In conclusion, the proposed optimization model offers a viable solution to enhance the economic efficiency of the multi-community integrated energy system and mitigate hydraulic instability in heat transmission.</description>
      <author>Wenjia Ji, Shu-Guang Guo, Hongbin Sun, Deyou Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Coal Control and Carbon Reduction Path in Henan Province's Power Industry Under the Carbon Peak and Neutralization Target: A Medium- and Long-term Study].</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202303086</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Yu Meng, Wei Zhang, Dong Cao, Zhao Jiancheng, Bo Li, Ying-Lan Xue, Hongqiang Jiang, PubMed. 45(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394740414

                Achieving peak carbon dioxide emissions and accelerating decarbonization progress in the power industry is of paramount significance to Henan Province's objective of achieving carbon peak and neutrality. In this study, the Carbon Emission-Energy Integrated Model (iCEM) was employed to conduct scenario studies on the coal reduction and carbon reduction paths under the "dual-carbon" goal of Henan's power industry. The results indicated that, by considering measures such as optimizing the power source structure and technological progress, Henan Province's power industry carbon emissions will reach their peak between 2028-2033, with coal consumption in the power industry continuing to grow during the "14th Five-Year Plan" period. With a peak range between 2027-2031, the peak value increased by 1881, 1592, and 11.48 million tce, respectively, compared with that in 2020. To control coal in Henan Province under the constraint of carbon peak goals, it is proposed to develop clean energy sources such as wind and solar power, use more low-carbon or zero-carbon heat sources, increase the proportion of external electricity supply, and enhance energy-saving transformation in coal-fired power plants. Accelerating the elimination of backward units and energy-saving transformation of existing units, accelerating non-fossil energy development, advanced planning for external electricity supply, improving market mechanisms for the exit of coal-fired power plants and peak regulation, increasing system flexibility, and accelerating external policies to ensure clean energy security are effective paths for controlling coal and reducing carbon emissions in Henan's power industry. Additionally, inland nuclear power layout is one of the crucial paths to alleviate coal control pressure in Henan Province and achieve "dual-carbon" goals during the carbon-neutral stage. Therefore, it is imperative to conduct research on demonstrations in advance. Henan Province is highly dependent on energy from other provinces, and the power supply and demand situation in Henan Province will become increasingly tense in the future. It is necessary to support Henan Province from the State Grid and coordinate the construction of inter-provincial and inter-regional power transmission channels.</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Yu Meng, Wei Zhang, Dong Cao, Zhao Jiancheng, Bo Li, Ying-Lan Xue, Hongqiang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202303086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese organic rice transition spatial econometrics empirical analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0297784</link>
      <description>Zhuo Luo, Yisong Huang, PloS one. 19(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394710949

                Based on the integrated model of Super-SBM model, spatial Durbin model (SDM) and Grey neural network model, this paper analyzes the panel data of various provinces in China from multiple angles and dimensions. It was found that there were significant differences in eco-efficiency between organic rice production and conventional rice production. The response of organic rice to climate change, the spatial distribution of ecological and economic benefits and the impact on carbon emission were analyzed. The results showed that organic rice planting not only had higher economic benefits, but also showed a rising trend of ecological benefits and a positive feedback effect. This finding highlights the importance of organic rice farming in reducing carbon emissions. Organic rice farming effectively reduces greenhouse gas emissions, especially carbon dioxide and methane, by improving soil management and reducing the use of fertilizers and pesticides. This has important implications for mitigating climate change and promoting soil health and biodiversity. With the acceleration of urbanization, the increase of organic rice planting area shows the trend of organic rice gradually replacing traditional rice cultivation, further highlighting the potential of organic agriculture in emission reduction, environmental protection and sustainable agricultural production. To this end, it is recommended that the Government implement a diversified support strategy to encourage technological innovation, provide guidance and training, and raise public awareness and demand for organic products. At the same time, private sector participation is stimulated to support the development of organic rice cultivation through a public-private partnership model. Through these measures, further promote organic rice cultivation, achieve the dual goals of economic benefits and environmental benefits, and effectively promote the realization of double carbon emission reduction targets.</description>
      <author>Zhuo Luo, Yisong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0297784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic and environmental performance of microalgal energy products &#8211; A case study exploring circular bioeconomy principles applied to recycled anaerobic digester waste flows</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120802</link>
      <description>Jin Wook Ro, Cody Yothers, Alissa Kendall, Annaliese K. Franz, Ruihong Zhang, Journal of environmental management. 358(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394632276

                This study quantifies the financial and environmental impacts of a microalgal bioenergy system that attempts to maximize circular flows by recovering and reusing the carbon, nutrients, and water within the system. The system produces microalgal biomass using liquid digestate of an anaerobic digester that processes 45 metric tons of food waste and generates 28.6 m3 of permeate daily in California, and three energy production scenarios from the biomass are considered: producing biodiesel, electricity, and both. In all scenarios, the resulting energy products delivered only modest reductions in environmental impacts as measured by carbon dioxide equivalent emissions. The carbon intensities (CIs) of biodiesel from this study were 91.0 gCO2e/MJ and 93.3 gCO2e/MJ, which were lower than 94.71 gCO2e/MJ of conventional petroleum diesel, and the CI of electricity from this study was 70.6 gCO2e/MJ, lower than the average electricity grid CI in California (82.92 gCO2e/MJ). The economic analysis results show that generating electricity alone can be profitable, while biodiesel produced via this system is not cost competitive with conventional diesel due to high capital expenses. Thus, generating electricity in lieu of biodiesel appears to be a better option to maximize the use of waste flows and supply lower-carbon energy.</description>
      <author>Jin Wook Ro, Cody Yothers, Alissa Kendall, Annaliese K. Franz, Ruihong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A life cycle analysis of the environmental impact of procurement, waste and water in the dental practice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41415-024-7239-5</link>
      <description>Peddengatagari Suresh, John Crotty, Sonja Tesanovic, Othman Alaweed, Suzanne Doyle, Mikra Kiandee, Emily Hayes, Vanessa Umeh, Bita Khalilinejad, Brett Duane, British dental journal. 236(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394747742

                Background Health care is a significant contributor to climate change. Global pressure for a change towards a more sustainable way of providing dental health care has resulted in the creation of the Green Impact Toolkit, which is comprised of a list of suggested changes that dental practices can make to become more sustainable in a number of categories, such as procurement, waste and water.Aims To compare the effectiveness of changes suggested by the Green Impact Toolkit.Materials and methods A comparative life cycle assessment (LCA) was conducted using the Ecoinvent database v3.8 and these data were processed using OpenLCA v1.10.3 software.Results The carbon footprint per patient was significantly reduced after the recommendations were implemented. For instance, using water from a rainwater collection tank instead of the mains supply saved 30 g CO2eq (carbon dioxide equivalents) per patient, a 90% reduction in carbon footprint.Discussion This comparative LCA identified some effective changes which can be easily made by a dental practice. Nevertheless, some actions require some initial financial investment and may be difficult to implement in a busy modern dental practice setting.Conclusion The findings from this study can be used to guide dental practices to making choices which are more sustainable and eco-friendly in the future.</description>
      <author>Peddengatagari Suresh, John Crotty, Sonja Tesanovic, Othman Alaweed, Suzanne Doyle, Mikra Kiandee, Emily Hayes, Vanessa Umeh, Bita Khalilinejad, Brett Duane</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41415-024-7239-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial-temporal differentiation and influencing factors of carbon emission trajectory in Chinese cities - A case study of 247 prefecture-level cities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.172325</link>
      <description>Xin Yang, Ke Jin, Zhenfeng Duan, Yuhe Gao, Yun Sun, Chao Gao, Science of the total environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394690056

                Cities, where human energy activities and greenhouse gas emissions are concentrated, contribute significantly to alleviating the impacts of global climate change. Utilizing the China Carbon Emissions Accounting Database (CEADs) to provide carbon dioxide emission inventories for urban areas in China at the prefecture level, this study closely examines the historical evolution trajectories of carbon emissions across 247 urban units from 2005 to 2019. The logarithmic cubic function model was employed to simulate these trajectories, evaluating urban emission peaks and classifying the different carbon emission trajectories. Further, the Geographical and Temporal Weighted Regression model was employed to explore spatiotemporal traits and essential variables that impact the variations in carbon emissions among four identified trajectory types. Our results showed that Chinese urban carbon emission trajectories can be classified into four categories: a) peaking emissions, b) fluctuating growth, c) continuous growth, and d) passive decline. Specifically, 43 cities, primarily in North China, proactively attained their emission peak post-2010, driven by the reduction in secondary industry and energy intensity. 90 cities, largely industrial hubs in the southeast coast and inland, reached an emission plateau around 2015, exhibiting fluctuating growth due to dependencies on secondary industries. 101 cities, predominantly located in western and central regions, demonstrated a clear upward trend in carbon emissions, propelled by rapid urbanization and heavy industry-oriented economic development. Lastly, 13 cities, typically in the northeastern and southwestern regions, experienced a passive decline in carbon emissions, attributable to resource depletion or economic downturns. It is evident that China's city-level carbon peaking has demonstrated some effectiveness, yet considerable progress is still required.</description>
      <author>Xin Yang, Ke Jin, Zhenfeng Duan, Yuhe Gao, Yun Sun, Chao Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.172325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The carbon footprint of as-needed budesonide-formoterol in mild asthma: a post hoc analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.01705-2023</link>
      <description>Lee Hatter, Mark Holliday, Allie Eathorne, Pepa Bruce, Ian Pavord, Helen K Reddel, Robert J. Hancox, Alberto Papi, Mark Weatherall, Richard Beasley, European respiratory journal/&#152;The &#156;European respiratory journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394766472

                Introduction The use of pressurised metered-dose inhalers (pMDIs) and asthma exacerbations necessitating healthcare reviews contribute substantially to the global carbon footprint of healthcare. It is possible that a reduction in carbon footprint could be achieved by switching patients with mild asthma from salbutamol pMDI reliever therapy to inhaled corticosteroid-formoterol dry powder inhaler (DPI) reliever therapy, as recommended by the Global Initiative for Asthma (GINA). Methods This post hoc analysis included all 668 adult participants in the Novel START trial, who were randomised 1:1:1 to treatment with: as-needed budesonide-formoterol DPI, as-needed salbutamol pMDI, or maintenance budesonide DPI plus as-needed salbutamol pMDI. The primary outcome was carbon footprint of asthma management, expressed as kilograms of carbon dioxide equivalent emissions (kgCO 2 e), per person year. Secondary outcomes explored the effect of baseline symptom control and adherence (maintenance budesonide DPI arm only) on carbon footprint. Results As-needed budesonide-formoterol DPI was associated with 95.8% and 93.6% lower carbon footprint compared with as-needed salbutamol pMDI (least squares mean 1.1 versus 26.2 kgCO 2 e; difference &#8722;25.0, 95% CI &#8722;29.7 to &#8722;20.4; p&lt;0.001) and maintenance budesonide DPI plus as-needed salbutamol pMDI (least squares mean 1.1 versus 17.3 kgCO 2 e; difference &#8722;16.2, 95% CI &#8722;20.9 to &#8722;11.6; p&lt;0.001), respectively. There was no statistically significant evidence that treatment differences in carbon footprint depended on baseline symptom control or adherence in the maintenance budesonide DPI arm. Conclusions The as-needed budesonide-formoterol DPI treatment option was associated with a markedly lower carbon footprint than as-needed salbutamol pMDI and maintenance budesonide DPI plus as-needed salbutamol pMDI.</description>
      <author>Lee Hatter, Mark Holliday, Allie Eathorne, Pepa Bruce, Ian Pavord, Helen K Reddel, Robert J. Hancox, Alberto Papi, Mark Weatherall, Richard Beasley</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.01705-2023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilization of the simulated flue gas on the cultivation of Chlorella protothecoides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2104.08334</link>
      <description>Cem &#214;zel, Muharrem Erdem Bo&#287;o&#231;lu, Ceren Ke&#231;eciler, Ecem Kaplan, Sevil Y&#252;cel, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4394669303

                In recent years, fossil-based fuels have been used to supply the energy needs of the world. Fossil-based fuels induce accumulation of the atmospheric CO2 which causes global warming. One of CO2 source is flue gas emission from the power plant. The microalgae have been considered excellent biological materials for reduction CO2 with ability to photosynthesis. In this study, air, 10% CO2, 15% CO2 and simulated flue gas (containing 15% CO2) feed were used to observe effect CO2 concentration and flue gas on cell growth and lipid content of Chlorella protothecoides. The highest dry cell weight (1,5 g/L) and lipid content (45%) values were obtained with 15% CO2 feed while the highest growth rate (1,10), biomass productivity (0,125 g/L/day), and lipid weight (0,63 g/g) were observed in 10% CO2 feed. Cultures fed with flue gas did not inhibited C. protothecoides growth and showed similar results with those fed with 15% CO2 gas in terms of growth rate, dry cell weight, biomass productivity and lipid content. These results showed that C. protothecoides has great potential for reducing CO2 emission from flue gas.</description>
      <author>Cem &#214;zel, Muharrem Erdem Bo&#287;o&#231;lu, Ceren Ke&#231;eciler, Ecem Kaplan, Sevil Y&#252;cel</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2104.08334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diving deep into solid oxide-based CO2 electrolysis: Operando insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101514</link>
      <description>Vipin Kamboj, Soham Raychowdhury, Chinmoy Ranjan, Current opinion in electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394618072

                CO2 reduction to fuels using solid oxide electrodes is a promising approach due to high faradaic and energy efficiencies. CO2 reducing electrodes (cathodes) form the central challenge in enabling solid oxide technology for CO2 electrolysis. Typical cathodes can comprise of both oxides such as perovskites and metals such as Ni and Fe. Efforts at improving the activity, selectivity and stability of the electrodes continues. Operando methods provide direct access to active sites during the reaction and provide valuable information such as the identity of catalytic material, nature of reaction intermediates, oxidation state of catalytic ions etc. These methods have created a deeper mechanistic understanding, unravelled new performance indicators, and increasingly enabling a deep diagnostic based systematic development of catalysts and processes. This study summarises and analyses data from operando approaches to develop an understanding of CO2 reduction mechanism on certain commonly studied electrodes. In particular, this review discusses CO2 reduction mechanism on electrodes such as Ni-YSZ, CeO2-x and perovskites such as La1-xSrxFeOy. The CO2 reduction on these surfaces essentially progresses on an oxide terminated surface via formation of a three coordinated carbon (carbonate type) intermediate formed at oxygen defect sites. Metal electrodes such as Ni-YSZ were found to oxidize in situ in presence of CO2 and the reaction proceeded via oxide mediated mechanism. In electrodes such as La1-x SrxFeOy, exsolution of metals was essentially found to have no direct impact on CO2 electrolysis. In the context of catalyst coking on CeOx electrodes, new descriptors, such as the number of reduced sites (Ce3+), and the existence of metal carbonyl species "Ce3+ -- CO" have emerged.</description>
      <author>Vipin Kamboj, Soham Raychowdhury, Chinmoy Ranjan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transfer Payments and Carbon Reduction in China: The Effect of the National Comprehensive Demonstration City of Energy Saving and Emission Reduction Fiscal Policy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131253</link>
      <description>Kaike Wang, Rong Yin, He Qiang, Shuhong Wang, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394600139

                To address climate change and achieve high-quality economic development, China began implementing the Comprehensive Demonstration City of Energy Saving and Emission Reduction Fiscal Policy (ESERFP) in 2011. This policy relies on special transfer payments to increase the integration of various energy conservation and emission reduction fiscal policies, thereby accelerating institutional and mechanism innovation, actively promoting economic structure adjustment and development mode transformation, and achieving energy conservation and emission reduction goals in various regions. This study uses a multi-period difference-in-difference (DID) model to estimate the ESERFP's CO2 emission reduction effect and paths. The findings demonstrate the following: (1) The ESERFP has lessened the CO2 emission intensity of the demonstration city and effectively played a role in reducing CO2 emissions. (2) Mechanism analysis demonstrates that the ESERFP has significantly improved the green travel level of residents in pilot cities and can also reduce cities' total energy consumption. Therefore, the ESERFP can effectively suppress CO2 emissions by improving transportation systems and optimizing energy consumption structures. (3) Further analysis shows that the ESERFP can reduce the CO2 emission scale of the demonstration cities and effectively promote the increase of actual per capita gross domestic product in pilot cities, bringing economic dividends and thus achieving a "win-win" situation of environmental protection and economic growth. (4) Heterogeneity analysis demonstrates that the CO2 emission reduction effect is more significant in non-old industrial-based cities, non-resource-based cities, and urban agglomerations. This study not only evaluates the CO2 reduction effect of the demonstration city but also provides reference significance for the improvement of subsequent environmental regulations. In addition, clarifying the implementation effect of the ESERFP can help alleviate ecological and environmental problems in the process of urban economic development in China and achieve the sustainable development goal of green transformation.</description>
      <author>Kaike Wang, Rong Yin, He Qiang, Shuhong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by the SnS| PTFE| Pt Surface in an Aqueous Imidazole Medium: Catalysis and Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03142</link>
      <description>Md. Tarikul Islam, Mohammad Imran Hossain, Kyoko Aoki, Yuki Nagao, Md. Mahmudul Hasan, Mostafizur Rahaman, Ali Aldalbahi, Mohammad A. Hasnat, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394602307

                Development of a novel SnS| PTFE| Pt electrode as an efficient catalyst for electrochemical CO2 reduction to formate in an aqueous alkaline imidazole medium is reported in this paper. The electrode was prepared through the incorporation of polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) with SnS and modification of the Pt surface by SnS/PTFE. The electrode facilitated a first-order CO2 reduction at &#8722;1.1 V vs Ag/AgCl (saturated KCl) via a diffusion-controlled pathway with a cathodic electron transfer coefficient (&#945;) of 0.22 and two-electron transfer kinetics in two steps, where the first electron transfer step determined the reaction rate. The SnS| PTFE| Pt electrode surface exhibited well-defined cyclic voltammograms (CVs) for CO2 reduction in comparison to GCE, Au, Pd, and graphite-modified electrodes utilizing the same catalyst, indicating superior catalytic efficiency and its conduciveness to kinetic investigations. Such performance indicates that the SnS| PTFE| Pt electrode would be a promising alternative for CO2 reduction in the context of renewable energy generation.</description>
      <author>Md. Tarikul Islam, Mohammad Imran Hossain, Kyoko Aoki, Yuki Nagao, Md. Mahmudul Hasan, Mostafizur Rahaman, Ali Aldalbahi, Mohammad A. Hasnat</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous mitigation of greenhouse gases and ammonia by boric acid during composting: Emission reduction potentials and microbial mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142139</link>
      <description>Shunxi Zhou, Yifeng He, Minna Jiao, Qian Li, Xiuna Ren, Mukesh Kumar Awasthi, Ronghua Li, Zengqiang Zhang, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394620758

                Greenhouse gases (GHGs) and ammonia (NH3) are the main gas pollutants emitted during composting. This study used boric acid (H3BO3) as an additive to simultaneously mitigate GHG and NH3 emissions during composting and produce boron-rich organic fertilizer. The results showed that high dose of boric acid (1425 mg/kg) simultaneously reduced carbon dioxide (16.4%), methane (97.0%), nitrous oxide (91.7%), and NH3 (27.1%) emissions in the composting process, resulting in the lowest carbon and nitrogen losses and global warming potential. However, low doses of boric acid (75 and 375 mg/kg) promoted nitrous oxide emissions and had limited emission reduction effects on other gases. Pearson correlation analysis showed that Corynebacterium, Planococcus, norank_f_MWH-CFBk5, Ruminofilibacter, norank_o_Actinomarinales and Truepera are key bacterial genera strongly associated with gas emissions. The results of principal co-ordinates analysis, network analysis, and structural equation modeling collectively indicated that the high dose of boric acid mitigates GHG and NH3 emissions by undergoing chemical reactions, altering physicochemical properties, and reshaping bacterial communities. This study provides an innovative approach for synchronously mitigating GHG and NH3 emissions and producing high value-added boron-rich organic fertilizer.</description>
      <author>Shunxi Zhou, Yifeng He, Minna Jiao, Qian Li, Xiuna Ren, Mukesh Kumar Awasthi, Ronghua Li, Zengqiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influencing factors and spatiotemporal heterogeneity of livestock greenhouse gas emission: Evidence from the Yellow River Basin of China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120788</link>
      <description>Xiao Zhang, Shuhui Sun, Shunbo Yao, Journal of environmental management. 358(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394719502

                Livestock is one of major sources of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions in China. Clarifying spatiotemporal characteristics of GHG emissions from livestock and exploring influencing factors can provide reference for grasping regional changes of GHG emission and formulate strategies of carbon reduction for livestock industry. However, existing literatures considered both spatial and temporal impacts and dynamic evolution trend of these factors seldomly. This paper used the life cycle assessment (LCA) method to estimate GHG emissions of livestock in 114 cities of the YRB from 2000 to 2021. On this basis, spatiotemporal heterogeneity of influencing factors was analyzed by using geographically and temporally weighted regression (GTWR) model. Finally, future evolution trend of GHG emissions from livestock was predicted by combining traditional and spatial Markov chain. Four main results were listed as follows. Firstly, GHG emission in the life cycle of livestock industry increased from &#215;&#215;carbon dioxide equivalent (CO2e) in 2000 to 77.568 Mt CO2e in 2021. Secondly, structure of livestock industry, labor flow and mechanization were vital factors that led to increase of GHG emissions from livestock. Positive effects of labor flow and mechanization were increasing year by year, while negative effect of urbanization and positive effect of economic development were decreasing year by year. Markov chain analysis shown that probability of keeping high level of GHG emissions of livestock in the YRB unchanged were 96% (T = 1) and 90% (T = 5), and there also existed a Matthew effect. In addition, probability of level transfer of GHG emission in urban livestock was spatially dependent. Government should formulate strategies for livestock development and optimize low-carbon transformation of energy structure for livestock and poultry husbandry based on local conditions and key driving factors in the future. Meanwhile, boundaries of administrative divisions should be broken to promote reduction of GHG emissions in livestock comprehensively.</description>
      <author>Xiao Zhang, Shuhui Sun, Shunbo Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peculiarities of CH4 and CO2 Distribution in Sediments of the Arctic Seas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0016752523020085</link>
      <description>V. S. Sevastyanov, V. Yu. Fedulova, &#1054;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1079;&#1085;&#1077;&#1094;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, S. G. Naimushin, N. V. Dushenko, V. S. Fedulov, &#1040;. &#1055;. &#1050;&#1088;&#1080;&#1074;&#1077;&#1085;&#1100;&#1082;&#1086;, A. I. Malova, E. A. Tkachenko, Geohimi&#226;. 68(2)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394784052

                The distribution of the concentrations of CH4 and CO2 and other gases in the sediments of the Kara, Laptev and East Siberian seas was studied. A correlation was found between CH4 and CO2 in most sediment cores. The correlation coefficient R for the sediments of the Kara Sea ranges from 0.58 to 0.97 and does not depend on the gas distribution with depth. Methanogenesis in marine sediments is presumably associated with sulfate reduction, and hydrogenotrophic methanogenesis leads to an increase in CH4 concentration against the background of high CO2 concentration. The high concentration of dimethyl sulfide in the sediments indicates the simultaneous formation of CH4 and CO2 through methylotrophic methanogenesis with the participation of CH3SCH3. In the upper layers of the sediment, opposite trends in the CH4 and CO2 distribution can be observed. The fact that the correlation coefficients between CH4 and CO2 gases in the sediments of the Laptev Sea acquire both negative and positive values is probably related to the fact that gas formation processes in the upper layers of the sediment captured by short columns differ from those of deep layers.</description>
      <author>V. S. Sevastyanov, V. Yu. Fedulova, &#1054;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1079;&#1085;&#1077;&#1094;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, S. G. Naimushin, N. V. Dushenko, V. S. Fedulov, &#1040;. &#1055;. &#1050;&#1088;&#1080;&#1074;&#1077;&#1085;&#1100;&#1082;&#1086;, A. I. Malova, E. A. Tkachenko</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0016752523020085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Environmental Benefits of Pollution and Carbon Reduction by Bus Fleet Electrification in Zhengzhou].</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202304156</link>
      <description>Chao Zou, Yanan Wang, Lin Wu, Jinghan He, Jingwei Ni, Hongjun Mao, PubMed. 45(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394760107

                Electrification of bus fleets is an effective approach to reducing transportation-related pollution and carbon emissions. Evaluating the impact of electrification on existing bus fleets can provide valuable insights for promoting full electrification of public transportation in large cities. Utilizing the fuel life cycle method, we analyzed the CO2 and pollutant emissions of Zhengzhou's bus fleet before and after electrification and evaluated emissions under different electrification scenarios. Our results indicated that after electrification, the fuel life cycle CO2 and PM2.5 emissions increased by 32.6% and 42.6%, respectively, whereas CO, NOx, and VOC emissions decreased by 28%, 34%, and 25%, respectively. Optimizing the power generation structure is a critical factor in reducing CO2 and PM2.5 emissions during the electrification process. The best scenario for comprehensive electrification and power generation structure optimization could result in a 38.7% reduction in CO2, as well as reductions of 80.1% in CO, 84.4% in NOx, 92.2% in VOC, and 30.2% in PM2.5. Prioritizing electrification on long-distance routes is recommended during the replacement process. Additionally, replacing plug-in hybrid natural gas vehicles with pure electric vehicles has both advantages and disadvantages in terms of emission reduction. Achieving pollution reduction and carbon synergies requires advancing fleet replacement and power structure adjustments simultaneously.</description>
      <author>Chao Zou, Yanan Wang, Lin Wu, Jinghan He, Jingwei Ni, Hongjun Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202304156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relationship between Structural Properties of the Unsupported Ni&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;Ga&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst and Methanol Synthesis Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00241</link>
      <description>Huanyu Zhou, Shuanglin Zhang, Yan Shao, Shoujie Liu, Xiaolei Fan, Huanhao Chen, Industrial &amp; engineering chemistry research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394755424

                Here, the unsupported Ni5Ga3 catalyst was prepared at different reduction temperatures in H2 for methanol synthesis via CO2 hydrogenation. The structural variation incurred by changing the reduction temperature was characterized carefully (including extended X-ray absorption fine structure (EXAFS)) and related to the activity and reaction mechanism (by in situ diffuse reflectance Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS)). The findings show the significant influence of H2 activation on the structural properties, activity, and selectivity of the catalysts. Specifically, Ni5Ga3-500 (i.e., reduced at 500 &#176;C) encourages the copresence of Ga2O3 and NiGa alloys, which is key to achieve the appropriate interaction strength with the CO2-related intermediates, thus giving comparatively highest CO2 conversion and methanol yield. Longevity tests (100 h) of Ni5Ga3-500 showed slightly declined performance at the lower reaction temperature (viz., 220 and 260 &#176;C), which was due to the further reduction of Ga2O3 and NiGa alloying during the catalysis.</description>
      <author>Huanyu Zhou, Shuanglin Zhang, Yan Shao, Shoujie Liu, Xiaolei Fan, Huanhao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PREREQUISITES AND KEY MEASURES FOR THE IMPLEMENTATION OF SUSTAINABLE ENERGY INNOVATIONS IN CHINA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32782/2520-2200/2024-1-2</link>
      <description>Kateryna Kopishynska, Olena Trofymenko, Ting Shen, Problemi sistemnogo p&#236;dhodu v ekonom&#236;c&#236;. None(1(94))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626659

                The article is devoted to the study of prerequisites, directions and measures to ensure China's energy transition. The purpose of the article is to study China's experience in ensuring the energy transition and identify key directions and policy initiatives for the implementation and development of sustainable energy innovations. It has been established that China is the world's largest energy consumer and in recent years has been characterized by continuous economic growth and acceleration of industrialization, development of the energy industry. The energy structure was analyzed and the dominance of coal production and consumption was determined &#8211; the first place in the world. The activity of green energy development has been revealed, but the share of clean energy sources in total energy consumption is still low. It was determined that the implementation of the principle of sustainable development and energy innovation is a priority for the further development of the Chinese economy. The key directions for ensuring the energy transition have been identified: diversified energy supply; green and low-carbon development; technological transformation and development. The dynamics of China's energy imports from 2013 to 2022 are analyzed. It was established that China ranked 17th in the Energy Transition Index in 2023, and for the first time entered the TOP-20 countries according to this ranking, which indicates the growing potential of China's energy transition. It analyzed the reasons for reducing energy consumption by 10,000 yuan of GDP from 2013 to 2022. In particular, it is notable that individual companies have reduced energy consumption and environmental pollution, promoting energy conservation, emission reduction and circular economy. It found that, along with the problem of high industrial emissions, China has become a leader in the adoption of clean energy technologies with investments in clean energy technologies exceeding US$650 billion per year. Key political initiatives contributing to the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions and the introduction of energy innovations are analyzed.</description>
      <author>Kateryna Kopishynska, Olena Trofymenko, Ting Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32782/2520-2200/2024-1-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development and investigation of a multilayer PDMS/zeolite composite membrane for CO2 separation applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127344</link>
      <description>Alireza Taherizadeh, Adrian Simon, Hannes Richter, Michael Stelter, Ingolf Voigt, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394600315

                This work aims to investigate and develop a concept for CO2 separation based on PDMS/SSZ&#8211;13 (high-Si CHA) composite membranes. Firstly, an Al2O3 support was coated with SSZ-13 zeolite layer, then to increase the performance of the membrane, a Polydimethylsiloxane layer was effectively deposited homogeneously to cover the cracks and defects of the zeolite layer. The results of single gas permeation measurements displayed a notable increase in ideal CO2/CH4 selectivity up to 428 at the lowest PDMS concentration of 0.5 vol%. Moreover, a coating time of 10 min preserved CO2 permeance while increasing CO2/CH4 selectivity from 5 to 120. A twentyfold increase in CO2/CH4 selectivity was noted with mixed gas permeation without a reduction in CO2 permeance. Quantitative and qualitative microscopic analyses were also carried out on the coated membrane to better understand its morphology and microstructure. The outcomes indicated that PDMS layer decreased the permeation of N2 and CH4 and enhanced surface affinity toward CO2, resulting in reduced defects in the zeolite membranes and enhanced selectivity for CO2/N2 and CO2/CH4.</description>
      <author>Alireza Taherizadeh, Adrian Simon, Hannes Richter, Michael Stelter, Ingolf Voigt</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Dynamic Simulation on the Dynamic Process of CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Displacement by CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in Shale Pores</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00009</link>
      <description>Jingru Zhang, Guangjun Gong, Ke Chen, Yi Zhang, Lanlan Jiang, Yongchen Song, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394604625

                The technology of CO2-ESGR(CO2-enhanced shale gas recovery) is an effective means to practice energy saving and emission reduction and has drawn the attention of countries all over the world for its promising future. At present, the possibility and potential of the CO2-ESGR have been confirmed by some studies. However, the mechanism of shale gas occurrence is complex; existing studies have mainly focused on the static results of CH4 displacement by CO2. Therefore, the dynamic process of CH4 adsorbed in the shale being displaced by CO2 was simulated in this study. The results show that the process of CH4 displaced by CO2 is divided into the CH4 self-resolution phase, the displacement of residual CH4 by CO2, and the stabilization phase. Moreover, the diffusion and desorption of CH4 are less affected by pressure and pore size, and the effect of pressure and pore size on the diffusion and adsorption of CO2 is more significant. The high pressure enhances the adsorption capacity between the pore wall and CO2, which can promote the effect of CH4 displacement by CO2. In addition, another displacement phenomenon is derived in this study by examining the offset of the CO2 and CH4 density peak, in which CO2 only occupies part of the CH4 adsorption site and then both coexist for adsorption. This is different from the traditional theory that CO2 displaces CH4 by taking the place of it. It is conducive to revealing the dynamic mechanism of CO2 displacing CH4. An in-depth study of the dynamic repulsion mechanism of CH4 by CO2 in geological rock formations can promote the application of the CO2-ESGR technology.</description>
      <author>Jingru Zhang, Guangjun Gong, Ke Chen, Yi Zhang, Lanlan Jiang, Yongchen Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the Trends and Affecting Factors of CO2 Emissions under Different Urban Development Patterns: An Econometric Study on the Yangtze River Economic Belt in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scs.2024.105443</link>
      <description>Xiujuan He, Dongjie Guan, Xiao&#8208;Jun Yang, Lei Zhou, Weijun Gao, Sustainable cities and society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394790153

                Environmental issues are rarely investigated within the framework of different urban development patterns, especially concerning CO2 emissions. This research works to reveal the trends and determining factors of urban CO2 emissions under different urban development patterns. Taking the cities in the Yangtze River Economic Belt (YREB) as an example, this study develops an identification system in light of the dynamics of urban population and population density to categorize urban development patterns as growth, potential shrinkage, smart shrinkage, and continuous shrinkage. Then, the Theil-sen medium analysis and spatial econometric modeling are applied to shed light on the trend and influencing factors of CO2 emissions, respectively. The findings indicate that urban growth and potential shrinkage are the main development patterns in the YREB, and the percentage of growing cities and potentially shrinking cities is more than 77% across the different geographic areas of the YREB. CO2 emissions are remarkably heterogeneous under different urban development patterns. Over 90% of cities show a growth trend or fluctuation in per capita CO2 emissions under the four development patterns during 2010&#8764;2019. Only a few growing and potentially shrinking cities show a decreasing trend in per capita carbon emissions, suggesting a severe peak carbon challenge in the YREB. CO2 emissions in growing and shrinking cities are significantly influenced by their neighboring cities. Factors affecting CO2 emissions are different in shrinking and growing cities, and spatial spillover effects enhance the role of these factors. Compared with growing cities, improving population concentration, developing appropriate tertiary industries, strictly controlling land expansion, and developing green areas can pave the way for carbon emission reduction in shrinking cities. This study can support designing efficient carbon emission reduction measures for various cities.</description>
      <author>Xiujuan He, Dongjie Guan, Xiao&#8208;Jun Yang, Lei Zhou, Weijun Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scs.2024.105443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Dual Fuel Hydrogen/Diesel Combustion Varying Diesel and Hydrogen Injection Parameters in a Single Cylinder Research Engine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-01-2363</link>
      <description>Ezio Mancaruso, Simona Rossetti, Bianca Maria Vaglieco, SAE technical papers on CD-ROM/SAE technical paper series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394617456

                &lt;div class="section abstract"&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;In the perspective of a reduction of emissions and a rapid decarbonisation, especially for compression ignition engines, hydrogen plays a decisive role. The dual fuel technology is perfectly suited to the use of hydrogen, a fuel characterized by great energy potential. In fact, replacing, at the same energy content, the fossil fuel with a totally carbon free one, a significant reduction of the greenhouse gases, like carbon dioxide and total hydrocarbon, as well as of the particulate matter can be obtained. The dual fuel with indirect injection of gaseous fuel in the intake manifold, involves the problem of hydrogen autoignition. In order to avoid this difficulty, the optimal conditions for the injection of the incoming mixture into the cylinder were experimentally investigated. All combustion processes are carried out on a research engine with optical access. The engine speed has is set at 1500 rpm, while the EGR valve is deactivated. The purpose of this work is to research the minimum amount of diesel fuel, which allows efficient and controlled hydrogen ignition. Starting from the dual fuel conditions investigated in previous works with two injections per cycle, one of the diesel injections was removed. Subsequently, the shift of the start of injection and the reduction of the energizing time of the diesel injection as well as the increase in the delivered mass of hydrogen are analysed. The final aim is to obtain an indicated mean effective pressure equal to the one previously analysed avoiding backfiring phenomena in the manifolds or abnormal engine operation. All the analysed tests are in ultra lean combustion conditions with premixed ratio higher than 95% and equivalence ratio higher than 0.32. From the investigated cases, it can be found that the best combustion efficiency is determined with a diesel start of injection around 10 before top dead centre, while the lowest amount of diesel corresponds to an energizing time of the injector equal to 209&#956;s. Regarding the hydrogen injection in the intake manifold, a dependency on the intake valve timing is highlighted. Hydrogen was prevented from being thrown into the exhaust by starting its supply after the valve crossing; on the other hand, to avoid backfiring phenomena, it is noted that the hydrogen injection has to end prior to the compression phase commences. This information is of particular interest to fulfil engine decarbonisation optimizing the use of hydrogen in compression ignition engines and facilitating CFD analysis of hydrogen combustion in ultra lean conditions.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <author>Ezio Mancaruso, Simona Rossetti, Bianca Maria Vaglieco</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-01-2363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Operation of Paired CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction/Glycerol Oxidation at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05952</link>
      <description>Attila Korm&#225;nyos, Adrienn Szirmai, Bal&#225;zs Endr&#337;di, Csaba Jan&#225;ky, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394786891

                Despite the considerable efforts made by the community, the high operation cell voltage of CO2 electrolyzers is still to be decreased to move toward commercialization. This is mostly due to the high energy need of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is the most often used anodic pair for CO2 reduction. In this study, OER was replaced by the electrocatalytic oxidation of glycerol using carbon-supported Pt nanoparticles as an anode catalyst. In parallel, the reduction of CO2 to CO was performed at the Ag cathode catalyst using a membraneless microfluidic flow electrolyzer cell. Several parameters were optimized, starting from the catalyst layer composition (ionomer quality and quantity), through operating conditions (glycerol concentration, applied electrolyte flow rate, etc.), to the applied electrochemical protocol. By identifying the optimal conditions, a 75&#8211;85% Faradaic efficiency (FE) toward glycerol oxidation products (oxalate, glycerate, tartronate, lactate, glycolate, and formate) was achieved at 200 mA cm&#8211;2 total current density while the cathodic CO formation proceeded with close to 100% FE. With static protocols (potentio- or galvanostatic), a rapid loss of glycerol oxidation activity was observed during the long-term measurements. The anode catalyst was reactivated by applying a dynamic potential step protocol. This allowed the periodic reduction, hence, refreshing of Pt, ensuring stable, continuous operation for 5 h.</description>
      <author>Attila Korm&#225;nyos, Adrienn Szirmai, Bal&#225;zs Endr&#337;di, Csaba Jan&#225;ky</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupled conversion of polyethylene and carbon dioxide catalyzed by a zeolite&#8211;metal oxide system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adn0252</link>
      <description>Yangyang Liu, Bing Ma, Jingqing Tian, Chen Zhao, Science advances. 10(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394743767

                Zeolite-catalyzed polyethylene (PE) aromatization achieves reduction of the aromatic yield via hydrogenation and hydrogenolysis reactions. The hydrogen required for CO2 hydrogenation can be provided by H radicals formed during aromatization. In this study, we efficiently convert PE and CO2 into aromatics and CO using a zeolite-metal oxide catalyst (HZSM-5 + CuZnZrOx) at 380&#176;C and under hydrogen- and solvent-free reaction conditions. Hydrogen, derived from the aromatization of PE over HZSM-5, diffuses through the Br&#248;nsted acidic sites of the zeolite to the adjacent CuZnZrOx, where it is captured in situ by CO2 to produce bicarbonate and further hydrogenated to CO. This favors aromatization while inhibiting hydrogenation and secondary hydrogenolysis reactions. An aromatic yield of 62.5 wt % is achieved, of which 60% consisted of benzene, toluene, and xylene (BTX). The conversion of CO2 reaches values as high as 0.55 mmol gPE-1. This aromatization-hydrogen capture pathway provides a feasible scheme for the comprehensive utilization of waste plastics and CO2.</description>
      <author>Yangyang Liu, Bing Ma, Jingqing Tian, Chen Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adn0252</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scenario-based multi-criteria evaluation of sector coupling-based technology pathways for decarbonization with varying degrees of disruption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131248</link>
      <description>Jonas Beckmann, Kai Kl&#246;ckner, Peter Letmathe, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394782610

                The concept of sector coupling is gaining international attention as a means to drive further decarbonization. Our study develops and simulates 27 sector coupling technology combinations based on assumptions derived from the literature and then evaluates their efficacy in meeting Germany's CO2 emission targets for 2030, 2045, and 2050, respectively. Our findings reveal that only ambitious technological pathways involving disruptive innovations in multiple sectors offer realistic pathways for achieving the country's decarbonization targets. Using a scoring system that incorporates technical and socioeconomic indicators, we reveal the relation between reductions in CO2 emissions and multi-criteria-based scores assigned to specific sector coupling scenarios. Our results favor emission reductions from both a socio-economic perspective and a purely economic one, and they highlight the benefits of disruptive sectoral linkages in achieving emission reduction targets. Nevertheless, none of the technology combinations analyzed here meet the more ambitious German emission targets set in 2021.</description>
      <author>Jonas Beckmann, Kai Kl&#246;ckner, Peter Letmathe</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snowflake relocated Cu2O electrocatalyst on Ag backbone template for the production of liquid C2+ chemicals from CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00199k</link>
      <description>Youjin Lee, Minjun Choi, Sooan Bae, Akhil Tayal, Okkyun Seo, Hojoon Lim, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Jae Hyuck Jang, Beomgyun Jeong, Jae Kwang Lee, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394711145

                In this study, we perform the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) with a structural composite catalyst of cuprous oxide (Cu2O) and silver (Ag) that simultaneously electrodeposited. While the underneath Ag electrodeposits...</description>
      <author>Youjin Lee, Minjun Choi, Sooan Bae, Akhil Tayal, Okkyun Seo, Hojoon Lim, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Jae Hyuck Jang, Beomgyun Jeong, Jae Kwang Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00199k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biodegradable Plastics: Environmental Friendly Alternative to Petroleum Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1152-9_9</link>
      <description>Mrinal Kashyap, Palak Saket, Energy, environment, and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626001

                The presence of plastic waste in the environment poses a serious threat to all living beings and their immediate environment. The presence of micro and nano plastics in the environment has further endangered the soil health and aquatic life. The robust nature of plastics makes it stay in the environment for several years. Moreover, the processes like landfills and chemical treatments are not enough to handle the plastic waste generated at present, globally. Biodegradable plastics can offer a solution to the plastic waste issue, and could be beneficial for the environment. The bioplastics produced from the microorganisms like bacteria, microalgae, and macroalgae are potential candidates to replace the petroleum plastics with the biodegradable plastics. The use of biodegradable plastics leads to reduction in fossil fuel usage and thus reduces the carbon dioxide emissions. It also reduces the waste generation and thus aids in the recycling and reuse process. The current chapter deals with the various sources from which the biodegradable plastics can be produced, and the impact of plastic waste on agricultural lands, fresh, and marine water bodies. The technological readiness levels (TRLs) of the current technologies necessary for the production of biodegradable plastics, as well as the techno-economical aspects of the production process are discussed in the current chapter. Manufacturing, marketing, and acceptability of biodegradable plastics will affect the future of human kind in many ways. Thus, it is crucial to understand its manufacturing process, and its bottlenecks to further improve the overall process.</description>
      <author>Mrinal Kashyap, Palak Saket</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1152-9_9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to Ethane by Iodide-Derived Copper with the Hydrophobic Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02115</link>
      <description>Y. Wang, Yanming Liu, Peike Cao, Shuo Chen, Yan Su, Xie Quan, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394710076

                Electrochemical reduction of CO2 to value-added products provides a feasible pathway for mitigating net carbon emissions and storing renewable energy. However, the low dimerization efficiency of the absorbed CO intermediate (*CO) and the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction hinder the selective electroreduction of CO2 to ethane (C2H6) with a high energy density. Here, we designed hydrophobic iodide-derived copper electrodes (I&#8211;Cu/Nafion) for reducing CO2 to C2H6. The Faradaic efficiency of C2H6 reached 23.37% at &#8722;0.7 V vs RHE over the I&#8211;Cu/Nafion electrode in an H-type cell, which was about 1.7 times higher than that of the I&#8211;Cu electrode. The hydrophobic properties of the I&#8211;Cu/Nafion electrodes led to an increase in the local CO2 concentration and stabilized the Cu+ species. In situ Raman characterizations and density functional theory calculations indicate that the enhanced performances could be ascribed to the strong *CO adsorption and decreased the formation energy of *COOH and *COCOH intermediates. This study highlights the effect of the hydrophobic surface on Cu-based catalysts in the electroreduction of CO2 and provides a promising way to adjust the selectivity of C2 products.</description>
      <author>Y. Wang, Yanming Liu, Peike Cao, Shuo Chen, Yan Su, Xie Quan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding CO2 adsorption in layered double oxides synthesized by slag through kinetic and modelling techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131303</link>
      <description>Wenjing Duan, Jiachen Han, Shyh-Ching Yang, Zhimei Wang, Qingbo Yu, Yaquan Zhan, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394787397

                As main by-product in iron and steel industry, high value-added utilization of blast furnace slag had received extensive attention. In this paper, a novelty technology was proposed for using blast furnace slag as raw material to obtain excellent CO2 adsorbent-layered double oxides. The characteristics of layered double hydroxides and layered double oxides were investigated in detailed. Most notably, the laminate structure of layered double hydroxides collapsed and the pore structure, particle size distribution and functional groups of the sample had been greatly changed. The layered double oxides were occupied by phases of CaO, Ca12Al14O32Cl2 and MgO. The transformation mechanism of the layered double oxides preparation was obtained. In addition, CO2 concentration and temperature influencing on CO2 adsorption of layered double oxides were studied and established a suitable kinetic model. The optimal kinetic mechanism model of CO2 adsorption by layered double oxides was PSO. The activation energy and pre-exponential factors were 56.88 kJ&#8231;mol-1 and 12.26 min-1, respectively. Ultimately, CO2 adsorption capacity comparison and preliminary economic evaluation were conducted to assess the industrial feasibility of this technology. This work achieved the goals between CO2 reduction and high value-added utilization of solid waste in iron and steel industry.</description>
      <author>Wenjing Duan, Jiachen Han, Shyh-Ching Yang, Zhimei Wang, Qingbo Yu, Yaquan Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global energy use and carbon emissions from irrigated agriculture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47383-5</link>
      <description>Jingxiu Qin, Weili Duan, Shan Zou, Y. Chen, Wenjing Huang, Lorenzo Rosa, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394688455

                Irrigation is a land management practice with major environmental impacts. However, global energy consumption and carbon emissions resulting from irrigation remain unknown. We assess the worldwide energy consumption and carbon emissions associated with irrigation, while also measuring the potential energy and carbon reductions achievable through the adoption of efficient and low-carbon irrigation practices. Currently, irrigation contributes 216 million metric tons of CO2 emissions and consumes 1896 petajoules of energy annually, representing 15% of greenhouse gas emissions and energy utilized in agricultural operations. Despite only 40% of irrigated agriculture relies on groundwater sources, groundwater pumping accounts for 89% of the total energy consumption in irrigation. Projections indicate that future expansion of irrigation could lead to a 28% increase in energy usage. Embracing highly efficient, low-carbon irrigation methods has the potential to cut energy consumption in half and reduce CO2 emissions by 90%. However, considering country-specific feasibility of mitigation options, global CO2 emissions may only see a 55% reduction. Our research offers comprehensive insights into the energy consumption and carbon emissions associated with irrigation, contributing valuable information that can guide assessments of the viability of irrigation in enhancing adaptive capacity within the agricultural sector.</description>
      <author>Jingxiu Qin, Weili Duan, Shan Zou, Y. Chen, Wenjing Huang, Lorenzo Rosa</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47383-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CARB Off-Road Low NOx Demonstration Program - Engine Calibration and Initial Test Results</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-01-2130</link>
      <description>Gary D. Neely, Christopher Sharp, Kartik Adsule, Bryan Zavala, SAE technical papers on CD-ROM/SAE technical paper series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394617375

                &lt;div class="section abstract"&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;Off-road diesel engines remain one of the most significant contributors to the overall oxides of nitrogen (NO&lt;sub&gt;X&lt;/sub&gt;) inventory and the California Air Resources Board (CARB) has indicated that reductions of up to 90% from current standards may be necessary to achieve its air quality goals. In recognition of this, CARB has funded a program aimed at demonstrating emission control technologies for off-road engines. This program builds on previous efforts to demonstrate Low NO&lt;sub&gt;X&lt;/sub&gt; technologies for on-road engines. The objective was to demonstrate technologies to reduce tailpipe NO&lt;sub&gt;X&lt;/sub&gt; and particulate matter (PM) emissions by 90 and 75%, respectively, from the current Tier 4 Final standards. In addition, the emission reductions were to be achieved while also demonstrating a 5 to 8.6% carbon dioxide (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) reduction and remaining Greenhouse Gas (GHG) neutral with respect to nitrous oxide (N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O) and methane (CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;). This paper focuses on the engine calibration efforts for aftertreatment (AT) thermal management and improved fuel economy which included a diesel Dynamic Skip Fire (dDSF&#8482;) calibration. Test results obtained with a development-aged (hydrothermal aging only) AT system over the applicable off-road test cycles and a low load cycle are presented. The emission control system and modified calibrations could achieve internal tailpipe (TP) NO&lt;sub&gt;X&lt;/sub&gt; development targets with technologies suitable for production, allowing for a significant potential compliance margin. The level of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction was dependent on the test cycle with the target achievable without dDSF for all cycles except for the RMC where a 4% reduction was observed. The addition of dDSF reduced cycle CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by an additional 0.5 to 3%, depending on the test cycle, and maintained higher AT temperatures which reduced the use of AT thermal management modes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <author>Gary D. Neely, Christopher Sharp, Kartik Adsule, Bryan Zavala</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-01-2130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 emissions: A challenge but also a big opportunity for Spain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.17116.1</link>
      <description>Paolo Dess&#236;, Teresa Bosch-Vilardell, Sebasti&#224; Puig, Open research Europe. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394743797

                Spain is among the 11 virtuous European countries that achieved the 2020 European targets, including the reduction of energy consumption and greenhouse gas emissions, as well as the implementation of renewable energy. Yet, about 250 Mtons CO2 equivalent were still emitted in 2020 and is out of the question that the current efforts are not sufficient to reach net-zero emissions by 2050. This Policy Brief aims to describe the current situation, critically analyze the trends, and give recommendations to the policy makers based on the ten-year experience of our group on CO2 emissions research.</description>
      <author>Paolo Dess&#236;, Teresa Bosch-Vilardell, Sebasti&#224; Puig</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.17116.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy-efficient and advanced electrowinning of metallic manganese within a novel H exchange membrane cell using a Ti/IrO &#8722; RuO &#8722; SiO anode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127489</link>
      <description>Kexuan Lyu, Chengyan Wang, Yongqiang Chen, Chengyan Wang, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394770667

                Coated Titanium Anodes (CTAs) exhibit significant potential in addressing the high energy consumption challenge inherent in current manganese electrowinning processes. However, the electrodeposition of manganese dioxide (MnO2) at the anode limits the utilization of CTAs in conventional manganese electrolytic cells. Herein, a novel H+ exchange membrane (HEM) electrolytic cell was proposed and applied to manganese electrowinning employing Ti/IrO2 &#8722; RuO2 &#8722; SiO2 anode. The HEM electrolytic cell is a three-chamber electrolytic reactor consisting of cathode chamber, acidification chamber and anode chamber separated by woven terylene diaphragm and HEM. The results indicated that after 24 h of electrowinning, the cathodic current efficiency (CE) of 85.1 % was achieved, along with a specific energy consumption (EC) of 4189 kW&#183;h/t. Compared to conventional industrial electrowinning technology, this represents an increase in CE by more than 15 % and a reduction in EC by over 1400 kW&#183;h/t. The unique structure of the HEM electrolytic cell effectively prevents MnO2 deposition, ensuring the functionality of the CTAs and eliminating the generation of anode mud. Additionally, the H+ from the oxygen evolution reaction at the anode is collected and concentrated in the acidification chamber. This resulted in a spent electrolyte with 15.2 g/L H2SO4, enabling its reuse in extracting manganese ores. Employing the HEM electrolytic cell with a Ti/IrO2 &#8722; RuO2 &#8722; SiO2 anode for manganese electrowinning is therefore considered an energy-efficient and clean approach. It is highly recommended for saving energy and reducing carbon emissions in industrial processes.</description>
      <author>Kexuan Lyu, Chengyan Wang, Yongqiang Chen, Chengyan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Lead Removal by Assembly of Bio&#8208;Derived Ellagate Framework, Which Enables Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400978</link>
      <description>Song Chen, Lai&#8208;Hon Chung, Shaoru Chen, Zhixin Jiang, Ning Li, Jieying Hu, Wei&#8208;Ming Liao, Jun He, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394596335

                Lead (Pb) poisoning and CO2-induced global warming represent two exemplary environmental and energy issues threatening humanity. Various biomass-derived materials are reported to take up Pb and convert CO2 electrochemically into low-valent carbon species, but these works address the problems separately rather than settle the issues simultaneously. In this work, cheap, natural ellagic acid (EA) extracted from common plants is adopted to assemble a stable metal-organic framework (MOF), EA-Pb, by effective capture of Pb2+ ions in an aqueous medium (removal rate close to 99%). EA-Pb represents the first structurally well-defined Pb-based MOF showing selective electrocatalytic CO2-to-HCOO- conversion with Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 95.37% at -1.08 V versus RHE. The catalytic mechanism is studied by 13CO2 labeling, in situ diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS), and theoretical calculation. The use of EA-Pb as an electrocatalyst for CO2 reduction represents a 2-in-1 solution of converting detrimental wastes (Pb2+) as well as natural resources (EA) into wealth (electrocatalytic EA-Pb) for addressing the global warming issue.</description>
      <author>Song Chen, Lai&#8208;Hon Chung, Shaoru Chen, Zhixin Jiang, Ning Li, Jieying Hu, Wei&#8208;Ming Liao, Jun He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400978</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancy-enrich Ag/brookite TiO2 Schottky junction for enhanced photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114140</link>
      <description>Xinyu Tong, Wei Chen, Gang Cheng, Molecular catalysis. 560(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394789216

                Insufficient surface catalytic sites and charge kinetics constrains the progress of CO2 photoreduction reaction. In this work, oxygen vacancy-enriched Ag/brookite TiO2 hybrid by anchoring Ag nanoparticles on brookite TiO2 has been synthesized through the transformation of Ti-glycerol precursor with simultaneous reduction of Ag+ in the diethylene glycol (DEG)-H2O solution. In particular, the involving of oxygen vacancy and Ag species could extend light absorption range, facilitate charge separation and transfer, and accumulate the electrons on Ag center. As a result, the Ag/brookite TiO2 with formed Schottky junction reveals enhanced CO2 photoreduction performance compare with pristine TiO2 and solvothermal treated TiO2 (TiO2-sol). Particularly, the oxygen vacancy-enriched Ag/TiO2 hybrid shows the highest catalytic activity with CH4 and CO yields. This work offers an approach to modify brookite phase TiO2 with metallic sites and oxygen vacancy for improved CO2 photoreduction.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Tong, Wei Chen, Gang Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atomic-Ni electrocatalyst derived from phthalocyanine-modified MOF for convoying CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; intelligent utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2023.123</link>
      <description>S. R. Wang, Xiaoliang Yuan, Shenghua Zhou, Xiaofang Li, Shu&#8208;Guo Han, Wenbin Lin, Lirong Zheng, Dongdong Ma, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu, Energy materials. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394618080

                Single-atomic-site catalysts have been demonstrated as promising candidates for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR). However, the universal construction strategies need to be further developed to synthesize the desired single-atomic-site catalysts with high eCO2RR activity for feasible CO2 utilization. Herein, a novel 2-methylimidazole-phthalocyanine-Ni (IM4NiPc) coordinatively modified ZIF-8 was rationally fabricated and applied to derive the single-atomic-Ni electrocatalyst (Ni-N-C-l), which is capable of delivering much improved activity for eCO2RR, compared to the pristine IM4NiPc immobilized onto ZIF-8-derived N-doped carbon surface, and is also comparable to the best reported catalysts. The satisfied Faradaic efficiency, current density and stability of CO2-to-CO electroconversion over Ni-N-C-l are shown to originate from the verified Ni-N4 configuration, particularly, reaching a CO Faradaic efficiency of 99% in a wide potential range. Moreover, based on the outstanding eCO2RR activity of Ni-N-C-l, we successfully realized the exemplary synthesis of amide polymer materials through CO-mediated electro/thermocatalytic cascade processes, demonstrating the feasibility of utilizing CO2 for material manufacturing. This finding is expected to provide useful insight on the precise design and rational synthesis of the novel single-atomic-site catalysts for future CO2 intelligent utilization.</description>
      <author>S. R. Wang, Xiaoliang Yuan, Shenghua Zhou, Xiaofang Li, Shu&#8208;Guo Han, Wenbin Lin, Lirong Zheng, Dongdong Ma, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2023.123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eLife assessment: Knockdown of PHOX2B in the retrotrapezoid nucleus reduces the central CO2 chemoreflex in rats</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.94653.2.sa3</link>
      <description>Jeffrey C. Smith, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394728112

                PHOX2B is a transcription factor essential for the development of different classes of neurons in the central and peripheral nervous system. Heterozygous mutations in the PHOX2B coding region are responsible for the occurrence of Congenital Central Hypoventilation Syndrome (CCHS), a rare neurological disorder characterised by inadequate chemosensitivity and life-threatening sleep- related hypoventilation. Animal studies suggest that chemoreflex defects are caused in part by the improper development or function of PHOX2B expressing neurons in the retrotrapezoid nucleus (RTN), a central hub for CO2 chemosensitivity.Although the function of PHOX2B in rodents during development is well established, its role in the adult respiratory network remains unknown. In this study, we investigated whether reduction in PHOX2B expression in chemosensitive neuromedin-B (NMB) expressing neurons in the RTN altered respiratory function. Four weeks following local RTN injection of a lentiviral vector expressing the short hairpin RNA (shRNA) targeting Phox2b mRNA, a reduction of PHOX2B expression was observed in Nmb neurons compared to both na&#239;ve rats and rats injected with the non-target shRNA. PHOX2B knockdown did not affect breathing in room air or under hypoxia, but ventilation was significantly impaired during hypercapnia. PHOX2B knockdown did not alter Nmb expression but it was associated with reduced the expression of both Task2 and Gpr4, two CO2 sensors in the RTN. We conclude that PHOX2B in the adult brain has an important role in CO2 chemoreception and reduced PHOX2B expression in CCHS beyond the developmental period may contribute to the impaired central chemoreflex function.</description>
      <author>Jeffrey C. Smith</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.94653.2.sa3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response: Knockdown of PHOX2B in the retrotrapezoid nucleus reduces the central CO2 chemoreflex in rats</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.94653.2.sa4</link>
      <description>Silvia Cardani, Tara A. Janes, William Betzner, Silvia Pagliardini, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394728185

                PHOX2B is a transcription factor essential for the development of different classes of neurons in the central and peripheral nervous system. Heterozygous mutations in the PHOX2B coding region are responsible for the occurrence of Congenital Central Hypoventilation Syndrome (CCHS), a rare neurological disorder characterised by inadequate chemosensitivity and life-threatening sleep- related hypoventilation. Animal studies suggest that chemoreflex defects are caused in part by the improper development or function of PHOX2B expressing neurons in the retrotrapezoid nucleus (RTN), a central hub for CO2 chemosensitivity.Although the function of PHOX2B in rodents during development is well established, its role in the adult respiratory network remains unknown. In this study, we investigated whether reduction in PHOX2B expression in chemosensitive neuromedin-B (NMB) expressing neurons in the RTN altered respiratory function. Four weeks following local RTN injection of a lentiviral vector expressing the short hairpin RNA (shRNA) targeting Phox2b mRNA, a reduction of PHOX2B expression was observed in Nmb neurons compared to both na&#239;ve rats and rats injected with the non-target shRNA. PHOX2B knockdown did not affect breathing in room air or under hypoxia, but ventilation was significantly impaired during hypercapnia. PHOX2B knockdown did not alter Nmb expression but it was associated with reduced the expression of both Task2 and Gpr4, two CO2 sensors in the RTN. We conclude that PHOX2B in the adult brain has an important role in CO2 chemoreception and reduced PHOX2B expression in CCHS beyond the developmental period may contribute to the impaired central chemoreflex function.</description>
      <author>Silvia Cardani, Tara A. Janes, William Betzner, Silvia Pagliardini</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.94653.2.sa4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Long-Term Controlled-Release Urea on Soil Greenhouse Gas Emissions in an Open-Field Lettuce System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13081071</link>
      <description>Xuexia Wang, Bing Cao, Yapeng Zhou, Meng Zhao, Yanhua Chen, Jiajia Zhang, Jiachen Wang, Lina Liang, Plants. 13(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394720047

                Controlled-release urea (CRU) fertilizers are widely used in agricultural production to reduce conventional nitrogen (N) fertilization-induced agricultural greenhouse gas emissions (GHGs) and improve N use efficiency (NUE). However, the long-term effects of different CRU fertilizers on GHGs and crop yields in vegetable fields remain relatively unexplored. This study investigated the variations in GHG emissions at four growth stages of lettuce in the spring and autumn seasons based on a five-year field experiment in the North China Plain. Four treatments were setup: CK (without N application), U (conventional urea&#8212;N application), ON (20% reduction in urea&#8212;N application), CRU (20% reduction in polyurethane-coated urea without topdressing), and DCRU (20% reduction in polyurethane-coated urea containing dicyandiamide [DCD] without topdressing). The results show that N application treatments significantly increased the GHG emissions and the lettuce yield and net yield, and DCRU exhibited the lowest N2O and CO2 emissions, the highest lettuce yield and net yield, and the highest lettuce N content of the N application treatments. When compared to U, the N2O emission peak under CRU and DCRU treatments was notably decreased and delayed, and their average N2O emission fluxes were significantly reduced by 10.20&#8211;20.72% and 17.51&#8211;29.35%, respectively, leading to a significant reduction in mean cumulative N2O emissions during the 2017&#8211;2021 period. When compared to U, the CO2 fluxes of DCRU significantly decreased by 8.0&#8211;16.54% in the seedling period, and mean cumulative CO2 emission decreased by 9.28%. Moreover, compared to U, the global warming potential (GWP) and greenhouse gas intensity (GHGI) of the DCRU treatment was significantly alleviated by 9.02&#8211;17.13% and 16.68&#8211;20.36%, respectively. Compared to U, the N content of lettuce under DCRU was significantly increased by 6.48&#8211;17.25%, and the lettuce net yield was also significantly increased by 5.41&#8211;7.71%. These observations indicated that the simple and efficient N management strategy to strike a balance between enhancing lettuce yields and reduce GHG emissions in open-field lettuce fields could be obtained by applying controlled-release urea containing DCD without topdressing.</description>
      <author>Xuexia Wang, Bing Cao, Yapeng Zhou, Meng Zhao, Yanhua Chen, Jiajia Zhang, Jiachen Wang, Lina Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13081071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Indispensable Role of In&#8208;Situ Electrochemically Reconstructed Mn(II)/Mn(III) in Improving the Performance of Lithium&#8208;Carbon Dioxide Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403229</link>
      <description>Limin Liu, Shenyu Shen, Ning Zhao, Hongyang Zhao, Ke Wang, Xiaofeng Cui, Bin Wen, Jiuhong Wang, Chunhui Xiao, Xiaofei Hu, Yaqiong Su, Shujiang Ding, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394648101

                Li-CO2 batteries are regarded as promising high-energy-density energy conversion and storage devices, but their practicability is severely hindered by the sluggish CO2 reduction/evolution reaction (CORR/COER) kinetics. Due to the various crystal structures and unique electronic configuration, Mn-based cathode catalysts have shown considerable competition to facilitate CORR/COER. However, the specific active sites and regulation principle of Mn-based catalysts remain ambiguous and limited. Herein, we design novel Mn dual-active sites supported on N-doped carbon nanofibers (MOC@NCNF) and conduct a comprehensive investigation into the underlying relationship between different Mn active sites and their electrochemical performance in Li-CO2 batteries. Impressively, we find that owing to the in-situ generation and stable existence of Mn(III), MOC undergoes obvious electrochemical reconstruction during battery cycling. Moreover, a series of characterizations and theoretical calculations demonstrate that the different electronic configurations and coordination environments of Mn(II) and Mn(III) are conducive to promoting CORR and COER, respectively. Benefiting from such a modulating behavior, the Li-CO2 batteries deliver a high full discharge capacity of 10.31 mAh cm-2, and ultra-long cycle life (327 cycles/1308 h). This fundamental understanding of MOC reconstruction and the electrocatalytic mechanisms provides a new perspective for designing high-performance multivalent Mn-integrated hybrid catalysts for Li-CO2 batteries. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</description>
      <author>Limin Liu, Shenyu Shen, Ning Zhao, Hongyang Zhao, Ke Wang, Xiaofeng Cui, Bin Wen, Jiuhong Wang, Chunhui Xiao, Xiaofei Hu, Yaqiong Su, Shujiang Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of decarbonization measures for the Indian Cement Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120860</link>
      <description>G.S. Krishna Priya, Rahul Gundre, Santanu Bandyopadhyay, Seethamraju Srinivas, Journal of environmental management. 358(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394789451

                Cement is one of the widely used materials in construction, and its production is both energy- and emission-intensive, contributing significantly to industrial emissions. This study investigates multiple methods for reducing emissions in the Indian cement sector based on the mass and energy balances of a representative cement plant. A novel methodology for calculating the overall emissions reduction per tonne of cement with multiple emission reduction measures and their interdependencies is proposed. The effect of captive power plants in the cement industry on emissions reduction is also considered. The results are depicted using an emission abatement curve, which gives the CO2 abatement cost against cumulative emission reduction per tonne of cement, and a cost premium curve, which shows the cumulative abatement cost against percentage abatement. The analysis shows that up to 30% emissions reduction is possible using existing emission reduction measures in all the cases considered with no additional cost, and near-zero emission reduction is only possible with the adoption of emerging technologies such as carbon capture and storage. The proposed methodology is the first to explore the impact of multiple measures for emission reduction on a given cement plant, allowing for a realistic estimate of emission reduction from the measures implemented.</description>
      <author>G.S. Krishna Priya, Rahul Gundre, Santanu Bandyopadhyay, Seethamraju Srinivas</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Mapping and Monitoring of Agroforestry Area in Yamunanagar District of Haryana State Using Geospatial</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4191121/v1</link>
      <description>Bojja Harish Babu, S. Arya, K. R. Kumar, Krishma Nanda, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394610457

                Abstract Diverse agroforestry practices are prevalent in different Agro-Climatic regions of India and occupies substantial area. In Northern India&#8217;s Indo-Gangetic plains, agroforestry activities with respect to (eucalyptus) Eucalyptus tereticornis and (poplar) Populus deltoides based practices are very dominant. These agroforestry systems not only satisfy the need for wood to Wood-based Industries, but also contribute significantly to employment generation and the reduction of atmospheric Carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) vis-&#224;-vis mitigating climate change. Mapping and monitoring agroforestry areas by using the LISS-III and LISS-IV Multispectral High Resolution Satellite Remote Sensing data in the Yamunanagar district of Haryana has been undertaken to develop an operational method in the present research. Supervised classification method was used for land use land cover analysis for the year 2010 and 2019 in which training sites for seven parameters viz , agroforestry (Poplar, Eucalyptus based), agriculture, plantations (Horticulture, Scrub plantations, miscellaneous plantations) water bodies, forest, buildups, riverbed areas were mapped and monitored. The maximum area was estimated under agroforestry systems i.e. 4.06 and 9.69 percent, which includes both poplar and eucalyptus based Agri-silviculture and boundary systems for the year 2010 and 2019 respectively. Agricultural land, forests and other plantations constitute about 73.56%, 11.08% and 1.96% in 2010 and 67.77%, 10.99%, 1.7% in the year 2019 respectively of total district area. The accuracy of the image classification was delineated based on the ground truth data collected from the Yamunanagar district by using GPS (Global Positioning System) and accuracy found in Agroforestry was 90%.</description>
      <author>Bojja Harish Babu, S. Arya, K. R. Kumar, Krishma Nanda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4191121/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promising CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture and Effective Iodine Adsorption of Hyper-Cross-Linked Conjugated Porous Organic Polymers Prepared from a Cyclopentannulation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02948</link>
      <description>Noorullah Baig, Suchetha Shetty, Sk Abdul Wahed, Atikur Hassan, Neeladri Das, Bassam Alameddine, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394762866

                Three novel conjugated porous organic polymers, denoted as C-POP1-3 and which consist of alternating pyrene cores with various contorted fluorene surrogates, were successfully synthesized from a versatile one-pot palladium-catalyzed [3+2] cyclocondensation reaction. The resulting polymers were obtained in excellent yields and displayed weight-average molecular weights (Mw) ranging from 12.2 to 20.2 kg/mol with polydispersity indices (Mw/Mn) ranging between 1.8 and 2.4, suggesting that the molecular masses are narrowly distributed and thus implying homogeneous polymer chains. Thermal stability exploration of C-POP1-3 by thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) revealed an impressive robustness with a 10% weight reduction temperature attaining 485 &#176;C. Investigation of the inherent microporosity properties of C-POP1-3 via nitrogen adsorption experiments using Brunauer-Emmett-Teller (BET) theory discloses their surface areas which reach up to 560 m2 g-1 and pore volumes averaging 0.47 cm3 g-1. The target conjugated polymers were explored as adsorbents disclosing a maximum carbon dioxide adsorption of 83.0 mg g-1 at 273 K and low pressure for C-POP1, whereas iodine sorption tests portrayed prominent outcomes, notably for C-POP3 which proved to owe a strong affinity toward the hitherto mentioned halogen by achieving a maximum adsorption of 2220 mg g-1. Additionally, recyclability experiments confirmed the possibility to regenerate the polymers' adsorption capabilities even after seven consecutive cycles of adsorption-desorption cycles, which qualify them as auspicious iodine adsorbents.</description>
      <author>Noorullah Baig, Suchetha Shetty, Sk Abdul Wahed, Atikur Hassan, Neeladri Das, Bassam Alameddine</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy-saving extractive distillation process for the separation of close-boiling 2, 6-xylenol and p-cresol mixture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105505</link>
      <description>Chao Pan, Jing Guo, Bingxiao Feng, Xiaomin Qiu, Quanhong Zhu, Hongbing Song, Hengjun Gai, Meng Xiao, Ting&#8208;Ting Huang, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 159(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394789404

                2,6-xylenol and p-cresol are widely used in medicine synthesis, which are both important raw materials in chemical engineering. It is shown significant economic benefits to separate 2,6-xylenol and p-cresol. Owing to the extremely relative volatility between 2,6-xylenol and p-cresol, it is difficult to separate the two phenolic compounds through conventional distillation. The results of vapor&#8211;liquid equilibrium analysis, COSMO-SAC and reduced density gradient result are used to investigate molecular interaction in the separation system, indicating diethylene glycol (DEG) as the optimal solvent. Accordingly, we propose an energy-saving extractive distillation process with DEG as an efficient entrainer for the separation of 2,6-xylenol and p-cresol. Total annual cost (TAC) and CO2 emission are investigated for optimization and estimation of the proposed process. In addition, three energy-saving scenarios for further reductions in TAC and CO2 emission are proposed. Compared with the benchmark process, the TAC and CO2 emission of the energy-saving design vapor recompression heat pump assisted extractive distillation separation sequence B are reduced by 26.18 % and 49.18 %, respectively, which indicates that the considerable industrial potential of the proposed design.</description>
      <author>Chao Pan, Jing Guo, Bingxiao Feng, Xiaomin Qiu, Quanhong Zhu, Hongbing Song, Hengjun Gai, Meng Xiao, Ting&#8208;Ting Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105505</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resembling Graphene/Polymer Aerogel Morphology for Advancing the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Selectivity of the Postcombustion CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.3c02989</link>
      <description>Iranzu Barbarin, Emilija Fidanchevski, Nikolaos Politakos, Luis Serrano Cantador, Juan Antonio Cecilia, Dolores Mart&#237;n, Oihane S&#225;nz, Radmila Tomovsk&#225;, Industrial &amp; engineering chemistry research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394605171

                The separation of CO2 from N2 remains a highly challenging task in postcombustion CO2 capture processes, primarily due to the relatively low CO2 content (3&#8211;15%) compared to that of N2 (70%). This challenge is particularly prominent for carbon-based adsorbents that exhibit relatively low selectivity. In this study, we present a successfully implemented strategy to enhance the selectivity of composite aerogels made of reduced graphene oxide (rGO) and functionalized polymer particles. Considering that the CO2/N2 selectivity of the aerogels is affected on the one hand by the surface chemistry (offering more sites for CO2 capture) and fine-tuned microporosity (offering molecular sieve effect), both of these parameters were affected in situ during the synthesis process. The resulting aerogels exhibit improved CO2 adsorption capacity and a significant reduction in N2 adsorption at a temperature of 25 &#176;C and 1 atm, leading to a more than 10-fold increase in selectivity compared to the reference material. This achievement represents the highest selectivity reported thus far for carbon-based adsorbents. Detailed characterization of the aerogel surfaces has revealed an increase in the quantity of surface oxygen functional groups, as well as an augmentation in the fractions of micropores (&lt;2 nm) and small mesopores (&lt;5 nm) as a result of the modified synthesis methodology. Additionally, it was found that the surface morphology of the aerogels has undergone important changes. The reference materials feature a surface rich in curved wrinkles with an approximate diameter of 100 nm, resulting in a selectivity range of 50&#8211;100. In contrast, the novel aerogels exhibit a higher degree of oxidation, rendering them stiffer and less elastic, resembling crumpled paper morphology. This transformation, along with the improved functionalization and augmented microporosity in the altered aerogels, has rendered the aerogels almost completely N2-phobic, with selectivity values ranging from 470 to 621. This finding provides experimental evidence for the theoretically predicted relationship between the elasticity of graphene-based adsorbents and their CO2/N2 selectivity performance. It introduces a new perspective on the issue of N2-phobicity. The outstanding performance achieved, including a CO2 adsorption capacity of nearly 2 mmol/g and the highest selectivity of 620, positions these composites as highly promising materials in the field of carbon capture and sequestration (CCS) postcombustion technology.</description>
      <author>Iranzu Barbarin, Emilija Fidanchevski, Nikolaos Politakos, Luis Serrano Cantador, Juan Antonio Cecilia, Dolores Mart&#237;n, Oihane S&#225;nz, Radmila Tomovsk&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.3c02989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal decomposition behavior of Mountain Pass rare earth concentrate in air/CO2 atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.04.002</link>
      <description>Xu Sun, Lihua He, Deliang Meng, Xiaowei Huang, Zongyu Feng, Meng Wang, Yijiao Zhao, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394725714

                The Mountain Pass mine is recognized as one of the world's primary sources of rare earth minerals. These rare earth minerals mainly consist of bastnaesite and a small amount of monazite phosphate, which cannot be decomposed and recovered through conventional oxidative roasting and hydrochloric acid leaching process. An efficient, clean, and economical process called the "combined method" was proposed for the utilization of the Mountain Pass mine to extract rare earths from Mountain Pass rare earth concentrate (MPREC). The main steps of this process include weak oxidation atmosphere roasting, step leaching of hydrochloric acid, solid-liquid separation, the monazite slag with sulfuric acid roasting water leaching, etc. In this paper, the roasting process of MPREC under a weak oxidation atmosphere was investigated. The study examines the thermal decomposition kinetics, phase transition process, and leaching behavior of MPREC in air/CO2 atmosphere. Results show that, the activation energy (Ea) for MPREC thermal decomposition in air and CO2 atmosphere are 146 and 320 kJ/mol, respectively. At temperature above 500 &#176;C in air or above 700 &#176;C in CO2 atmosphere, REOF are generated from bastnaesite through an in-situ reaction with CaO, which is decomposed from CaCO3, to form CaF2 and rare earth oxide (REO). Thus, F is regulated into solid phase. In an oxidizing atmosphere, the thermal decomposition of bastnaesite is accompanied by the rapid oxidation of Ce(&#8546;). In contrast, the oxidation of Ce(&#8546;) in a CO2 atmosphere is significantly inhibited. At 700 &#176;C, the oxidation rate of Ce in air is 74.09%, while in a CO2 atmosphere, it is only 33.83%. The hydrochloric acid leaching experiment shows that, the leaching rate of rare earth after roasting at 600 &#176;C under an air atmosphere reaches to 82.9%, and it reaches 87% after roasting at 800 &#176;C under a CO2 atmosphere. The reduction of Ce oxidation in a weak oxidizing atmosphere significantly improves the leaching rate of Ce.</description>
      <author>Xu Sun, Lihua He, Deliang Meng, Xiaowei Huang, Zongyu Feng, Meng Wang, Yijiao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.04.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive demand response and dynamic thermal line rating for minimizing the wind power spillage and carbon emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.epsr.2024.110399</link>
      <description>Samaa Fawzy, Elhossaini E. Abd-Raboh, Abdelfattah A. Eladl, Electric power systems research. 232(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394779486

                Spilling has already occurred as a result of rising the penetration of intermittent renewable generation, and it is anticipated that the level of renewable energy curtailment will continue to soar. This leads to an increase in operating costs, CO2 emissions, and not good utilization of renewable energy resources. A bi-level multi-objective optimization model is proposed in this paper to reduce wind power spillage (WPS) based on demand response (DR) and dynamic thermal line rating (DTLR). In the upper level, multiple objectives will be satisfied based on the optimal allocation and time of DR programs considering DTLR obtained in the lower level. The minimization of WPS, load shedding, power losses, and CO2 emissions are the objectives of this level. While the lower-level aims to maximize social welfare under different scenarios and overall system constraints. Under the uncertainty of the wind power and load demand, a collection of lower-level problems that represent the market clearing conditions is used to constrain the upper-level. The effectiveness of the proposed algorithm is examined on a modified two-area IEEE 24-bus test system. Results depict that the suggested bi-level model enables considerable reductions in the WPS by up to 32.7 %. Also, there is an enhancement in load shedding, power losses, and CO2 emissions by 28.93 %, 23.07 %, and 13.9 % respectively. Finally, the social welfare increased by up to 36.6 %.</description>
      <author>Samaa Fawzy, Elhossaini E. Abd-Raboh, Abdelfattah A. Eladl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.epsr.2024.110399</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Pricing Policy to Support Net Zero Emission: A Comparative Study of Indonesia, Finland and Sweden</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3233/epl-230047</link>
      <description>Yati Nurhayati, Ifrani Ifrani, Mokhamad Khoirul Huda, Environmental policy and law. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394748460

                The Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) of Indonesia in the Paris Agreement targeted emission reductions of 29% on its own and 41% with international cooperation in 2030, followed by Net Zero Emissions (NZE) in 2060. To achieve NZE, Indonesia enacted a carbon tax policy on April 1, 2022. The 2022&#8211;2024 carbon tax is limited to Steam Power Plants and will be imposed on other sectors by 2030. This research examines the ratio legis of carbon cost policies in Indonesia and compares the core of carbon tax policies in Indonesia with Sweden and Finland. Indonesia is starting to implement a Carbon Pricing policy under the &#8216;Cap-and-Tax&#8217; scheme. The Cap scheme will be a means to force changes in the business culture in Indonesia, so the companies will pay attention to and reduce the carbon emission produced to avoid paying penalties for carbon exceeding the limits. Meanwhile, the Carbon Tax will provide economic resources to Indonesia to develop environmentally friendly technologies, fund research on renewable energy, and provide incentives for environmentally friendly businesses during the transition process to a carbon culture in Indonesia. Referring to the results of the comparison of carbon pricing policies in Finland and Sweden, Indonesia can gradually increase the cost of carbon taxes starting from Rp30,000/US$2 per ton CO2 equivalent to US$10 per ton CO2 equivalent. Meanwhile, for the imposition of high carbon tax rates, such as in Finland (US$73.02 per ton CO2 equivalent) and Sweden (US$137 per ton CO2 equivalent), Indonesia must carry out tax reforms, so the applied carbon tax is able to reduce carbon emissions without causing adverse impacts for the Indonesian economy.</description>
      <author>Yati Nurhayati, Ifrani Ifrani, Mokhamad Khoirul Huda</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3233/epl-230047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting air transportation demand and its impacts on energy consumption and emission</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.123031</link>
      <description>Majid Emami Javanmard, Yili Tang, J. Adri&#225;n Mart&#237;nez-Hern&#225;ndez, Applied energy. 364(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394706254

                With the increasing demand of passenger and freight air transportation and their key role in energy consumptions, this study developed a hybrid framework integrating machine learning algorithms to predict passenger and freight demand in air transportation and analyzed the impacts of the air transportation demand on energy consumption and CO2 emission. Critical variables are identified through correlation analyses between air transportation characteristics and economic, social, and environmental components, which are further selected to predict the air passenger and freight transportation demand. A hybrid framework is then developed where pairwise machine learning algorithms are developed to enhance prediction accuracy with an optimization model. Furthermore, sensitivity analyses are conducted to assess the effects of passenger and freight demand on energy consumption and CO2 emission. The framework is employed using Canadian air transportation as a case study. The pairwise machine learning algorithms are compared to single algorithm which increases prediction accuracy by 24.5% for passenger demand and by 25.85% for freight demand. It is predicted that the air passenger will increase by 94% to 94.25% and freight transportation demand will increase by 28.12% to 33.97% in 2050 relative to 2019 level. This surge can raise energy consumption and CO2 emission by 8.91% to 9.46% and 11.32% to 12.12% respectively. A 50% decrease in both air passenger and freight transport demand will result in a 5.43% reduction in energy consumption in Canada's transportation sector. Conversely, if demand increases by 50%, CO2 emissions will rise by 3.42% for air passenger transport and 3.67% for air freight transport. The predicted air transportation demand growth and trends can be used for capacity development and emission mitigations for sustainable planning and controls in passenger and freight demand in air transportation.</description>
      <author>Majid Emami Javanmard, Yili Tang, J. Adri&#225;n Mart&#237;nez-Hern&#225;ndez</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.123031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Performance and Emission Traits of CI Engine Fueled by Waste Cooking Oil- derived Biodiesel Enhanced with Nano Particles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4192984/v1</link>
      <description>Biru Birhanu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394717598

                Abstract In this groundbreaking experimental study, examines the impact of copper oxide (CuO) and Titanium oxide (TiO2) nanoparticles on both emissions and performance of a 4.1.5 kW diesel engine fueled by waste cooking oil biodiesel. B20 test fuel blends fortified with 50 ppm concentrations of CuO and TiO2 nanoparticles, subjected to rigorous testing across diverse engine loads (20%, 40%, 60%, and 80%) while maintaining a constant speed of 1,500 rpm. Through meticulous evaluation of key performance metrics such as brake thermal efficiency (BTE) and brake-specific fuel consumption (BSFC), coupled with the analysis of emissions including CO, CO2, HC, and NOx, we observed remarkable enhancements. Notably, the introduction of 50 ppm copper oxide and titanium oxide nanoparticles into biodiesel blends resulted in a notable boost in brake power (BP) and BTE, showcasing a remarkable surge from 12.39% to 22.14% in BP and 4.92% to 15% in BTE, underscoring their profound impact of particular significance, B2050CuO exhibited superior combustion characteristics compared to titanium nanoparticles, leading to elevated flame temperature and reduced ignition delay, thereby translating into improved engine performance, enhanced braking power output, and overall superior brake thermal efficiency. Furthermore, CuO and TiO2 nanoparticle blends demonstrated a significant reduction in CO emissions at full load with a 50 ppm dosage, achieving reductions of 6.32%, 8.57%, and 6.25%, respectively. Moreover, for B20 and B2050 TiO2 blends, HC emissions saw a notable drop by 9.14%, 6.57%, and 2.817%, promoting efficient combustion through enhanced fuel molecule interaction. Comparatively, the inclusion of B20, B2050TiO2, and B2050CuO fuel blends led to substantial reductions in CO2 levels by 14.4%, 4.8%, and 3.75%, along with lowered NOx emissions by 5.2%, 3.125%, and 2%, highlighting their potential in mitigating environmental impact."</description>
      <author>Biru Birhanu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4192984/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The environmental impact of the zero energy ready home program on manufactured housing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100194</link>
      <description>Mengjia Tang, Kuma Sumathipala, Dylan J. Poku, Antonio Aldykiewicz, Next materials. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394631859

                Manufactured homes, which are built in the factory and shipped to the site, provide economical housing for more than 20 million Americans. To improve energy measures and facilitate deployment of renewable energy systems to achieve net zero energy in manufactured homes, the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) made public the Zero Energy Ready Home (ZERH) National Program Requirements for manufactured housing in 2022. To understand how these changes will impact the environment and the building's durability, life cycle assessment and hygrothermal simulations were carried out for a standard manufactured home design and two ZERH designs in Knoxville, Tennessee. The embodied carbon and operational emissions were compared for the standard design and two ZERH designs for a service life of 60 years. Operational emissions were determined using the Building Energy Optimization tool, BEopt, and durability assessment was carried out using WUFI Pro. Life cycle assessment was performed in accordance with ISO 14040 using Athena's Impact Estimator for buildings. Results indicate that the investment in embodied carbon of the zero energy ready homes is small relative to the savings in operational emissions. The increase in embodied carbon in the zero energy ready homes is offset by the reduction in operational emissions compared to the standard home for the first year of operation. With an investment of 59 kg CO2 eq in embodied carbon, the reduction in operational emissions is approximately 680 kg CO2 eq after one year compared to a construction that meets the prescriptive performance of the building code for manufactured housing.</description>
      <author>Mengjia Tang, Kuma Sumathipala, Dylan J. Poku, Antonio Aldykiewicz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO2 methanation activity of Ni-Rutile-based catalyst by tuning the metal&#8722;support interaction with Fe doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114132</link>
      <description>Nan Zhou, Xin Jia, Siyuan Chen, Huafan Li, F Li, Botao Qiao, Huazhong Tang, Guoyi Bai, Molecular catalysis. 560(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394734215

                CO2 methanation is an effective way for CO2 recycling, and nickel-based catalysts have attracted much attention in this field due to their excellent CH4 selectivity and cost-effectiveness; however, their applications are limited by their suboptimal catalytic activity. In this work, the catalytic activity of Ni-rutile-based catalysts was increased by almost an order of magnitude simply by doping the rutile with Fe. Series characterizations show that three factors that mainly contributed to the improved catalytic performance of the Ni/Fe-Rutile, which are the reduction of the Ni size, the increase of the basic sites, and the inhibition of the encapsulation of the Ni particles by the support. With Fe doping, the OH and oxygen vacancies on the rutile surface were reduced, which made the support difficult to reduce and thus suppressed the encapsulation of Ni by the support. As a result, the number of exposed active sites on the Ni/Fe-Rutile which with a smaller Ni size was further successfully increased, and the catalytic activity was significantly improved. This study provides new ideas for the design of activity-enhanced supported catalysts from the perspective of tuning the metal-support interaction and may be applicable to other reducible oxide-supported metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Nan Zhou, Xin Jia, Siyuan Chen, Huafan Li, F Li, Botao Qiao, Huazhong Tang, Guoyi Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental benefits and supply dynamics of electric vehicles sharing: From a systematic perspective of transportation structure and trip purposes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trd.2024.104193</link>
      <description>Shunchao Wang, Jingfeng Ma, Qi Cao, Lichao Wang, Transportation research. Part D, Transport and environment. 130(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394776526

                This study elucidates the environmental benefits and the supply dynamics of electric vehicle sharing (EVS) across various trip modes and purposes. A comprehensive survey involving 1,784 participants is carried out to gauge travelers' latent preferences to EVS. An integrated model of the structural equation modeling (SEM) and the partial proportional odds model (PPOM) is developed to identify the interactive relationships between EVS and other trip modes. A before-and-after analysis is conducted to unveil the environmental benefits of EVS across different trip modes and purposes, based on the Theory of Planned Behavior (TPB) and the Technology Acceptance Model (TAM). In particular, marginal effect analysis is performed to assess the environmental benefits and supply dynamics as EVS adoption levels vary. The findings highlight a remarkable reduction in energy consumption and CO2 emissions in Beijing due to EVS operations, amounting to reductions of 168,000 kgce and 406,000 kgCO2, respectively. This study provides policymakers with insights into EVS's environmental potentials and optimization recommendations.</description>
      <author>Shunchao Wang, Jingfeng Ma, Qi Cao, Lichao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trd.2024.104193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methodology for Fifth Generation District Heating and Cooling Network Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52825/isec.v1i.1123</link>
      <description>Charlie Pr&#233;tot, Nicolas Lamaison, No host. 1(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394605025

                5th generation district heating and cooling networks (5GDHC) will play a rolein the reduction of CO2 emissions and the resilience to global warming. Our analysis of the literature points out that no simulation study proposes a comprehensive enough description of such networks. The simulation solution presented in this article considers the intertwined influences between the thermal-hydraulic balance in the network, the behavior of the decentralized heat pumps and chillers at substations, and the thermal coupling with the ground. For a given simulation scenario, the 3 developed models are iteratively solved until convergence is reached. After showing how the latter is handled,we exhibit an original result about the influence of the differential pressure between the hot and cold pipes.</description>
      <author>Charlie Pr&#233;tot, Nicolas Lamaison</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52825/isec.v1i.1123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of remote-monitored home non-invasive ventilation on patient outcomes: a retrospective cohort study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.04.11.24305702</link>
      <description>Charlotte Levey, M Manthe, Ashleigh Taylor, Maryam Sahibqran, E. Walker, G McDowell, Eric Livingston, Adam Benjafield, C Carlin, medRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394785400

                Introduction Use of home non invasive ventilation (NIV) to treat persistent hypercapnic respiratory failure in patients with stable chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) effectively reduces readmission rates and mortality compared with standard therapy. Traditional workflows around the initiation and management of NIV include elective admission for therapy initiation and frequent face to face clinic visits for follow up, but use of telemedicine offers an alternative approach. Aim This retrospective cohort study evaluated the clinical efficacy and health resource use impact of a remote monitoring approach to the initiation and monitoring of home NIV. Methods Individuals with COPD, COPD obstructive sleep apnoea or obesity related respiratory failure who were started on remote-monitored home NIV from July 2016 to December 2020 were included. Data were obtained from electronic health records. The primary outcome was healthcare utilisation (hospital admissions and average number of bed days) in the 12 months after versus 12 months before starting NIV; secondary endpoints included 2 year survival and time to readmission, and blood gas analysis. Results In the 12 months after versus before NIV initiation, there was a significant reduction in the mean number of admissions (1.0&#177; 2.1 vs. 1.4&#177; 2.1; p&lt;0.0001) and occupied bed days (9.6&#177; 26.8 vs. 17.2&#177; 27.5; p&lt;0.0001); results were consistent across NIV indications. Time to first readmission (hazard ratio [HR] 2.11, 95% confidence interval [CI] 1.58 &#8211; 2.8; p&lt;0.001) and time to death (HR 2.25, 95% CI 1.51 &#8211; 3.34; p&lt;0.0001) were significantly worse in NIV non users versus users, but did not differ by deprivation quintile. Blood gas analysis showed that NIV significantly reduced carbon dioxide pressure and bicarbonate compared with before NIV. Conclusions A technology assisted service model for the remote initiation and monitoring of home NIV therapy for individuals with chronic hypercapnic respiratory failure was feasible, had a beneficial effect on healthcare utilisation and outcomes, and offset typical adverse relative survival outcomes associated with deprivation.</description>
      <author>Charlotte Levey, M Manthe, Ashleigh Taylor, Maryam Sahibqran, E. Walker, G McDowell, Eric Livingston, Adam Benjafield, C Carlin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.04.11.24305702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A non-consumable argon plasma anode for carbon-free electrochemical ironmaking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.03.011</link>
      <description>Shuwei Feng, Junjie Zhang, Junli Xu, Mouhamadou A. Diop, Aimin Liu, Fengguo Liu, Xianwei Hu, Zhaowen Wang, Miroslav Bo&#269;a, Zhongning Shi, Materials today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394757862

                Blast furnace ironmaking produces abundant CO2, and molten oxide electrolysis (MOE) attracts great interest in ironmaking due to its carbon-free emissions. However, the anodes are the key limiting factor, making them very challenging due to high temperature and the intensive oxidation atmosphere. In this respect, a non-consumable argon plasma anode for iron electrolysis is proposed as a new technological process. During electrolysis, argon ionizes anodically and forms Ar+, which will jet into the molten oxide electrolyte and react with the O2&#8211; complex anion from the electrolyte. Metallic iron is obtained by cathodic reduction, while oxygen evolution and argon regeneration occur in the electrolyte through 2O2&#8211;(complex) + 4Ar+ = O2 + 4Ar, demonstrating the workability of the argon plasma as a non-consumable anode for molten oxide electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Shuwei Feng, Junjie Zhang, Junli Xu, Mouhamadou A. Diop, Aimin Liu, Fengguo Liu, Xianwei Hu, Zhaowen Wang, Miroslav Bo&#269;a, Zhongning Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.03.011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 mineralization and utilization by tailings sand in China for potential carbon sinks and spatial project layout</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.resconrec.2024.107598</link>
      <description>Huaqing Li, Yahui Bian, Mingliang Liu, Jianyi Lin, Min Dai, Hongyi Xie, Huajun Yu, Bin Chen, Meili Xue, Zhiwei Li, Jun Yin, Lianqing Xue, Resources, conservation and recycling. 206(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394706325

                The use of tailings sand for CO2 mineralization and utilization (CMU) has been emerging globally, offering a sustainable solution for repurposing tailings sand while establishing a stable carbon sink. Despite several reports that evaluated process performance and project benefits, existing research has not delved into the project layout focusing on the tailings pond facility and the feasibility considerations from a cluster and ownership perspective. Conducting facility-scale refined mineralized carbon sink (MCS) and layout feasibility assessment is a key issue that needs to be addressed urgently. Here, we accounted for CMU potential (CMUP) of tailings sand using a sample of 6219 tailings pond ownerships in China, predicted future annual carbon sinks through an innovative ARIMA-cloud model, and analyzed the feasibility of project layouts within potential clusters concerning enterprise size. Our results indicate that the CMUP of accumulated tailings sand in China amounts to 1817.87 Mt. In a combined scenario involving future technological leapfrogging and increased utilization, the average annual carbon sink by 2030 is projected to be 24.73 Mt. A considerable reduction in project layout feasibility across all scenarios was observed due to the mismatch between carbon clusters and enterprise size. Our study reveals that CMU using tailings sand should be regarded as one of the essential green technologies in the portfolio of strategic Chinese CO2 mitigation. However, we highlight the necessity of aligning cluster programs with the support capacity of the ownership enterprise to ensure the optimal project success.</description>
      <author>Huaqing Li, Yahui Bian, Mingliang Liu, Jianyi Lin, Min Dai, Hongyi Xie, Huajun Yu, Bin Chen, Meili Xue, Zhiwei Li, Jun Yin, Lianqing Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.resconrec.2024.107598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heavy Metal Removal from Aqueous Solutions Using a Customized Bipolar Membrane Electrodialysis Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081754</link>
      <description>Samuel Bunani, Gudrun Abbt&#8208;Braun, Harald Horn, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394750435

                Lack of safe water availability and access to clean water cause a higher risk of infectious diseases and other diseases as well. Heavy metals (HMs) are inorganic pollutants that cause severe threats to humans, animals, and the environment. Therefore, an effective HM removal technology is urgently needed. In the present study, a customized bipolar membrane electrodialysis process was used to remove HMs from aqueous solutions. The impacts of the feed ionic strength, applied electrical potential, and the type and concentration of HMs (Cd2+, Co2+, Cr3+, Cu2+, and Ni2+) on the process performance were investigated. The results showed that feed solution pH changes occurred in four stages: it first decreased linearly before stabilizing in the acidic pH range, followed by an increase and stabilization in the basic range of the pH scale. HM speciation in the basic pH range revealed the presence of anionic HM species. The presence of HMs on anion exchange membranes confirmed the contribution of these membranes for HM removal in the base channels of the process. While no clear trend was seen in the ionic strength solution, the maximum HM removal was observed when 1.5 g/L NaCl was used. The initial HM concentration showed a linear increase in HMs removal of up to 30 mg/L. A similar trend was seen with an increase in the applied electrical potential of up to 15 V. In general, the amount of HMs removed increased in the following order: Cd2+ &#707; Ni2+ &#707; Co2+ &#707; Cu2+ &#707; Cr3+. Under some operational conditions, however, the removed amount of Cu2+, Co2+, and Ni2+ was similar. The mass balance and SEM-EDX results revealed that the removed HMs were sorbed onto the membranes. In conclusion, this process efficiently separates HMs from aqueous solutions. It showed the features of diluate pH adjustment, reduction in the overall stack electrical resistance, and contribution of anion exchange membranes in multivalent cation removal. The mechanisms involved in HMs removal were diffusion and migration from the bulk solution, followed by their sorption on both cation and anion exchange membranes.</description>
      <author>Samuel Bunani, Gudrun Abbt&#8208;Braun, Harald Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Coordinated Control of Carbon Emission Reduction and Air Quality Improvement in the Industrial Sector in Hunan Province].</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202303057</link>
      <description>Nan Li, Wanwan Liu, Simin Zhu, Xiao-Wen Xing, Keqin Tang, Songwei Wang, Lei Bai, PubMed. 45(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394745110

                Climate warming and air pollution are the main environmental problems in China. This study used China's Carbon Accounting Database, energy economic model, and air quality model to analyze the potential carbon emission peaking path and synergistic air quality improvement gain in the industrial sector in Hunan Province. Based on China's Carbon Accounting Database and the local industry/energy statistical yearbooks in Hunan, the total CO2 emissions in Hunan Province in 2019 were 310.6 Mt, of which the industrial sector accounted for over 70% of the emissions, mainly from the production and supply of electricity, steam, and heat; the production of non-metallic minerals; and the smelting and pressing of ferrous metals. Three potential industrial carbon emission peaking scenarios were analyzed using the LEAP energy economic model, including the business-as-usual scenario (peaking by 2030), moderate emission reduction scenario (peaking by 2028), and aggressive emission reduction scenario (peaking by 2025), by employing different economic growth rates, energy technology progress, and energy structures of the industrial sector. Furthermore, by combining the anthropogenic air pollutant emission inventory and the regional air quality model WRF-Chem, we analyzed the air quality improvement associated with various carbon emission peak paths. The results showed that the annual mean concentrations of major air pollutants had decreased in the three scenarios, especially in the Chang-Zhu-Tan Region. The aggressive emission reduction scenario was the most effective scenario, followed by the moderate emission reduction scenario and the business-as-usual scenario. Manufacturing was the sector with the most significant synergistic effect of pollution and carbon reduction. When carbon emission peaks were achieved, the annual average concentrations of PM2.5 and PM10 in Hunan Province could be synergistically reduced by 0.6-1.8 &#956;g&#183;m-3 and 1.8-8.9 &#956;g&#183;m-3, respectively. Our findings offer important insights into carbon emission peaking and can provide useful information for potential mitigation actions.</description>
      <author>Nan Li, Wanwan Liu, Simin Zhu, Xiao-Wen Xing, Keqin Tang, Songwei Wang, Lei Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202303057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weight reduction analysis of a four-door passenger car using computer-aided modelling and experimental investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22581/muet1982.3002</link>
      <description>Faraz Akbar, Zia Ur Rahman, Mehran University research journal of engineering and technology. 43(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394786745

                The door of a passenger car is one of the key components used for the safety of passengers from side collisions. Mostly car doors are made of Steel that increase the overall weight of the vehicle since steel is the primary metal used for the construction of door. The main objective of this research is to replace Steel material of a car door with low-cost automotive materials such as aluminium alloy, magnesium alloy, and carbon fibre material to perform weight reduction analysis without compromising the strength and safety. A comprehensive theoretical study of the existing car door has been performed with 3D Computer-Aided Design (CAD) models through commercially available software SolidWorks. Results of this research work revealed that by selecting the appropriate engineering materials of the doors for a commercially available passenger car, the overall weight reduced to 45% when used aluminium material and 64% when used magnesium and carbon-fibre materials compared to the total weight of four doors made of typical steel material. Furthermore, reduction in fuel consumption and CO2 emission was also obtained by reducing the overall weight of the passenger car doors. Lastly, the performance was measured through power-to-weight ratio (PWR) analysis for steel and aluminium which revealed that the latter material was more economical and lighter in weight than the former material.</description>
      <author>Faraz Akbar, Zia Ur Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22581/muet1982.3002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 hydrogenation to methanol on intermetallic PdGa and PdIn catalysts and the effect of Zn co-deposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119735</link>
      <description>Naomi Lawes, Nicholas F. Dummer, Samantha Fagan, Oskar Wielgosz, Isla Gow, Louise Smith, Thomas J. A. Slater, Thomas E. Davies, Kieran J. Aggett, David Morgan, Stuart H. Taylor, Graham J. Hutchings, Michael Bowker, Applied catalysis. A, General. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394617555

                The behaviour of Pd deposited on Ga2O3 and In2O3 by CVI is compared for the hydrogenation of CO2 to methanol. Ga2O3 alone is inactive, but In2O3 has good conversion, and selectivity as high as 89% to CH3OH. The addition of Pd to the catalysts had relatively little effect for In2O3, but in contrast, the addition of Pd to Ga2O3, has a very big effect, inducing high activity and selectivity to methanol. Both oxides form Pd intermetallics - Pd2In3 and Pd2Ga. However, for the In catalysts there is also a thick (~3 nm) overlayer of the oxide, while for the Ga catalyst there was no such overlayer. Hence this is why addition of Pd to the Indium catalysts has relatively little effect on performance compared with Ga. Furthermore, the effect of Pd and Zn co-deposition on Ga&#8322;O&#8323; and In&#8322;O&#8323; was investigated, as well as the effect of the support morphology. Upon co-deposition of Pd and Zn, and after reduction, the Pd2In3 catalyst remains phase stable, whereas the Pd2Ga alloy is replaced by PdZn, and is improved in methanol yield.</description>
      <author>Naomi Lawes, Nicholas F. Dummer, Samantha Fagan, Oskar Wielgosz, Isla Gow, Louise Smith, Thomas J. A. Slater, Thomas E. Davies, Kieran J. Aggett, David Morgan, Stuart H. Taylor, Graham J. Hutchings, Michael Bowker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photosynthetic Resilience of Elymus elymoides and Pseudoroegneria spicata Seedlings Following Acute Water Stress</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rama.2024.03.012</link>
      <description>Robert T. O&#8217;Connor, Victoria G. Fox, Erik P. Hamerlynck, Rangeland ecology &amp; management. 94(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394789371

                Demographic studies suggest that mortality of emerging bunchgrass seedlings limits restoration success across North American cold desert rangelands, but how variation in seedling resilience to ecophysiological stress contributes to this is unclear. We measured light-saturated photosynthetic rate (Asat), apparent CO2 assimilation quantum yield (&#934;CO2), and light-adapted PSII yield (&#934;PSII) of seedlings from two native perennial bunchgrasses (Elymus elymoides, Pseudoroegneria spicata) during and in recovery from acute water stress (6% soil moisture). All seedlings of both species survived the 14-d dry-down and recovery, and both had &#8764;95% reduction in Asat and &#934;CO2 by day 3 of the dry-down but had divergent recoveries from the acute water stress. E. elymoides took a single day to recover Asat and &#934;CO2 to prestress levels, while it took P. spicata 6 d to have 50% recovery from acute water stress. Especially notable is that after reduction in &#934;PSII on d 7 of the dry-down, E. elymoides recovered within 1 d at a lower &#934;PSII compared with pretreatment, while P. spicata had an additional 1-d lag in &#934;PSII recovery. These results suggest that E. elymoides (Turkey Lake germplasm) seedlings are more physiologically resilient to acute water stress than P. spicata (Anatone germplasm), which has implications for restoration planning and native plant breeding.</description>
      <author>Robert T. O&#8217;Connor, Victoria G. Fox, Erik P. Hamerlynck</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rama.2024.03.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Off-Gassing and Self-Heating in Fuel Wood Pellets Storage: A Raw Materials Selection and Pre-Treatment Centred Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59217/hzkh1134</link>
      <description>Workson Siwale, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394755466

                Wood pellets have become a preferred solid biomass fuel for heat and power generation due to their standardized nature, known properties, and consistent quality. However, pellets produced from fresh sawdust sometimes undergo self-heating and off-gassing and this poses a challenge for their transportation and storage. The aim of this thesis was to increase the body of knowledge towards understanding the mechanisms underlying the self-heating and off-gassing of wood pellets. The results from paper I showed that the total amount of extractives in the raw material has little effect on off-gassing. Although pellets produced from Scots pine sawdust with lower extractive contents exhibited reduced concentrations of off-gasses; CO, CO2 and CH4, increasing the extractive content of the sawdust through the addition of additive oils did not result in increased off-gas emissions. The results of pure cellulose pellets with added additive oils showed that off-gassing is influenced by the type of extractives in the raw material (paper II). The highest concentrations of off-gasses were recorded from pure cellulose pellets with added linseed oil due to their high content of unsaturated fatty acids of 73.9% linolenic and 7.6% linoleic. The results from papers III and IV indicated significant effects of both raw material and drying temperature on off-gassing and self-heating of wood pellets. There was a strong linear correlation between off-gassing and the sapwood content of the raw material, with correlation coefficient (R) values greater than 0.9 at p &lt; 0.001 for all the off-gases (paper III). An increase in sapwood content led to a significant increase in off-gassing of CO2, CO and CH4, and O2 consumption. Storing of sawdust for over six months prior to pellet production, and increasing the drying temperature led to a significant reduction in off-gassing for sapwood pellets. For heartwood pellets, increasing the drying temperature resulted in increased off-gassing while raw material storage had no effect. In the other study (paper IV), the pellets produced from Scots pine mature wood sawdust were more prone to self-heating and off-gassing compared to those produced from juvenile wood sawdust. Steam drying the sawdust at high temperature led to a significant reduction in heat and gas generation for both materials. The overall results indicated that a biological process, in combination with the chemical oxidation of unsaturated fatty acids lay behind the self-heating and off-gassing of wood pellets.</description>
      <author>Workson Siwale</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59217/hzkh1134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Electrostatic Interaction via Pulsed Electroreduction for Boosting the Electrocatalytic Urea Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202402684</link>
      <description>Weibin Qiu, Shimei Qin, Yibao Li, Ning Cao, Wei&#8208;Rong Cui, Zedong Zhang, Zechao Zhuang, Dingsheng Wang, Yong Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394678988

                Electrocatalytic urea synthesis under ambient conditions offers a promising alternative strategy to the traditional energy-intensive urea industry protocol. Limited by the electrostatic interaction, the reduction reaction of anions at the cathode in the electrocatalytic system is not easily achievable. Here, we propose a novel strategy to overcome electrostatic interaction via pulsed electroreduction. We found that the reconstruction-resistant CuSiOx nanotube, with abundant atomic Cu-O-Si interfacial sites, exhibits ultrastability in the electrosynthesis of urea from nitrate and CO2. Under a pulsed potential approach with optimal operating conditions, the Cu-O-Si interfaces achieve a superior urea production rate (1606.1 &#956;g h-1 mgcat.-1) with high selectivity (79.01%) and stability (the Faradaic efficiency is retained at 80% even after 80 h of testing), outperforming most reported electrocatalytic synthesis urea catalysts. We believe our strategy will incite further investigation into pulsed electroreduction increasing substrate transport, which may guide the design of ambient urea electrosynthesis and other energy conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Weibin Qiu, Shimei Qin, Yibao Li, Ning Cao, Wei&#8208;Rong Cui, Zedong Zhang, Zechao Zhuang, Dingsheng Wang, Yong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202402684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voice Therapy Outcome Post Transoral Thyroarytenoid Myoneurectomy in Adductor Spasmodic Dysphonia: A Case Series</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2024.02.023</link>
      <description>Vrunda B. Desai, Bennet Elsa Joseph, Journal of voice. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394694975

                Postoperative evaluations of patients, who undergo of transoral thyroarytenoid myoneurectomy using CO2 laser for the treatment of Adductor Spasmodic Dysphonia (ASD), reveal some residual laryngeal symptoms such as intermittent spasms, vocal effort, and stiffness in laryngeal muscles which can be identified on videolaryngo-stroboscopy (VLS) by patterns of Muscle Tension Dysphonia (MTD) and mucosal wave, and as deviations in acoustic perceptual measures. This study aims to document these vocal symptoms observed postoperatively, and most importantly highlight the need for voice therapy postoperatively and report the short-term vocal outcomes post-therapy.Retrospective case series.The case series includes five patients, three females and two males, in the age range of 40 to 76years, who underwent transoral thyroarytenoid myoneurectomy using CO2 laser for severe ASD. The assessment protocol to document pretherapy (3-week postop) and post-therapy (after 1month of therapy) findings included VLS, Maximum Phonation Time (MPT), VHI-10 GRBAS, and Multi-Dimensional Voice Profile (MDVP) (acoustic voice analysis). Voice therapy regimen included Resonant Voice Therapy, semi-occluded vocal tract exercises, Vocal Function Exercises, and/or breath support exercises customized for individual symptoms.MTD of varying grades, MPT less than 10 seconds, deviant F0, mild to moderate degrees of perceptually rough and predominantly strained voice were noted in the pretherapy evaluation. Following 1month of voice therapy, changes noted were a reduction in strained and rough voice quality and an increase in MPT and muscle tension. Improvement of almost all parameters of MDVP tended towards normative as compared to pretherapy including F0.Voice therapy initiated at the earliest recovery stage postoperatively does lead to positive short-term vocal outcomes in patients with severe ASD. It is necessary to have long-term follow-ups and aim for the maintenance of satisfactory vocal outcomes.</description>
      <author>Vrunda B. Desai, Bennet Elsa Joseph</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2024.02.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh bell peppers consumed in cities: Unveiling the environmental impact of urban and rural food supply systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.172359</link>
      <description>Kumar Srinivasan, Vineet Kumar Yadav, Science of the total environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394737850

                Agriculture and its supply chain pose significant environmental threats. This study employs Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) to explore the environmental impact of fresh bell pepper production and distribution, comparing Urban and Peri-Urban Agriculture (UPA) with Rural Long-Distance Food Supply Systems (RLDFS). Four UPA scenarios (hydroponics, soil-based greenhouse, open-field conventional, and organic) and two RLDFS scenarios (soil-based greenhouse and open-field conventional) are evaluated using SimaPro, incorporating input from UPA practitioners and rural farmers. Results reveal an energy demand range of 0.011 to 5.5 kWh/kg eq., with urban greenhouses exhibiting the lowest consumption and hydroponics the highest due to lighting, ventilation, and irrigation. Hydroponics exhibits a global warming potential of 7.24 kg of CO2 eq&#183;kg&#8722;1, with energy demand contributing over 95 %, surpassing other scenarios by 7&#8211;25 times, necessitating reduction for sustainability. RLDFS's environmental impact is dominated by transportation (over 70 %), meanwhile other UPA systems are influenced by irrigation, infrastructure, and fertilizers. Despite challenges, UPA-hydroponics proves to be 1.7 to 4.3 times more land-use-efficient than other scenarios, emphasizing its potential. The study highlights the need to address electricity usage in UPA-hydroponics for carbon footprint reduction. Despite challenges, hydroponics could contribute to sustainable food security, and RLDFS does not significantly lag in environmental performance compared to UPA other than Ozone layer depletion criteria attributed to fossil fuel usage in transportation. These insights offer valuable guidance for urban development and policy formulation, promoting sustainable agricultural practices and supporting policies for agronomic and supply chain sustainability.</description>
      <author>Kumar Srinivasan, Vineet Kumar Yadav</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.172359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Honeycomb-like' triazine-based covalent organic framework derivative for remarkably improving both flame retardancy and mechanical properties of epoxy resin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136166</link>
      <description>Yingbing Zou, Z.B. Shi, Junjie Shi, Fubin Luo, Hongzhou Li, Construction &amp; building materials. 426(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394789459

                In this work, a new triazine-based covalent organic framework (COF) was synthesized and further modified by 9,10-dihydro-9-oxa-10-phosphaphenanthrene-10-oxide (DOPO) to obtain a 'honeycomb-like' DOPO@COF material, which was used as flame retardant (FR) for epoxy resin (EP). Surprisingly, DOPO@COF overcomes the ineffective effect of DOPO on smoke release inhibition and the weak flame retardancy of COF. DOPO@COF can exhibit suppression of smoke and harmful gases while effectively reducing heat release. When incorporating 3 wt% of DOPO@COF into the EP (0.2 wt% phosphorus content), significant reductions of 39.0% in peak heat release rate (pHRR), 18.7% in total heat release rate (THR), 20.6% in peak CO production rate (pCOPR), and 38.7% in peak CO2 production rate (pCO2PR) were observed. Moreover, the introduction of DOPO@COF effectively enhances the storage modulus, crosslinking density and the tensile and impact strength of EP composite. This work provides a new research idea for the development of N, P synergistic EP FRs for nanomaterials based on DOPO and triazine-based COFs.</description>
      <author>Yingbing Zou, Z.B. Shi, Junjie Shi, Fubin Luo, Hongzhou Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Spatial differentiation and mechanism of carbon source/sink of forest swamps in riverside of Changbai Mountains, China].</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13287/j.1001-9332.202312.005</link>
      <description>Wenjing Wang, Changcheng Mu, Mei-Lin Li, Zhengguo Sun, Ting Wang, Wenlong Xu, Hai-Ming Zhao, PubMed. 34(12)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394759990

                To quantify the carbon source/sink function of riparian zone swamps and explore the feedback relationship with climate change, we measured the annual fluxes of soil greenhouse gas, soil carbon emission, net vegetation carbon sequestration and related environmental factors (temperature, water level, etc.) by static chamber-gas chromatography and relative growth equation methods in three kinds of forest swamps (Alnus sibirica swamp, Betula platyphylla swamp, and Larix olgensis swamp) distributed along the water reduction gradient of lowland to highland in the stream riparian zone of Changbai Mountains. The results showed that the annual fluxes of CH4(0.19-0.85 mg&#183;m-2&#183;h-1), CO2(60.81-228.63 mg&#183;m-2&#183;h-1), and N2O (-0.02-0.05 mg&#183;m-2&#183;h-1) showed spatial variations along the water gradient of lowland to highland, with a trend of first constant then decreasing, decreasing, and first absorption then emission, respectively. The spatial variations of annual fluxes of these greenhouse gases were controlled by water levels. The annual net carbon sequestration of vegetation (2.61-3.45 t C&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1) was constant along the water gradient, which was mainly promoted by nitrate nitrogen content. The carbon source/sink and global warming potential (GWP) undergo regular changes along water gradients. The A. sibirica swamp was a carbon sink (1.93 t C&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1), the B. platyphylla swamp was a weak carbon source (-0.18 t C&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1), and the L. olgensis swamp was a strong carbon source (-2.51 t C&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1). The spatial variation of carbon source/sink in forest swamps was jointly promoted by water level and nitrate nitrogen content. A. sibirica swamp exhibited a strong cooling effect with a strong negative feedback effect on climate change (-5.88 t CO2&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1). L. olgensis swamp exhibited a strong warming effect with a strong positive feedback effect (10.97 t CO2&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1). B. platyphylla swamp exhibited a weak warming effect, approximately neutral (2.95 t CO2&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1). The spatial variation of GWP in forest swamps was mainly inhibited by water level.&#20026;&#37327;&#21270;&#27827;&#23736;&#24102;&#28287;&#22320;&#30899;&#28304;/&#27719;&#24182;&#25506;&#31350;&#20854;&#23545;&#27668;&#20505;&#21464;&#21270;&#30340;&#21453;&#39304;&#20851;&#31995;,&#37319;&#29992;&#38745;&#24577;&#31665;-&#27668;&#30456;&#33394;&#35889;&#27861;&#21644;&#30456;&#23545;&#29983;&#38271;&#26041;&#31243;&#27861;,&#27979;&#23450;&#38271;&#30333;&#23665;&#28330;&#27969;&#27827;&#23736;&#24102;&#20302;&#22320;&#33267;&#39640;&#22320;&#27839;&#27700;&#20998;&#20943;&#23567;&#26799;&#24230;&#20381;&#27425;&#20998;&#24067;&#30340;3&#31181;&#26862;&#26519;&#27836;&#27901;(&#27611;&#36196;&#26472;&#27836;&#27901;&#12289;&#30333;&#26726;&#27836;&#27901;&#21644;&#33853;&#21494;&#26494;&#27836;&#27901;)&#22303;&#22756;&#28201;&#23460;&#27668;&#20307;&#24180;&#36890;&#37327;&#12289;&#22303;&#22756;&#24180;&#20928;&#30899;&#25490;&#25918;&#37327;&#12289;&#26893;&#34987;&#24180;&#20928;&#22266;&#30899;&#37327;&#21450;&#30456;&#20851;&#29615;&#22659;&#22240;&#23376;(&#28201;&#24230;&#12289;&#27700;&#20301;&#31561;)&#12290;&#32467;&#26524;&#34920;&#26126;: &#38271;&#30333;&#23665;&#28330;&#27969;&#27827;&#23736;&#24102;&#26862;&#26519;&#27836;&#27901;&#30340;CH4(0.19&#65374;0.85 mg&#183;m-2&#183;h-1)&#12289;CO2(60.81&#65374;228.63 mg&#183;m-2&#183;h-1)&#21644;N2O(-0.02&#65374;0.05 mg&#183;m-2&#183;h-1)&#24180;&#36890;&#37327;&#27839;&#20302;&#22320;&#33267;&#39640;&#22320;&#27700;&#20998;&#26799;&#24230;&#20381;&#27425;&#21576;&#20808;&#24658;&#23450;&#21518;&#38477;&#20302;&#12289;&#36882;&#20943;&#21644;&#20808;&#21560;&#25910;&#21518;&#25490;&#25918;&#30340;&#31354;&#38388;&#21464;&#21270;&#35268;&#24459;,&#19988;&#36825;3&#31181;&#28201;&#23460;&#27668;&#20307;&#24180;&#36890;&#37327;&#30340;&#31354;&#38388;&#21464;&#21270;&#22343;&#21463;&#27700;&#20301;&#25511;&#21046;&#12290;&#27827;&#23736;&#24102;&#26862;&#26519;&#27836;&#27901;&#30340;&#26893;&#34987;&#24180;&#20928;&#22266;&#30899;&#37327;(2.61&#65374;3.45 t C&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1)&#27839;&#27700;&#20998;&#26799;&#24230;&#21576;&#24658;&#23450;&#22411;,&#20027;&#35201;&#21463;&#30813;&#24577;&#27694;&#21547;&#37327;&#20419;&#36827;&#12290;&#27827;&#23736;&#24102;&#26862;&#26519;&#27836;&#27901;&#30340;&#30899;&#28304;/&#27719;&#21450;&#20840;&#29699;&#22686;&#28201;&#28508;&#21183;(GWP)&#27839;&#27700;&#20998;&#26799;&#24230;&#21457;&#29983;&#20102;&#35268;&#24459;&#24615;&#30340;&#36716;&#21464;,&#20854;&#20013;,&#27611;&#36196;&#26472;&#27836;&#27901;&#20026;&#30899;&#27719;(1.93 t C&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1),&#30333;&#26726;&#27836;&#27901;&#20026;&#24369;&#30899;&#28304;(-0.18 t C&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1),&#32780;&#33853;&#21494;&#26494;&#27836;&#27901;&#20026;&#24378;&#30899;&#28304;(-2.51 t C&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1);&#19988;&#26862;&#26519;&#27836;&#27901;&#30899;&#28304;/&#27719;&#30340;&#31354;&#38388;&#21464;&#21270;&#21463;&#27700;&#20301;&#21644;&#30813;&#24577;&#27694;&#21547;&#37327;&#32852;&#21512;&#20419;&#36827;&#12290;&#27611;&#36196;&#26472;&#27836;&#27901;&#34920;&#29616;&#20026;&#24378;&#20919;&#21364;&#25928;&#24212;,&#19982;&#27668;&#20505;&#21464;&#21270;&#38388;&#23384;&#22312;&#36739;&#24378;&#36127;&#21453;&#39304;&#20316;&#29992;(-5.88 t CO2&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1);&#33853;&#21494;&#26494;&#27836;&#27901;&#34920;&#29616;&#20026;&#24378;&#22686;&#28201;&#25928;&#24212;,&#23384;&#22312;&#36739;&#24378;&#27491;&#21453;&#39304;&#20316;&#29992;(10.97 t CO2&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1);&#32780;&#30333;&#26726;&#27836;&#27901;&#34920;&#29616;&#20026;&#24369;&#22686;&#28201;&#25928;&#24212;,&#36817;&#20284;&#20110;&#20013;&#24615;(2.95 t CO2&#183;hm-2&#183;a-1);&#19988;&#26862;&#26519;&#27836;&#27901;GWP&#30340;&#31354;&#38388;&#21464;&#21270;&#20027;&#35201;&#21463;&#27700;&#20301;&#25233;&#21046;&#12290;.</description>
      <author>Wenjing Wang, Changcheng Mu, Mei-Lin Li, Zhengguo Sun, Ting Wang, Wenlong Xu, Hai-Ming Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13287/j.1001-9332.202312.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Investigation of Waterflood Performance Challenges in a Low-Permeability Morrowan Sandstone Reservoir: Implications for Mechanistic Modeling and Enhanced Oil Recovery Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/218876-ms</link>
      <description>Anthony Morgan, William Ampomah, Reid B. Grigg, Song Wang, Robert Czarnota, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394604347

                Abstract An indispensable factor to the development of improved enhanced oil recovery (EOR) is the in-depth insight into the fractional flow mechanistic effects of waterflood performance. Especially for an inefficient waterflood operated field. In this study the inefficiency of waterflood on FWU is investigated. The field is divided into two halves (East and west) of the same reservoir and similar geological characteristics. Though the east was prolific on primary recovery it failed on waterflood whiles the west performed efficiently and hence its undergoing WAG CO2-EOR improved recovery technique. Through core-flood experiments, the causative mechanisms are unraveled. X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy and energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (SEM/EDS) analyses were also conducted to assess mineral composition, pore characteristics and distribution. The core samples exhibited extremely low permeability, resulting in a drastic reduction in flow capacity. The reservoir primarily consists of quartz, clay minerals (kaolinite, illite, smectite), feldspar, and carbonates. Single-phase injection of low salinity water (SIIW) further reduced permeability and increased differential pressure compared to high salinity water (SCW). Higher flow rates caused significant increments in differential pressure, likely due to velocity-induced fine migration. pH changes and the presence of Al3+, Fe2+, and Zn ions indicated brine reactions. Two flood recovery strategies showed incremental recovery with SIIW injection with observed adverse effects. Fine migrations, clay swelling, scaling, and precipitation were identified as key causes of formation damage during low salinity water flooding. Element-mineral associations showed clays and mineral particles obstructing pores and pore throats. In summary, the principal mechanisms of waterflood inefficiency include low permeability, mineral composition (especially clay minerals), clay mineral reactivity, and increased pressure drop (&#916;P). These factors collectively contribute to formation damage, pore plugging, reduced flow capacity, and ultimately the inefficiency of waterflood operations. These insights contribute to the development of effective waterflood strategies and improved recovery techniques for incremental recovery from the FWU-east field especially considering CO2-WAG EOR.</description>
      <author>Anthony Morgan, William Ampomah, Reid B. Grigg, Song Wang, Robert Czarnota</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/218876-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewable energy and carbon-neutral gaming: A holistic approach to sustainable electricity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131203</link>
      <description>Chien&#8208;Chiang Lee, Jafar Hussain, &#38997; &#37428;&#26408;, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394601652

                Carbon emissions are a global issue around the world due to energy consumption, and to resolve this, increasing focus has been placed on attaining carbon neutrality. This research bridges the gap in related literature by considering perspectives on electricity. We develop a regression model from renewable energy consumption and production and apply game theory to get different decisions on electricity production from renewable energy (RE) production-consumption and subsidies on RE resources. Subsequently, a simulation-driven optimization method is employed to generate various scenarios. Various experiments are manipulated to find the optimal decisions of carbon-neutral indicators. Results indicate that subsidies on renewable energy that generate electricity exhibit a significant role in maximizing CO2 emission reduction. It is found that subsidies on wind energy consumption and production play a pivotal role in mitigating carbon emissions. This study elaborates on a valuable contribution in providing optimal decisions for achieving carbon neutrality in RE production and consumption. It offers guidelines to pay attention to the policies about RE resources to make the environment clean. Ultimately, this research not only presents optimal pathways for attaining carbon neutrality but also marks the necessity of targeted policies focused on RE resources to promote a cleaner and sustainable environment globally.</description>
      <author>Chien&#8208;Chiang Lee, Jafar Hussain, &#38997; &#37428;&#26408;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tubular electrochemical hydrogen compressor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.355</link>
      <description>Wibke Z&#228;ngler, Mojtaba Mohseni, Robert Keller, Wibke Z&#228;ngler, International journal of hydrogen energy. 66(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394733677

                Electrochemical hydrogen compression is a promising alternative to conventional mechanical compression due to low maintenance costs and high one-stage compression ratios. The typically employed planar systems, however, are intrinsically difficult to operate in high differential pressure environments. Tubular systems are inherently advantageous for high differential pressure systems but require innovative membrane electrode assembly development. This study unveils the first tubular EHC featuring a membrane electrode assembly supported by a stainless steel 3D-printed porous anode. The membrane electrode assembly for gas-phase electrochemistry is produced by spray coating the porous anode with Pt/C as the catalyst and joining the anode with a tubular catalyst-coated membrane. Electrochemical characterization demonstrates the functionality of the tubular EHC at current densities up to 60 mAcm&#8722;2 with a cell potential of 200 mV under non-pressurized conditions. Moreover, a pressure difference of 2 bar is achieved at 60 mAcm&#8722;2 within the first 60 min in continuous mode. By demonstrating the proof-of-principle for the first tubular EHC, this work paves the way for new research avenues in electrochemical process engineering, offering a broad spectrum of applications, from enhancing EHC technologies to advancing electrochemical CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Wibke Z&#228;ngler, Mojtaba Mohseni, Robert Keller, Wibke Z&#228;ngler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revitalizing soil health for climate resilience in Africa: The need for high rates of carbon inputs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.farsys.2024.100096</link>
      <description>Idowu A. Atoloye, Farming system. 2(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394704316

                Enhancing soil health is critical to improve crop productivity, fertilizer use efficiency, and resilience to climate change impacts for smallholder farmers in Africa. Increasing the use of mineral fertilizers is critical for achieving higher crop yield and residue return. However, it is crucial to consider the simultaneous use of carbon (C)-rich organic materials alongside mineral fertilizers to support soil health and enhance fertilizer use efficiency. It is proposed that increasing mineral fertilizer use without a concurrent increase in C-rich organic materials may not enhance soil organic carbon (SOC) and soil health in the long term. When the labile pool of nutrients is increased through mineral fertilizer, it can reduce microbial C use efficiency, thereby hindering the formation and stabilization of SOC. This reduction in efficiency can cause a more significant proportion of the returned plant residues to be lost as CO2 through microbial respiration rather than being incorporated into the SOC pool. However, this effect can be mitigated by the concurrent application of large amounts of organic amendments, such as compost, manure or biochar, which provide a balanced supply of nutrients and C substrates to support microbial activity and enhance SOC formation.</description>
      <author>Idowu A. Atoloye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.farsys.2024.100096</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planned expansion of transportation infrastructure in Brazil has implications for the pattern of agricultural production and carbon emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.172434</link>
      <description>Zhan Wang, G. B. Martha, Jing Liu, Cicero Zanetti De Lima, Thomas W. Hertel, Science of the total environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394790110

                High transportation costs have been a barrier to the expansion of agriculture in the interior of Brazil. To reduce transportation costs, Brazil launched the National Logistics Plan, aiming to expand its railway network by up to 91 % by 2035. Such a large-scale infrastructure investment raises concerns about its economic and environmental consequences. By combining geospatial estimation of transportation cost with a grid-resolving, multi-scale economic model that bridges fine-scale crop production with its trade and demand from national and global perspectives, we explore impacts of transportation infrastructure expansion on agricultural production, land use changes, and carbon emissions both locally and nationally in Brazil. We find that globally, the impacts on output and land use changes are small. However, within Brazil, the plan's primary impacts are impressive. PNL2035 results in the reduction of transportation costs by 8&#8211;23 % across states (depending on expansion's extent) in the interior Cerrado biome. This results in cropland expansion and increases in terrestrial carbon emissions in the Cerrado region. However, the increase in terrestrial carbon emissions in the Cerrado is offset by spillover effects elsewhere in Brazil, as crop production shifts away from the Southeast-South regions and accompanying change in the mix of transportation mode for farm products from roadway to more emission-efficient railway. Furthermore, we argue that the transportation infrastructure's impact on the enhanced mobility of labor and other agricultural inputs would further accentuate the regional shift in agricultural production and contribute to carbon emission mitigation. Upon its completion, PNL2035 is expected to result in the reduction of net national emissions by 1.8&#8211;30.7 million metric ton of CO2-equivalent, depending on the impacts on labor and purchased input mobility. We conclude that the omission of spillover effects due to infrastructure expansion can lead to misleading assessments of transport policies.</description>
      <author>Zhan Wang, G. B. Martha, Jing Liu, Cicero Zanetti De Lima, Thomas W. Hertel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.172434</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decarbonizing Process Heat Supply in the Austrian Pharmaceutical Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52825/isec.v1i.1043</link>
      <description>Anton Beck, Matthias Traninger, Benedikt Mauel, Timo Kloska, Felix Hubmann, Daniela Leibetseder, Verena Sulzgruber, Nicolas Neubauer, Gerwin Drexler-Schmid, International Sustainable Energy Conference - Proceedings. 1(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394748425

                In the pharmaceutical industry, energy efficiency has played a minor role compared to other energy-intensive industries. However, there is a growing recognition of the need to address environmental concerns. With ambitious climate targets and the increasing demand for significant reductions in CO2 emissions, the pharmaceutical industry is now embracing the opportunity to enhance its sustainability practices. Mainly fossil fuels are used to provide process steam at moderate temperature levels at about 160-180&#176;C and to a lesser extent to provide hot water or for on-site power production in CHPs. In this paper, the main processes with demands for process heat, such as media supply, cleaning, or air conditioning, are presented and possibilities for increasing efficiency, for switching to alternative heat supply and for using alternative process technologies are evaluated with respect to economics, but also regarding hurdles for implementation such as requirements for revalidation of production processes and possible necessity of re-approval of products. The present study highlights the potentials for decarbonization of the Austrian pharmaceutical industry using a generic but representative production site applying various measures that either reduce heating and cooling requirements or alter the temperature requirements for heat supply. It is shown that, at least for the example case, full decarbonization is technically feasibly without an increase in energy costs if efficiency measures are progressively used on demand level.</description>
      <author>Anton Beck, Matthias Traninger, Benedikt Mauel, Timo Kloska, Felix Hubmann, Daniela Leibetseder, Verena Sulzgruber, Nicolas Neubauer, Gerwin Drexler-Schmid</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52825/isec.v1i.1043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physiological and transcriptional changes associated with obligate aestivation in the cabbage stem flea beetle (Psylliodes chrysocephala)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.04.08.588545</link>
      <description>G&#246;zde G&#252;ney, Doga CEDDEN, Johannes Koernig, B. Ulber, Franziska Beran, Stefan Scholten, Michael Rost&#225;s, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394713470

                Aestivation is a form of seasonal dormancy observed in various insect species, usually coinciding with the summer season. Psylliodes chrysocephala (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae), the cabbage stem flea beetle, is a key pest of oilseed rape and obligatorily aestivates as adult in late summer. At present, our understanding of the physiological and transcriptional changes linked to aestivation in P. chrysocephala is still limited. In this study, physiological parameters and RNA-seq analyses were performed with laboratory-reared beetles at pre-aestivation, aestivation, and post-aestivation stages. Measurements of CO2 production supported the notion that aestivating beetles dramatically reduce their metabolic rate and, together with assessments of reproductive maturation, allowed precise discrimination between the three adult stages. Aestivating beetles showed a reduction in carbohydrate reserves and an increase in lipid reserves compared to pre-aestivating beetles, indicating that aestivation is associated with drastic changes in energy metabolism. In agreement with these findings, we found that genes involved in carbohydrate and lipid metabolism, digestion, and mitochondrial activity are differentially expressed between the three stages. Furthermore, RNA-seq analysis suggested the regulation of transcription factors associated with aestivation maintenance and the involvement of cytochrome P450s in conferring a summer-resistant phenotype during the aestivation period. In conclusion, this study represents the first exploration of the transcriptomic and physiological aspects of the aestivation response in P. chrysocephala.</description>
      <author>G&#246;zde G&#252;ney, Doga CEDDEN, Johannes Koernig, B. Ulber, Franziska Beran, Stefan Scholten, Michael Rost&#225;s</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.04.08.588545</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CARBON FOOTPRINT REDUCTION ON MANUFACTURING SMES FROM DIGITAL TECHNOLOGIES</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5593/sgem2023v/6.2/s26.65</link>
      <description>Agostinho Silva, Antonio Cardoso, International Multidisciplinary Scientific GeoConference SGEM .... None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394791300

                Europe must avoid losing manufacturing SMEs. However, presenting distinct maturity levels, these companies have a hard time fulfilling the necessary ecological sustainability level. Controversially, despite the intense debate about digital technologies, there is still a need for knowledge in the industrial world about the impact of these technologies to make manufacturing SMEs environmentally friendly. According to data made available by Stone Portuguese Federation, in 2019, the Portuguese Ornamental Stone sector (OS.Pt): (i) exported to 116 countries; (ii) ranked 9th in the World International Stone Trade; (iii); was the second country in the world in international trade per capita; (iv) exports covered imports by 660%; (v) 45% of exports were to countries outside Europe and (vi) had a total turnover of EUR1,230 million. Mainly comprised of small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs), the OS.Pt sector is relevant for the Portuguese Economy, representing over 16,600 direct jobs, and is one of the main generators of private employment in inland regions has registered an average annual growth rate in turnover of 5.13% over the last ten years and has generated around 500 new jobs from 2016. By using the Portuguese stone sector case study, considering the investment to improve the operations towards digital, a framework was designed and used in five groups of forty stone manufacturing SMEs, each representing a digital level. Through a quantitative methodology based on five years after the investment, depending on the technology used and level of investment in digital technologies, it was found a potential reduction of CO2 emissions between 10.7% and 35.1%.</description>
      <author>Agostinho Silva, Antonio Cardoso</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5593/sgem2023v/6.2/s26.65</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of a Triangle-Fused Six-Pointed Star and Its Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00550</link>
      <description>Guotao Wang, Z.-Y. Zhang, Hao Chen, Yingxue Fu, Kaisong Xiang, En&#8208;Hou Han, Tun Wu, Qixia Bai, Peiyang Su, Zhujiang Wang, Die Liu, Fenghua Shen, Hui Liu, Zhilong Jiang, Jie Yuan, Yiming Li, Pingshan Wang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394754824

                As electrocatalysts, molecular catalysts with large aromatic systems (such as terpyridine, porphyrin, or phthalocyanine) have been widely applied in the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). However, these monomeric catalysts tend to aggregate due to strong &#960;&#8211;&#960; interactions, resulting in limited accessibility of the active site. In light of these challenges, we present a novel strategy of active site isolation for enhancing the CO2RR. Six Ru(Tpy)2 were integrated into the skeleton of a metallo-organic supramolecule by stepwise self-assembly in order to form a rhombus-fused six-pointed star R1 with active site isolation. The turnover frequency (TOF) of R1 was as high as 10.73 s&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.6 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (vs RHE), which is the best reported value so far at the same potential to our knowledge. Furthermore, by increasing the connector density on R1's skeleton, a more stable triangle-fused six-pointed star T1 was successfully synthesized. T1 exhibits exceptional stability up to 126 h at &#8722;0.4 V vs RHE and excellent TOF values of CO. The strategy of active site isolation and connector density increment significantly enhanced the catalytic activity by increasing the exposure of the active site. This work provides a starting point for the design of molecular catalysts and facilitates the development of a new generation of catalysts with a high catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Guotao Wang, Z.-Y. Zhang, Hao Chen, Yingxue Fu, Kaisong Xiang, En&#8208;Hou Han, Tun Wu, Qixia Bai, Peiyang Su, Zhujiang Wang, Die Liu, Fenghua Shen, Hui Liu, Zhilong Jiang, Jie Yuan, Yiming Li, Pingshan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting oxygen vacancies utility for tetracycline degradation via peroxymonosulfate activation by reduced Mg-doped Co3O4: Kinetics and key role of electron transfer pathway</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118892</link>
      <description>Zhidong Chen, Lian Chang, Xiaodan Zhang, Hongxiang Chai, Yuming Huang, Environmental research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394606781

                Developing cobalt-based catalysts with a high abundance of oxygen vacancies (Vo) and exceptional Vo utility efficiency for the prompt removal of stubborn contaminants through peroxymonosulfate (PMS) activation poses a significant challenge. Herein, we reported the synthesis of the reduced Mg-doped Co3O4 nanosheets, i.e. Mg-doped Co3O4-r, via Mg doping and followed by NaBH4 reduction, aiming to degrade tetracycline (TC). Various characterization results illustrated that NaBH4 reduction imparted higher Vo utility efficiency to Mg-doped Co3O4-r, along with an ample presence of reduced Co2+ species and an increased surface area, thereby substantially elevating PMS activation capability. Notably, Mg-doped Co3O4-r achieved more than 97.9% degradation of 20 mg/L TC within 10 min, showing an over 8-fold increase in reaction rate relative to the Mg-doped Co3O4 (kobs: 0.3285 min-1 vs 0.0399 min-1). The high removal efficiency of TC was sustained across a broad pH range of 3 to 11, even in the presence of common anions and humic acid. Radical quenching trials, EPR outcomes, and electrochemical analysis indicated that neither radicals nor 1O2 were the primary active species. Instead, electron transfer pathway played dominant role in TC degradation. The Mg-doped Co3O4-r displayed excellent recyclability and versatility. Even after the fifth cycle, it maintained an impressive 83.0% removal of TC. Furthermore, it exhibited rapid degradation capabilities for various pollutants, including levofloxacin, pefloxacin, ciprofloxacin, malachite green, and rhodamine B. The TC degradation pathway was proposed based on LC-MS determination of its degradation intermediates. This study showcases an innovative strategy for the rational design of an efficient cobalt-based activator, leveraging electron transfer pathways through PMS activation to degrade antibiotics effectively.</description>
      <author>Zhidong Chen, Lian Chang, Xiaodan Zhang, Hongxiang Chai, Yuming Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inventory, Dynamic Evolution, and Scenario Projections of Agricultural Carbon Emissions in Shandong Province, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16083196</link>
      <description>Chenxi Gao, Qingping Hu, Lingxin Bao, Sustainability. 16(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394726393

                The reduction in agricultural carbon emissions (ACEs) in Shandong Province is essential to China&#8217;s carbon peak and carbon neutrality objectives. In this regard, we constructed an ACE inventory for Shandong Province at a resolution of 1 km &#215; 1 km, integrating the emission factor method with geographic information system (GIS) technology. Building upon this, we explored the dynamic evolution patterns of ACEs using kernel density estimation and conditional probability density estimation. Additionally, long short-term memory networks were trained to predict ACEs under various scenarios. The results showed that: (1) ACEs in Shandong Province exhibited two stages of change, i.e., &#8220;rise and decline&#8221;. Notably, 64.39% of emissions originated from the planting industry. The distribution of emissions was closely correlated with regional agricultural production modes. Specifically, CO2 emissions were predominantly distributed in crop cultivation areas, while CH4 and N2O emissions were primarily distributed in livestock breeding areas. The uncertainty of the emission inventory ranged from &#8722;12.04% to 10.74%, mainly caused by emission factors. (2) The ACE intensity of various cities in Shandong Province is decreasing, indicating a decoupling between ACEs and agricultural economic growth. Furthermore, the emission disparities among different cities are diminishing, although significant spatial non-equilibrium still persists. (3) From 2022 to 2030, the ACEs in Shandong Province will show a continuous downward trend. By 2030, the projected values under the baseline scenario, low-carbon scenario I, and low-carbon scenario II will be 6301.74 &#215; 104 tons, 5980.67 &#215; 104 tons, and 5850.56 &#215; 104 tons. The low-carbon scenario reveals greater potential for ACE reduction while achieving efficient rural economic development and urbanization simultaneously. This study not only advances the methodology of the ACE inventory but also provides quantitative references and scientific bases for promoting low-carbon, efficient, and sustainable regional agriculture.</description>
      <author>Chenxi Gao, Qingping Hu, Lingxin Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16083196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Solar and Biomass Perspectives Using Geographic Information System - the Case of Iraq Regions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.120463</link>
      <description>Qusay Hassan, Ahmed K. Nassar, Sameer Algburi, Ahmed Fouly, Emad Mahrous Awwad, Marek Jaszczur, Patrik Viktor, Ayesha Amjad, Hassan Falah Fakhruldeen, Ali Khudhair Al-Jiboory, Aws Zuhair Sameen, M. Barakat, Renewable energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394596629

                The study provides a comprehensive assessment of strategic zoning for biomass energy development across various regions in Iraq through GIS-based analysis. It delves into the energy surplus factor a pivotal metric indicating a region capacity to produce energy beyond its consumption needs. Results indicate a significant disparity in energy production-consumption balance across the regions, impacting local and national energy sustainability initiatives. A notable proportion of the study areas exceed a surplus factor of 3.5, showcasing the possibility of regions to not only meet their own energy needs but to also contribute to a surplus, thanks to effective renewable energy use and other energy-efficient practices. Conversely, a considerable number of cities have surplus factors below 1, signaling energy deficits and a dependence on external energy sources due to high consumption, underdeveloped local energy infrastructure, or other inefficiencies. Meanwhile, other regions achieve a balance, with surplus factors ranging from 1.5 to 4, indicating a more sustainable alignment of energy production with consumption. The study segments regions into tiers based on their surplus factors, suggesting that those with higher factors have greater CO2 reduction potential, thereby offering a nuanced strategy for resource management and environmental policy-making. These insights establish a nuanced framework for optimizing energy production, managing consumption, and reducing emissions, tailored to the diverse energy landscapes of Iraq regions.</description>
      <author>Qusay Hassan, Ahmed K. Nassar, Sameer Algburi, Ahmed Fouly, Emad Mahrous Awwad, Marek Jaszczur, Patrik Viktor, Ayesha Amjad, Hassan Falah Fakhruldeen, Ali Khudhair Al-Jiboory, Aws Zuhair Sameen, M. Barakat</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.120463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NOx Storage and Reduction (NSR) Performance of Sr-Doped LaCoO3 Perovskite Prepared by Glycine-Assisted Solution Combustion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/compounds4020014</link>
      <description>Xinru Luan, Xudong Wang, T.S. Zhang, Liangran Gan, Jianxun Liu, Yujia Zhai, Wei Liu, Liguo Wang, Zhongpeng Wang, Compounds. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394611156

                Here, we successfully synthesized Sr-doped perovskite-type oxides of La1&#8722;xSrxCo1&#8722;&#955;O3&#8722;&#948;, &#8220;LSX&#8221; (x = 0, 0.1, 0.3, 0.5, 0.7), using the glycine-assisted solution combustion method. The effect of strontium doping on the catalyst structure, NO to NO2 conversion, NOx adsorption and storage, and NOx reduction performance were investigated. The physicochemical properties of the catalysts were studied by XRD, SEM-EDS, N2 adsorption&#8211;desorption, FTIR, H2-TPR, O2-TPD, and XPS techniques. The NSR performance of LaCoO3 perovskite was improved after Sr doping. Specifically, the perovskite with 50% of Sr doping (LS5 sample) exhibited excellent NOx storage capacity within a wide temperature range (200&#8211;400 &#176;C), and excellent stability after hydrothermal and sulfur poisoning. It also displayed the highest NOx adsorption&#8211;storage capacity (NAC: 1889 &#956;mol/g; NSC: 1048 &#956;mol/g) at 300 &#176;C. This superior performance of the LS5 catalyst can be attributed to its superior reducibility, better NO oxidation capacity, increased surface Co2+ concentration, and, in particular, its generation of more oxygen vacancies. FTIR results further revealed that the LSX catalysts primarily store NOx through the &#8220;nitrate route&#8221;. During the lean&#8211;rich cycle tests, we observed an average NOx conversion rate of over 50% in the temperature range of 200&#8211;300 &#176;C, with a maximum conversion rate of 61% achieved at 250 &#176;C.</description>
      <author>Xinru Luan, Xudong Wang, T.S. Zhang, Liangran Gan, Jianxun Liu, Yujia Zhai, Wei Liu, Liguo Wang, Zhongpeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/compounds4020014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voltage Frequency Differential Protection Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17081845</link>
      <description>Zdravko Mati&#353;i&#263;, Tomislav Anti&#263;, Juraj Havelka, Tomislav Capuder, Energies. 17(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394754065

                Advancements in new technologies, a reduction in CO2 emissions, and the rising demand for energy are causing a growth in the share of renewable energy sources. In distribution networks, an increasing number of distributed generators (DGs) makes the utility grid&#8217;s protection complex and demanding. Vector surge and rate-of-change-of-frequency are the established anti-islanding protection methods, recognizing that the standard paradigm for protection, involving distributed generation, cannot be set only once but has to be continuously updated following the requirements and changes in the system. One of the requirements is active participation in the preservation of system frequency and voltage, which can be interrupted if the DG trips and disconnects from the utility grid. Anti-islanding protection and spurious tripping can be avoided by implementing new algorithms and techniques. This paper presents a novel protection scheme based on a voltage frequency differential. The proposed algorithm employs remote and local frequency measurements in such a manner that, for the occurrence of a frequency difference, it is assumed that the DG is in an islanding state. In this article, we demonstrate the feasibility of the algorithm through numerical analysis of grid events and laboratory testing emulating real grid-measured values. The test results show that the algorithm is resilient to false tripping for non-islanding events and more reliable than conventional methods in islanding detection. The algorithm can be set to low-frequency differential values, drastically reducing the non-detection zone in any DG type, regardless of its size and voltage level at the point of common coupling. Unlike standard anti-islanding methods, the algorithm supports the ability of the DG to fault-ride through demand.</description>
      <author>Zdravko Mati&#353;i&#263;, Tomislav Anti&#263;, Juraj Havelka, Tomislav Capuder</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17081845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing inflation and greenhouse gas emissions interplay via neural network analysis: a comparative study of energy use in the USA, EU, and China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12302-024-00905-w</link>
      <description>Mutaz AlShafeey, Mona Saleh, Environmental sciences Europe. 36(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394753901

                Abstract This study examines the relationship between inflation and greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions in three major economies: the United States of America (USA), the European Union (EU), and China. The analysis spans from 1960 to 2021 for the USA and EU, and from 1971 to 2021 for China. A feedforward neural network model, optimized using the Levenberg&#8211;Marquardt backpropagation algorithm, was employed to predict GHG emissions based on annual inflation rates and fossil fuel energy consumption. The study integrates historical data on inflation trends with GHG emissions, measured in CO2 equivalents, and fossil fuel energy consumption, expressed as a percentage of total energy use. This multidimensional approach allows for a nuanced understanding of the economic-environmental interplay in these regions. Key findings indicate a nonlinear response of GHG emissions to inflation rates. In the USA, GHG emissions begin to decrease when inflation rates exceed 4.7%. Similarly, in the EU, a steep reduction in emissions is observed beyond a 7.5% inflation rate. China presents a more complex pattern, with two critical inflection points: the first at a 4.5% inflation rate, where GHG emissions start to decline sharply, and the second at a 7% inflation rate, beyond which further increases in inflation do not significantly reduce emissions. A critical global insight is the identification of a uniform inflation rate, around 4.4%, across all regions, at which GHG emissions consistently increase by 1%, hinting at a shared global economic behavior impacting the environment. This discovery is vital for policymakers, emphasizing the need for tailored regional strategies that consider unique economic structures, energy policies, and environmental regulations, alongside a coordinated global approach.</description>
      <author>Mutaz AlShafeey, Mona Saleh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12302-024-00905-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic performance forecast analysis of MHP-PV/T-IDXSAHP system during heating season</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enbuild.2024.114175</link>
      <description>Jinping Li, Xiandong Chen, Xiaomin Liu, Zhiqian Jia, Y. C. Nan, Xiaofang Sun, Vojislav Novakovi&#263;, Energy and buildings. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394787228

                MHP-PV/T is a novel PV/T with phase change heat transfer, uniform flow of working medium and good anti-freeze performance. The excellent year-round performance of MHP-PV/T has been demonstrated in previous studies and is more suitable for winter heating in northern China. In this work, we further combine MHP-PV/T with dual source heat pump to form an experimentally validated indirect expansion-solar assisted heat pump (IDX-SAHP) system and simulates the overall performance of the heating system in winter based on TRNSYS in Lanzhou, China. The component type50b of TRNSYS was modified to make it closer to the actual results of MHP-PV/T. Research shown that the thermal efficiency of MHP-PV/T heat pump system can be maintained well throughout the heating season at the SAHP/ASHP switching temperature is 7 &#8451; in winter. The net system energy efficiency ratio (NSEER) during heating season is range from 3.28 to 5.42, which can achieve highly efficient and low cost heating. For this system, the photovoltaic power generation is sufficient to meet the operation of three water pumps. By connecting surplus electricity to the grid, a total of 1806.25 &#165; of electricity revenue can be obtained around the year. The PEUR of the system is 72.26 %, the DPP taking 5.133 years, and the annual CO2 emission reduction is 13486.5 kg. Significant energy, economic, and environmental benefits of the system. This study demonstrates the application prospects of PV/T heat pumps and provides a reference basis for subsequent research on MHP-PV/T heat pump systems in cold regions.</description>
      <author>Jinping Li, Xiandong Chen, Xiaomin Liu, Zhiqian Jia, Y. C. Nan, Xiaofang Sun, Vojislav Novakovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enbuild.2024.114175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Vision of the Reaction and Deactivation Routes in the Ethanol Steam Reforming on a Catalyst Derived from a Ni&#8211;Al Spinel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00646</link>
      <description>Sergio Iglesias-V&#225;zquez, Jos&#233; Valecillos, Aingeru Remiro, Beatr&#237;z Valle, Javier Bilbao, Ana G. Gayubo, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394603586

                Ethanol steam reforming (ESR) over a Ni/Al2O3 catalyst prepared by reduction of a NiAl2O4 spinel is a promising alternative route to produce H2 from biomass. This work deepens into the effect of reaction conditions (450&#8211;650 &#176;C, a steam/ethanol (S/E) ratio of 3&#8211;9, and a weight space time up to 1.3 h) and evaluates the time on stream evolution of the yields of H2, gaseous byproducts (CO, CO2, CH4, C2H4, C2H4O), and formed carbon/coke. The results are explained taking into consideration the thermodynamics, the extent of each individual reaction, and the catalyst deactivation. Up to 600 &#176;C, the predominant intermediate in the H2 formation is C2H4 (formed by ethanol dehydration) with the preferential formation of nanostructured carbon (nanotubes/filaments) by C2H4 decomposition. The deposition of this type of carbon partially deactivates the catalyst, mainly affecting the extent of the C2H4 decomposition causing a sharp decrease in the H2 and carbon yields. Nevertheless, the catalyst reaches a pseudosteady state with an apparent constant activity for other reactions in the kinetic scheme. At 650 &#176;C, C2H4O (formed by the ethanol dehydrogenation) is the main intermediate in the H2 formation, which is the precursor of an amorphous/turbostratic carbon (coke) formation that initially causes a rapid deactivation of the catalyst, affecting the ethanol dehydration and, to a lower extent, the reforming and water gas shift reactions. The increase in the S/E ratio favors the H2 formation, attenuates the catalyst deactivation due to the suppression of the ethanol dehydration to C2H4, and promotes the reforming, water gas shift, and carbon/coke gasification reactions. A H2 yield of 85% stable for 48 h on stream is achieved at 600 &#176;C, with a space time of 0.1 h and an S/E ratio of 9.</description>
      <author>Sergio Iglesias-V&#225;zquez, Jos&#233; Valecillos, Aingeru Remiro, Beatr&#237;z Valle, Javier Bilbao, Ana G. Gayubo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact and mitigation of Climate Change on the building performance of nonresidential buildings: Case studies of typical UK supermarkets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36828/xvqy0596</link>
      <description>Agha Usama Hasan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394742156

                The UK Government's Climate Change Act (CCA) aims to achieve a net zero greenhouse gas emission by 2050. Supermarkets, being among the most energy-intensive non-residential buildings, play a pivotal role in this endeavour. This research delves into the influence of climate change on supermarket buildings, exploring methodologies to mitigate its impact and assessing its effects on operational energy and carbon emissions. The United Nations has emphasized the built environment's significant contribution to global CO2 emissions, necessitating urgent action. Using a quantitative approach, this study employs the TAS &#8211; EDSL software to simulate energy consumption, carbon emission, and building regulations for various supermarket case studies. The research also evaluates the performance of these buildings across different UK climates and emission scenarios, incorporating EU Zebra2020 tool metrics. The primary challenge encountered was the scarcity of literature specifically targeting the UK supermarket industry in the context of climate change. The research underscores the importance of balancing energy consumption, carbon emissions, and future climate adaptations, especially given the industry's nZEB target by 2050. The findings of this study serve as a beacon for all non-residential buildings, bridging the knowledge gap between climate change, building futureproofing, and emission reduction strategies. The research underscores the importance of long-term planning, continuous monitoring of energy-intensive buildings, and the holistic approach of reducing emissions across a building's lifespan. This research aims to guide policymakers and building designers in future-proofing structures, emphasizing the need for energy-efficient measures and the integration of renewable technologies. The overarching goal is to foster the creation of sustainable, climate-resilient buildings for future generations.</description>
      <author>Agha Usama Hasan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36828/xvqy0596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep carbon recycling viewed from global plate tectonics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwae089</link>
      <description>Maoliang Zhang, Sheng Xu, Yuji Sano, National Science Review/National science review. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394765481

                Abstract Plate tectonics plays an essential role in the redistribution of life-essential volatile elements between Earth's interior and surface, whereby our planet has been well tuned to maintain enduring habitability over much of its history. Here we present an overview of deep carbon recycling in the regime of modern plate tectonics, with a special focus on convergent plate margins for assessing global carbon mass balance. The up-to-date flux compilation implies approximate balance between deep carbon outflux and subduction carbon influx within uncertainty but remarkably limited return of carbon to convecting mantle. If correct, carbon would gradually accumulate in the lithosphere over time by (i) massive subsurface carbon storage occurring primarily in continental lithosphere from convergent margins to continental interior and (ii) persistent surface carbon sinks to seafloors sustained by high-flux deep CO2 emissions to the atmosphere. Further assessment of global carbon mass balance requires updates on fluxes of subduction-driven carbon recycling paths and reduction in uncertainty of deep carbon outflux. From a global plate tectonics point of view, we particularly emphasize that continental reworking is an important mechanism for remobilizing geologically sequestered carbon in continental crust and sub-continental lithospheric mantle. In light of recent advances, future research is suggested to focus on a better understanding of the reservoirs, fluxes, mechanisms, and climatic effects of deep carbon recycling following an integrated methodology of observation, experiment, and numerical modeling, with the aim of decoding the self-regulating Earth system and its habitability from the deep carbon recycling perspective.</description>
      <author>Maoliang Zhang, Sheng Xu, Yuji Sano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwae089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydration kinetics, strength, autogenous shrinkage, and sustainability of cement pastes incorporating ultrafine limestone powder</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03149</link>
      <description>Wanli Zhang, Junyan Wang, Zhiwei Chen, Case studies in construction materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394602269

                This study investigated the effects of ordinary limestone powder (OLP) and two ultrafine limestone powders (ULPs) on the early and late age hydration characteristics of cement pastes with low water-to-binder (w/b) ratios of 0.21. The compressive strengths and autogenous shrinkage rates were also examined. Calorimetry and setting data showed that finer limestone powder (LP) significantly shortened the induction period and setting time of the paste and accelerated the early hydration reaction. The kinetic model showed that the rates of nucleation and crystal growth (NG), phase boundary reaction (I), and diffusion (D) increased, and the duration of process I decreased with increasing LP fineness. This indicated that the increased rate from the early hydration reaction was closely related to accelerated nucleation of smaller LP particles. Thermogravimetric-differential thermal analyses (TG-DTA) revealed that the finer LPs generated more hydration products and improved hydration degree in the later stages. Moreover, under favorable conditions for nucleation and increased effective w/b ratios, the hydration products of the LP pastes were formed rapidly, exceeding those of the pure paste at late stages. A finer LP increased the compressive strength and autogenous shrinkage, but due to the reduction in clinker, the compressive strength and autogenous shrinkage were lower than those of the pure paste. Mercury intrusion porosimetry (MIP) showed that the cumulative volume of the pores greater than 50 nm decreased when the LP was finer, thus increasing the compressive strength and autogenous shrinkage. The incorporation of 25 vol% ULP (dv,50 = 2.653 &#956;m) decreased the CO2 emissions per unit 28-day compressive strength by 17.34% compared to those of the pure paste. This study improves our understanding of the hydration behavior and properties of ULPs in cement-based materials with low w/b ratios and improves the use of LPs in HPC and UHPC.</description>
      <author>Wanli Zhang, Junyan Wang, Zhiwei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosis, Therapy and Follow-Up of Diabetes Mellitus in Children and Adolescents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1055/a-2166-6730</link>
      <description>Martin Holder, Thomas Kapellen, Ralph Ziegler, Jutta B&#252;rger-B&#252;sing, Thomas Danne, Axel Dost, Reinhard W. Holl, Paul&#8208;Martin Holterhus, Beate Karges, Olga Kordonouri, Karin Lange, Susanne M&#252;ller, Klemens Raile, Roland Schweizer, Simone von Sengbusch, Rainer Stachow, Verena Wagner, Susanna Wiegand, Andreas Neu, Experimental and clinical endocrinology &amp; diabetes. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394709774

                &#956;g microgram ABCC8 gene gene localization for the sulfonylurea receptor 1 ACE angiotensin-converting enzyme ACR albumin creatinine ratio ADA American Diabetes Association ADHD attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder AER albumin excretion rate AGA Working Group for Obesity/Arbeitsgemeinschaft f&#252;r Adipositas AGPD Working Group for Paediatric Diabetology/ Arbeitsgemeinschaft f&#252;r P&#228;diatrische Diabetologie AHCPR Agency for Health Care Policy and Research AIHA autoimmune hemolytic anemia Abs antibodies ALT alanine transaminase = liver enzyme APS Working Group for Paediatric Metabolic Disorders/Arbeitsgemeinschaft f&#252;r P&#228;diatrische Stoffwechselst&#246;rungen APS autoimmune polyglandular syndrome AT1 blocker angiotensin II type 1 receptor blocker AWMF German Association of the Scientific Medical Professional Societies/Arbeitsgemeinschaft der wissenschaftlichen medizinischen Fachgesellschaften BABYDIAB German BabyDiab-Study (German baby diabetes study) BAR Federal Working Group for Rehabilitation/ Bundesarbeitsgemeinschaft f&#252;r Rehabilitation BdKJ Association of Diabetic Children and Adolescents/ Bund diabetischer Kinder und Jugendlicher BG blood glucose BMI body mass index BMI-SDS body mass index standard deviation score BS blood sugar CFRD cystic fibrosis-related diabetes CGM continuous glucose monitoring CK creatine kinase C-peptide connecting peptide = part of proinsulin CSII continuous subcutaneous insulin injection = insulin pump CT computed tomography DAG German Obesity Society/Deutsche Adipositas Gesellschaft DAISY Diabetes Autoimmunity Study of the Young (autoimmunity study for adolescents with diabetes) DCC-Trial Diabetes Control and Complications Trial (study on the control and complications of diabetes) DDG German Diabetes Society/Deutsche Diabetes Gesellschaft DENIS German Nicotinamide Intervention Study/ Deutsche Nicotinamide-Intervention-Study DEPS-R Diabetes Eating Problem Survey &#8211; Revised DGE German Nutrition Society/Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#252;r Ern&#228;hrung DGEM German Society for Nutritional Medicine/ Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#252;r Ern&#228;hrungsmedizin DGKJP German Society for Paediatric and Adolescent Psychiatry, Psychosomatics and Psychotherapy/ Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#252;r Kinderund Jugendpsychiatrie, Psychosomatik und Psychotherapie diab. diabetic diabetesDE Diabetes Germany DIAMYD Diamyd&#174; Study DIPP Diabetes Prediction and Prevention Project DKA diabetic ketoacidosis dl decilitre DNSG Diabetes And Nutrition Study Group DPT-1 Diabetes Prevention Trial &#8211; Type 1 DPM Diabetes patient management (documentation system) EASD European Association for the Study of Diabetes EDIC-Trial Epidemiology of Diabetes Interventions and Complications Trial = Follow-up Study of the DCC Trial EIF2AK3 gene locus for mutations leading to a genetic syndrome with diabetes EC evidence class (methodological quality of a study according to criteria of evidencebased medicine) ECG electrocardiogram EMA European Medicines Agency European Nicotinamide Intervention Trial ES educational support (therapeutic support in parenting) ethn. ethnic fam. familiar FES family environment scale = scale for the evaluation of social characteristics and the environment of families FOXP3 gene locus for mutations leading to genetic syndromes with diabetes FST-D family system therapy for patients with diabetes fT3 free triiodothyronine fT4 free thyroxine g gram GAD glutamate decarboxylase GCK glucokinase h hour HbA1c glycated haemoglobin HDL high-density lipoprotein HHS hyperosmolar hyperglycaemic syndrome HLA human leukocyte antigen HNF hepatocyte nuclear factor HTA health technology assessment = systematic assessment of medical technologies, procedures aids and organizational structures, in which medical services are provided I.U. international unit(s) i. m. intramuscular IV intravenously IA-2 tyrosine phosphatase IA-2 antibody IAA insulin autoantibody ICA islet cell antibody ICT intensified conventional insulin therapy IgA immunoglobulin A IgG immunoglobulin G INS insulin(s) IPEX immunodysregulation polyendocrinopathy enteropathy X-linked syndrome IPF-1 insulin promoter factor 1 = gene locus with mutations leading to MODY-4 diabetes IRMA intraretinal microvascular anomaly ISPADISPAD International Society for Paediatric and Adolescent Diabetes ITP immune thrombocytopenic purpura Y years n/a not available kcal kilocalories KCNJ11 inward-rectifier potassium ion channel, subfamily J, member 11 kg kilogram BW body weight Kir6.2 gene locus for KCNJ11 KJHG child and youth welfare law l litre LDL low-density lipoprotein LGS low-glucose suspend m2 square meters max. maximum mg milligram micro microalbuminuria min. minimum avg. average MJ megajoule ml millilitre mm millimetre mmHg millimetres of mercury = used to measure blood pressure mmol millimole mon month(s) MODY maturity onset diabetes of the young (adult diabetes in adolescents) = monogenetic diabetes MRI magnetic resonance imaging n number NaCl sodium chloride NDM neonatal diabetes mellitus NCV nerve conduction velocity NPH insulin neutral protamine Hagedorn insulin NYHA New York Heart Association classification system for the severity of heart failure OGTT oral glucose tolerance test p p-value/probability value &#8211; exceeding probability, statistical information PAL value physical activity level (value for measuring the daily physical activity expenditure) Pat. patient(s) pCO2 arterial partial pressure of carbon dioxide pH potentia hydrogenii (capacity of hydrogen) = negative logarithm of the hydrogen ion concentration/activity, measure for acidity of a medium PLGM predictive low glucose management PNDM permanent neonatal diabetes mellitus RCT randomized controlled trial RR Riva Rocci = arterial blood pressure, measured according to the method of Riva Rocci s. c. subcutaneous SC standard care (standard treatment) SEARCH search for diabetes in the youth study (studies for the identification of diabetes in children and adolescents) SGB German Social Code Book/Sozialgesetzbuch SIGN Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network sign. significant SSRI selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor STIKO Standing Vaccination Commission of the Federal Republic of Germany/St&#228;ndige Impfkommission der Bundesrepublik Deutschland SaP sensor-augmented pump therapy SUR 1 sulphonylurea receptor 1 SaT sensor-augmented insulin therapy T3 triiodothyronine T4 thyroxine daily daily tTG-IgA tissue transglutaminase antibodies Tg thyroglobulin TNDM transient neonatal diabetes mellitus TPO thyroid peroxidase TSHR thyrotropin receptor TRIGR Trial to Reduce IDDM in the Genetically at the Risk (Study on the reduction of diabetes mellitus by immunodeficiency for genetical risks) TSH thyroid-stimulating hormone/thyrotropin U unit UK United Kingdom esp. especially vs. versus WHO World Health Organization c. a. condition after CNS central nervous system ZnT8 zinc transporter 8</description>
      <author>Martin Holder, Thomas Kapellen, Ralph Ziegler, Jutta B&#252;rger-B&#252;sing, Thomas Danne, Axel Dost, Reinhard W. Holl, Paul&#8208;Martin Holterhus, Beate Karges, Olga Kordonouri, Karin Lange, Susanne M&#252;ller, Klemens Raile, Roland Schweizer, Simone von Sengbusch, Rainer Stachow, Verena Wagner, Susanna Wiegand, Andreas Neu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1055/a-2166-6730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate emergency and decent work</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5271/sjweh.4162</link>
      <description>Fernando G. Benavides, George L. Delclos, Scandinavian journal of work, environment &amp; health. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394753278

                The climate crisis and loss of biodiversity, two closely related threats to human and planetary health, meet the criteria for the World Health Organization (WHO) to declare an international public health emergency, as occurred with COVID-19 (1), and urged by numerous scientific journals (2). Attaining decent work, understood as "opportunities for women and men to work in conditions of freedom, equity, security and human dignity" (3), in the context of the climate emergency, creates a paradox for worker health. Outdoor workers (notably those in agriculture and construction), many of them informal workers, are among the populations most vulnerable to climate-related hazards. Simultaneously, they are inevitably at risk of exposure due to their role in maintaining the economy and functioning of society. A similar situation happened during the pandemic with essential workers (4). The WHO declaration of a public health emergency helped manage that global crisis. A consequence of the industrial revolution The current climate crisis is a direct consequence of the Industrial Revolution where key processes emerged to explain the current situation: the appearance of wage labor and the working class, with consumerism as a basic economic driver, and the exploitation of natural resources &#8211; especially fossil fuels &#8211; in their own territories and in the colonies. The extension of this capitalist model of society to virtually the entire planet is a reality. Now, we see how this economic system has brought both great harm and significant benefits. Since its beginning, capitalism has wrought great suffering for people, masterfully described, among others, by Fredrich Engels in the Manchester of 1845 (5) or the London of 1838 in Charles Dickens` Oliver Twist (6). Although working conditions have since improved in many countries, there are still unbearable examples worldwide of worker exploitation and suffering. Among them, child labor, where 70% are working in agriculture (7) or some underregulated platform work (8), in a context of ever-increasing social inequalities (9). On the other hand, due to improved working and life conditions, there has also been an extraordinary increase in the world population, from one billion at the beginning of the 19th century to approximately eight billion today, leading to a linear increase in life expectancy at birth, which doubled globally between the beginning of the 20th century and the present. In 2015, the Lancet Commission on Planetary Health (10) pointed out that never before has humanity faced such an unintended paradox. While human well-being has been improving, the planet has been degrading. A contradiction that can no longer be sustained. We have lived as if our planet`s resources are unlimited. Based on comparisons to average temperature readings of the planet between 1850 and 1900, the United Nations International Panel on Climate Change estimated in its latest report that temperatures increased by 1.1&#176; C between 2011 and 2020. This increase is very close to the 1.5&#176; C established by the 2015 Paris Agreement as the limit beyond which climate impacts may become irreversible. Beyond any reasonable doubt, this is mostly attributable to the greenhouse effect produced by CO2 emissions, a consequence mainly of human activity and our way of living initiated by the Industrial Revolution. This global increase in temperature, with heat waves, floods and other extreme temperature events as its most obvious manifestations, is already having effects on worker health (12, 13). Climate change is also having effects on the economy and the labor market, both in the primary (agriculture and fishing) and services (tourism) sectors, with reductions in productivity and employment. Estimates from the European Commission reveal an average loss of 3% of GDP among EU countries between 1980 and 2020 (14). Simultaneously, we should not forget that the capitalist society that emerged from the Industrial Revolution is based, among other pillars, on full or near full employment. As such, wages represent the main economic resource for the majority of people, in addition to being the primary source of wealth generation for society, on whose income and taxes the welfare state was built. Of course, employment means much more than wage earning, as it plays a fundamental role in the social processes that sustain human dignity and social cohesion (15). However, only approximately 50% of the employed population, mainly in high-income countries, enjoy decent employment with a living wage and social rights (16). The resulting Gordian knot before us is enormous, with humanity facing the climate emergency and trying to move from fossil fuels to renewable energy sources, while simultaneously seeking to maintain and increase decent employment for all Earth`s inhabitants, boosting the welfare states at the same time (17). Controlling climate-related hazards and just green transition The alternatives proposed to escape this crossroads vary between those that propose a new paradigm, which radically changes the current economic model, betting on measures that break drastically from the capitalist economy (18), versus a gradual process, supported by mitigation, adaptation, and compensation policies (19). Favoring this second alternative, but without ruling out the need to profoundly change human consumption patterns with important repercussions on the productive system (energy, transportation, food, etc.), gradualist policies will also directly or indirectly impact employment and working conditions during the transition from carbon emission energy to green energy. To cope with this urgent situation, specific control measures have been proposed over the last few decades. Schulte and colleagues have systematically reviewed the literature (20, 21, 22), identifying new and exacerbated old climate-related hazards such as extreme temperatures, air pollution, ultraviolet radiation, natural disasters, biological hazards, indoor air quality, etc., and they also assessed the impact of employment transition and economic burden on occupational health equity and mental health. On this basis, the US National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health has elaborated recommendations to mitigate and control the impact of several climate-related hazards on worker health and well-being (23). Similarly, the EU Agency for Safety and Health at Work has published guidelines for heat at work (24). Going further, some governments, such as Spain, have begun regulating and enforcing specific measures (25). Implementation of these workplace preventive measures to mitigate the impact of climate change is the responsibility of employers, with full participation of workers. Devoting resources to hazard recognition; performing risk assessments to identify which workers are most vulnerable to climate change-related hazards; and implementing a control strategy with policies, procedures, equipment, and work organization changes aiming to eliminate or minimize the impact of these hazards can improve employer preparedness (26). Adaptation policies to reduce emissions of CO2 and other gases that are driving the greenhouse effect, still with limited results, could mean a loss of six million jobs worldwide, according to estimates of the International Labor Organization (ILO) (27). This same estimation predicts a promising creation of 24 million jobs, mainly in economies emphasizing recycling and reutilization of manufactured products (the so-called "circular economy"), infrastructure construction, development of renewables and energy efficiency. Also, during this transition, new forms of work will emerge (e.g., human-robot interfaces and artificial intelligence), and with them the need to train workers, both new and existing, to adapt to those new forms of work. While waiting for positive results from mitigation and adaptation policies, a just transition to a green economy must simultaneously incorporate compensation policies. To achieve this, it is essential to strengthen social protection systems, a cornerstone of decent employment. For example, there were measures adopted during the pandemic, such as temporary employment regulation for employees or benefits covering the cessation of activity of the self-employed. Similar compensation measures may help workers affected by mitigation and adaptation policies during a transition phase, possibly to a lesser degree than in the pandemic, but lasting longer. In summary, as was the case in the most recent public health emergency, the COVID-19 pandemic, declaring the climate emergency as an international public health emergency by the WHO could play a critical role in managing this new global health crisis. Research programs, supported by global occupational health surveillance systems, to monitor the effectiveness of mitigation, adaptation and compensation measures are urgent. Conflict of interest statement The authors report no conflicts of interest. References 1. WHO. International Health Regulations, 3rd edition. Geneva: WHO; 2016. Available on: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241580496. Accessed 4 February 2024. 2. Zielinski C. Time to treat the climate and nature crisis as one indivisible global health emergency. BMJ Open. 2023;13(10):e080907. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2023-080907 3. International Labour Organization. Report of the Director-General: decent work. Paper presented at the 87th Annual International Labour Conference, Geneva, 1999. Available at: https://www.ilo.org/public/english/standards/relm/ilc/ilc87/rep-i.htm [Accessed March 9 2024]. 4. Burdorf A, Porru F, Rugulies R. The COVID-19 (Coronavirus) pandemic: consequences for occupational health. Scand J Work Environ Health. 2020; 46(3):229-230. https://doi.org/10.5271/sjweh.3893 5. Engels, F. The condition of the working class in England (D. McLellan, Ed.). Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2009. https://doi.org/10.1093/owc/9780199554652.003.0151 6. Dickens C. Oliver Twist. London: Lacy; 1938. https://doi.org/10.1093/oseo/instance.00121337 7. Piketty, T. Capital in the twenty-first century (A. Goldhammer, Trans.). London: Belknap Press; 2017. https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctvjnrvx9 8. International Labour Organization, Issue paper on child labour and climate change, Geneva: ILO; 2023. Available on: https://www.ilo.org/global/about-the-ilo/newsroom/news/WCMS_905673/lang--en/index.htm. 9. Eurofound. Back to the future: Policy pointers from platform work scenarios, New forms of employment series. Luxembourg: Publications Office of the European Union; 2020. 10. Whitmee S, Haines A, Beyrer C et al. Safeguarding human health in the Anthropocene epoch: report of The Rockefeller Foundation-Lancet Commission on planetary health. Lancet. 2015;386(10007):1973-2028. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(15)60901-1 11. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). Synthesis report (SYR) of the IPCC sixth assessment report (AR6). Available on: https://www.ipcc.ch/report/sixth-assessment-report-cycle. Accessed 4 February 2024. 12. Mart&#237;nez-Solanas &#200;, L&#243;pez-Ruiz M, Wellenius GA, Gasparrini A et. Evaluation of the impact of ambient temperatures on occupational injuries in Spain. Environ Health Perspect. 2018;126(6):067002. https://doi.org/10.1289/EHP2590 13. Johnson RJ, Wesseling C, Newman LS. Chronic kidney disease of unknown cause in agricultural communities. N Engl J Med. 2019;380(19):1843-1852. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra1813869 14. European Environment Agency. Economic losses and fatalities from weather and climate-related events in Europe. Available on: https://www.eea.europa.eu/publications/economic-losses-and-fatalities-from#:~:text=Between%201980%20%20and%202020%2C%20total,of%20these%20losses%20were%20insured. Accessed 4 February 2024. 15. Budd JW. The thought of work. J Ind Rel. 2012;54(4):542-545. https://doi.org/10.1177/0022185612456331 16. Frank J, Mustard C, Smith P, Siddiqi A, Cheng Y, Burdorf A et al. Work as a social determinant of health in high-income countries: past, present, and future. Lancet. 2023 Oct 14;402(10410):1357-1367. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(23)00871-1 17. Benavides FG, Serra C, Delclos GL. What can public health do for the welfare state? Occupational health could be an answer. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2019;73(12):1141-1144. https://doi.org/10.1136/jech-2018-211561 18. Saito K. El capital en la era del Antropoceno. Barcelona: Penguin Random House Grupo Editorial, 2022. 19. Eurofound. Impact of climate change and climate policies on living conditions, working conditions, employment and social dialogue: A conceptual framework. Luxembourg: Eurofound research paper, Publications Office of the European Union; 2023. 20. Schulte PA, Chun H. Climate change and occupational safety andhealth: establishing a preliminary framework. J Occup Environ Hyg. 2009; 6:9, 542-554. https://doi.org/10.1080/15459620903066008 21. Schulte PA, Bhattacharya A, Butler CR et al. Advancing the framework for considering the effects of climate change on worker safety and health. J Occup Environ Hyg. 2016;13(11):847-65. https://doi.org/10.1080/15459624.2016.1179388 22. Schulte PA, Jacklitsch LB, Bhattacharya A et al. Updated assessment of occupational safety and health hazards of climate change. J Occup Environ Hyg. 2023;20(5-6):183-206, https://doi.org/10.1080/15459624.2023.2205468 23. US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH). Occupational safety and health and climate. Available on: https://www.cdc.gov/niosh/topics/climate/default.html. Accessed 6 February 2024. 24. European Agency for Safety and Health at Work. Heat at work - Guidance for workplaces. Available on: https://osha.europa.eu/en/publications/heat-work-guidance-workplaces. Accessed 7 February 2024. 25. Real Decreto-ley 4/2023, de 11 de mayo, por el que se adoptan medidas urgentes en materia de [&#8230;] prevenci&#243;n de riesgos laborales en episodios de elevadas temperaturas. Available on: https://www.boe.es/eli/es/rdl/2023/05/11/4. Accessed at 7 February 2024. 26. Levy, Barry S, Cora Roelofs. Impacts of climate change on workers' health and safety. Oxford Research Encyclopedia of Global Public Health. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1093/acrefore/9780190632366.013.39 27. International Labor Organization (ILO). World employment and social outlook 2018: Greening with jobs. Geneva: ILO; 2018. Available on: https://www.ilo.org/weso-greening/documents/WESO_Greening_EN_web2.pdf. Accessed at 7 February 2024.</description>
      <author>Fernando G. Benavides, George L. Delclos</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5271/sjweh.4162</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
