<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 17:07:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A general and facile calcination method to synthesize single-site catalysts for highly efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-023-6378-3</link>
      <description>Rui Sui, Bingyan Wang, Yongsheng Wang, Jiajing Pei, Wei Zhu, Wenxing Chen, Chunhui Li, Anbang Sun, Zhongbin Zhuang, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024.
No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Sui, Bingyan Wang, Yongsheng Wang, Jiajing Pei, Wei Zhu, Wenxing Chen, Chunhui Li, Anbang Sun, Zhongbin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-023-6378-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Redox Conversion of Formate to CO via Coupling Fe&#8208;Co Layered Double Hydroxides and Au Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202303383</link>
      <description>Xiaojiao Zheng, Qianbao Wu, Mengjun Xiao, Lei Li, Ruijuan Zhao, Chunhua Cui, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024.
Formate has been considered an inactive molecule and thus cannot be further reduced under CO2 reduction conditions, which limits its widespread application as feedstock. Here we present an electrochemical redox conversion of formate to CO through the potential&#8208;dependent generation of carbon dioxide radical anions (CO2&#8226;&#8208;) on Fe&#8208;Co layered double hydroxides (Fe&#8208;Co LDHs) and the subsequent reduction of CO2&#8226;&#8208; to CO on Au catalysts. We present an electrodeposition protocol for the synthesis of Fe&#8208;Co LDHs with precise composition control and find that Fe1Co4 exhibits a promising potential window for CO2&#8208;&#8226; formation between 1.14 and 1.4 V and an optimized potential at 1.24 V at a neutral pH condition. We further determined the formation of CO2&#8226;&#8208; at 1.24 V via electron paramagnetic resonance and CO2 at &amp;gt; 1.4 V through differential electrochemical mass spectrometry. This work provides a redox chemistry route for converting formate into CO through a coupled slit parallel&#8208;plate electrode system.</description>
      <author>Xiaojiao Zheng, Qianbao Wu, Mengjun Xiao, Lei Li, Ruijuan Zhao, Chunhua Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202303383</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequential co-reduction of nitrate and carbon dioxide enables selective urea electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44131-z</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Shu Guo Zheng, Hao L&#237;u, Qi Xiong, Haocong Yi, Haibin Yang, Zongwei Mei, Qinghe Zhao, Zhoulan Yin, Ming Huang, Yuan Lin, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Shi Xue Dou, Feng Pan, Shunning Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024.
Abstract Despite the recent achievements in urea electrosynthesis from co-reduction of nitrogen wastes (such as NO 3 &#8722; ) and CO 2 , the product selectivity remains fairly mediocre due to the competing nature of the two parallel reduction reactions. Here we report a catalyst design that affords high selectivity to urea by sequentially reducing NO 3 &#8722; and CO 2 at a dynamic catalytic centre, which not only alleviates the competition issue but also facilitates C&#8722;N coupling. We exemplify this strategy on a nitrogen-doped carbon catalyst, where a spontaneous switch between NO 3 &#8722; and CO 2 reduction paths is enabled by reversible hydrogenation on the nitrogen functional groups. A high urea yield rate of 596.1 &#181;g mg &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 with a promising Faradaic efficiency of 62% is obtained. These findings, rationalized by in situ spectroscopic techniques and theoretical calculations, are rooted in the proton-involved dynamic catalyst evolution that mitigates overwhelming reduction of reactants and thereby minimizes the formation of side products.</description>
      <author>Yang Li, Shu Guo Zheng, Hao L&#237;u, Qi Xiong, Haocong Yi, Haibin Yang, Zongwei Mei, Qinghe Zhao, Zhoulan Yin, Ming Huang, Yuan Lin, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Shi Xue Dou, Feng Pan, Shunning Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44131-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd&#8211;Mo bimetallic catalysts for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide to carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.118007</link>
      <description>Devina Thasia Wijaya, Chan Woo Lee, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024.
Electrochemical CO2 reduction is considered a promising solution to mitigate the increasing CO2 emissions in the atmosphere. Despite the promising potential of this process, highly active catalysts are needed to enable its efficient operation. Mixed metal oxide (MMO) materials can promote the formation of a dynamic interface between a metal and its oxidized form under applied potential, resulting in a unique interaction with the reaction intermediates. We synthesized a Pd&#8211;Mo MMO with controlled size and composition and examined the effect of these properties on CO2 electroreduction. Electron microscopy images confirmed the homogeneous distribution of the synthesized Pd7Mo1 on a ZIF-8-derived porous carbon support, with sizes of &#8764;1.3 and 4.5 nm for the samples annealed at 200 and 400 &#176;C, respectively. As shown by density functional theory calculations and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, adding 12.5 % Mo altered the electronic structure of Pd, enhancing CO desorption, and reducing the potential needed for CO production by up to &#8764;0.2 V, corresponding to a &#8764;40 % higher partial CO current density compared to pure Pd. This work demonstrates a facile MMO synthesis enabling particle size and composition control, which will facilitate the development of highly active MMO-derived nanoalloy materials for CO2 electroreduction.</description>
      <author>Devina Thasia Wijaya, Chan Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.118007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra&#8208;Fast Pulsed Discharge Preparation of Coordinatively Unsaturated Asymmetric Copper Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202312589</link>
      <description>Kaiyuan Liu, Zhaolin Sun, Wenxing Chen, Xiufeng Lang, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024.
Abstract Single&#8208;atom catalysts possess great potential for applications in electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reactions. Recently, the fast and low&#8208;cost preparation of highly efficient single&#8208;atom catalysts remains a challenge. Herein, a high&#8208;density current generated by pulsed discharge is employed for the formation of graphene aerogel anchored Cu single atom catalysts perfectly. The Cu atoms decomposed by Cu(NO 3 ) 2 &#8226;xH 2 O are fixed on graphene under the local transient high temperature and intense electromagnetic field. The activity and selectivity of formic acid are correlated with the coordinatively unsaturated Cu&#9472;N 1 O 1 moieties, reaching an optimal Faradaic efficiency (93.7%) at &#8722;0.9 V versus a reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). In situ characterizations reveal that the asymmetric Cu&#9472;N/O structure in a pinched state displays better catalytic activity in CO 2 RR. Density functional theory results indicate that the Cu&#9472;N 1 O 1 sites regulate the adsorption configuration of intermediates and lower the energy barrier for the hydrogenation of * OCHO species, thereby promoting CO 2 &#8208;to&#8208;HCOOH conversion.</description>
      <author>Kaiyuan Liu, Zhaolin Sun, Wenxing Chen, Xiufeng Lang, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202312589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Based Materials for Enhanced C2+ Product Selectivity in Photo-/Electro-Catalytic CO2 Reduction: Challenges and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-023-01276-2</link>
      <description>Baker Rhimi, Min Zhou, Zaoxue Yan, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhifeng Jiang, Nano-Micro Letters. 16(1)] 2024.
Abstract Carbon dioxide conversion into valuable products using photocatalysis and electrocatalysis is an effective approach to mitigate global environmental issues and the energy shortages. Among the materials utilized for catalytic reduction of CO 2 , Cu-based materials are highly advantageous owing to their widespread availability, cost-effectiveness, and environmental sustainability. Furthermore, Cu-based materials demonstrate interesting abilities in the adsorption and activation of carbon dioxide, allowing the formation of C 2+ compounds through C&#8211;C coupling process. Herein, the basic principles of photocatalytic CO 2 reduction reactions (PCO 2 RR) and electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction reaction (ECO 2 RR) and the pathways for the generation C 2+ products are introduced. This review categorizes Cu-based materials into different groups including Cu metal, Cu oxides, Cu alloys, and Cu SACs, Cu heterojunctions based on their catalytic applications. The relationship between the Cu surfaces and their efficiency in both PCO 2 RR and ECO 2 RR is emphasized. Through a review of recent studies on PCO 2 RR and ECO 2 RR using Cu-based catalysts, the focus is on understanding the underlying reasons for the enhanced selectivity toward C 2+ products. Finally, the opportunities and challenges associated with Cu-based materials in the CO 2 catalytic reduction applications are presented, along with research directions that can guide for the design of highly active and selective Cu-based materials for CO 2 reduction processes in the future.</description>
      <author>Baker Rhimi, Min Zhou, Zaoxue Yan, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhifeng Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-023-01276-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide reduction utilizing a bismuth halide perovskite as immobilized photocatalyst in a 3D printed microreactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6439/ad1b1c</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Francisco Ruiz Cordero, Hannia L&#243;pez Mena, Marisol Ledezma, Leslie W. Pineda, J. Herrera, Journal of Micromechanics and Microengineering. None(None)] 2024.
Abstract The rising concerns about CO 2 levels in the atmosphere and energy dependency on non-renewable sources, such as fossil fuels, could find an integral solution in CO 2 photocatalytic reduction. The present work explores two alternatives to the main hindering factors for this reaction, i.e., the reactor configuration and the photocatalyst utilized. A microreactor was designed and 3D printed, providing a cheap and versatile reaction platform. Three bismuth halide perovskites, Cs 3 Bi 2 Cl 9 , Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 , and Cs 4 MnBi 2 Cl 12 , were synthesized and characterized by their band gaps (E g ); Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 presented the lowest E g and was therefore chosen for further evaluation as potential CO 2 -reduction photocatalyst. Aqueous-phase photocatalytic CO 2 reduction was achieved using this perovskite in the microreactor, obtaining CO as a reduction product with maximal production rates of 737 &#956;mol g cat -1 h -1 . The reaction system was evaluated under different flow rates and light intensities. A balance between space-time and reactant feed was found to define the behavior of CO concentration and production in the microreactor. For the light intensity, it was observed that as it increased, both CO production and concentration increased due to generating more electron-hole pairs, favoring the photocatalytic reaction. With these results, Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 perovskite immobilized in the designed microreactor demonstrates having great potential as an effective CO 2 photocatalytic reduction system.&amp;amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Francisco Ruiz Cordero, Hannia L&#243;pez Mena, Marisol Ledezma, Leslie W. Pineda, J. Herrera</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6439/ad1b1c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full-exposed Cu site of Cu2O-(1 0 0) driven high ethylene selectivity of carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.159243</link>
      <description>Youming Dong, Xingcheng Ma, Zhaoyong Jin, Xin Xu, Tianyi Xu, Dantong Zhang, Xiaoqiang Cui, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024.
Cu2O shows great potential as a catalyst for the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (ECO2RR). However, the mechanism behind the formation of different final products from Cu2O nanostructures remains a challenge. In this study, we combine theoretical and experimental approaches to demonstrate that the full-exposed Cu sites in Cu2O (1 0 0) microcubes contribute to superior C2H4 selectivity compared to other microstructures such as Cu2O (1 1 1), (1 1 0), and (3 1 1) facets. Density functional theoretical (DFT) calculations reveal that the stronger orbital splitting between Cu 3d and O 2p orbital of Cu2O (1 0 0) facet facilitates the formation of neighboring and low valence state Cu active site, thereby enhancing *CO adsorption and C2H4 formation. These DFT results are supported by the synthesis of four kinds of Cu2O microparticles (MPs) with different exposed facets, where cubic-Cu2O with the (1 0 0) facet exhibits the highest Faradaic efficiency (61.3 %). This study has significant implications for the structural design and mechanism analysis of innovative catalysts used in ECO2RR.</description>
      <author>Youming Dong, Xingcheng Ma, Zhaoyong Jin, Xin Xu, Tianyi Xu, Dantong Zhang, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.159243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd&#8211;Mo bimetallic catalysts for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide to carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.118007</link>
      <description>Devina Thasia Wijaya, Chan Woo Lee, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024.
Electrochemical CO2 reduction is considered a promising solution to mitigate the increasing CO2 emissions in the atmosphere. Despite the promising potential of this process, highly active catalysts are needed to enable its efficient operation. Mixed metal oxide (MMO) materials can promote the formation of a dynamic interface between a metal and its oxidized form under applied potential, resulting in a unique interaction with the reaction intermediates. We synthesized a Pd&#8211;Mo MMO with controlled size and composition and examined the effect of these properties on CO2 electroreduction. Electron microscopy images confirmed the homogeneous distribution of the synthesized Pd7Mo1 on a ZIF-8-derived porous carbon support, with sizes of &#8764;1.3 and 4.5 nm for the samples annealed at 200 and 400 &#176;C, respectively. As shown by density functional theory calculations and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, adding 12.5 % Mo altered the electronic structure of Pd, enhancing CO desorption, and reducing the potential needed for CO production by up to &#8764;0.2 V, corresponding to a &#8764;40 % higher partial CO current density compared to pure Pd. This work demonstrates a facile MMO synthesis enabling particle size and composition control, which will facilitate the development of highly active MMO-derived nanoalloy materials for CO2 electroreduction.</description>
      <author>Devina Thasia Wijaya, Chan Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.118007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequential co-reduction of nitrate and carbon dioxide enables selective urea electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44131-z</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Shu Guo Zheng, Hao L&#237;u, Qi Xiong, Haocong Yi, Haibin Yang, Zongwei Mei, Qinghe Zhao, Zhoulan Yin, Ming Huang, Yuan Lin, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Shi Xue Dou, Feng Pan, Shunning Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024.
Abstract Despite the recent achievements in urea electrosynthesis from co-reduction of nitrogen wastes (such as NO 3 &#8722; ) and CO 2 , the product selectivity remains fairly mediocre due to the competing nature of the two parallel reduction reactions. Here we report a catalyst design that affords high selectivity to urea by sequentially reducing NO 3 &#8722; and CO 2 at a dynamic catalytic centre, which not only alleviates the competition issue but also facilitates C&#8722;N coupling. We exemplify this strategy on a nitrogen-doped carbon catalyst, where a spontaneous switch between NO 3 &#8722; and CO 2 reduction paths is enabled by reversible hydrogenation on the nitrogen functional groups. A high urea yield rate of 596.1 &#181;g mg &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 with a promising Faradaic efficiency of 62% is obtained. These findings, rationalized by in situ spectroscopic techniques and theoretical calculations, are rooted in the proton-involved dynamic catalyst evolution that mitigates overwhelming reduction of reactants and thereby minimizes the formation of side products.</description>
      <author>Yang Li, Shu Guo Zheng, Hao L&#237;u, Qi Xiong, Haocong Yi, Haibin Yang, Zongwei Mei, Qinghe Zhao, Zhoulan Yin, Ming Huang, Yuan Lin, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Shi Xue Dou, Feng Pan, Shunning Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44131-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilized Tetraalkylammonium Cations Enable Metal&#8208;free CO2 Electroreduction in Acid and Pure Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202317828</link>
      <description>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024.
Carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) provides an efficient pathway to convert CO2 into desirable products, yet its commercialization is greatly hindered by the huge energy cost due to CO2 loss and regeneration. Performing CO2RR under acidic conditions containing alkali cations can potentially address the issue, but still causes (bi)carbonate deposition at high current densities, compromising product Faradaic efficiencies (FEs) in present&#8208;day acid&#8208;fed membrane electrode assemblies. Herein, we present a strategy using a positively charged polyelectrolyte &#8212; poly(diallyldimethylammonium) immobilized on graphene oxide via electrostatic interactions to displace alkali cations. This enables a FE of ~85%, a carbon efficiency of ~93%, and an energy efficiency (EE) of ~35% for CO at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 on modified Ag catalysts in acid. In a pure&#8208;water&#8208;fed reactor, we obtained a 78% CO FE with a 30% EE at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 at 40oC . All the performance metrics are comparable to or even exceed those attained in the presence of alkali metal cations.</description>
      <author>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202317828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilized Tetraalkylammonium Cations Enable Metal&#8208;free CO2 Electroreduction in Acid and Pure Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202317828</link>
      <description>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024.
Carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) provides an efficient pathway to convert CO2 into desirable products, yet its commercialization is greatly hindered by the huge energy cost due to CO2 loss and regeneration. Performing CO2RR under acidic conditions containing alkali cations can potentially address the issue, but still causes (bi)carbonate deposition at high current densities, compromising product Faradaic efficiencies (FEs) in present&#8208;day acid&#8208;fed membrane electrode assemblies. Herein, we present a strategy using a positively charged polyelectrolyte &#8212; poly(diallyldimethylammonium) immobilized on graphene oxide via electrostatic interactions to displace alkali cations. This enables a FE of ~85%, a carbon efficiency of ~93%, and an energy efficiency (EE) of ~35% for CO at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 on modified Ag catalysts in acid. In a pure&#8208;water&#8208;fed reactor, we obtained a 78% CO FE with a 30% EE at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 at 40oC . All the performance metrics are comparable to or even exceed those attained in the presence of alkali metal cations.</description>
      <author>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202317828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating CHO* intermediate pathway towards the significant acceleration of photocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4 through rGO-coated ultrafine Pd nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2023.148497</link>
      <description>Fanlin Kong, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Jindou Hu, Yue Feng, Yali Cao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024.
Tailoring catalytic reaction pathways by using reduced graphene oxide (rGO) to tune the electron-hole separation channels in the active sites of noble metals for achieving ideal yield and selectivity in photocatalytic CO2 reduction of hydrocarbon fuels remains a challenge. Herein, ternary catalyst of rGO-coated SnO2-supported noble metal Pd nanoparticles (Pd4/SnO2@rGO) has been prepared by coassembly between negatively charged graphene oxide and positively charged Pd nanoparticles. By coating with ultrathin rGO, the selectivity can be shifted from CO (44.69 % for Pd4/SnO2) toward CH4 as the prevalent species, in which the Pd nanoparticles acted as catalytic sites and electron capture sites. The rGO coating reduced the recombination of the photogenerated carriers as well as optimized the band gap and reduction potential of the catalyst. The in situ spectroscopic tests and density functional theory calculations revealed that CO2 adsorbed on Pd nanoparticles selectively formed dominant low-energy CHO* intermediates because of the generation of HCOOH* intermediates, thus providing a unique reaction pathway for the reduction of CO2 to CH4. Therefore, under sunlight irradiation, the CH4 selectivity of the catalyst is enhanced to 94.1 % with a production rate of up to 77.8 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1. This work demonstrated the prospect to tune the electronic structure of Pd using rGO, which provided a strategy for enhancing the carbon dioxide reduction reaction and selectively obtaining CH4 products in photocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Fanlin Kong, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Jindou Hu, Yue Feng, Yali Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2023.148497</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra&#8208;Fast Pulsed Discharge Preparation of Coordinatively Unsaturated Asymmetric Copper Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202312589</link>
      <description>Kaiyuan Liu, Zhaolin Sun, Wenxing Chen, Xiufeng Lang, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024.
Abstract Single&#8208;atom catalysts possess great potential for applications in electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reactions. Recently, the fast and low&#8208;cost preparation of highly efficient single&#8208;atom catalysts remains a challenge. Herein, a high&#8208;density current generated by pulsed discharge is employed for the formation of graphene aerogel anchored Cu single atom catalysts perfectly. The Cu atoms decomposed by Cu(NO 3 ) 2 &#8226;xH 2 O are fixed on graphene under the local transient high temperature and intense electromagnetic field. The activity and selectivity of formic acid are correlated with the coordinatively unsaturated Cu&#9472;N 1 O 1 moieties, reaching an optimal Faradaic efficiency (93.7%) at &#8722;0.9 V versus a reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). In situ characterizations reveal that the asymmetric Cu&#9472;N/O structure in a pinched state displays better catalytic activity in CO 2 RR. Density functional theory results indicate that the Cu&#9472;N 1 O 1 sites regulate the adsorption configuration of intermediates and lower the energy barrier for the hydrogenation of * OCHO species, thereby promoting CO 2 &#8208;to&#8208;HCOOH conversion.</description>
      <author>Kaiyuan Liu, Zhaolin Sun, Wenxing Chen, Xiufeng Lang, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202312589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Impacts of Biochar Addition to Substrate on Mitigating Carbon Dioxide Emissions in Green Roofs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46109-5_11</link>
      <description>Gaochuan Zhang, Bin Tang, Haohao Bian, Yangfei Huang, Hexian Jin, Bao&#8208;Jie He, Advances in science, technology &amp; innovation. None(None)] 2023.
The utilization of biochar is often heralded as a salient approach to curtailing emissions and sequestering carbon. Agricultural and forestry soils have demonstrated its efficaciousness in reducing carbon emissions; however, the urban greening industry has yet to be thoroughly researched in this regard. To address this lacuna, the present study undertook the application of biochar to the soil of an urban green roof, with the aim of ascertaining its potential to mitigate carbon dioxide emissions. By studying the effects of applying BS-0%, BS-1%, BS-5%, and BS-10% biochar on green roof substrate, the study examined the carbon dioxide value over a period of 36 h encompassing both sunny and nocturnal environments. The results indicated that the addition of biochar to the soil was effective in reducing carbon emission, with all of the biochar additions demonstrating an aptitude for carbon dioxide fixation. Notably, the application of BS-1% biochar evinced a statistically significant reduction in the carbon dioxide value. Furthermore, the addition of biochar to the roof substrate was found to be crucial in controlling rainwater runoff and alleviating urban eutrophication, indirectly reducing carbon emissions. This study provides a practical and theoretical framework for the application of biochar to mitigate the urban heat island effect.</description>
      <author>Gaochuan Zhang, Bin Tang, Haohao Bian, Yangfei Huang, Hexian Jin, Bao&#8208;Jie He</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46109-5_11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217; Benefits from Superelevated CO2 While Adapting to Far-red Light Over Time</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21273/hortsci17522-23</link>
      <description>Emily J. Kennebeck, Qingguo Meng, Hortscience. 59(2)] 2024.
Compared with the ambient Earth carbon dioxide concentration (&#8776;415 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 ), the International Space Station has superelevated carbon dioxide (&#8776;2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 ), which can be a stressor to certain crops. Far-red light can drive plant photosynthesis and increase extension growth and biomass. However, the effects of far-red light under superelevated carbon dioxide are unclear. We grew hydroponic mustard ( Brassica carinata ) &#8216;Amara&#8217; seedlings in four growth chambers using a randomized complete block design with two carbon dioxide concentrations (415 and 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 ), two lighting treatments, and two blocks at temperature and relative humidity set points of 22 &#176;C and 40%, respectively. Each growth chamber had two lighting treatments at the same total photon flux density of 200 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 . Under the same blue and green light at 50 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 each, plants received either red light at 100 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 or red + far-red light at 50 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 each. At day 15 after planting, far-red light did not influence shoot fresh or dry mass at 415 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide, but decreased both parameters by 22% to 23% at 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide. Increasing the carbon dioxide concentration increased shoot fresh and dry mass 27% to 49%, regardless of the lighting treatment. Far-red light decreased leaf area by 16% at 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide, but had no effect at 415 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide. Increasing the carbon dioxide concentration increased leaf area by 21% to 33%, regardless of far-red light. Regardless of the carbon dioxide concentration, far-red light promoted stem elongation and decreased chlorophyll concentrations by 39% to 42%. These responses indicate far-red light elicited a crop-specific shade avoidance response in mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217;, increasing extension growth but decreasing leaf area, thereby reducing light interception and biomass. In addition, carbon dioxide enrichment up to 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 increased the biomass of mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217; but decreased the biomass of other crops, indicating crop-specific tolerance to superelevated carbon dioxide. In conclusion, mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217; seedlings benefit from superelevated carbon dioxide, but exhibit growth reduction under far-red light under superelevated carbon dioxide.</description>
      <author>Emily J. Kennebeck, Qingguo Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21273/hortsci17522-23</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Water Heating: Comprehensive Review, Critical Analysis and Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.z0lx6v</link>
      <description>Amal Herez, No host. None(None)] 2023.
The increasing global demand for renewable energy sources underscores the significance of Solar Water Heating Systems (SWHS), emphasizing the need for thorough research and analysis in this domain. SWHS play a pivotal role in addressing energy efficiency and environmental sustainability, making it imperative to conduct in-depth studies on their utilization. Hence, this paper aims to provide a comprehensive overview of SWHS. It starts by explaining the principles behind these systems, including their components and classification. Moreover, this review consolidates various studies that have been conducted on SWHS to highlight both their advantages and disadvantages. Additionally, a case study is conducted in which it takes into consideration important economic and environmental factors. In particular, it focuses on several scenarios present in Lebanon such as family homes, schools, restaurants hotels and gyms to estimate potential cost savings achieved through implementing SWHS as opposed to relying solely on electric heaters. Furthermore, this investigation also examines the corresponding payback period associated with adopting SWHS along with assessing the significant reduction in carbon dioxide emissions possible if these systems were widely implemented. The findings of the study demonstrate that there is a direct correlation between the extent to which SWHS are utilized and both the payback period and reduction in CO2 emissions. It was observed that when SWHS are used more frequently, with a high percentage of time (Pr=0.9), significant advantages can be achieved. For instance, for different types of establishments such as family homes, schools, restaurants, hotels, and gyms, it was estimated that average payback periods would be 14.2 years, 4.6 years, 9.2 years, 4.4 years, and 5.3 years, respectively. These results indicate that adopting a greater dependency on SWHSs not only leads to quicker cost recovery but also significantly contributes towards reducing carbon dioxide emissions. The analysis reveals that the yearly decrease in carbon dioxide emissions per individual is 0.16 t within a household, 0.016 t per student in an educational institution, 0.04 t per customer within a dining establishment, 0.37 t for each occupied bed in a hotel accommodation, and 0.11 t per individual at a gym. This paper serves as guidelines to SWH community. Additionally, it adds a practical insights into economic and environmental issues relevant to both Lebanon and countries with similar climates.</description>
      <author>Amal Herez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.z0lx6v</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of tillage methods on carbon dioxide emissions in spring wheat crops</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/20248206006</link>
      <description>Evgeniy Demin, Stanislav Miller, Kirill Likhanov, BIO web of conferences. 82(None)] 2024.
The agriculture intensification is associated with an increase in anthropogenic load on arable soils. Tillage leads to disruption of the natural process of soil formation in connection with which the soil biota activity changes and the carbon cycle is disrupted. The purpose of the study is to establish the effects of the tillage method on the carbon dioxide emission in spring wheat crops. The emission of carbon dioxide during the growing season of spring wheat varies significantly depending on the soil processing method and temperature. At the beginning of spring wheat development, the daily emission of carbon dioxide during the dump and subsurface tillage method does not exceed 36.0 and 36.2 CO 2 kg/ha using zero technology provides a reduction in production CO 2 production to 27.8 kg/ha*day. With an increase in soil temperature by July 24, the daily emission increases on a dump and subsurface background to 105.5 and 106.0 CO 2 kg/ha*day, on a zero background to 95.4 CO 2 kg/ha*day. In the future, it decreases. The total carbon losses during the dump and subsurface tillage methods are 2829 and 2793 kg/ha, the use of zero tillage technology reduces carbon losses in grain agrocenosis by 18%.</description>
      <author>Evgeniy Demin, Stanislav Miller, Kirill Likhanov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/20248206006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the coal saving and emission reduction potential of advanced technologies in China's iron and steel industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esd.2023.101373</link>
      <description>Hui Huang, Mengyun Guan, Qing Wang, Jun Zhao, Qiong Yang, Energy for Sustainable Development. 78(None)] 2024.
The coal-based energy consumption structure has led to high coal consumption and carbon emissions in China's iron and steel industry, and the task of coal saving and carbon reduction in the steel industry is difficult and urgent. The economic viability of various coal-saving and emission-reduction technologies, the extent of their coal-saving and emission-reduction potential, and the guidance on the adoption of advanced technologies are crucial issues that need to be addressed in the Chinese steel industry. This article employs the Energy-Production (E-P) analysis method and the Conservation Supply Curve (CSC) model incorporating coal consumption ratio coefficients to systematically analyze coal consumption and carbon dioxide emissions in the overall iron and steel industry and its sub-processes under different scenarios. It calculates the coal-saving emission reduction costs of 32 technologies, evaluates them comprehensively based on their coal-saving and emission-reduction potentials and cost-effectiveness, and categorizes them accordingly. According to the cost of coal saving and emission reduction as the demarcation point, a total of 19 technologies are cost-effective; according to the coal-saving emission reduction potential and cost division, 32 technologies are divided into 6 categories, among which 6 technologies such as sintering waste heat recovery technology can be used as key technologies for popularization and application. Seven technologies, such as efficient preheating technology of ladle, have high cost and low potential, which can be gradually eliminated or improved and upgraded. After the comprehensive promotion of the 32 technologies, the maximum coal saving potential is about 3.453 billion GJ, the CO2 emission reduction potential is 395 million tons, the total coal consumption of the steel industry can be reduced to about 13.904 billion GJ, and the carbon dioxide emissions can be reduced to 1.179 billion tons.</description>
      <author>Hui Huang, Mengyun Guan, Qing Wang, Jun Zhao, Qiong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esd.2023.101373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Operation of On-Grid Park &amp;amp; Ride EV Parking Station Considering Dynamic Pricing in Japan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/itecasia-pacific59272.2023.10372344</link>
      <description>Soichiro Ueda, N. Kumarappan, Masahiro Furukakoi, Ashraf Mohamed Hemeida, Hasan Masrur, Tomonobu Senjyu, No host. None(None)] 2023.
In recent years, achieving a decarbonized society has necessitated reducing greenhouse gas emissions. Many countries set goals to reduce their greenhouse gas emissions during each of these periods. To achieve this goal, the introduction of carbon dioxide-free Electric Vehicles will be effective. In this paper, we propose an on-grid Park &amp; Ride parking station to charge EVs with PV and WG. We also showed that the dynamic pricing case with varying electricity prices is better than the constant electricity price case. Variable prices encourage the purchase of electricity during the hours when electricity price is low. Such price cases contribute the reduction of operating costs.</description>
      <author>Soichiro Ueda, N. Kumarappan, Masahiro Furukakoi, Ashraf Mohamed Hemeida, Hasan Masrur, Tomonobu Senjyu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/itecasia-pacific59272.2023.10372344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecological Impact versus Energy Generation by Floating Photovoltaic Power Plant for a Small Romanian Lake</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378724</link>
      <description>Gabriela Elena Dumitran, Liana Ioana Vu&#355;&#259;, Bogdan Popa, No host. None(None)] 2023.
The development of floating photovoltaic systems in Romania can help to the share of more than 30.7 % of the total energy produced from renewable energy sources set for the year 2030. Floating photovoltaic plants ensure the achievement of overall energy targets without affecting biodiversity and/or agricultural crops. This study evaluates the insolation and the possibility of installing this technology on Lake F&#259;c&#259;u, Romania, to benefit from the generation of electricity but also better water quality and reduction of carbon dioxide emissions $\left(\mathrm{CO}_{2}\right)$. The obtained results are promising as Floating photovoltaic plants covering around 0.22 % of the lake surface, provide 26.76 $M W h /$ year and the estimated reduction of CO &lt;inf xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;2&lt;/inf&gt; emission is 7.52 $\mathbf{t C O}_{2 \mathrm{eq}} /$ year.</description>
      <author>Gabriela Elena Dumitran, Liana Ioana Vu&#355;&#259;, Bogdan Popa</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near-Infrared Reflective Greenhouse Covering: A Novel Strategy for Electricity-Free Cooling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsagscitech.3c00281</link>
      <description>Song Zhang, Zhang Chen, Chuanxiang Cao, Yanfeng Gao, ACS Agricultural Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024.
Traditional cooling strategies for greenhouses commonly result in significant electricity consumption and a substantial release of carbon dioxide emissions. Considering the industrial fabrication process for the greenhouse covering film and the thermal management theory, we developed a composite greenhouse covering film that incorporates titanium dioxide into polyethylene to achieve near-infrared reflection. The film demonstrates an impressive near-infrared reflectance of 54.4% within the wavelength range of 780&#8211;2500 nm. A tunnel-type greenhouse demo comparative test results show that the composite film can effectively decrease the average temperature inside the greenhouse by 6.7 &#176;C in comparison to the pure polyethylene film. The reduction implies a significant annual saving in cooling electricity at the national level of 2151912.3 MW h, along with an annual CO2 emission reduction by 1250261.1 tons.</description>
      <author>Song Zhang, Zhang Chen, Chuanxiang Cao, Yanfeng Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsagscitech.3c00281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Potential Carbon Dioxide Utilization Pathways in Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/asec2023-15503</link>
      <description>Azizbek Kamolov, Zafar Turakulov, Adham Norkobilov, Miroslav Variny, Marcos Fallanza, No host. None(None)] 2023.
Reaching net-zero emissions by the middle of this century requires the implementation of massive carbon dioxide (CO2) emission reduction strategies along with the reduction of other greenhouse gases on both global and country scales. Thus, carbon capture, storage, and utilization (CCSU) is a promising technology in combination with renewable energy transition. Currently, CO2 utilization has attracted much attention from the scientific community worldwide, since it can improve the economic viability of CCSU deployment by creating a market for the recovered CO2 stream. In this study, a brief assessment and comparison of potential CO2 utilization pathways in Uzbekistan, including CO2-to-chemical/fuel conversion, CO2 bio-fixation/mineralization, and the direct use of CO2, such as for enhanced hydrocarbon recovery (EHR), are conducted considering the CO2 stationary sources and site-specific conditions of the country. In addition, possible challenges and opportunities for large-scale CO2 utilization routes are also discussed. According to this assessment, there is great potential for the direct use of CO2 as a process-boosting agent for EHR in more than 22 major natural gas, crude oil, and coal reservoirs. Moreover, methanol and urea production processes can also create huge market demand for recovered CO2 as long as the conventional CO2 production processes are replaced by sustainable ones.</description>
      <author>Azizbek Kamolov, Zafar Turakulov, Adham Norkobilov, Miroslav Variny, Marcos Fallanza</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/asec2023-15503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Based Materials for Enhanced C2+ Product Selectivity in Photo-/Electro-Catalytic CO2 Reduction: Challenges and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-023-01276-2</link>
      <description>Baker Rhimi, Min Zhou, Zaoxue Yan, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhifeng Jiang, Nano-Micro Letters. 16(1)] 2024.
Abstract Carbon dioxide conversion into valuable products using photocatalysis and electrocatalysis is an effective approach to mitigate global environmental issues and the energy shortages. Among the materials utilized for catalytic reduction of CO 2 , Cu-based materials are highly advantageous owing to their widespread availability, cost-effectiveness, and environmental sustainability. Furthermore, Cu-based materials demonstrate interesting abilities in the adsorption and activation of carbon dioxide, allowing the formation of C 2+ compounds through C&#8211;C coupling process. Herein, the basic principles of photocatalytic CO 2 reduction reactions (PCO 2 RR) and electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction reaction (ECO 2 RR) and the pathways for the generation C 2+ products are introduced. This review categorizes Cu-based materials into different groups including Cu metal, Cu oxides, Cu alloys, and Cu SACs, Cu heterojunctions based on their catalytic applications. The relationship between the Cu surfaces and their efficiency in both PCO 2 RR and ECO 2 RR is emphasized. Through a review of recent studies on PCO 2 RR and ECO 2 RR using Cu-based catalysts, the focus is on understanding the underlying reasons for the enhanced selectivity toward C 2+ products. Finally, the opportunities and challenges associated with Cu-based materials in the CO 2 catalytic reduction applications are presented, along with research directions that can guide for the design of highly active and selective Cu-based materials for CO 2 reduction processes in the future.</description>
      <author>Baker Rhimi, Min Zhou, Zaoxue Yan, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhifeng Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-023-01276-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Life Cycle Assessment of Reusable and Disposable Distribution Packaging for Fresh Food</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20909/kopast.2023.29.3.181</link>
      <description>Kim Sy, CHAROENSRI KORAKOT, Shin Yj, Park Hj, Han-gug pojang hag-hoeji. 29(3)] 2023.
In this study, we conducted a comparative life cycle assessment (LCA) of two different products, considering reusable and single-use packaging for fresh food distribution. For reusable packaging, we utilized expanded polyethylene (EPE), while for comparison, a disposable box made of widely used expanded polystyrene (EPS) was selected. We comprehensively analyzed the environmental impacts of production, transportation, reprocessing (for reused boxes), and disposal across 18 impact categories. Upon analyzing the actual reuse of 300 rounds of fresh food, the cumulative global warming potential (GWP) values for the EPE box were found to be 280.21 kg carbon dioxide (CO2) eq, demonstrating a significant 75% reduction compared to those of the EPS box. Furthermore, it was observed that the GWP values for the EPE boxes became equivalent to those of the EPS boxes after 12 rounds of reuse. In conclusion, reusable packaging shows substantial potential to contribute to the reduction of environmental burdens, aligning well with global environmental requirements for sustainable food distribution and related industries.</description>
      <author>Kim Sy, CHAROENSRI KORAKOT, Shin Yj, Park Hj</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20909/kopast.2023.29.3.181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Current Situation and Measures to Prevent Food Loss and Food Waste in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15276/ej.03.2023.9</link>
      <description>Volodymyr Filippov, Roza Sagitova, Lidiia Voloshchuk, Lisa Jack, Ekonom&#236;&#269;nij &#382;urnal Odes&#697;kogo pol&#236;tehn&#236;&#269;nogo un&#236;versitetu. 3(25)] 2023.
Reducing food losses and waste is of significant importance in a world where the number of people suffering from hunger is increasing, especially after 2014. Food waste leads to ecological issues, including carbon dioxide emissions that exacerbate global warming, and it can also result in social and economic problems. It is also crucial to consider force majeure circumstances such as the COVID-19 pandemic, Russian invasion, and the declaration of martial law in Ukraine. Studying and adapting the Ukrainian experience in managing food waste during force majeure situations can be beneficial for other countries in reducing and processing food losses and waste globally. This article is an interim outcome of the UUT17 project (Research Project No. 1877-01/17) "Evaluation of opportunities for prevention, reduction, recycling and reuse of FLW in Ukraine".</description>
      <author>Volodymyr Filippov, Roza Sagitova, Lidiia Voloshchuk, Lisa Jack</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15276/ej.03.2023.9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASTM Method for Inclusion Analysis of Prepared Green Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/icmeas58693.2023.10379397</link>
      <description>Maharishi Arvind, A. A. Adeleke, Ammasi Ayyandurai, Temitayo S. Ogedengbe, M Madan, No host. None(None)] 2023.
In the present situation, steel-making industries have turned their attention towards producing quality steel, through more feasible routes. One of the routes is the production of green steel, which is a kind of steel produced through a process which reduces the emission of carbon dioxide. Steel produced through traditional methods relies heavily on fossil fuel and coal, emitting large amounts of CO2, resulting in 6 &#8211; 7 % of global greenhouse gas emissions. Eventually, steel production using blast furnaces requires coking coal, which has limited reserves in India. An alternative approach to this is the utilization of DRI which consumes either non-coking coal or Hydrogen for its reduction, which significantly reduces carbon emission. To produce clean steel, it is necessary to undergo a complete assessment of the Non-Metallic Inclusions (NMI). Often, Types, sizes and distribution of Non-Metallic Inclusions play a major role in the steel properties. The present study has been performed to investigate the inclusion rating of steel produced from hydrogen-based DRI (HDRI) during steel making in an Induction Furnace (IF) and carbon-based DRI to understand the cleanness of steel as per ASTM E-45 standard. The kinetics of inclusion formation during steel making in induction furnaces has been studied using Classical Nucleation Theory. Thermodynamic modelling of different types of inclusion formation was carried out using the Fact Sage software package and it has been validated experimentally with the inclusion classifier of the SEM/EDS analyzer.</description>
      <author>Maharishi Arvind, A. A. Adeleke, Ammasi Ayyandurai, Temitayo S. Ogedengbe, M Madan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/icmeas58693.2023.10379397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pole to Ground Fault Detection Using Leakage Current for DC Distribution System with IT ground</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5207/jieie.2023.37.6.043</link>
      <description>Kyung-Min Lee, Chul&#8208;Won Park, Journal of The Korean Institute of Illuminating and Electrical Installation Engineers. 37(6)] 2023.
Recently, policies such as expansion of distributed power sources, and transition to electric vehicles are being promoted to reduce carbon dioxide. Most distributed power sources generate DC power, so when the direct current system is activated, it is effective in many aspects, including power loss reduction, grid connection efficiency, and economic feasibility. As a DC system protection plan is required according to the grounding system, the fault detection method for Pole to Ground Fault is very important. In this paper, we propose a technique using DWT (Discrete Wavelet Transform) for Pole to Ground Fault detection by leakage current in DC distribution system with IT ground system. First, after modeling the IT grounding DC distribution system using PSCAD s/w, Pole to Ground fault simulation is performed while varying the fault point and fault resistance. After implementing the proposed fault detection using MATLAB s/w, the performance is verified by comparing the proposed technique with the traditional technique through insulation resistance measurement.</description>
      <author>Kyung-Min Lee, Chul&#8208;Won Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5207/jieie.2023.37.6.043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provision of Reliable Power Supply for the First Category of Consumers Because of Renewable Energy Sources</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-51127-1_46</link>
      <description>Irina Kirpichnikova, Sergey Shipilov, Lecture notes in electrical engineering. None(None)] 2024.
This article describes the objects of the first category of power supply in the example of maternity hospital of the clinic of the Medical University of Chelyabinsk. There is a current power Supply Scheme and a group of electric consumers. The costs are calculated for electricity consumption under various schemes of power supply of the facility. It is also shown how the reduction in electricity consumption is associated with a reduction of carbon dioxide emissions into the atmosphere. It was suggested to use renewable energy sources as a way of power supply of the objects of the first category, such as wind turbines and Solar power plants. The cost of the equipment was calculated based on technical characteristics. It was also calculated the cost of savings on electricity consumptions from centralized sources. The benefits and the possibility of application of the renewable energy sources for objects of the first category are shown.</description>
      <author>Irina Kirpichnikova, Sergey Shipilov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-51127-1_46</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Isopropanol Additive on Exhaust Emissions in Gasoline Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378725</link>
      <description>Elitsa Nakova, Simeon Iliev, Kiril Hadjiev, No host. None(None)] 2023.
The steady increase in transport needs worldwide, especially in areas with dense populations, makes it necessary to seek methods and means of using sustainable alternatives to conventional fuels to reduce the use of fossil fuels and significantly reduce environmental pollution. This study investigated the effectiveness of Isopropanol as a blend with gasoline to improve the environmental performance of internal combustion engines. Besides, as an alternative fuel isopropyl alcohol can also be considered as a renewable source of energy. Alcohols, as an alternative energy source, are considered with priority, building on their characteristics. Isopropanol, as part of the group of alcohols, has been investigated with regard to its potential to improve the mixing and combustion process and also to influence the laminar flame speed as well as the combustion rate compared to conventional gasoline in internal combustion engines. The study focused on its impact on emissions, specifically hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide and nitrogen oxides. The study was carried out in a laboratory environment, on a 4-cylinder gasoline engine, for the purpose of the study gasoline and gasoline-Isopropanol mixtures were used in the ratio as follows: 95% gasoline and 5% Isopropanol (IP5), 90% gasoline and 10% Isopropanol (IP10), 85% gasoline and 15% Isopropanol (IP15) and 80% gasoline and 20% Isopropanol (IP20). Due to the properties of Isopropanol there is a reduction of HC, CO, CO2 and NOx emissions, the most favorable for this engine is the fuel mixture with Isopropanol content between 10%-15%.</description>
      <author>Elitsa Nakova, Simeon Iliev, Kiril Hadjiev</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Synergistic Dual-Functional Silver-Manganese Dioxide-CNTs Ternary Composite Electrocatalyst for Solid-State Zinc-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202401.0200.v1</link>
      <description>Guoqing Zhang, Tuan&#8208;Wu Cao, Peng Zhang, Shuying Kong, Binbin Jin, No host. None(None)] 2024.
Exploring effective oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalysts is crucial for progress in solid-state alkaline zinc-air batteries (ZAB). In this paper, silver-manganese dioxide-carbon nanotubes (SMC) ternary composites, which function as Electrocatalyst for air Electrodes, was produced via the pyrolysis of silver permanganate under microwave irradiation in one step. A scanning electron microscope (SEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and an energy dispersion spectrometer (EDS) have consistently determined that SMC consists of silver and alpha-manganese dioxide, which anchored on the surface of CNTs. Through polarization and chronoamperometery curves, the electrocatalytic activity of SMC for ORR was examined. The results reveal that SMC has higher catalytic activity than the chemically produced electrocatalyst for ORR in alkaline condition. Finally, a solid-state zinc-air cell with an electrocatalyst was constructed and tested. Constant current discharge curve of the zinc-air cell with SMC has a long discharge voltage plateau and a 60.03 mAh capacity at 30 mA &amp;amp;middot; cm&amp;amp;minus;2 . The mechanism of improvement in electrocatalytic activity was also discussed. In a summary, the strategy described in this study and the electrocatalyst produced can be regarded as an effective method for making a robust oxygen reduction catalyst toward solid-state zinc-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Guoqing Zhang, Tuan&#8208;Wu Cao, Peng Zhang, Shuying Kong, Binbin Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202401.0200.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide reduction utilizing a bismuth halide perovskite as immobilized photocatalyst in a 3D printed microreactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6439/ad1b1c</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Francisco Ruiz Cordero, Hannia L&#243;pez Mena, Marisol Ledezma, Leslie W. Pineda, J. Herrera, Journal of Micromechanics and Microengineering. None(None)] 2024.
Abstract The rising concerns about CO 2 levels in the atmosphere and energy dependency on non-renewable sources, such as fossil fuels, could find an integral solution in CO 2 photocatalytic reduction. The present work explores two alternatives to the main hindering factors for this reaction, i.e., the reactor configuration and the photocatalyst utilized. A microreactor was designed and 3D printed, providing a cheap and versatile reaction platform. Three bismuth halide perovskites, Cs 3 Bi 2 Cl 9 , Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 , and Cs 4 MnBi 2 Cl 12 , were synthesized and characterized by their band gaps (E g ); Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 presented the lowest E g and was therefore chosen for further evaluation as potential CO 2 -reduction photocatalyst. Aqueous-phase photocatalytic CO 2 reduction was achieved using this perovskite in the microreactor, obtaining CO as a reduction product with maximal production rates of 737 &#956;mol g cat -1 h -1 . The reaction system was evaluated under different flow rates and light intensities. A balance between space-time and reactant feed was found to define the behavior of CO concentration and production in the microreactor. For the light intensity, it was observed that as it increased, both CO production and concentration increased due to generating more electron-hole pairs, favoring the photocatalytic reaction. With these results, Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 perovskite immobilized in the designed microreactor demonstrates having great potential as an effective CO 2 photocatalytic reduction system.&amp;amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Francisco Ruiz Cordero, Hannia L&#243;pez Mena, Marisol Ledezma, Leslie W. Pineda, J. Herrera</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6439/ad1b1c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full-exposed Cu site of Cu2O-(1 0 0) driven high ethylene selectivity of carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.159243</link>
      <description>Youming Dong, Xingcheng Ma, Zhaoyong Jin, Xin Xu, Tianyi Xu, Dantong Zhang, Xiaoqiang Cui, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024.
Cu2O shows great potential as a catalyst for the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (ECO2RR). However, the mechanism behind the formation of different final products from Cu2O nanostructures remains a challenge. In this study, we combine theoretical and experimental approaches to demonstrate that the full-exposed Cu sites in Cu2O (1 0 0) microcubes contribute to superior C2H4 selectivity compared to other microstructures such as Cu2O (1 1 1), (1 1 0), and (3 1 1) facets. Density functional theoretical (DFT) calculations reveal that the stronger orbital splitting between Cu 3d and O 2p orbital of Cu2O (1 0 0) facet facilitates the formation of neighboring and low valence state Cu active site, thereby enhancing *CO adsorption and C2H4 formation. These DFT results are supported by the synthesis of four kinds of Cu2O microparticles (MPs) with different exposed facets, where cubic-Cu2O with the (1 0 0) facet exhibits the highest Faradaic efficiency (61.3 %). This study has significant implications for the structural design and mechanism analysis of innovative catalysts used in ECO2RR.</description>
      <author>Youming Dong, Xingcheng Ma, Zhaoyong Jin, Xin Xu, Tianyi Xu, Dantong Zhang, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.159243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd&#8211;Mo bimetallic catalysts for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide to carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.118007</link>
      <description>Devina Thasia Wijaya, Chan Woo Lee, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024.
Electrochemical CO2 reduction is considered a promising solution to mitigate the increasing CO2 emissions in the atmosphere. Despite the promising potential of this process, highly active catalysts are needed to enable its efficient operation. Mixed metal oxide (MMO) materials can promote the formation of a dynamic interface between a metal and its oxidized form under applied potential, resulting in a unique interaction with the reaction intermediates. We synthesized a Pd&#8211;Mo MMO with controlled size and composition and examined the effect of these properties on CO2 electroreduction. Electron microscopy images confirmed the homogeneous distribution of the synthesized Pd7Mo1 on a ZIF-8-derived porous carbon support, with sizes of &#8764;1.3 and 4.5 nm for the samples annealed at 200 and 400 &#176;C, respectively. As shown by density functional theory calculations and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, adding 12.5 % Mo altered the electronic structure of Pd, enhancing CO desorption, and reducing the potential needed for CO production by up to &#8764;0.2 V, corresponding to a &#8764;40 % higher partial CO current density compared to pure Pd. This work demonstrates a facile MMO synthesis enabling particle size and composition control, which will facilitate the development of highly active MMO-derived nanoalloy materials for CO2 electroreduction.</description>
      <author>Devina Thasia Wijaya, Chan Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.118007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequential co-reduction of nitrate and carbon dioxide enables selective urea electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44131-z</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Shu Guo Zheng, Hao L&#237;u, Qi Xiong, Haocong Yi, Haibin Yang, Zongwei Mei, Qinghe Zhao, Zhoulan Yin, Ming Huang, Yuan Lin, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Shi Xue Dou, Feng Pan, Shunning Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024.
Abstract Despite the recent achievements in urea electrosynthesis from co-reduction of nitrogen wastes (such as NO 3 &#8722; ) and CO 2 , the product selectivity remains fairly mediocre due to the competing nature of the two parallel reduction reactions. Here we report a catalyst design that affords high selectivity to urea by sequentially reducing NO 3 &#8722; and CO 2 at a dynamic catalytic centre, which not only alleviates the competition issue but also facilitates C&#8722;N coupling. We exemplify this strategy on a nitrogen-doped carbon catalyst, where a spontaneous switch between NO 3 &#8722; and CO 2 reduction paths is enabled by reversible hydrogenation on the nitrogen functional groups. A high urea yield rate of 596.1 &#181;g mg &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 with a promising Faradaic efficiency of 62% is obtained. These findings, rationalized by in situ spectroscopic techniques and theoretical calculations, are rooted in the proton-involved dynamic catalyst evolution that mitigates overwhelming reduction of reactants and thereby minimizes the formation of side products.</description>
      <author>Yang Li, Shu Guo Zheng, Hao L&#237;u, Qi Xiong, Haocong Yi, Haibin Yang, Zongwei Mei, Qinghe Zhao, Zhoulan Yin, Ming Huang, Yuan Lin, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Shi Xue Dou, Feng Pan, Shunning Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44131-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilized Tetraalkylammonium Cations Enable Metal&#8208;free CO2 Electroreduction in Acid and Pure Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202317828</link>
      <description>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024.
Carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) provides an efficient pathway to convert CO2 into desirable products, yet its commercialization is greatly hindered by the huge energy cost due to CO2 loss and regeneration. Performing CO2RR under acidic conditions containing alkali cations can potentially address the issue, but still causes (bi)carbonate deposition at high current densities, compromising product Faradaic efficiencies (FEs) in present&#8208;day acid&#8208;fed membrane electrode assemblies. Herein, we present a strategy using a positively charged polyelectrolyte &#8212; poly(diallyldimethylammonium) immobilized on graphene oxide via electrostatic interactions to displace alkali cations. This enables a FE of ~85%, a carbon efficiency of ~93%, and an energy efficiency (EE) of ~35% for CO at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 on modified Ag catalysts in acid. In a pure&#8208;water&#8208;fed reactor, we obtained a 78% CO FE with a 30% EE at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 at 40oC . All the performance metrics are comparable to or even exceed those attained in the presence of alkali metal cations.</description>
      <author>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202317828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilized Tetraalkylammonium Cations Enable Metal&#8208;free CO2 Electroreduction in Acid and Pure Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202317828</link>
      <description>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024.
Carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) provides an efficient pathway to convert CO2 into desirable products, yet its commercialization is greatly hindered by the huge energy cost due to CO2 loss and regeneration. Performing CO2RR under acidic conditions containing alkali cations can potentially address the issue, but still causes (bi)carbonate deposition at high current densities, compromising product Faradaic efficiencies (FEs) in present&#8208;day acid&#8208;fed membrane electrode assemblies. Herein, we present a strategy using a positively charged polyelectrolyte &#8212; poly(diallyldimethylammonium) immobilized on graphene oxide via electrostatic interactions to displace alkali cations. This enables a FE of ~85%, a carbon efficiency of ~93%, and an energy efficiency (EE) of ~35% for CO at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 on modified Ag catalysts in acid. In a pure&#8208;water&#8208;fed reactor, we obtained a 78% CO FE with a 30% EE at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 at 40oC . All the performance metrics are comparable to or even exceed those attained in the presence of alkali metal cations.</description>
      <author>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202317828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating CHO* intermediate pathway towards the significant acceleration of photocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4 through rGO-coated ultrafine Pd nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2023.148497</link>
      <description>Fanlin Kong, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Jindou Hu, Yue Feng, Yali Cao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024.
Tailoring catalytic reaction pathways by using reduced graphene oxide (rGO) to tune the electron-hole separation channels in the active sites of noble metals for achieving ideal yield and selectivity in photocatalytic CO2 reduction of hydrocarbon fuels remains a challenge. Herein, ternary catalyst of rGO-coated SnO2-supported noble metal Pd nanoparticles (Pd4/SnO2@rGO) has been prepared by coassembly between negatively charged graphene oxide and positively charged Pd nanoparticles. By coating with ultrathin rGO, the selectivity can be shifted from CO (44.69 % for Pd4/SnO2) toward CH4 as the prevalent species, in which the Pd nanoparticles acted as catalytic sites and electron capture sites. The rGO coating reduced the recombination of the photogenerated carriers as well as optimized the band gap and reduction potential of the catalyst. The in situ spectroscopic tests and density functional theory calculations revealed that CO2 adsorbed on Pd nanoparticles selectively formed dominant low-energy CHO* intermediates because of the generation of HCOOH* intermediates, thus providing a unique reaction pathway for the reduction of CO2 to CH4. Therefore, under sunlight irradiation, the CH4 selectivity of the catalyst is enhanced to 94.1 % with a production rate of up to 77.8 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1. This work demonstrated the prospect to tune the electronic structure of Pd using rGO, which provided a strategy for enhancing the carbon dioxide reduction reaction and selectively obtaining CH4 products in photocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Fanlin Kong, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Jindou Hu, Yue Feng, Yali Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2023.148497</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra&#8208;Fast Pulsed Discharge Preparation of Coordinatively Unsaturated Asymmetric Copper Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202312589</link>
      <description>Kaiyuan Liu, Zhaolin Sun, Wenxing Chen, Xiufeng Lang, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024.
Abstract Single&#8208;atom catalysts possess great potential for applications in electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reactions. Recently, the fast and low&#8208;cost preparation of highly efficient single&#8208;atom catalysts remains a challenge. Herein, a high&#8208;density current generated by pulsed discharge is employed for the formation of graphene aerogel anchored Cu single atom catalysts perfectly. The Cu atoms decomposed by Cu(NO 3 ) 2 &#8226;xH 2 O are fixed on graphene under the local transient high temperature and intense electromagnetic field. The activity and selectivity of formic acid are correlated with the coordinatively unsaturated Cu&#9472;N 1 O 1 moieties, reaching an optimal Faradaic efficiency (93.7%) at &#8722;0.9 V versus a reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). In situ characterizations reveal that the asymmetric Cu&#9472;N/O structure in a pinched state displays better catalytic activity in CO 2 RR. Density functional theory results indicate that the Cu&#9472;N 1 O 1 sites regulate the adsorption configuration of intermediates and lower the energy barrier for the hydrogenation of * OCHO species, thereby promoting CO 2 &#8208;to&#8208;HCOOH conversion.</description>
      <author>Kaiyuan Liu, Zhaolin Sun, Wenxing Chen, Xiufeng Lang, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202312589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Impacts of Biochar Addition to Substrate on Mitigating Carbon Dioxide Emissions in Green Roofs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46109-5_11</link>
      <description>Gaochuan Zhang, Bin Tang, Haohao Bian, Yangfei Huang, Hexian Jin, Bao&#8208;Jie He, Advances in science, technology &amp; innovation. None(None)] 2023.
The utilization of biochar is often heralded as a salient approach to curtailing emissions and sequestering carbon. Agricultural and forestry soils have demonstrated its efficaciousness in reducing carbon emissions; however, the urban greening industry has yet to be thoroughly researched in this regard. To address this lacuna, the present study undertook the application of biochar to the soil of an urban green roof, with the aim of ascertaining its potential to mitigate carbon dioxide emissions. By studying the effects of applying BS-0%, BS-1%, BS-5%, and BS-10% biochar on green roof substrate, the study examined the carbon dioxide value over a period of 36 h encompassing both sunny and nocturnal environments. The results indicated that the addition of biochar to the soil was effective in reducing carbon emission, with all of the biochar additions demonstrating an aptitude for carbon dioxide fixation. Notably, the application of BS-1% biochar evinced a statistically significant reduction in the carbon dioxide value. Furthermore, the addition of biochar to the roof substrate was found to be crucial in controlling rainwater runoff and alleviating urban eutrophication, indirectly reducing carbon emissions. This study provides a practical and theoretical framework for the application of biochar to mitigate the urban heat island effect.</description>
      <author>Gaochuan Zhang, Bin Tang, Haohao Bian, Yangfei Huang, Hexian Jin, Bao&#8208;Jie He</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46109-5_11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217; Benefits from Superelevated CO2 While Adapting to Far-red Light Over Time</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21273/hortsci17522-23</link>
      <description>Emily J. Kennebeck, Qingguo Meng, Hortscience. 59(2)] 2024.
Compared with the ambient Earth carbon dioxide concentration (&#8776;415 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 ), the International Space Station has superelevated carbon dioxide (&#8776;2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 ), which can be a stressor to certain crops. Far-red light can drive plant photosynthesis and increase extension growth and biomass. However, the effects of far-red light under superelevated carbon dioxide are unclear. We grew hydroponic mustard ( Brassica carinata ) &#8216;Amara&#8217; seedlings in four growth chambers using a randomized complete block design with two carbon dioxide concentrations (415 and 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 ), two lighting treatments, and two blocks at temperature and relative humidity set points of 22 &#176;C and 40%, respectively. Each growth chamber had two lighting treatments at the same total photon flux density of 200 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 . Under the same blue and green light at 50 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 each, plants received either red light at 100 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 or red + far-red light at 50 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 each. At day 15 after planting, far-red light did not influence shoot fresh or dry mass at 415 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide, but decreased both parameters by 22% to 23% at 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide. Increasing the carbon dioxide concentration increased shoot fresh and dry mass 27% to 49%, regardless of the lighting treatment. Far-red light decreased leaf area by 16% at 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide, but had no effect at 415 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide. Increasing the carbon dioxide concentration increased leaf area by 21% to 33%, regardless of far-red light. Regardless of the carbon dioxide concentration, far-red light promoted stem elongation and decreased chlorophyll concentrations by 39% to 42%. These responses indicate far-red light elicited a crop-specific shade avoidance response in mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217;, increasing extension growth but decreasing leaf area, thereby reducing light interception and biomass. In addition, carbon dioxide enrichment up to 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 increased the biomass of mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217; but decreased the biomass of other crops, indicating crop-specific tolerance to superelevated carbon dioxide. In conclusion, mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217; seedlings benefit from superelevated carbon dioxide, but exhibit growth reduction under far-red light under superelevated carbon dioxide.</description>
      <author>Emily J. Kennebeck, Qingguo Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21273/hortsci17522-23</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Water Heating: Comprehensive Review, Critical Analysis and Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.z0lx6v</link>
      <description>Amal Herez, No host. None(None)] 2023.
The increasing global demand for renewable energy sources underscores the significance of Solar Water Heating Systems (SWHS), emphasizing the need for thorough research and analysis in this domain. SWHS play a pivotal role in addressing energy efficiency and environmental sustainability, making it imperative to conduct in-depth studies on their utilization. Hence, this paper aims to provide a comprehensive overview of SWHS. It starts by explaining the principles behind these systems, including their components and classification. Moreover, this review consolidates various studies that have been conducted on SWHS to highlight both their advantages and disadvantages. Additionally, a case study is conducted in which it takes into consideration important economic and environmental factors. In particular, it focuses on several scenarios present in Lebanon such as family homes, schools, restaurants hotels and gyms to estimate potential cost savings achieved through implementing SWHS as opposed to relying solely on electric heaters. Furthermore, this investigation also examines the corresponding payback period associated with adopting SWHS along with assessing the significant reduction in carbon dioxide emissions possible if these systems were widely implemented. The findings of the study demonstrate that there is a direct correlation between the extent to which SWHS are utilized and both the payback period and reduction in CO2 emissions. It was observed that when SWHS are used more frequently, with a high percentage of time (Pr=0.9), significant advantages can be achieved. For instance, for different types of establishments such as family homes, schools, restaurants, hotels, and gyms, it was estimated that average payback periods would be 14.2 years, 4.6 years, 9.2 years, 4.4 years, and 5.3 years, respectively. These results indicate that adopting a greater dependency on SWHSs not only leads to quicker cost recovery but also significantly contributes towards reducing carbon dioxide emissions. The analysis reveals that the yearly decrease in carbon dioxide emissions per individual is 0.16 t within a household, 0.016 t per student in an educational institution, 0.04 t per customer within a dining establishment, 0.37 t for each occupied bed in a hotel accommodation, and 0.11 t per individual at a gym. This paper serves as guidelines to SWH community. Additionally, it adds a practical insights into economic and environmental issues relevant to both Lebanon and countries with similar climates.</description>
      <author>Amal Herez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.z0lx6v</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of tillage methods on carbon dioxide emissions in spring wheat crops</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/20248206006</link>
      <description>Evgeniy Demin, Stanislav Miller, Kirill Likhanov, BIO web of conferences. 82(None)] 2024.
The agriculture intensification is associated with an increase in anthropogenic load on arable soils. Tillage leads to disruption of the natural process of soil formation in connection with which the soil biota activity changes and the carbon cycle is disrupted. The purpose of the study is to establish the effects of the tillage method on the carbon dioxide emission in spring wheat crops. The emission of carbon dioxide during the growing season of spring wheat varies significantly depending on the soil processing method and temperature. At the beginning of spring wheat development, the daily emission of carbon dioxide during the dump and subsurface tillage method does not exceed 36.0 and 36.2 CO 2 kg/ha using zero technology provides a reduction in production CO 2 production to 27.8 kg/ha*day. With an increase in soil temperature by July 24, the daily emission increases on a dump and subsurface background to 105.5 and 106.0 CO 2 kg/ha*day, on a zero background to 95.4 CO 2 kg/ha*day. In the future, it decreases. The total carbon losses during the dump and subsurface tillage methods are 2829 and 2793 kg/ha, the use of zero tillage technology reduces carbon losses in grain agrocenosis by 18%.</description>
      <author>Evgeniy Demin, Stanislav Miller, Kirill Likhanov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/20248206006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the coal saving and emission reduction potential of advanced technologies in China's iron and steel industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esd.2023.101373</link>
      <description>Hui Huang, Mengyun Guan, Qing Wang, Jun Zhao, Qiong Yang, Energy for Sustainable Development. 78(None)] 2024.
The coal-based energy consumption structure has led to high coal consumption and carbon emissions in China's iron and steel industry, and the task of coal saving and carbon reduction in the steel industry is difficult and urgent. The economic viability of various coal-saving and emission-reduction technologies, the extent of their coal-saving and emission-reduction potential, and the guidance on the adoption of advanced technologies are crucial issues that need to be addressed in the Chinese steel industry. This article employs the Energy-Production (E-P) analysis method and the Conservation Supply Curve (CSC) model incorporating coal consumption ratio coefficients to systematically analyze coal consumption and carbon dioxide emissions in the overall iron and steel industry and its sub-processes under different scenarios. It calculates the coal-saving emission reduction costs of 32 technologies, evaluates them comprehensively based on their coal-saving and emission-reduction potentials and cost-effectiveness, and categorizes them accordingly. According to the cost of coal saving and emission reduction as the demarcation point, a total of 19 technologies are cost-effective; according to the coal-saving emission reduction potential and cost division, 32 technologies are divided into 6 categories, among which 6 technologies such as sintering waste heat recovery technology can be used as key technologies for popularization and application. Seven technologies, such as efficient preheating technology of ladle, have high cost and low potential, which can be gradually eliminated or improved and upgraded. After the comprehensive promotion of the 32 technologies, the maximum coal saving potential is about 3.453 billion GJ, the CO2 emission reduction potential is 395 million tons, the total coal consumption of the steel industry can be reduced to about 13.904 billion GJ, and the carbon dioxide emissions can be reduced to 1.179 billion tons.</description>
      <author>Hui Huang, Mengyun Guan, Qing Wang, Jun Zhao, Qiong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esd.2023.101373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Operation of On-Grid Park &amp;amp; Ride EV Parking Station Considering Dynamic Pricing in Japan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/itecasia-pacific59272.2023.10372344</link>
      <description>Soichiro Ueda, N. Kumarappan, Masahiro Furukakoi, Ashraf Mohamed Hemeida, Hasan Masrur, Tomonobu Senjyu, No host. None(None)] 2023.
In recent years, achieving a decarbonized society has necessitated reducing greenhouse gas emissions. Many countries set goals to reduce their greenhouse gas emissions during each of these periods. To achieve this goal, the introduction of carbon dioxide-free Electric Vehicles will be effective. In this paper, we propose an on-grid Park &amp; Ride parking station to charge EVs with PV and WG. We also showed that the dynamic pricing case with varying electricity prices is better than the constant electricity price case. Variable prices encourage the purchase of electricity during the hours when electricity price is low. Such price cases contribute the reduction of operating costs.</description>
      <author>Soichiro Ueda, N. Kumarappan, Masahiro Furukakoi, Ashraf Mohamed Hemeida, Hasan Masrur, Tomonobu Senjyu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/itecasia-pacific59272.2023.10372344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecological Impact versus Energy Generation by Floating Photovoltaic Power Plant for a Small Romanian Lake</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378724</link>
      <description>Gabriela Elena Dumitran, Liana Ioana Vu&#355;&#259;, Bogdan Popa, No host. None(None)] 2023.
The development of floating photovoltaic systems in Romania can help to the share of more than 30.7 % of the total energy produced from renewable energy sources set for the year 2030. Floating photovoltaic plants ensure the achievement of overall energy targets without affecting biodiversity and/or agricultural crops. This study evaluates the insolation and the possibility of installing this technology on Lake F&#259;c&#259;u, Romania, to benefit from the generation of electricity but also better water quality and reduction of carbon dioxide emissions $\left(\mathrm{CO}_{2}\right)$. The obtained results are promising as Floating photovoltaic plants covering around 0.22 % of the lake surface, provide 26.76 $M W h /$ year and the estimated reduction of CO &lt;inf xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;2&lt;/inf&gt; emission is 7.52 $\mathbf{t C O}_{2 \mathrm{eq}} /$ year.</description>
      <author>Gabriela Elena Dumitran, Liana Ioana Vu&#355;&#259;, Bogdan Popa</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near-Infrared Reflective Greenhouse Covering: A Novel Strategy for Electricity-Free Cooling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsagscitech.3c00281</link>
      <description>Song Zhang, Zhang Chen, Chuanxiang Cao, Yanfeng Gao, ACS Agricultural Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024.
Traditional cooling strategies for greenhouses commonly result in significant electricity consumption and a substantial release of carbon dioxide emissions. Considering the industrial fabrication process for the greenhouse covering film and the thermal management theory, we developed a composite greenhouse covering film that incorporates titanium dioxide into polyethylene to achieve near-infrared reflection. The film demonstrates an impressive near-infrared reflectance of 54.4% within the wavelength range of 780&#8211;2500 nm. A tunnel-type greenhouse demo comparative test results show that the composite film can effectively decrease the average temperature inside the greenhouse by 6.7 &#176;C in comparison to the pure polyethylene film. The reduction implies a significant annual saving in cooling electricity at the national level of 2151912.3 MW h, along with an annual CO2 emission reduction by 1250261.1 tons.</description>
      <author>Song Zhang, Zhang Chen, Chuanxiang Cao, Yanfeng Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsagscitech.3c00281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Potential Carbon Dioxide Utilization Pathways in Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/asec2023-15503</link>
      <description>Azizbek Kamolov, Zafar Turakulov, Adham Norkobilov, Miroslav Variny, Marcos Fallanza, No host. None(None)] 2023.
Reaching net-zero emissions by the middle of this century requires the implementation of massive carbon dioxide (CO2) emission reduction strategies along with the reduction of other greenhouse gases on both global and country scales. Thus, carbon capture, storage, and utilization (CCSU) is a promising technology in combination with renewable energy transition. Currently, CO2 utilization has attracted much attention from the scientific community worldwide, since it can improve the economic viability of CCSU deployment by creating a market for the recovered CO2 stream. In this study, a brief assessment and comparison of potential CO2 utilization pathways in Uzbekistan, including CO2-to-chemical/fuel conversion, CO2 bio-fixation/mineralization, and the direct use of CO2, such as for enhanced hydrocarbon recovery (EHR), are conducted considering the CO2 stationary sources and site-specific conditions of the country. In addition, possible challenges and opportunities for large-scale CO2 utilization routes are also discussed. According to this assessment, there is great potential for the direct use of CO2 as a process-boosting agent for EHR in more than 22 major natural gas, crude oil, and coal reservoirs. Moreover, methanol and urea production processes can also create huge market demand for recovered CO2 as long as the conventional CO2 production processes are replaced by sustainable ones.</description>
      <author>Azizbek Kamolov, Zafar Turakulov, Adham Norkobilov, Miroslav Variny, Marcos Fallanza</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/asec2023-15503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Based Materials for Enhanced C2+ Product Selectivity in Photo-/Electro-Catalytic CO2 Reduction: Challenges and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-023-01276-2</link>
      <description>Baker Rhimi, Min Zhou, Zaoxue Yan, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhifeng Jiang, Nano-Micro Letters. 16(1)] 2024.
Abstract Carbon dioxide conversion into valuable products using photocatalysis and electrocatalysis is an effective approach to mitigate global environmental issues and the energy shortages. Among the materials utilized for catalytic reduction of CO 2 , Cu-based materials are highly advantageous owing to their widespread availability, cost-effectiveness, and environmental sustainability. Furthermore, Cu-based materials demonstrate interesting abilities in the adsorption and activation of carbon dioxide, allowing the formation of C 2+ compounds through C&#8211;C coupling process. Herein, the basic principles of photocatalytic CO 2 reduction reactions (PCO 2 RR) and electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction reaction (ECO 2 RR) and the pathways for the generation C 2+ products are introduced. This review categorizes Cu-based materials into different groups including Cu metal, Cu oxides, Cu alloys, and Cu SACs, Cu heterojunctions based on their catalytic applications. The relationship between the Cu surfaces and their efficiency in both PCO 2 RR and ECO 2 RR is emphasized. Through a review of recent studies on PCO 2 RR and ECO 2 RR using Cu-based catalysts, the focus is on understanding the underlying reasons for the enhanced selectivity toward C 2+ products. Finally, the opportunities and challenges associated with Cu-based materials in the CO 2 catalytic reduction applications are presented, along with research directions that can guide for the design of highly active and selective Cu-based materials for CO 2 reduction processes in the future.</description>
      <author>Baker Rhimi, Min Zhou, Zaoxue Yan, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhifeng Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-023-01276-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Life Cycle Assessment of Reusable and Disposable Distribution Packaging for Fresh Food</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20909/kopast.2023.29.3.181</link>
      <description>Kim Sy, CHAROENSRI KORAKOT, Shin Yj, Park Hj, Han-gug pojang hag-hoeji. 29(3)] 2023.
In this study, we conducted a comparative life cycle assessment (LCA) of two different products, considering reusable and single-use packaging for fresh food distribution. For reusable packaging, we utilized expanded polyethylene (EPE), while for comparison, a disposable box made of widely used expanded polystyrene (EPS) was selected. We comprehensively analyzed the environmental impacts of production, transportation, reprocessing (for reused boxes), and disposal across 18 impact categories. Upon analyzing the actual reuse of 300 rounds of fresh food, the cumulative global warming potential (GWP) values for the EPE box were found to be 280.21 kg carbon dioxide (CO2) eq, demonstrating a significant 75% reduction compared to those of the EPS box. Furthermore, it was observed that the GWP values for the EPE boxes became equivalent to those of the EPS boxes after 12 rounds of reuse. In conclusion, reusable packaging shows substantial potential to contribute to the reduction of environmental burdens, aligning well with global environmental requirements for sustainable food distribution and related industries.</description>
      <author>Kim Sy, CHAROENSRI KORAKOT, Shin Yj, Park Hj</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20909/kopast.2023.29.3.181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Current Situation and Measures to Prevent Food Loss and Food Waste in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15276/ej.03.2023.9</link>
      <description>Volodymyr Filippov, Roza Sagitova, Lidiia Voloshchuk, Lisa Jack, Ekonom&#236;&#269;nij &#382;urnal Odes&#697;kogo pol&#236;tehn&#236;&#269;nogo un&#236;versitetu. 3(25)] 2023.
Reducing food losses and waste is of significant importance in a world where the number of people suffering from hunger is increasing, especially after 2014. Food waste leads to ecological issues, including carbon dioxide emissions that exacerbate global warming, and it can also result in social and economic problems. It is also crucial to consider force majeure circumstances such as the COVID-19 pandemic, Russian invasion, and the declaration of martial law in Ukraine. Studying and adapting the Ukrainian experience in managing food waste during force majeure situations can be beneficial for other countries in reducing and processing food losses and waste globally. This article is an interim outcome of the UUT17 project (Research Project No. 1877-01/17) "Evaluation of opportunities for prevention, reduction, recycling and reuse of FLW in Ukraine".</description>
      <author>Volodymyr Filippov, Roza Sagitova, Lidiia Voloshchuk, Lisa Jack</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15276/ej.03.2023.9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASTM Method for Inclusion Analysis of Prepared Green Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/icmeas58693.2023.10379397</link>
      <description>Maharishi Arvind, A. A. Adeleke, Ammasi Ayyandurai, Temitayo S. Ogedengbe, M Madan, No host. None(None)] 2023.
In the present situation, steel-making industries have turned their attention towards producing quality steel, through more feasible routes. One of the routes is the production of green steel, which is a kind of steel produced through a process which reduces the emission of carbon dioxide. Steel produced through traditional methods relies heavily on fossil fuel and coal, emitting large amounts of CO2, resulting in 6 &#8211; 7 % of global greenhouse gas emissions. Eventually, steel production using blast furnaces requires coking coal, which has limited reserves in India. An alternative approach to this is the utilization of DRI which consumes either non-coking coal or Hydrogen for its reduction, which significantly reduces carbon emission. To produce clean steel, it is necessary to undergo a complete assessment of the Non-Metallic Inclusions (NMI). Often, Types, sizes and distribution of Non-Metallic Inclusions play a major role in the steel properties. The present study has been performed to investigate the inclusion rating of steel produced from hydrogen-based DRI (HDRI) during steel making in an Induction Furnace (IF) and carbon-based DRI to understand the cleanness of steel as per ASTM E-45 standard. The kinetics of inclusion formation during steel making in induction furnaces has been studied using Classical Nucleation Theory. Thermodynamic modelling of different types of inclusion formation was carried out using the Fact Sage software package and it has been validated experimentally with the inclusion classifier of the SEM/EDS analyzer.</description>
      <author>Maharishi Arvind, A. A. Adeleke, Ammasi Ayyandurai, Temitayo S. Ogedengbe, M Madan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/icmeas58693.2023.10379397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pole to Ground Fault Detection Using Leakage Current for DC Distribution System with IT ground</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5207/jieie.2023.37.6.043</link>
      <description>Kyung-Min Lee, Chul&#8208;Won Park, Journal of The Korean Institute of Illuminating and Electrical Installation Engineers. 37(6)] 2023.
Recently, policies such as expansion of distributed power sources, and transition to electric vehicles are being promoted to reduce carbon dioxide. Most distributed power sources generate DC power, so when the direct current system is activated, it is effective in many aspects, including power loss reduction, grid connection efficiency, and economic feasibility. As a DC system protection plan is required according to the grounding system, the fault detection method for Pole to Ground Fault is very important. In this paper, we propose a technique using DWT (Discrete Wavelet Transform) for Pole to Ground Fault detection by leakage current in DC distribution system with IT ground system. First, after modeling the IT grounding DC distribution system using PSCAD s/w, Pole to Ground fault simulation is performed while varying the fault point and fault resistance. After implementing the proposed fault detection using MATLAB s/w, the performance is verified by comparing the proposed technique with the traditional technique through insulation resistance measurement.</description>
      <author>Kyung-Min Lee, Chul&#8208;Won Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5207/jieie.2023.37.6.043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provision of Reliable Power Supply for the First Category of Consumers Because of Renewable Energy Sources</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-51127-1_46</link>
      <description>Irina Kirpichnikova, Sergey Shipilov, Lecture notes in electrical engineering. None(None)] 2024.
This article describes the objects of the first category of power supply in the example of maternity hospital of the clinic of the Medical University of Chelyabinsk. There is a current power Supply Scheme and a group of electric consumers. The costs are calculated for electricity consumption under various schemes of power supply of the facility. It is also shown how the reduction in electricity consumption is associated with a reduction of carbon dioxide emissions into the atmosphere. It was suggested to use renewable energy sources as a way of power supply of the objects of the first category, such as wind turbines and Solar power plants. The cost of the equipment was calculated based on technical characteristics. It was also calculated the cost of savings on electricity consumptions from centralized sources. The benefits and the possibility of application of the renewable energy sources for objects of the first category are shown.</description>
      <author>Irina Kirpichnikova, Sergey Shipilov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-51127-1_46</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Isopropanol Additive on Exhaust Emissions in Gasoline Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378725</link>
      <description>Elitsa Nakova, Simeon Iliev, Kiril Hadjiev, No host. None(None)] 2023.
The steady increase in transport needs worldwide, especially in areas with dense populations, makes it necessary to seek methods and means of using sustainable alternatives to conventional fuels to reduce the use of fossil fuels and significantly reduce environmental pollution. This study investigated the effectiveness of Isopropanol as a blend with gasoline to improve the environmental performance of internal combustion engines. Besides, as an alternative fuel isopropyl alcohol can also be considered as a renewable source of energy. Alcohols, as an alternative energy source, are considered with priority, building on their characteristics. Isopropanol, as part of the group of alcohols, has been investigated with regard to its potential to improve the mixing and combustion process and also to influence the laminar flame speed as well as the combustion rate compared to conventional gasoline in internal combustion engines. The study focused on its impact on emissions, specifically hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide and nitrogen oxides. The study was carried out in a laboratory environment, on a 4-cylinder gasoline engine, for the purpose of the study gasoline and gasoline-Isopropanol mixtures were used in the ratio as follows: 95% gasoline and 5% Isopropanol (IP5), 90% gasoline and 10% Isopropanol (IP10), 85% gasoline and 15% Isopropanol (IP15) and 80% gasoline and 20% Isopropanol (IP20). Due to the properties of Isopropanol there is a reduction of HC, CO, CO2 and NOx emissions, the most favorable for this engine is the fuel mixture with Isopropanol content between 10%-15%.</description>
      <author>Elitsa Nakova, Simeon Iliev, Kiril Hadjiev</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Synergistic Dual-Functional Silver-Manganese Dioxide-CNTs Ternary Composite Electrocatalyst for Solid-State Zinc-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202401.0200.v1</link>
      <description>Guoqing Zhang, Tuan&#8208;Wu Cao, Peng Zhang, Shuying Kong, Binbin Jin, No host. None(None)] 2024.
Exploring effective oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalysts is crucial for progress in solid-state alkaline zinc-air batteries (ZAB). In this paper, silver-manganese dioxide-carbon nanotubes (SMC) ternary composites, which function as Electrocatalyst for air Electrodes, was produced via the pyrolysis of silver permanganate under microwave irradiation in one step. A scanning electron microscope (SEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and an energy dispersion spectrometer (EDS) have consistently determined that SMC consists of silver and alpha-manganese dioxide, which anchored on the surface of CNTs. Through polarization and chronoamperometery curves, the electrocatalytic activity of SMC for ORR was examined. The results reveal that SMC has higher catalytic activity than the chemically produced electrocatalyst for ORR in alkaline condition. Finally, a solid-state zinc-air cell with an electrocatalyst was constructed and tested. Constant current discharge curve of the zinc-air cell with SMC has a long discharge voltage plateau and a 60.03 mAh capacity at 30 mA &amp;amp;middot; cm&amp;amp;minus;2 . The mechanism of improvement in electrocatalytic activity was also discussed. In a summary, the strategy described in this study and the electrocatalyst produced can be regarded as an effective method for making a robust oxygen reduction catalyst toward solid-state zinc-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Guoqing Zhang, Tuan&#8208;Wu Cao, Peng Zhang, Shuying Kong, Binbin Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202401.0200.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide reduction utilizing a bismuth halide perovskite as immobilized photocatalyst in a 3D printed microreactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6439/ad1b1c</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Francisco Ruiz Cordero, Hannia L&#243;pez Mena, Marisol Ledezma, Leslie W. Pineda, J. Herrera, Journal of Micromechanics and Microengineering. None(None)] 2024.
Abstract The rising concerns about CO 2 levels in the atmosphere and energy dependency on non-renewable sources, such as fossil fuels, could find an integral solution in CO 2 photocatalytic reduction. The present work explores two alternatives to the main hindering factors for this reaction, i.e., the reactor configuration and the photocatalyst utilized. A microreactor was designed and 3D printed, providing a cheap and versatile reaction platform. Three bismuth halide perovskites, Cs 3 Bi 2 Cl 9 , Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 , and Cs 4 MnBi 2 Cl 12 , were synthesized and characterized by their band gaps (E g ); Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 presented the lowest E g and was therefore chosen for further evaluation as potential CO 2 -reduction photocatalyst. Aqueous-phase photocatalytic CO 2 reduction was achieved using this perovskite in the microreactor, obtaining CO as a reduction product with maximal production rates of 737 &#956;mol g cat -1 h -1 . The reaction system was evaluated under different flow rates and light intensities. A balance between space-time and reactant feed was found to define the behavior of CO concentration and production in the microreactor. For the light intensity, it was observed that as it increased, both CO production and concentration increased due to generating more electron-hole pairs, favoring the photocatalytic reaction. With these results, Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 perovskite immobilized in the designed microreactor demonstrates having great potential as an effective CO 2 photocatalytic reduction system.&amp;amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Francisco Ruiz Cordero, Hannia L&#243;pez Mena, Marisol Ledezma, Leslie W. Pineda, J. Herrera</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6439/ad1b1c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full-exposed Cu site of Cu2O-(1 0 0) driven high ethylene selectivity of carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.159243</link>
      <description>Youming Dong, Xingcheng Ma, Zhaoyong Jin, Xin Xu, Tianyi Xu, Dantong Zhang, Xiaoqiang Cui, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024.
Cu2O shows great potential as a catalyst for the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (ECO2RR). However, the mechanism behind the formation of different final products from Cu2O nanostructures remains a challenge. In this study, we combine theoretical and experimental approaches to demonstrate that the full-exposed Cu sites in Cu2O (1 0 0) microcubes contribute to superior C2H4 selectivity compared to other microstructures such as Cu2O (1 1 1), (1 1 0), and (3 1 1) facets. Density functional theoretical (DFT) calculations reveal that the stronger orbital splitting between Cu 3d and O 2p orbital of Cu2O (1 0 0) facet facilitates the formation of neighboring and low valence state Cu active site, thereby enhancing *CO adsorption and C2H4 formation. These DFT results are supported by the synthesis of four kinds of Cu2O microparticles (MPs) with different exposed facets, where cubic-Cu2O with the (1 0 0) facet exhibits the highest Faradaic efficiency (61.3 %). This study has significant implications for the structural design and mechanism analysis of innovative catalysts used in ECO2RR.</description>
      <author>Youming Dong, Xingcheng Ma, Zhaoyong Jin, Xin Xu, Tianyi Xu, Dantong Zhang, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.159243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd&#8211;Mo bimetallic catalysts for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide to carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.118007</link>
      <description>Devina Thasia Wijaya, Chan Woo Lee, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024.
Electrochemical CO2 reduction is considered a promising solution to mitigate the increasing CO2 emissions in the atmosphere. Despite the promising potential of this process, highly active catalysts are needed to enable its efficient operation. Mixed metal oxide (MMO) materials can promote the formation of a dynamic interface between a metal and its oxidized form under applied potential, resulting in a unique interaction with the reaction intermediates. We synthesized a Pd&#8211;Mo MMO with controlled size and composition and examined the effect of these properties on CO2 electroreduction. Electron microscopy images confirmed the homogeneous distribution of the synthesized Pd7Mo1 on a ZIF-8-derived porous carbon support, with sizes of &#8764;1.3 and 4.5 nm for the samples annealed at 200 and 400 &#176;C, respectively. As shown by density functional theory calculations and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, adding 12.5 % Mo altered the electronic structure of Pd, enhancing CO desorption, and reducing the potential needed for CO production by up to &#8764;0.2 V, corresponding to a &#8764;40 % higher partial CO current density compared to pure Pd. This work demonstrates a facile MMO synthesis enabling particle size and composition control, which will facilitate the development of highly active MMO-derived nanoalloy materials for CO2 electroreduction.</description>
      <author>Devina Thasia Wijaya, Chan Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.118007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequential co-reduction of nitrate and carbon dioxide enables selective urea electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44131-z</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Shu Guo Zheng, Hao L&#237;u, Qi Xiong, Haocong Yi, Haibin Yang, Zongwei Mei, Qinghe Zhao, Zhoulan Yin, Ming Huang, Yuan Lin, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Shi Xue Dou, Feng Pan, Shunning Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024.
Abstract Despite the recent achievements in urea electrosynthesis from co-reduction of nitrogen wastes (such as NO 3 &#8722; ) and CO 2 , the product selectivity remains fairly mediocre due to the competing nature of the two parallel reduction reactions. Here we report a catalyst design that affords high selectivity to urea by sequentially reducing NO 3 &#8722; and CO 2 at a dynamic catalytic centre, which not only alleviates the competition issue but also facilitates C&#8722;N coupling. We exemplify this strategy on a nitrogen-doped carbon catalyst, where a spontaneous switch between NO 3 &#8722; and CO 2 reduction paths is enabled by reversible hydrogenation on the nitrogen functional groups. A high urea yield rate of 596.1 &#181;g mg &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 with a promising Faradaic efficiency of 62% is obtained. These findings, rationalized by in situ spectroscopic techniques and theoretical calculations, are rooted in the proton-involved dynamic catalyst evolution that mitigates overwhelming reduction of reactants and thereby minimizes the formation of side products.</description>
      <author>Yang Li, Shu Guo Zheng, Hao L&#237;u, Qi Xiong, Haocong Yi, Haibin Yang, Zongwei Mei, Qinghe Zhao, Zhoulan Yin, Ming Huang, Yuan Lin, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Shi Xue Dou, Feng Pan, Shunning Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44131-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilized Tetraalkylammonium Cations Enable Metal&#8208;free CO2 Electroreduction in Acid and Pure Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202317828</link>
      <description>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024.
Carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) provides an efficient pathway to convert CO2 into desirable products, yet its commercialization is greatly hindered by the huge energy cost due to CO2 loss and regeneration. Performing CO2RR under acidic conditions containing alkali cations can potentially address the issue, but still causes (bi)carbonate deposition at high current densities, compromising product Faradaic efficiencies (FEs) in present&#8208;day acid&#8208;fed membrane electrode assemblies. Herein, we present a strategy using a positively charged polyelectrolyte &#8212; poly(diallyldimethylammonium) immobilized on graphene oxide via electrostatic interactions to displace alkali cations. This enables a FE of ~85%, a carbon efficiency of ~93%, and an energy efficiency (EE) of ~35% for CO at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 on modified Ag catalysts in acid. In a pure&#8208;water&#8208;fed reactor, we obtained a 78% CO FE with a 30% EE at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 at 40oC . All the performance metrics are comparable to or even exceed those attained in the presence of alkali metal cations.</description>
      <author>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202317828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilized Tetraalkylammonium Cations Enable Metal&#8208;free CO2 Electroreduction in Acid and Pure Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202317828</link>
      <description>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024.
Carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) provides an efficient pathway to convert CO2 into desirable products, yet its commercialization is greatly hindered by the huge energy cost due to CO2 loss and regeneration. Performing CO2RR under acidic conditions containing alkali cations can potentially address the issue, but still causes (bi)carbonate deposition at high current densities, compromising product Faradaic efficiencies (FEs) in present&#8208;day acid&#8208;fed membrane electrode assemblies. Herein, we present a strategy using a positively charged polyelectrolyte &#8212; poly(diallyldimethylammonium) immobilized on graphene oxide via electrostatic interactions to displace alkali cations. This enables a FE of ~85%, a carbon efficiency of ~93%, and an energy efficiency (EE) of ~35% for CO at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 on modified Ag catalysts in acid. In a pure&#8208;water&#8208;fed reactor, we obtained a 78% CO FE with a 30% EE at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 at 40oC . All the performance metrics are comparable to or even exceed those attained in the presence of alkali metal cations.</description>
      <author>Fan Jia, Binbin Pan, Jia&#8208;Ling Wu, Chaochen Shao, Zi Wen, Yan Yao, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202317828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating CHO* intermediate pathway towards the significant acceleration of photocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4 through rGO-coated ultrafine Pd nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2023.148497</link>
      <description>Fanlin Kong, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Jindou Hu, Yue Feng, Yali Cao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024.
Tailoring catalytic reaction pathways by using reduced graphene oxide (rGO) to tune the electron-hole separation channels in the active sites of noble metals for achieving ideal yield and selectivity in photocatalytic CO2 reduction of hydrocarbon fuels remains a challenge. Herein, ternary catalyst of rGO-coated SnO2-supported noble metal Pd nanoparticles (Pd4/SnO2@rGO) has been prepared by coassembly between negatively charged graphene oxide and positively charged Pd nanoparticles. By coating with ultrathin rGO, the selectivity can be shifted from CO (44.69 % for Pd4/SnO2) toward CH4 as the prevalent species, in which the Pd nanoparticles acted as catalytic sites and electron capture sites. The rGO coating reduced the recombination of the photogenerated carriers as well as optimized the band gap and reduction potential of the catalyst. The in situ spectroscopic tests and density functional theory calculations revealed that CO2 adsorbed on Pd nanoparticles selectively formed dominant low-energy CHO* intermediates because of the generation of HCOOH* intermediates, thus providing a unique reaction pathway for the reduction of CO2 to CH4. Therefore, under sunlight irradiation, the CH4 selectivity of the catalyst is enhanced to 94.1 % with a production rate of up to 77.8 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1. This work demonstrated the prospect to tune the electronic structure of Pd using rGO, which provided a strategy for enhancing the carbon dioxide reduction reaction and selectively obtaining CH4 products in photocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Fanlin Kong, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Jindou Hu, Yue Feng, Yali Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2023.148497</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra&#8208;Fast Pulsed Discharge Preparation of Coordinatively Unsaturated Asymmetric Copper Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202312589</link>
      <description>Kaiyuan Liu, Zhaolin Sun, Wenxing Chen, Xiufeng Lang, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024.
Abstract Single&#8208;atom catalysts possess great potential for applications in electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reactions. Recently, the fast and low&#8208;cost preparation of highly efficient single&#8208;atom catalysts remains a challenge. Herein, a high&#8208;density current generated by pulsed discharge is employed for the formation of graphene aerogel anchored Cu single atom catalysts perfectly. The Cu atoms decomposed by Cu(NO 3 ) 2 &#8226;xH 2 O are fixed on graphene under the local transient high temperature and intense electromagnetic field. The activity and selectivity of formic acid are correlated with the coordinatively unsaturated Cu&#9472;N 1 O 1 moieties, reaching an optimal Faradaic efficiency (93.7%) at &#8722;0.9 V versus a reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). In situ characterizations reveal that the asymmetric Cu&#9472;N/O structure in a pinched state displays better catalytic activity in CO 2 RR. Density functional theory results indicate that the Cu&#9472;N 1 O 1 sites regulate the adsorption configuration of intermediates and lower the energy barrier for the hydrogenation of * OCHO species, thereby promoting CO 2 &#8208;to&#8208;HCOOH conversion.</description>
      <author>Kaiyuan Liu, Zhaolin Sun, Wenxing Chen, Xiufeng Lang, Xin Gao, Pengwan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202312589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Impacts of Biochar Addition to Substrate on Mitigating Carbon Dioxide Emissions in Green Roofs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46109-5_11</link>
      <description>Gaochuan Zhang, Bin Tang, Haohao Bian, Yangfei Huang, Hexian Jin, Bao&#8208;Jie He, Advances in science, technology &amp; innovation. None(None)] 2023.
The utilization of biochar is often heralded as a salient approach to curtailing emissions and sequestering carbon. Agricultural and forestry soils have demonstrated its efficaciousness in reducing carbon emissions; however, the urban greening industry has yet to be thoroughly researched in this regard. To address this lacuna, the present study undertook the application of biochar to the soil of an urban green roof, with the aim of ascertaining its potential to mitigate carbon dioxide emissions. By studying the effects of applying BS-0%, BS-1%, BS-5%, and BS-10% biochar on green roof substrate, the study examined the carbon dioxide value over a period of 36 h encompassing both sunny and nocturnal environments. The results indicated that the addition of biochar to the soil was effective in reducing carbon emission, with all of the biochar additions demonstrating an aptitude for carbon dioxide fixation. Notably, the application of BS-1% biochar evinced a statistically significant reduction in the carbon dioxide value. Furthermore, the addition of biochar to the roof substrate was found to be crucial in controlling rainwater runoff and alleviating urban eutrophication, indirectly reducing carbon emissions. This study provides a practical and theoretical framework for the application of biochar to mitigate the urban heat island effect.</description>
      <author>Gaochuan Zhang, Bin Tang, Haohao Bian, Yangfei Huang, Hexian Jin, Bao&#8208;Jie He</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46109-5_11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217; Benefits from Superelevated CO2 While Adapting to Far-red Light Over Time</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21273/hortsci17522-23</link>
      <description>Emily J. Kennebeck, Qingguo Meng, Hortscience. 59(2)] 2024.
Compared with the ambient Earth carbon dioxide concentration (&#8776;415 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 ), the International Space Station has superelevated carbon dioxide (&#8776;2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 ), which can be a stressor to certain crops. Far-red light can drive plant photosynthesis and increase extension growth and biomass. However, the effects of far-red light under superelevated carbon dioxide are unclear. We grew hydroponic mustard ( Brassica carinata ) &#8216;Amara&#8217; seedlings in four growth chambers using a randomized complete block design with two carbon dioxide concentrations (415 and 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 ), two lighting treatments, and two blocks at temperature and relative humidity set points of 22 &#176;C and 40%, respectively. Each growth chamber had two lighting treatments at the same total photon flux density of 200 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 . Under the same blue and green light at 50 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 each, plants received either red light at 100 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 or red + far-red light at 50 &#956;mol&#8901;m &#8211;2 &#8901;s &#8211;1 each. At day 15 after planting, far-red light did not influence shoot fresh or dry mass at 415 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide, but decreased both parameters by 22% to 23% at 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide. Increasing the carbon dioxide concentration increased shoot fresh and dry mass 27% to 49%, regardless of the lighting treatment. Far-red light decreased leaf area by 16% at 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide, but had no effect at 415 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 carbon dioxide. Increasing the carbon dioxide concentration increased leaf area by 21% to 33%, regardless of far-red light. Regardless of the carbon dioxide concentration, far-red light promoted stem elongation and decreased chlorophyll concentrations by 39% to 42%. These responses indicate far-red light elicited a crop-specific shade avoidance response in mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217;, increasing extension growth but decreasing leaf area, thereby reducing light interception and biomass. In addition, carbon dioxide enrichment up to 2800 &#956;mol&#8901;mol &#8211;1 increased the biomass of mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217; but decreased the biomass of other crops, indicating crop-specific tolerance to superelevated carbon dioxide. In conclusion, mustard &#8216;Amara&#8217; seedlings benefit from superelevated carbon dioxide, but exhibit growth reduction under far-red light under superelevated carbon dioxide.</description>
      <author>Emily J. Kennebeck, Qingguo Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21273/hortsci17522-23</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Water Heating: Comprehensive Review, Critical Analysis and Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.z0lx6v</link>
      <description>Amal Herez, No host. None(None)] 2023.
The increasing global demand for renewable energy sources underscores the significance of Solar Water Heating Systems (SWHS), emphasizing the need for thorough research and analysis in this domain. SWHS play a pivotal role in addressing energy efficiency and environmental sustainability, making it imperative to conduct in-depth studies on their utilization. Hence, this paper aims to provide a comprehensive overview of SWHS. It starts by explaining the principles behind these systems, including their components and classification. Moreover, this review consolidates various studies that have been conducted on SWHS to highlight both their advantages and disadvantages. Additionally, a case study is conducted in which it takes into consideration important economic and environmental factors. In particular, it focuses on several scenarios present in Lebanon such as family homes, schools, restaurants hotels and gyms to estimate potential cost savings achieved through implementing SWHS as opposed to relying solely on electric heaters. Furthermore, this investigation also examines the corresponding payback period associated with adopting SWHS along with assessing the significant reduction in carbon dioxide emissions possible if these systems were widely implemented. The findings of the study demonstrate that there is a direct correlation between the extent to which SWHS are utilized and both the payback period and reduction in CO2 emissions. It was observed that when SWHS are used more frequently, with a high percentage of time (Pr=0.9), significant advantages can be achieved. For instance, for different types of establishments such as family homes, schools, restaurants, hotels, and gyms, it was estimated that average payback periods would be 14.2 years, 4.6 years, 9.2 years, 4.4 years, and 5.3 years, respectively. These results indicate that adopting a greater dependency on SWHSs not only leads to quicker cost recovery but also significantly contributes towards reducing carbon dioxide emissions. The analysis reveals that the yearly decrease in carbon dioxide emissions per individual is 0.16 t within a household, 0.016 t per student in an educational institution, 0.04 t per customer within a dining establishment, 0.37 t for each occupied bed in a hotel accommodation, and 0.11 t per individual at a gym. This paper serves as guidelines to SWH community. Additionally, it adds a practical insights into economic and environmental issues relevant to both Lebanon and countries with similar climates.</description>
      <author>Amal Herez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.z0lx6v</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of tillage methods on carbon dioxide emissions in spring wheat crops</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/20248206006</link>
      <description>Evgeniy Demin, Stanislav Miller, Kirill Likhanov, BIO web of conferences. 82(None)] 2024.
The agriculture intensification is associated with an increase in anthropogenic load on arable soils. Tillage leads to disruption of the natural process of soil formation in connection with which the soil biota activity changes and the carbon cycle is disrupted. The purpose of the study is to establish the effects of the tillage method on the carbon dioxide emission in spring wheat crops. The emission of carbon dioxide during the growing season of spring wheat varies significantly depending on the soil processing method and temperature. At the beginning of spring wheat development, the daily emission of carbon dioxide during the dump and subsurface tillage method does not exceed 36.0 and 36.2 CO 2 kg/ha using zero technology provides a reduction in production CO 2 production to 27.8 kg/ha*day. With an increase in soil temperature by July 24, the daily emission increases on a dump and subsurface background to 105.5 and 106.0 CO 2 kg/ha*day, on a zero background to 95.4 CO 2 kg/ha*day. In the future, it decreases. The total carbon losses during the dump and subsurface tillage methods are 2829 and 2793 kg/ha, the use of zero tillage technology reduces carbon losses in grain agrocenosis by 18%.</description>
      <author>Evgeniy Demin, Stanislav Miller, Kirill Likhanov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/20248206006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the coal saving and emission reduction potential of advanced technologies in China's iron and steel industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esd.2023.101373</link>
      <description>Hui Huang, Mengyun Guan, Qing Wang, Jun Zhao, Qiong Yang, Energy for Sustainable Development. 78(None)] 2024.
The coal-based energy consumption structure has led to high coal consumption and carbon emissions in China's iron and steel industry, and the task of coal saving and carbon reduction in the steel industry is difficult and urgent. The economic viability of various coal-saving and emission-reduction technologies, the extent of their coal-saving and emission-reduction potential, and the guidance on the adoption of advanced technologies are crucial issues that need to be addressed in the Chinese steel industry. This article employs the Energy-Production (E-P) analysis method and the Conservation Supply Curve (CSC) model incorporating coal consumption ratio coefficients to systematically analyze coal consumption and carbon dioxide emissions in the overall iron and steel industry and its sub-processes under different scenarios. It calculates the coal-saving emission reduction costs of 32 technologies, evaluates them comprehensively based on their coal-saving and emission-reduction potentials and cost-effectiveness, and categorizes them accordingly. According to the cost of coal saving and emission reduction as the demarcation point, a total of 19 technologies are cost-effective; according to the coal-saving emission reduction potential and cost division, 32 technologies are divided into 6 categories, among which 6 technologies such as sintering waste heat recovery technology can be used as key technologies for popularization and application. Seven technologies, such as efficient preheating technology of ladle, have high cost and low potential, which can be gradually eliminated or improved and upgraded. After the comprehensive promotion of the 32 technologies, the maximum coal saving potential is about 3.453 billion GJ, the CO2 emission reduction potential is 395 million tons, the total coal consumption of the steel industry can be reduced to about 13.904 billion GJ, and the carbon dioxide emissions can be reduced to 1.179 billion tons.</description>
      <author>Hui Huang, Mengyun Guan, Qing Wang, Jun Zhao, Qiong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esd.2023.101373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Operation of On-Grid Park &amp;amp; Ride EV Parking Station Considering Dynamic Pricing in Japan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/itecasia-pacific59272.2023.10372344</link>
      <description>Soichiro Ueda, N. Kumarappan, Masahiro Furukakoi, Ashraf Mohamed Hemeida, Hasan Masrur, Tomonobu Senjyu, No host. None(None)] 2023.
In recent years, achieving a decarbonized society has necessitated reducing greenhouse gas emissions. Many countries set goals to reduce their greenhouse gas emissions during each of these periods. To achieve this goal, the introduction of carbon dioxide-free Electric Vehicles will be effective. In this paper, we propose an on-grid Park &amp; Ride parking station to charge EVs with PV and WG. We also showed that the dynamic pricing case with varying electricity prices is better than the constant electricity price case. Variable prices encourage the purchase of electricity during the hours when electricity price is low. Such price cases contribute the reduction of operating costs.</description>
      <author>Soichiro Ueda, N. Kumarappan, Masahiro Furukakoi, Ashraf Mohamed Hemeida, Hasan Masrur, Tomonobu Senjyu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/itecasia-pacific59272.2023.10372344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecological Impact versus Energy Generation by Floating Photovoltaic Power Plant for a Small Romanian Lake</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378724</link>
      <description>Gabriela Elena Dumitran, Liana Ioana Vu&#355;&#259;, Bogdan Popa, No host. None(None)] 2023.
The development of floating photovoltaic systems in Romania can help to the share of more than 30.7 % of the total energy produced from renewable energy sources set for the year 2030. Floating photovoltaic plants ensure the achievement of overall energy targets without affecting biodiversity and/or agricultural crops. This study evaluates the insolation and the possibility of installing this technology on Lake F&#259;c&#259;u, Romania, to benefit from the generation of electricity but also better water quality and reduction of carbon dioxide emissions $\left(\mathrm{CO}_{2}\right)$. The obtained results are promising as Floating photovoltaic plants covering around 0.22 % of the lake surface, provide 26.76 $M W h /$ year and the estimated reduction of CO &lt;inf xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;2&lt;/inf&gt; emission is 7.52 $\mathbf{t C O}_{2 \mathrm{eq}} /$ year.</description>
      <author>Gabriela Elena Dumitran, Liana Ioana Vu&#355;&#259;, Bogdan Popa</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near-Infrared Reflective Greenhouse Covering: A Novel Strategy for Electricity-Free Cooling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsagscitech.3c00281</link>
      <description>Song Zhang, Zhang Chen, Chuanxiang Cao, Yanfeng Gao, ACS Agricultural Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024.
Traditional cooling strategies for greenhouses commonly result in significant electricity consumption and a substantial release of carbon dioxide emissions. Considering the industrial fabrication process for the greenhouse covering film and the thermal management theory, we developed a composite greenhouse covering film that incorporates titanium dioxide into polyethylene to achieve near-infrared reflection. The film demonstrates an impressive near-infrared reflectance of 54.4% within the wavelength range of 780&#8211;2500 nm. A tunnel-type greenhouse demo comparative test results show that the composite film can effectively decrease the average temperature inside the greenhouse by 6.7 &#176;C in comparison to the pure polyethylene film. The reduction implies a significant annual saving in cooling electricity at the national level of 2151912.3 MW h, along with an annual CO2 emission reduction by 1250261.1 tons.</description>
      <author>Song Zhang, Zhang Chen, Chuanxiang Cao, Yanfeng Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsagscitech.3c00281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Potential Carbon Dioxide Utilization Pathways in Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/asec2023-15503</link>
      <description>Azizbek Kamolov, Zafar Turakulov, Adham Norkobilov, Miroslav Variny, Marcos Fallanza, No host. None(None)] 2023.
Reaching net-zero emissions by the middle of this century requires the implementation of massive carbon dioxide (CO2) emission reduction strategies along with the reduction of other greenhouse gases on both global and country scales. Thus, carbon capture, storage, and utilization (CCSU) is a promising technology in combination with renewable energy transition. Currently, CO2 utilization has attracted much attention from the scientific community worldwide, since it can improve the economic viability of CCSU deployment by creating a market for the recovered CO2 stream. In this study, a brief assessment and comparison of potential CO2 utilization pathways in Uzbekistan, including CO2-to-chemical/fuel conversion, CO2 bio-fixation/mineralization, and the direct use of CO2, such as for enhanced hydrocarbon recovery (EHR), are conducted considering the CO2 stationary sources and site-specific conditions of the country. In addition, possible challenges and opportunities for large-scale CO2 utilization routes are also discussed. According to this assessment, there is great potential for the direct use of CO2 as a process-boosting agent for EHR in more than 22 major natural gas, crude oil, and coal reservoirs. Moreover, methanol and urea production processes can also create huge market demand for recovered CO2 as long as the conventional CO2 production processes are replaced by sustainable ones.</description>
      <author>Azizbek Kamolov, Zafar Turakulov, Adham Norkobilov, Miroslav Variny, Marcos Fallanza</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/asec2023-15503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Based Materials for Enhanced C2+ Product Selectivity in Photo-/Electro-Catalytic CO2 Reduction: Challenges and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-023-01276-2</link>
      <description>Baker Rhimi, Min Zhou, Zaoxue Yan, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhifeng Jiang, Nano-Micro Letters. 16(1)] 2024.
Abstract Carbon dioxide conversion into valuable products using photocatalysis and electrocatalysis is an effective approach to mitigate global environmental issues and the energy shortages. Among the materials utilized for catalytic reduction of CO 2 , Cu-based materials are highly advantageous owing to their widespread availability, cost-effectiveness, and environmental sustainability. Furthermore, Cu-based materials demonstrate interesting abilities in the adsorption and activation of carbon dioxide, allowing the formation of C 2+ compounds through C&#8211;C coupling process. Herein, the basic principles of photocatalytic CO 2 reduction reactions (PCO 2 RR) and electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction reaction (ECO 2 RR) and the pathways for the generation C 2+ products are introduced. This review categorizes Cu-based materials into different groups including Cu metal, Cu oxides, Cu alloys, and Cu SACs, Cu heterojunctions based on their catalytic applications. The relationship between the Cu surfaces and their efficiency in both PCO 2 RR and ECO 2 RR is emphasized. Through a review of recent studies on PCO 2 RR and ECO 2 RR using Cu-based catalysts, the focus is on understanding the underlying reasons for the enhanced selectivity toward C 2+ products. Finally, the opportunities and challenges associated with Cu-based materials in the CO 2 catalytic reduction applications are presented, along with research directions that can guide for the design of highly active and selective Cu-based materials for CO 2 reduction processes in the future.</description>
      <author>Baker Rhimi, Min Zhou, Zaoxue Yan, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhifeng Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-023-01276-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Life Cycle Assessment of Reusable and Disposable Distribution Packaging for Fresh Food</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20909/kopast.2023.29.3.181</link>
      <description>Kim Sy, CHAROENSRI KORAKOT, Shin Yj, Park Hj, Han-gug pojang hag-hoeji. 29(3)] 2023.
In this study, we conducted a comparative life cycle assessment (LCA) of two different products, considering reusable and single-use packaging for fresh food distribution. For reusable packaging, we utilized expanded polyethylene (EPE), while for comparison, a disposable box made of widely used expanded polystyrene (EPS) was selected. We comprehensively analyzed the environmental impacts of production, transportation, reprocessing (for reused boxes), and disposal across 18 impact categories. Upon analyzing the actual reuse of 300 rounds of fresh food, the cumulative global warming potential (GWP) values for the EPE box were found to be 280.21 kg carbon dioxide (CO2) eq, demonstrating a significant 75% reduction compared to those of the EPS box. Furthermore, it was observed that the GWP values for the EPE boxes became equivalent to those of the EPS boxes after 12 rounds of reuse. In conclusion, reusable packaging shows substantial potential to contribute to the reduction of environmental burdens, aligning well with global environmental requirements for sustainable food distribution and related industries.</description>
      <author>Kim Sy, CHAROENSRI KORAKOT, Shin Yj, Park Hj</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20909/kopast.2023.29.3.181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Current Situation and Measures to Prevent Food Loss and Food Waste in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15276/ej.03.2023.9</link>
      <description>Volodymyr Filippov, Roza Sagitova, Lidiia Voloshchuk, Lisa Jack, Ekonom&#236;&#269;nij &#382;urnal Odes&#697;kogo pol&#236;tehn&#236;&#269;nogo un&#236;versitetu. 3(25)] 2023.
Reducing food losses and waste is of significant importance in a world where the number of people suffering from hunger is increasing, especially after 2014. Food waste leads to ecological issues, including carbon dioxide emissions that exacerbate global warming, and it can also result in social and economic problems. It is also crucial to consider force majeure circumstances such as the COVID-19 pandemic, Russian invasion, and the declaration of martial law in Ukraine. Studying and adapting the Ukrainian experience in managing food waste during force majeure situations can be beneficial for other countries in reducing and processing food losses and waste globally. This article is an interim outcome of the UUT17 project (Research Project No. 1877-01/17) "Evaluation of opportunities for prevention, reduction, recycling and reuse of FLW in Ukraine".</description>
      <author>Volodymyr Filippov, Roza Sagitova, Lidiia Voloshchuk, Lisa Jack</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15276/ej.03.2023.9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASTM Method for Inclusion Analysis of Prepared Green Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/icmeas58693.2023.10379397</link>
      <description>Maharishi Arvind, A. A. Adeleke, Ammasi Ayyandurai, Temitayo S. Ogedengbe, M Madan, No host. None(None)] 2023.
In the present situation, steel-making industries have turned their attention towards producing quality steel, through more feasible routes. One of the routes is the production of green steel, which is a kind of steel produced through a process which reduces the emission of carbon dioxide. Steel produced through traditional methods relies heavily on fossil fuel and coal, emitting large amounts of CO2, resulting in 6 &#8211; 7 % of global greenhouse gas emissions. Eventually, steel production using blast furnaces requires coking coal, which has limited reserves in India. An alternative approach to this is the utilization of DRI which consumes either non-coking coal or Hydrogen for its reduction, which significantly reduces carbon emission. To produce clean steel, it is necessary to undergo a complete assessment of the Non-Metallic Inclusions (NMI). Often, Types, sizes and distribution of Non-Metallic Inclusions play a major role in the steel properties. The present study has been performed to investigate the inclusion rating of steel produced from hydrogen-based DRI (HDRI) during steel making in an Induction Furnace (IF) and carbon-based DRI to understand the cleanness of steel as per ASTM E-45 standard. The kinetics of inclusion formation during steel making in induction furnaces has been studied using Classical Nucleation Theory. Thermodynamic modelling of different types of inclusion formation was carried out using the Fact Sage software package and it has been validated experimentally with the inclusion classifier of the SEM/EDS analyzer.</description>
      <author>Maharishi Arvind, A. A. Adeleke, Ammasi Ayyandurai, Temitayo S. Ogedengbe, M Madan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/icmeas58693.2023.10379397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pole to Ground Fault Detection Using Leakage Current for DC Distribution System with IT ground</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5207/jieie.2023.37.6.043</link>
      <description>Kyung-Min Lee, Chul&#8208;Won Park, Journal of The Korean Institute of Illuminating and Electrical Installation Engineers. 37(6)] 2023.
Recently, policies such as expansion of distributed power sources, and transition to electric vehicles are being promoted to reduce carbon dioxide. Most distributed power sources generate DC power, so when the direct current system is activated, it is effective in many aspects, including power loss reduction, grid connection efficiency, and economic feasibility. As a DC system protection plan is required according to the grounding system, the fault detection method for Pole to Ground Fault is very important. In this paper, we propose a technique using DWT (Discrete Wavelet Transform) for Pole to Ground Fault detection by leakage current in DC distribution system with IT ground system. First, after modeling the IT grounding DC distribution system using PSCAD s/w, Pole to Ground fault simulation is performed while varying the fault point and fault resistance. After implementing the proposed fault detection using MATLAB s/w, the performance is verified by comparing the proposed technique with the traditional technique through insulation resistance measurement.</description>
      <author>Kyung-Min Lee, Chul&#8208;Won Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5207/jieie.2023.37.6.043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provision of Reliable Power Supply for the First Category of Consumers Because of Renewable Energy Sources</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-51127-1_46</link>
      <description>Irina Kirpichnikova, Sergey Shipilov, Lecture notes in electrical engineering. None(None)] 2024.
This article describes the objects of the first category of power supply in the example of maternity hospital of the clinic of the Medical University of Chelyabinsk. There is a current power Supply Scheme and a group of electric consumers. The costs are calculated for electricity consumption under various schemes of power supply of the facility. It is also shown how the reduction in electricity consumption is associated with a reduction of carbon dioxide emissions into the atmosphere. It was suggested to use renewable energy sources as a way of power supply of the objects of the first category, such as wind turbines and Solar power plants. The cost of the equipment was calculated based on technical characteristics. It was also calculated the cost of savings on electricity consumptions from centralized sources. The benefits and the possibility of application of the renewable energy sources for objects of the first category are shown.</description>
      <author>Irina Kirpichnikova, Sergey Shipilov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-51127-1_46</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Isopropanol Additive on Exhaust Emissions in Gasoline Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378725</link>
      <description>Elitsa Nakova, Simeon Iliev, Kiril Hadjiev, No host. None(None)] 2023.
The steady increase in transport needs worldwide, especially in areas with dense populations, makes it necessary to seek methods and means of using sustainable alternatives to conventional fuels to reduce the use of fossil fuels and significantly reduce environmental pollution. This study investigated the effectiveness of Isopropanol as a blend with gasoline to improve the environmental performance of internal combustion engines. Besides, as an alternative fuel isopropyl alcohol can also be considered as a renewable source of energy. Alcohols, as an alternative energy source, are considered with priority, building on their characteristics. Isopropanol, as part of the group of alcohols, has been investigated with regard to its potential to improve the mixing and combustion process and also to influence the laminar flame speed as well as the combustion rate compared to conventional gasoline in internal combustion engines. The study focused on its impact on emissions, specifically hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide and nitrogen oxides. The study was carried out in a laboratory environment, on a 4-cylinder gasoline engine, for the purpose of the study gasoline and gasoline-Isopropanol mixtures were used in the ratio as follows: 95% gasoline and 5% Isopropanol (IP5), 90% gasoline and 10% Isopropanol (IP10), 85% gasoline and 15% Isopropanol (IP15) and 80% gasoline and 20% Isopropanol (IP20). Due to the properties of Isopropanol there is a reduction of HC, CO, CO2 and NOx emissions, the most favorable for this engine is the fuel mixture with Isopropanol content between 10%-15%.</description>
      <author>Elitsa Nakova, Simeon Iliev, Kiril Hadjiev</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/ciees58940.2023.10378725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Synergistic Dual-Functional Silver-Manganese Dioxide-CNTs Ternary Composite Electrocatalyst for Solid-State Zinc-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202401.0200.v1</link>
      <description>Guoqing Zhang, Tuan&#8208;Wu Cao, Peng Zhang, Shuying Kong, Binbin Jin, No host. None(None)] 2024.
Exploring effective oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalysts is crucial for progress in solid-state alkaline zinc-air batteries (ZAB). In this paper, silver-manganese dioxide-carbon nanotubes (SMC) ternary composites, which function as Electrocatalyst for air Electrodes, was produced via the pyrolysis of silver permanganate under microwave irradiation in one step. A scanning electron microscope (SEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and an energy dispersion spectrometer (EDS) have consistently determined that SMC consists of silver and alpha-manganese dioxide, which anchored on the surface of CNTs. Through polarization and chronoamperometery curves, the electrocatalytic activity of SMC for ORR was examined. The results reveal that SMC has higher catalytic activity than the chemically produced electrocatalyst for ORR in alkaline condition. Finally, a solid-state zinc-air cell with an electrocatalyst was constructed and tested. Constant current discharge curve of the zinc-air cell with SMC has a long discharge voltage plateau and a 60.03 mAh capacity at 30 mA &amp;amp;middot; cm&amp;amp;minus;2 . The mechanism of improvement in electrocatalytic activity was also discussed. In a summary, the strategy described in this study and the electrocatalyst produced can be regarded as an effective method for making a robust oxygen reduction catalyst toward solid-state zinc-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Guoqing Zhang, Tuan&#8208;Wu Cao, Peng Zhang, Shuying Kong, Binbin Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202401.0200.v1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
