<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 01:12:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Ionic Liquids Functionalized Copper Catalytic Systems for Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401049</link>
      <description>Zhengyi Fu, Jingfang Zhang, Haonan Wu, Yanan Gao, Hui Hu, Lijuan Shi, Qun Yi, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401366230

                The extensive combustion of fossil fuels results in excessive release of carbon dioxide (CO2), causing a global environmental crisis. It is imperative to develop sustainable methods for converting CO2 into renewable energy sources. Electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) offers the potential to generate valuable chemicals, including C1 products (e.g., carbon monoxide, methane, etc.) and C2+ products (e.g., ethene, ethanol, acetic acid, propyl alcohol, etc.). Copper&#8208;based (Cu&#8208;based) catalysts show promise for producing value&#8208;added C2+ products, but they face challenges like low selectivity and stability. The catalytic performances of Cu&#8208;based catalysts can be promoted through electronic structure adjustment, selective crystal face exposure, as well as molecular additive approaches. Ionic liquids (ILs), known for their strong CO2 adsorption capacity, adjustable hydrophobicity, and wide chemical window, hold significant promise for addressing the current challenges associated with Cu&#8208;based catalysts. This review provides a comprehensive overview of the structural characterization and catalytic mechanisms of ILs used in Cu&#8208;based CO2RR catalytic systems. Additionally, it offers suggestions for future research avenues regarding IL&#8208;functionalized Cu catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhengyi Fu, Jingfang Zhang, Haonan Wu, Yanan Gao, Hui Hu, Lijuan Shi, Qun Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Organic Frameworks for Photocatalytic Reduction of Carbon Dioxide: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06783</link>
      <description>Jinglun Yang, Zihao Chen, Lei Zhang, Qichun Zhang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401419317

                Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) are crystalline networks with extended backbones cross-linked by covalent bonds. Due to the semiconductive properties and variable metal coordinating sites, along with the rapid development in linkage chemistry, the utilization of COFs in photocatalytic CO</description>
      <author>Jinglun Yang, Zihao Chen, Lei Zhang, Qichun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling carbon dioxide emissions reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2024.08.004</link>
      <description>Andriy Matviychuk, Olena Zhytkevych, Natalia Osadcha, Energy Reports. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401448978

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andriy Matviychuk, Olena Zhytkevych, Natalia Osadcha</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2024.08.004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Synthesis of MOF&#8208;based Materials for Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400684</link>
      <description>Mitra Bagheri, Mirtha A. O. Louren&#231;o, Julien K. Dangbegnon, Nicol&#242; B. D. Monti, Lu&#237;s Mafra, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Juqin Zeng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401463455

                Porous ZIF&#8208;8 and ZIF&#8208;67 were synthesized via a green steam&#8208;assisted dry&#8208;gel technique and investigated as potential catalysts for CO2 electroreduction. The synthesis conditions are found to significantly influence the growth of these metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs). Notably, the water content employed during synthesis plays a crucial role in shaping the morphological properties of ZIF&#8208;8. Specifically, a moderate water content results in the formation of uniform ZIF&#8208;8 with a size distribution ranging from 240 to 440 nm. During CO2 electroreduction, these morphological properties exert substantial effects on the selectivity for CO formation, thereby facilitating the production of syngas with adjustable CO: H2 ratios. This feature holds promise for the widespread adoption of syngas as a clean alternative to fossil fuels, offering potential benefits for electricity generation and liquid fuel production. Despite sharing similar structural properties with ZIF&#8208;8, ZIF&#8208;67 exhibits distinct performance characterized by its limited selectivity for CO2 electroreduction. This discrepancy is attributed to the different metal centers of the two MOFs, resulting in the distinct activation of CO2 and H2O molecules and their further reduction. This finding highlights the critical role of metal centers in MOF&#8208;based materials for electrocatalysis application.</description>
      <author>Mitra Bagheri, Mirtha A. O. Louren&#231;o, Julien K. Dangbegnon, Nicol&#242; B. D. Monti, Lu&#237;s Mafra, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Juqin Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub&#8208;3 nm ultrafine Cu2O for electroreduction of carbon dioxide to ethane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129109</link>
      <description>Junhua You, Jun&#8208;Peng Chen, Sheng Wang, Jiali Ren, Hangzhou Zhang, Qi Zhang, Jian Tian, Haibo Liu, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401475192

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junhua You, Jun&#8208;Peng Chen, Sheng Wang, Jiali Ren, Hangzhou Zhang, Qi Zhang, Jian Tian, Haibo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel phthalocyanine anchored onto N-doped biochar for efficient electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154686</link>
      <description>Kai Hu, Shuna Jia, Boxiong Shen, Zhiqiang Wang, Zhijiang Dong, Honghong Lyu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401486392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Hu, Shuna Jia, Boxiong Shen, Zhiqiang Wang, Zhijiang Dong, Honghong Lyu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D and 3D phthalocyanine covalent organic frameworks for electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110330</link>
      <description>Qi Zhang, Bin Han, Yucheng Jin, Mingrun Li, Enhui Zhang, Jianzhuang Jiang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401486413

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Zhang, Bin Han, Yucheng Jin, Mingrun Li, Enhui Zhang, Jianzhuang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic reduction of air pollutants and carbon dioxide emissions in Shanxi Province, China from 2013 to 2020</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175342</link>
      <description>Li&#8208;Ling Wu, Shida Sun, G. M. Zhang, Zimu Jia, Yuyun Liu, Chenxi Xu, Mengjie Guo, Luyao Zhang, C. Cai, Runcao Zhang, Jialin Zheng, Wenjie He, Jun Yu, Bo Yu, Kebin He, The Science of The Total Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351327

                Synergistic reduction of air pollutants and carbon dioxide (CO</description>
      <author>Li&#8208;Ling Wu, Shida Sun, G. M. Zhang, Zimu Jia, Yuyun Liu, Chenxi Xu, Mengjie Guo, Luyao Zhang, C. Cai, Runcao Zhang, Jialin Zheng, Wenjie He, Jun Yu, Bo Yu, Kebin He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysts for Urea Synthesis from CO2 and Nitrogenous Species: from CO2 and N2/NOx Reduction to urea synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401333</link>
      <description>Li Chun, Qiuji Zhu, Chaojie Song, Yimin Zeng, Ying Zheng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401452383

                The traditional industrial synthesis of urea relies on the energy-intensive and polluting process, namely the Haber-Bosch method for ammonia production, followed by the Bosch-Meiser process for urea synthesis. In contrast, electrocatalytic C-N coupling from carbon dioxide (CO2) and nitrogenous species presents a promising alternative for direct urea synthesis under ambient conditions, bypassing the need for ammonia production. This review provides an overview of recent progress in the electrocatalytic coupling of CO2 and nitrogen sources for urea synthesis. It focuses on the role of intermediate species and active site structures in promoting urea synthesis, drawing from insights into reactants' adsorption behavior and interactions with catalysts tailored for CO2 reduction, nitrogen reduction, and nitrate reduction. Advanced electrocatalyst design strategies for urea synthesis from CO2 and nitrogenous species under ambient conditions are explored, providing insights for efficient catalyst design. Key challenges and prospective directions are presented in the conclusion. Mechanistic studies elucidating the C-N coupling reaction and future development directions are discussed. The review aims to inspire further research and development in electrocatalysts for electrochemical urea synthesis.</description>
      <author>Li Chun, Qiuji Zhu, Chaojie Song, Yimin Zeng, Ying Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amino-Functionalization Enhanced CO2 Reduction Reaction in Pure Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01416b</link>
      <description>Junfeng Chen, Wenzhe Niu, Liangyao Xue, Kai Sun, Xiaolong Yang, Xinyue Zhang, Weihang Li, Shuanglong Huang, Wenjuan Shi, Shouxin Zhang, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401403770

                The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO 2 RR) to carbon monoxide 11 represents a cost-effective pathway towards realizing carbon neutrality. To suppress 12 the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the...</description>
      <author>Junfeng Chen, Wenzhe Niu, Liangyao Xue, Kai Sun, Xiaolong Yang, Xinyue Zhang, Weihang Li, Shuanglong Huang, Wenjuan Shi, Shouxin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01416b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Reduction Potential of Sustainable Stainless Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s38313-024-1954-9</link>
      <description>Stefan Lindner, MTZ worldwide. 85(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401408525

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stefan Lindner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s38313-024-1954-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte manipulation on Cu-based electrocatalysts for electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.055</link>
      <description>Hongyao Zhou, Wanlong Xi, Peng Yang, Huiting Huang, Jia Tian, Marina Ratova, Dan Wu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongyao Zhou, Wanlong Xi, Peng Yang, Huiting Huang, Jia Tian, Marina Ratova, Dan Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Non-CO2 Greenhouse Gas Emissions by Catalytic Processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-6431-0_49-4</link>
      <description>Gabriele Centi, Siglinda Perathoner, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401366802

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gabriele Centi, Siglinda Perathoner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-6431-0_49-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction performance of shape-controlled bismuth nanowires</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3037959</link>
      <description>Yue Guan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401389639

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3037959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature Promotes Selectivity During Electrochemical CO2 Reduction on NiO:SnO2 Nanofibers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04116j</link>
      <description>M. A. Rodriguez-Olguin, Raju Lipin, Eleazar Casta&#241;eda-Morales, Cristina Flox Donoso, Tanja Kallio, Matthias Vandichel, Arturo Susarrey&#8208;Arce, Milla Suominen, Francisco Ru&#237;z-Zepeda, A. Manzo&#8208;Robledo, Han Gardeniers, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401415802

                Electrolyzers operate over a range of temperatures; hence, it is crucial to design electrocatalysts that do not compromise the product distribution unless temperature can promote selectivity. This work reports a...</description>
      <author>M. A. Rodriguez-Olguin, Raju Lipin, Eleazar Casta&#241;eda-Morales, Cristina Flox Donoso, Tanja Kallio, Matthias Vandichel, Arturo Susarrey&#8208;Arce, Milla Suominen, Francisco Ru&#237;z-Zepeda, A. Manzo&#8208;Robledo, Han Gardeniers</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04116j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Reaction: Comprehensive Strategic Approaches to Catalyst Design for Selective Liquid Products Formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402477</link>
      <description>Nivedita Sikdar, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401420173

                The escalating concern regarding the release of CO2 into the atmosphere poses a significant threat to the contemporary efforts in mitigating climate change. Amidst a multitude of strategies for curtailing CO2 emissions, the electrochemical CO2 reduction presents a promising avenue for transforming CO2 molecules into a diverse array of valuable gaseous and liquid products, such as CO, CH3OH, CH4, HCO2H, C2H4, C2H5OH, CH3CO2H, 1&#8208;C3H7OH and others. The mechanistic investigations of gaseous products (e.g. CO, CH4, C2H4, C2H6 and others) broadly covered in the literature. There is a noticeable gap in the literature when it comes to a comprehensive summary exclusively dedicated to coherent roadmap for the designing principles for a selective catalyst all possible liquid products (such as CH3OH, C2H5OH, 1&#8208;C3H7OH, 2&#8208;C3H7OH, 1&#8208;C4H9OH, as well as other C3&#8208;C4 products like methylglyoxal and 2,3&#8208;furandiol, in addition to HCO2H, AcOH, oxalic acid and others), selectively converted by CO2 reduction. This entails a meticulous analysis to justify these approaches and a thorough exploration of the correlation between materials and their electrocatalytic properties. Furthermore, these insightful discussions illuminate the future prospects for practical applications, a facet not exhaustively examined in prior reviews.</description>
      <author>Nivedita Sikdar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352454

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353277

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag/Cu Foam Catalyst for Selective Reduction of Co2 to Ch3oh at Low Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916909</link>
      <description>Xiaolong Deng, Renfeng Nie, H. Yang, Hongwei Chen, Jie Yang, Meijuan Lu, Kaiping Peng, Xiaoyu Zhou, Chen Yang, Juan Xie, Hu Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401378139

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaolong Deng, Renfeng Nie, H. Yang, Hongwei Chen, Jie Yang, Meijuan Lu, Kaiping Peng, Xiaoyu Zhou, Chen Yang, Juan Xie, Hu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916909</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352451

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353249

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353499

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-performance watermelon skin ion-solvating membrane for electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51139-6</link>
      <description>Qing-Lu Liu, Tang Tang, Zhimei Tian, Shiwen Ding, Linqin Wang, Dexin Chen, Zhiwei Wang, Wentao Zheng, Husileng Lee, Xingyu Lu, Xiaohe Miao, Lin Liu, Licheng Sun, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401389316

                Ion-solvating membranes have been gaining increasing attention as core components of electrochemical energy conversion and storage devices. However, the development of ion-solvating membranes with low ion resistance and high ion selectivity still poses challenges. In order to propose an effective strategy for high-performance ion-solvating membranes, this study conducted a comprehensive investigation on watermelon skin membranes through a combination of experimental research and molecular dynamics simulation. The micropores and continuous hydrogen-bonding networks constructed by the synergistic effect of cellulose fiber and pectin enable the hypodermis of watermelon skin membranes to have a high ion conductivity of 282.3 mS cm</description>
      <author>Qing-Lu Liu, Tang Tang, Zhimei Tian, Shiwen Ding, Linqin Wang, Dexin Chen, Zhiwei Wang, Wentao Zheng, Husileng Lee, Xingyu Lu, Xiaohe Miao, Lin Liu, Licheng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51139-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Hydrogen as Fuel in Decarbonizing US Clinker Manufacturing for Cement Production: Costs and CO2 Emissions Reduction Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.155078</link>
      <description>Ikenna J. Okeke, Sachin Nimbalkar, Kiran Thirumaran, Joe Cresko, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401459996

                As a low-carbon fuel, feedstock, and energy source, hydrogen is expected to play a vital role in the decarbonization of high-temperature process heat during the pyroprocessing steps of clinker production in cement manufacturing. However, to accurately assess its potential for reducing CO2 emissions and the associated costs in clinker production applications, a techno-economic analysis and a study of facility-level CO2 emissions are necessary. Assuming that up to 20% hydrogen can be blended in clinker fuel mix without significant changes in equipment configuration, this study evaluates the potential reduction in CO2 emissions (scopes 1 and 2) and cost implications when replacing current carbon-intensive fuels with hydrogen. Using the direct energy substitution method, we developed an Excel-based model of clinker production, considering different hydrogen&#65533;blend scenarios. Hydrogen from steam methane reformer (gray) and renewable-based electrolysis (green) are considered as sources of hydrogen fuel for blend scenarios of 5%&#65533;20%. Metrics such as the cost of cement production, facility-level CO2 emissions, and cost of CO2 avoided were computed. Results show that for hydrogen blends (gray or green) between 5% and 20%, the cost of cement increases by 0.6% to 16%, with only a 0.4% to 6% reduction in CO2 emissions. When the cost of CO2 avoided was computed, the extra cost required to reduce CO2 emissions is $229 to $358/ metric ton CO2. In summary, although green hydrogen shows promise as a low-carbon fuel, its adoption for decarbonizing clinker production is currently impeded by costs.</description>
      <author>Ikenna J. Okeke, Sachin Nimbalkar, Kiran Thirumaran, Joe Cresko</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.155078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352985

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-based metal-oxides and MOFs for efficient CO2 detection/reduction to chemical/fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100952</link>
      <description>Deepak Kumar, Pashupati Pratap Neelratan, Anshika Gupta, Neeru Sharma, Manisha Sharma, Sangeeta Shukla, Satendra Pal Singh, Jong&#8208;Sung Yu, Ajeet Kaushik, Sanjeev Kumar Sharma, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401361304

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deepak Kumar, Pashupati Pratap Neelratan, Anshika Gupta, Neeru Sharma, Manisha Sharma, Sangeeta Shukla, Satendra Pal Singh, Jong&#8208;Sung Yu, Ajeet Kaushik, Sanjeev Kumar Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353005

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Catalytic reduction of CO2 with 4e: formaldehyde, acetal synthesis and complex transformations"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Sarah Desmons, Julien Bonin, Marc Robert, S&#233;bastien Bontemps, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarah Desmons, Julien Bonin, Marc Robert, S&#233;bastien Bontemps</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02888k/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Dimension Reduction of Complex Three-dimensional CO2 Saturation using Deep Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2426378</link>
      <description>Hongsheng Wang, Seyyed A. Hosseini, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401437836

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongsheng Wang, Seyyed A. Hosseini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2426378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insight into electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to formate by the iron(I) porphyrin complex: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114430</link>
      <description>Yaqing Wang, Wenzhen Lai, Molecular Catalysis. 566(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401386102

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaqing Wang, Wenzhen Lai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114430</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b</link>
      <description>Jia Li, Jianning Lu, Shuai Li, Lu Dai, Kai Wang, Pengfei Li, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401377717

                2D conjugated MOFs (2D c-MOFs) have attracted significant interest in electrocatalysis due to their intrinsic electrical conductivity. Their catalytic performance heavily relied on the metal centers and structures of highly...</description>
      <author>Jia Li, Jianning Lu, Shuai Li, Lu Dai, Kai Wang, Pengfei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altering electronic states of Cu sites in Covalent organic frameworks for synthesis of formate via CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154636</link>
      <description>Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Qizheng An, Shuang Zheng, Guojuan Liu, Shuai Yang, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401437806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Qizheng An, Shuang Zheng, Guojuan Liu, Shuai Yang, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381913

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382002

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381984

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of primary drivers leading to emission reduction of major air pollutants and CO2 from global power plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2024.108936</link>
      <description>Haoran Xu, Wenxiao Zhang, Yu&#8217;ang Ren, Yuanzheng Zhang, Jin Li, Shuxiu Zheng, Rongji Dai, Jianying Hu, Hefa Cheng, Guofeng Shen, Huizhong Shen, Jianmin Ma, Shu Tao, Environment International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401478231

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoran Xu, Wenxiao Zhang, Yu&#8217;ang Ren, Yuanzheng Zhang, Jin Li, Shuxiu Zheng, Rongji Dai, Jianying Hu, Hefa Cheng, Guofeng Shen, Huizhong Shen, Jianmin Ma, Shu Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2024.108936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381983

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381884

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving towards synergistic reductions on PM2.5 and CO2 and its mechanism: A case study of Yangtze River Economic Belt, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11442-024-2258-3</link>
      <description>Binjie Gu, Haixia Zhao, Xin Li, Qianqian Zhang, Journal of Geographical Sciences. 34(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481960

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Binjie Gu, Haixia Zhao, Xin Li, Qianqian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11442-024-2258-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Jia Li, Jianning Lv, Shuai Li, Lu Dai, Xiaogang Wang, Pengfei Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Li, Jianning Lv, Shuai Li, Lu Dai, Xiaogang Wang, Pengfei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "In situ post-modification of substoichiometric 2D conjugated MOFs to boost ethylene selectivity in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381883

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04011b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S&#8208;scheme MnO2/Co3O4 sugar&#8208;gourd nanohybrids with abundant oxygen vacancies for efficient visible&#8208;light&#8208;driven CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401057</link>
      <description>Linfeng Jin, Hao Yu, Chenhui Wang, Changfa Guo, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Yijun Zhong, Yong Hu, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401399360

                Converting CO2 to carbon&#8208;based fuels using solar energy via photocatalysis is a promising approach to boost carbon neutrality. However, the solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion efficiency is hampered by interconnected multiple factors including insufficient light absorption, low separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers as well as complex and sluggish surface reaction kinetics. Herein, we incorporate MnO2 nanowires and Co3O4 hollow polyhedrons with abundant oxygen vacancies (Vo) into MnO2/Co3O4 sugar&#8208;gourd nanohybrids for boosting CO2 photoreduction. The MnO2/Co3O4 nanohybrids not only display strong absorption in the visible&#8211;near infrared region, but also facilitate the separation of photogenerated carriers in terms of S&#8208;scheme transfer pathway, supplying abundant electrons for CO2 reduction reaction. Furthermore, the presence of VO enhances the separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers and promotes the chemical adsorption to CO2 molecules. In addition, the interfacial electronic interaction between MnO2 and Co3O4 also contributes to the chemical adsorption and activation to CO2. Owing to the synergy of S&#8208;scheme transfer pathway and VO, the MnO2/Co3O4 hybrids exhibit greatly enhanced photocatalytic activity towards CO2 reduction under the irradiation of visible light in comparison with bare MnO2 and Co3O4, delivering a CO evolution rate of 15.9 umol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 with a 100% selectivity.</description>
      <author>Linfeng Jin, Hao Yu, Chenhui Wang, Changfa Guo, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Yijun Zhong, Yong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;SEWGS integration in a direct reduction steelmaking process for CO2 mitigation&#8221; [International Journal of Greenhouse Gas Control, Volume 130 (2023), 103991]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104203</link>
      <description>Nicola Zecca, P.D. Cobden, Leonie L&#252;cking, Giampaolo Manzolini, International journal of greenhouse gas control. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354476

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicola Zecca, P.D. Cobden, Leonie L&#252;cking, Giampaolo Manzolini</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does economic growth targets setting lead to carbon emissions? An empirical study from China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122084</link>
      <description>Beibei Shi, Guiyi Zhu, Nan Li, Journal of Environmental Management. 368(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401408719

                Accurately identifying the historical causes of carbon emissions in the process of national economic development is an important basis for developing countries to achieve carbon emission reduction. This paper explores the intrinsic institutional causes of China's high CO2 emission growth based on the characteristic economic growth target system of China, and attempts to empirically test the environmental effects behind this system. The results of the study show that the setting of absolute economic growth targets significantly increases the carbon dioxide emissions of cities under horizontal competition, and the setting of relative economic growth targets exacerbates the above carbon emission effect under vertical competition. In addition, the heterogeneity analysis shows that the carbon emission effect of setting economic growth targets is stronger in resource-dependent cities and cities with a lower level of economic development. Mechanism tests show that economic growth targets not only significantly increases total fossil energy consumption and reduces energy efficiency at the firm level, but also leads to the increase of energy consumption and the reduction of energy efficiency at the industry level. The findings of this study provide an intrinsic institutional explanation for China's high carbon emissions and provide useful guidance for the design of mechanisms to achieve large-scale carbon emission reductions in developing countries.</description>
      <author>Beibei Shi, Guiyi Zhu, Nan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of Methanol Production using PyBOUND</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.194568</link>
      <description>Prapatsorn Borisut, Bianca Williams, Aroonsri Nuchitprasittichai, Selen Cremaschi, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401442238

                In this paper, we study the design optimization of methanol production with the goal of minimizing methanol production cost. One challenge of methanol production via carbon dioxide (CO2) hydrogenation is the reduction of operating costs. The simulation of methanol production is implemented within the Aspen HYSYS simulator. The feeds are pure hydrogen and captured CO2. The process simulation involves a single reactor and incorporates recycling at a ratio of 0.995. The methanol production cost is determined using an economic analysis. The cost includes capital and operating costs, which are determined through the equations and data from the capital equipment-costing program. The decision variables are the pressure and temperature of the reactor contents. The optimization problem is solved using a derivative-free algorithm, pyBOUND, a Python-based black-box model optimization algorithm that uses random forests (RFs) and multivariate adaptive regression splines (MARS). The predicted minimum methanol production cost by pyBOUND is $1396.56 per tonne of methanol, which corresponds to the pressure of 68.82 bar and temperature of 192.23&#65533;C while the actual cost is $1393.95 per tonne of methanol at these conditions. The cost breakdown of methanol production is 75% hydrogen price, 11% utility cost, 8% capital cost, 5% carbon dioxide price, and 1% operating cost.</description>
      <author>Prapatsorn Borisut, Bianca Williams, Aroonsri Nuchitprasittichai, Selen Cremaschi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.194568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Power Generation Systems With and Without Carbon Capture on Offshore Hydrocarbon Processing Facilities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-135750</link>
      <description>Jaime HuiChoo Tan, C. Lee, Ravi Kumar Mantry, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401458469

                Abstract There are very few offshore hydrocarbon processing facilities in operation that have implemented combined-cycle power generation systems, and this power scheme deserves more serious consideration and adoption due to its positive effect on carbon reduction. In this study, assessment is made of power generation schemes based on gas-driven power generation system, steam-driven power generation system and combined-cycle power generation system for an example floating production, storage and offloading (FPSO) platform design, to compare the engineering design, fuel gas consumption, equipment weights, and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions associated to each power generation system. It is found that the combined-cycle power generation system improves energy efficiency, reduces fuel gas consumption and in turn reduces CO2 emissions. Further, potential implementation of an offshore carbon capture system for separating CO2 from the gas turbine flue gases using a proprietary amine absorption technology, is presented. This paper recommends integrating combined-cycle power generation scheme and post-combustion carbon capture on the gas turbine exhausts for reducing the carbon footprint of the power generation system on the facility. Carbon capture of the process waste gas incinerator exhausts can further achieve the overall facility net-zero carbon emissions target, however this aspect is not in the scope of this paper.</description>
      <author>Jaime HuiChoo Tan, C. Lee, Ravi Kumar Mantry</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-135750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Study on Shale Mechanical Properties Interacted with Supercritical Carbon Dioxide and Brine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0352</link>
      <description>Wenying Li, Tianshou Ma, Yang Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401479189

                ABSTRACT: Supercritical carbon dioxide (SC-CO2) can be utilized to displace methane in shale gas reservoirs due to its low viscosity, high diffusivity, and high density. However, injection of SC-CO2 can cause a series of physical and chemical interactions with the pore brine and shale rock, leading to irreversible changes in the mechanical properties of the shale. To investigate changes in the mechanical properties of the shale that interacted with SC-CO2 and brine, Longmaxi shale samples were soaked in pure SC-CO2 and SC-CO2 + brine for seven days at 50 &#176; C and 15MPa. Uniaxial and triaxial compression tests were performed on the soaked samples, and acoustic emission was monitored during the loading process. The results indicated that the Longmaxi shale exhibited a more pronounced reduction in strength under the SC-CO2+brine condition compared to the pure SC-CO2 condition. In the loading process, the acoustic emission signals exhibit a distinct staged characteristic, and the signals are generated primarily during the unstable crack expansion stage. The observed increase in the fractal dimension of the signals at the same circumferential pressure indicates that the shale damage is multifaceted, resulting in a reduction in the stability of the shale. This study may help to elucidate the alterations in the mechanical properties of shale as a consequence of its interaction with SC-CO2. Furthermore, the findings may provide a foundation for the recovery of shale gas using CO2 displacement. 1. INTRODUCTION With the rapid growth of the global economy and the increasing level of industrialization, the supply of traditional fossil energy has gradually failed to meet the energy needs of today's society (Zou et al., 2016). Shale gas, as one of the most important unconventional oil and gas resources, has attracted a lot of attention because of its abundant reserves, cleanliness, low cost, and long supply cycle (Zhou and Zhang, 2020). Shale reservoirs are typically characterized by low porosity, low permeability, and high clay content (Jin et al., 2012), so hydraulic fracturing is commonly used to enhance shale gas production (Daneshy, 2010). However, it can result in significant water loss, damage to the physical properties of the reservoir, and contamination of surface water with back-draining fluids (Estrada and Bhamidimarri, 2016; Yang et al., 2019; DiStefano et al., 2019). Supercritical carbon dioxide (SC-CO2) is often used to enhance shale gas recovery due to its low viscosity, low surface tension, and high extraction capacity in its supercritical state (Adwani, 2007; Wang et al., 2011; Yang et al., 2008). This method has several advantages, including no damage to the reservoir, high efficiency of jet breakthrough, and the ability to lower the viscosity of crude oil and displace shale gas (Lu et al., 2021; Zhao et al., 2021).</description>
      <author>Wenying Li, Tianshou Ma, Yang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DOE's Carbon Transport and Storage Program: Supporting Storage Infrastructure Build-Out Critical for Decarbonization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1223</link>
      <description>I. G. Rosen, Amanda Raddatz Bopp, Darin Damiani, Traci Rodosta, Rajesh Pawar, Robert H. Smith, Kevin Dooley, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481715

                ABSTRACT: For decades, the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) Office of Fossil Energy and Carbon Management's (FECM) Carbon Transport and Storage (CTS) Program has invested in projects to validate safe and secure geologic storage of captured carbon dioxide (CO2) through technology development and pilot- and large-scale field tests. Recent U.S. legislation, such as the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law (BIL) and the Inflation Reduction Act (IRA), provide the financial backing and policy incentives that have enabled the CTS Program to accelerate the deployment of carbon capture and storage (CCS), storage-based carbon dioxide removal (CDR), and multi-modal CO2 transport systems, which are crucial for helping the administration meet its incremental decarbonization goals through 2050. With appropriations enacted under the BIL, the CTS Program is investing in projects that will help facilitate the build-out and expansion of industry-led CCS/CDR and CO2 transport projects that are safe, efficient, equitable, and environmentally responsible. In addition, annual appropriations for the base CTS Program are supporting BIL-funded efforts by investing in projects that will facilitate development and validation of cost-effective next generation technologies, expand basin-scale storage resource assessment and management, provide technical assistance to stakeholders and impacted communities, and establish a CO2 transport research program that considers multiple modes of transport, such as pipeline, ship, rail, and truck. The CTS Program will accelerate CCS/CDR and transport deployment through strategically interfacing five key initiatives: Carbon Storage Assurance Facility Enterprise (CarbonSAFE), Carbon Basin Assessment and Storage Evaluation (CarbonBASE), Carbon Storage Technology Operations and Research (CarbonSTORE), regional technical assistance, and a CO2 transport research consortium. The CTS Program recognizes that accelerating CCS/CDR and CO2 transport infrastructure development will require technical assistance to stakeholders and communities. To achieve this, the CTS Program's technical assistance projects are building on past successes and the ongoing Regional Initiative projects by providing stakeholders with access to expertise in areas such as characterization methods, consultation on permitting and monitoring strategies, business model development, and community engagement. The most recent regional technical assistance projects selected in 2023 are focused on assistance for developers of large- and hub-scaled projects with a strong emphasis on community engagement and participation. In 2024, the CTS Program is expected to select new Regional Initiative Technical Assistance Partnership (RITAP) projects that is expected to address the unique challenges and opportunities of multiple CCS/CDR and CO2 transport projects developed within a single geologic basin. Technical assistance may include properly siting storage projects to avoid pressure interference between neighboring storage facilities, pore space and mineral rights issues, transportation rights-of way, navigating diverse regulatory jurisdictions, storage resource management, and other aspects.</description>
      <author>I. G. Rosen, Amanda Raddatz Bopp, Darin Damiani, Traci Rodosta, Rajesh Pawar, Robert H. Smith, Kevin Dooley</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Caprock Integrity with Laboratory Scale In-Situ CO2 Injection Test</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0671</link>
      <description>Kanitthorn Adisornsupawat, Anusarn Sangnimnuan, Porranut Rabiabpo, Sudarshan Govindarajan, Akshay Thombare, Deepak Gokaraju, Munir Aldin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481137

                ABSTRACT: Maximum injection or breakthrough pressure is a key factor to determine storage volume of CO2 and to ensure integrity of caprock. In some studies, the maximum injection pressure is based on 90% of fracture pressure (Solomon, 2007). Seal capacity using Mercury Injection Capillary Pressure (MICP) has mainly been utilized in petroleum industry to obtain maximum injection pressure (Purcell, 1949). Laboratory experiments of injection pressure can be performed using both direct and indirect method. The indirect method that widely used mainly consists of mercury intrusion porosimetry. This can quickly estimate breakthrough pressure. However, conversion factor from mercury-air condition into CO2-brine condition is needed. In addition, most of the tests are conducted at ambient condition where impact of pressure and temperature are excluded. In this study, Super Critical CO2 is injected directly into reservoir samples to obtain maximum injection pressure under reservoir condition. The step rate pressure was then applied at a series of increasing magnitudes with a steady holding period until breakthrough pressure is observed. Representative stress and temperature were maintained using confining pressure and heater in triaxial system. Acoustic and resistivity sensors were recorded in real-time. Results of pressure breakthrough for outcrops and reservoir samples are presented. 1. INTRODUCTION With the increase of global warming due to excessive release of CO2 emission, Carbon dioxide capture and geological storage or utilization and storage (CCS or CCUS) has become crucial and to be implemented to meet the net zero emission goals (Masson-Delmotte et al., 2018, Metz et al., 2005). In many industries, the policies start to include the net zero emission as one of the main company's goals. Carbon credit will also be obtained as the CO2 emission has been reduced. The implementation of CCS and CCUS has started globally, including the US, EU, and Asia. The policy for each region/country differs but under the same goal to reduce CO2 emission. The success of a CCUS operation and emissions reduction is dependent on injecting CO2 back to the reservoir after production and keeping the CO2 stored inside the reservoir without migrating to the caprock. Therefore, the caprock sealing ability is crucial and needs to be studied thoroughly. One of the parameters used to characterize the caprock integrity is the breakthrough pressure, which is the point where CO2 starts to leak into the caprock after being injected into the reservoir. The breakthrough or maximum injection pressure is also used to design the CO2 storage volume in reservoir or aquifer. Whether the desired volume can be achieved or not, successful sealing is directly dependent on breakthrough pressure. If the breakthrough pressure used in the study is too low, the storage volume might not be enough to meet the CO2 reduction and carbon credit goal set by the company. This will result in a new site or an additional site to be able to meet the injection target (Smith et al., 2011, DOE-NETL, 2017).</description>
      <author>Kanitthorn Adisornsupawat, Anusarn Sangnimnuan, Porranut Rabiabpo, Sudarshan Govindarajan, Akshay Thombare, Deepak Gokaraju, Munir Aldin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0671</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability Study of Tight Sandstone Reservoirs During CO2 Dynamic Storage Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0142</link>
      <description>Yuting He, Yuetian Liu, Jingru Wang, Jingpeng Li, Peiying Zhang, Rukuan Chai, Pingtian Fan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401479289

                ABSTRACT: The tight sandstone reservoirs present a viable option for geological CO2 storage. The stability and safety of the reservoir rock are fundamental for long-term CO2 storage. However, the injection may lead to interactions between H2O, CO2, and rock, potentially impacting the mineral composition and physical properties of the reservoir. This ultimately leads to a decrease in the mechanical properties of the rock and disrupts the stability of the reservoir in high-pressure environments. In this study, rock mechanics experiments, nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) experiments, and scanning electron microscopy (SEM) experiments were carried out to investigate the changes in mechanical properties, pore size, and microstructure of cores with different mineral compositions treated with aqueous carbonate solution under different confining pressures, in order to analyze the effects of the dynamic CO2 storage process on reservoir stability. The results show that the presence of CO2 under confining pressure leads to a decrease in rock strength. Carbonic acid solution can effectively dissolve feldspars and clay minerals in the rock composition, causing changes in pore structure and leading to a decrease in rock strength. The study aims to provide insights and recommendations for developing oil and gas extraction and carbon sequestration. 1. INTRODUCTION Carbon dioxide geological storage technology is one of the effective ways to mitigate the global warming trend, and its basic principle is to inject captured carbon dioxide into deep underground rock pores for long-term isolation and fixation (Chen et al., 2023; Farquhar et al., 2015). Among the many potential storage media, tight sandstone reservoirs have received great attention from scientists and industry for their complex pore structure and high storage capacity (Bachu et al., 1994; Michael et al., 2009). However, CO2 injection affects the porosity, permeability, and mechanical properties of reservoirs, which may cause reservoir damage and reduced storage efficiency (Yu et al., 2012). For example, CO2 reacts chemically with minerals in the rock, which may lead to dissolution or precipitation of minerals, and thus change the physical structure of the rock (Fischer et al., 2010). The physical structure of the rock may be altered. Therefore, the mechanical response of rocks during CO2 injection must be thoroughly studied to ensure the safety and efficiency of the storage process. In recent years, in the field of CO2 geological storage research, scholars have carried out a large number of experimental and simulation studies, aiming to explore the mechanism of CO2 interaction with reservoir rocks and trying to predict and optimize the reservoir performance (Vafaie et al., 2023). The CO2 has different dissolution capacities for different minerals, leading to changes in the microstructure and mechanical properties of mineral surfaces, which indirectly leads to the decline of rock mechanical properties, thus affecting the production of unconventional oil and gas and reservoir stability (Vogt et al., 2014; Zhang et al., 2020; Zhang et al., 2022). Among various minerals, carbonate minerals (e.g., calcite and dolomite) have the highest solubility and the fastest reaction rate, while silicate minerals such as feldspar and quartz have lower solubility and slower reaction rate (Memon et al., 2022; Ranjith et al., 2019; Xing et al., 2019). Under the combined effect of CO2, the compressive strength and modulus of elasticity of the rock are significantly reduced (Huang et al., 2020; Rathnaweera et al., 2015; Zhou et al., 2024). The geological sequestration of carbon dioxide is a dynamic process, with the continuous injection of fluids, the formation pressure gradually increases. In fractured and low-permeability formations, the physical properties of rocks are affected by the increase in pore pressure, and their physical properties change significantly, which affects reservoir capacity (D&#225;vila et al., 2017; Pavan &amp; Govindarajan, 2023; Vialle &amp; Vanorio, 2011). Zhao et al. carried out CO2 in brine solution saturated dense sandstone reservoir core samples for oil repulsion and explained the increase in porosity and permeability due to the increase in pore pressure (Zhao et al., 2021). Liteanu et al. investigated the effect of supercritical CO2 on rock mechanics, where carbonic acid solution led to stress corrosion fracturing and strength reduction of rocks (Liteanu et al., 2013).</description>
      <author>Yuting He, Yuetian Liu, Jingru Wang, Jingpeng Li, Peiying Zhang, Rukuan Chai, Pingtian Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameter Estimation of Breakthrough Curve Models in the Adsorption Process of H2S and CO2 Using the Markov Chain Monte Carlo Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14166956</link>
      <description>Haianny Beatriz Saraiva Lima, Ana Paula Souza de Sousa, Wellington Betencurte da Silva, Deibson Silva da Costa, Emerson Cardoso Rodrigues, Diego Cardoso Estumano, Applied Sciences. 14(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401410408

                The increase in emissions of toxic gasses such as hydrogen sulfide (H2S) and carbon dioxide (CO2), resulting from growing urbanization and industrialization, has caused environmental and public health problems, making the implementation of air purification techniques through adsorption important. Thus, modeling the gas adsorption process is fundamental for good agreement with experimental data, employing mathematical models that enable the prediction of adsorption capacity. In this way, the present work aimed to compare different analytical breakthrough curve models (Thomas, Yoon&#8211;Nelson, Adams&#8211;Bohart, and Yan) for the adsorption of H2S and CO2 in fixed-bed columns, using experimental data from the literature, estimating the curve parameters through the Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) method with the Metropolis&#8211;Hastings algorithm, and ranking using the determination coefficients (R2 and R2Adjusted) and the Bayesian Information Criterion (BIC). The models showed better agreement using the estimation of maximum adsorption capacity (qs, N0) and the constants of each model (kth, kyn, and kba). In the adsorption of H2S, the Yan model stood out for its precision in estimating qs. For the adsorption of CO2, the Adams&#8211;Bohart model achieved better results with the estimation of N0, along with the Yoon&#8211;Nelson model. Furthermore, the use of this method allows for a reduction in computational effort compared to models based on complex differential equations.</description>
      <author>Haianny Beatriz Saraiva Lima, Ana Paula Souza de Sousa, Wellington Betencurte da Silva, Deibson Silva da Costa, Emerson Cardoso Rodrigues, Diego Cardoso Estumano</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14166956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Application for CCUS Carbon Storage: Fracture Analysis and Mapping in the Illinois Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1183</link>
      <description>Gao Liu, Abhash Kumar, William Harbert, Hema Siriwardane, Dustin Crandall, Luciane Cunha, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401479922

                ABSTRACT: In this paper, an innovative method comprising of multi-tiered analysis has been developed to leverage advanced Machine Learning (ML) techniques to process passive seismic monitoring data acquired over a three-year injection period into a CO2 storage site in the Illinois Basin for potential fracture/fault analysis. The study is aimed at contributing to monitoring design and de-risking operation for carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS) and improving monitoring, verification, and accounting (MVA) of injected subsurface CO2. Information on fractures from well logs and core data is integrated together to develop a comprehensive understanding of how these fractures correlate with the rock petrophysical properties. The fracture networks obtained from this approach can directly benefit field operations and reservoir management decision-making for CCUS, which include the dynamic injection scheduling/workover, risk assessment, and further monitoring design. Furthermore, the proposed methodology is potentially applicable to oil and gas assets as well as geothermal development, operations, and monitoring. 1. INTRODUCTION Injecting significant volume of anthropogenic carbon dioxide (CO2) into geological reservoirs is one of the piloted practices for greenhouse gas reduction. These operations have gained considerable traction in the last decade as a viable option to reduce the long-term environmental footprint. However, monitoring the storage reservoir to ensure safe and long-term storage of CO2 for de-risk operations and storage management is undergoing dynamic shifts, expanding opportunities for implementing innovative techniques and applications, especially for the commercial-scale deployment. This study is part of the Science-informed Machine Learning (ML) for Accelerating Real-Time Decisions in Subsurface Applications (SMART) Initiative which have funded by the US Department of Energy Carbon Storage program to transform our ability to make better, informed decisions related to the subsurface through real-time visualization, forecasting, and virtual learning. The outcomes of the SMART Initiative are science-informed machine learning-based tools that can be applied at carbon storage sites throughout the nation and the world to 1) improve the ability to consolidate technical knowledge, site-specific characterization information, and real-time data in a digestible way; 2) enable the optimization of carbon storage reservoirs by creating a capability for "real-time" forecasting of carbon storage reservoir behavior; and 3) improve the ability to understand and communicate subsurface behavior during carbon storage operations to non-experts. The ultimate objectives aim in helping accelerate the deployment of field scale carbon storage in the US and the world.</description>
      <author>Gao Liu, Abhash Kumar, William Harbert, Hema Siriwardane, Dustin Crandall, Luciane Cunha</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PERHITUNGAN EMISI GAS RUMAH KACA DALAM KAWASAN PERTAMBANGAN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.70191/jplp.v1i1.55151</link>
      <description>Aulya Putri, Suwardi Suwardi, Hermanu Widjaja, Dyah Tjahyandari Suryaningtyas, Putri Oktariani, Octaviana Randrikasari, No host. 1(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401498564

                Carbon emissions are one of the components of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions in the form of carbon dioxide (CO2) which mainly comes from the use of fossil fuels and various human activities. Based on fossil fuel and industrial emissions data, in 2022 Indonesia ranked as the 6th largest carbon emitting country in the world after China, the United States, India, Russia and Japan, with 728.88 million tons of CO2e total emissions. The Ministry of Industry reported that total GHG emissions from Indonesia's industrial sector reached 238.1 million tons of CO2e in 2022. In the mining industry, GHG emissions originate from deforestation, energy use, processing, and refining, with non-renewable energy use being the largest emitter. GHG emissions from primary mineral and metal production contribute approximately 10% of global GHG emissions related to energy. Each mining industry may have varying primary sources of GHG emissions depending on the type of mine and the final product. Mining industries, as one of the major emitters, must conduct GHG inventories to understand emission sources and develop effective reduction strategies. GHG inventory activities are conducted based on guidelines provided by the Ministry of Environment and Forestry's National Greenhouse Gas Inventory Management Handbook (2012), Book II Volumes 1-4. Efforts to reduce GHG emissions can be undertaken through planting plants that have high carbon absorption and storage capabilities in mine reclamation activities, as well as using New and Renewable Energy (NRE) as an alternative to replace fossil energy.</description>
      <author>Aulya Putri, Suwardi Suwardi, Hermanu Widjaja, Dyah Tjahyandari Suryaningtyas, Putri Oktariani, Octaviana Randrikasari</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.70191/jplp.v1i1.55151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wavelet Transform and Hidden Markov Model Application for Unsupervised Clustering of Microseismic Events from CO2 Injection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0844</link>
      <description>Richard Willis, Hongkyu Yoon, Jenny Harding, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481726

                ABSTRACT: Injection of CO2 increases pore pressures that trigger complex subsurface interactions, leading to slip or reactivation of pre-existing faults/fractures and/or creating fractures. Understanding the subsurface response is key to preserving the integrity of the storage site, optimizing the injection, and mitigating the risk of seismic hazards. Machine learning (ML) models have shown the potential to improve our understanding of complex earth systems by identifying subtle changes in patterns of seismic and microseismic data. Furthermore, ML has shown great promise in revealing patterns in time-dependent spectral properties of (micro-) seismic data to identify differences in subsurface response. In this study, a wavelet transform scheme is implemented to isolate high energy frequency bands within microseismic data from the Illinois Basin Decatur Project (IBDP). Subsequently, an unsupervised ML method is used to identify various subsurface responses attributed to CO2 injection at the IBDP. Specifically, the unsupervised method known as SpecUFEx is used to further reduce the dimensionality of the reconstructed high energy micro-seismic spectrograms, solve for characteristic fingerprints, and apply K-means clustering to group similar fingerprints. Finally, a comparison is made between our clustering results and an implementation of SpecUFEx where the full frequency spectrum of the microseismic data was used. 1 INTRODUCTION Carbon capture and storage (CCS) has emerged as a critical technology in the global effort to mitigate climate change by reducing carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions from industrial processes and power generation. The concept of CCS involves capturing CO2 emissions from large point sources such as power plants and industrial facilities, transporting the captured CO2 to suitable storage sites, and securely storing it underground in geological formations to prevent its release into the atmosphere. This approach not only helps reduce greenhouse gas emissions but also enables the continued use of fossil fuels while transitioning to cleaner energy sources. As nations strive to meet ambitious climate targets, CCS is increasingly recognized as a key component of the portfolio of solutions needed to achieve significant and sustained reductions in CO2 emissions on a global scale. However, one primary risk of CCS is induced seismicity. Injecting CO2 into subsurface formations increases pore pressure, leading to changes in local stress conditions and potentially triggering micro-seismic events within basement rock. Accurate monitoring and modeling are imperative for the success of CCS projects, ensuring efficiency, safety, and societal acceptance.</description>
      <author>Richard Willis, Hongkyu Yoon, Jenny Harding</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Reservoir Effect of Adjacent Fe Nanoclusters Boosts Atomic Fe Active Sites on Porous Carbon for the Both Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405157</link>
      <description>Jiaxin He, Li Xu, Chenchen Qin, Jian Zhang, Daomeng Liu, Qingyi Li, Ziyi Feng, Junzhong Wang, Peigen Liu, Hongbao Li, Zhengkun Yang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401485552

                Electrochemical oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO</description>
      <author>Jiaxin He, Li Xu, Chenchen Qin, Jian Zhang, Daomeng Liu, Qingyi Li, Ziyi Feng, Junzhong Wang, Peigen Liu, Hongbao Li, Zhengkun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular enhancement of Cu-based catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02619e</link>
      <description>Haiqiang Luo, Bo Li, Jian&#8208;Gong Ma, Peng Cheng, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401375322

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (eCO</description>
      <author>Haiqiang Luo, Bo Li, Jian&#8208;Gong Ma, Peng Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02619e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the scaling relations of effective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrochemical reduction in diatomic catalysts by adjusting the flow direction of intermediate structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03085k</link>
      <description>Yanwen Zhang, Zhaoqun Yao, Yiming Yang, Xingwu Zhai, Feng Zhang, Zhijun Guo, Xinghuan Liu, Bin Yang, Yunxia Liang, Guixian Ge, Xin Jia, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401430982

                The electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO</description>
      <author>Yanwen Zhang, Zhaoqun Yao, Yiming Yang, Xingwu Zhai, Feng Zhang, Zhijun Guo, Xinghuan Liu, Bin Yang, Yunxia Liang, Guixian Ge, Xin Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03085k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic Modeling of Carbonation of Blended Cements for Wellbore Integrity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1110</link>
      <description>Farzana Rahman, Raissa Douglas Ferron, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480260

                ABSTRACT: Carbon capture and storage (CCS) holds promise for mitigating global greenhouse gas emissions by capturing carbon dioxide (CO2) from industrial sources and storing it in deep geological formations. However, the potential impacts of CCS on oil well cements, critical components for wellbore integrity, demand careful evaluation. These cements are employed in primary, remedial cementing and plugging and abandonment operations of oil and gas wells. Alteration of cement hydration products via carbonation poses threat to wellbore integrity since it leads to leaching of cement matrix. Although carbonation of Portland cement is an inevitable process due to its favorable thermodynamic conditions, its negative impacts can be mitigated by optimizing the chemical composition of blended cements, tailored to specific thermodynamic environments. These blended cements incorporate supplementary cementitious materials (SCMS), such as silica, calcined clay, limestone, fly ash etc, to promote pozzolanic reactions. These pozzolanic reactions in blended systems produce chemically resistant hydration products. These hydration products differ from those of neat Portland cement due to the blend's initial lower calcium-to-silica (C/S) ratio. Blending cements with a low C/S ratio have been shown to produce hydration products that are less susceptible to CO2 attack. This study investigates the carbonation behavior of blended cements using thermodynamic modeling. Predicted carbonated phase assemblages indicate blended cements with SCMs are expected to provide wellbore integrity in the long run under static conditions. Thermodynamic modeling of neat and blended cements will provide us with insight to understand the progress of carbonation and the effectiveness of SCMs in blended cements for improving carbonation resistance. 1. INTRODUCTION Recent years have seen a spike in global interest to reduce carbon footprint in hopes of mitigating climate change. More actions are being taken by global society towards a low carbon future. Keeping that in mind, the energy industry is adapting to the emerging needs of the 21st century by means of effective sustainable practices and development. Oil and gas wells require high temperature and pressure (HTHP) resistant cement sheath that provides structural integrity and zonal isolation to these wells. At the end of their service life, these geothermal wells require plugging and abandonment (P&amp;A) in the form of cement sealant to prevent hydrocarbon leakage. It is estimated that over 2 million of unplugged abandoned wells in U.S. are leaking pollutants such as methane into groundwater reservoir, sea, and ocean, causing severe environmental pollution (Marcacci, 2020). Thus, advanced cement performance is required for geothermal cementing to mitigate issues related to leaky wellbore (both active and abandoned). Additionally, cement production itself is a carbon intensive process, which accounts for at least 8% of global CO2 emission. The cement industry needs to cut down its emission by at least 16% by 2030 to comply with the Paris Agreement (Tigue, 2022). Although concrete construction is considered as an avenue for such a reduction, one area that is overlooked is the cement used in the wellbores.</description>
      <author>Farzana Rahman, Raissa Douglas Ferron</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review on the Influence of Crystal Facets on the Product Selectivity of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR over Cu Metal Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c05326</link>
      <description>Dandan Ma, Chuanqi Zhi, Yimeng Zhang, Jiantao Chen, Yanmin Zhang, Jian&#8208;Wen Shi, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401477842

                The electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (ECRR) is promising in converting environmentally harmful CO</description>
      <author>Dandan Ma, Chuanqi Zhi, Yimeng Zhang, Jiantao Chen, Yanmin Zhang, Jian&#8208;Wen Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c05326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Contribution in Fault Stability Assessment During Fluid Injection: Improvement of the Analytical Probabilistic Approach of an In-House Tool</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0330</link>
      <description>Stefania Petroselli, A. Stiz, M. Brignoli, S. Monaco, F. Marton, D. Grilli, Guglielmo Luigi Daniele Facchi, F. Bottazzi, Stefano Mantica, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401479448

                ABSTRACT: Among the geomechanical aspects associated to the fluid injection in a reservoir, the effective stress reduction due to a cold fluid may be critical for the fault stability. To account for this aspect, Eni has implemented the thermal contribution in the in-house SAFE tool used for the fault stability assessment associated to injection projects. The validation of this feature has been carried out using Perkins and Gonzales (1984) model as a benchmark, considering a hypothetical vertical fault at a certain distance from the injection well, and oriented perpendicularly to the minimum horizontal stress direction. The results in terms of stress have been compared to a 2D Finite Element Abaqus simulation of the same case, previously validated with the benchmark. Finally, the unfavorable impact of the thermal aspect when a fluid colder than the rock mass is injected in a formation has been analyzed through a synthetic case. 1. INTRODUCTION One of the most critical challenges related to the actual problem of global climate change is to find an environmentally and economical solution to immediately reduce greenhouse gases emissions, particularly the carbon dioxide (CO2). To this aim, CO2 capture and storage (CCS) in deep geologic formations, such as depleted oil and gas reservoirs or deep saline aquifers, will have a crucial role in reducing gas emissions. To implement CCS on the scale needed to make noticeable changes, geological media suitable for gas storage must have sufficient capacity and injectivity, and a comprehensive understanding of their hydrologic-geochemical-geomechanical is needed to ensure the confinement for the lateral or vertical migration of CO2 to the surface (Rutqvist, 2012). The importance of geomechanics associated to carbon storage started to be recognized in the 2000s, when studies of actual CO2 injection sites have shown that significant geomechanical changes may indeed occur, depending on the injection conditions and the site-specific properties (Rutqvist et al., 2010). Among all known phenomena related to fluid injection, rock integrity and fault stability are key factors to be evaluated for reservoir development. Fault reactivation and associated induced seismicity have been observed in many water injection projects in the US, where the earthquake rate increase, since 2001, is due to the injection of water resulting from hydraulic fracturing operations in nearby disposal wells. High CO2 injection pressures can induce fluid driven fractures as well, triggering displacements along pre-existing faults and generating seismic events (Ellsworth, 2013). Moreover, the injection of a fluid with different temperature than the formation temperature leads to a thermal effect on the geomechanical integrity, adding a stress variation that could alter the fault resistance. More specifically, once the fluid is injected, rock usually cools down in the area around the well. In this condition, within the cooled zone, horizontal earth tension decreases as a result of the formation rock contracting (Perkins &amp; Gonzales, 1984; Kim &amp; Hosseini, 2017).</description>
      <author>Stefania Petroselli, A. Stiz, M. Brignoli, S. Monaco, F. Marton, D. Grilli, Guglielmo Luigi Daniele Facchi, F. Bottazzi, Stefano Mantica</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Forcing and Policy Synergy: A Multidimensional Approach in the Governance of Air Pollution and Carbon Emission</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.119747</link>
      <description>Qianwen Li, Tianchen Qian, Hui Wang, Li Bai, Ruyin Long, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401440721

                Policy synergies effectively contribute to the integrated management of air pollution and carbon emissions, which is crucial for safeguarding ecosystem stability and public health. This study uses the causal network model of Gaussian process regression to analyze the combined impacts of dynamic and static carbon emission reduction and air quality policies on carbon emissions and air quality. The causal effects of policy measures and their synergistic effects are also examined. The study results indicate: (1) There is significant geographical heterogeneity in the implementation of environmental policies and regional economic development, with the economically developed eastern coastal regions adopting more stringent carbon emission and air pollution control measures, while the western provinces adopt relatively lax environmental policies. (2) The synergistic effect of carbon emission reduction policies and air quality policies exists, and the two types of static policies are substitutable for managing carbon dioxide emissions and air pollution. (3) Policies' forced effect exists, where the exacerbation of environmental problems leads to the formation and implementation of policies. (4) The value added by the secondary industry is a key motivation for forming carbon emission reduction policies and air quality control policies. Additionally, the value added by the secondary industry directly impacts the incidence of respiratory diseases (e.g., tuberculosis). Finally, dynamic and synergistic policy recommendations are proposed based on the study's findings.</description>
      <author>Qianwen Li, Tianchen Qian, Hui Wang, Li Bai, Ruyin Long</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.119747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The synergistic effect of green innovation and governance in carbon neutrality: Insights from Japanese companies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bse.3922</link>
      <description>K. Keerthana, S. P. Wu, Thangavelu Kokulnathan, Mu&#8208;En Wu, Business Strategy and the Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401431553

                Abstract Japan is firmly committed to transitioning to a low&#8208;carbon economy to address climate change. This research focuses on the role of innovation and governance in achieving carbon neutrality among Japanese companies listed on the Tokyo Stock Exchange from 2017 to 2023, particularly in all carbon dioxide&#8208;contributing sectors. Through multivariate statistics, regression modeling, and quantitative literature analysis, we provide robust evidence of the relationship among innovation, governance, and carbon neutrality. The findings highlight the importance of fostering a sustainability&#8208;oriented culture to drive sustainable innovation and achieve carbon neutrality. We compared the environmental, social, and governance (ESG) and governance to expand our scope. Its results underscore the significance of strong corporate governance in facilitating sustainable initiatives. A robustness test is included to finalize that the samples have avoided endogeneity. These findings demonstrate a positive outlook for Japan's future emissions reduction.</description>
      <author>K. Keerthana, S. P. Wu, Thangavelu Kokulnathan, Mu&#8208;En Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bse.3922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of hydrogen production potential of wastewater based on GRA-BiLSTM model under shared socioeconomic pathway in Guangdong</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2024.117988</link>
      <description>Bingchun Liu, Yawei Du, Mingzhao Lai, Desalination. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401361114

                With the deepening of the energy transition, hydrogen production from wastewater has attracted widespread attention as an energy production method that can realize resource recycling. To explore whether hydrogen production from wastewater can have a significant role in the energy transition, it is crucial to effectively assess the future potential of hydrogen production from municipal wastewater. Based on the Guangdong Province of China, this study proposed a prediction model combining grey relation analysis (GRA) and bi-directional long short term memory (BiLSTM). Combined with a common socio-economic pathway (SSP), wastewater production is predicted from 2023 to 2050, and the potential for hydrogen production from wastewater is further analyzed. The cost of hydrogen production and carbon reduction potential under different scenarios are explored on this basis. The results show that by 2050, the SSP4 (Inequality) scenario will produce the most hydrogen, which will reach 22.0 billion m3, and reduce 247.2 billion tons of carbon dioxide emissions. In contrast, the SSP1 (Sustainability) scenario will produce 7.5 billion m3 of hydrogen and reduce carbon emissions by 84.5 billion tons. From the perspective of energy production and environmental protection, future hydrogen production from wastewater will make a great contribution to the global energy transition and sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Bingchun Liu, Yawei Du, Mingzhao Lai</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2024.117988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Institutional Performance and Carbon Reduction Effect of High-Quality Development of New Energy: China&#8217;s Experience and Policy Implication</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166734</link>
      <description>L. Zhang, Dong Zheng-ai, Zhixiong Tan, Jiahui Luo, Dong Yan, Sustainability. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354919

                Based on the policy text from 1999 to 2022, this paper quantitatively analyzes photovoltaic power, wind power and new energy policies in mainland China by keyword capture and policy strength and establishes a spatial Durbin model to study the carbon reduction effects. The results show the following: (1) The development of new energy is primarily project-based and concentrated in rural areas. (2) Financial support is a double-edged sword. (3) After the implementation of the Renewable Energy Law in 2015, the change trend in policy quantity, total policy intensity, and average policy intensity is generally consistent. (4) The increase in the strength of new energy policies has effectively reduced the intensity of provincial carbon dioxide emissions. (5) New energy policies introduced in a single region are less effective in reducing carbon emissions than joint regional regulation. Therefore, it is necessary to improve the quality and coordination of new energy policies through the effective convergence of policies and regular evaluations to enhance the positive guidance of the policies. Policy measures for new energy are refined in three areas: improving the amount and quality of new energy policies, strengthening new energy policies and establishing cooperation mechanisms for the cross-regional consumption of new energy.</description>
      <author>L. Zhang, Dong Zheng-ai, Zhixiong Tan, Jiahui Luo, Dong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyanobacterial Artificial Plants for Enhanced Indoor Carbon Capture and Utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400401</link>
      <description>Maryam Rezaie, Seokheun Choi, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401482587

                Abstract Indoor carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) levels are often significantly higher than those outdoors, which is a growing health concern, particularly in urban areas where people spend over 80% of their time indoors. Traditional CO 2 mitigation methods, such as ventilation and filtration, are becoming less effective as outdoor CO 2 levels increase due to global warming. This study introduces a novel solution: cyanobacterial artificial plants that enhance indoor carbon capture while converting CO 2 into oxygen (O 2 ) and bioelectricity. These artificial plants use indoor light to drive photosynthesis, achieving a 90% reduction in indoor CO 2 levels, from 5000 to 500 ppm&#8212;far surpassing the 10% reduction seen with natural plants. In addition to improving air quality, the system produces O 2 and enough bioelectricity to power portable electronics. Each artificial leaf contains five biological solar cells that generate electricity during photosynthesis, with water and nutrients supplied through transpiration and capillary action, mimicking natural plant systems. The system generates an open circuit voltage of 2.7 V and a maximum power output of 140 &#181;W. This decentralized approach offers a sustainable, energy&#8208;efficient solution to indoor environmental challenges, providing improved air quality and renewable electricity amid rising global CO 2 levels.</description>
      <author>Maryam Rezaie, Seokheun Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Clustered, Multi-modal CO2 Transport Considering Non-linear Costs &#65533; a Path-planning Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.150076</link>
      <description>Kang Qiu, Sigmund Eggen Holm, Julian Straus, Simon Roussanaly, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456022

                An important measure to achieve global reduction in CO2 emissions is CO2 capture, transport, and storage. The deployment of CO2 capture requires the development of a shared CO2 transport infrastructure, where CO2 can be transported with different transport modes. Furthermore, the cost of CO2 transport can be subject to significant economies of scale effects with respect to the amount of CO2 transported, also mentioned as clustering effects. Therefore, optimizing the shared infrastructure of multiple CO2 sources can lead to significant reductions in infrastructure costs. This paper presents a novel formulation of the clustered CO2 transport network. The Markov Decision Process formulation defined here allows for more detailed modeling of non-linear, discrete transport costs and increased geographical resolution. The clustering effects are modeled through cooperative multi-agent interactions. A multi-agent, reinforcement learning-based algorithm is proposed to optimize the shared transportation network, with examples illustrating the results of the method.</description>
      <author>Kang Qiu, Sigmund Eggen Holm, Julian Straus, Simon Roussanaly</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.150076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combustion Mode Evaluation of a Methanol&#8211;Diesel Dual Direct Injection Engine with a Control of Injection Timing and Energy Substitution Ratio</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4271/03-18-01-0002</link>
      <description>Yifan Zhao, Xinyu Liu, Sanghoon Kook, SAE International Journal of Engines. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401486134

                &lt;div&gt;Methanol, as a renewable fuel, is an attractive option for internal combustion engines. The dual direct injection method is one of the most promising strategies for applying methanol fuel in diesel engines as the flexible injection control enables combustion mode switching. In this study, a 1-L single-cylinder common-rail diesel engine with a compression ratio of 17.4 is retrofitted by installing an additional methanol direct injector with 35 MPa injection pressure. The engine is operated at 1400 rpm, intermediate load, and fixed midpoint combustion phasing of 10 &#176;CA aTDC with a fixed total amount of energy while applying an energy substitution principle with up to 70% energy supplied by methanol. From the experiments, three distinct combustion modes were identified. When early methanol injection timings were selected in the range of 180&#8211;60 &#176;CA bTDC, the primary combustion mode was premixed burn. Late injection timings of 10 &#176;CA bTDC to TDC led to heat release rate shapes of the diffusion flame mode. In between these injection timings, partially premixed combustion was achieved where the higher methanol substitution ratio achieved carbon dioxide (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) emissions reduction by up to 11% and nitrogen oxides (NO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;) emission suppression by up to 12%. It was also found that with increasing methanol energy substitution ratio, a significant reduction in smoke emissions was achieved. However, the decreased power output and increased emissions of unburnt hydrocarbon (uHC) and carbon monoxide (CO) were measured due to incomplete combustion caused by lower flame temperature of methanol.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <author>Yifan Zhao, Xinyu Liu, Sanghoon Kook</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4271/03-18-01-0002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning&#8208;Driven Selection of Two&#8208;Dimensional Carbon&#8208;Based Supports for Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts in CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400470</link>
      <description>Zhen Tan, Xinyu Li, Yanzhang Zhao, Zhen Zhang, Qinfeng Shi, Haobo Li, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401498041

                The electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide by metal catalysts featuring dual&#8208;atomic active sites, supported on two&#8208;dimensional carbon&#8208;nitrogen materials, holds promise for enhanced efficiency. The potential synergy between various support materials and transition metal compositions in influencing reaction performance has been recognized. However, systematic studies on the selection of optimal support materials remain limited, primarily due to the intricate structure of dual&#8208;atom catalysts generating a variety of potential adsorption sites. Incorporating the influence of support materials further amplifies computational challenges, doubling the already substantial calculation requirements. This study addresses this challenge by introducing a machine learning approach to expedite the identification of the most stable intermediate adsorption sites and simultaneous prediction of adsorption energy. This innovative method significantly reduces computational costs, enabling the simultaneous consideration of active sites and support materials. We explore the use of both graphene&#8208;like (g&#8208;)C2N and g&#8208;C9N4 materials, revealing their main distinction in the adsorption capacity for the intermediate *CHO. This variation is attributed to the different C:N ratios influencing support for the active site through distinct charge transfer conditions. Our findings offer valuable insights for the design and optimization of dual&#8208;atom catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhen Tan, Xinyu Li, Yanzhang Zhao, Zhen Zhang, Qinfeng Shi, Haobo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of photoelectrochemical conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.03</link>
      <description>Xia Jiang, Rui Chen, Yanxin Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu, Chemical Synthesis. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401375495

                The reduction of CO2 to C2+ products using photoelectrochemistry (PEC) is significant and highly challenging. However, systematic summaries on PEC CO2 conversion into C2+ products are lacking. Therefore, this paper systematically reviews the current research status of the PEC CO2 conversion for the preparation of C2+ products, including the pathways of C2+ products, the usage of catalysts and reactors, and methods for improving C2+ product selectivity. Besides, the deficiencies in current research are analyzed, and future developments are discussed.</description>
      <author>Xia Jiang, Rui Chen, Yanxin Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.03</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering the Site Distance of Atomic Cu&#8208;Cu Pairs by First&#8208;Shell Halogen Coordination Boosts CO2&#8208;to&#8208;C2 Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412785</link>
      <description>Fengya Ma, Pengfang Zhang, Xiaoyan Zheng, Liang Chen, Yunrui Li, Zechao Zhuang, Yameng Fan, Peng Jiang, Hui Zhao, Jiawei Zhang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaojing Yao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401368251

                Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 into C2 products of high economic value provides a promising strategy to realize resourceful CO2 utilization. Rational design and construct dual sites to realize the CO protonation and C&#8208;C coupling to unravel their structure&#8208;performance correlation is of great significance in catalysing electrochemical CO2 reduction reactions. Herein, Cu&#8208;Cu dual sites with different site distance coordinated by halogen at the first&#8208;shell are constructed and shows a higher intramolecular electron redispersion and coordination symmetry configurations. The long&#8208;range Cu&#8208;Cu (Cu&#8208;I&#8208;Cu) dual sites show an enhanced Faraday efficiency of C2 products, up to 74.1%, and excellent stability. In addition, the linear relationships that the long&#8208;range Cu&#8208;Cu dual site is accelerated to C2H4 generation and short&#8208;range Cu&#8208;Cu (Cu&#8208;Cl&#8208;Cu) dual site is beneficial for C2H5OH formation are disclosed. In situ electrochemical attenuated total reflection surface enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy, in situ Raman and theoretical calculations manifest that long&#8208;range Cu&#8208;Cu dual sites can weaken reaction energy barriers of CO hydrogenation and C&#8208;C coupling, as well as accelerating deoxygenation of *CH2CHO. This study uncovers the exploitation of site&#8208;distance&#8208;dependent electrochemical property to steer the CO2 reduction pathway, as well as a potential generic tactic to target C2 synthesis by constructing the desired Cu&#8208;Cu dual sites.</description>
      <author>Fengya Ma, Pengfang Zhang, Xiaoyan Zheng, Liang Chen, Yunrui Li, Zechao Zhuang, Yameng Fan, Peng Jiang, Hui Zhao, Jiawei Zhang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaojing Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering the Site Distance of Atomic Cu&#8208;Cu Pairs by First&#8208;Shell Halogen Coordination Boosts CO2&#8208;to&#8208;C2 Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412785</link>
      <description>Fengya Ma, Pengfang Zhang, Xiaoyan Zheng, Liang Chen, Yunrui Li, Zechao Zhuang, Yameng Fan, Peng Jiang, Hui Zhao, Jiawei Zhang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaojing Yao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401368113

                Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 into C2 products of high economic value provides a promising strategy to realize resourceful CO2 utilization. Rational design and construct dual sites to realize the CO protonation and C-C coupling to unravel their structure-performance correlation is of great significance in catalysing electrochemical CO2 reduction reactions. Herein, Cu-Cu dual sites with different site distance coordinated by halogen at the first-shell are constructed and shows a higher intramolecular electron redispersion and coordination symmetry configurations. The long-range Cu-Cu (Cu-I-Cu) dual sites show an enhanced Faraday efficiency of C2 products, up to 74.1%, and excellent stability. In addition, the linear relationships that the long-range Cu-Cu dual site is accelerated to C2H4 generation and short-range Cu-Cu (Cu-Cl-Cu) dual site is beneficial for C2H5OH formation are disclosed. In situ electrochemical attenuated total reflection surface enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy, in situ Raman and theoretical calculations manifest that long-range Cu-Cu dual sites can weaken reaction energy barriers of CO hydrogenation and C-C coupling, as well as accelerating deoxygenation of *CH2CHO. This study uncovers the exploitation of site-distance-dependent electrochemical property to steer the CO2 reduction pathway, as well as a potential generic tactic to target C2 synthesis by constructing the desired Cu-Cu dual sites.</description>
      <author>Fengya Ma, Pengfang Zhang, Xiaoyan Zheng, Liang Chen, Yunrui Li, Zechao Zhuang, Yameng Fan, Peng Jiang, Hui Zhao, Jiawei Zhang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaojing Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Air Quality Indeks Using Long Short Term Memory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30871/jaic.v8i1.7402</link>
      <description>Irfan Wahyu Ramadhani, Filmada Ocky Saputra, Ricardus Anggi Pramunendar, Galuh Wilujeng Saraswati, Nurul Anisa Sri Winarsih, Muhammad Syaifur Rohman, Danny Oka Ratmana, Guruh Fajar Shidik, Journal of Applied Informatics and Computing. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401432188

                Exercise offers significant physical and mental health benefits. However, undetected air pollution can have a negative impact on individual health, especially lung health when doing physical activity in crowded sports venues. This study addresses the need for accurate air quality predictions in such environments. Using the Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) method or what is known as high performance time series prediction, this research focuses on forecasting the Air Quality Index (AQI) around crowded sports venues and its supporting parameters such as ozone gas, carbon dioxide, etc. -others as internal factors, without involving external factors causing the increase in AQI. Preprocessing of the data involves removing zero values &#8203;&#8203;and calculating correlations with AQI and the final step performs calculations with the LSTM model. The LSTM model which adds tuning parameters, namely with epoch 100, learning rate with a value of 0.001, and batch size with a value of 64, consistently shows a reduction in losses. The best results from the AQI, PM2.5, and PM10 features based on performance are MSE with the smallest value of 6.045, RMSE with the smallest value of 4.283, and MAE with a value of 2.757.</description>
      <author>Irfan Wahyu Ramadhani, Filmada Ocky Saputra, Ricardus Anggi Pramunendar, Galuh Wilujeng Saraswati, Nurul Anisa Sri Winarsih, Muhammad Syaifur Rohman, Danny Oka Ratmana, Guruh Fajar Shidik</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30871/jaic.v8i1.7402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Ionic Polymer Membrane Based on PVDF for Capacitor Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/0118722121313373240730072512</link>
      <description>Kamlesh Kukreti, Varij Panwar, Recent Patents on Engineering. 19(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401401742

                Objective: To address these issues, we propose the use of ionic polymer membranes. By reducing the demand for synthetic plastics, these membranes contribute to pollution reduction. Moreover, they offer economic and environmental benefits. Ionic polymers can also help limit carbon dioxide emissions. Method: In our study, we created a blend of polyvinylidene fluoride (PVDF), polyvinylpyrrolidone (PVP), and polyvinyl sulfonic acid (PVSA). This blend was used to fabricate an ionic membrane through the solvent casting method. The resulting membrane acts as a successful dielectric material, sandwiched between copper electrodes. We conducted extensive characterization, including microstructure analysis, crystal structure examination, identification of functional groups, and thermal behavior assessment. Results: Our findings demonstrate the potential of ionic polymer membranes for capacitor applications. By varying the composition of PVDF/PVP/PVSA, we explored different dielectric properties. Notably, the ionic polymer electrolyte can serve as an effective dielectric material, with copper electrodes providing a practical application. Conclusion: Our investigation included electrical current density measurements using cyclic voltammetry, elemental composition analysis, morphological studies, and material composition assessments.</description>
      <author>Kamlesh Kukreti, Varij Panwar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/0118722121313373240730072512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Hanwha Ocean Liquefied CO2 Carrier</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-126076</link>
      <description>Insoo Jun, Teuk-Jin Koh, Bruce S. Kang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456673

                Abstract The interest in carbon neutrality is growing around the world as human faces the climate crisis caused mainly by greenhouse gas emission. The methodologies for carbon reduction are being introduced in every industry and carbon reduction through Carbon Capture Utilization &amp; Storage (hereafter &#8220;CCUS&#8221;) is being recognized as one of the most feasible carbon reduction plan at the moment. CCUS is defined as a system of technologies that intergrates three stages: CO2 capture, transportation and utilization &amp; geological storage. The transportation sector is a major part in CCUS value chain to link the capture sector and utilization &amp; storage sector. Transportation methods of trucks, trains, pipelines, ships, etc. are being considered in the CCUS value chain and pipelines and ships are applicable in ocean transportation field. As the transportation distance of CCUS projects under development becomes longer and the total transportation volume is increased, ocean transportation using a dedicated liquefied CO2 (LCO2) carrier is expected to play a key role in carbon transportation of CCUS chain. In these market trends, Hanwha Ocean began developing a new vessel that can transfer liquid CO2 safely. This paper is to introduce the design development of Hanwha Ocean LCO2 carrier such as ship &amp; cargo tank design, tank material, CHS (Cargo Handling System) test facility, etc.</description>
      <author>Insoo Jun, Teuk-Jin Koh, Bruce S. Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-126076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Development for Hydrogen-Conversion Businesses in C&#244;te d&#8217;Ivoire</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/biomass4030050</link>
      <description>Kass&#233; Jean Hugues Angb&#233;, Yawovi Nougbl&#233;ga, Satyanarayana Narra, Vidhi Singh, Biomass. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401482426

                C&#244;te d&#8217;Ivoire has substantially neglected crop residues from farms in rural areas, so this study aimed to provide strategies for the sustainable conversion of these products to hydrogen. The use of existing data showed that, in the C&#244;te d&#8217;Ivoire, there were up to 16,801,306 tons of crop residues from 11 crop types in 2019, from which 1,296,424.84 tons of hydrogen could potentially be derived via theoretical gasification and dark fermentation approaches. As 907,497.39 tons of hydrogen is expected annually, the following estimations were derived. The three hydrogen-project implementation scenarios developed indicate that Ivorian industries could be supplied with 9,026,635 gigajoules of heat, alongside 17,910 cars and 4732 buses in the transport sector. It was estimated that 817,293.95 tons of green ammonia could be supplied to farmers. According to the study, 5,727,992 households could be expected to have access to 1718.40 gigawatts of electricity. Due to these changes in the transport, energy, industry, and agricultural sectors, a reduction of 1,644,722.08 tons of carbon dioxide per year could theoretically be achieved. With these scenarios, around 263,276.87 tons of hydrogen could be exported to other countries. The conversion of crop residues to hydrogen is a promising opportunity with environmental and socio-economic impacts. Therefore, this study requires further extensive research.</description>
      <author>Kass&#233; Jean Hugues Angb&#233;, Yawovi Nougbl&#233;ga, Satyanarayana Narra, Vidhi Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/biomass4030050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking CO2 emissions in East Asia Pacific-5 countries: Exploring the dynamics relationships among economic growth, foreign direct investment, trade openness, financial development and energy consumption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i8.5639</link>
      <description>Happy Febrina Hariyani, Dani Galih Prasetyo, Taemin Ha, Bich Ha Dam, Tran Thai Ha Nguyen, Journal of Infrastructure Policy and Development. 8(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401432095

                The increase in world carbon emissions is always in line with national economic growth programs, which create negative environmental externalities. To understand the effectiveness of related factors in mitigating CO2 emissions, this study investigates the intricate relationship among macro-pillars such as economic growth, foreign investment, trade and finance, energy, and renewable energy with CO2 emissions of the high gross domestic product economies in East Asia Pacific, such as China, Japan, Korea, Australia and Indonesia (EAP-5). Through the application of the Vector Error Correction Model (VECM), this research reveals the long-term equilibrium and short-term dynamics between CO2 emissions and selected factors from 1991 to 2020. The long-term cointegration vector test results show that economic growth and foreign investment contribute to carbon reduction. Meanwhile, the short-term Granger causality test shows that economic growth has a two-way causality towards carbon emissions, while energy consumption and renewable energy consumption have a one-way causality towards carbon emissions. In contrast, the variables trade, foreign direct investment, and domestic credit to the private sector do not have two-way causality towards CO2 emissions. The findings reveal that economic growth and foreign investment play significant roles in carbon reduction, which are observed in long-term causality relationships, while energy consumption and renewable energy are notable factors. Thus, the study offers implications for mitigating environmental concerns on national economic growth agendas by scrutinizing and examining the efficacy of related factors.</description>
      <author>Happy Febrina Hariyani, Dani Galih Prasetyo, Taemin Ha, Bich Ha Dam, Tran Thai Ha Nguyen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24294/jipd.v8i8.5639</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Product Selectivity of Single-Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Beyond CO Formation by Orbital Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02650k</link>
      <description>Vasanthapandiyan Mari, Naiwrit Karmodak, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401461304

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction (CO2R) is one of the promising strategies for developing sustainable energy resources. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have emerged as efficient catalysts for CO2R. However, the efficiency of SACs...</description>
      <author>Vasanthapandiyan Mari, Naiwrit Karmodak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02650k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Inter&#8208;Metal Interaction between Ni and Fe Atoms in Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts to Boost CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411543</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Jia Li, Xiaoli Pan, Ning Li, Zhounan Yu, Li Wang, Tianyi Ma, Sen Lin, Jian Lin, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401420908

                Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) are promising for applications in electrochemical CO2 reduction due to the enhanced flexibility of the catalytic sites and the synergistic effect between dual atoms. However, precisely controlling the atomic distance and identifying the dual&#8208;atom configuration of DACs to optimize the catalytic performance remains a challenge. Here, the Ni and Fe atomic pairs were constructed on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon support in three different configurations: NiFe&#8208;isolate, NiFe&#8208;N bridge, and NiFe bonding. It was found that the NiFe&#8208;N bridge catalyst with NiN4 and FeN4 sharing two N atoms exhibited superior CO2 reduction activity and promising stability when compared to the NiFe&#8208;isolate and NiFe&#8208;bonding catalysts. A series of characterizations and density functional theory calculations suggested that the N&#8208;bridged NiFe sites with an appropriate distance between Ni and Fe atoms can exert a more pronounced synergy. It not only regulated the suitable adsorption strength for the *COOH intermediate but also promoted the desorption of *CO, thus accelerating the CO2 electroreduction to CO. This work provides an important implication for the enhancement of catalysis by the tailoring of the coordination structure of DACs, with the identification of distance effect between neighboring dual atoms.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Jia Li, Xiaoli Pan, Ning Li, Zhounan Yu, Li Wang, Tianyi Ma, Sen Lin, Jian Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Inter&#8208;Metal Interaction between Ni and Fe Atoms in Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts to Boost CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411543</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Jia Li, Xiaoli Pan, Ning Li, Zhounan Yu, Li Wang, Tianyi Ma, Sen Lin, Jian Lin, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401421250

                Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) are promising for applications in electrochemical CO2 reduction due to the enhanced flexibility of the catalytic sites and the synergistic effect between dual atoms. However, precisely controlling the atomic distance and identifying the dual&#8208;atom configuration of DACs to optimize the catalytic performance remains a challenge. Here, the Ni and Fe atomic pairs were constructed on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon support in three different configurations: NiFe&#8208;isolate, NiFe&#8208;N bridge, and NiFe bonding. It was found that the NiFe&#8208;N bridge catalyst with NiN4 and FeN4 sharing two N atoms exhibited superior CO2 reduction activity and promising stability when compared to the NiFe&#8208;isolate and NiFe&#8208;bonding catalysts. A series of characterizations and density functional theory calculations suggested that the N&#8208;bridged NiFe sites with an appropriate distance between Ni and Fe atoms can exert a more pronounced synergy. It not only regulated the suitable adsorption strength for the *COOH intermediate but also promoted the desorption of *CO, thus accelerating the CO2 electroreduction to CO. This work provides an important implication for the enhancement of catalysis by the tailoring of the coordination structure of DACs, with the identification of distance effect between neighboring dual atoms.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Jia Li, Xiaoli Pan, Ning Li, Zhounan Yu, Li Wang, Tianyi Ma, Sen Lin, Jian Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determination of Thermo-Mechanical Coal Deformations and Implication for CO2 Storage in Deep Coal Formations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0409</link>
      <description>Zhang Kunming, Shimin Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480269

                ABSTRACT: CO2 sequestration along with enhanced coalbed methane (ECBM) has received considerable attention for energy recovery and CO2 storage. CO2 injection not only reduces permeability due to the swelling effect but modifies the temperature field, resulting in coupled thermo-mechanical coal deformations. Limited efforts have been devoted towards the understanding of thermo-mechanical deformations in the coalbed methane (CBM) industry. This study proposed a theoretical model of thermal expansion coefficients through energy principle. Direct measurements of coal deformations with variations in temperature and pressure were carried out. The results indicate that thermo-induced deformation linearly correlates with temperature variations with estimated thermo-deformative coefficients between 8&#215;10-5/K to 10&#215;10-5/K, falling within the theoretical bounds. Additionally, the coal matrix retains its elastic properties after thermal cycling. The mechanical compression at different temperatures exhibits similar trends, increasing linearly with pressure. The matrix bulk modulus increases with pressure cycles at elevated temperatures, indicating that the coal becomes stiffer due to residual strain and gradually increases with pressure depletion. Anisotropic matrix deformation was observed when the temperature was above 273.15 K. The deformation of the coal can have significant implications on the evolution of effective stress, permeability, and localized failure, ultimately controlling CO2 sequestration and long-term CBM production. 1. INTRODUCTION CBM is an unconventional natural gas resource stored within coal seams. Over the past four decades, CBM has developed rapidly and become an important energy source in the United States, Canada, Australia, China, et al. (Yang &amp; Liu, 2021). CBM is known for its relatively low risk associated with low costs due to the maturity of CBM exploration, drilling, completion, and stimulation processes (Flores, 2013). In the United States, CBM production peaked at 1.97 trillion cubic feet (TCF) in 2008, and as of 2022, it still contributes 0.72 TCF, accounting for 2% of the overall U.S. natural gas production (U.S. Department of Energy, 2022, 2023). ECBM was first proposed by Puri (Puri &amp; Yee, 1990) to address the inefficiencies resulting from the reservoir pressure reduction during the late time reservoir depletion. More recent attention has focused on the CO2-ECBM technology and CO2 storage, as depicted in Figure 1 (a) (Jessen, Tang, &amp; Kovscek, 2008; Lin, Ren, Cheng, &amp; Nemcik, 2021; Mazzotti, Pini, &amp; Storti, 2009). CO2 can displace methane attributed to its higher affinity for coal, effectively enhancing methane recovery, particularly in low-permeability CBM reservoirs (White, Strazisar, Granite, Hoffman, &amp; Pennline, 2003). Furthermore, this innovative process has a long-term environmental benefit of sequestering and storing CO2 within underground coal seams. The storage potential of CO2 in unminable coal seams is considerable, with estimated capacities ranging from 3 to 200 GtCO2, making it a relevant option for mitigating anthropogenic CO2 emissions (Mazzotti et al., 2009; Metz, Davidson, De Coninck, Loos, &amp; Meyer, 2005). Many researchers have considered that during the CO2 injection process, CO2 adsorption can induce a significant matrix swelling (Figure 1 (b)), resulting in cleat closure and reduction in permeability (Pekot &amp; Reeves, 2002; J.-Q. Shi &amp; Durucan, 2005; Siriwardane, Gondle, &amp; Smith, 2009; G. X. Wang, Wei, Wang, Massarotto, &amp; Rudolph, 2010; White et al., 2005). This reduction in permeability limits the CO2 injection rate, which is critical for the success of CO2-ECBM (Bai et al., 2022; Lu &amp; Connell, 2008; Zhang &amp; Ranjith, 2019). Indeed, in addition to sorption-induced strain, the coal deformation can also be influenced by fluid composition, temperature, and water saturation, as demonstrated in Figure 1 (c), (d), and (e).</description>
      <author>Zhang Kunming, Shimin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Geochemical Monitoring Technologies for CO2 Geological Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166784</link>
      <description>Jianhua Ma, Yongzhang Zhou, Yijun Zheng, Lixiang He, Hanyu Wang, L. L. Niu, Xinhui Yu, Wei Cao, Sustainability. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401418288

                CO2 geological storage, as a large-scale, low-cost, carbon reduction technology, has garnered widespread attention due to its safety. Monitoring potential leaks is critical to ensuring the safety of the carbon storage system. Geochemical monitoring employs methods such as gas monitoring, groundwater monitoring, tracer monitoring, and isotope monitoring to analyze the reservoir&#8217;s storage state and secondary changes after a CO2 injection. This paper summarizes the recent applications and limitations of geochemical monitoring technologies in CO2 geological storage. In gas monitoring, the combined monitoring of multiple surface gasses can analyze potential gas sources in the storage area. In water monitoring, pH and conductivity measurements are the most direct, while ion composition monitoring methods are emerging. In tracer monitoring, although artificial tracers are effective, the environmental compatibility of natural tracers provides them with greater development potential. In isotope monitoring, C and O isotopes can effectively reveal gas sources. Future CO2 geological storage project monitoring should integrate various monitoring methods to comprehensively assess the risk and sources of CO2 leakage. The incorporation of artificial intelligence, machine learning technologies, and IoT monitoring will significantly enhance the accuracy and intelligence of numerical simulations and baseline monitoring, ensuring the long-term safety and sustainability of CO2 geological storage projects.</description>
      <author>Jianhua Ma, Yongzhang Zhou, Yijun Zheng, Lixiang He, Hanyu Wang, L. L. Niu, Xinhui Yu, Wei Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antimicrobial activity of laser assisted endodontic therapy in disinfecting root canals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6026/973206300200610</link>
      <description>Shivam Patel, Harpreet Hundal, Geeta Nishad, Nityanand Shetty, Vinita Banjare, Jyotsna Sethumadhavan, Ramanpal Singh Makkad, Anushree Tiwari, Bioinformation. 20(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401366283

                Light Amplified Stimulated Emission of Radiation (LASER) is nowadays widely studied regarding their use in endodontics and restorative dentistry. Therefore, it is of interest to evaluate the antibacterial activity of three types of LASERs namely CO2 LASER.Er, Cr:YSGG LASER and Diode LASER in disinfection of root canals. 70 patients (105 single rooted teeth) were included in the study. There was application of 2% Sodium Hypochlorite (NaOCl), 2780 nm Er,Cr:YSGG LASER, 900 nm Diode LASER and CO2 LASER. Microbial samples were collected from root canals both before and after the interventions through paper points. These parameters were evaluated in microbiology laboratory to obtain Log10 Colony Forming Units (CFUs). There was significant reduction in CFUs of microorganisms inside root canal in all three LASERs evaluated and NaOCl. The reduction in CFUs in LASERs was comparable to NaOCl. Then secondly we applied each LASER in combination with NaOCl. It was observed that reduction in CFU was greater when combination of LASER with NaOCl was applied as compared when applied alone. It can be inferred that LASER when applied with NaOCl can have significant role in disinfection of root canals.</description>
      <author>Shivam Patel, Harpreet Hundal, Geeta Nishad, Nityanand Shetty, Vinita Banjare, Jyotsna Sethumadhavan, Ramanpal Singh Makkad, Anushree Tiwari</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6026/973206300200610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physiological and Biochemical Responses of Maize to Elevated CO2 Concentrations: Implications for Growth and Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14081751</link>
      <description>Pirzada Khan, Fardous Mohammad Safiul Azam, Tong Lian, Ashraf M. M. Abdelbacki, Mohammed Albaqami, Rahmatullah Jan, Kyung&#8208;Min Kim, Wei Wang, Agronomy. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401500504

                Rising atmospheric CO2 levels, a significant consequence of anthropogenic activities, profoundly impact global agriculture and food security by altering plant physiological processes. Despite extensive research, a comprehensive understanding of the specific effects of elevated CO2 on maize (Zea mays L.)&#8217;s primary and secondary metabolism remains elusive. This study investigated the responses of maize seedlings cultivated in open-top chambers (OTCs) under three CO2 concentrations: ambient (380 ppm), elevated (600 ppm), and high (1800 ppm). Key growth parameters, including plant height, leaf area, and aboveground biomass (leaf and stem), were assessed alongside metabolic profiles encompassing nonstructural and structural carbohydrates, syringyl (S) and guaiacyl lignin, the syringyl-to-guaiacyl (S/G)-lignin ratio, photosynthetic pigments, total soluble protein, and malondialdehyde (MDA) levels. The results demonstrated that exposure to 600 ppm CO2 significantly enhanced plant height, leaf area, and aboveground biomass compared to ambient conditions. Concurrently, there were notable increases in the concentrations of primary metabolites. In contrast, exposure to 1800 ppm CO2 severely inhibited these growth parameters and induced reductions in secondary metabolites, such as chlorophyll and soluble proteins, throughout the growth stages. The findings underscore the intricate responses of maize metabolism to varying CO2 levels, highlighting adaptive strategies in primary and secondary metabolism under changing atmospheric conditions. This research contributes to a nuanced understanding of maize&#8217;s physiological adaptations to future climate scenarios characterized by elevated CO2, with implications for sustainable agriculture and food security.</description>
      <author>Pirzada Khan, Fardous Mohammad Safiul Azam, Tong Lian, Ashraf M. M. Abdelbacki, Mohammed Albaqami, Rahmatullah Jan, Kyung&#8208;Min Kim, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy14081751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Study on CO2 Flooding Characteristic in Low-Permeability Sandstone Considering the Influence of In-Situ Stress</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/223076-pa</link>
      <description>Tong Zhang, Mingcheng Zhu, Guoliang Zhou, Jun Wu, Xin Yang, Ruilong Li, SPE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401411447

                Summary The pore network controlled by in-situ stress significantly influences the CO2 flooding in low-permeability reservoirs. In this study, the CO2/oil distribution and response of pore structure were monitored online using low-field nuclear magnetic resonance (LF-NMR), and the in-situ stress dependence of oil recovery was analyzed. The results show that the pore structure consists of adsorption pore (AP &amp;lt; 1 millisecond), percolation pore (1 millisecond &amp;lt; PP &amp;lt; 10 milliseconds), and migration pore (10 milliseconds &amp;lt; MP). Oil recovery was primarily influenced by AP and MP at lower in-situ stress, while PP and MP are the main contributors at higher in-situ stress. The matrix experienced compression deformation, microfracture generation, and shrinkage of pore, combined with an increase and followed by a decrease in oil recovery, responding to the increase of in-situ stress from 5 MPa to 15 MPa and from 15 MPa to 20 MPa. The reduction in gas channels promotes a piston-like advancement of oil displacement, resulting in an initial increase in oil recovery, while subsequent decline is linked to heightened pore heterogeneity caused by high in-situ stress. Increased heterogeneity reduces gas displacement stability, hampers CO2 sweep efficiency, and results in a granular distribution of residual oil. The findings provide insight on CO2-enhanced oil recovery (EOR) in low-permeability reservoirs.</description>
      <author>Tong Zhang, Mingcheng Zhu, Guoliang Zhou, Jun Wu, Xin Yang, Ruilong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/223076-pa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Study on Optimization of Combustion Cycle Parameters and Exhaust Gas Emissions in Marine Dual-Fuel Engines by Adjusting Ammonia Injection Phases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12081340</link>
      <description>Martynas Drazdauskas, Serg&#279;jus Lebedevas, Journal of Marine Science and Engineering. 12(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401391371

                Decarbonizing maritime transport hinges on transitioning oil-fueled ships (98.4% of the fleet) to renewable and low-carbon fuel types. This shift is crucial for meeting the greenhouse gas (GHG) reduction targets set by the IMO and the EU, with the aim of achieving climate neutrality by 2050. Ammonia, which does not contain carbon atoms that generate CO2, is considered one of the effective solutions for decarbonization in the medium and long term. However, the concurrent increase in nitrogen oxide (NOx) emissions during the ammonia combustion cycle, subject to strict regulation by the MARPOL 73/78 convention, necessitates implementing solutions to reduce them through optimizing the combustion cycle. This publication presents a numerical study on the optimization of diesel and ammonia injection phases in a ship&#8217;s medium-speed engine, Wartsila 6L46. The study investigates the exhaust gas emissions and combustion cycle parameters through a high-pressure injection strategy. At an identified 7&#176; CAD injection phase distance between diesel and ammonia, along with an optimal dual-fuel start of injection 10&#176; CAD before TDC, a reduction of 47% in greenhouse gas emissions (GHG = CO2 + CH4 + N2O) was achieved compared to the diesel combustion cycle. This result aligns with the GHG reduction target set by both the IMO and the EU for 2030. Additionally, during the investigation of the thermodynamic combustion characteristics of the cycle, a comparative reduction in NOx of 4.6% was realized. This reduction is linked to the DeNOx process, where the decrease in NOx is offset by an increase in N2O. However, the optimized ammonia combustion cycle results in significant emissions of unburnt NH3, reaching 1.5 g/kWh. In summary, optimizing the combustion cycle of dual ammonia and diesel fuel is essential for achieving efficient and reliable engine performance. Balancing combustion efficiency with emission levels of greenhouse gases, unburned NH3, and NOx is crucial. For the Wartsila 6L46 marine diesel engine, the recommended injection phasing is A710/D717, with a 7&#176; CAD between injection phases.</description>
      <author>Martynas Drazdauskas, Serg&#279;jus Lebedevas</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12081340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Influence of Defective Cement Ring on Casing Stress During CO2 Geological Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0224</link>
      <description>Hui Li, Jun Li, Shan Lu, Wei Lian, Jinlu Liu, Xing Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401479379

                ABSTRACT: In the CCUS operation site, CO2 geological buried Wells are mostly worn out or abandoned old oil and gas reservoir Wells, which have undergone well testing, production, stimulation (fracturing, acidification) and other operations. The temperature and pressure in the wellbore have undergone great changes, and the wellbore cement ring has defects due to elastic mismatch. In this paper, from the perspective of missing ring opening, missing thickness, missing location, casing eccentricity, etc., the finite element numerical simulation method is used to establish a casing - cement ring with defects - formation model, and analyze the stress change rule of casing at the missing part of cement ring under the influence of temperature and non-uniform ground stress during CO2 injection. The research shows that the higher the ratio of cement ring diameter to thickness, the greater the casing stress, the casing is still in a safe state; The circumferential missing Angle of cement ring has great influence on the casing stress. When the missing Angle is 60&#176;, the casing has reached the maximum stress state and has been damaged. The azimuth Angle of cement ring is closely related to the ground stress, and the casing has been damaged at 0-60&#176;. The eccentricity of cement ring has no obvious effect on the stress rush of casing. Therefore, it is necessary to control reasonable CO2 injection parameters for the wellbore with cement ring defects, so as to improve the safety of the casing during CO2 storage and ensure the integrity of the wellbore. 1. INTRODUCTION With the rapid development of social economy, greenhouse gases generated by human activities have been discharged into the atmosphere beyond the standard, resulting in an increase in global temperature year by year (H&#246;&#246;K, et al., 2023; Qureshi, et al., 2016; Peter, et al., 2018). According to the International Energy Agency's 2021 report, global carbon emissions will continue to grow in the future, predicting that global CO2 emissions will increase by 500 million tons by 2030, 600 million tons by 2040, and 700 million tons by 2050. The problem of climate change and environmental pollution caused by excessive CO2 emissions has attracted great attention from the international community. In order to cope with this problem, countries have actively explored CO2 emission reduction technologies, among which CCUS technology is one of the effective ways. CO2 storage technology is the core component of CCUS technology, aiming to store CO2 captured from industry or other emission sources in geological environment. Achieve long-term isolation of CO2 and atmospheric environment. The target reservoirs for CO2 geological storage mainly include deep salt water, depleted oil and gas reservoirs, unconventional oil and gas Wells and CO2 geothermal enhanced reservoirs, etc. The depleted oil and gas reservoirs are widely distributed and have good closed circles, which can not only efficiently bury CO2 to reduce its leakage risk, but also have good economic and social benefits. Therefore, CO2 injection into abandoned reservoirs is one of the important ways to achieve efficient CO2 storage.</description>
      <author>Hui Li, Jun Li, Shan Lu, Wei Lian, Jinlu Liu, Xing Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Design of Intensified Towers for CO2 Capture with Internal, Printed Heat Exchangers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.123118</link>
      <description>Stephen Summits, Paul Akula, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456246

                Solvent-based carbon capture processes typically suffer from the temperature rise of the solvent due to the heat of absorption of CO2. This increased temperature is not thermodynamically favorable and results in a significant reduction in performance in the absorber column. As opposed to interstage coolers, which only remove, cool, and return the solvent at discrete locations in the column, internal coolers that are integrated with the packing can cool the process inline, which can result in improved efficiency. This work presents the modeling of these internal coolers within an existing generic, equation-oriented absorber column model that can cool the process while allowing for simultaneous mass transfer. Optimization of this model is also performed, which is capable of optimally choosing the best locations to place these devices, such that heat removal and mass transfer area are balanced. Results of the optimization have shown that optimally placed cooling elements result in a significant increase in the capture efficiency of the process, compared to a similar column with no internal cooling, with a common trend being the cooling of the column in the temperature bulge region. It is observed that by optimally placing an internal cooler, the solvent flow rate can be decreased, and the CO2 lean loading can be increased while still maintaining the same efficiency. These process changes can lead to a substantial reduction in costs due to lower reboiler duty.</description>
      <author>Stephen Summits, Paul Akula, Debangsu Bhattacharyya, Grigorios Panagakos, Benjamin Omell, Michael Matuszewski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.123118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Well Integrity Analysis During CO2 Injection in a Depleted Chalk Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0944</link>
      <description>F. Amour, Mohammad Reza Hajiabadi, Seyedbehzad Hosseinzadehsadati, Hamidreza M. Nick, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481624

                ABSTRACT: The present study is part of the Bifrost project and aims at assessing the feasibility of storing CO2 in chalk reservoirs by using the depleted Harald East gas field located in the northern part of the Danish North Sea as a showcase. Chalk is a singular rock with a high compressibility and the resulting pronounced compaction during hydrocarbon exploitation and possibly during CO2 storage raises questions on the integrity of cement surrounding the legacy, monitoring, and injector wells. In this context, the study carries out a well stability analysis of a well present in the field. The strain and stress distribution computed by a full-field coupled thermo-hydro-mechanical model is used as input data in a finite element model, which captures the properties and mechanical behavior of a near wellbore area (formation, cement, and casing) located in the seal interval of the field. The results show negligible deformation in the cement during hydrocarbon production and CO2 storage, thereby suggesting low risk of leakage along the studied well. 1. INTRODUCTION Complying with the ambitious objectives of the intergovernmental panel on climate change in terms of amount of greenhouse gas emission reduction requires the quick implementation of multiple carbon capture storage (CCS) projects worldwide (IPCC, 2005). In this context, the re-use of pre-existing oil and gas infrastructures and fields that were thoroughly studied for decades represents a time- and cost-efficient opportunity associated with a relatively low risk of leakage due to a proof of containment at least at pre-production time (Schmelz et al., 2020). In the Danish North Sea, over 800 Mt of CO2 storage capacity was estimated within mature chalk fields (Bonto et al., 2021). Assessing the possibility of storing CO2 in chalk deposits is currently based on laboratory studies such as batch-reactor and flow-through experiments combined with triaxial tests. Exposures of the rock to CO2 in supercritical and gas phase under temperature and pressure conditions relevant for the subsurface of the North Sea indicate no to minor mechanical alteration of the elastic, shear, plastic, and time-dependent properties (Alam et al., 2014; Ditlevsen &amp; Christensen, 2010; Liteanu et al., 2013; Schroeder et al., 2001).</description>
      <author>F. Amour, Mohammad Reza Hajiabadi, Seyedbehzad Hosseinzadehsadati, Hamidreza M. Nick</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0944</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Caprock Integrity Through Thermo-Hydro-Mechanical Modeling of CO2 in a Deformable Chalk Depleted Gas Reservoir</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0507</link>
      <description>Bahram Hosseinzadeh Samani, F. Amour, Alejandro Barrera C., Mohammad Reza Hajiabadi, Carlos A. S. Ferreira, Hamidreza M. Nick, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480316

                ABSTRACT: This paper presents a hydromechanical simulation of large-scale analysis to assess the risk of CO2 leakage through faults within the reservoir and caprock as potential pathways. The study involves the evaluation of slip tendency and distance to failure of existing faults in both the caprock and reservoir, which are crucial parameters influencing the potential for induced seismicity. To that aim, thermo-hydro-mechanical simulation of cold CO2 injection close to the cap rock and within a high-temperature (110&#176;C) depleted gas reservoir is carried out to quantify the additional stresses and strains caused by the thermal expansion/contraction of the rocks. Since preferential fluid flow is more pronounced through faults and fractures experiencing high slip tendency, here the assessment of slip tendency shows no concerns regarding fault seal and the behavior of faults as pathways for the migration of CO2 injection. In addition, this study utilizes distance to failure analysis by driving data from analyses of stress orientation, magnitude, fault geometry, and temperature. The findings indicate that there are no significant concerns regarding the integrity of fault seals or the behavior of faults as potential routes for CO2 injection migration. 1. INTRODUCTION The injection of CO2 alters both the reservoir pressure and the distribution of effective stress within the reservoir and caprock formations. The primary mechanism influencing hydromechanical behavior is the overall reduction in effective stresses, which is induced by the high-pressure injection of CO2 around the injection well. However, injecting CO2 into depleted gas reservoirs requires further analysis. During gas production, the reservoir pressure significantly decreases, leading to an increase in effective stresses. This study presents a numerical simulation of large-scale coupled analysis to evaluate the risk of fault reactivation within the reservoir and caprock. Rohmer &amp; Seyedi (2010) conducted an analysis of fault slip potential during CO2 injection, accounting for factors such as fluid pressure, stress fields, and poro-elastic effects. Through coupled simulation, they demonstrated that the maximum sustainable overpressure is strongly dependent on the in-situ stress state. Soltanzadeh &amp; Hawkes (2008) explored how changes in fluid pressure within porous reservoirs can lead to stress alterations in surrounding rocks, potentially triggering the reactivation of existing faults. The findings indicate that, under fluid injection into a reservoir experiencing an extensional stress regime, fault reactivation tendencies are observed solely in rocks situated above and below the reservoir. Conversely, within a compressional stress regime, fault reactivation is more likely to manifest within the reservoir itself. Ferrill et al. (2020) explored the interconnected concepts of failure mode and resolved stress analysis, offering examples of fault geometry in normal and reverse faulting stress regimes. These analyses predicted deformation behavior and elucidated how variations in fault geometry and associated deformation mechanisms influence fluid transmission.</description>
      <author>Bahram Hosseinzadeh Samani, F. Amour, Alejandro Barrera C., Mohammad Reza Hajiabadi, Carlos A. S. Ferreira, Hamidreza M. Nick</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0507</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous in Situ Characterization by AFM of Surface Mechanical and Electrical Features of Shale Organic Matter Under Different Atmospheres</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0681</link>
      <description>Ying Kang, Zhengfu Ning, Fangtao Lyu, Zejiang Jia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481377

                ABSTRACT: Unconventional reservoirs, which are the mainstay of CO2 enhancement and carbon sequestration, are not well characterized in terms of micro-surface electrical properties. In this study, the micro-surface morphology and potential of organic matter (OM) under three atmospheres: dry, water-wet, and ScCO2 were characterized in detail using atomic force microscopy (Tapping mode, KPFM). The results showed that the micro-surface morphology of the OM fluctuated in the range of less than ten nanometers, and the micro-surface roughness under dry and ScCO2 conditions was higher than that under water-wet conditions, which indicated that the ScCO2 extraction and induced swelling were effective. In addition, the contact potential difference of the organic surface under water-wet and ScCO2 conditions was positive, and there was no correlation with the change of surface morphology. Combined with the reduction of Young's modulus, the difference of organic surface potential and the reduction of Young's modulus provide a good physical basis for the emergence of micro-cracks and other defects under the external forces, and provide a new idea for revealing the adsorption characteristics of unconventional reservoirs and realizing the long-term and stable carbon geologic sequestration. 1. INTRODUCTION Due to the decrease of conventional oil and gas resource production rates and the impact of the greenhouse effect in recent years, unconventional oil and gas reservoirs, such as shale, have become an important option for enhancing resource production rates and realizing carbon geologic sequestration (Farokhpoor et al., 2013; J. Zhang et al., 2023). A large number of studies have been carried out on rock damage, fracture generation and other related phenomena, but most of these studies have focused on the macro-scale level and lacked detailed analysis of related changes at the micro- and nano-scale (J. He et al., 2020; Yin et al., 2023; Gu et al., 2023). For unconventional reservoirs such as shale, which is both a key target for the implementation of CO2 enhanced recovery measures and an ideal place to realize efficient and stable carbon geological storage. Direct surface characterization of them can provide a better understanding of the CO2 action mechanism.</description>
      <author>Ying Kang, Zhengfu Ning, Fangtao Lyu, Zejiang Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study of High-Temperature HDR Fracture Features Under True-Triaxial Stress with Supercritical CO2 Fracturing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1015</link>
      <description>Xuhao Fan, Haizhu Wang, Mingsheng Liu, Bin Wang, Yunpeng Zhang, Zhenchuan Mao, Hao Chen, Sergei Stanchits, &#1040;lexey Cheremisin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480441

                ABSTRACT: The paper presents fracturing experiments on Hot Dry Rock using water and SC-CO2 (supercritical CO2) to obtain the characteristics of fracture morphologies under actual temperature and pressure conditions. These experiments utilized an in-house developed, real-time, high-temperature, high-pressure, true triaxial experimental system. The study investigates fracture propagation characteristics under various formation stresses and initial rock temperatures while quantitatively analyzing post-fracturing parameters such as fractal dimension, using tools like surface profilometers. The results demonstrate that the fracturing pressure with SC-CO2 is significantly lower than that of conventional hydraulic fracturing, with the fracture pressure of the rock reduced from 21.8 MPa to approximately 14.9 MPa, a decrease of 31.7%, and SC-CO2 fracturing results in more complex fracture morphologies and larger fractal dimensions of the fracture surfaces. Under the same conditions, compared to hydraulic fracturing, the increase in temperature results in a greater reduction in rock fracture pressure and a larger increase in fractal dimension with SC-CO2 fracturing. Additionally, high stress differentials impact fracture orientation and complexity. This research elucidates the fracture characteristics of Hot Dry Rock induced by SC-CO2, laying a foundation for understanding the complex fracture formation mechanisms in Hot Dry Rock SC-CO2 fracturing. 1. INTRODUCTION With the continuous rapid development of the national economy, human demand for energy is increasing day by day. Conventional fossil fuels such as oil and coal are non-renewable resources, not only facing the problems of diminishing reserves and resource depletion, but also severe environmental pollution issues (Yijin, 2015). Therefore, the development and utilization of new alternative energy sources is urgent, and the vigorous development of clean renewable energy has become an important measure for countries around the world to cope with energy shortages and environmental pollution issues (Panwar et al., 2011; Pachauri et al., 2014). Geothermal energy, as an important clean and renewable energy source, has the characteristics of low carbon, environmental protection, stability, and efficiency. Compared with wind and solar energy, it is not affected by external factors such as seasons, climate, and day and night, making it a realistic and competitive new energy source (Chao et al., 2020). Hot Dry Rock (HDR) is a thermal rock body that contains no water or only a small amount of water (which cannot flow) and is an important component of geothermal energy resources (Tianfu et al., 2016). China is rich in HDR resources. According to data from the China Geological Survey, the resource amount of HDR buried at depths of 3 to 10 km is equivalent to 856 trillion tons of standard coal (Guiling et al., 2020). Therefore, accelerating the efficient development and utilization of HDR resources has significant political and economic significance in terms of meeting China's energy demand, optimizing the energy structure, and achieving carbon peak and carbon neutrality goals (Yaofeng, 2015; Zhu et al., 2015; Zhonghe et al., 2020; Breede and Dzebisashvili et al., 2013). Enhanced Geothermal Systems (EGS) are currently the main means of developing HDR (Anderson et al., 2019; Geothermal energy terms, 2018), which involves creating artificial reservoirs in high-temperature formations through methods such as hydraulic fracturing to form a network of fractures connecting injection wells and production wells, followed by circulating a working fluid for heat extraction, power generation, and comprehensive utilization. HDR reservoirs have characteristics such as hardness, density, and high geostress, requiring fracturing to enhance permeability and form effective heat exchange channels. However, traditional water-based fracturing methods and heat extraction technologies face challenges such as high fracturing pressure, poor enhancement effect, and low heat extraction efficiency, severely limiting the development and utilization of HDR (Zhigang et al., 2019). SC-CO2 fluid refers to CO2 fluid at temperatures and pressures exceeding its critical temperature (31.1&#176;C) and critical pressure (7.38MPa), characterized by high density, high diffusivity, low viscosity, and low surface tension. Compared with conventional water-based fracturing fluids, SC-CO2 has strong fluidity and diffusivity, effectively reducing the fracturing pressure required for the reservoir and helping to form complex fracture networks, and its superiority in transforming low-permeability/dense reservoirs has been widely recognized (Haizhu et al., 2020; Haizhu et al.,2012; Junping et al., 2019; Middleton et al., 2015). Studies have shown that using SC-CO2 for fracturing HDR has the following technical advantages(Bing et al., 2021; Legarth et al., 2003; Honglian et al., 2022): (1) low viscosity and near-zero surface tension of SC-CO2, strong penetration ability, and the capability to connect more natural fractures; (2) extremely weak intermolecular forces and very low surface tension of SC-CO2, resulting in strong fluidity and facilitating SC-CO2 flow and diffusion in formations; (3) injection of CO2 into geothermal formations can promote water-rock reactions, increasing reservoir porosity and permeability, thereby enhancing heat extraction efficiency; (4) full utilization of greenhouse gas CO2 for fracturing, saving water resources, and facilitating CO2 geological sequestration. However, due to the high-temperature and high-stress environment of HDR reservoirs, the mechanical properties of rocks and CO2 flow parameters change, causing the CO2 fracturing mechanism in HDR reservoirs to differ from traditional fracture mechanics theories, making them unsuitable for guiding CO2 fracturing design and construction in HDR reservoirs.</description>
      <author>Xuhao Fan, Haizhu Wang, Mingsheng Liu, Bin Wang, Yunpeng Zhang, Zhenchuan Mao, Hao Chen, Sergei Stanchits, &#1040;lexey Cheremisin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Waste Management Performance in Pariaman City Using Life Cycle Assessment (LCA)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24036/cived.v10i3.326</link>
      <description>Dyah Paramita, Rizki Aziz, Shinta Indah, CIVED. 10(3)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4401373126

                Pariaman City's waste generation in 2022 is 38.26 tons/day. Waste management in Pariaman City is still not optimal, resulting in waste piling up in TPA South Tungkal. The waste reduction value at the research location after processing with BSF larvae can reduce 0.005 tons/day or 0.02% of the total waste generation in Pariaman City. The environmental impacts in waste management studied are Global Warming Potential (GWP), Acidification Potential (AP), and Eutrophication Potential (EP). Reducing the environmental impact of processing organic waste has been carried out, the smallest impact reduction results were obtained, namely in scenario 1, namely processing organic waste with BSF larvae in waste banks and TPS 3R. The results obtained were the impact characterization value from comparing several impact categories. GWP value 32,060,838.136 103 kg CO2-eq, AP 0.00246 x103 SO2-eq, and EP 0.00134 x103 kg PO4-3. So it can be concluded that scenario 1 has a smaller GWP, AP, and EP impact on the environment compared to scenario 0 and is used as the best alternative scenario for waste management in Pariaman City</description>
      <author>Dyah Paramita, Rizki Aziz, Shinta Indah</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24036/cived.v10i3.326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening New Mungbean Varieties for Terminal Drought Tolerance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14081328</link>
      <description>Sobia Ikram, Surya P. Bhattarai, Kerry B. Walsh, Agriculture. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401520705

                Rainfed mungbean crops in Queensland Australia frequently experience terminal drought (drought stress in the final stages of reproductive development), highlighting the importance of drought-tolerant varieties for sustainable mungbean production. Given there is limited information on the relative drought tolerance of current mungbean varieties in Australia, the study of genetic variations and mechanisms of drought tolerance in summer mungbean can provide a basis for developing drought-tolerant mungbean varieties. This study evaluated the physiological, biochemical, and phenological traits underpinning yield attributes associated with drought tolerance in selected mungbean varieties. Four new mungbean varieties (AVTMB#1 to 4) and the Australian commercial line (Jade-AU) were grown in tall (75 cm) polyvinyl chloride (PVC) lysimeters where drought stress was imposed at the early flowering stage (R1) and maintained until maturity. Drought stress significantly impacted all the varieties. Averaged across all the varieties, drought stress was associated with a reduction in stomatal conductance (gs) and photosynthetic rate (Asat) by 78% and 86%, respectively, compared to well-watered plants. Internal carbon dioxide concentration (Ci), the effective quantum yield of photosystem II (&#934;PSII) and maximum light-use efficiency of light-acclimated photosystem II (PSII) centres (Fv&#8217;/Fm&#8217;) were also decreased, while excitation pressure (1-qP) increased with drought treatment. A positive correlation (r = 0.60) existed between seed yield and &#934;PSII assessed at R1, while a weak correlation with Fv&#8217;/Fm&#8217; (r = 0.24) was observed. Excitation pressure (1-qP) at the R1 stage was negatively correlated with seed yield (r = &#8722;0.66). Therefore, leaf fluorescence measures, viz., 1-qP and &#934;PSII, were recommended for use in screening mungbean varieties for drought tolerance. The varieties, AVTMB#1 and AVTMB#4, respectively achieved 39 and 38% greater seed yields relative to the commercial variety, Jade-AU, under terminal drought conditions.</description>
      <author>Sobia Ikram, Surya P. Bhattarai, Kerry B. Walsh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14081328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Assessment of End-Of-Life Wells and Fields for Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS) Suitability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/219642-ms</link>
      <description>Edward Hoskin, S. Mahyildin, M. Crookes, No host. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401407878

                Abstract In the coming decades many thousands of fields and tens of thousands of wells globally will reach the end of their commercial life due to dwindling production rates and will need to be decommissioned at a substantial cost. The scale of the task can be appreciated by considering that in Southeast Asia alone, it is forecast that approximately 1,500 platforms and over 7,000 wells are projected to need decommissioning by 2030 with costs estimated to range from $30 billion to as high as $100 billion (Evans, 2019). At the same time as the backlog for decommissioning grows, CO2 concentrations in the atmosphere continue to increase (www.co2.earth/daily-co2) without viable at-scale alternatives to eliminate fossil fuel use for the foreseeable future. Since governments world-wide (Carver, 2021) have committed to net zero targets or substantial reductions in CO2 emissions in the coming decades, there is a pressing need to address how to maintain use of fossils fuels (in countries and for activities for which there are no alternatives) while at the same time reducing or maintaining atmospheric CO2 concentrations at existing levels (12 countries have passed legislation on net zero targets and over 190 countries signed the Paris Agreement, a legally binding international treaty on climate change reached at COP21 in 2015, including all ASEAN nations). While the process of reducing or removing CO2 emissions from various sources is not straightforward for any country, there are a convergence of challenges faced by ASEAN nations. In the last two decades, a time of rapid economic development, renewable energy sources have not gained ground on fossil fuels in the overall total energy consumption of ASEAN nations (The World Bank, 2024) and data show a decrease in ratio of renewable energy generated compared to total energy consumed. Although the share of electricity generated from renewable sources increased from 2015 to 2020 it was insufficient to offset the increased fossil fuel use in transport and industry sectors (Lau, 2022). The slow increase in renewable energy generation can be partly attributed to sustainability concerns with both hydropower and bioenergy in ASEAN, for example, the over-damming of the Mekong River and the clearing of rainforest in Borneo (Lau, 2022). Furthermore, the deployment of other effective methods of renewable energy generation such as wind turbines and solar panels are less well suited to ASEAN countries. Minimum windspeeds across much of the region fall below the 4 m/s threshold level for efficient use of a wind turbine, except for coastal areas around Philippines and Vietnam where wind speeds are higher (Lau, 2022). Solar is rated as a moderate potential renewable source, with other parts of Asia rated higher, (Lau, 2022) but it requires a significant landmass to make a meaningful contribution, which is not available due to the dense population in ASEAN. Lau, 2022, assessed that it is unlikely that renewable energies will replace energy generated from fossil fuels within the 2030&#8211;2050 timeframe and fossil fuels will remain an important part of the energy mix requiring ASEAN countries to adopt strategies and technologies to mitigate CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Edward Hoskin, S. Mahyildin, M. Crookes</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/219642-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Fracture Initiation and Expansion of Coal Rock by CO2 Foam Fracturing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1023</link>
      <description>Yong-Gang Xie, Xuhao Fan, Changjing Zhou, Haizhu Wang, Zhenchuan Mao, Li Wang, Feng Mao, Sergei Stanchits, &#1040;lexey Cheremisin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480054

                ABSTRACT: To investigate the crack initiation and propagation mechanism of CO2 foam fracturing coal rock. In this study, experiments were conducted on CO2 foam fracturing of coal rock using custom-designed indoor quasi-triaxial and true-triaxial fracturing equipment. The resulting fracture parameters (fracture area, width, fractal dimension) were quantitatively analyzed through CT scanning and topography scanning. The research investigated the influence of varying foam quality, temperature, and flow rate on the initiation and propagation of fractures in coal rock. The results indicate that with a higher CO2 foam mass fraction, the fractures exhibit a higher level of complexity and lower fracturing pressure. Specifically, the initiation pressure at 70% foam mass is 7.1% lower than that at 40% foam mass, As the quality of CO2 foam improves, the post-fracturing fracture area and fractal dimension increase, indicating a rougher fracture surface and enhanced conductivity. As the temperature rises, the foaming volume of the foam decreases, leading to a shorter half-life, reduced interaction with coal rock, and slightly higher initiation pressure; CO2 foam fracturing can maintain larger fracture widths and has a greater fractal dimension compared to conventional fracturing fluids. This study reveals the fracture initiation and propagation mechanism of coal rock by CO2 foam fracturing. 1. INTRODUCTION The rapid development of China's economy and society drives a surge in oil and gas consumption, while conventional resources dwindle. This reliance on foreign oil and gas constrains China's economic and social progress. Coalbed methane products mainly comprise methane, an associated gas generated during coal production. Coalbed methane products primarily consist of methane, an associated gas formed during coal production. Comparable to natural gas, this clean energy source boasts high heat levels (Zonghu, 2006). The energy generated per 1000m3 of coalbed methane is equal to the energy generated by 1 ton of fuel oil and 1.25 ton of standard coal. With a calorific value of up to 33.44MJ/m3, CBM matches the quality of high-grade coal (Bozhang, 2005). Aligned with the "double carbon" objective, the exploration and exploitation of coalbed methane embody key values of "economy, safety, and environmental protection", contributing to a reduction in greenhouse gas emissions. Positioned as a pivotal facet and growth trajectory within the energy sector, coalbed methane holds immense promise for expansion and implementation, poised to emerge as a vital avenue addressing societal energy needs in the years ahead (Lei, 2018). China possesses abundant coalbed methane resources, ranking second globally after Russia and Canada (Qingbo &amp; Wenguang, 2008; CHO and KIM, 2013), surpassing the United States and Australia by a significant margin. Despite this abundance, China has maintained relatively low production of coalbed methane. The inherent characteristics of Chinese coalbed methane reservoirs, characterized by low pressure, low saturation, low permeability, and high adsorption, constitute the primary bottleneck hindering the accelerated development of coalbed methane (Yali et al., 2021). Based on statistical data, China's geological coalbed methane resources stand at 29.8&#215;10^12 m3, with technically recoverable resources estimated at 11.2&#215;10^12 m3. The majority of these resources are situated within the three main regions of Northeast China, North China, and Northwest China. The top four regions with the most significant deposits include Ordos Basin, Qinshui Basin, Eastern Yunnan and Western Guizhou, and Junggar Basin, accounting for 24.4%, 13.4%, 11.6%, and 10.4% of total reserves, respectively (Xiaozhi et al., 2022). Currently, the development of coalbed methane faces a number of challenges, including the unclear migration mechanism and stimulation process for horizontal wells. The conventional method of hydraulic fracturing is often utilized, but it yields limited fractures, higher initial fracturing pressure, and simplistic fracture networks. Further, this approach wastes significant amounts of water resources and can even damage surface environments (Shaokai &amp; Deli, 2019; Johnson &amp; Johnson, 2012; Bostrom et al., 2014; Shibing et al., 2014; Haizhu et al., 2015; Zhonghou et al., 2010; Xiaojiang et al., 2017; Zhonghou et al., 2011). In response to diverse geological and technological demands, a range of CO2 fracturing technologies have surfaced, including CO2 foam fracturing, pre-CO2 energy-increasing fracturing, quasidry CO2 fracturing, dry CO2 fracturing, and various other variants. Notably, CO2 foam fracturing involves the injection of liquid CO2 into the well using a dedicated CO2 pump truck. This liquid CO2 is combined with gel fluid during the process and utilized for sand fracturing purposes (Changlin et al., 2016; Ting et al., 2016; Jidong et al., 2004). Due to the distinctive structure of the foam system, it boasts exceptional capabilities in minimizing sand sedimentation rates, even under high sand ratios. This unique structure enables excellent suspension and efficient transport of sand particles within the system (Shaohua, 2014; Siwei et al., 2024; Bo et al., 2023). Based on field data, the CO2 foam fracturing process has demonstrated significant advantages over conventional water-based fracturing methods. It enables complete self-flowing drainage post-fracturing, resulting in a high flowback rate and shorter drainage time. Moreover, this process causes minimal damage to the formation and fractures, while yielding remarkable fracturing outcomes (Hui &amp; Xuxing, 2018; Xuxing et al., 2019; Zhandong, 2010; Honglian et al., 2022; Junping et al., 2019). The fracture characteristics observed in laboratory-scale experiments can offer insights into field construction scenarios. However, the in-depth exploration of the fracture initiation mechanism in CO2 foam fracturing of coal rock remains relatively limited. This study aims to address this gap by conducting CO2 foam fracturing experiments on coal rock using self-designed indoor quasi-triaxial and true-triaxial fracturing experimental equipment. The integration of CT scanning and morphology scanning allows for the quantitative analysis of fracture parameters, such as fractal dimension, fracture width, and fracture area. Furthermore, the study investigates the influence of various factors, including foam quality, temperature, stress differential, and flow rate, on the initiation and propagation patterns of cracks in coal rock. The experimental findings uncover the laws governing crack initiation and propagation in coal rock fractured by CO2 foam, offering an experimental foundation for the application of CO2 foam fracturing in coalbed methane development and contributing to the advancement of CO2 foam fracturing technology.</description>
      <author>Yong-Gang Xie, Xuhao Fan, Changjing Zhou, Haizhu Wang, Zhenchuan Mao, Li Wang, Feng Mao, Sergei Stanchits, &#1040;lexey Cheremisin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Thermal Cycling on Cemented Sandstone in Relation to CCS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0797</link>
      <description>H. Smith, Magnus Soldal, L. Grande, Luke Griffiths, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401479112

                ABSTRACT: As widespread Carbon Capture and Sequestration becomes more relevant, challenges related to thermal cooling upon injection and the potential for significant stress perturbation needs to be accounted for in geomechanical modelling. The current work shows an example of how temperature fluctuations related to CO2 injection can affect the stress changes within a reservoir using a stiff cemented sandstone analogue for deep reservoirs, and further demonstrates how a laboratory test program can be efficiently used to better define thermal aspects of typical geomechanical parameters such as Young's moduli and Poisson's ratio. The current program has shown how elastic moduli can be affected by changes in temperature, and how these changes can affect the estimation of stress changes within a reservoir. This comprehensive triaxial test also displayed a non-linear behavior at lower effective radial stresses during temperature reduction, which can be related to plastic deformation achieved during cooling. 1. INTRODUCTION As carbon capture and Sequestration (CCS) has gained the public's attention, the necessity to demonstrate that CCS can be deployed safely is key to make CCS an accepted solution as a contribution for reducing global emissions. To predict the reservoir response and ensure safe operations, geomechanical models are used to determine the influence of pressure and temperature change due to injection on the in situ stress conditions. To provide accurate predictions, one of the first steps will be the production of relevant laboratory data to both populate numerical models with the relevant parameters, and to validate these models through laboratory experiments simulating pressure and temperature changes expected due to injection. These models will need to accommodate reservoir responses to typical challenges related to CCS. Thermal effects play a significant role in the geomechanical behavior of reservoirs during CCS operations, where cool CO2 is injected into a warmer reservoir. The resulting changes in temperature lead to contraction of the rock matrix and modification of the stress state (Fj&#230;r, 2008; S&#248;reide et al., 2014; Thompson et al., 2021). In sandstone reservoirs, cooling is expected to lead to reduction of effective horizontal stress due to thermal contraction of the rock (S&#248;reide et al., 2014). This reduction in horizontal stress can potentially lead to a more critical stress-state. To understand and predict the influence of temperature on stress in the reservoir, it is critical to determine the relative parameters that may be used to model the influence of cooling.</description>
      <author>H. Smith, Magnus Soldal, L. Grande, Luke Griffiths</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consolidation Behaviors of Clays, Mudstones and Shales -CO2 Storage Sites in Horda Platform, Offshore Norway</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0457</link>
      <description>L. Grande, E. Skurtveit, Jung Chan Choi, Nazmul Haque Mondol, Nazmul Haque Mondol, N. Thompson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481650

                ABSTRACT: Clays, mudstones and shales above CO2 storage reservoirs are all together defining the top seal. In this paper, we evaluate the constrained modulus (M) and permeability (k) of clay sediments, mudstones and shales from the Horda Platform area, offshore Norway, where the CO2 storage sites Aurora, Smeaheia and Luna are located. We utilize a dataset of uniaxial strain tests in depth range 0-2.6 km including Quaternary clays from geotechnical site investigations (depth &amp;lt;220m), three mudstones (depth ca 1.1-1.4km) and one deep shale (depth ca 2.6km) and combine with the larger NGI database and previous tests on synthetic mixtures of clay and silt. M and k are key input to a range of analysis i.e. settlement of structures (geotechnical), burial compaction in sedimentary basins, surface settlement or heave from petroleum production or subsurface CO2 storage. New empirical relationships for M, based on modulus number (m), volume of clay (Vcl), plasticity index (Ip) and water content (wi) are suggested, and new method for upscaling M using Vcl from gamma ray logs are demonstrated from clays at geotechnical through mudstones down to depth of caprock for Smeaheia CO2 storage site. Permeabilities (k) in the mechanically compacted natural clays and mudstones aligns well into an exponential trendline when compared against maximum burial depth. 1. INTRODUCTION The impact of geological history on rheology and stresses in sedimentary basins has been evaluated for various CO2 storage sites in the SHARP project (www.sharp-storage-act-eu). This includes burial compaction, erosion and uplift, glacial loading during the last ice age. Constrained modulus (M) and permeability (k) are key parameters in modelling deformation responses during compaction, tectonic uplift, erosion and glacial loading/unloading in sedimentary basins including time-dependent undrained vs. drained behaviors and overpressure developments. M and k are also key parameters in field scale ground models, i.e. to evaluate reservoir deformation from CO2 injection using predictions based on monitoring of surface heave (i.e., Bohloli et al., 2022). In such cases, parameters covering the entire lithology from the seabed to the CO2 storage reservoirs are needed. Empirical correlations for M vs. index properties have been developed for geotechnical applications (i.e. Andersen and Schjetne, 2013; DeGroot et al., 2019). Empirical correlations stiffness based on velocity logs are normally used for mudstones and shales (i.e. Horsrud et al., 2001, Grande et al. 2008 and 2022). However, the transition zone at ca 0.2 - 1 km, deeper than geotechnical borehole and shallower than what is normally cored in petroleum and CCS projects, are not well constrained in empirical correlations. High-stress uniaxial strain tests (UST) on mixtures of sediments with well-known mineralogy are useful to constrain engineering parameters, i.e. systematic studies of sand (Chuhan et al., 2002 and 2003) and silt-clays mixtures (Mondol et al., 2009 and Grande et al., 2013). Ageing and mineral transformation can occur in the transition of clays to mudstones (&amp;lt;2km); however chemical compaction process (diagenesis) and porosity reduction and stiffening from cementation, starts at temperatures &amp;gt;70&#176;C, further transforming mudstones to shales (Bj&#248;rlykke and H&#248;eg, 1997, Bj&#248;rlykke, 1998). Nevertheless, the initial composition of the sediment defines the behavior of deeper mudstones and significant parts of sealing units for CO2 storage.</description>
      <author>L. Grande, E. Skurtveit, Jung Chan Choi, Nazmul Haque Mondol, Nazmul Haque Mondol, N. Thompson</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Geomechanical Modeling Workflow for CCUS Near-Well Integrity Assessment in Layered Poroelastic Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0969</link>
      <description>Guang Zhai, E. Peters, Thibault Candela, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480199

                ABSTRACT: The practice of cold CO2 injection into depleted oil/gas reservoirs addressing the increasing global emissions requires efficient and robust geomechanical assessment of near-well (caprock) damage risks. The geomechanical responses involve driving forces of small-footprint cooling zones from thermal effects, large-footprint pressure plumes from fluid diffusion, and possible continuing reservoir inelastic compaction. The workflow of coupling these processes to rock mechanics for geomechanical assessment is based on numerical or (semi-)analytical solutions. Among the latter, the recent development of MACRIS at TNO considers the fundamental point-source solution in homogeneous half-space which has been validated with FEM methods and is computationally efficient. Here, we extend the MACRIS framework and use the point-source solution in a layered, poroelastic half-space. Such improvement can provide several advantages of considering vertical heterogeneity of earth medium, solid-fluid coupling outside the reservoir, and undrained conditions in caprock. By incorporating the layered poroelastic point-source solution, we develop a workflow consisting of reservoir hydro-thermal simulation for temperature and fluid pressure distributions, calculating point-source mechanical influence functions in layered poroelastic medium, and integration for geomechanical assessment at targets. Finally, we demonstrate the workflow and show results from a case study using realistic model parameters provided by operators. 1. INTRODUCTION Enabling large-scale CO2 capture, utilization and storage (CCUS) is crucial to ensure global emission reductions in line with the Paris agreement (Hennessy et al., 2022). Several previous large-scale projects for CO2 storage have been focused on deep aquifers, e.g., in the Salah CO2 storage site in Algeria (Ringrose et al., 2013). Recently, using depleted oil/gas reservoir for large-scale CCUS has been proposed to be promising for addressing the increasing global emissions, since they are well characterized from previous O&amp;G activities with large pressure margins for safe storage (Wei et al., 2023). During the practice of CCUS in the context of depleted oil/gas reservoirs, one of the major challenges is the timely and robust geomechanical assessment of near-well damage hazards, which can help mitigate potential damage-related risks and enhance the safe operations (Wei et al., 2023). The geomechanical assessment may require the consideration of both reservoir depletion (oil/gas production) and re-pressurization (CO2 injection) phases, since the reservoir deformation processes during the two phases can be physically linked. In reservoir leakage pathways. Such processes have not received much study to date (Fan et al., 2020; Liu et al., 2020).</description>
      <author>Guang Zhai, E. Peters, Thibault Candela</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Study on the Stabilization of CO2 Oil-Based Foam by a Novel Compound Surfactant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-122352</link>
      <description>Zhoujie Wang, Kaiqiang Zhang, Shaopeng Li, Jia Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401458221

                Abstract The effectiveness of CO2 oil-based foam in conventional and unconventional oil and gas development, as well as CO2 storage, relies on its stability. This study delves into the gas-liquid surface properties and liquid film behavior of a compound surfactant FS oil-based foam system, with a focus on understanding the mechanisms influencing its stability. The investigation reveals that the viscoelastic modulus of the FS surfactant system initially rises and then stabilizes with increased concentration, reaching a peak of 15.43 mN/m at 1.5 wt%. In the FS oil-based foaming system, the inhibition of sliding between liquid molecules enhances resistance to external deformation, promoting stability. Observing the liquid film of FS oil-based foam, color transitions signify evolving film thickness. The film initially displays various colors, gradually shifting from cyan and purple to deep blue and brown. As the film stratifies, forming dark domains that expand and eventually lead to rupture, FS significantly prolongs thinning time and reduces film thickness. At 2 wt% FS concentration, the foam rupture time is maximized at 4550 s. The presence of surfactant molecules forming a molecular layer in the liquid film strengthens and toughens the film, enhancing durability against external forces. This research suggests that the FS oil-based foam system with a 2 wt% concentration exhibits superior stability. Insights gained from this study contribute to the strategic use of oil-based foam, offering potential benefits for enhancing oilfield development efficiency and supporting carbon reduction goals.</description>
      <author>Zhoujie Wang, Kaiqiang Zhang, Shaopeng Li, Jia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/omae2024-122352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental impact assessment in the Caspian region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32454/0016-7762-2024-66-2-124-140</link>
      <description>Elnur Aliyev, V. Yu. Kerimov, Yu. &#1040;. Lobanov, Proceedings of higher educational establishments Geology and Exploration. 66(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401399031

                Background. The current state and pressures associated with the anthropogenic impact on the Caspian region environment are examined. Surrounded by five coastal countries, including the Republic of Azerbaijan, the Russian Federation, the Republic of Kazakhstan, Turkmenistan, and the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Caspian Sea is the world&#8217;s largest endorheic water body. The isolation of the Caspian Sea, which is characterized by special climatic conditions and salinity gradients, has led to the formation of a unique ecosystem. Aim. Environmental impact assessment of the Caspian region and the associated anthropogenetic load. Materials and methods. The anthropogenic processes affecting the environment of the Caspian Sea and the surrounding area were assessed using the DPSIR concept. This concept includes the components of driving forces, pressures, state, impacts, and response in order to inclusively determine the connections between human activities and the environment. This concept was used as by the European Environmental Agency as the basis for integrated environmental analysis. Results. The conducted study determined the scale and geography of greenhouse gas degassing, the volume of pollutant emissions into the atmosphere by components, the structure of greenhouse gas emissions, and the dynamics of emissions of carbon dioxide, methane, and nitrogen oxide generated from stationary sources in the Caspian region. Anthropogenic emissions of greenhouse gases that pollute the atmosphere and sea waters, generated from stationary sources, are formed as a result of the production activities of a number of industries: mining; electricity, gas, and steam generation; air conditioning; manufacturing; water supply; wastewater treatment; construction industry; agriculture and forestry; transport storage and communications; repair of vehicles and motorcycles; as well as other activities. Conclusion. The share of enterprises in the fuel and energy complex that emit greenhouse gases is about 60%. The structure of greenhouse gas emissions and the dynamics of CO 2 , CH 4 , and N 2 O emissions generated from stationary sources in the Caspian region are shown. The Caspian Sea is one of the most important endorheic basins in the world. Being surrounded by land on all sides, the Caspian Sea lacks flows that would maintain its self-purification. Pollutants that enter the Sea remain there due to the lack of mechanisms for their removal. Complete information about the level of pollutant inputs is crucial for selecting the most effective means of environmental compensation or pollution reduction. The largest polluting sectors are agriculture, industry, including oil and gas, and urbanization.</description>
      <author>Elnur Aliyev, V. Yu. Kerimov, Yu. &#1040;. Lobanov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32454/0016-7762-2024-66-2-124-140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging clean technologies: policy-driven cost reductions, implications and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4696747/v1</link>
      <description>Mohamed Atouife, Jesse Jenkins, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401437119

                Abstract Hydrogen production from water electrolysis, direct air capture (DAC), and synthetic kerosene derived from hydrogen and CO2 ('e-kerosene') are expected to play an important role in global decarbonization efforts. So far, the economics of these nascent technologies hamper their market diffusion. However, a wave of recent policy support in the United States, Europe, China, and elsewhere is anticipated to drive their commercial liftoff and bring their costs down. To this end, we evaluate the potential cost reductions driven by policy-induced scale-up of these emerging technologies through 2030 using an experience curves approach accounting for both local and global learning effects. We then analyze the consequences of projected cost declines on the competitiveness of these nascent technologies compared to conventional fossil alternatives, where applicable, and highlight some of the tradeoffs associated with their expansion. Our findings indicate that enacted policies could lead to substantial capital cost reductions for electrolyzers. Nevertheless, electrolytic hydrogen production at \$1-2/kg would still require some form of policy support. Given expected costs and experience curves, it is unlikely that liquid solvent DAC (L-DAC) scale-up will bring removal costs to stated targets of $100/tCO2, though a $200/tCO2 may eventually be within reach. We also underscore the importance of tackling methane leakage for natural gas-powered L-DAC: unmitigated leaks amplify net removal costs, exacerbate the investment requirements to reach targeted costs, and cast doubt on the technology's role in the clean energy transition. Lastly, despite reductions in electrolysis and L-DAC costs, e-kerosene remains considerably more expensive than fossil jet fuel. The economics of e-kerosene and the resources required for production raise questions about the fuel's ultimate viability as a decarbonization tool for aviation.</description>
      <author>Mohamed Atouife, Jesse Jenkins</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4696747/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Carbon Emissions and Influencing Factors of Residents&#8217; Lives in Hebei Province</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166770</link>
      <description>Cuiling Zhang, Yang Wei-hua, Ruyan Wang, Wen Zheng, Liying Guo, Sustainability. 16(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401418326

                The standard of living has significantly risen along with ongoing economic progress, but CO2 emissions have also been rising. The reduction in CO2 resulting from the daily activities of residents has become a crucial priority for every province. A relevant study on the carbon emissions of Hebei Province residents was conducted for this publication, aiming to provide a theoretical basis for the sustainable development of Hebei Province. The first part of the article calculates the carbon emissions of Hebei Province people from 2005 to 2020 using the emission factor method and the Consumer Lifestyle Approach (CLA). Secondly, the Logarithmic Mean Divisia Index (LMDI) decomposition approach is used to assess the components that influence both direct and indirect carbon emissions. Finally, the scenario analysis approach is employed in conjunction with the LEAP model to establish baseline, low-carbon, and ultra-low-carbon scenarios to predict the trend of residents&#8217; carbon emissions in Hebei Province from 2021 to 2040. The results show that the total carbon emissions of residents in Hebei Province from 2005 to 2020 rose, from 77.45 million tons to 153.35 million tons. Income level, energy consumption intensity, and population scale are factors that contribute to the increase in direct carbon emissions, while consumption tendency factors have a mitigating effect on direct carbon emissions. Economic level, consumption structure, and population scale factors are factors that contribute to the increase in indirect carbon emissions, while energy consumption intensity and energy structure factors have a mitigating effect on indirect carbon emissions. The prediction results show that under the baseline scenario, the cumulative residents&#8217; carbon emissions in Hebei Province will not reach a zenith from 2021 to 2040. However, under the low-carbon situation, the carbon emissions of residents in Hebei Province will peak in 2029, with a peak of 174.69 million tons, whereas under the ultra-low-carbon scenario, it will peak in 2028, with a peak of 173.27 million tons.</description>
      <author>Cuiling Zhang, Yang Wei-hua, Ruyan Wang, Wen Zheng, Liying Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16166770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling And Simulation Of Renewable Technologies For Economic And Environmental Analysis And Optimization Of Dairy Farms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34719/tcud9414</link>
      <description>Michael Breen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401392626

                The aim of this thesis was to develop a dairy optimisation platform to optimise investments in dairy farm technology and changes to on-farm management practices and electricity tariffs, in order to maximise profitability and minimise environmental impacts. Increased dairy herd sizes and milk production levels in Ireland as well as changing regulations concerning emissions, renewable penetration and energy efficiency have necessitated a means of financial decision support for farmers. Therefore this body of work focused on the creation of a comprehensive method for optimising dairy farm technology selection, management practices and electricity tariffs. The measures which could be implemented on dairy farms to improve economic performance and reduce environmental impacts were categorised in this study under the headings of efficiency through technology adoption, efficiency through management practices, and reduction in primary energy through renewable generation. To improve efficiency through technology adoption, technologies including plate heat exchangers, variable speed drives, solar thermal water heating and heat recovery systems were considered. To improve efficiency through management practices, load shifting measures were considered. To reduce primary energy through renewable generation, photovoltaic systems and wind turbines were considered. A comprehensive optimisation method was required which took into account all measures and the relationships between them, while the conflicting goals of improving profitability and environmental performance necessitated the use of multi-objective optimisation to assess trade-offs between these goals. Moreover, to facilitate the analysis of efficiency through technology adoption, efficiency through management practices, and reduction in primary energy through Abstract xxi renewable generation, validated scalable models of energy efficient and renewable technologies were created which enabled their effect on dairy farm profitability and environmental performance to be quantified. These models were employed when carrying out multi-objective optimisation to optimise dairy farm technology, management practices and electricity tariffs for maximisation of dairy farm net profit, minimisation of farm electricity related CO2 emissions, maximisation of farm renewable contribution and optimisation of milking start times for farmers. Trade-offs between these objectives were also assessed. A test case of a 195 cow farm was employed to demonstrate the applicability and usefulness of the optimisation platform, with results indicating that farm electricity related CO2 emissions could be reduced by 40%, 3% and 31% through technology adoption, management practices and renewable generation respectively. Furthermore, the use of a plate heat exchanger was the most economically feasible technology of the technologies examined. It is anticipated that the methods presented in this thesis will be used as a comprehensive means of decision support for farm advisors, policymakers and farmers. The outputs of the thesis will enable these key stakeholders to make prudent decisions pertaining to investments in technology and farm management changes, in order to increase farm profitability and contribute to national greenhouse gas mitigation.</description>
      <author>Michael Breen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34719/tcud9414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373364

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non-magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core-shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores' local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells' surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen-containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm-2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376553

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core&#8208;shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores&#8217; local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells&#8217; surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Coupled THM Problem and Wellbore Integrity Analyses with Two-Phase Fluid Flow in Naturally Fractured Reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0123</link>
      <description>Yarlong Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401479268

                ABSTRACT: Multi-phase fluid flow in naturally fractured reservoirs (NFR) is a complex and important process to be studied in energy and environmental industries. Either during CH4/H2/CO2 injection/sequestration or thermal EOR process, both fluid pressure and temperature changes may take place which will lead to significant thermal-hydraulic-mechanical (THM) responses that will impact both safety and efficiency of the project. Simulating THM responses in NFR, Formulation for an implicit pressure and explicit saturation (IMPES+T) finite element approach with an explicit thermal coupling is developed. Different shape functions, i.e. Petrov-Galerkin method, are applied to the saturation, displacement, fluid pressures, and temperature with convective energy transport calculation. In addition, a simplified coupled hydraulic-mechanical (HM) algorithm is proposed for displacement-pressures calculations, which is also coupled to an independently calculated convective-conductive thermal process. The induced pore pressure and critical stresses are highlighted in a dual-porosity medium, evaluating the wellbore integrity during injection and production in naturally fractured formations. A thermally induced tangential stress increase of 1 MPa on the wellbore wall is equivalent to a formation strength reduction of the same magnitude and yet more than 50% increase of the effective tangential stress, the key stress affecting wellbore integrity, at the wellbore wall in the fracture system may be achievable in the naturally fractured media (NFM). 1. INTRODUCTION To simulate multiphase fluid flow, heat transport and skeleton deformation processes in NFR [Bai et al., 1993; Khalili, and Valliappan, 1996; Khalili, 2008], numerical method such finite element method has been applied to approximate solutions of the Thermal-Hydraulic-Mechanical (THM) responses. Isothermal multi-phase fluid flow and non-isothermal single-phase cases are extensively dealt with, respectively [Lewis and Ghafouri, 1997; Nair et al., 2005; Pao and Lewis, 2002; Gelet et al., 2012; Khoei et al., 2016; Arzanfudi and Al-Khoury, 2017]. Simulating CO2 injection, energy enhanced production and geothermal energy extraction processes in a NFR, a fully coupled THM model with multi-phase fluid flow is required and thus developed in this paper.</description>
      <author>Yarlong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biofuels with Carbon Capture and Storage in the United States Transportation Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.167890</link>
      <description>Caleb H. Geissler, Christos T. Maravelias, No host. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401461015

                There is a need to drastically reduce greenhouse gas emissions. While significant progress has been made in electrifying transport, heavy duty transportation and aviation are not likely to be capable of electrification in the near term, spurring significant research into biofuels. When coupled with carbon capture and storage, biofuels can achieve net-negative greenhouse gas emissions via many different conversion technologies such as fermentation, pyrolysis, or gasification to produce ethanol, gasoline, diesel, or jet fuel. However, each pathway has a different efficiency, capital and operating costs, and potential for carbon capture, making the optimal pathway dependent on policy and spatial factors. We use the Integrated Markal-EFOM System model applied to the USA, adding a rich suite of biofuel and carbon capture technologies, region-specific CO2 transportation and injection costs, and government incentives from the Inflation Reduction Act. We find that under current government incentives, biofuels and carbon capture from biorefineries are primarily focused in the Midwest and South of the USA, but play a relatively small role in the overall USA transportation sector even in 2055. However, increased government incentives, biomass availability, or oil price could lead to increased biofuel production and reduced transportation emissions.</description>
      <author>Caleb H. Geissler, Christos T. Maravelias</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.167890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective electroreduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; products on cobalt decorated copper catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.11</link>
      <description>Sanaz Soodi, Junjun Zhang, Jie Zhang, Yuefeng Liu, Mohsen Lashgari, Spyridon Zafeiratos, Andreas Z&#252;ttel, Kun Zhao, Wen Luo, Chemical Synthesis. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373815

                Cu-catalyzed electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to multi-carbon (C2+) products is often plagued by low selectivity because the adsorption energies of different reaction intermediates are in a linear scaling relationship. Development of Cu-based bimetallic catalysts has been considered as an attractive strategy to address this issue; however, conventional bimetallic catalysts often avoid metals with strong CO adsorption energies to prevent surface poisoning. Herein, we demonstrated that limiting the amount of Co in CuCo bimetallic catalysts can enhance C2+ product selectivity. Specifically, we synthesized a series of CuCox catalysts with trace amounts of Co (0.07-1.8 at%) decorated on the surface of Cu nanowires using a simple dip coating method. Our results revealed a volcano-shaped correlation between Co loading and C2+ selectivity, with the CuCo0.4% catalyst exhibiting a 2-fold increase in C2+ selectivity compared to the Cu nanowire sample. In situ Raman and Infrared spectroscopies suggested that an optimal amount of Co could stabilize the Cu oxide/hydroxide species under the CO2RR condition and promote the adsorption of CO, thus enhancing the C2+ selectivity. This work expands the potential for developing Cu-based bimetallic catalysts for CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Sanaz Soodi, Junjun Zhang, Jie Zhang, Yuefeng Liu, Mohsen Lashgari, Spyridon Zafeiratos, Andreas Z&#252;ttel, Kun Zhao, Wen Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Role of Lithium Carbonate at Lithium Metal Anodes Through Study of Gas-Reacted Interphases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6d92</link>
      <description>Katherine Steinberg, Betar M. Gallant, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401447826

                Abstract A stable, ionically-conductive solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) is vital to lithium (Li) metal anodes, yet key properties of common SEI phases remain unknown. Among these, Li2CO3, central to foundational SEI models, has been difficult to probe given its metastability on Li. To address this, we adopted two approaches: (i) synthesis and study of model Li2CO3-based SEI and (ii) cycling and titration-based analysis of SEI from Li&#8211;Cu cells with or without additive CO2, with the aim of modulating Li2CO3 content natively. In (i), reductive instability of Li2CO3 led to co-formation of Li2O and Li2C2 in a multiphasic film with a Li+ conductivity (~8&#215;10-9 S cm-1) more than 4x higher than previously measured Li2O or LiF films. Li2CO3 content in native interphases from (ii) was found to correlate with decreased inactive Li0 accumulation and improved Coulombic efficiency (CE) across diverse electrolytes having moderate CE. In high CE electrolytes, however, capacity losses become dominated by SEI formation rather than inactive Li0, and Li2CO3 enrichment had negligible impact. This work updates understanding of Li2CO3 in modern electrolytes, reveals a leading mechanism by which Li2CO3 can boost CE despite its metastability, and indicates the potential and limitations of enriching this phase through electrolyte design.</description>
      <author>Katherine Steinberg, Betar M. Gallant</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6d92</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valorizing Polymeric Wastes and Biomass through Optimized Co-Pyrolysis for Upgraded Pyrolysis Oil: A study on TG-FTIR and Fixed bed reactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106686</link>
      <description>Gulzeb Rajput, Bin Liu, Minhui Pan, Akash Kumar, Lata Kumari, Muhammad Zohaib Farooq, Dan Li, Fawei Lin, Longlong Ma, Journal of Analytical and Applied Pyrolysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401362519

                The co-pyrolysis of biomass and polymeric wastes offers a promising approach for waste reduction and valuable product recovery while decreasing fossil fuel dependence. This study aimed to investigate the synergistic effects of blending waste tire (WT) or polystyrene (PS) with sawdust (SD) at varying effective hydrogen/carbon ratio (H/Ceff) on liquid product distribution. Thermal degradation behavior was analyzed using TGA-FTIR, followed by fixed-bed reactor pyrolysis experiments at different temperatures. The devolatilization of SD primarily occurred between 185 and 390&#176;C, while WT and PS decomposed between 250-500&#176;C and 350-460&#176;C, respectively. Results showed that SD addition to WT accelerated degradation at lower temperatures. Optimal H/Ceff ratios were 0.42 for WT/SD and 0.64 for PS/SD blends at 500&#176;C, maximizing valued hydrocarbons, reducing pollutants, and yielding the highest liquid fraction. TGA-FTIR analysis revealed the presence of various functional groups, including C-H, C=C, CO2, and O-H. The pyrolytic oil showed improved stability with significantly fewer undesired compounds. This research provides theoretical and practical insights into the control and application potential as well as the limitations of high-value energy products derived from the co-pyrolysis of SD, WT, and PS.</description>
      <author>Gulzeb Rajput, Bin Liu, Minhui Pan, Akash Kumar, Lata Kumari, Muhammad Zohaib Farooq, Dan Li, Fawei Lin, Longlong Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano Technolgy Application to Enhance the Emission Control by Using Activated Carbons Modified by Magnesium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52783/jes.4547</link>
      <description>Khalid Hussein Rahi, Deleted Journal. 20(9s)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401397413

                One of the fundamental processes for planet safety is the catalytic conversion of carbon monoxide (CO). CO has even been named one of the unseen toxins of this century. Inhaling CO can lead to hypoxic damage, neurological break, and even death. CO poisoning decays greenery life and accumulations in global warming and ozone layer depletion. CO is created in the atmosphere by the partial oxidation of carbon-containing mixtures. The primary origin of CO emissions is vehicles. Therefore, oxidizing contaminated CO to nonpoisonous CO2 under ambient conditions is essential for life protection in multiple applications. Additionally, low-temperature CO oxidation is crucial in reducing emissions at the cold start of an internal explosion in the engine. For controlling pollution, the available methods are pre-pollution control and post-pollution. This project depends on the post-pollution control method in Peugeot ROA automobiles using Activated Carbons Modified by Magnesium Oxide as a catalyst. An innovative catalytic converter design activated carbons modified by magnesium oxide nanoparticles as a catalyst to control pollution with different NPs lodgings and carbon structures. This proposed method aims for the reduction environmental pollution contributed by automobiles. It involves using more affordable materials than the existing rhodium nanoparticles, platinum, and palladium technique. The dispersion states of the grafted nanoparticles were examined with scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and X-ray diffraction analysis (XRD), confirming the correlation between high grafted ratio states and improved properties. The nanocomposites' desired properties were significantly enhanced when the graft density was high.</description>
      <author>Khalid Hussein Rahi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52783/jes.4547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GHG Policies in Maritime Transport: A Comparative Analysis using Cost-Effectiveness and Multi-Criteria Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4855186/v1</link>
      <description>R. Garcia, Cristiane Elia de Marsillac, Paula Carvalho Pereda, Andrea Lucchesi, Jean-David Caprace, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401407908

                Abstract Maritime transport accounts for approximately 3% of global greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions with the sector aiming to achieve net zero by or around i.e. close 2050. There has been intense debate on medium-term measures that combine regulatory frameworks with financial incentives or economic penalties. Among the main proposals under discussion are a GHG levy, two flexible mechanisms (FCMs) based on the GHG Fuel Intensity (GFI) and a feebate. Despite extensive discussions on carbon levies, there is a notable lack of studies comparing the cost-effectiveness of these different GHG reduction measures in the maritime sector. This study aims to fill this gap by developing a comprehensive methodology to evaluate and compare these GHG policies. Using cost-effectiveness and multi-criterion decision analysis (MCDA), the study assesses the technical feasibility, economic implications, and environmental benefits of the proposed measures. The main quantitative results reveal that a GHG levy starting at $100 per ton of CO2 doubles fuel costs, while new fuels become economically attractive only after 2040 under the feebate mechanism. Both original and revised FCM proposals show similar cost patterns, with the revised FCM leading to earlier adoption of new fuels. We find that the FCMs and the carbon levy are effective in achieving the IMO's final and intermediate targets. However, FCMs are the most cost-effective proposals, achieving targets with the lowest present value of costs and the cost per avoided GHG emissions. The proposed methodology provides a robust framework for facilitating objective and structured discussions with stakeholders, helping to balance economic and environmental goals in maritime policymaking.</description>
      <author>R. Garcia, Cristiane Elia de Marsillac, Paula Carvalho Pereda, Andrea Lucchesi, Jean-David Caprace</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4855186/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geomechanical Lessons from Oil and Gas Produced Water Injection Towards Subsurface Carbon Dioxide Sequestration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1043</link>
      <description>G. Ramos, John McLennan, Ion Ispas, S&#237;dney Green, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480262

                ABSTRACT: The petroleum sector, with its competencies in water flooding and produced-water re-injection (PWRI), provides complementary technologies for carbon capture and sequestration (CCS). Our objective is to identify oil &amp; gas technologies and procedures that would be beneficial to future CCS implementations. We reviewed PWRI operations in 3 major petroleum basins. We then compared their geological and geomechanical settings, PWRI data, and induced seismicity. The most prominent impact is induced seismicity, as others have shown, the cause being the increase of pore pressure in faults. Contributing causes of rock failure and pressure communication are perturbation of the in-situ stresses, water-induced weakening, static creep, and fatigue-induced weakening. Measures for effective risk reduction are volume/pressure management, well placement, managed pumping schedules, high-resolution reservoir description, frequent monitoring coupled with laboratory programs, and strain-coupled reservoir simulation. We recommend adopting these practices learned from water-flood oil-gas operations. These would help promote gradual ramping of the reservoir pressure, a uniform CO2 flooding front, flooding profile control, and most importantly, rock stability. 1. INTRODUCTION With growing public interest and government incentives for carbon capture, the oil and gas sectors are uniquely positioned in future implementation of large-scale carbon capture and sequestration as supercritical CO2 (sCO2 or "CCS"). The industry's experience, personnel, infrastructure, and core competencies in deep subsurface operations can immediately provide complementary technologies for subsurface Carbon Sequestration (CS). As geo-engineers/scientists in the upstream petroleum sector, we offer practical lessons from our experience in large-scale water floods and Produced Water Re-Injection (PWRI), also called Salt Water Disposal (SWD). The multimillion-barrel daily produced water disposal operations in Texas and Oklahoma are very relevant to future high-tonnage injection of sCO2. The most prominent adverse impact is induced seismicity, because of its impact on structures and the general public. Another unfavorable effect is the contamination of freshwater aquifers. Lesser known and poorly understood effects are induced microseismicity, surface heave, loss of injectivity, and overestimation of reservoir capacity. All of these arise from combinations of factors such as: pore pressure rise, proximity to unmapped structures, perturbation of in-situ stresses leading to rock failure, injection fluids' geochemical effects, induced fatigue from pumping schedules, concentration of pressurized zones/bulbs, and perturbation of pre-existing geologic creep rate. This paper provides an overview of PWRI operations in 3 major oil and gas (O/G) fields in Texas and Oklahoma, and how seismicity may have developed. We identified other geomechanical processes that contribute to rock weakening and debilitation of rock interfaces.</description>
      <author>G. Ramos, John McLennan, Ion Ispas, S&#237;dney Green</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-1043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Impact of CO2 on Calcium SulphoAluminate (CSA) Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14082462</link>
      <description>Daniel D. Akerele, Federico Aguayo, Buildings. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401484366

                The construction industry is a significant contributor to global CO2 emissions, primarily due to the extensive use of ordinary portland cement (OPC). In response to the urgent need for sustainable construction materials, calcium sulphoaluminate (CSA) cement has emerged as a promising alternative. CSA cement is renowned for its low carbon footprint, high early-age strength, and superior durability, making it an attractive option for reducing the environmental impact of construction activities. While CSA cement offers benefits in carbon emissions reduction, its susceptibility to carbonation presents challenges. Although the body of literature on CSA cement is rapidly expanding, its adoption rate remains low. This disparity may be attributed to several factors including the level of scientific contribution in terms of research focus and lack of comprehensive standards for various applications. As a result, the present study sets out to track the research trajectory within the CSA cement research landscape through a systematic literature review. The study employed the Prefer Reporting Item for Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis (PRISMA) framework to conduct a literature search on three prominent databases, and a thematic analysis was conducted to identify the knowledge gap for future exploration. The study revealed that while CSA concrete demonstrates superior early-age strength and environmental resistance, its susceptibility to carbonation can compromise structural integrity over time. Key mitigation strategies identified include the incorporation of supplementary cementitious materials (SCMs), use of corrosion inhibitors, and optimization of mix designs. The review also highlights the global distribution of research, with notable contributions from the USA, China, and Europe, emphasizing the collaborative effort in advancing CSA concrete technology. The findings are crucial for enhancing sustainability and durability in the construction sector and advancing CSA binders as a sustainable alternative to traditional cement.</description>
      <author>Daniel D. Akerele, Federico Aguayo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14082462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential For Ch4-enriched Biogas As A Transport Fuel In Ireland</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34719/vrkk7758</link>
      <description>Niamh Power, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401364246

                "Ireland needs a biofuel industry- to aid compliance with the Kyoto Protocol, the Biofuels Directive and to secure its energ&gt;' supply. The overall aim of this work is to assess the potential of CH4-enriched biogas as a transport fuel in Ireland. Biogas is produced during the anaerobic digestion of biomass. This work investigates biogas production from two different feedstocks; biodegradable municipal waste and agricultural crops. To assess the potential for biogas as a transport fuel the alternatives to biogas are investigated and compared. Thus digestion and composting of biodegradable municipal waste, and biogas and ethanol production from agricultural crops arc investigated on a technical, economic and environmental basis. Ireland is facing a waste crisis; municipal waste production has grown at a significant rate over the last number of years; to compound this problem the Landfill Directive requires a reduction in the quantity of biodegradable municipal waste consigned to landfill. This thesis compares composting to anaerobic digestion with biogas utilisation as a transport fuel. The composting model is based on two weeks in-vessel composting followed by eight to ten weeks aerated static pile composting. The anaerobic digestion model is based on a dry digestion process, followed by water absorption for biogas upgrading, and biogas compression. At present biogas is not subjected to excise duty; if this situation remains then biogas is economically preferable to composting when treating more than 18,000 t/a (which equates to the waste produced by 80,000 people). However, if excise duty were applied to biogas, then composting is economically preferable when treating less than 48,000 t/a. The area of land that is available for energy crops was examined. Crops for energy production can be grown on set-aside land and land previously under sugar beet without affecting food production. Currently there are three main crops in Ireland; wheat, barley and sugar beet. Biogas production from these crops is investigated for various rotations, however in addition to biogas these crops can also be used for ethanol production. Thus biogas from these crops is in direct competition with ethanol; consequently biogas and ethanol are compared. On a technical basis it was found that biogas produces more energy per hectare than ethanol. It was also found that a crop rotation of wheat, wheat and sugar beet is preferable in terms of energy production for both biogas and ethanol production. On an economic basis, biogas is preferable to ethanol when compared per unit of energy&#8217;. On an environmental basis ethanol saves more CO2 than biogas; this is due to present documented levels of leakage of methane at the biogas facilities. If biogas losses were reduced to between 3.4-4.4% then biogas saves more CO2 than ethanol. Overall this work shows that biogas from biodegradable municipal waste and agricultural crops on 48,000 ha of land previously under sugar beet and set aside can replace up to 3.3% of petroleum fuels in 2010. Biogas on its own will not enable Ireland to comply with the Biofuels Directive but can aid Ireland if used in a combined approach with other renew able fuels and biogas from different sources."</description>
      <author>Niamh Power</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34719/vrkk7758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluid Flow in a Fracture Network Under Changing Stresses: A Laboratory Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0170</link>
      <description>Zili Mei, Wei Li, Wencheng Jin, Ghanashyam Neupane, Trevor A. Atkinson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480268

                ABSTRACT: Fluid flow in fractured rocks is ubiquitous in natural and human-induced subsurface processes. Subsurface technologies, such as in-situ mining, CO2 storage and geothermal exploitations, require large contact areas between the flowing fluid and the rock to facilitate efficient heat and mass transport and, therefore, ensure the effectiveness of these technologies. Much of the experimental research on fluid flow in fractures has focused on a single fractures in a rock specimen, which leaves the fluid flow in fracture networks under changing stresses largely unexplored. Here, we study fluid flow in a fracture network under changing stresses using a triaxial system. We create the fracture network composed of five orthogonal fractures in rock specimens by assembling six saw-cut rock parts. We measure the overall permeability of the fracture networks under changing vertical and horizontal stresses. We find that the fracture network permeability decreases when the vertical and horizontal stresses both increase. A greater reduction of permeability is observed with increasing horizontal stress than that with increasing vertical stress. We show that this phenomenon results from the larger total area of the vertical fractures than that of the horizontal fractures, making the fracture network more sensitive to horizontal stress changes. Our study shows the importance of the relative orientations between the fractures and the stresses in determining the permeability of the fracture network. This insight can be incorporated to improve the discrete and continuum modeling of fracture networks. 1 INTRODUCTION Fracture networks are the "highways" for the fluid flow in subsurface rock-fluid systems. They provide a fast path for contaminant transport in fractured aquifers (Tsang and Tsang, 1987; Grisak and Pickens, 1980; Grisak et al., 1980). They could increase the permeability of a geothermal reservoir and, at the same time, reduce the heat extraction efficiency by inducing short-circuiting (Gee et al., 2021). They can also localize the dissolution of porous rocks to the fracture along and induce larger cavities earlier (Li et al., 2021). The overall permeability of a fracture network is affected by the fracture orientation, stress conditions, and fluid pressure. Understanding and predicting the the fracture network permeability as the stresses and pore pressure changes are important for many engineering applications in the subsurface rock-fluid systems.</description>
      <author>Zili Mei, Wei Li, Wencheng Jin, Ghanashyam Neupane, Trevor A. Atkinson</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Company Valuation Before and After IPO Study Case PT Pertamina Geothermal Energy Tbk</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47191/ijcsrr/v7-i8-21</link>
      <description>Anita Nur Afidah, Ana Noveria, Subiakto Subiakto, International Journal of Current Science Research and Review. 07(08)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401400980

                Affordable energy resources of energy play a crucial role in economic and social development to support food production, availability of water supply and sustainable healty lifestyle. In order to avoid long-term scarcity resulting from the continuous use of non-renewable energy sources, we must explore all potential renewable energy source that align with concernes about climate change and other environmental issues. As a continuation of the Indonesian government&#8217;s efforts to generate clean and environmental friendly energy, PT Pertamina Geothermal Energy (PGE) was established in 2006. It has contributed 82% of the installed geothermal energy capacity in Indonesia. By leveraging Indonesia&#8217;s location within the Ring of Fire as one of the world&#8217;s geothermal energy hubs, PGE has been supplying electricity to more than 2 million households in Indonesia with a potential emission reduction of 9.7 million tons of CO2 per year. To achieve sustainable business growth, PGEO is optimizing production in its operational areas by expanding installed capacity. In the company consideration, IPO is an appropriate step to financing the expansion. The author compares the company&#8217;s value before and after the IPO to determine the short-term impact of the IPO, helping investors gauge their confidence in making investment decisions in PGEO. This study utilizes secondary data from prospectuses, financial statements, annual reports, sustainability reports, company-published documents, as well as data from IDX.co.id and IDN Financials.com. The data was collected and analyzed to understand evaluate financial performance, and assess the company&#8217;s value before and after the IPO. The calculation of the company&#8217;s intrinsic value is conducted using the Discounted Cash Flow Valuation method for the pre-IPO period against the company&#8217;s financial projections for the years 2019 to 2022 and for the post-IPO period against the company&#8217;s financial projections for the years 2024 to 2028, using discount rates of 8.25% and 8.65% for each. In resulting the intrinsic value pre-IPO is IDR 1.141,28 and the intrinsic value post-IPO is IDR 1.300,86. The stock price of PGEO at its IPO on February 23, 2023, was IDR 875, while the adjusted closing price on December 29, 2023, was IDR 1,170. This study founds that the market price of PGEO&#8217;s stock, both before and after the IPO, are overvalued.</description>
      <author>Anita Nur Afidah, Ana Noveria, Subiakto Subiakto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47191/ijcsrr/v7-i8-21</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of mediterranean diet promotion on environmental sustainability: a longitudinal analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32920/26528053</link>
      <description>Laura &#193;lvarez&#8208;&#193;lvarez, Facundo Vitelli&#8208;Storelli, Mar&#237;a Rub&#237;n&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Silvia Garc&#237;a, Cristina Bouzas, Miguel Ruiz&#8208;Canela, Dolores Corella, Jordi Salas&#8208;Salvad&#243;, Montserrat Fit&#243;, J. Alfredo Mart&#237;n&#233;z, Lucas Tojal&#8208;Sierra, Julia W&#228;rnberg, Jes&#250;s Vioqu&#233;, Dora Romaguera, Jos&#233; L&#243;pez&#8208;Miranda, Ram&#243;n Estruch, Francisco J. Tinahones, Manuel Ortega&#8208;Calvo, Llu&#237;s Serra&#8208;Majem, Aurora Bueno&#8208;Cavanillas, Cristina Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Virginia Esteve-Luque, Miguel Delgado-Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Macarena Torrego-Ellacur&#237;a, Josep Vidal, Lu&#237;s Prieto, Lidia Daimiel, Rosa Casas, Ana Garc&#237;a&#8208;Arellano, Sangeetha Shyam, Jos&#233; I. Gonz&#225;lez, Olga Casta&#241;er, Antonio Garc&#237;a&#8208;R&#237;os, Fran&#231;ois D&#237;az, Antonio Castro Fern&#225;ndez, Almudena S&#225;nchez&#8208;Villegas, Marga Morey, Naomi Cano&#8208;Ib&#225;&#241;ez, Carolina Sorto-S&#225;nchez, M. Rosa Bernal&#8208;L&#243;pez, Maira Bes&#8208;Rastrollo, Stephanie Nishi, &#211;scar Coltell, Mar&#237;a Dolores Zome&#241;o, Patricia J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Orihuela, D.V. Aparicio, M. &#193;ngeles Zulet, Zenaida V&#225;zquez&#8208;Ruiz, Nancy Babi&#243;, K.A. P&#233;rez, Josep A. Tur, Vicente Mart&#237;n, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401455005

                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This article aims to estimate the differences in environmental impact (greenhouse gas [GHG] emissions, land use, energy used, acidification and potential eutrophication) after one year of promoting a Mediterranean diet (MD).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Baseline and 1-year follow-up data from 5800 participants in the PREDIMED-Plus study were used. Each participant's food intake was estimated using validated semi-quantitative food frequency questionnaires, and the adherence to MD using the Dietary Score. The influence of diet on environmental impact was assessed through the EAT-Lancet Commission tables. The influence of diet on environmental impact was assessed through the EAT-Lancet Commission tables. The association between MD adherence and its environmental impact was calculated using adjusted multivariate linear regression models.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After one year of intervention, the kcal/day consumed was significantly reduced (&#8722;125,1 kcal/day), adherence to a MD pattern was improved (+0,9) and the environmental impact due to the diet was significantly reduced (GHG: &#8722;361 g/CO2-eq; Acidification:-11,5 g SO2-eq; Eutrophication:-4,7 g PO4-eq; Energy use:-842,7 kJ; and Land use:-2,2 m2). Higher adherence to MD (high vs. low) was significantly associated with lower environmental impact both at baseline and one year follow-up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meat products had the greatest environmental impact in all the factors analysed, both at baseline and at one-year follow-up, in spite of the reduction observed in their consumption.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A program promoting a MD, after one year of intervention, significantly reduced the environmental impact in all the factors analysed. Meat products had the greatest environmental impact in all the dimensions analysed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Laura &#193;lvarez&#8208;&#193;lvarez, Facundo Vitelli&#8208;Storelli, Mar&#237;a Rub&#237;n&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Silvia Garc&#237;a, Cristina Bouzas, Miguel Ruiz&#8208;Canela, Dolores Corella, Jordi Salas&#8208;Salvad&#243;, Montserrat Fit&#243;, J. Alfredo Mart&#237;n&#233;z, Lucas Tojal&#8208;Sierra, Julia W&#228;rnberg, Jes&#250;s Vioqu&#233;, Dora Romaguera, Jos&#233; L&#243;pez&#8208;Miranda, Ram&#243;n Estruch, Francisco J. Tinahones, Manuel Ortega&#8208;Calvo, Llu&#237;s Serra&#8208;Majem, Aurora Bueno&#8208;Cavanillas, Cristina Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Virginia Esteve-Luque, Miguel Delgado-Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Macarena Torrego-Ellacur&#237;a, Josep Vidal, Lu&#237;s Prieto, Lidia Daimiel, Rosa Casas, Ana Garc&#237;a&#8208;Arellano, Sangeetha Shyam, Jos&#233; I. Gonz&#225;lez, Olga Casta&#241;er, Antonio Garc&#237;a&#8208;R&#237;os, Fran&#231;ois D&#237;az, Antonio Castro Fern&#225;ndez, Almudena S&#225;nchez&#8208;Villegas, Marga Morey, Naomi Cano&#8208;Ib&#225;&#241;ez, Carolina Sorto-S&#225;nchez, M. Rosa Bernal&#8208;L&#243;pez, Maira Bes&#8208;Rastrollo, Stephanie Nishi, &#211;scar Coltell, Mar&#237;a Dolores Zome&#241;o, Patricia J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Orihuela, D.V. Aparicio, M. &#193;ngeles Zulet, Zenaida V&#225;zquez&#8208;Ruiz, Nancy Babi&#243;, K.A. P&#233;rez, Josep A. Tur, Vicente Mart&#237;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32920/26528053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEMAKAIAN GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEM UNTUK PEMETAAN EMISI GAS RUMAH KACA SEKTOR LIMBAH DI KABUPATEN KARANGASEM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36002/jutik.v6i3.1307</link>
      <description>Affan Irfan Fauziawan, I Made Agus Wirahadi Putra, Ratna Kartika Wiyati, Jurnal Teknologi Informasi dan Komputer. 6(3)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4401494427

                ABSTRACTWaste production increases with the increase in population, urbanization rate and people&#8217;s income. Solid waste is a contributor to greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions which can cause global warming. At the Conference of Parties 25 (COP 25) in Madrid 2019, the Indonesian government is still commited to reducing GHG emissions and working to reduce/limit the increase in temperature below 1.50C. Karangasem regency is an area located in the eastern part of Bali Island, which administratively is one of the regency in Bali Province. The population of Karangasem regency in 2018 based on results of population registration was 414,800 people. The population is spread across 8 sub-districs with the population growth rate in Karangasem averaging 0.88% per year. The distribution of the population will be directly proportional to the distribution of solid waste produced. The method for calculating municipal solid waste will be carried out using the First Order Decay method contained in the IPCC (Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change) Guidelines. From the calculation results, GHG emission have been obtained in each sub-district in Karangasem regency. Total GHG emission in 2019 amounted to 11,764 tonnes of CO2-e. Mapping the area in Karangasem district to determine the amount of waste produced by each district is deemed necessary as a mitigation effort to be implemented. In this study, a mapping of each sub-district was carried out on the basis of Geographical Information System (GIS). It is necessary to carry out a GHG inventory at the district level, to determine how much GHG emission are generated from the waste sector. After the GHG emission in known, a mapping of each sub-district will be made to determine the level of emission produced, so that this GHG emission reduction mitigation action will focus more on the sub-districts that produce the most emission first followed by other sub-districts.Keywords: Waste, GHG Inventory, First Order Decay, Geographic Information System.ABSTRAKProduksi limbah meningkat seiring dengan meningkatnya jumlah penduduk, tingkat urbanisasi dan pendapatan masyarakat. Sampah merupakan salah satu penyumbang emisi gas rumah kaca (GRK) yang dapat menyebabkan adanya pemanasan global (global warming). Pada Conference of Parties 25 (COP 25) di Madrid tahun 2019, pemerintah Indonesia masih berkomitmen untuk dapat menurunkan emisi gas rumah kaca dan berupaya untuk mengurangi/membatasi peningkatan suhu dibawah 1,50C. Kabupaten Karangasem, merupakan daerah yang berada di belahan timur Pulau Bali, yang secara administratif merupakan salah satu kabupaten dalam wilayah Provinsi Bali. Jumlah penduduk Kabupaten Karangasem pada tahun 2018 berdasarkan hasil registrasi penduduk adalah 414.800 jiwa. Jumlah penduduk tersebut tersebar dalam 8 kecamatan dengan angka pertambahan penduduk di Karangasem rata-rata 0,88% per tahun. Sebaran jumlah penduduk akan berbanding lurus dengan sebaran limbah padat yang dihasilkan. Metode penghitungan limbah padat kota akan dilakukan dengan menggunakan metode First Order Decay yang terdapat pada IPCC (Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change) Guidelines. Dari hasil perhitungan telah didapatkan emisi GRK di tiap-tiap kecamatan yang ada di Kabupaten Karangasem. Total emisi GRK pada tahun 2019 yaitu sebesar 11.764 ton CO2-e. Pemetaan wilayah di kabupaten392 Jurnal Teknologi Informasi dan Komputer, Volume 6, Nomor 3, Oktober 2020Karangasem untuk mengetahui jumlah sampah yang dihasilkan tiap kecamatan dipandang perlu dilaksanakan sebagai upaya mitigasi yang akan dilaksanakan. Pada penelitian ini dilaksanakan pemetaan tiap-tiap kecamatan dengan basis Sistem Informasi Geografis (SIG). Inventarisasi GRK di tingkat kabupaten ini perlu dilakukan, untuk mengetahui sampai berapa besar emisi GRK yang dihasilkan dari sektor limbah tersebut. Setelah emisi GRK sudah diketahui, maka akan dibuat sebuah pemetaan tiap-tiap kecamatan untuk mengetahui tingkat emisi yang dihasilkan, sehingga aksi mitigasi penurunan emisi GRK ini akan lebih fokus pada kecamatan-kecamatan yang menghasilkan emisi paling besar terlebih dahulu dilanjutkan dengan kecamatan yang lainnya.Kata Kunci : Limbah, Inventarisasi GRK, First Order Decay, Sistem Informasi Geografis.</description>
      <author>Affan Irfan Fauziawan, I Made Agus Wirahadi Putra, Ratna Kartika Wiyati</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36002/jutik.v6i3.1307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of the Reservoir Stress Path During Depletion and Re-Inflation and its Implications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0272</link>
      <description>Puneet Seth, Duane Mikulencak, Ronny Hofmann, J. W. Dudley, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401479572

                ABSTRACT: Several researchers have studied the impact of reservoir depletion on rock mechanical behavior and associated changes in in-situ stresses and reservoir depletion stress path. However, the evolution of the reservoir stress path (ratio of change in minimum horizontal stress with reservoir pressure change) due to re-inflation of the reservoir during injection operations such as waterflooding is less understood. In this work, a more fundamental approach to the evolution of the reservoir stress path under both depletion and re-inflation is studied through core plug uniaxial-strain experiments and field-scale numerical modeling which includes the impact of plastic deformation. Both unconsolidated and consolidated sandstones are considered. Results from the uniaxial-strain compaction experiments agree with findings from 3-D field scale numerical modeling that the injection stress path coefficient &#947;h,i = &#916;&#963;h/&#916;Pinj is either similar or greater than the depletion stress path coefficient &#947;h,d = &#916;&#963;h/&#916;Pdep. The findings in this study have significant implications for waterflooding operations, infill drilling window estimation for re-inflated reservoirs, and CO2 capture and storage operations (CCS). The assumptions on &#947;h,i directly impact the allowable injection pressure, injection rate, and storage capacity for CCS projects. Hence a more thorough understanding could prevent overly conservative designs and promote a more accurate screening of potential waterflooding, infill drilling, and CCS projects. 1. INTRODUCTION The reservoir minimum horizontal stress path is the ratio of change in total minimum horizontal stress, &#916;&#963;h to change in reservoir pressure, &#916;P: (equation) It is crucial to understand the anticipated minimum horizontal stress changes in a reservoir during long-term production and during injection operations such as waterflooding because &#963;h is closely related to hydraulic fracturing in a normal stress environment. When describing the reduction in &#963;h from depletion, the stress path coefficient is defined as &#947;h,d. When describing the increase in &#963;h from re-inflation, the stress path coefficient is defined as &#947;h,i. The &#916;'s in these definitions are defined to always give positive values of &#947;h,d or &#947;h,i. The assumptions on &#947;h,i (injection stress path coefficient) could impact the allowable injection pressure, injection rate, and storage capacity for waterflooding &amp; CCS projects and a more thorough understanding could prevent overly conservative designs.</description>
      <author>Puneet Seth, Duane Mikulencak, Ronny Hofmann, J. W. Dudley</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of mediterranean diet promotion on environmental sustainability: a longitudinal analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32920/26528053.v1</link>
      <description>Laura &#193;lvarez&#8208;&#193;lvarez, Facundo Vitelli&#8208;Storelli, Mar&#237;a Rub&#237;n&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Silvia Garc&#237;a, Cristina Bouzas, Miguel Ruiz&#8208;Canela, Dolores Corella, Jordi Salas&#8208;Salvad&#243;, Montserrat Fit&#243;, J. Alfredo Mart&#237;n&#233;z, Lucas Tojal&#8208;Sierra, Julia W&#228;rnberg, Jes&#250;s Vioqu&#233;, Dora Romaguera, Jos&#233; L&#243;pez&#8208;Miranda, Ram&#243;n Estruch, Francisco J. Tinahones, Manuel Ortega&#8208;Calvo, Llu&#237;s Serra&#8208;Majem, Aurora Bueno&#8208;Cavanillas, Cristina Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Virginia Esteve-Luque, Miguel Delgado-Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Macarena Torrego-Ellacur&#237;a, Josep Vidal, Lu&#237;s Prieto, Lidia Daimiel, Rosa Casas, Ana Garc&#237;a&#8208;Arellano, Sangeetha Shyam, Jos&#233; I. Gonz&#225;lez, Olga Casta&#241;er, Antonio Garc&#237;a&#8208;R&#237;os, Fran&#231;ois D&#237;az, Antonio Castro Fern&#225;ndez, Almudena S&#225;nchez&#8208;Villegas, Marga Morey, Naomi Cano&#8208;Ib&#225;&#241;ez, Carolina Sorto-S&#225;nchez, M. Rosa Bernal&#8208;L&#243;pez, Maira Bes&#8208;Rastrollo, Stephanie Nishi, &#211;scar Coltell, Mar&#237;a Dolores Zome&#241;o, Patricia J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Orihuela, D.V. Aparicio, M. &#193;ngeles Zulet, Zenaida V&#225;zquez&#8208;Ruiz, Nancy Babi&#243;, K.A. P&#233;rez, Josep A. Tur, Vicente Mart&#237;n, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401476329

                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This article aims to estimate the differences in environmental impact (greenhouse gas [GHG] emissions, land use, energy used, acidification and potential eutrophication) after one year of promoting a Mediterranean diet (MD).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Baseline and 1-year follow-up data from 5800 participants in the PREDIMED-Plus study were used. Each participant's food intake was estimated using validated semi-quantitative food frequency questionnaires, and the adherence to MD using the Dietary Score. The influence of diet on environmental impact was assessed through the EAT-Lancet Commission tables. The influence of diet on environmental impact was assessed through the EAT-Lancet Commission tables. The association between MD adherence and its environmental impact was calculated using adjusted multivariate linear regression models.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After one year of intervention, the kcal/day consumed was significantly reduced (&#8722;125,1 kcal/day), adherence to a MD pattern was improved (+0,9) and the environmental impact due to the diet was significantly reduced (GHG: &#8722;361 g/CO2-eq; Acidification:-11,5 g SO2-eq; Eutrophication:-4,7 g PO4-eq; Energy use:-842,7 kJ; and Land use:-2,2 m2). Higher adherence to MD (high vs. low) was significantly associated with lower environmental impact both at baseline and one year follow-up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meat products had the greatest environmental impact in all the factors analysed, both at baseline and at one-year follow-up, in spite of the reduction observed in their consumption.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A program promoting a MD, after one year of intervention, significantly reduced the environmental impact in all the factors analysed. Meat products had the greatest environmental impact in all the dimensions analysed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Laura &#193;lvarez&#8208;&#193;lvarez, Facundo Vitelli&#8208;Storelli, Mar&#237;a Rub&#237;n&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Silvia Garc&#237;a, Cristina Bouzas, Miguel Ruiz&#8208;Canela, Dolores Corella, Jordi Salas&#8208;Salvad&#243;, Montserrat Fit&#243;, J. Alfredo Mart&#237;n&#233;z, Lucas Tojal&#8208;Sierra, Julia W&#228;rnberg, Jes&#250;s Vioqu&#233;, Dora Romaguera, Jos&#233; L&#243;pez&#8208;Miranda, Ram&#243;n Estruch, Francisco J. Tinahones, Manuel Ortega&#8208;Calvo, Llu&#237;s Serra&#8208;Majem, Aurora Bueno&#8208;Cavanillas, Cristina Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Virginia Esteve-Luque, Miguel Delgado-Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Macarena Torrego-Ellacur&#237;a, Josep Vidal, Lu&#237;s Prieto, Lidia Daimiel, Rosa Casas, Ana Garc&#237;a&#8208;Arellano, Sangeetha Shyam, Jos&#233; I. Gonz&#225;lez, Olga Casta&#241;er, Antonio Garc&#237;a&#8208;R&#237;os, Fran&#231;ois D&#237;az, Antonio Castro Fern&#225;ndez, Almudena S&#225;nchez&#8208;Villegas, Marga Morey, Naomi Cano&#8208;Ib&#225;&#241;ez, Carolina Sorto-S&#225;nchez, M. Rosa Bernal&#8208;L&#243;pez, Maira Bes&#8208;Rastrollo, Stephanie Nishi, &#211;scar Coltell, Mar&#237;a Dolores Zome&#241;o, Patricia J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Orihuela, D.V. Aparicio, M. &#193;ngeles Zulet, Zenaida V&#225;zquez&#8208;Ruiz, Nancy Babi&#243;, K.A. P&#233;rez, Josep A. Tur, Vicente Mart&#237;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32920/26528053.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluid Injection-Rate Controls on Seismic Moment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0686</link>
      <description>M. Roseboom, Agathe M. Eijsink, D. Elsworth, Jianjun Yu, C. Marone, Jacques Rivi&#232;re, Parisa Shokouhi, John Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480396

                ABSTRACT: Fluid-induced shear reactivation of pre-stressed faults poses a project terminating risk during reservoir stimulation in geothermal, CO2 sequestration, wastewater disposal injection and hydraulic fracturing operations. Micro-earthquakes (MEQs) can be tolerated but fluid injection is capable of triggering large earthquakes that can cause major damage to surface infrastructure. Understanding the linkage between fluid-injection volume or injection rate and seismic moment is essential in safeguarding such infrastructure. We report shear experiments that specifically explore the link between fluid-injection rate and seismic moment resulting from shear reactivation of laboratory faults. Experiments are performed on granitoid cores from the UtahFORGE EGS demonstration site containing a single inclined fracture and with small-scale roughness added to the fracture surface. We inject fluids into the fracture and measure the resulting slip and drop in frictional shear stress. We record reactivation and pressure distributions over a range of fluid injection rates. Along-fault pressure distributions are progressively less-uniform as injection rates increase representing a switch from steady-state to transient conditions. Triggered shear displacement is used as a proxy for seismic moment and is indexed against cumulative injection volume and rate. Preliminary results suggest that seismic moment and injection volume increase with increased fluid-injection rates. 1. INTRODUCTION Anthropogenic induced seismicity typically stems from industrial operations in energy developments such as engineered geothermal systems and shale gas recovery as well as in carbon sequestration and wastewater disposal. Fluid injection associated with these activities is known to alter the state of stress in subsurface formations due to the increase in pore pressure and reduction in fault shear strength, sometimes inducing earthquakes in critically-stressed faults (Nicholson and Wesson, 1990; McGarr et al., 2002; Evans et al., 2012; Ellsworth, 2013). In particular, triggered and induced seismic events have terminated geothermal projects in Basel, Switzerland in 2006 and Pohang, South Korea in 2017 (Giardini, 2009; Kim et al., 2018; Kwiatek, 2019; Ji and Wu, 2020). Additionally, fluid injection through wastewater disposal has triggered events, including that in Prague, Oklahoma in 2011, resulting in an M=5.7 earthquake (Sumy et al., 2014). It remains a challenge to define the seismic moment of potential seismic events triggered by fluid injection, as much of our understanding derives from analyzing unintended earthquakes and evaluating the mechanisms that control shear reactivation and fault slip (Keranen et al., 2014; Walsh and Zoback, 2015; Bao, 2016; Ji and Wu, 2020). Generally, induced seismicity may result from: 1) increase in pore pressure where the effective normal stress is reduced, therefore, destabilizing pre-existing faults in shear, or 2) regional tectonic stresses that are perturbed by poroelastic effects which increase shear stresses and trigger failure (Ellsworth, 2013; Bao, 2016; Guglielmi et al., 2016).</description>
      <author>M. Roseboom, Agathe M. Eijsink, D. Elsworth, Jianjun Yu, C. Marone, Jacques Rivi&#232;re, Parisa Shokouhi, John Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0686</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
