<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 18:49:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Activity of Graphitic Carbon Nitride via the Capping-Agent-Free Involvement of Ag Nanocrystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.3c03841</link>
      <description>Liang Ma, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhiqiang Liang, Shun Lu, Pengxuan Wu, Songbai Qiu, Qian Zhang, Tiejun Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391111388

                In this work, a facile method to tune the carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction reaction (CRR) activities of graphitic carbon nitride (GCN) was developed via the capping-agent-free involvement of a trace amount of Ag nanocrystals with a decreased size. After the optimization of experimental conditions, the CRR performance investigation confirms that Ag-GCN-0.2 exhibited a superior CRR performance, achieving a faradaic efficiency (FE) of more than 72 &#177; 1% for CO in a wide potential range from &#8722;0.6 to &#8722;1.1 V (vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE)) and a max FE of 89 &#177; 1% at an overpotential of 0.9 V with a constant current density and a well-maintained microstructure even after 12 h of electrolysis. This work provides a new route to tune the catalytical performance of GCN and pave the way for the rational design, synthesis, and accurate estimation of the GCN-based catalysts, which will be synthesized on a large scale and utilized in industries.</description>
      <author>Liang Ma, Xiaoyan Cai, Zhiqiang Liang, Shun Lu, Pengxuan Wu, Songbai Qiu, Qian Zhang, Tiejun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.3c03841</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction to formate on tin electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148972</link>
      <description>Anoop Naikkath, Nikhil George Mohan, Kothandaraman Ramanujam, Surash Ramanathan, Chemical Engineering Journal. 482(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391112540

                Carbon dioxide can be electrochemically reduced to formate on tin electrodes. Formate is one of the most economically viable products of CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). While CO2 is reduced to formate, hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) occurs concomitantly. The kinetics of CO2RR and HER on the tin electrode was investigated. Potentiodynamic polarization studies were conducted in CO2 saturated and N2 saturated 0.1 M KHCO3 solutions, in the potential range from &#8722;0.014 V to &#8722;1.59 V vs. RHE. A faradaic efficiency of 93.95 % towards formate production was obtained at &#8722;1.09 V vs. RHE. The mass transfer effects and bicarbonate dissociation equilibrium were used to estimate the concentration of the reactants at the electrode surface. Density functional theory calculations indicate that &#8211;OCHO intermediate species is thermodynamically favoured, and a four-step reaction with two intermediates is proposed. The proposed mechanism captures the major features of the polarization data. CO2 reduction occurs via two intermediate species, viz. adsorbed H and OCHO species, while HER occurs via Volmer-Heyrovsky steps. The model predicts that in N2 saturated solutions, the fractional surface coverage of adsorbed H reaches a maximum of &#8764;0.48 at a potential of &#8722;0.82 V vs. RHE while in CO2 saturated solutions, the corresponding value is &#8764;0.29. In addition, the maximum fractional surface coverage of adsorbed OCHO is predicted to be &#8764;0.12 in CO2 saturated solutions.</description>
      <author>Anoop Naikkath, Nikhil George Mohan, Kothandaraman Ramanujam, Surash Ramanathan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Products via Enhancing Localized *Co Coverage And Local Pressure in Conical Cavity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202312204</link>
      <description>Chunzhong Li, Tingting Zhang, Heng Liu, Zhongyuan Guo, Zhongliang Liu, Huancong Shi, Jialin Cui, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Chunzhong Li, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391212986

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2 RR) involves a multistep proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) process that generates a variety of intermediates, making it challenging to transform them into target products with high activity and selectivity. Here, we report a catalyst featuring a nanosheets-stacked sphere structure with numerous open and deep conical cavities (OD-CCs). Under the guidance of finite-element method (FEM) simulations and theoretical analysis, we showed that exerting control over the confinement space resulted in diffusion limitation of the carbon intermediates, thereby increasing local pressure and subsequently enhancing localized *CO coverage for dimerization. The nanocavities exhibited a structure-driven shift in selectivity of multi-carbon (C2+ ) product from 41.8% to 81.7% during the CO2 RR process. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</description>
      <author>Chunzhong Li, Tingting Zhang, Heng Liu, Zhongyuan Guo, Zhongliang Liu, Huancong Shi, Jialin Cui, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202312204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cadmium sulfide nanoparticles compositing with chitosan and metal-organic framework: Enhanced photostability and increased carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-024-00837-2</link>
      <description>Ying Zhang, Hao Liang, Advanced Composites and Hybrid Materials. 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391276659

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Zhang, Hao Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-024-00837-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free&#8208;standing Stanene for High Selectivity of Formate in Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303889</link>
      <description>Xuanhao Mei, Cong Liu, Dezheng Zhang, Jing Cao, Rile Ge, Junhu Wang, Weilin Xu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391280930

                Abstract As well&#8208;known electrocatalysts with good catalytic efficiency for carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) towards the production of formate, tin (Sn)&#8208;based catalysts have aroused broad concern. Here, free&#8208;standing porous stanene is synthesized for the first time by a facile wet chemical method, and its excellent electrocatalytic performance for formate (HCOO &#8722; ) formation in CO 2 RR is demonstrated. High Faradaic efficiency (F.E., 93% at &#8722;930 mV versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE)) can be achieved in the CO 2 RR catalyzed by stanene in 0.5 m KHCO 3 aqueous solution. The in situ M&#246;ssbauer spectra reveal that zero&#8208;valent Sn aids in improving the selectivity of formate production. Furthermore, density functional theory calculations suggest that the high selectivity of HCOO &#8722; of CO 2 RR on stanene mainly originates from the edge sites on Sn (100). To further explore the practicability of the stanene&#8208;based catalysts for CO 2 RR, stanene decorated by 3 wt% BP&#8208;2000 is prepared, showing an excellent F.E. of 98% at &#8722;930 mV versus RHE due to the higher exposure of catalytic active sites. These new findings of the activity origination and reaction mechanism of stanene contribute to the deeper understanding of Sn&#8208;based catalysts for CO 2 RR, which is beneficial for the future designation of highly efficient CO 2 RR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xuanhao Mei, Cong Liu, Dezheng Zhang, Jing Cao, Rile Ge, Junhu Wang, Weilin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface gallium oxide hydroxide species adsorbing carbon dioxide to enhance the photocatalytic activity of a silver-loaded calcium titanate for carbon dioxide reduction with water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3se01390a</link>
      <description>Hongxuan Qiu, Akira Yamamoto, Hisao Yoshida, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391319608

                Photocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) has attracted considerable attention as a new method to build a carbon cycle. Particularly, photocatalytic reduction of CO 2 using water as an electron and...</description>
      <author>Hongxuan Qiu, Akira Yamamoto, Hisao Yoshida</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3se01390a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOFs materials as photocatalysts for CO2 reduction: Progress, challenges and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100191</link>
      <description>Mazhar Khan, Zeeshan Akmal, Muhammad Tayyab, Seemal Mansoor, Adnan Zeb, Ziwei Ye, Jinlong Zhang, Shiqun Wu, Lingzhi Wang, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391019430

                Photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) presents a pivotal solution to address meteorological and ecological challenges. Currently, metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) with their crystalline porosity, adjustable structures, and diverse chemical functionalities have garnered significant attention in the realm of photocatalytic CO2 reduction. This review provides a brief introduction to CO2 reduction and MOF material and their applications in CO2 reduction. Then, it undertakes a comprehensive examination of MOFs, summarizing their key attributes, including porosity, large surface area, structural multifunctionalities, and responsiveness to visible light, along with an analysis of heterojunctions and their methods of preparation. Additionally, it elucidates the fundamental principle of photocatalysis and CO2 reduction, encompassing both half and overall reactions. Furthermore, the classification of MOF-based materials is explored, along with the proposed mechanism for CO2 reduction and an update on recent developments in this field. Finally, this review outlines the challenges and potential opportunities for utilizing MOFs in CO2 reduction, offering valuable insights to scholars seeking innovative approaches not only to enhance CO2 reduction but also to advance other photocatalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Mazhar Khan, Zeeshan Akmal, Muhammad Tayyab, Seemal Mansoor, Adnan Zeb, Ziwei Ye, Jinlong Zhang, Shiqun Wu, Lingzhi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Carbon Monoxide and Carbon Dioxide Adsorption on (5,5) Aluminum Nitride Nanotubes for Enhanced Sensor Applications: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29030557</link>
      <description>Nafiu Suleiman, Vitus A. Apalangya, Bismark Mensah, Kwabena Kan-Dapaah, Abu Yaya, Molecules. 29(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391136623

                This study examined the sensitivity of single-walled (5,5) aluminium nitride nanotubes ((5,5) AlNNTs) to carbon monoxide (CO) and carbon dioxide (CO2) gas molecules by performing DFT calculations using a hybrid functional, specifically, B3LYP (Becke&#8217;s three-parameter, Lee-Yang-Parr) exchange-correlation functional at a 6&#8211;31G* basis set. This research investigates the adsorption behavior of CO2 and CO molecules on pristine and silicon-doped aluminum nitride nanotubes (AlNNTs) and examines their implications for sensor applications. The study assesses each system&#8217;s adsorption energy, sensing potential, and recovery time to gain insights into their binding strength and practical viability. For CO2 adsorption on (5,5) AlNNT, significant adsorption energy of &#8722;24.36 kcal/mol was observed, indicating a strong binding to the nanotube surface, with a sensing potential of 8.95%. However, the slow recovery time of approximately 4.964 days may limit its real-time application. Si-(5,5) AlNNT exhibited a CO2 adsorption energy of &#8722;19.69 kcal/mol, a sensing potential of 5.40%, and a relatively short recovery time of approximately 2.978 min, making it a promising candidate for CO2 sensing. CO adsorption on (5,5) AlNNT showed an adsorption energy of &#8722;25.20 kcal/mol, a sensing potential of 9.095%, but a longer recovery time of approximately 20.130 days. Si-(5,5) AlNNT displayed a high CO adsorption energy of &#8722;20.78 kcal/mol, a sensing potential of 4.29%, and a recovery time of approximately 18.320 min. These findings provide insights into the adsorption characteristics of carbon molecules on AlNNTs, highlighting their potential for CO2 and CO sensing applications.</description>
      <author>Nafiu Suleiman, Vitus A. Apalangya, Bismark Mensah, Kwabena Kan-Dapaah, Abu Yaya</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29030557</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering the Selectivity of Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction from Single-Carbon to Multicarbon Products on Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks via Facet Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.3c04092</link>
      <description>Pengyi Lu, Jia Lv, Yu Chen, Yangbo Ma, Yunhao Wang, Wei Lyu, Jinli Yu, Jingwen Zhou, Jinwen Yin, Yi Xiong, Guozhi Wang, Chongyi Ling, Shibo Xi, Daliang Zhang, Zhanxi Fan, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391160753

                Although metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) have attracted more attention for the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), obtaining multicarbon products with a high Faradaic efficiency (FE) remains challenging, especially under neutral conditions. Here, we report the controlled synthesis of stable Cu(I) 5-mercapto-1-methyltetrazole framework (Cu-MMT) nanostructures with different facets by rationally modulating the reaction solvents. Significantly, Cu-MMT nanostructures with (001) facets are acquired using isopropanol as a solvent, which favor multicarbon production with an FE of 73.75% and a multicarbon:single-carbon ratio of 3.93 for CO2RR in a neutral electrolyte. In sharp contrast, Cu-MMT nanostructures with (100) facets are obtained utilizing water, promoting single-carbon generation with an FE of 63.98% and a multicarbon: single-carbon ratio of only 0.18. Furthermore, this method can be extended to other Cu-MMT nanostructures with different facets in tuning the CO2 reduction selectivity. This work opens up new opportunities for the highly selective and efficient CO2 electroreduction to multicarbon products on MOFs via facet engineering.</description>
      <author>Pengyi Lu, Jia Lv, Yu Chen, Yangbo Ma, Yunhao Wang, Wei Lyu, Jinli Yu, Jingwen Zhou, Jinwen Yin, Yi Xiong, Guozhi Wang, Chongyi Ling, Shibo Xi, Daliang Zhang, Zhanxi Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.3c04092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selectively Adsorbed Mercaptoethanesulfonic Acid on Au/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Enhances the Yield and Selectivity of Photocatalytic Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03093</link>
      <description>Mengdan Guan, Junjie Wang, Zhongyan Gong, Kun Gao, Xing Kang, Yulong Zhang, Chengcheng Zhu, Zhihao L&#252;, Xinya Chen, Jianguo L&#252;, Qinghua Liu, Haonan Chen, Liuyingzi Yu, Kaili Wang, Zhuoyao Li, Gang L&#252;, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391239090

                The photocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2RR) is of paramount importance in the energy industry and environmental protection. Developing highly efficient catalysts plays a central role in advancing CO2RR for practical applications, and a Au/TiO2 heterostructure has emerged as a prominent photocatalyst in CO2RR. However, there is still a need to improve the reaction efficiency and selectivity of this heterostructure to realize its full potential in practical applications. Herein, a significant enhancement in the total gas-production rate on the Au/TiO2 heterostructure is achieved by selectively adsorbing thiol molecules, specifically mercaptoethanesulfonic acid, onto the gold surface. Remarkably, the selectivity toward carbon monoxide has also improved from 62.3 to 79.3%. Notably, the reaction rate and selectivity are strongly influenced by the choice of thiol molecules, their concentration, and the wavelength of light used for illumination. The improved reaction efficiency and selectivity can be attributed to the promotion of charge transfer at the Au&#8211;TiO2 interface induced by molecular adsorption of thiols. This phenomenon leads to enhanced performance in the photocatalytic CO2RR process. Importantly, this work presents a simple, convenient, cost-effective, and controllable strategy to improve the reaction efficiency and selectivity of photocatalytic CO2RR on the Au/TiO2 heterostructure. Furthermore, this strategy holds promise for application in various other heterogeneous photocatalytic systems in the near future.</description>
      <author>Mengdan Guan, Junjie Wang, Zhongyan Gong, Kun Gao, Xing Kang, Yulong Zhang, Chengcheng Zhu, Zhihao L&#252;, Xinya Chen, Jianguo L&#252;, Qinghua Liu, Haonan Chen, Liuyingzi Yu, Kaili Wang, Zhuoyao Li, Gang L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective reduction on flame soot via plasma coupled with carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.133669</link>
      <description>Dandan Qi, Mingxiao Chen, Kaixuan Yang, Tianjiao Li, Yaoyao Ying, Dong Liu, Journal of Hazardous Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391451084

                This study explored the impact of non-thermal plasma and CO2 on the flame soot characteristics within the diffusion flames. We analyzed on flame structures that were diluted with either CO2 or N2, temperature distributions, and soot characteristics, both in the presence and absence of plasma. Due to the higher specific heat capacity of CO2 compared to N2, the optical observations consistently showed lower temperatures in flames diluted with CO2 as compared to those diluted with N2. The inclusion of plasma and carbon dioxide resulted in the lowest soot concentration, indicating that plasma coupled with CO2 has a synergistic inhibitory effect on soot emissions. The findings revealed that when CO2 was used to dilute the flames and the oxygen concentration was low, the soot nanostructure appeared amorphous. Raman results showed that the level of graphitization observed in soot particles from CO2 dilution flames was lower than that from N2 dilution flames. In the presence of plasma and CO2, the soot obtained exhibited the shortest fringe length and the highest fringe tortuosity. Significant correlations were observed between the nanostructure of soot and its reactivity. The combined application of plasma and CO2 proved to be effective in reducing the soot carbonization degree. Soot particles produced during incomplete combustion not only reduce the performance of the combustion system but also cause significant environmental pollution and health problems. Oxygen-fuel combustion integrated with O2/CO2 as an oxidant instead of O2/N2 has drawn extensive attention due to its unique advantages in reducing soot and NOx generation and combining with CO2 recycling technologies. This topic provides a detailed and profound understanding of the mechanisms behind soot suppression through the combined effects of CO2 addition and plasma activation.</description>
      <author>Dandan Qi, Mingxiao Chen, Kaixuan Yang, Tianjiao Li, Yaoyao Ying, Dong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.133669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Interplay of the Br&#248;nsted Acidity of Catalyst Ancillary Groups and the Solution Components in Iron-porphyrin-Mediated Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10127</link>
      <description>Ana Sonea, Nicholas R. Crudo, Jeffrey J. Warren, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391464343

                The rapid and efficient conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) to carbon monoxide (CO) is an ongoing challenge. Catalysts based on iron-porphyrin cores have emerged as excellent electrochemical mediators of the two proton + two electron reduction of CO2 to CO, and many of the design features that promote function are known. Of those design features, the incorporation of Br&#248;nsted acids in the second coordination sphere of the iron ion has a significant impact on catalyst turnover kinetics. The Br&#248;nsted acids are often in the form of hydroxyphenyl groups. Herein, we explore how the acidity of an ancillary 2-hydroxyphenyl group affects the performance of CO2 reduction electrocatalysts. A series of meso-5,10,15,20-tetraaryl porphyrins were prepared where only the functional group at the 5-meso position has an ionizable proton. A series of cyclic voltammetry (CV) experiments reveal that the complex with &#8722;OMe positioned para to the ionizable &#8722;OH shows the largest CO2 reduction rate constants in acetonitrile solvent. This is the least acidic &#8722;OH of the compounds surveyed. The turnover frequency of the &#8722;OMe derivative can be further improved with the addition of 4-trifluoromethylphenol to the solution. In contrast, the iron-porphyrin complex with &#8722;CF3 positioned opposite the ionizable &#8722;OH shows the smallest CO2 reduction rate constants, and its turnover frequency is less enhanced with the addition of phenols to the reaction solutions. The origin of this effect is rationalized based on kinetic isotope effect experiments and density functional calculations. We conclude that catalysts with weaker internal acids coupled with stronger external acid additives provide superior CO2 reduction kinetics.</description>
      <author>Ana Sonea, Nicholas R. Crudo, Jeffrey J. Warren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts for electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00003-3</link>
      <description>Subhash Chandra Shit, Indranil Mondal, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488466

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction carries tremendous significance to tackle the exponential rising of CO2 level in the atmosphere. The development of different classes of electrocatalyst materials emerged with more understanding of the catalyst features, reaction mechanism, catalytic efficiency, and product selectivity using modern analytical tools (such as in situ techniques). Single-atom catalysts (SACs) are a new class of material that allows atom-by-atom utilization in the catalytic process, thereby influencing the CO2 reduction efficiency and product selectivity in more precise manner. In this chapter, we highlight the fundamental of CO2 electroreduction, including general mechanism for varied product formation, electrolyzer component, operational parameter, and development of SACs electrode material for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Subhash Chandra Shit, Indranil Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00003-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvation of oxygen, carbon dioxide, carbon monoxide and nitrous oxide in fluorinated liquids</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4391327398</link>
      <description>Margarida F Costa Gomes, A.A.H. Padua J. Deschamps D.-H. Menz, No host. None(None)] 2005. https://openalex.org/W4391327398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Margarida F Costa Gomes, A.A.H. Padua J. Deschamps D.-H. Menz</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4391327398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in novel materials for photocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.107</link>
      <description>Suye L&#252;, Shengwei Zhang, Qi Liu, Wen Wang, Nanjing Hao, Yajun Wang, Zhou Li, Dan Luo, Carbon Neutralization. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391102665

                Abstract The conversion of CO 2 into chemical fuels, which can be stored and utilized through photocatalysis, represents an effective, environmentally friendly, and sustainable means to address both environmental concerns and energy shortages. CO 2 , as a stable oxidation product, poses challenges for reduction through light energy alone, necessitating the use of catalysts. Thus, a crucial aspect of CO 2 photocatalytic reduction technology lies in the development of effective photocatalysts. Based on the basic principle of PCRR (photocatalytic CO 2 reduction reaction), the review provides a detailed introduction to the core issues in PCRR process, including the relationship between band gap and catalyst reduction performance, effective utilization of photogenerated carriers, product selectivity, and methods for product analysis. Then, the recent research progresses of various photocatalysts are reviewed in the form of research examples combined with the above basic principles. Finally, this review summarizes and provides insights into the effective techniques for enhancing the photocatalytic activity of CO 2 , while also offering future prospects in this field.</description>
      <author>Suye L&#252;, Shengwei Zhang, Qi Liu, Wen Wang, Nanjing Hao, Yajun Wang, Zhou Li, Dan Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determining kinetics of electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction to carbon monoxide with scanning electrochemical microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118061</link>
      <description>Qikang Huang, Peize Li, Mingkui Wang, Yan Shen, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391116059

                This study reports on determining kinetics of electrochemical reduction CO2 to CO on Au catalysts using the substrate generation/tip collection (SG/TC) mode of scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM). We introduced a simple but effective method based on transient technique to obtain a series of apparent heterogeneous rate constants k based on Fick&#8217;s second law by controlling the tip-substrate distance and the voltage of the substrate electrode within the SECM framework. By analysis the transient current recorded during the chronoamperometric characterization, we can successfully determine the apparent rate constant k for the simplified total conversion process of CO2 + 2H+ + 2e- &#8594; CO + H2O onto Au catalyst electrode serving as an example, which increases from 5.02 &#215; 10&#8211;2 cm&#8901;s&#8722;1 to 7.16 &#215; 10&#8211;2 cm&#8901;s&#8722;1 in the low potential range of &#8722;2.2 to &#8722;2.6 V (vs. Pt/PPy) and decreases to 6.54 &#215; 10-2 cm&#8901;s&#8722;1 at &#8211;2.8 V (vs. Pt/PPy). The method proposed here can be applied to quantitatively analyze the kinetic of CO2 electrochemical reduction reaction, and thus provide a useful tool to guide the synthesis of catalyst as well as in-situ performance evaluation.</description>
      <author>Qikang Huang, Peize Li, Mingkui Wang, Yan Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide reduction to methane and ethanol by using boron carbide monolayer as a suitable photocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.110849</link>
      <description>Mohamed J. Saadh, Saade Abdalkareem Jasim, Linda Mariuxi Flores Fiallos, Anupam Yadav, Louay Saleh, Edwin J&#225;come, C&#233;sar Gerardo Mej&#237;a Gallegos, Yazen M. Alawaideh, Yasser Elmasry, Diamond and Related Materials. 142(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391089745

                A new-type boron carbide material has been used, as an electrocatalyst for the reduction of CO2 to C2 and C1 based on the computational study. Within the current research, DFT was adopted to investigate the BC3 nanoflake as an electrocatalyst for the reduction of CO2. The optoelectronic attributes of the BC3 nanoflake indicated that BC3 nanoflake had a longer visible-light region and its band gap was 2.25 eV. Based on the spatial distribution of the LUMO and the HOMO, the introduction of boron extended the &#960; network of BC3 nanoflake, thereby dramatically increasing the photocatalytic efficiency. Additionally, we estimated the Gibbs free energy of each potential CO2 reaction path onto BC3 nanoflake. Based on the findings, CO2 could reduce into CH4 and CH3CH2OH with low limiting potentials of &#8722;0.41 V and &#8722;0.53 V, respectively. The current study can provide useful insights into the application of BC3 nanoflake as an encouraging photocatalyst for the reduction reaction CO2.</description>
      <author>Mohamed J. Saadh, Saade Abdalkareem Jasim, Linda Mariuxi Flores Fiallos, Anupam Yadav, Louay Saleh, Edwin J&#225;come, C&#233;sar Gerardo Mej&#237;a Gallegos, Yazen M. Alawaideh, Yasser Elmasry</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.110849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Thermodynamic View on the In-situ Carbon Dioxide Reduction by Biomass-derived Hydrogen during Calcium Carbonate Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjche.2023.12.017</link>
      <description>Peng Jiang, Hao Zhang, Guanhan Zhao, Lin Li, Tuo Ji, Liwen Mu, Xiaohua L&#252;, Jiahua Zhu, Chinese Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391037978

                In the carbonate industry, deep decarbonization strategies are necessary to effectively remediate CO2. These strategies mainly include both sustainable energy supplies and the conversion of CO2 in downstream processes. This study developed a coupled process of biomass chemical looping H2 production and reductive calcination of CaCO3. Firstly, a mass and energy balance of the coupled process was established in Aspen Plus. Following this, process optimization and energy integration were implemented to provide optimized operation conditions. Lastly, a life cycle assessment was carried out to assess the carbon footprint of the coupled process. Results reveal that the decomposition temperature of CaCO3 in an H2 atmosphere can be reduced to 780 oC (generally around 900 oC), and the conversion of CO2 from CaCO3 decomposition reached 81.33% with an H2:CO ratio of 2.49 in gaseous products. By optimizing systemic energy through heat integration, an energy efficiency of 86.30% was achieved. Additionally, the carbon footprint analysis revealed that the process with energy integration had a low GWP of -2.624 kgCO2-eq&#183;kg-CaO-1. Conclusively, this work performed a systematic analysis of introducing biomass-derived H2 into CaCO3 calcination and demonstrated the positive role of reductive calcination using green H2 in mitigating CO2 emissions within the carbonate industry.</description>
      <author>Peng Jiang, Hao Zhang, Guanhan Zhao, Lin Li, Tuo Ji, Liwen Mu, Xiaohua L&#252;, Jiahua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjche.2023.12.017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancies synergistic cobalt phosphide electron bridge modulated bismuth oxychloride/carbon nitride Z-scheme junction for efficient carbon dioxide reduction coupled with tetracycline oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.149</link>
      <description>Haoyu Sun, Xuemei Jia, Jing Cao, Shifu Chen, Yong Chen, Haili Lin, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391264958

                Although great progress has been made with respect to electron bridges, the electron mobility of the state-of-the-art electron bridges is far from satisfactory because of weak electrical conductivity. To overcome the above issue, cobalt phosphide (CoP), as a model electron bridge, was modified with superficial oxygen vacancies (OVs) and embedded into a defective bismuth oxychloride/carbon nitride (BiO1-xCl/g-C3N4) Z-scheme heterojunction to obtain atomic-level insights into the effect of surface OVs on CoP electron bridges. Compared to BiO1-xCl/g-C3N4 and bismuth oxychloride/cobalt phosphide/carbon nitride (BiOCl/CoP/g-C3N4) composites, the defective bismuth oxychloride/cobalt phosphide/carbon nitride (BiO1-xCl/CoP/g-C3N4) heterojunction exhibited remarkable photocatalytic redox performance, indicating that the surface OVs-assisted CoP electron bridge effectively boosted electrical conductivity and yielded ultrafast electron transfer rates. The theoretical and experimental results demonstrate that the surface OVs play a critical role in improving the electrical conductivity of the CoP electron bridge, thereby accelerating electron mobility. This research provides insights into interfacial OVs-modified transition metal phosphide (TMP) electron bridges and their potential application in heterojunctions for energy crisis mitigation and environmental remediation.</description>
      <author>Haoyu Sun, Xuemei Jia, Jing Cao, Shifu Chen, Yong Chen, Haili Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The synergistic role of carbon dioxide removal and emission reductions in achieving the Paris Agreement goal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.spc.2024.01.004</link>
      <description>Humphrey Adun, Jeffrey Dankwa Ampah, Olusola Bamisile, Yihua Hu, Sustainable Production and Consumption. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391071426

                The limiting global carbon budget underscores the urgent need for effective and ambitious climate mitigation measures across diverse sectors to curb greenhouse gas emissions and prevent further exacerbation of global warming, aligning with international agreements such as the Paris Agreement. The role of carbon dioxide removal (CDR) becomes increasingly crucial in this context, though the extent to which this applies as a complementary measure to mitigation actions still requires careful examination and quantitative analysis. In this study, we carry out an assessment contingent upon the intertwined roles of mitigation actions and the levels of CDR deployment using the Energy-Rapid Overview and Decision-Support (En-ROADS) simulation tool. We develop sectoral emission reduction assumptions and a broad portfolio of CDR archetypes and deployment levels to evaluate their impacts on the intricate climate-land-energy nexus, and global warming temperature. We find that high levels of CDR permit the continual consumption of fossil fuels, though driving substantial renewable energy consumption post-mid-century. We also observe that high levels of CDR negatively impact sustainability factors, such as reduction in agricultural farmland, which is pronounced under high mitigation actions. We observe that the largest share of CDR is in agricultural soil carbon, with its proportion ranging from 27.4 % to 31.3 % across all scenarios. In conclusion, though CDRs are what put the &#8216;net&#8217; in the &#8216;net-zero emissions&#8217; goal, they are not a silver bullet but rather a crucial piece in the complex puzzle of climate action. We recommend that CDR should be strategically deployed as complementary options to vigorous emission reduction efforts, as this paves the way towards a sustainable and balanced approach to achieving our global climate objectives.</description>
      <author>Humphrey Adun, Jeffrey Dankwa Ampah, Olusola Bamisile, Yihua Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.spc.2024.01.004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Flexible Operation of a Wastewater Treatment Plant in the Reduction of Its Indirect Carbon Dioxide Emissions&#8212;A Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/w16030483</link>
      <description>Nil&#252;fer Topuz, Frank Alsmeyer, Hasancan Okutan, Hermann-Josef Roos, Water. 16(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391432666

                The increasing share of renewables in electricity grids comes with a challenge of energy surpluses and deficits, which needs be handled by demand side management (DSM) and storage options. Within this approach, wastewater treatment plants (WWTPs), with flexible energy consumption and production processes and storage units, can contribute to stabilizing the grids and integrating more renewables. In this study, the operation of a real WWTP was optimized by mixed integer linear programming (MILP) to minimize its indirect carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions. The operation of the WWTP was shown to be flexible in following the CO2 emission factor of the electricity grid, which was possible with the utilization of the WWTP&#8217;s storage units and flexible co-substrate feeding. As a result, by changing only the operational behavior of the WWTP, its indirect CO2 emissions decreased by 4.8% due to the higher share of renewables in the electricity grid. The CO2 emissions were shown to decrease further up to 6.9% by adding virtual storage units.</description>
      <author>Nil&#252;fer Topuz, Frank Alsmeyer, Hasancan Okutan, Hermann-Josef Roos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/w16030483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green steel from red mud through climate-neutral hydrogen plasma reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-023-06901-z</link>
      <description>Matic Jovi&#269;evi&#263;&#8208;Klug, Isnaldi Rodrigues de Souza Filho, Hauke Springer, Christian Adam, Dierk Raabe, Nature. 625(7996)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391166907

                Abstract Red mud is the waste of bauxite refinement into alumina, the feedstock for aluminium production 1 . With about 180 million tonnes produced per year 1 , red mud has amassed to one of the largest environmentally hazardous waste products, with the staggering amount of 4 billion tonnes accumulated on a global scale 1 . Here we present how this red mud can be turned into valuable and sustainable feedstock for ironmaking using fossil-free hydrogen-plasma-based reduction, thus mitigating a part of the steel-related carbon dioxide emissions by making it available for the production of several hundred million tonnes of green steel. The process proceeds through rapid liquid-state reduction, chemical partitioning, as well as density-driven and viscosity-driven separation between metal and oxides. We show the underlying chemical reactions, pH-neutralization processes and phase transformations during this surprisingly simple and fast reduction method. The approach establishes a sustainable toxic-waste treatment from aluminium production through using red mud as feedstock to mitigate greenhouse gas emissions from steelmaking.</description>
      <author>Matic Jovi&#269;evi&#263;&#8208;Klug, Isnaldi Rodrigues de Souza Filho, Hauke Springer, Christian Adam, Dierk Raabe</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-023-06901-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>None</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.v5.1</link>
      <description>, Advanced energy and sustainability research. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391491858

                Biomass-Derived Electrocatalysts In article number 2300168, Tengyi Liu, and Hiroshi Yabu summarize the latest reports on synthesizing oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, and other electrochemical catalysts from biomass-derived materials. The review provides guidelines for the design and synthesis of electrocatalysts that form catalytic active sites and realize high conductivity, either individually or both, using biomass-derived materials.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.v5.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic Analysis of Exhaust Gas Waste Heat Recovery with Organic Rankine Cycle for Container Ship</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4703037</link>
      <description>Merve G&#220;L &#199;IVGIN, Cengiz Deniz, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391097601

                Highlights&#8226; Thermodynamic analysis of organic rankine cycle using exhaust gas as a heat source was done.&#8226; The amount of carbon dioxide reduction obtained using the organic rankine cycle was shown.&#8226; The cases where the exhaust gas has different thermal values such as boiler outlet, turbocharger outlet were analyzed.&#8226; The selection of working fluid was evaluated according to exhaust gas specifications as a heat source.&#8226; The effect of evaporation temperature of working fluid and degree of superheating on the ORC system performance was analyzed.</description>
      <author>Merve G&#220;L &#199;IVGIN, Cengiz Deniz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4703037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#12503;&#12521;&#12474;&#12510;&#35302;&#23186;&#20316;&#29992;&#12434;&#29992;&#12356;&#12383;&#20108;&#37240;&#21270;&#28845;&#32032;&#36996;&#20803;&#21453;&#24540;&#12398;&#20419;&#36914;&#12395;&#38306;&#12377;&#12427;&#22522;&#30990;&#30740;&#31350;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7791/jspmee.13.31</link>
      <description>Susumu Toko, Takamasa Okumura, Kunihiro Kamataki, Kosuke Takenaka, Kazunori KOGA, Masaharu Shiratani, Yuichi Setsuhara, No host. 13(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391161005

                Carbon dioxide reduction is one of the key technologies for achieving a sustainable society. In this study, plasma catalysis were used to hydrogenate carbon dioxide to produce methane. Plasma catalysis have attracted attention in recent years as a technology promoting a reaction at lower temperatures by various synergistic effects between plasma and catalysts. In this study, molecular sieve with a pore diameter of 3 &#197; was used as a catalyst and its role was investigated. The results showed that: 1. molecular and atomic adsorption functions of molecular sieves are useful to inhibit reverse reactions; 2. the influence of molecular sieves becomes stronger at higher pressures, resulting in higher methane production; 3. energetic reactive particles derived from hydrogen deactivate molecular sieves; 4. molecules adsorbed on molecular sieve can be recycled by hydrogen plasma irradiation.</description>
      <author>Susumu Toko, Takamasa Okumura, Kunihiro Kamataki, Kosuke Takenaka, Kazunori KOGA, Masaharu Shiratani, Yuichi Setsuhara</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7791/jspmee.13.31</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXene-based hybrid nanomaterials in photocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95515-7.00008-x</link>
      <description>Attia shaheen, Waseem Raza, Hajera Gul, Nadeem Raza, Arshad Hussain, Andleeb Mehmood, Munir Ahmad, Muhammad Mushtaq, Ghulam Yasin, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488942

                MXenes possess unique properties, such as high electrical conductivity and suitable bandgap, due to which they are very useful in a large number of applications, such as, optoelectronic, energy storage, communications, biomedical, and environmental sectors. Because of their distinctive characteristics, the number of research articles and patents published has been growing quickly. Therefore, owing to its huge research interest, in this chapter we have discussed MXene-based hybrid nanomaterials and focused on their role in photocatalysis and discussed theoretical aspects describing the mechanism of photocatalysis to avoid redundancy. This chapter covers the role of MXenes in the photodegradation of dyes, water splitting, nitrogen fixation or reduction, carbon dioxide reduction, and organic synthesis. Moreover, it includes a detailed discussion on the advantages of MXenes for these applications, and the main challenges that limit their utilization and prospects are outlined.</description>
      <author>Attia shaheen, Waseem Raza, Hajera Gul, Nadeem Raza, Arshad Hussain, Andleeb Mehmood, Munir Ahmad, Muhammad Mushtaq, Ghulam Yasin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95515-7.00008-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmonic&#8208;assisted Electrocatalysis for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300805</link>
      <description>Xiu Wang, Miao Yu, Ziyun Wang, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391173783

                Abstract Integrating plasmonic features as an emerging strategy for enhancing electrocatalysis for the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR). The key parameters responsible for the enhanced electrocatalysis performance are the local heating, the hot carriers, and near&#8208;field enhancement induced by localized surface plasmon resonance (LSPR, that is, plasmonic) excitation. This review provides a concise overview of the fundamental mechanism of CO 2 RR, detailing the generation and decay of plasmonic and the energy transfer dynamics between plasmonic nanostructures and adsorbates. It further involves recent progress in plasmonic&#8208;assisted electrocatalysis for CO 2 RR, including experimental and theoretical research to decipher plasmonic mechanisms. Finally, it ends with an insightful discussion of the existing challenges and potential future directions in this field.</description>
      <author>Xiu Wang, Miao Yu, Ziyun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress of 3d transition metal as single-atom catalysts for electrochemical CO2 reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102690</link>
      <description>Song Lu, Sachin Chavan, Zhixin Yu, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391243406

                Electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction (ECR) presents a promising technology to attain carbon neutrality. Recent studies have indicated that transition metal atoms as single-atom catalysts (SACs) show many advantages in ECR due to their tunable electronic structure, high atom utilization rate, and uniform active site. Among the various reduction products, CO is an important chemical feedstock that can be used in some essential processes such as Fischer-Tropsch, which produces a series of chemicals and fuels. However, few relevant reviews focus on 3d transition atoms as SACs for ECR to CO. In this review, we first emphasize the advantages of SACs and the CO product. Then, we summarize the recent development of SACs (Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, and Zn) in ECR to CO, focusing on the configurations of the active center. Finally, we briefly propose suggestions for future advancement of transition metal SACs for ECR to CO.</description>
      <author>Song Lu, Sachin Chavan, Zhixin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of Cu2o/In(Oh)3 for Efficient Solar-Driven Co2 Electrochemical Reduction to Syngas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4704994</link>
      <description>Juan Wang, Jinglian Huang, Siyuan Dong, Shuangyan Li, Bingna Zheng, Yun Yang, Shun Wang, Dajie Lin, Tingjie Mao, Huile Jin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391178525

                Electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) holds greater promise for converting CO2 into value-added chemicals, but designing and manufacturing efficient CO2RR catalysts remains desirable but challenging. Here, the Cu2O/In(OH)3 with heterojunction interface was prepared as an efficient CO2RR electrocatalysts. The optimized Cu2O/In(OH)3-1:1 stabilizes over a wide range of potentials to generate syngas (hydrogen/carbon monoxide, H2/CO) at a ratio of 2:1, and the total Faraday efficiency (FE) remains close to 100%. However, the ratio of syngas will change to 1:1 when the Cu/In ratio becomes 1:2. In addition, creatively using solar energy to drive the CO2RR system can directly and efficiently achieve the conversion of solar energy to chemical energy (syngas). Moreover, in-situ experiments show that part of Cu+ is converted to Cu during the CO2RR process, and In(OH)3 remains stable. This work highlights an efficient electrocatalyst for producing syngas based on interface engineering.</description>
      <author>Juan Wang, Jinglian Huang, Siyuan Dong, Shuangyan Li, Bingna Zheng, Yun Yang, Shun Wang, Dajie Lin, Tingjie Mao, Huile Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4704994</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Identification of Carbon-confined SnOx Nanodots Dynamics during CO2-to-formate Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3853964/v1</link>
      <description>Zheng Jiang, Jianing Mao, Bingbao Mei, Shuai Yang, Jianrong Zeng, Fanfei Sun, Wei Chen, Fei Song, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391227764

                Abstract Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) using tin oxide-based catalysts holds significant potential for producing formate products from renewable energy, while obscurely quantification of structure changes in local configuration hinders the development of highly active and robust electrocatalysts. Herein, the operando spectroscopy revealed the quantitatively oxygen-released behavior in tin oxide nanostructure of the graphene confined SnOx nanodots (rGO@SnO x ND) under the reduction potentials, which promotes the SnOx lattice modulation by the Sn cluster and the adsorption of *OCHO intermediate by increasing the charge density. The controllable reduction degree in rGO@SnO x ND among CO2RR facilitates the excellent exceptional performance of the maximum formate partial current density of 567 mA cm &#8722;2 with 96.5 % selectivity and a 50 h long-term stability in flow-cell. These findings show that the controllable oxygen vacancies regulation determines the yield of formate, further emphasizing the importance of operando spectrosopy characterization to understand the dynamic surface structure-performance relationship.</description>
      <author>Zheng Jiang, Jianing Mao, Bingbao Mei, Shuai Yang, Jianrong Zeng, Fanfei Sun, Wei Chen, Fei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3853964/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial microenvironment effects on electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148944</link>
      <description>Xianlang Chen, Chunhua Chen, Yuyao Wang, Zhengyu Pan, Junjie Chen, Yuyang Xu, Liehuang Zhu, Tongyang Song, Rongrong Li, Liang Chen, Ji-Qing Lu, Chemical Engineering Journal. 482(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391057924

                Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (ECR) powered by renewable energy has the potential to utilize the intermittent renewable electric energy, alleviate the problem of excessive CO2 emissions and yield high value-added chemicals. Despite the intrinsic activity of the well-designed catalysts, subtle changes in the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface will have a significant impact on the overall reaction. The electrode and its microenvironment together determine the ECR performance. Revealing the relationship between the microenvironment of the catalyst-electrolyte interface and the ECR performance is critical for explaining the reaction mechanism and controlling the reaction process accurately. To maximize the catalytic performance includes the activity, selectivity and stability, the fundamental understanding of the interfacial microenvironment should be clarified as important as the intrinsic properties of the catalyst. Researches on the microenvironment in ECR have been gradually launched while the comprehensive discussion is scarcely. In this review, the interfacial microenvironment changes affected by multiple influence factors including the electrolyte effects (cation effect, anion effect, local pH, electrolyte type and concentration), morphological effects (tip effect, confinement effect), catalyst surface modification (surface hydrophobicity, chemical and electronic state) and electrolyzers improvement (gas diffusion electrode, membrane electrode reaction microenvironment control) are illustrated. Finally, some perspectives are offered on the basis of understanding the connection of catalytic activity and the interfacial microenvironment, these insights obtained can be applied for better control the CO2 reduction and rational design reactors.</description>
      <author>Xianlang Chen, Chunhua Chen, Yuyao Wang, Zhengyu Pan, Junjie Chen, Yuyang Xu, Liehuang Zhu, Tongyang Song, Rongrong Li, Liang Chen, Ji-Qing Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148944</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes for CO2 reduction: a promising choice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95515-7.00011-x</link>
      <description>Saira Ajmal, Anuj Kumar, Tuan Anh Nguyen, Ghulam Yasin, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488885

                Fast industrialization and urban growth emit significant amounts of hazardous CO2, which not only produces environmental problems but also causes illness all over the world. Several technologies for purifying air and water have been developed over the last two decades, but they have all failed due to high costs, poor effectiveness, and the creation of secondary contaminants. The photochemical and electrochemical conversion of CO2 into energy-rich molecules is a novel method that can aid in environmental rehabilitation while also meeting the world&#8217;s expanding energy demands. These techniques, however, necessitate extremely selective, energetic, and long-lasting catalysts. Scientists have investigated numerous keen and multifunctional materials for the conversion of CO2 pollution into useful compounds in this area. MXenes, a type of two-dimensional (2D) material made of transition metal nitrides, carbides, and carbonitrides, have engrossed attention because of their extraordinary physicochemical, mechanical, and electrochemical properties. This chapter focuses on CO2 conversion by photochemical and electrochemical methods to valuable products, emphasizing MXene-based materials and their catalytic activity, as well as future prospects.</description>
      <author>Saira Ajmal, Anuj Kumar, Tuan Anh Nguyen, Ghulam Yasin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95515-7.00011-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic CO2 reduction co&#8208;catalyzed by ionic liquids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301454</link>
      <description>Lisa Eisele, Wilaiwan Chaikhan, Samar Batool, Alexey Cherevan, Dominik Eder, Katharina Bica-Schr&#246;der, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391218414

                Efficiently generating C1 building blocks from environmentally friendly carbon sources, such as through photocatalytic CO2 reduction, is essential for fostering a sustainable circular economy. The pursuit of gentle catalytic activation methods has yielded powerful catalysts that can be synergistically employed alongside various reaction media to enhance overall performance. Herein, we elucidate the influence of diverse imidazolium&#8208;based ionic liquids as additives for visible&#8208;light&#8208;driven CO2reduction with ruthenium(II)&#8208; and rhenium(I)&#8208;bipyridine complexes. Our investigation reveals that incorporating ionic liquids into traditional solvents at concentrations below 10% can markedly boost CO production while suppressing H2 generation. The best results were obtained for the highly basic ionic liquid [C2mim][OAc], resulting in a substantial rise in CO formation from 0.3 &#181;mol/h to 5.4 &#181;mol/h and an increase in turnover number from 3 to 59. This study underscores the cooperative influence of imidazolium&#8208;based ionic liquids on CO2 photoreduction while circumventing their use as primary solvents, thus offering a promising avenue for sustainable chemical synthesis.</description>
      <author>Lisa Eisele, Wilaiwan Chaikhan, Samar Batool, Alexey Cherevan, Dominik Eder, Katharina Bica-Schr&#246;der</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Water Oxidation and CO2 Reduction with a Nickel Molecular Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29030578</link>
      <description>Hengxin Jian, Mengyu Lu, Zheng Haowen, Shuai Yan, M. Wang, Molecules. 29(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391175526

                Mimicking the photosynthesis of green plants to combine water oxidation with CO2 reduction is of great significance for solving energy and environmental crises. In this context, a trinuclear nickel complex, [NiII3(paoH)6(PhPO3)2]&#183;2ClO4 (1), with a novel structure has been constructed with PhPO32&#8722; (phenylphosphonate) and paoH (2-pyridine formaldehyde oxime) ligands and possesses a reflection symmetry with a mirror plane revealed by single-crystal X-ray diffraction. Bulk electrocatalysis demonstrates that complex 1 can homogeneously catalyze water oxidation and CO2 reduction simultaneously. It can catalyze water oxidation at a near-neutral condition of pH = 7.45 with a high TOF of 12.2 s&#8722;1, and the Faraday efficiency is as high as 95%. Meanwhile, it also exhibits high electrocatalytic activity for CO2 reduction towards CO with a TOF of 7.84 s&#8722;1 in DMF solution. The excellent electrocatalytic performance of the water oxidation and CO2 reduction of complex 1 could be attributed to the two unique &#181;3-PhPO32&#8722; bridges as the crucial factor for stabilizing the trinuclear molecule as well as the proton transformation during the catalytic process, while the oxime groups modulate the electronic structure of the metal centers via &#960; back-bonding. Therefore, apart from the cooperation effect of the three Ni centers for catalysis, simultaneously, the two kinds of ligands in complex 1 can also synergistically coordinate the central metal, thereby significantly promoting its catalytic performance. Complex 1 represents the first nickel molecular electrocatalyst for both water oxidation and CO2 reduction. The findings in this work open an avenue for designing efficient molecular electrocatalysts with peculiar ligands.</description>
      <author>Hengxin Jian, Mengyu Lu, Zheng Haowen, Shuai Yan, M. Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29030578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction at Different Electrocatalyst Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12020303</link>
      <description>Marcela Miranda Barcelos, Maria de Lourdes Soprani Vasconcellos, Josimar Ribeiro, Processes. 12(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391384166

                Given the environmental problems caused by burning fossil fuels, it is believed that converting carbon dioxide (CO2) into chemical inputs is a great ally to generating clean energy. In this way, investigative studies related to electrochemical CO2 reduction (CO2RE) concerning the behavior of metal catalysts have received attention about the processes involved. CO2RE can be an important tool to mitigate the presence of this gas in the Earth&#8217;s atmosphere. Given these considerations, in this review, we report the main catalysts used to act as CO2RE. Among them, we emphasize catalysts based on Ni, Zn, and Cu, which encompass the main properties related to the electrochemical conversion of CO2. Regarding the Cu-based catalyst, it presents high conversion efficiency but low selectivity. Furthermore, we also describe the main mechanisms related to the electrochemical conversion of CO2.</description>
      <author>Marcela Miranda Barcelos, Maria de Lourdes Soprani Vasconcellos, Josimar Ribeiro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12020303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction properties of boron-doped diamond powder</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.110821</link>
      <description>Yudai Miyake, Takeshi Kondo, Atsushi Otake, Yasuaki Einaga, Takeo Tojo, Makoto Yuasa, Diamond and Related Materials. 142(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391074415

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) properties of boron-doped diamond powder (BDDP) were investigated. A BDDP-painted electrode was prepared by casting BDDP ink on the surface of a BDD thin-film electrode as a current collector. The CO2RR properties of the BDDP-painted electrode were compared to those of conventional BDD thin-film electrodes, which were prepared directly on a conductive silicon wafer substrate by the microwave plasma-assisted chemical vapor deposition method. The result of the electrolysis at &#8722;1.8 V vs. Ag/AgCl in 0.5 M KCl catholyte showed that the BDDP-painted electrode was superior to the BDD thin-film electrode because it produced a large amount of products (formic acid and carbon monoxide) at a low overpotential. The highest performance of the CO2RR in the BDDP-painted electrode was achieved with the BDDP with high boron doping and high sp2 carbon content. We considered that structural defects, boron doping level, and sp2 carbon content influenced the reactivity for CO2 reduction. Therefore, the BDDP-painted electrodes should be useful not only for the production of a large-size electrode but also for efficient CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Yudai Miyake, Takeshi Kondo, Atsushi Otake, Yasuaki Einaga, Takeo Tojo, Makoto Yuasa</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.110821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057005

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review5</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057105

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057004

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057130

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057123

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review4</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057107

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391056983

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057020

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The enhancement effect of oxygen vacancy on photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta07981c</link>
      <description>Qiang Yang, Yunyi Wang, Qingwen Tian, Xiang Li, Aixiang Pan, Mingshan Zhao, Yanan Zhu, Tao Wu, Guigan Fang, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488490

                BiOBr with various concentrations of oxygen vacancies was manufactured via a solvothermal method using various alcohols as reducing agents. The reductive alcohol resulted in the fracture of the Bi-O bond,...</description>
      <author>Qiang Yang, Yunyi Wang, Qingwen Tian, Xiang Li, Aixiang Pan, Mingshan Zhao, Yanan Zhu, Tao Wu, Guigan Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta07981c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the photocatalytic CO2 reduction activity of g-C3N4 by acid modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126577</link>
      <description>Licheng Zhou, Jianping Ao, Zhi Wang, Zhenhong Huang, Zhaoyi Xu, Xiaofeng Wu, Zhenmin Cheng, Kangle Lv, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391293841

                Graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4 denoted as CN) is a typical organic polymeric semiconductor photocatalyst for CO2 reduction to produce solar fuels. In this study, the effect of phosphoric acid (H3PO4) modification on the property and photocatalytic performance of CN towards CO2 reduction was systematically studied. It was found that modification of CN with phosphoric acid (CNP photocatalyst) caused a reduced band gap width and negatively shifted conduction band (CB) potential. The photoreactivity of the optimized photocatalyst (CNP0.75) for CO production rate reaches 35.66 &#956;molg-1h&#8722;1, which is 4.38 times higher than that of CN sample with a CO evolution rate of only 8.14 &#956;molg-1h&#8722;1. The enhanced photoreativity of g-C3N4 towards CO2 reduction after phosphoric acid modification is ascribed to the combined effects of enhanced adsorption, stimulated charge separation and improved reduction ability of CB electrons. The positive effect of acid modification on the enhanced photocatalytic activity of CN was further observed by sulfuric acid (H2SO4) modification and hydrochloric acid (HCl) modification, suggesting the versatility of the method. The present study provides a novel way in preparation of high efficient g-C3N4 photocatalyst for CO2 conversion and utilization.</description>
      <author>Licheng Zhou, Jianping Ao, Zhi Wang, Zhenhong Huang, Zhaoyi Xu, Xiaofeng Wu, Zhenmin Cheng, Kangle Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126577</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon nitride based nanoarchitectonics for nature-inspired photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101242</link>
      <description>Aathira M. Sadanandan, Jae&#8208;Hun Yang, Vidyasagar Devtade, Gurwinder Singh, Nithinraj Panangattu Dharmarajan, Mohammed Fawaz, Jang Mee Lee, Ehsan Tavakkoli, Chung-Hwan Jeon, Prashant Kumar, Ajayan Vinu, Progress in Materials Science. 142(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391065107

                Drawing inspiration from the natural process of photosynthesis found in plant leaves, scientists are exploring the use of photocatalysis to convert carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable products using solar light and water. Photocatalytic CO2 conversion has emerged as one of the efficient green approaches to revitalize the environment from greenhouse gas pollution. Owing to its visible-range band gap, non-toxicity, ease of synthesis at economic costs and stability under light irradiation, g-C3N4 has emerged as the most explored photocatalyst. However, due to rampant exciton recombination owing to poor electrical conductivity, the efficiency of CO2 reduction falls short for g-C3N4 in its pure/pristine form. Therefore, the structural manoeuvre of g-C3N4 materials using N-rich configurations, heteroatom/single-atom doping and hybridization with various functional materials including metal oxides/sulfides, perovskite halides and metal complexes has been adopted, thereby overcoming their inherent drawbacks in photocatalytic CO2 reduction. In this timely review, we present an overview of the recent advances in surface/interface engineering of carbon nitrides for the conversion of CO2 to fuels and useful chemical by-products. More importance is given to the critical evaluation of surface manipulation in carbon nitrides and how it amplifies and affects their photocatalytic properties in CO2 reduction. Finally, we provide a comprehensive outlook into the future directions of these functionalised carbon nitrides for various applications. We strongly believe that this unique review will offer new knowledge on the surface property relationship of carbon nitride-based materials and their impact on enhancing their performance in various photocatalytic reactions and further create new opportunities for them in various areas.</description>
      <author>Aathira M. Sadanandan, Jae&#8208;Hun Yang, Vidyasagar Devtade, Gurwinder Singh, Nithinraj Panangattu Dharmarajan, Mohammed Fawaz, Jang Mee Lee, Ehsan Tavakkoli, Chung-Hwan Jeon, Prashant Kumar, Ajayan Vinu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in design and preparation of multi-atom catalysts for photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2698-5</link>
      <description>Zhonghao Wang, Guojun Zou, Jae Hyung Park, Kan Zhang, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391035964

                Photocatalytic CO2 reduction towards various fuels is of significant interest under the background of mitigating the global warming induced by CO2 emission and lowering the depletion of fossil fuels. However, state-of-the-art photocatalysts still suffer from sluggish reaction dynamics and frustrated product selectivity, especially for C2+ generations, which are of great interest for industrial applications. Over the past decades, comprehensive research on solar-driven CO2 reduction has consistently unveiled some encouraging results in meaningful pathways and architectural design of active sites over photocatalysts. This review highlights the recent advances in boosting photocatalytic CO2 reduction of atomically dispersed catalysts via engineered active sites, including two separated active sites, paired dual-active sites, and nanoclusters based on the configuration of active sites. Both the mechanism of CO2 activation over active sites and advanced characterization methods are discussed in detail. Particularly, in consideration of the wide gap between fundamental research and practical applications, the integrations of experimental and theoretical results are analyzed to realize the underlying structure-activity relationships as well as promising selectivity toward target products. Finally, the remaining challenges in the field are outlined, and inquisitive perspectives with a focus on the rational design of active sites and mechanistic investigation are proposed.</description>
      <author>Zhonghao Wang, Guojun Zou, Jae Hyung Park, Kan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2698-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of photocatalytic CO2 reduction over MOFs using machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta07001h</link>
      <description>Simay &#214;zsoysal, Burcu Oral, Ramazan Y&#305;ld&#305;r&#305;m, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391453336

                Photocatalytic CO2 reduction over metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) is investigated by constructing a database from published articles and analyzed using machine learning tools to predict the total gas product yield (random...</description>
      <author>Simay &#214;zsoysal, Burcu Oral, Ramazan Y&#305;ld&#305;r&#305;m</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta07001h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057087

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/response1</link>
      <description>John Cruz, Anna Balog, P&#233;ter S. T&#243;th, G&#225;bor Bencsik, Gergely F. Samu, Csaba Jan&#225;ky, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John Cruz, Anna Balog, P&#233;ter S. T&#243;th, G&#225;bor Bencsik, Gergely F. Samu, Csaba Jan&#225;ky</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Au-decorated Sb2Se3 photocathodes for solar-driven CO2 reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391057006

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ey00222e/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic screening of transition-metal-doped hydroxyapatite for efficient photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102692</link>
      <description>Yuting Li, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Josep Albero, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Lourdes F. Vega, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391448738

                We present the first comprehensive investigation of transition metal-substituted Hydroxyapatite (TM-HAP) materials for photocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2RR). Density functional theory (DFT) was used to study in a systematic manner the stability of 3d, 4d, 5d transition metal dopants on the HAP (000&#773;1) surface, analyzing their stability, activity, and selectivity for photocatalytic CO2RR. DFT results allowed to narrow down the selection to three transition metal elements (Co, Ni, Mo) based on their structural stability, band structure and performance. A selective analysis of product formation for carbon monoxide and formate was made, showing that TM dopants facilitate the initial protonation step in the CO2 reduction by adsorbing H2 molecule on TM atoms and then dissociating it into two hydrogen atoms. The performance of Ni- and Co-HAP towards the reaction activity is consistent with experimental results. Mo-HAP stands as a new and attractive photocatalyst for further investigation, given its excellent predicted performance.</description>
      <author>Yuting Li, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Josep Albero, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Lourdes F. Vega</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding of strain effect on Mo-based MXenes for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159501</link>
      <description>Dongyue Gao, Yue Xu, Zhe Li, Yadong Yu, Caiyan Yu, Yi Fang, Yang Huang, Chengchun Tang, Zhonglu Guo, Applied Surface Science. 654(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391151075

                Strain engineering is a powerful approach to tuning the electrocatalytic properties, but the systematic understanding of the strain effect in electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2RR) is still lacking. Here, we have extensively investigated the impact of strain on the catalytic selectivity and activity of Mo-based MXenes towards CO2RR. Our calculations suggest that strain can effectively tune the CO2 activation and reduction processes on MXenes, endowing great potential to obtain enhanced electrocatalytic performance. Notably, the activated CO2 can be selectively reduced to methane (CH4) on all electrocatalysts, which is conducive to restricting the production of HCOOH, H2CO, CH3OH and H2 (HER). Then, we highlight that compressive strains can reduce the limiting potential (UL) of CO2RR on Mo2C and Mo3C2 from &#8722;0.68 and &#8722;0.66 V to &#8722;0.49 and &#8722;0.38 V at the strain of &#8722;4%@Mo2C and &#8722;6%@Mo3C2, respectively, which are superior to benchmark Cu (2 1 1) (&#8722;0.67 V). Further mechanism analysis illuminates that the strain can significantly modify the d-band center of MXene, which endows the selective modulation of the adsorption strength of OCH2O* and HOCH2O* to achieve promoted catalytic activity. Our results provide an in-depth understanding of the strain effect and rational design principles for enhanced electrocatalytic CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Dongyue Gao, Yue Xu, Zhe Li, Yadong Yu, Caiyan Yu, Yi Fang, Yang Huang, Chengchun Tang, Zhonglu Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159501</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
