<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 01:21:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress and Future Perspectives of Ionic Liquid-Based Carbon Dioxide Capture and Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.10.002</link>
      <description>Anum Zafar, Karolina Matuszek, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Xinyi Zhang, Green Energy &amp; Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403426780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anum Zafar, Karolina Matuszek, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Xinyi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.10.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development and application of carbon dioxide direct mineralization technology and emission reduction device</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2853/1/012035</link>
      <description>Dongfang Li, Zheng Zhang, Zengyang Huang, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2853(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403451764

                Abstract This study analyzes the principles and methods of carbon dioxide mineralization fixation to address the challenges posed by global climate and ecological changes, achieve carbon neutrality goals, and solve carbon utilization issues in the development of the fluorosilicon new material industry. The research focuses on the direct mineralization reaction system of carbon dioxide flue gas and the development of a carbon dioxide emission reduction device utilizing wet mineralized gas treatment technology. To implement alkaline waste management for industrial solid waste. The research shows that the wet carbon dioxide mineralization and emission reduction device can make the alkaline solution better mineralize carbon dioxide, avoid the gas discharge too fast and affect the reaction rate. At the same time, the solution is mixed and the exhaust linkage is carried out to further improve the reaction rate, and provide a reference for the development of large-scale carbon dioxide utilization technology suitable for high energy consumption industries.</description>
      <author>Dongfang Li, Zheng Zhang, Zengyang Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2853/1/012035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Two-dimensional Tellurophosphates: Visible Light Photocatalysts for Water Splitting and Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105255</link>
      <description>Sajid Ur Rehman, Haris Habib, Zeeshan Tariq, Hafiz Muhammad Naeem Ullah, Faheem K. Butt, Xiaoming Zhang, Chuanbo Li, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403464897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sajid Ur Rehman, Haris Habib, Zeeshan Tariq, Hafiz Muhammad Naeem Ullah, Faheem K. Butt, Xiaoming Zhang, Chuanbo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of Platinum&#8211;Copper Alloy/Titanium Dioxide for Enhanced Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120191</link>
      <description>Xin Wang, Wei Tan, Bo Peng, Shangcong Sun, Xue Li, Kaiqiang Wang, Jiawei Ji, Haohong Liao, Jingfang Sun, Qing Tong, Haiqin Wan, Lin Dong, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403531303

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Wang, Wei Tan, Bo Peng, Shangcong Sun, Xue Li, Kaiqiang Wang, Jiawei Ji, Haohong Liao, Jingfang Sun, Qing Tong, Haiqin Wan, Lin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing In-Situ Oxidation of Nanostructured MXene to Modulate the Electronic Structure for Improved Selectivity for Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110385</link>
      <description>Guangxin Sun, Yimin Zhang, Haonan Xie, Ya He, Caiwei Zhang, Yukun Hu, Enzuo Liu, Chunnian He, Andrew Barnabas Wong, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403559337

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guangxin Sun, Yimin Zhang, Haonan Xie, Ya He, Caiwei Zhang, Yukun Hu, Enzuo Liu, Chunnian He, Andrew Barnabas Wong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repurposing First-Row Transition Metal Carbon Dioxide Reduction Electrocatalysts for Electrochemical Carboxylation of Benzyl Chloride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsorginorgau.4c00051</link>
      <description>Pornwimon Kongkiatkrai, Thana Anusanti, Teera Chantarojsiri, ACS Organic &amp; Inorganic Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403572803

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pornwimon Kongkiatkrai, Thana Anusanti, Teera Chantarojsiri</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsorginorgau.4c00051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposition of Cu 3D structures suitable for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2024.35.2.1</link>
      <description>Birut&#279; Serapinien&#279;, Laurynas Stai&#353;i&#363;nas, Algirdas Selskis, Remi&#173;gi&#173;jus Ju&#353;k&#279;nas, L. Gudavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Jurga Juodkazyt&#279;, R. Ramanauskas, Chemija. 35(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403406643

                Porous Cu foam electrodes, suitable for cathodic CO2 reduction, were deposited in an acidic sulphate solution with different additives to obtain structures with a high real surface area and an adequate mechanical stability. The influence of the electrodeposition time and solution composition on the porosity parameters, microstructure and stiffness of Cu 3D structures was evaluated. Neither ammonium acetate nor polyethylene glycol were found to be effective additives to the Cu sulphate electrolyte to achieve the main objectives. Only the presence of Cl&#8211; ions in the deposition solution resulted in a threefold increase in the real surface area and the achievement of a sufficient mechanical stability of the Cu 3D structure. The latter effect is related to the specific influence of Cl&#8211; ions during the electrodeposition process on the microstructural characteristics, such as the size of micropores in the walls of holes and crystallite aggregates that form dendritic branches. These structural changes, in contrast to the Cu samples deposited in a solution without additives, resulted in larger real surface areas, while the denser structures deposited in the presence of Cl&#8211; ions ensured the mechanical stability of the 3D structure.</description>
      <author>Birut&#279; Serapinien&#279;, Laurynas Stai&#353;i&#363;nas, Algirdas Selskis, Remi&#173;gi&#173;jus Ju&#353;k&#279;nas, L. Gudavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Jurga Juodkazyt&#279;, R. Ramanauskas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2024.35.2.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supercritical carbon dioxide foamed thermoplastic polyester elastomer with poly(lactic acid) blending: shrinkage reduction and expansion ratio improvement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00396-024-05329-9</link>
      <description>Zongquan Gu, Bo Zhao, Li Zhang, Jin-Biao Bao, Colloid &amp; Polymer Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403515043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongquan Gu, Bo Zhao, Li Zhang, Jin-Biao Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00396-024-05329-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT investigations of the MoS2 properties as photocatalyst for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4403445063</link>
      <description>R. Favre, Tangui Le Bahers, Pascal Raybaud, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4403445063

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Favre, Tangui Le Bahers, Pascal Raybaud</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4403445063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performing electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reactions at a high pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43979-024-00106-7</link>
      <description>Baoliang Chen, M. Feng, Yi&#8208;Ping Phoebe Chen, J.-L. Yang, Ya Liu, Carbon Neutrality. 3(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403401447

                Abstract Electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction technology offers an effective way to convert CO 2 into valuable chemicals and fuels, presenting a sustainable solution for carbon emissions. Current electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction technologies encounter significant issues such as salt precipitation and hydrogen evolution, which prevent energy conversion efficiency, selectivity, current density, and stability from simultaneously meeting industrial standards. In recent years, researchers have discovered that increasing the CO 2 pressure on the gas supply could enhance the coverage of the catalyst and activate more CO 2 reduction reaction sites on the catalyst surface, which provides a practical and effective approach for optimizing the energy conversion and mass transfer. In this review, we provide a comprehensive review of the development history and current status of high-pressure CO 2 electrocatalytic reduction technology, focusing on its reaction devices, catalytic performance, and reaction mechanisms. Furthermore, we summarize and offer insights into the most promising research avenues to propel the field forward.</description>
      <author>Baoliang Chen, M. Feng, Yi&#8208;Ping Phoebe Chen, J.-L. Yang, Ya Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43979-024-00106-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Riddle of the Sands: Co2 Emissions Reduction and California's Renewables Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4989267</link>
      <description>G. Cornelis van Kooten, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403466478

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. Cornelis van Kooten</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4989267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous C-doped C3N5 as a superior photocatalyst for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124701</link>
      <description>Aathira M. Sadanandan, Mohammed Fawaz, Nithinraj Panangattu Dharmarajan, Matej Hu&#353;, Gurwinder Singh, C. I. Sathish, Bla&#382; Likozar, Zhixuan Li, Ajanya M. Ruban, Chung&#8208;Hwan Jeon, Jae&#8208;Hun Yang, Prashant Kumar, Ajayan Vinu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403409752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aathira M. Sadanandan, Mohammed Fawaz, Nithinraj Panangattu Dharmarajan, Matej Hu&#353;, Gurwinder Singh, C. I. Sathish, Bla&#382; Likozar, Zhixuan Li, Ajanya M. Ruban, Chung&#8208;Hwan Jeon, Jae&#8208;Hun Yang, Prashant Kumar, Ajayan Vinu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to HCO2H by protic NHC-Ir complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2024.123422</link>
      <description>Saswati Ray, Sanajit Kumar Mandal, Joyanta Choudhury, Journal of Organometallic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403566238

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saswati Ray, Sanajit Kumar Mandal, Joyanta Choudhury</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2024.123422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab initio calculations of high-entropy clusters for oxygen reduction and evolution as well as CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161555</link>
      <description>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403561270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to ethylene using cuprous oxide derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1482168</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Fei Dong, Dejun Fu, Zhifeng Zhang, Zhiqiang Wu, Hongjian Zhao, W. Liu, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403395491

                Copper-based materials play a vital role in the electrochemical transformation of CO 2 into C 2 /C 2+ compounds. In this study, cross-sectional octahedral Cu 2 O microcrystals were prepared in situ on carbon paper electrodes via electrochemical deposition. The morphology and integrity of the exposed crystal surface (111) were meticulously controlled by adjusting the deposition potential, time, and temperature. These cross-sectional octahedral Cu 2 O microcrystals exhibited high electrocatalytic activity for ethylene (C 2 H 4 ) production through CO 2 reduction. In a 0.1 M KHCO 3 electrolyte, the Faradaic efficiency for C 2 H 4 reached 42.0% at a potential of &#8722;1.376 V vs. RHE. During continuous electrolysis over 10 h, the FE (C 2 H 4 ) remained stable around 40%. During electrolysis, the fully exposed (111) crystal faces of Cu 2 O microcrystals are reduced to Cu 0 , which enhances C-C coupling and could serve as the main active sites for catalyzing the conversion of CO 2 to C 2 H 4 .</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Fei Dong, Dejun Fu, Zhifeng Zhang, Zhiqiang Wu, Hongjian Zhao, W. Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1482168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ Imaging and Time-resolved Investigation of Local pH in Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124727</link>
      <description>Zezhong Xie, Qiushi Wang, Rongge Yang, Jingnan Zhang, S P Ou, Gangfeng Ouyang, Mingyang Li, Jianxin Shi, Yexiang Tong, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zezhong Xie, Qiushi Wang, Rongge Yang, Jingnan Zhang, S P Ou, Gangfeng Ouyang, Mingyang Li, Jianxin Shi, Yexiang Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic reduction of imines with silylformates: Formation of silyl carbamates through CO2 insertion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-hfwdz</link>
      <description>Neethu Thyagarajan, Ruqaya Buhaibeh, Emmanuel Nicolas, Thibault Cantat, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403541356

                Silylformates are emerging surrogates of hydrosilanes, able to reduce carbonyl groups in transfer hydrosilylation reactions, with the concomitant release of CO2. In this work, a new reactivity is revealed for silylformates, in the presence of imines. Using ruthenium catalysts, and lithium iodide as a co-catalyst, imines are shown to undergo hydrocarboxysilylation by formal insertion of CO2 to the N-Si bond of silyl amine to yield silyl carbamates in excellent yields.</description>
      <author>Neethu Thyagarajan, Ruqaya Buhaibeh, Emmanuel Nicolas, Thibault Cantat</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-hfwdz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing the Stability of Ultra-Thin Metal Oxide Catalyst Films in Non-thermal Plasma CO2 Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k0svz</link>
      <description>Samuel K. Conlin, Joseph Joel Muhanga, David N. Parette, Robert H. Coridan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403540654

                The use of metal oxide catalysts to enhance plasma CO2 reduction has seen significant recent development towards processes to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and produce renewable chemical feedstocks. While plasma reactors are effective at producing the intended chemical transformations, the conditions can result in catalyst degradation. Atomic layer deposition (ALD) can be used to synthesize complex, hierarchically structured metal oxide plasma catalysts that, while active for plasma CO2 reduction, are particularly vulnerable to degradation due to their high surface area and nanoscopic thickness. In this work, we characterized the effects of extended non-thermal, glow-discharge plasma exposure on ALD synthesized, ultra-thin film (&lt; 30 nm) TiO2 and ZnO catalysts. We used x-ray diffraction, reflectivity, and spectroscopy to compare films exposed to a CO2 plasma to ones exposed to an Ar plasma and to ones annealed in air. We found that the CO2 plasma exposure generated some surface reduction in TiO2 and increased surface roughening by a small amount, but did not initiate any phase changes or crystallite growth. The results suggest that ALD-deposited metal oxide films are robust to low pressure CO2 plasma exposure and are suitable as catalysts or catalyst supports in extended reactions.</description>
      <author>Samuel K. Conlin, Joseph Joel Muhanga, David N. Parette, Robert H. Coridan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k0svz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Capping Ligands on Metal-Nanoparticle-Driven Hydrogen Evolution and CO2 Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/3418_2024_116</link>
      <description>Gerard Mart&#237;, &#193;lvaro Lozano-Roche, Nuria Romero, Laia Franc&#224;s, Karine Philippot, Roger Bofill, Jordi Garc&#305;&#769;a-Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala, Topics in organometallic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403433128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gerard Mart&#237;, &#193;lvaro Lozano-Roche, Nuria Romero, Laia Franc&#224;s, Karine Philippot, Roger Bofill, Jordi Garc&#305;&#769;a-Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/3418_2024_116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Charge Delivery within Covalently Ligated Cobalt Phthalocyanine Electrocatalyst for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03220a</link>
      <description>Alena Kochubei, Aleksei N. Marianov, Yuming Wu, Mengxin Liu, Haoyue Sun, Jun Huang, Oliver J. Conquest, Teng Lu, Yun Liu, Catherine Stampfl, Yijiao Jiang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403460694

                Cobalt(II) phthalocyanine (CoPc) complexes are some of the most active catalysts for CO2 electroreduction reaction (CO2ERR). However, these organic complexes are non-conductive, thus the CO2ERR rate is hindered by the...</description>
      <author>Alena Kochubei, Aleksei N. Marianov, Yuming Wu, Mengxin Liu, Haoyue Sun, Jun Huang, Oliver J. Conquest, Teng Lu, Yun Liu, Catherine Stampfl, Yijiao Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03220a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Structural Dynamics of Cu@Ag Core-Shell Nanoparticles during CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926022</link>
      <description>Daniel Arenas Esteban, Lien Pacquets, Daniel Choukroun, Saskia Hoekx, Ajinkya Kadu, Jonathan Schalck, Nick Daems, Tom Breugelmans, Sara Bals, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496461

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel Arenas Esteban, Lien Pacquets, Daniel Choukroun, Saskia Hoekx, Ajinkya Kadu, Jonathan Schalck, Nick Daems, Tom Breugelmans, Sara Bals</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Construction of Cubi-Mof Derived Heterojunctions with Electron-Rich Effects Enhances Localized Co2 Enrichment Integrated with Si Photocathodes for Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4987328</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Jingwei Hong, Jing Shang, Hiromi Yamashita, Chaohai Wei, Yun Hang Hu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403385945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Jingwei Hong, Jing Shang, Hiromi Yamashita, Chaohai Wei, Yun Hang Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4987328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis of WCu-C/N for Effective Catalyst toward Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3740/mrsk.2024.34.9.409</link>
      <description>Chaoyu Chen, Ze-Da Meng, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Yilei Sun, Liang Yuan, Won&#8208;Chun Oh, Korean Journal of Materials Research. 34(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403581781

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoyu Chen, Ze-Da Meng, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Yilei Sun, Liang Yuan, Won&#8208;Chun Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3740/mrsk.2024.34.9.409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-controlled formation of NixPy catalyst using environmental TEM for potential application in CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926038</link>
      <description>Kshipra Sharma, Tianyi Hu, Kimberly A. Dick, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496672

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kshipra Sharma, Tianyi Hu, Kimberly A. Dick</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ TEM/EELS and spatially resolved XAS/XRF analysis of CuO electrocatalyst for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412925028</link>
      <description>M. Schuster, Gea T. van de Kerkhof, Angela E. Goode, Ur&#353;a Podbev&#353;ek, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496016

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Schuster, Gea T. van de Kerkhof, Angela E. Goode, Ur&#353;a Podbev&#353;ek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412925028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A cluster-nanozyme-coenzyme system mimicking natural photosynthesis for CO2 reduction under intermittent light irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53377-0</link>
      <description>Xiaofeng Cui, Hui Bai, Jun Zhang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Haiyan Yu, Y.Q. Wang, Tingting Kong, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Zhou Lu, Yujie Xiong, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403560302

                Natural photosynthesis utilizes solar energy to convert water and atmospheric CO2 into carbohydrates through all-weather light/dark reactions based on molecule-based enzymes and coenzymes, inspiring extensive development of artificial photosynthesis. However, development of efficient artificial photosynthetic systems free of noble metals, as well as rational integration of functional units into a single system at the molecular level, remain challenging. Here we report an artificial system, the assembly system of Cu6 cluster and cobalt terpyridine complex, that mimics natural photosynthesis through precise integration of nanozyme complexes and ubiquinone (coenzyme Q) on Cu6 clusters. This biomimetic system efficiently reduces CO2 to CO in light reaction, achieving a production rate of 740.7 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1 with high durability for at least 188 hours. Notably, our system realizes the decoupling of light and dark reactions, utilizing the phenol-evolutive coenzyme Q acting as an electron reservoir. By regulating the stabilizer of coenzyme Q, the dark reaction time can be extended up to 8.5 hours, which fully meets the natural day/night cycle requirements. Our findings advance the molecular design of artificial systems that replicate the comprehensive functions of natural photosynthesis. Natural photosynthesis converts H2O and CO2 into carbohydrates through all-weather reactions based on enzymes and coenzymes. Here, the authors report an artificial photosynthesis system under intermittent light irradiation by integrating nanozyme complexes and ubiquinone on a copper nanocluster.</description>
      <author>Xiaofeng Cui, Hui Bai, Jun Zhang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Haiyan Yu, Y.Q. Wang, Tingting Kong, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Zhou Lu, Yujie Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53377-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical reduction of nitrate to ammonia using Fe-based catalyst: insights into N2, CO2, and CO environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114482</link>
      <description>Seon Young Hwang, Gaeun Yun, So Young Kim, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403457588

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seon Young Hwang, Gaeun Yun, So Young Kim, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114482</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stimulating the C&#8722;C coupling ability of ultrafine copper nanoclusters via nitrogen coordination for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124704</link>
      <description>Yanan Cao, Guodong Sun, Mingzhen Hu, Zhe Wang, Xiaoxin Yang, Xinhu Liang, Zengjian Cai, Hao Ren, Fengyi Shen, Dan Cheng, Kebin Zhou, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403409751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Cao, Guodong Sun, Mingzhen Hu, Zhe Wang, Xiaoxin Yang, Xinhu Liang, Zengjian Cai, Hao Ren, Fengyi Shen, Dan Cheng, Kebin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring electrochemical CO2 reduction selectivity over CuSn by modulating surface oxidation state with infrared laser treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156752</link>
      <description>Yunji Gwon, Seon Young Hwang, So Young Kim, Gaeun Yun, Sooyeon Bae, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn, Chemical Engineering Journal. 499(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403510825

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunji Gwon, Seon Young Hwang, So Young Kim, Gaeun Yun, Sooyeon Bae, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photoelectrochemical CO2 reduction activity towards selective generation of alcohols over CuxO/SrTiO3 heterojunction photocathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solmat.2024.113203</link>
      <description>Guguloth Venkanna, Sovan Kumar Patra, Gajanan U. Kapure, Kamal K. Pant, Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells. 278(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403385242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guguloth Venkanna, Sovan Kumar Patra, Gajanan U. Kapure, Kamal K. Pant</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solmat.2024.113203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO2 Reduction via S-Scheme Heterojunction of Amorphous/Crystalline Metal-free Carbon Nitride Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156777</link>
      <description>Liting Wu, Dingyi Yang, Yalin Dong, Ze Wang, Yu Zhang, Tingting Wang, Liang Cheng, Yong Wang, Yizhang Wu, Chemical Engineering Journal. 500(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403503972

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liting Wu, Dingyi Yang, Yalin Dong, Ze Wang, Yu Zhang, Tingting Wang, Liang Cheng, Yong Wang, Yizhang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando TEM Studies of Re@Cu2O-SnO2 catalysts during CO2 reduction reaction with optimized liquid flow configuration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926012</link>
      <description>Cecilia Irene Gho, Katarzyna Bejtka, Marco Fontana, Maria J. Lopez Tendero, Alberto Lopera L&#243;pez, Roger Mir&#243;, Miriam D&#237;az de los Bernardos, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Stefan Merkens, Andrey Chuvilin, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Angelica Chiodoni, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403497223

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cecilia Irene Gho, Katarzyna Bejtka, Marco Fontana, Maria J. Lopez Tendero, Alberto Lopera L&#243;pez, Roger Mir&#243;, Miriam D&#237;az de los Bernardos, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Stefan Merkens, Andrey Chuvilin, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Angelica Chiodoni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting selectivity for multi-carbon products in electrochemical CO2 reduction via enhanced hydroxide adsorption in ultrafine CuOx/CeOx Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114445</link>
      <description>Harshad A. Bandal, Mintesinot Dessalegn Dabaro, Hern Kim, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403424715

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harshad A. Bandal, Mintesinot Dessalegn Dabaro, Hern Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction on Single-Atom aluminum catalysts supported on graphene and N-doped Graphene: Mechanistic insights and hydration effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161523</link>
      <description>Shiuan&#8208;Yau Wu, Tsai-Chun Chuang, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403427125

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiuan&#8208;Yau Wu, Tsai-Chun Chuang, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Molecular Dispersion of Crown Ether&#8208;Decorated Cobalt Phthalocyanineon Carbon Nanotubes for Robust CO2 Reduction through Host&#8208;Guest Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418156</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403494193

                Immobilizing molecular catalysts on electro&#8208;conductive supports (for example, multi&#8208;walled carbon nanotubes, CNTs) represent a promising way to well&#8208;defined catalyst/support interfaces, which has shown appreciable performance for catalytic transformation. However, their full potential is far from achieved due to insufficient utilization of the intrinsic activity for each immobilized molecular catalyst, especially at loadings that should allow decent current densities. In the present work, we discover host&#8208;guest interaction between tetra&#8208;crown ether substituted cobalt phthalocyanine and metal ions, for example K+ ions, not only eliminate catalyst aggregation at immobilization procedures but also reinforce catalyst/support interactions by additional electrostatic attractions under operational conditions. Through simple dip&#8208;coating procedures, a successful single&#8208;molecular dispersion is achieved. Such a catalyst/electrode interface is stable and can selectively catalyze CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion (&#65310;96%) with almost unchanged turnover frequency (TOF) at all loading conditions, which implies a full utilization of the intrinsic activity of supported molecular catalysts. Therefore, a simultaneous achievement of high TOF and high current density (TOF of 111 s&#8208;1 at 38 mA/cm2) is achieved, in an aqueous H&#8208;type electrolyzer at an overpotential of 570 mV.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Molecular Dispersion of Crown Ether&#8208;Decorated Cobalt Phthalocyanineon Carbon Nanotubes for Robust CO2 Reduction through Host&#8208;Guest Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418156</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403494457

                Immobilizing molecular catalysts on electro&#8208;conductive supports (for example, multi&#8208;walled carbon nanotubes, CNTs) represent a promising way to well&#8208;defined catalyst/support interfaces, which has shown appreciable performance for catalytic transformation. However, their full potential is far from achieved due to insufficient utilization of the intrinsic activity for each immobilized molecular catalyst, especially at loadings that should allow decent current densities. In the present work, we discover host&#8208;guest interaction between tetra&#8208;crown ether substituted cobalt phthalocyanine and metal ions, for example K+ ions, not only eliminate catalyst aggregation at immobilization procedures but also reinforce catalyst/support interactions by additional electrostatic attractions under operational conditions. Through simple dip&#8208;coating procedures, a successful single&#8208;molecular dispersion is achieved. Such a catalyst/electrode interface is stable and can selectively catalyze CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion (&#65310;96%) with almost unchanged turnover frequency (TOF) at all loading conditions, which implies a full utilization of the intrinsic activity of supported molecular catalysts. Therefore, a simultaneous achievement of high TOF and high current density (TOF of 111 s&#8208;1 at 38 mA/cm2) is achieved, in an aqueous H&#8208;type electrolyzer at an overpotential of 570 mV.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concentration of carbon dioxide in products of combustion of GTE NK-16ST and NK-16-18ST</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31772/2712-8970-2023-24-4-697-705</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1072;&#1082;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Siberian Aerospace Journal. 24(4)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4403393562

                This paper considers the design of two combustion chambers of a gas turbine engine running on natural gas. One combustion chamber has 32 burners, and the other has 136 nozzles located in two rows in the flame tube head. A major contributor to global warming is considered to be the significant emissions of greenhouse gases, primarily CO2, including those emitted by gas turbine engines and power plants. The reduction of carbon dioxide levels by developing a set of structural measures in the combustion chamber is one of the urgent tasks of engine construction which requires a solution in order to meet modern environmental requirements for gas turbine engines serving as blower drives for gas compressor units. The presented research is dedicated to the analysis of influence of changes in combustion chamber design on reduction of &#1057;&#1054;2 level in exhaust gases of gas turbine engine NK-16ST. Two modifications of the combustion chamber are considered. The first one was a serial combustion chamber with diffusion combustion, the second one was a modernized combustion chamber with a modified front device. Each of the chambers considered was tested as part of the engine. During the study, combustion products were sampled directly in the exhaust shaft and their concentrations, including the CO2 content, were determined. As a result of this work, it was confirmed that there is a possibility to reduce the concentration of CO2 in the engine combustion products up to 20 % without affecting the engine parameters. This reduction in carbon dioxide content was made possible by reducing the completeness of fuel combustion in the combustion chamber. The obtained data on changes in CO2 concentration can be useful in selecting the most suitable mode of engine operation, and the presented approaches to combustion processes organization can be used by developers in designing combustion chambers of natural gas-fired gas turbine engines.</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1072;&#1082;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31772/2712-8970-2023-24-4-697-705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A hybrid electro-thermochemical device for methane production from the air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53336-9</link>
      <description>Yao&#8208;Wei Huang, Da Xu, Shuai Deng, Meng Lin, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403467171

                Coupling direct air capture (DAC) with methane (CH4) production is a potential strategy for fuel production from the air. Here, we report a hybrid electro-thermochemical device for direct CH4 production from air. The proposed device features the cogeneration of carbon dioxide (CO2) and hydrogen (H2) in a single compartment via a bipolar membrane electrodialysis module, avoiding a separate water electrolyzer, followed by a thermochemical methanation reaction to produce CH4. H2-induced disturbances lead to efficient CO2 extraction without pumping requirement. The energy consumption and techno-economic analysis predict an energy reduction of 37.8% for DAC and a cost reduction of 36.6% compared with the decoupled route, respectively. Accordingly, CH4 cost is reduced by 12.6%. Our proof-of-concept experiments show that the energy consumption for CO2 release and H2 production is 704.0 kJ mol&#8722;1 and 967.4 kJ mol&#8722;1, respectively with subsequent methanation achieving a 97.3% conversion of CO2 and a CH4 production energy of 5206.4 kJ mol&#8722;1 showing a promising pathway for fuel processing from the air. Direct capture and conversion of CO2 from the atmosphere is appealing to realize negative emissions but challenging due to the inherent low CO2 concentration. Here, authors report a proof-of-concept hybrid electro-thermochemical device for direct CH4 production from the air.</description>
      <author>Yao&#8208;Wei Huang, Da Xu, Shuai Deng, Meng Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53336-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re-Imagining Trade Policy and Energy Efficiency: Groundbreaking Pathways to Strengthen Environmental Sustainability in South Korea</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14209443</link>
      <description>Dongxue Wang, Yugang He, Applied Sciences. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403491441

                This study explores the long-term interplay between trade policy, energy efficiency, and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions in South Korea, using data spanning from 1985 to 2023. By applying the Fourier autoregressive distributed lag (FARDL) model, the analysis reveals that while trade liberalization initially leads to a 0.23% increase in CO2 emissions for each 1% rise in trade openness&#8212;driven by the energy demands of industrial expansion&#8212;integrating energy efficiency standards within trade agreements helps mitigate these effects over time; this results in a 0.26% reduction in emissions for every 1% improvement in energy efficiency. The study also highlights the dual role of foreign direct investment (FDI), which contributes to a short-term 0.08% rise in emissions but significantly reduces carbon intensity in the long term by facilitating the adoption of cleaner technologies. These findings underscore the importance of innovation and FDI in decoupling economic growth from environmental degradation. The study advocates for the incorporation of energy efficiency measures into trade agreements and the prioritization of green technologies, recommending strategies that could enable South Korea to reduce its CO2 emissions by up to 40% by 2030. This research positions South Korea as a key actor in achieving global climate goals while maintaining economic competitiveness, offering valuable insights into the balance between sustainable development and industrial growth.</description>
      <author>Dongxue Wang, Yugang He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14209443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon footprints: Uncovering spatiotemporal dynamics of global container ship emissions during 2015&#8211;2021</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marpolbul.2024.117165</link>
      <description>Hongchu Yu, Qinglong Fang, Zhixiang Fang, Lei Xu, Jingxian Liu, Marine Pollution Bulletin. 209(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403523302

                The proposed "peak carbon" and "carbon neutral" targets have catapulted the reduction of carbon dioxide (CO</description>
      <author>Hongchu Yu, Qinglong Fang, Zhixiang Fang, Lei Xu, Jingxian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marpolbul.2024.117165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing CO2 Emission of POME Treatment System Using MILP Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.1065.v1</link>
      <description>Sivakumar Pallikodathan, Hasfalina Che Man, Tinia Idaty, A. B. R. Sulaiman, Gunasilan Nagarajoo, Mohamad Firdza Shukery, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403439460

                This paper presents a strategic planning model aimed at optimizing the economic and environmental impacts of Palm Oil Mill Effluent (POME) treatment systems. The model determines the optimal selection of POME treatment systems to minimize environmental impact, specifically focusing on three systems: Anaerobic Digester Tank System (ADT), Covered Lagoon System (CL) with biogas capture, and Open Pond System (OP). The model incorporates constraints related to Fresh Fruit Bunch (FFB) production, POME generation, Biological Oxygen Demand (BOD), Chemical Oxygen Demand (COD), and Carbon Dioxide (CO2) emissions. The optimization framework, formulated as a mixed-integer linear programming (MILP) model, is solved using the GAMS 40.1.0 software. Integer decision variables are used to represent the choice of POME treatment systems that minimize environmental impact. The study specifically considers the ADT, CL, and OP systems, with results indicating that the ADT system is the most effective in reducing BOD, COD, and CO2 equivalent emissions, thereby highlighting its environmental benefits. The model has selected the ADT treatment system, which exhibits the lowest COD, BOD and CO2e emissions. Specifically, the COD registered an 85% reduction rate from 84,830 mg/L to 12,725 mg/L. The BOD level was reduced by 88% resulting in a BOD level from 41,208 mg/L to 4,945 mg/L. The minimum CO2e emission that can be archived was about 3,034 t CO2e per annum. This model provides a valuable tool for governmental agencies and policymakers to guide the private sector in developing environmentally sustainable POME treatment strategies.</description>
      <author>Sivakumar Pallikodathan, Hasfalina Che Man, Tinia Idaty, A. B. R. Sulaiman, Gunasilan Nagarajoo, Mohamad Firdza Shukery</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.1065.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freestanding Germanium Photonic Crystal Waveguide for a Highly Sensitive and Compact Mid-Infrared On-Chip Gas Sensor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssensors.4c00941</link>
      <description>Inki Kim, Jinha Lim, Joonsup Shim, Juhyuk Park, Seung&#8208;Yeop Ahn, Hyeong-Rak Lim, Sanghyeon Kim, ACS Sensors. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403471605

                The performance of mid-infrared (MIR) on-chip gas sensors, operating via laser absorption spectroscopy, hinges critically on light&#8211;matter interaction dynamics, significantly influenced by external confinement and the effective light path length. Conventional on-chip sensors, however, face challenges in achieving the required limit of detection for highly sensitive applications, primarily due to their intrinsically short effective light path. Furthermore, these sensors are limited in their spectral range coverage within the MIR spectrum by the constraints of standard silicon-based platforms. To overcome these limitations, our research presents a novel approach to fabricate a freestanding germanium (Ge) photonic crystal waveguide (PCW) on a germanium-on-insulator (Ge&#8211;OI) platform, utilizing yttrium oxide (Y2O3) as the buried oxide layer. This device leverages the broad transparent windows of Ge and Y2O3, broadening the spectral coverage across the MIR range. The introduction of the PCW and its slow light effect significantly elevate external confinement and light&#8211;matter interactions, enabling a notable reduction in waveguide length, which traditionally limits on-chip configurations. The freestanding structure not only expands the sensing region and enhances external confinement but also prevents the emergence of leaky modes within the PCW. As a result, our compact sensor achieves an exceptionally low LoD of 7.56 ppm for carbon dioxide (CO2) sensing at the operational wavelength of 4.23 &#956;m, with a compact waveguide length of only 800 &#956;m.</description>
      <author>Inki Kim, Jinha Lim, Joonsup Shim, Juhyuk Park, Seung&#8208;Yeop Ahn, Hyeong-Rak Lim, Sanghyeon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssensors.4c00941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dry Reforming of Methane (DRM) over Hydrotalcite-Based Ni-Ga/(Mg, Al)Ox Catalysts: Tailoring Ga Content for Improved Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100721</link>
      <description>Ahmed Yagoub Elnour, Ahmed E. Abasaeed, Anis H. Fakeeha, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Salwa B. Alreshaidan, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403455288

                Dry reforming of methane (DRM) is a promising way to convert methane and carbon dioxide into syngas, which can be further utilized to synthesize value-added chemicals. One of the main challenges for the DRM process is finding catalysts that are highly active and stable. This study explores the potential use of Ni-based catalysts modified by Ga. Different Ni-Ga/(Mg, Al)Ox catalysts, with various Ga/Ni molar ratios (0, 0.1, 0.3, 0.5, and 1), were synthesized by the co-precipitation method. The catalysts were tested for the DRM reaction to evaluate their activity and stability. The Ni/(Mg, Al)Ox and its Ga-modified Ni-Ga/(Mg, Al)Ox were characterized by N2 adsorption&#8211;desorption, Fourier Transform Infrared Spectroscopy (FTIR), H2-temperature-programmed reduction (TPR), X-ray diffraction (XRD), thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) and Raman techniques. The test of catalytic activity, at 700 &#176;C, 1 atm, GHSV of 42,000 mL/h/g, and a CH4: CO2 ratio of 1, revealed that Ga incorporation effectively enhanced the catalyst stability. Particularly, the Ni-Ga/(Mg, Al)Ox catalyst with Ga/Ni ratio of 0.3 exhibited the best catalytic performance, with CH4 and CO2 conversions of 66% and 74%, respectively, and an H2/CO ratio of 0.92. Furthermore, the CH4 and CO2 conversions increased from 34% and 46%, respectively, when testing at 600 &#176;C, to 94% and 96% when the catalytic activity was operated at 850 &#176;C. The best catalyst&#8217;s 20 h stream performance demonstrated its great stability. DFT analysis revealed an alteration in the electronic properties of nickel upon Ga incorporation, the d-band center of the Ga modified catalyst (Ga/Ni ratio of 0.3) shifted closer to the Fermi level, and a charge transfer from Ga to Ni atoms was observed. This research provides valuable insights into the development of Ga-modified catalysts and emphasizes their potential for efficient conversion of greenhouse gases into syngas.</description>
      <author>Ahmed Yagoub Elnour, Ahmed E. Abasaeed, Anis H. Fakeeha, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Salwa B. Alreshaidan, Ahmed S. Al&#8208;Fatesh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide injection into the Achimov formations using reinjection technology by the example of Ach3-4 formation in the Novo-Urengoy area of the Urengoy field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31660/0445-0108-2024-5-80-103</link>
      <description>A. S. Rusanov, A.V. Strekalov, A. S. Romanov, E. A. Reitblat, M. Moskalets, Ashley C. Karp, &#1044;. &#1053;. &#1043;&#1083;&#1091;&#1084;&#1086;&#1074;, Oil and Gas Studies. None(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403575323

                The prerequisites for the study are the calculation results for the cycling process, where carbon dioxide is proposed as the injection agent into the Achimov formations instead of dry gas, with the goal of increasing the condensate recovery factor. The work is focused on the efficiency assessment of carbon dioxide reinjection technology and reducing carbon footprint at a late stage of field development. The research object is the &#1040;ch 3-4 formation within the Novo-Urengoy license area of the Urengoy field. The leading method to identify this problem is the results of the full-scale composite dynamic model in the ECLIPSE 300 format. The model takes into account the history of field development on depletion. The articles deals with two schemes for injecting carbon dioxide into the formation. In the first scheme, pure carbon dioxide is injected in a closed-loop system, but carbon neutrality through storage is not achieved. In the second scheme, carbon dioxide is injected using reinjection technology. Once injection begins, gas production stops. Only the condensate separated from the formation gas during low-temperature separation is sold and sent for further processing. After allocation of the condensate, the mixture of natural gas and carbon dioxide, in a specific proportion, is sent to the compressor station for reinjection into the formation in a gaseous state. Injecting pure carbon dioxide achieves a condensate recovery factor similar to that of gas injection with a 30 % carbon dioxide mixture. However, this option is less economically viable compared to the base and other scenarios due to high capital costs for upgrading the existing gas processing equipment (requiring the construction of an amine treatment unit). With carbon dioxide injection using reinjection technology, in addition to recovering extra condensate that had condensed during natural depletion, a reduction in the carbon footprint is also achieved. To maximize the condensate recovery factor, the optimal concentration of carbon dioxide in the injection mixture has been determined. The optimal timing for the start of injection was identified to maximize gas recovery. Economic efficiency is expected from the additional recovery of condensate trapped in the reservoir and from achieving carbon neutrality through the monetization and storage of carbon dioxide.</description>
      <author>A. S. Rusanov, A.V. Strekalov, A. S. Romanov, E. A. Reitblat, M. Moskalets, Ashley C. Karp, &#1044;. &#1053;. &#1043;&#1083;&#1091;&#1084;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31660/0445-0108-2024-5-80-103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site selection and effects of background towers on urban CO2 estimates: A case study from central downtown Zhengzhou in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120169</link>
      <description>Ge Ren, Kailun Du, A. Karion, Shiqi Zhao, Israel L&#243;pez-Coto, Wei Wang, J. R. Whetstone, Hong Lin, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403457990

                With China's proposed carbon reduction goals, many carbon monitoring pilot city projects have been launched, involving greenhouse gas (GHG) inverse estimate analysis based on GHG observations. For the evaluation of emissions estimates in a targeted urban area, the contributions of extra-urban fluxes on urban GHG observations must be excluded, especially for core cities within urban agglomerations, which face more severe emission interference from adjacent cities. In this study, we quantified the impact of external emissions on urban carbon dioxide (CO</description>
      <author>Ge Ren, Kailun Du, A. Karion, Shiqi Zhao, Israel L&#243;pez-Coto, Wei Wang, J. R. Whetstone, Hong Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of green credit policy on carbon emissions based on China&#8217;s provincial panel data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-73942-3</link>
      <description>Xuerui Yang, Lianmei Zhu, Tong Wei, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403432116

                The attainment of "carbon peaking" and "carbon neutrality" is of utmost significance for the optimal progress of China's economy. As the main channel for green finance, the carbon reduction effectiveness of green credit policy is worth discussing. This article constructs an analytical framework for green credit, carbon emissions and technological advancement. Based on panel data from 30 provincial administrative regions in China from 2012 to 2021, this article uses the mediation effect model and the Spatial Durbin Model to investigate the transmission mechanism and spatial spillover effect of green credit policies on carbon emissions. According to baseline regression model results, our study revealed that overall, carbon emissions were reduced by green credit. The spatial spillover effect of green credit on carbon emissions points to the interconnectedness of different regions in terms of environmental impact. The significant negative indirect effect indicates that the increase of local green credit also has a significant inhibitory effect on surrounding carbon dioxide emissions. It suggests that efforts to reduce carbon emissions in one area can have positive consequences for neighboring regions as well. Green credit is able to reduce carbon emissions indirectly via technological advancement, according to the mechanism testing mediation effect model. This paper presents policy recommendations for relevant departments.</description>
      <author>Xuerui Yang, Lianmei Zhu, Tong Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-73942-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whole-life greenhouse gas emission reduction and removal strategies for buildings: Impacts and diffusion potentials across EU Member States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122915</link>
      <description>Nicolas Alaux, Csaba Marton, Jacob Steinmann, Dominik Maierhofer, Alessio Mastrucci, D. Petrou, Tajda Potr&#269; Obrecht, Delphine Ramon, Xavier Le Den, Karen Allacker, Alexander Passer, Martin R&#246;ck, Journal of Environmental Management. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403527689

                As the European Union (EU) is aiming to realize climate neutrality by 2050, there is a need to investigate greenhouse gas (GHG) reduction and carbon dioxide removal strategies (CRRS) from a life cycle perspective. Existing literature lacks harmonization of building-related strategies considering the whole-life cycle of buildings and the interlinkages across life cycle stages. The aim and novelty of this study was to systematically identify, classify and quantify the impacts of CRRS, as well as assess their applicability in different EU Member States. We identified a total of 35 measures grouped in 11 CRRS for the whole-life cycle of buildings. We classified these measures according to various criteria, such as the avoid-shift-improve framework or the life cycle stages influenced. We then assessed the potential diffusion of these strategies in each EU Member State up to 2050 via qualitative assessment criteria. We could achieve notable short-term reductions in GHG emissions by improving use-phase energy use, selecting low-carbon materials or reducing the per capital space demand. In the medium to long term, the applicability and reduction potential of strategies such as circularity and prioritizing renovation over new construction will increase as supply chains and skills develop across the EU. Due to their different potentials and times of implementation, the entire range of strategies is needed to support building and construction transition efforts.</description>
      <author>Nicolas Alaux, Csaba Marton, Jacob Steinmann, Dominik Maierhofer, Alessio Mastrucci, D. Petrou, Tajda Potr&#269; Obrecht, Delphine Ramon, Xavier Le Den, Karen Allacker, Alexander Passer, Martin R&#246;ck</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrate-dependent antimony oxidase in an uncultured &lt;i&gt;Symbiobacteriaceae&lt;/i&gt; member</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae204</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Zhipeng Yin, Wei Ma, Jialong Hao, Fei Tian, Jianbo Shi, The ISME Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403469138

                Abstract Autotrophic antimony (Sb) oxidation coupled to nitrate reduction plays an important role in the transformation and detoxification of Sb. However, the specific oxidase involved in this process has yet to be identified. Herein, we enriched the microbiota capable of nitrate-dependent Sb(III) oxidation and identified a new Sb(III) oxidase in an uncultured member of Symbiobacteriaceae. Incubation experiments demonstrated that nitrate-dependent Sb(III) oxidation occurred in the microcosm supplemented with Sb(III) and nitrate. Both the 16S rRNA gene and metagenomic analyses indicated that a species within Symbiobacteriaceae played a crucial role in this process. Furthermore, carbon-13 isotope labelling with carbon dioxide-fixing Rhodopseudomonas palustris in combination with nanoscale secondary ion mass spectrometry revealed that a newly characterized oxidase from the dimethylsulfoxide reductase family, designated as NaoABC, was responsible for autotrophic Sb(III) oxidation coupled with nitrate reduction. The NaoABC complex functions in conjunction with the nitrate reductase NarGHI, forming a redox loop that transfers electrons from Sb(III) to nitrate, thereby generating the energy necessary for autotrophic growth. This research offers new insights into the understanding of how microbes link Sb and nitrogen biogeochemical cycles in the environment.</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Zhipeng Yin, Wei Ma, Jialong Hao, Fei Tian, Jianbo Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of Mn-based low-temperature SCR denitrification catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05140h</link>
      <description>Jiadong Zhang, Zengyi Ma, Ang Cao, Jianhua Yan, Li Wang, Miao Yu, Linlin Hu, Shaojing Pan, RSC Advances. 14(44)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403492703

                Selective catalytic reduction (SCR) is a efficiently nitrogen oxides removal technology from stationary source flue gases. Catalysts are key component in the technology, but currently face problems including poor low-temperature activity, narrow temperature windows, low selectivity, and susceptibility to water passivation and sulphur dioxide poisoning. To develop high-efficiency low-temperature denitrification activity catalyst, manganese-based catalysts have become a focal point of research globally for low-temperature SCR denitrification catalysts. This article investigates the denitrification efficiency of unsupported manganese-based catalysts, exploring the influence of oxidation valence, preparation method, crystallinity, crystal form, and morphology structure. It examines the catalytic performance of binary and multicomponent unsupported manganese-based catalysts, focusing on the use of transition metals and rare earth metals to modify manganese oxide. Furthermore, the synergistic effect of supported manganese-based catalysts is studied, considering metal oxides, molecular sieves, carbon materials, and other materials (composite carriers and inorganic non-metallic minerals) as supports. The reaction mechanism of low-temperature denitrification by manganese-based catalysts and the mechanism of sulphur dioxide/water poisoning are analysed in detail, and the development of practical and efficient manganese-based catalysts is considered.</description>
      <author>Jiadong Zhang, Zengyi Ma, Ang Cao, Jianhua Yan, Li Wang, Miao Yu, Linlin Hu, Shaojing Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05140h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharing is caring for the environment: But why would managers resist shared mobility?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bse.4006</link>
      <description>Alex Ntsiful, Business Strategy and the Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403507016

                Abstract The debate on carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) reduction strategies for a sustainable environment continues unabated. Thus, this study proposes and validates a model for understanding essential factors that can explain resistance to managers' bus&#8208;sharing system (MBS). MBS is a sustainability strategy where organizations have well&#8208;maintained buses to transport 10&#8211;15 managers to and from work. By drawing on an extended status quo bias theory, the study sampled and analyzed 234 responses from managers using the partial least square structural equation modeling. The results show that perceived switching benefits (PSWB) and perceived switching costs (PSWC) relate to perceived value and influence resistance to the proposed MBS. Meanwhile, managers' family/personal life conflicts and perceived prestige concerns increase the PSWC. These findings have essential theoretical implications for sustainability scholarship and inform organizations to adopt family&#8208;friendly policies to reduce resistance to MBS.</description>
      <author>Alex Ntsiful</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bse.4006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and swift heating technique for crafting highly graphitized carbon and crystalline silicon (Si@GC) composite anodes for lithium&#8208;ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240025</link>
      <description>Chinmayee Padwal, Xijue Wang, Hong Duc Pham, Thi My Linh Hoang, Sagadevan Mundree, Deepak P. Dubal, Battery energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403484794

                Abstract The synthesis of battery materials from biomass as feedstock is not only effective but also aligns with sustainable practices. However, current methods like slow pyrolysis/heating are both energy&#8208;intensive and economically impractical. Hence, integrating energy&#8208;efficient technologies becomes imperative to curtail substantial energy consumption and, consequently, minimize carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) emissions during electricity usage. Herein, we employed a one&#8208;step pyrolysis/reduction based on the microwave heating method to synthesize a composite of high&#8208;purity silicon and highly graphitized carbon (Si@GC) from rice husk as feedstock. Compared to the conventional heating methods, the Si@GC samples prepared via the microwave heating method required less time (30&#8211;50 min). Benefiting from ultrahigh heating rates, the highly graphitized carbon and crystalline silicon composite was successfully synthesized. The synthesis by microwave irradiation showed homogenous material, excellent surface area, essential functional groups, and crystallinity revealing the outstanding reaction kinetics to form the material. The as&#8208;synthesized Si@GC composite anode material delivered a high discharge capacity of 799 mAh/g with high cyclic stability of ~71% over 120 cycles. The ex situ ToF&#8208;SIMS revealed great inorganic SEI composition, mainly consisting of the fluorinated species and carbonate species produced at the initial cycle. This investigation provides a novel rapid heating method for the synthesis of battery materials, which can also be extended for other materials and applications.</description>
      <author>Chinmayee Padwal, Xijue Wang, Hong Duc Pham, Thi My Linh Hoang, Sagadevan Mundree, Deepak P. Dubal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiffGLE: Differentiable Coarse-Grained Dynamics using Generalized
  Langevin Equation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.08424</link>
      <description>Jinu Jeong, Ishan Nadkarni, N. R. Aluru, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403444161

                Capturing the correct dynamics at the Coarse-Grained (CG) scale remains a central challenge in the advancement of systematic CG models for soft matter simulations. The Generalized Langevin Equation (GLE), rooted in the Mori-Zwanzig formalism, provides a robust framework for incorporating friction and stochastic forces into CG models, that are lost due to the reduction in degrees of freedom. Leveraging recent advancements in Automatic Differentiation (AD) and reformulating the non-Markovian GLE using a colored noise ansatz, we present a top-down approach for accurately parameterizing the non-Markovian GLE for different coarse-grained fluids that accurately reproduces the velocity-autocorrelation function of the original All-Atom (AA) model. We demonstrate our approach on two different fluids namely, SPC/E water and carbon dioxide which have distinct structure and dynamical characteristics. Importantly, by being end-to-end differentiable, this approach offers a simplified and efficient solution to achieving accurate CG dynamics, effectively bypassing the complexities inherent in most bottom-up methods.</description>
      <author>Jinu Jeong, Ishan Nadkarni, N. R. Aluru</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.08424</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited Manganese Dioxides and Their Composites as Electrocatalysts for Energy Conversion Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401907</link>
      <description>Masaharu Nakayama, Wataru Yoshida, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403463183

                Enhancing the efficiencies of electrochemical reactions for converting renewable energy into clean chemical fuels as well as generating clean energy is critical to achieving carbon neutrality. However, this enhancement can be achieved using materials that are not constrained by resource limitations and those that can be converted into devices in a scalable manner, preferably for industrial applications. This review explores the applications of electrochemically deposited manganese dioxides (MnO2) and their composites as electrochemical catalysts for oxygen evolution (OER) and hydrogen evolution reactions for converting renewable energy into chemical fuels. It also explores their applications as electrochemical catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and bifunctional OER/ORR for the efficient operation of fuel cells and metal&#8211;air batteries, respectively. Manganese is the second most abundant transition metal in the Earth&#8217;s crust, and electrodeposition represents a binder&#8208;free and scalable technique for fabricating devices (electrodes). To propose an improved catalyst design, the studies on the electrodeposition mechanism of MnO2 as well as the fabrication techniques for MnO2&#8208;based nanocomposites accumulated in the development of electrodes for supercapacitors are also included in this review.</description>
      <author>Masaharu Nakayama, Wataru Yoshida</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mechanical and hydrochemical properties of cemented calcareous soil under long-term soaking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-75540-9</link>
      <description>Peng Feng, Piergiorgio Cao, Sili Ren, Junping Ren, Ying Dong, Gao&#8208;Lin Wu, Ran Tang, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403523263

                This study investigates the impact of long-term water immersion on the mechanical and hydrochemical properties of cemented calcareous soil, emphasizing the critical role of carbonate content in mechanical performance. Utilizing hydrochemical analysis and triaxial testing, the research revealed that prolonged immersion disrupts the acid-base balance of the solution, resulting in an increased concentration of ions and chemicals. Significant dissolution of carbonates and soluble minerals occurs, which reacts with carbon dioxide to generate bicarbonate ions, thereby elevating the alkalinity of the soaking solution. Additionally, the gradual dissolution of clay minerals compromises the cementitious structure, leading to particle reorientation and interlocking. The study quantitatively assesses the changes in soil properties, demonstrating a substantial reduction in soil cohesion by up to 86.1% and an increase in the internal friction angle by 37.5%. Furthermore, the gradual dissolution of clay minerals compromises the cementitious structure, resulting in particle reorientation and interlocking that contribute to the observed mechanical changes. The findings underscore the importance of understanding the effects of extended immersion on the stability and engineering applicability of cemented calcareous soils.</description>
      <author>Peng Feng, Piergiorgio Cao, Sili Ren, Junping Ren, Ying Dong, Gao&#8208;Lin Wu, Ran Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-75540-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electroencephalographic depression after abruptly increasing partial pressure of end-tidal carbon dioxide: a case series</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871-024-02764-7</link>
      <description>Shikuo Li, Yuyi Zhao, Qifeng Wang, Xuehan Li, Chao Chen, Yunxia Zuo, BMC Anesthesiology. 24(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403423909

                Prolonged electroencephalographic depression during surgery is associated with poor outcomes for patients. However, the published literature on electroencephalographic depression caused by a sudden increase in the partial pressure of end-tidal carbon dioxide (PETCO2) is lacking. We report four patients who were scheduled for laparoscopic liver surgery under general anesthesia. During the process of EEG monitoring with Sedline, four patients experienced electroencephalographic depression closely after a sudden increase in PETCO2. The four patients showed that electroencephalographic depression mainly manifested as a slow in EEG frequency, a reduction in the amplitude and power of EEG, and a decrease in spectral edge frequency. Patient state index was elevated in three cases. To summarize, our patients showed EEG depression when PETCO2 suddenly increased, which suggests that clinical doctors should be alert to electroencephalographic depression when the PETCO2 abruptly increases. EEG monitoring devices should be applied in patients with possible hypercapnia. Anesthesiologists must comprehensively interpret the raw EEG, spectral edge frequency, and density spectral array data, in addition to patient sedation index values.</description>
      <author>Shikuo Li, Yuyi Zhao, Qifeng Wang, Xuehan Li, Chao Chen, Yunxia Zuo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871-024-02764-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Results on the Use of Straw Cover and Effective Microorganisms for Mitigating GHG and Ammonia Emissions in Pig Slurry Storage Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14101788</link>
      <description>Martire Ang&#233;lica Terrero Turb&#237;, Melisa G&#243;mez Garrido, Oumaima El bied, Jos&#233; Gregorio Cuevas Bencosme, &#193;ngel Faz Cano, Agriculture. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403400565

                Spain has been the largest pork producer in the EU in recent years, leading to significant pig slurry (PS) production that requires proper management to prevent environmental impacts. The objectives of this study were to quantify greenhouse gas (GHG) and ammonia emissions and to characterize the PS in storage pond systems. A straw cover pond (SP) and addition of effective microorganisms (EMs) in a biological pond (BP) were used to treat the slurries. During two periods (autumn and spring), PS was characterized and GHG (CO2, CH4, N2O) and NH3 emissions were measured with a dynamic chamber. After 5 weeks of storage, BP achieved a reduction of 96% for CO2, 98% for CH4 and 59% for NH3 compared to the control pond (CP) in spring, while SP presented a 74% reduction for CO2 in autumn, and 60% and 97% reductions for CH4 and NH3, respectively, in spring. Additionally, the PS samples showed a decreasing trend for EC, dry matter, COD, BOD5, total N, NH4+-N, Org.-N, NO3&#8722;-N, and PO43&#8722; during both seasons. This preliminary study shows promise in reducing GHG/NH3 emissions and improving PS properties, but further replication is recommended. Varying straw cover thickness, optimizing EM dose, and a pH reduction may enhance outcomes.</description>
      <author>Martire Ang&#233;lica Terrero Turb&#237;, Melisa G&#243;mez Garrido, Oumaima El bied, Jos&#233; Gregorio Cuevas Bencosme, &#193;ngel Faz Cano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14101788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power&#8208;to&#8208;Ethanol Using Bimetallic Catalysts: Reaction Paths, Transfer to Gas Diffusion Electrode, and Future Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elsa.202400017</link>
      <description>Elisabeth Gr&#228;fin von Westarp, Burkhard Hecker, Hermann Tempel, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel, Electrochemical Science Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403394539

                ABSTRACT Ethanol is a promising product for the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), as ethanol as a value&#8208;added product can help to enable the near&#8208;term feasibility of this technique, thus Power&#8208;to&#8208;ethanol can act as a pioneering process for the CO 2 RR. Furthermore, CO 2 RR offers a green production process for ethanol in addition to biomass fermentation. However, the formation of ethanol via electrolysis often competes with ethylene production, which makes the selective formation of ethanol more difficult. We show that this problem can be circumvented by using a bimetallic catalyst that provides abundant *CO and thus activates an alternative and selective reaction path for ethanol. However, this study was carried out in an aqueous&#8208;fed H&#8208;type electrolyzer, which has mass transport limitations and thus insufficient current densities. To solve this issue, the studied catalyst is transferred to a gas diffusion electrode. Here we emphasize that, in addition to other relevant parameters, the choice of the binder also can have a high impact on the performance of the electrode. As an outlook, various enhanced reactor designs and their influence on ethanol formation are presented.</description>
      <author>Elisabeth Gr&#228;fin von Westarp, Burkhard Hecker, Hermann Tempel, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elsa.202400017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy use and greenhouse gas emissions in selected tea factories in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pclm.0000329</link>
      <description>Joy Kibet, Sammy Letema, PLOS Climate. 3(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403448486

                Tea sector is a major contributor to Kenya&#8217;s economy through foreign exchange via export. However, extensive amount of energy is required to produce one kilogram of tea, making tea processing energy-intensive. Comparing greenhouse gas emissions from different types of energy consumed in tea factories is imperative to enable policymakers make informed intervention in emission reduction. Reducing greenhouse gas emissions in tea factories is one of the pathways to meeting Kenya&#8217;s nationally determined 32% reduction of carbon emissions by 2030 and commitment to the Paris Agreement. This paper assesses greenhouse gas emissions from different sources of energy used in four tea factories in Kenya. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change emission factor is used to calculate the total emissions of each type of energy used for 5 years. Life cycle assessment using SimaPro 8 software, Eco-indicator 99 method and Eco invent database was used to assess the specific compound causing the emission. The findings reveal that the 5-year greenhouse gas emissions by biogas, solar, wood, briquettes, and electricity are 336.111, 7.108, 3057.729, and 1,338.28 kg CO 2 /MWh, respectively. Firewood has the highest concentration of carbon dioxide, while solar energy has the least. Analysis of variance confirms significant difference (0.05&gt;p = 0.0272) in greenhouse gas emissions from the different energy sources. Post-hoc analyses shows a significant difference in emissions between solar and firewood (p&lt;0.0125) and no significant difference between other sources of energy. The key environmental hotspot is the energy intensive processes such as drying involved in tea production and processing, which leads to consumption of fossil fuel in the factories. To reduce such key hotspot, switching to renewable energy sources is key. Sustainability in the tea sector can therefore be achieved through switching to macadamia briquettes as a source of thermal energy and a combination of electricity and solar for electrical energy.</description>
      <author>Joy Kibet, Sammy Letema</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pclm.0000329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascade Conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Ethylene Carbonate under Ambient Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11390</link>
      <description>Zhaoyu Wen, Mengjing Wang, Chen&#8208;Jui Liang, Bolun Fan, Yuchen Yan, Fan Jia, Na Han, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403553455

                Ethylene carbonate (EC) is the simplest cyclic carbonate with great industrial significance, most importantly as the vital electrolyte component for lithium-ion batteries. Its conventional synthesis generally involves the use of toxic precursors and requires elevated temperatures and pressures. Herein, we propose a cascade catalytic route for converting CO2 to EC under ambient conditions. Such a hybrid reaction scheme consists of the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to ethylene catalyzed by copper in a membrane electrode assembly reactor, the bromine-mediated conversion of ethylene to bromoethanol catalyzed by WO3 nanoarrays grown on carbon cloth, and the reaction between bromoethanol and CO2 to form EC. By separately optimizing individual catalytic steps and then integrating them together in series, we achieved the conversion of CO2 to EC at a good yield under room temperature and atmospheric pressure. Our study also represents the first demonstration about the successful synthesis of organic carbonates from CO2 as the exclusive carbon source.</description>
      <author>Zhaoyu Wen, Mengjing Wang, Chen&#8208;Jui Liang, Bolun Fan, Yuchen Yan, Fan Jia, Na Han, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Thermal Chamber Expansion of VH-SAGD Process Using CO2-Inducing Effect for Heavy Oil Reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102260</link>
      <description>Haojun Xie, Shiming Zhang, Guanghuan Wu, Wei Li, Processes. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403448923

                In heavy oil thermal recovery processes, higher pressure usually leads to low dryness and expansion difficulty for the injected steam in thermal recovery processes, which will result in lower oil recovery and more carbon emissions. This paper proposed a new CO2-inducing method to accelerate the steam chamber expansion, based on a core flooding experiment and numerical simulation. First, the CO2 showed significant viscosity reduction at high pressure in the PVT test. In the core flooding experiment, the CO2 provided strong flow conductivity in porous media for the thermal flooding, as the CO2 pre-injection restrained the steam condensation. Using the CO2-inducing method, CO2 pre-injection before steam built a fast flow channel in a relatively higher permeability layer and reduced the thermal injection pressure by about 1.0~2.4 MPa. As a result, the steam overlap around the injection wells became slower and the gravity drainage process was able to heat and displace the heavy oil above the channel. Furthermore, the CO2 gas trapped at the top reduced heat loss by about 12.4%. The field numerical simulation showed that this new method improved thermal recovery by 7.5% and reduced CO2 emissions by about 18 million kg/unit for the whole process. This method changes the conventional thermal expansion direction by CO2 inducing effect and fundamentally reduces heat loss, which provides significant advantages in low-carbon EOR.</description>
      <author>Haojun Xie, Shiming Zhang, Guanghuan Wu, Wei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BetterFuture Co. and its CO2 Footprint: A Case to Learn About ESG (Environmental, Social and Governance)/GHG (Greenhouse Gas)/CO2, Compliance, and SMART Goal Setting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/21649987241291014</link>
      <description>Melinda Ratkai, A. van Rheede, Journal of Hospitality &amp; Tourism Cases. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403520215

                The case study delves into the complex issue of CO2 footprint from three distinct viewpoints: sustainability, legislative, and managerial. Each perspective offers unique insights into the challenges and opportunities of mitigating greenhouse gas emissions using scope 1, 2, and 3 data. From a sustainability viewpoint, students are encouraged to explore the concept of CO2 footprint within the broader context of ESG considerations. Key questions delve into understanding sustainability frameworks, assessing the impact of CO2 emissions on ecosystems and communities, and exploring strategies for carbon footprint reduction aligned with sustainability goals. From the legislative perspective, students examine the regulatory landscape governing CO2 emissions. Students learn how legal frameworks shape corporate behavior by studying global sustainability goals such as the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), the Global Reporting Initiative (GRI), and national legislation. Discussion questions focus on analyzing the effectiveness of existing regulations, identifying gaps, and proposing regulatory strategies to incentivize carbon reduction. The managerial perspective emphasizes decision-making and goal-setting within organizations. Students explore how managers can leverage data on CO2 footprint to set SMART (Specific, Measurable, Achievable, Relevant, Time-bound) goals for departments or individuals. This involves understanding the role of carbon accounting, evaluating trade-offs in sustainability initiatives, and exploring best practices in integrating sustainability into organizational strategy. The case encourages critical thinking and data analysis, allowing educators to pose additional questions based on student interests and course objectives. The rich dataset allows for extensive exploration beyond the core questions, facilitating interdisciplinary learning across various courses. Ultimately, the case is a versatile teaching tool that can be applied to courses focusing on sustainability, environmental studies, business ethics, managerial decision-making, and public policy. It equips students with the knowledge and skills to navigate the multifaceted challenges of reducing their CO2 footprint while advancing sustainable practices within organizations and society.</description>
      <author>Melinda Ratkai, A. van Rheede</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/21649987241291014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cradle-To-Gate Analyses of Biochar Produced from Agricultural Crop Residues by Vacuum Pyrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ce/zkae069</link>
      <description>Nakum Divyangkumar, N. L. Panwar, Chitranjan Agrawal, Trilok Gupta, G. L. Meena, Manjeet Singh, Clean Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403517028

                Abstract Agricultural waste, if not managed efficiently, can pose significant environmental threats. Biochar production, a cost-effective solution, offers a potential to significantly reduce carbon dioxide emissions and thereby combat climate change. However, the environmental impact of this process is not uniform and varies depending on the agricultural residue used. These impacts, spanning the entire lifecycle from cultivation to disposal, underscore the necessity of a thorough assessment before biochar can be widely adopted for practical applications. This study employs a cradle-to-gate approach to evaluate the life cycle assessment of producing biochar from various agro-residues, such as rice husk, sugarcane bagasse, and corn cob. The life cycle assessment was conducted using SimaPro software, version 9.5.0.1, and the ReCiPe impact assessment method. The results indicate that corn cob cultivation has the highest impact across most categories, while rice husks exhibit higher water consumption (2.8&#215;103 m3). Using diesel, electricity, and fertilizers significantly contributes to global warming potential. Sugarcane bagasse shows the most negligible impact during biomass cultivation. However, pyrolysis processes exhibit high implications on various indicators. Applying biochar to soil for carbon sequestration and improvement can reduce global warming potential. Sensitivity analysis demonstrates a notable reduction in global warming potential and cumulative energy demand, approximately 10-24 % and 4-11 MWh, respectively. Paddy cultivation and rice husk biochar production have a lesser environmental impact. Changing energy sources during biomass growth and biochar production significantly influences environmental factors.</description>
      <author>Nakum Divyangkumar, N. L. Panwar, Chitranjan Agrawal, Trilok Gupta, G. L. Meena, Manjeet Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ce/zkae069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coaxially Bi/ZnO@ZnSe array photocathode enables highly efficient CO2 to C1 conversion via long&#8208;lived high&#8208;energy photoelectrons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401436</link>
      <description>Wei Ma, Haiqiang Mu, Zhenli Lv, Jia-Xing Guo, Shengli Zhu, Yonghong Li, Xiaozhong Wang, Jing Li, Feng Li, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533548

                The key aspect of the photoelectrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (PEC CO2 RR) lies in designing cathode materials that can generate high&#8208;energy photoelectrons, enabling the activation and conversion of CO2 into high&#8208;value products. In this study, a coaxially wrapped ZnO@ZnSe array heterostructure was synthesized using a simple anion exchange strategy and metallic Bi nanoparticles (NPs) were subsequently deposited on the surface to construct a Bi/ZnO@ZnSe photocathode with high CO2 conversion capability. This array photocathode possesses a large aspect ratio, which simultaneously satisfies a low charge carrier migration path and a large specific surface area that facilitates mass transfer. Additionally, the barrier formed at the n&#8208;n heterojunction interface hinders the transfer of high&#8208;energy photoelectrons from ZnSe to lower energy levels, resulting in their rapid capture by Bi while maintaining a relatively long lifetime. These captured electrons act as active sites, efficiently converting CO2 into CO with a Faradaic efficiency above 88.9% at &#8208;0.9 V vs. RHE and demonstrating superior stability. This work provides a novel approach for synthesizing high&#8208;energy photoelectrode materials with long lifetimes.</description>
      <author>Wei Ma, Haiqiang Mu, Zhenli Lv, Jia-Xing Guo, Shengli Zhu, Yonghong Li, Xiaozhong Wang, Jing Li, Feng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio carbon footprints and decarbonization progress of China's asset managers: a decade analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4976708/v1</link>
      <description>Dabo Guan, Jinglei Wang, Xiang Yu, Wenqiang Wang, Gesangyangji Gesang, Jie Li, Shuping Li, Ning Zhang, Zengkai Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403386894

                Abstract Despite repeated calls to reduce CO2 emissions, asset managers continue to invest heavily in carbon-intensive assets, creating hidden carbon bombs within their equity portfolios. Timely tracking of portfolio carbon footprints is essential as a dynamic tool for monitoring companies' efforts to reduce carbon reduction. However, the availability and quality of firm-level CO2 emissions data present significant challenges in measuring financed emissions. As a result, potential climate-related risks for asset managers are likely to be severely underestimated. This study analyses CO2 emissions embodied in the equity portfolios of 105 Chinese asset managers from 2010 to 2020. Results show that over 50% of financed emissions comes from carbon-intensive assets, primarily emitted by individual high-emitting companies. Positively, some managers have reallocated capital towards High-tech Industries and Advanced Services during the period, and achieved over 50% reduction in carbon intensity. Comparison between asset managers' commitments versus actual mitigation actions shows that five out of six leading asset managers in China have failed to take their mitigation actions, despite their commitment to the UN Principles for Responsible Investment (UNPRI). Our qualitative analysis provide scientific evidence for China's asset managers in measuring companies&#8217; portfolio carbon footprints and supporting their decarbonization pathways.</description>
      <author>Dabo Guan, Jinglei Wang, Xiang Yu, Wenqiang Wang, Gesangyangji Gesang, Jie Li, Shuping Li, Ning Zhang, Zengkai Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4976708/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the dependence of the catalytic activity of nickel ferrite nanoparticles in the oxidative dehydrogenation of 2-propanol on the crystallite size</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-4jzln</link>
      <description>Michael Pittenauer, Raffael Rameshan, Florian Schrenk, Chunlei Wang, Moritz Eder, Gareth S. Parkinson, Christoph Rameshan, Karin F&#246;ttinger, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403466060

                Nickel ferrite spinel nanoparticles of different crystallite sizes were prepared in a glycine assisted sol-gel autocombustion reaction and characterised by powder x-ray diffraction, attenuated total reflection infrared spectroscopy, near ambient pressure x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, nitrogen physisorption, hydrogen and carbon monoxide temperature programmed reduction and oxygen and carbon dioxide temperature programmed desorption. A different distribution of Ni2+ cations in the tetrahedrally and octahedrally coordinated sites of the spinel lattice and an increased reducibility of the smaller crystallite size sample were identified as the main impacts of different crystallite size. Their catalytic activity in the oxidative dehydrogenation of 2-propanol was investigated by temperature programmed reaction studies using different ratios of 2-propanol:O2 as well as of possible parallel and consecutive reactions at atmospheric pressure and maximum 400 &#176;C. Operando-DRIFTS-MS studies at different 2-propanol:O2 ratios were carried out under continuous-flow conditions at atmospheric pressure as well. Thereby, the increased reducibility of the small crystallite size sample could be linked to an unselective activity for dehydrogenation yielding acetone and hydrogen, partial oxidation of 2-propanol and acetone, and total combustion leading to a complex network of reactions going on, being further pushed by an excess of oxygen. Ex-situ x-ray diffraction measurements were performed following the temperature programmed reaction experiments. The large crystallite size sample was found to be generally less active, but more selective towards non-oxidative dehydrogenation. Ex-situ x-ray diffraction measurements performed following the temperature programmed reaction experiments confirmed the increased reducibility of the smaller crystallite size sample. In the operando IR studies, 2-propoxide, adsorbed acetone, carbonates and acetates were identified as species occurring in the reaction.</description>
      <author>Michael Pittenauer, Raffael Rameshan, Florian Schrenk, Chunlei Wang, Moritz Eder, Gareth S. Parkinson, Christoph Rameshan, Karin F&#246;ttinger</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-4jzln</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of welding gas mixtures on weld material and bead geometry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1757-899x/1315/1/012007</link>
      <description>Michael A. Unger, Jo&#227;o R. Neves, Martin Schnall, IOP Conference Series Materials Science and Engineering. 1315(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403545844

                Abstract Shielding gas is an essential parameter in welding processes, serves to shield the molten material from the atmosphere and external contaminations while providing a stable electric-arc pathway during the process, thus influencing the quality of the weld bead and several other aspects of the process. Therefore, any welding-based process, such as wire-arc additive manufacturing, could benefit from shielding gas mixture optimisation to selectively improve the processing and possibly the final mechanical properties of the welded material. In this study welding of EN AW 5183 aluminium (single weld bead and wire-arc additive manufacturing build-up) was conducted using several gas mixtures and their influence on final geometry defects, and microstructure measured. The gas mixtures used were a combination of varying amounts of carbon dioxide, nitrogen, and oxygen. These were added to commercially available argon gas. It was observed that: CO 2 additions led to an unfavourable bonding defect and increased mean grain size; nitrogen additions caused a decrease in mean grain size, decreased pore count while maintaining a similar pore volume fraction to the reference argon mixture samples; oxygen additions showed slight reduction of mean grain size, decreased pore count and decreased pore volume fraction. These results further showcase that varying shielding gas mixtures influence the final material properties and should be considered as an additional improvement route for conventional welding and additive manufacturing.</description>
      <author>Michael A. Unger, Jo&#227;o R. Neves, Martin Schnall</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1757-899x/1315/1/012007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Electro&#8208;Biosynthesis of Ectoine from Greenhouse Gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415445</link>
      <description>Shuqi Guo, Chengbo Li, Xiaohan Huang, Yanjing Su, Chenyue Zhang, Yizhou Dai, Yuan Ji, Rongzhan Fu, Tingting Zheng, Qiang Fei, Daidi Fan, Chuan Xia, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403475883

                Converting greenhouse gases into valuable products has become a promising approach for achieving a carbon&#8208;neutral economy and sustainable development. However, the conversion efficiency depends on the energy yield of the substrate. In this study, we developed an electro&#8208;biocatalytic system by integrating electrochemical and microbial processes to upcycle CO2 into a valuable product (ectoine) using renewable energy. This system initiates the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to methane, an energy&#8208;dense molecule, which then serves as an electrofuel to energize the growth of an engineered methanotrophic cell factory for ectoine biosynthesis. The scalability of this system was demonstrated using an array of ten 25 cm2 electrochemical cells equipped with a high&#8208;performance carbon&#8208;supported isolated copper catalyst. The system consistently generated methane at the cathode under a total partial current of approximately &#8722;37 A (~175 mmolCH4 h&#8211;1) and O2 at the anode under a total partial current of approximately 62 A (~583 mmolO2 h&#8211;1). This output met the requirements of a 3&#8208;L bioreactor, even at maximum CH4 and O2 consumption, resulting in the high&#8208;yield conversion of CO2 to ectoine (1146.9 mg L&#8211;1). This work underscores the potential of electrifying the biosynthesis of valuable products from CO2, providing a sustainable avenue for biomanufacturing and energy storage.</description>
      <author>Shuqi Guo, Chengbo Li, Xiaohan Huang, Yanjing Su, Chenyue Zhang, Yizhou Dai, Yuan Ji, Rongzhan Fu, Tingting Zheng, Qiang Fei, Daidi Fan, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Electro&#8208;Biosynthesis of Ectoine from Greenhouse Gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415445</link>
      <description>Shuqi Guo, Chengbo Li, Xiaohan Huang, Yanjing Su, Chenyue Zhang, Yizhou Dai, Yuan Ji, Rongzhan Fu, Tingting Zheng, Qiang Fei, Daidi Fan, Chuan Xia, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403475936

                Converting greenhouse gases into valuable products has become a promising approach for achieving a carbon&#8208;neutral economy and sustainable development. However, the conversion efficiency depends on the energy yield of the substrate. In this study, we developed an electro&#8208;biocatalytic system by integrating electrochemical and microbial processes to upcycle CO2 into a valuable product (ectoine) using renewable energy. This system initiates the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to methane, an energy&#8208;dense molecule, which then serves as an electrofuel to energize the growth of an engineered methanotrophic cell factory for ectoine biosynthesis. The scalability of this system was demonstrated using an array of ten 25 cm2 electrochemical cells equipped with a high&#8208;performance carbon&#8208;supported isolated copper catalyst. The system consistently generated methane at the cathode under a total partial current of approximately &#8722;37 A (~175 mmolCH4 h&#8211;1) and O2 at the anode under a total partial current of approximately 62 A (~583 mmolO2 h&#8211;1). This output met the requirements of a 3&#8208;L bioreactor, even at maximum CH4 and O2 consumption, resulting in the high&#8208;yield conversion of CO2 to ectoine (1146.9 mg L&#8211;1). This work underscores the potential of electrifying the biosynthesis of valuable products from CO2, providing a sustainable avenue for biomanufacturing and energy storage.</description>
      <author>Shuqi Guo, Chengbo Li, Xiaohan Huang, Yanjing Su, Chenyue Zhang, Yizhou Dai, Yuan Ji, Rongzhan Fu, Tingting Zheng, Qiang Fei, Daidi Fan, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>d&#8208;Electrons of Platinum Alloy Steering CO Pathway for Low&#8208;charge Potential Li&#8208;CO2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415728</link>
      <description>Limin Liu, Shenyu Shen, Jiatian Li, Ning Zhao, Xiangkai Yin, Jing Wang, Wei Yu, Yaqiong Su, Bao Yu Xia, Shujiang Ding, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403550087

                Aprotic Li&#8208;CO2 batteries suffer from sluggish solid&#8208;solid co&#8208;oxidation kinetics of C and Li2CO3, requiring extremely high charging potentials and leading to serious side reactions and poor energy efficiency. Herein, we introduce a novel approach to address these challenges by modulating the reaction pathway with tailored Pt d&#8208;electrons and develop an aprotic Li&#8208;CO2 battery with CO and Li2CO3 as the main discharge products. Note that the gas&#8208;solid co&#8208;oxidation reaction between CO and Li2CO3 is both kinetically and thermodynamically more favorable. Consequently, the Li&#8208;CO2 batteries with CoPt alloy&#8208;supported on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanofiber (CoPt@NCNF) cathode exhibit a charging potential of 2.89 V at 50 &#181;A cm&#8208;2, which is the lowest charging potential to date. Moreover, the CoPt@NCNF cathode also shows exceptional cycling stability (218 cycles at 50 &#181;A cm&#8208;2) and high energy efficiency up to 74.6%. Comprehensive experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that the lowered d&#8208;band center of CoPt alloy effectively promotes CO desorption and inhibits further CO reduction to C. This work provides promising insights into developing efficient and CO&#8208;selective Li&#8208;CO2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Limin Liu, Shenyu Shen, Jiatian Li, Ning Zhao, Xiangkai Yin, Jing Wang, Wei Yu, Yaqiong Su, Bao Yu Xia, Shujiang Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>d&#8208;Electrons of Platinum Alloy Steering CO Pathway for Low&#8208;charge Potential Li&#8208;CO2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415728</link>
      <description>Huijuan Liu, Shenyu Shen, Jiatian Li, Ning Zhao, Xiangkai Yin, Jing Wang, Wei Ma, Yaqiong Su, Bao Yu Xia, Shujiang Ding, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403550209

                Aprotic Li&#8208;CO2 batteries suffer from sluggish solid&#8208;solid co&#8208;oxidation kinetics of C and Li2CO3, requiring extremely high charging potentials and leading to serious side reactions and poor energy efficiency. Herein, we introduce a novel approach to address these challenges by modulating the reaction pathway with tailored Pt d&#8208;electrons and develop an aprotic Li&#8208;CO2 battery with CO and Li2CO3 as the main discharge products. Note that the gas&#8208;solid co&#8208;oxidation reaction between CO and Li2CO3 is both kinetically and thermodynamically more favorable. Consequently, the Li&#8208;CO2 batteries with CoPt alloy&#8208;supported on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanofiber (CoPt@NCNF) cathode exhibit a charging potential of 2.89 V at 50 &#181;A cm&#8208;2, which is the lowest charging potential to date. Moreover, the CoPt@NCNF cathode also shows exceptional cycling stability (218 cycles at 50 &#181;A cm&#8208;2) and high energy efficiency up to 74.6%. Comprehensive experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that the lowered d&#8208;band center of CoPt alloy effectively promotes CO desorption and inhibits further CO reduction to C. This work provides promising insights into developing efficient and CO&#8208;selective Li&#8208;CO2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Huijuan Liu, Shenyu Shen, Jiatian Li, Ning Zhao, Xiangkai Yin, Jing Wang, Wei Ma, Yaqiong Su, Bao Yu Xia, Shujiang Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fossil Diesel, Soybean Biodiesel and Hydrotreated Vegetable Oil: A Numerical Analysis of Emissions Using Detailed Chemical Kinetics at Diesel Engine Like Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15101224</link>
      <description>Leonel R Cancino, Jessica F. Rebelo, Felipe Kraus, Eduardo Homem de Siqueira Cavalcanti, Val&#233;ria S. de B. Pimentel, D&#233;cio Magioli Maia, Ricardo Almeida Barbosa de S&#225;, Atmosphere. 15(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403399750

                Nowadays, emissions from internal combustion engines are a relevant topic of investigation, taking into account the continuous reduction of emission limits imposed by environmental regulatory agencies around the world, obviously as the result of earnest studies that have pointed out the impact on the human health of high levels of contaminants released into the environment. Over recent years, the use of biofuels has contributed to attenuating this environmental issue; however, new problems have been raised, such as NOx emissions tend to increase as the biofuel percentage in the fuel used in engines increases. In this research, the emissions of a compression ignition internal combustion engine modeled as a variable volume reactor with homogeneous combustion were numerically investigated. To analyze the combustion process, a detailed kinetics model tailored specifically for this purpose was used. The kinetics model comprised 30,975 chemical reactions involving 691 chemical species. Mixtures of fuel surrogates were then created to represent the fuel used in the Brazilian fuel marketplace, involving (i) fossil diesel&#8212;&#8220;diesel A&#8221;, (ii) soybean diesel&#8212;&#8220;biodiesel&#8221;, and (iii) hydrotreated vegetable oil&#8212; &#8220;HVO&#8221;. Surrogate species were then selected for each of the aforementioned fuels, and blends of those surrogates were then proposed as mixture M1 (diesel A:biodiesel:HVO&#8212;90:10:0), mixture M2 (diesel A:biodiesel:HVO&#8212;85:15:0), and mixture M3 (diesel A:biodiesel:HVO&#8212;80:15:5). The species allowed in the kinetics model included all the fuel surrogates used in this research as well as the target emission species of this study: total hydrocarbons, non-methane hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide, methane, nitrogen oxides, carbon dioxide, soot, and soot precursors. When compared to experimental trends of emissions available in the literature, it was observed that, for all the proposed fuel surrogates blends, the numerical approach performed in this research was able to capture qualitative trends for engine power and the target emissions in the whole ranges of engine speeds and engine loads, despite the CO and NOx emissions at specific engine speeds and loads.</description>
      <author>Leonel R Cancino, Jessica F. Rebelo, Felipe Kraus, Eduardo Homem de Siqueira Cavalcanti, Val&#233;ria S. de B. Pimentel, D&#233;cio Magioli Maia, Ricardo Almeida Barbosa de S&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15101224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Effects in Stock Markets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/430kvj67</link>
      <description>Yang Ju, Highlights in Business Economics and Management. 41(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403572021

                Climate change significantly impacts global stock markets through both short-term extreme weather events and long-term climate shifts. This study examines the relationship between CO2 emissions and stock returns across 19 countries from 2001 to 2020 using regression analysis. The findings also reveal a positive correlation between CO2 emissions and stock returns, indicating that investors anticipate higher returns to offset climate-related risks. This suggests that higher CO2 emissions drive investor expectations for increased returns to compensate for potential economic losses. The study highlights the importance of balanced emission reduction strategies and promoting green finance to support sustainable economic growth. Additionally, it underscores the need to integrate climate risks into financial decision-making, offering valuable insights into the financial implications of climate change and guiding policymakers and investors in addressing these challenges. By providing empirical evidence on the link between CO2 emissions and stock returns, this research enriches existing knowledge and emphasizes the financial risks and opportunities presented by climate change. The study's results align with the carbon risk premium theory, which posits that investors demand higher returns from companies with higher carbon emissions. This study advocates for policies that balance economic growth with environmental sustainability, promoting green finance initiatives to facilitate the transition to a low-carbon economy and mitigate the adverse effects of climate change on financial markets.</description>
      <author>Yang Ju</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/430kvj67</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Nexus between Greenhouse Emissions, Environmental Degradation and Green Energy in Europe: A Critique of the Environmental Kuznets Curve</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17205109</link>
      <description>Alexandra Horobe&#355;, Lucian Bela&#351;cu, Magdalena Radulescu, Daniel Balsalobre&#8208;Lorente, Cosmin-Alin Bo&#355;oroga, Cristina-Carmencita Negreanu, Energies. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403392329

                This study examines the intricate relationship between economic growth and European environmental degradation via the Environmental Kuznets Curve (EKC). Our results contest the traditional inverted U-shape model of the Environmental Kuznets Curve, indicating that the theory may not be consistently applicable across European countries. Utilizing CS-ARDL and MMQR modelling, we reveal substantial regional disparities. Western European nations demonstrate a typical Environmental Kuznets Curve (EKC) pattern in the short term, characterized by an initial increase in emissions alongside GDP development, followed by a subsequent fall. Conversely, Eastern and Balkan nations exhibit a U-shaped connection, described by an early decline in emissions followed by a subsequent increase as their development levels increase. The influence of renewable energy differs, as it decreases emissions in the short term in Western Europe. However, its long-term impacts are variable, especially when contrasted with its more pronounced effect on emissions in Eastern and Balkan countries. Furthermore, trade openness intensifies environmental degradation in the short-term across all regions, although its long-term impact diminishes, particularly concerning greenhouse gases (GHG). The relationship between renewable energy and trade openness is substantial for the short-term reduction of carbon dioxide emissions, but this effect declines with time. The results indicate that a uniform environmental policy throughout Europe may lack efficacy. Customized strategies to expedite the transition in Western Europe and more specific interventions in Eastern Europe are essential to harmonize economic progress with environmental sustainability. Future research should examine the determinants of the diminishing long-term effects of renewable energy and the interplay between trade and environmental policies.</description>
      <author>Alexandra Horobe&#355;, Lucian Bela&#351;cu, Magdalena Radulescu, Daniel Balsalobre&#8208;Lorente, Cosmin-Alin Bo&#355;oroga, Cristina-Carmencita Negreanu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17205109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Sequestration by Preparing Recycled Cement, Recycled Aggregates, and Recycled Concrete from Construction and Demolition (C&amp;amp;D) Wastes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205020</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Rong Huang, Junjie Wang, Yi Zhang, Materials. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403392074

                As the world&#8217;s largest producer of construction waste, China&#8217;s recycling and related policies are of the biggest concern to the world. However, the effective disposal and reuse of this waste has become an important issue since currently China still has a very low recycling ratio compared to developed countries, and most of the waste concrete was only simply broken and used as low-grade recycled aggregates for subgrade cushion, cement stabilized crushed stone, and filler wall. In this paper, a concrete cycle model focusing on how to effectively recycle and utilize waste concrete is put forward to prepare high quality recycled concrete, especially through a series of technical means, such as effective separation, carbon sequestration, and reactivation. Producing high quality recycled concrete can not only replace traditional concrete but also effectively reduce the consumption and waste of raw materials. What&#8217;s more, the calculation results show a potential of significantly carbon sink; for every ton of recycled cement produced, the CO2 emission could be reduced by 0.35&#8211;0.77 tons compared to ordinary Portland cement, corresponding to a reduction of 47%&#8211;94%; and for every ton of recycled concrete produced, the CO2 emission could be reduced by 0.186 tons compared to normal concrete. A yearly CO2 sequestration of 1.4&#8211;3.08 gigatonnes could happen if the ordinary Portland cement could be replaced by the recycled cement around the world. Taking the currently accumulated construction and demolition (C&amp;D) wastes globally, the production of recycled cement, recycled aggregates, and recycled concrete could induce a significant carbon sink in the world.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Rong Huang, Junjie Wang, Yi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy-Derived Synthesis of the CuPd Sub-1nm Alloy for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-acetate Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07711</link>
      <description>Siyang Nie, Liang Wu, Qingda Liu, Xun Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403560250

                Bimetallic alloys exhibit remarkable properties in catalysis and energy storage, while their precise synthesis at the subnanoscale remains a formidable challenge due to their immiscible nature in thermodynamics. In this study, we engineer an atomically dispersed CuPd alloy with an average size of 1.5 nm loaded on CuO and phosphomolybdic acid (PMA) coassembly subnanosheets (CuO-PMA SNSs). Driven by the high vibrational entropy, Cu atoms could escape from CuO supports and bond with adjacent Pd single atoms, leading to the in situ formation of CuPd alloys. Furthermore, this strategy can also be utilized for synthesizing the ZnPt alloy with an average size of 1 nm, thereby providing a general pathway for the design of immiscible subnanoalloys. The fully exposed Cu&#8211;Pd pairs in CuPd subnanoalloys significantly enhance the adsorption and coverage of surface *CO during the electrochemical reduction of CO2, thereby leading to enhanced stability of ethenone intermediates and facilitating the production of C2 compounds. The resulting CuPd subnanoalloy exhibits a remarkable Faradaic efficiency of 46.5 &#177; 2.1% for CO2-to-acetate electroreduction and achieves a high acetate productivity of 99 &#177; 2.8 &#956;mol cm&#8211;2 at &#8722;0.7 V versus RHE.</description>
      <author>Siyang Nie, Liang Wu, Qingda Liu, Xun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07711</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermochemical Heterolytic Hydrogenation Catalysis Proceeds Through Polarization-Driven Hydride Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3rp1x</link>
      <description>Hai&#8208;Xu Wang, Yogesh Surendranath, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403476363

                Heterolytic hydrogenations, which split H2 across a hydride acceptor and proton acceptor, are a key class of reactions that span the chemical value chain, including CO2 hydrogenation to formate and NADH regeneration from NAD+. The dominant mechanistic models for heterogeneous catalysis of these reactions invoke classical surface mechanisms that ignore the role of interfacial charge separation. Herein, we quantify the electrochemical potential of the catalyst during turnover and uncover evidence supporting an interfacial electrochemical hydride transfer mechanism for this overall thermochemical reaction class. We find that the proton acceptor induces spontaneous electrochemical polarization of the metal catalyst surface, thereby controlling the thermodynamic hydricity of the surface M&#8211;H intermediates and driving rate-determining electrochemical hydride transfer to the hydride acceptor substrate. Overall, this model invokes that heterolytic hydrogenations proceed via the coupling of two electrochemical half-reactions, the hydrogen reduction reaction (HRR) and hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR), which convert H2 to hydride and proton, respectively. This mechanistic framework, which applies across diverse reaction media and for the hydrogenation of CO2 to formate and NAD+ to NADH, enables the determination of intrinsic reaction kinetics and exposes design principles for the future development of sustainable hydrogenation reactivity.</description>
      <author>Hai&#8208;Xu Wang, Yogesh Surendranath</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3rp1x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed standardization changes in the assessment of concrete durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5604/01.3001.0054.7473</link>
      <description>G. Bajorek, Z. Giergiczny, In&#380;ynieria i Budownictwo. LXXX(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403446216

                The article presents the concept of concrete durability based on the system of concrete resistance classes to ERC exposure included in the proposed standardization documents (EN 206-1 together with EN 206-100 and Eurocode 2). According to the ERC concept, the performance properties of concrete are tested using recognized test methods, and the results are assessed on the basis of criteria independent of the composition of the tested concrete. The ERC durability concept is open to new technical and standardization solutions in the field of concrete composition (new additives) and cement and should replace the generally applicable prescriptive solutions. This solution is important from the point of view of reducing the emissions of the cement industry (production of multi-component cements and the use of new non-clinker main ingredients) and reducing the carbon footprint of concrete (CO2 reduction classes of concrete according to prEN 206-1)</description>
      <author>G. Bajorek, Z. Giergiczny</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5604/01.3001.0054.7473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Sewage Sludge Stabilization, Pathogen Removal, and Biomass Production through Indigenous Microalgae Promoting Growth: A Sustainable Approach for Sewage Sludge Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling9050097</link>
      <description>Hajer Ben Hamed, Antoine Debuigne, Hetty KleinJan, Dominique Toye, Ang&#233;lique L&#233;onard, Recycling. 9(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403490659

                Sewage sludge (SS), a byproduct of wastewater treatment plants, poses significant environmental and health risks if not properly handled. Conventional approaches for SS stabilization often involve costly and energy-consuming processes. This study investigated the effect of promoting native microalgae growth in SS on its stabilization, pathogen bacteria removal, and valuable biomass production. The effect on settleability, filterability, and extracellular polymeric substances (EPSs) was examined as well. Experiments were conducted in photobioreactors (PBRs) without O2 supply and CO2 release under controlled parameters. The results show a significant improvement in SS stabilization, with a reduction of volatile solids (VSs) by 47.55%. Additionally, fecal coliforms and E. coli were efficiently removed by 2.25 log and 6.72 log, respectively. Moreover, Salmonella spp. was not detected after 15 days of treatment. The settleability was improved by 71.42%. However, a worsening of the sludge filterability properties was observed, likely due to a decrease in floc size following the reduction of protein content in the tightly bound EPS fraction. Microalgae biomass production was 16.56 mg/L/day, with a mean biomass of 0.35 g/L at the end of the batch treatment, representing 10.35% of the total final biomass. These findings suggest that promoting native microalgal growth in SS could be sustainable and cost-effective for SS stabilization, microalgal biomass production, and the enhancement of sludge-settling characteristics, notwithstanding potential filtration-related considerations.</description>
      <author>Hajer Ben Hamed, Antoine Debuigne, Hetty KleinJan, Dominique Toye, Ang&#233;lique L&#233;onard</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling9050097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobility Infrastructure Optimization via Stochastic Relaxation the Traffic Flow Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5093651/v1</link>
      <description>Stefano Bilotta, Enrico Collini, Marco Fanfani, Paolo Nesi, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403461561

                Abstract Urban traffic congestion and pollution represent critical challenges for sustainable city development. In this paper, we presents a novel approach to optimizing urban mobility infrastructure using a stochastic relaxation algorithm. The method is designed to address the growing challenges of traffic congestion, fuel consumption, and CO2 emissions in rapidly urbanizing cities. The system automates the generation and evaluation of road network modifications, drastically reducing the time and effort required for traditional simulation-based approaches. By utilizing real-time traffic data and traffic flow reconstruction algorithms within the Snap4City platform, the proposed system allows for the efficient exploration of "what-if" scenarios, optimizing key performance indicators such as travel time, fuel use, and emissions. A case study conducted in Florence, Italy, demonstrates significant improvements in traffic conditions, fuel efficiency, and emissions reduction, underscoring the system's potential to enhance urban mobility in a sustainable manner. This system has been developed exploiting the Snap4City platform Scenario Editor and platform.</description>
      <author>Stefano Bilotta, Enrico Collini, Marco Fanfani, Paolo Nesi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5093651/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melatonin Rinsing Treatment Associated with Storage in a Controlled Atmosphere Improves the Antioxidant Capacity and Overall Quality of Lemons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/foods13203298</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Eric Zheng, Ziqin Lin, Ze Miao, Yuhang Li, Shenqiang Hu, Yanan Gao, Yuqian Jiang, Lingling Pang, Xihong Li, Foods. 13(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403484294

                Antioxidant capacity is one of the most important biological activities in fruits and vegetables and is closely related to human health. In this study, &#8216;Eureka&#8217; lemons were used as experimental materials and stored at 7&#8211;8 &#176;C MT (melatonin, 200 &#956;mol, soaked for 15 min) and CA (controlled atmosphere, 2&#8211;3% O2 + 15&#8211;16% CO2) individually or in combination for 30 d. The changes in lemon fruits&#8217; basic physicochemical properties, enzyme activities, and antioxidant capacities were studied. Comparing the combined treatment to the control, the outcomes demonstrated a significant reduction in weight loss, firmness, stomatal opening, and inhibition of polyphenol oxidase (PPO) and peroxidase (POD) activities. Additionally, the combined treatment maintained high levels of titratable acidity (TA), vitamin C (VC), total phenolic content (TPC), and antioxidant capacity and preserved the lemon aroma. Meanwhile, the correlation between fruit color, aroma compounds, and antioxidant capacity was revealed, providing valuable insights into the postharvest preservation of lemons. In conclusion, the combined treatment (MT + CA) was effective in maintaining the quality and antioxidant capacity of lemons.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Eric Zheng, Ziqin Lin, Ze Miao, Yuhang Li, Shenqiang Hu, Yanan Gao, Yuqian Jiang, Lingling Pang, Xihong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/foods13203298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use of Edaphic Bioindicators to Mitigate Environmental Impact and Improve Agricultural Research and Training</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/soilsystems8040107</link>
      <description>Ana Cano-Ort&#237;z, Jos&#233; Carlos Pi&#241;ar Fuentes, J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Eus&#233;bio Cano, Soil Systems. 8(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403516759

                The world is currently experiencing unsustainable development, which poses significant risks to global society. In response, there is a growing advocacy for sustainable development across all sectors, driven by social resilience. This shift is fostering substantial socio-environmental tensions. However, the combined power of scientific research and social education has the potential to reverse this trend. Transitioning from an unsustainable territorial model to a sustainable one is both feasible and economically profitable. This transition can be achieved through knowledge of soil bioindicators, which provide valuable information about soil nutrient content. By understanding these indicators, nutrient inputs can be tailored, reducing or eliminating pollutants such as excessive fertilizers, herbicides, and pesticides. Training experts and raising social awareness through education on new research are essential steps in this process. For decades, it has been recognized that globalization, industrialization, and population growth have driven unsustainable development, leading to degraded agroecosystems. To address this issue, government institutions are promoting sustainability through ecological agriculture and CO2 reduction, both of which can be supported by the use of soil bioindicators.</description>
      <author>Ana Cano-Ort&#237;z, Jos&#233; Carlos Pi&#241;ar Fuentes, J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Eus&#233;bio Cano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/soilsystems8040107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental and Socio-Economic Impact Assessment of Renewable Energy Using Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32996/jefas.2024.6.5.13</link>
      <description>Md Fakhrul Islam Sumon, Md Osiujjaman, MD Azam Khan, Arifur Rahman, Md. Shazib Uddin, Laxmi Prasad Pant, Pravakar Debnath, Journal of Economics Finance and Accounting Studies. 6(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403567651

                Renewable energy sources, such as solar, hydro, wind, and geothermal energy, have emerged as key alternatives to fossil fuels in combating climate change and addressing energy security concerns in the USA and ad worldwide. Strategic use of this renewable resource is important not only for carbon emission reduction and improvement of environmental sustainability but also for maintaining future energy supplies. At the same time, such transition raises thorough assessments of environmental and socio-economic impacts. Machine learning (ML) models offer a powerful tool for predicting and analyzing such impacts, allowing for more efficient decision-making and long-term planning. These models are supposed to analyze patterns in energy production, land use, and emissions to make a more dynamic and predictive understanding of how renewable energy adoption influences CO2 levels. The principal aim of this research project was to develop and curate machine learning algorithms for predicting CO2 emissions based on renewable energy data, using the knowledge to better understand how solar, wind, hydro, and geothermal energy systems affect environmental outcomes. The predictive models developed in this research would serve as useful tools for the policymakers and major stakeholders in decision-making on investments in energy infrastructure and characterization of regulatory frameworks. These datasets for this research project were retrieved from several prominent institutions, including governmental agencies, international organizations such as the International Energy Agency-IEA and the World Bank, satellite data repositories, and USA environmental monitoring agencies. For this research project, 3 machine learning algorithms in the experiment were used, namely Logistic Regression, XG-Boost, and Random Forest. Amongst these three, the linear regression model gave the best performance, as it had the least MSE; indicating that its predictive capability was impressive. The comparative analysis of renewable energy projects in Germany, China, and California underlines that effective policy-making plays a very decisive role in the transition toward sustainable energy.</description>
      <author>Md Fakhrul Islam Sumon, Md Osiujjaman, MD Azam Khan, Arifur Rahman, Md. Shazib Uddin, Laxmi Prasad Pant, Pravakar Debnath</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32996/jefas.2024.6.5.13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Hybrid Vehicle Integration in Nablus Urban Shared-Taxis: Cost-Benefit and Exhaust Emissions Assessment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35552/anujr.a.39.1.2317</link>
      <description>Sharif Bassam Salman, Khaled Al&#8208;Sahili, An-Najah University Journal for Research - A (Natural Sciences). 39(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403414127

                There is a worldwide concern about the increase in vehicles&#8217; exhaust emissions of traditional fuels and the rise in fuel prices. Nablus city is a major city in the West Bank, Palestine with peculiar topography and traffic congestion. This increases fuel consumption and the gas emission of the diesel operated public transport (PT) shared-taxi vehicles. This paper investigates the viability of introducing hybrid vehicles to the urban shared-taxis in highly congested areas with peculiar topography. Interviews were conducted and questionnaires were distributed among PT drivers and route managers to obtain the operational and cost characteristics of each route. The existing expenses and revenues and gas emissions of diesel vehicles were analyzed. Expenses-revenues analysis revealed that there is no immediate urgency in switching all diesel-fuel shared-taxis to hybrid; therefore, two scenarios were developed. The first was replacing old PT cars (2009 or older) with hybrid vehicles, which provided an average financial saving of 20.9% with a reduction in exhausts emission of CO2-equivalent by 33%. The second scenario included replacing PT vehicles with production dates from 2009-2014, which produced financial savings of 15% and reduction of exhaust emissions by 35%. The comparison showed a preference for the first scenario at the current time, while implementing other scenarios gradually. The first scenario is simple and close to reality; as old vehicles should typically be replaced. The study recommends using hybrid vehicles for new shared-taxis introduced to the service, and establishing national level policies to encourage the use of alternative fuels for the transportation sector, focusing on PT. However, several critical factors must be considered, including topography and route characteristics.</description>
      <author>Sharif Bassam Salman, Khaled Al&#8208;Sahili</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35552/anujr.a.39.1.2317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Fuels for Decarbonising UK Rural Transport</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/encyclopedia4040101</link>
      <description>Al-Amin Abba Dabo, Andrew Gough, F. Frank Alparslan, Encyclopedia. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403513454

                Decarbonising transport is a crucial element of the UK&#8217;s strategy to achieve net-zero carbon emissions by 2050, as the transport sector is currently the largest contributor to the UK&#8217;s greenhouse gas emissions. Rural communities face distinct challenges in this effort due to their reliance on internal combustion engines (ICEs) across vehicles and machinery essential for daily life, including farming equipment and private transport. While the upcoming ban on new petrol and diesel vehicles paves the way for the adoption of Electric Vehicles (EVs), this solution may not fully address the unique needs of rural areas where infrastructure limitations and specific mobility requirements pose significant barriers. In this context, synthetic fuels, produced using renewable energy sources, offer a potential alternative. These fuels can be used directly in existing internal combustion engines without requiring major modifications and have the added benefit of reducing overall greenhouse gas emissions by capturing CO2 during production. This entry explores the potential advantages of adopting synthetic fuels, particularly in rural areas, and examines how community-based buying cooperatives could support their wider use through bulk purchasing, cost reduction, and community empowerment.</description>
      <author>Al-Amin Abba Dabo, Andrew Gough, F. Frank Alparslan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/encyclopedia4040101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incorporation of Nanoalumina in Potassium Feldspar-based Phosphoric Acid Activated Geopolymer Composites: A Sustainable Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13074/jent.2024.09.243840</link>
      <description>M. Nanthini, R Ganesan, V.M. Jaganathan, Journal of Environmental Nanotechnology. 13(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403388437

                This study investigates the potential of potassium feldspar-phosphate-based geopolymer concrete as a sustainable replacement to traditional concrete, addressing the environmental concerns associated with CO2 emissions during cement production. While geopolymer concrete offers a promising path towards sustainability, its performance often falls short of Portland cement concrete. This study investigates the use of nanoalumina in improving the performance of geopolymer concrete. A ternary mix was formulated with potassium feldspar powder, metakaolin and rice husk ash, incorporating varying percentages of nanoalumina geopolymer concrete mixes. The mechanical characteristics of the resulting geopolymer composites were assessed through compressive and split tensile strength tests. The findings revealed that a 4% nanoalumina dosage (GC-N4) yielded the most significant improvement in strength and durability. The GC-N4 mix performed superior in all metrics, demonstrating the highest compressive (41.82 MPa) and split tensile (3.7 Mpa) strengths. Reduction in water absorption and durability aspects were also optimum in GC-N4. These results highlight the potential of incorporating nanoalumina into a ternary mix of potassium feldspar powder, metakaolin and rice husk ash to significantly enhance the overall performance of geopolymer concrete, promoting its wider adoption as a sustainable construction material.</description>
      <author>M. Nanthini, R Ganesan, V.M. Jaganathan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13074/jent.2024.09.243840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warm Arctic-Cold Eurasia pattern helps predict spring wildfire burned area in West Siberia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53470-4</link>
      <description>Zhicong Yin, Yijia Zhang, Shengping He, Huijun Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403556988

                Extreme wildfires have devastating impacts on multiple fronts, and associated carbon greatly heats the earth's climate. Whether and how to predict wildfires becomes a critical question. In this study, we find that the preceding-winter "warm Arctic-cold Eurasia" (WACE) pattern significantly enlarges the spring burned area in West Siberia. The winter WACE and accompanying snow reduction result in dryness and vegetation exposure in West Siberia in spring, increasing fire risks. A multiple linear regression model is constructed that successfully predicts the spring burned area in West Siberia one season in advance (R-squared coefficient=0.64). The same predictors also well predict the corresponding fire carbon emissions. Independent predictions for spring burned area in 2019 and 2020 are very close to observations, with a mean absolute percentage error of only 3.0%. The findings of this study provide a possibility for guarding humans against extreme wildfires and predicting sharp rises in carbon emissions. The authors show that the winter "warm Arctic-cold Eurasia" pattern significantly enhances spring fire activity in West Siberia, contributing to the prediction of wildfire burned area, and resulting CO2 emissions, one season in advance.</description>
      <author>Zhicong Yin, Yijia Zhang, Shengping He, Huijun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53470-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Freight Transport Emissions Responsibility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c05658</link>
      <description>Jacob Fry, Keiichiro Kanemoto, Alastair Fraser, Keisuke Nansai, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403549224

                The transportation of freight by land, sea and air underpins the complex network of global trade in physical commodities. Greenhouse gas emissions from freight transportation are a significant component of global emissions and are predicted to grow in coming decades. However, the inclusion of freight transport in emissions accounts and environmental impact studies is often incomplete. Both data availability and difficulties in allocating freight emissions to specific commodity trades contributes to this. In this study, international freight movements by transport mode are estimated from the bottom-up by imputing global freight transport routes. Emissions are estimated from these freight movements and integrated with a global multiregional input&#8211;output model. This enables the calculation of carbon footprints that are complete with respect to freight emissions. We estimate that global freight transport emissions contributed 2.8 Gt CO2-equiv in 2012, or about 41% of total transport emissions. In general, freight footprints contribute about 9% to national emissions footprints. While trade in physical commodities (such as construction materials, food and fossil fuels) are associated with the largest embodied freight emissions, services (such as public administration, education and health) also require significant freight transport. Using a consumption-based allocation of freight transport emissions allows the decarbonisation of other sectors to be complementary to the decarbonisation of transport through reduction in demand, for example through material efficiency strategies. To drive decarbonisation in maritime transport it is critical to include bunker emissions in national emissions inventories, thereby completing the system boundary.</description>
      <author>Jacob Fry, Keiichiro Kanemoto, Alastair Fraser, Keisuke Nansai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c05658</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
