<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 14:51:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Membrane contactor-photocatalytic hybrid system for carbon dioxide capture and conversion to formic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102085</link>
      <description>Andi Rina Ayu Astuti, Wibawa Hendra Saputera, Danu Ariono, I Gede Wenten, Dwiwahju Sasongko, Results in engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393359313

                The escalating demand for Carbon Capture and Utilization (CCU) schemes to mitigate CO2 emissions has propelled research into more efficient methods of CO2 conversion, such as the production of formic acid. While traditional approaches often require harsh operating conditions and substantial energy inputs, photocatalysis offers a promising alternative by harnessing CO2, water, and light for formic acid production. This study evaluates the performance and reaction kinetics of CO2 capture and conversion to formic acid using an integrated membrane contactor and photocatalytic process. Investigation into various CO2 absorbents and reduction catalysts reveals that TEA achieves a CO2 loading of 0.957 moles of CO2/mole of solvent, while NaOH achieves 0.75 moles of CO2/mole of solvent over a 4-hour operation period. Subsequent photoreduction of CO2 results in formic acid concentration of 15.89 ppm using ZnO and 10.16 ppm using TiO2 within the same 4-hour operation period at a gas flow rate of 800 ml/min. The rate of CO2 photoreduction to formic acid emerges as the limiting factor in this integrated process, indicating a need for further optimization. Key parameters identified for optimal performance include a UV source of 500 W, a medium pH of 10, and a catalyst loading of 0.5 g/L. This study contributes to the advancement of CCU technologies by demonstrating the feasibility of integrating CO2 capture and photoreduction using membrane contactors and photocatalytic systems, paving the way for sustainable formic acid production.</description>
      <author>Andi Rina Ayu Astuti, Wibawa Hendra Saputera, Danu Ariono, I Gede Wenten, Dwiwahju Sasongko</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supported Tetra-Atom Clusters on G-Cn as Catalysts for Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4780685</link>
      <description>Wenjing Zhou, Xuxin Kang, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393376349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjing Zhou, Xuxin Kang, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4780685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size&#8208;Dependent Multi&#8208;Electron Donation in Metal&#8208;Complex Quantum Dots Hybrid Catalyst for Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315734</link>
      <description>Qian Zhao, Mohamed Abdellah, Yuehan Cao, Jie Meng, Xianshao Zou, Kasper Enemark&#8208;Rasmussen, Weihua Lin, Yang Li, Yijiang Chen, Hengli Duan, Qinying Pan, Ying Zhou, T&#246;nu Pullerits, Hong Xu, Sophie E. Canton, Yuran Niu, Kaibo Zheng, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393436393

                Abstract The effective conversion of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) into valuable chemical fuels relies significantly on the donation of multiple electrons. Its efficiency is closely linked to both the density and lifetime of excited charge carriers. In this study, a hybrid catalyst system comprising covalently bonded InP/ZnS quantum dots (QDs) and Re&#8208;complexes is showcased. The electronic band alignment between the QDs and the Re&#8208;complexes is revealed to dominate the multi&#8208;electron transfer process for photocatalytic conversion to methane (CH 4 ). Notably, the size of the QDs is found to be a determining parameter. Among the three QD sizes investigated, transient absorption spectroscopy studies unveil that rapid multi&#8208;electron transfer from the QDs to the Re&#8208;catalyst occurs in smaller QDs (2.3 nm) due to the substantial driving force. Consequently, the photocatalytic conversion of CO 2 to CH 4 is significantly enhanced with a turnover number of 6, corresponding to the overall apparent quantum yield of &#8776;1%. This research underscores the possibilities of engineering multi&#8208;electron transfer by manipulating the electronic band alignment within a catalytic system. This can serve as a guide for optimizing photocatalytic CO 2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhao, Mohamed Abdellah, Yuehan Cao, Jie Meng, Xianshao Zou, Kasper Enemark&#8208;Rasmussen, Weihua Lin, Yang Li, Yijiang Chen, Hengli Duan, Qinying Pan, Ying Zhou, T&#246;nu Pullerits, Hong Xu, Sophie E. Canton, Yuran Niu, Kaibo Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrochemical Co&#8208;Reduction of Carbon Dioxide and Nitrate to Urea with High Faradaic Efficiency on Cobalt&#8208;Based Dual&#8208;Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202401221</link>
      <description>Xiaoya Fan, Chaozhen Liu, Xun He, Zixiao Li, Luchao Yue, Wenxi Zhao, Jun Li, Yan Wang, Tingshuai Li, Yongsong Luo, Dewen Zheng, Shengjun Sun, Qian Liu, Luming Li, Wei Chu, Feng Gong, Bo Tang, Yongchao Yao, Xuping Sun, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393549453

                Abstract Renewable electricity&#8208;powered nitrate/carbon dioxide co&#8208;reduction reaction toward urea production paves an attractive alternative to industrial urea processes and offers a clean on&#8208;site approach to closing the global nitrogen cycle. However, its large&#8208;scale implantation is severely impeded by challenging C&#8208;N coupling and requires electrocatalysts with high activity/selectivity. Here, cobalt&#8208;nanoparticles anchored on carbon nanosheet (Co NPs@C) is proposed as a catalyst electrode to boost yield and Faradaic efficiency (FE) toward urea electrosynthesis with enhanced C&#8208;N coupling. Such Co NPs@C renders superb urea&#8208;producing activity with a high FE reaching 54.3% and a urea yield of 2217.5 &#956;g h &#8211;1 mg cat. &#8211;1 , much superior to the Co NPs and C nanosheet counterparts, and meanwhile shows strong stability. The Co NPs@C affords rich catalytically active sites, fast reactants diffusion, and sufficient catalytic surfaces&#8208;electrolyte contacts with favored charge and ion transfer efficiencies. The theoretical calculations reveal that the high&#8208;rate formation of *CO and *NH 2 intermediates is crucial for facilitating urea synthesis. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Xiaoya Fan, Chaozhen Liu, Xun He, Zixiao Li, Luchao Yue, Wenxi Zhao, Jun Li, Yan Wang, Tingshuai Li, Yongsong Luo, Dewen Zheng, Shengjun Sun, Qian Liu, Luming Li, Wei Chu, Feng Gong, Bo Tang, Yongchao Yao, Xuping Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202401221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances and perspectives in carbon nanotube production from the electrochemical conversion of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102745</link>
      <description>I Ketut Rai Asmara Dipta, Chan Woo Lee, Journal of CO2 utilization (Print). 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393854161

                No abstract</description>
      <author>I Ketut Rai Asmara Dipta, Chan Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte Effects on the Reduction Potential and Carbon Dioxide Binding Affinity of Quinones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad3ad7</link>
      <description>Alessandra Zito, Jenny Y. Yang, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393924865

                Abstract CO2 capture and concentration (CCC) is critical to carbon negative technologies and can reduce or eliminate carbon emission of current industrial processes. A popular method for electrochemically-driven CCC uses redox carriers that bind and release CO2 depending on their oxidation state. Two critical properties of redox carriers are the reduction potential required to &#8216;activate&#8217; the redox carrier for CO2 capture and the CO2 binding constant. The former impacts the stability of the redox carrier towards oxidants such as O2, while the later determines the concentration levels of CO2 that can be captured. Quinones have been heavily studied as redox carriers. However, the impact of electrolyte on these properties has not been systematically explored. The reduction potential and the CO2 binding constant for 6 quinones and 3 alkylammonium hexafluorophophate electrolytes are quantified in acetonitrile. While alkylammonium cations are often considered inert and interchangeable, our studies show up to 100 mV changes in reduction potential with minimal changes to the CO2 binding constant.</description>
      <author>Alessandra Zito, Jenny Y. Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad3ad7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weak Bimetal Coupling-Assisted MN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst for Enhanced Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00058</link>
      <description>Hong-Xue Cai, J.B. Wang, Yuan&#8208;Ru Guo, Qing&#8208;Jiang Pan, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393942817

                The design of multimetal catalysts holds immense significance for efficient CO2 capture and its conversion into economically valuable chemicals. Herein, heterobimetallic catalysts (MiMo)L were exploited for the CO2 reduction reactions (CO2RR) using relativistic density functional theory (DFT). The octadentate Pacman-like polypyrrolic ligand (H4L) accommodates two metal ions (Mo, W, Nd, and U) inside (Mi) and outside (Mo) its month, rendering a weak bimetal coupling-assisted MN4 catalytically active site. Adsorption reactions have access to energetically stable coordination modes of &#8211;OCO, &#8211;OOC, and &#8211;(OCO)2, where the donor atom(s) are marked in bold. Among all of the species, (UiMoo)L releases the most energy. Along CO2RR, it favors to produce CO. The high-efficiency CO2 reduction is attributed to the size matching of U with the ligand mouth and the effective manipulation of the electron density of both ligand and bimetals. The mechanism in which heterobimetals synergetically capture and reduce CO2 has been postulated. This establishes a reference in elaborating on the complicated heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Hong-Xue Cai, J.B. Wang, Yuan&#8208;Ru Guo, Qing&#8208;Jiang Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Role of mass transport in electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction to methanol using immobilized cobalt phthalocyanine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10251835</link>
      <description>Thomas Chan, Calton Kong, Alex J. King, Rajiv Prabhakar, Finn Babbe, Clifford P. Kubiak, Joel W. Ager, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393669259

                Cell files.zip .dwg files of the pocket for the cathode and anode chamber. .dwg files of the gasket design Experimental data.zip (&gt;60 experiments) Chronoamperometry data Each experiment has a mpr and txt file. The .mpr file can be read by EC-lab software, while the txt file has the raw data. H-NMR data Each experiment has its own folder, then another folder with the experiment number. Within that experiment number folder is .fid file needed to view the H-NMR data. Gas Chromatography data Each experiment has its own folder. the files can be opened using SRI proprietary software. There are also .log files which contain the results of each experiment as the raw data.</description>
      <author>Thomas Chan, Calton Kong, Alex J. King, Rajiv Prabhakar, Finn Babbe, Clifford P. Kubiak, Joel W. Ager</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10251835</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Role of mass transport in electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction to methanol using immobilized cobalt phthalocyanine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10251836</link>
      <description>Thomas Chan, Calton Kong, Alex J. King, Rajiv Prabhakar, Finn Babbe, Clifford P. Kubiak, Joel W. Ager, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393724552

                Cell files.zip .dwg files of the pocket for the cathode and anode chamber. .dwg files of the gasket design Experimental data.zip (&gt;60 experiments) Chronoamperometry data Each experiment has a mpr and txt file. The .mpr file can be read by EC-lab software, while the txt file has the raw data. H-NMR data Each experiment has its own folder, then another folder with the experiment number. Within that experiment number folder is .fid file needed to view the H-NMR data. Gas Chromatography data Each experiment has its own folder. the files can be opened using SRI proprietary software. There are also .log files which contain the results of each experiment as the raw data.</description>
      <author>Thomas Chan, Calton Kong, Alex J. King, Rajiv Prabhakar, Finn Babbe, Clifford P. Kubiak, Joel W. Ager</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10251836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo-electrochemical reduction of Water and Carbon Dioxide enhanced by molecular catalysis</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393407690</link>
      <description>A. Villagra, HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe). None(None)] 2016. https://openalex.org/W4393407690

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Villagra</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393407690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide on gas diffusion electrodes</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393712356</link>
      <description>Ziad Bitar, No host. None(None)] 2014. https://openalex.org/W4393712356

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziad Bitar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393712356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis, study and characterization of new molecular catalysts for reduction of carbon dioxide with a view to use it as a carbon source.</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393356945</link>
      <description>Marc Bourrez, No host. None(None)] 2012. https://openalex.org/W4393356945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marc Bourrez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393356945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly-Amide Modified Copper Foam Electrodes For Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction Of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1183430</link>
      <description>Sunyhik D. Ahn, Konstantin Klyukin, Russell J. Wakeham, Jennifer A. Rudd, Aled R. Lewis, Shirin Alexander, Francesco Carl&#224;, Vitaly Alexandrov, Enrico Andreoli, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4393481976

                Dataset for the paper "Poly-Amide Modified Copper Foam Electrodes for Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide". It includes data from: Electrochemistry, Gas Chromatography, Scanning Electron Microscopy/Energy-Dispersive X-ray Spectroscopy, X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy, Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy, Ex-situ and In-situ Synchrotron X-Ray Diffraction, and DFT computations.</description>
      <author>Sunyhik D. Ahn, Konstantin Klyukin, Russell J. Wakeham, Jennifer A. Rudd, Aled R. Lewis, Shirin Alexander, Francesco Carl&#224;, Vitaly Alexandrov, Enrico Andreoli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1183430</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly-Amide Modified Copper Foam Electrodes For Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction Of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1183429</link>
      <description>Sunyhik D. Ahn, Konstantin Klyukin, Russell J. Wakeham, Jennifer A. Rudd, Aled R. Lewis, Shirin Alexander, Francesco Carl&#224;, Vitaly Alexandrov, Enrico Andreoli, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4393503201

                Dataset for the paper "Poly-Amide Modified Copper Foam Electrodes for Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide". It includes data from: Electrochemistry, Gas Chromatography, Scanning Electron Microscopy/Energy-Dispersive X-ray Spectroscopy, X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy, Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy, Ex-situ and In-situ Synchrotron X-Ray Diffraction, and DFT computations.</description>
      <author>Sunyhik D. Ahn, Konstantin Klyukin, Russell J. Wakeham, Jennifer A. Rudd, Aled R. Lewis, Shirin Alexander, Francesco Carl&#224;, Vitaly Alexandrov, Enrico Andreoli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1183429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Operando Proton Transfer Reaction-Time of Flight-Mass Spectrometry of Carbon Dioxide Reduction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7047052</link>
      <description>Hangjuan Ren, Mikhail Kovalev, Zhaoyue Weng, Marsha Zakir Muhamad, Yuan Sheng, Libo Sun, J. Wang, Simon Rihm, Hongyang Ma, Wanfeng Yang, Alexei A. Lapkin, Joel W. Ager, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4393616536

                Seven top-level folders GC-PTR-TOF-MS - Raw data and Jupyter Notebook used for analysis of GC-PTR-TOF-MS data LSV-PTR-TOF-MS - Raw data and Jupyter Notebook used for analysis of PTR-TOF-MS data under linear sweep voltammetry MSCP-PTR-TOF-MS - Raw data and Jupyter Notebook used for analysis of PTR-TOF-MS data under multi-step chronopotentiometry PTR-TOF-MS-Calibration - Raw data and Jupyter Notebook used for analysis of PTR-TOF-MS calibration data SEM - Raw images from scanning electron microscope Stability - Raw data of electrochemical stability TEM - Raw images from transmission electron microscopy</description>
      <author>Hangjuan Ren, Mikhail Kovalev, Zhaoyue Weng, Marsha Zakir Muhamad, Yuan Sheng, Libo Sun, J. Wang, Simon Rihm, Hongyang Ma, Wanfeng Yang, Alexei A. Lapkin, Joel W. Ager</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7047052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Operando Proton Transfer Reaction-Time of Flight-Mass Spectrometry of Carbon Dioxide Reduction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6419994</link>
      <description>Hangjuan Ren, Mikhail Kovalev, Zhaoyue Weng, Marsha Zakir Muhamad, Yuan Sheng, Libo Sun, J. Wang, Simon Rihm, Hongyang Ma, Wanfeng Yang, Alexei A. Lapkin, Joel W. Ager, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4393769430

                GC-PTR-TOF-MS - Raw data and Jupyter Notebook used for analysis of Cu-1 at 0.8 and 1.0 ampere per square centimeter LSV-PTR-TOF-MS - Raw data and Jupyter Notebook used for analysis of Cu-1 and Cu-2 under linear sweep voltammetry MSCP-PTR-TOF-MS - Raw data and Jupyter Notebook used for analysis of Cu-1 and Ni-doped Cu-1 under multi-step chronopotentiometry SEM - Raw images from scanning electron microscope Stability - Electrochemical stability TEM - Raw images from transmission electron microscopy</description>
      <author>Hangjuan Ren, Mikhail Kovalev, Zhaoyue Weng, Marsha Zakir Muhamad, Yuan Sheng, Libo Sun, J. Wang, Simon Rihm, Hongyang Ma, Wanfeng Yang, Alexei A. Lapkin, Joel W. Ager</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6419994</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvation Procedures Assessment of Borohydride Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4323457</link>
      <description>Alex M. Maldonado, Satoshi Hagiwara, Tae Hoon Choi, Frank Eckert, Kathleen Schwarz, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Minoru Otani, John A. Keith, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4393887620

                Pathways, structures, gas-phase and solvation energies of aqueous borohydride reduction of carbon dioxide. Contents data Computational chemistry output files for gas-phase electronic energies, solvation energies, and QM/MM MD simulations are provided. They are organized by the method used to seek the reaction pathway. neb: contains computations involved with the g-SSNEB pathway from Groenenboom and Keith. gsm: contains computations either in preparation or execution of growing string method (GSM) calculations. The lego module of ABCluster was used to generate candidate starting structures. other: contains miscellaneous computations for additional analyses. scripts: contains all Python code used to generate Chemical JSON and CSV files. qmmm: contains GAMESS QM/MM MD trajectories and WHAM analyses. figures Contains Python scripts and figures made with matplotlib. Python files are named according to the data they use; for example, figure-neb.py is the code for figures that plot the various g-SSNEB pathways. Figures are organized according to where they appear: directly in the article (article/) or as supplemental information (si/). structures XYZ files relevant to this study organized by the chain-of-states method.</description>
      <author>Alex M. Maldonado, Satoshi Hagiwara, Tae Hoon Choi, Frank Eckert, Kathleen Schwarz, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Minoru Otani, John A. Keith</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4323457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvation Procedures Assessment of Borohydride Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4336730</link>
      <description>Alex M. Maldonado, Satoshi Hagiwara, Tae Hoon Choi, Frank Eckert, Kathleen Schwarz, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Minoru Otani, John A. Keith, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4393426326

                Pathways, structures, gas-phase and solvation energies of aqueous borohydride reduction of carbon dioxide. Contents data Computational chemistry output files for gas-phase electronic energies, solvation energies, and QM/MM MD simulations are provided. They are organized by the method used to seek the reaction pathway. neb: contains computations involved with the g-SSNEB pathway from Groenenboom and Keith. gsm: contains computations either in preparation or execution of growing string method (GSM) calculations. The lego module of ABCluster was used to generate candidate starting structures. other: contains miscellaneous computations for additional analyses. scripts: contains all Python code used to generate Chemical JSON and CSV files. qmmm: contains GAMESS QM/MM MD trajectories and WHAM analyses. Note: the QM/MM MD data is in the zip with the "qmmm" suffix. Everything else is in the other zip. figures Contains Python scripts and figures made with matplotlib. Python files are named according to the data they use; for example, figure-neb.py is the code for figures that plot the various g-SSNEB pathways. Figures are organized according to where they appear: directly in the article (article/) or as supplemental information (si/). structures XYZ files relevant to this study organized by the chain-of-states method.</description>
      <author>Alex M. Maldonado, Satoshi Hagiwara, Tae Hoon Choi, Frank Eckert, Kathleen Schwarz, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Minoru Otani, John A. Keith</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4336730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvation Procedures Assessment of Borohydride Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4323456</link>
      <description>Alex M. Maldonado, Satoshi Hagiwara, Tae Hoon Choi, Frank Eckert, Kathleen Schwarz, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Minoru Otani, John A. Keith, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4393895013

                Pathways, structures, gas-phase and solvation energies of aqueous borohydride reduction of carbon dioxide. Contents data Computational chemistry output files for gas-phase electronic energies, solvation energies, and QM/MM MD simulations are provided. They are organized by the method used to seek the reaction pathway. neb: contains computations involved with the g-SSNEB pathway from Groenenboom and Keith. gsm: contains computations either in preparation or execution of growing string method (GSM) calculations. The lego module of ABCluster was used to generate candidate starting structures. other: contains miscellaneous computations for additional analyses. scripts: contains all Python code used to generate Chemical JSON and CSV files. qmmm: contains GAMESS QM/MM MD trajectories and WHAM analyses. Note: the QM/MM MD data is in the zip with the "qmmm" suffix. Everything else is in the other zip. figures Contains Python scripts and figures made with matplotlib. Python files are named according to the data they use; for example, figure-neb.py is the code for figures that plot the various g-SSNEB pathways. Figures are organized according to where they appear: directly in the article (article/) or as supplemental information (si/). structures XYZ files relevant to this study organized by the chain-of-states method.</description>
      <author>Alex M. Maldonado, Satoshi Hagiwara, Tae Hoon Choi, Frank Eckert, Kathleen Schwarz, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Minoru Otani, John A. Keith</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4323456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved estimates of carbon dioxide emissions from drained peatlands support a reduction in emission factor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10069469</link>
      <description>Hongxing He, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393709502

                Summary of published carbon dioxide field emission data and their influence factors used for generating Tier 1 emission factor of peat extractions in IPCC 2013 Wetland Supplementary and extra data published after IPCC (2014). The dataset is supplementary to the published paper "Improved estimates of carbon dioxide emissions from drained peatlands support a reduction in emission factor" By Hongxing He and Nigel Roulet: He, H., Roulet, N.T. Improved estimates of carbon dioxide emissions from drained peatlands support a reduction in emission factor. Commun Earth Environ 4, 436 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-023-01091-y.</description>
      <author>Hongxing He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10069469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved estimates of carbon dioxide emissions from drained peatlands support a reduction in emission factor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10069468</link>
      <description>Hongxing He, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393749257

                Summary of published carbon dioxide field emission data and their influence factors used for generating Tier 1 emission factor of peat extractions in IPCC 2013 Wetland Supplementary and extra data published after IPCC (2014). The dataset is supplementary to the published paper "Improved estimates of carbon dioxide emissions from drained peatlands support a reduction in emission factor" By Hongxing He and Nigel Roulet: He, H., Roulet, N.T. Improved estimates of carbon dioxide emissions from drained peatlands support a reduction in emission factor. Commun Earth Environ 4, 436 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-023-01091-y.</description>
      <author>Hongxing He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10069468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data for: "Carbon dioxide reduction by lanthanide(III) complexes supported by redox-active Schiff base ligands"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7295465</link>
      <description>Nadir Jori, Davide Toniolo, Bang C. Huynh, Rosario Scopelliti, Marinella Mazzanti, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4393645692

                RAW DATA FOR ARTICLE DATE: NOVEMBER 2022 TITLE: Carbon dioxide reduction by lanthanide(III) complexes supported by redox-active Schiff base ligands AUTHORS: Nadir Jori, Davide Toniolo, Bang C. Huynh, Rosario Scopelliti, and Marinella Mazzanti* JOURNAL: Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers (RSC) 2020 DOI: 10.1039/D0QI00801J</description>
      <author>Nadir Jori, Davide Toniolo, Bang C. Huynh, Rosario Scopelliti, Marinella Mazzanti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7295465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data for: "Carbon dioxide reduction by lanthanide(III) complexes supported by redox-active Schiff base ligands"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7295464</link>
      <description>Nadir Jori, Davide Toniolo, Bang C. Huynh, Rosario Scopelliti, Marinella Mazzanti, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4393810733

                RAW DATA FOR ARTICLE DATE: NOVEMBER 2022 TITLE: Carbon dioxide reduction by lanthanide(III) complexes supported by redox-active Schiff base ligands AUTHORS: Nadir Jori, Davide Toniolo, Bang C. Huynh, Rosario Scopelliti, and Marinella Mazzanti* JOURNAL: Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers (RSC) 2020 DOI: 10.1039/D0QI00801J</description>
      <author>Nadir Jori, Davide Toniolo, Bang C. Huynh, Rosario Scopelliti, Marinella Mazzanti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7295464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Iron Oxides for CO2 Capture Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071673</link>
      <description>Antonio Fabozzi, Francesca Cerciello, Osvalda Senneca, Energies (Basel). 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393388356

                The iron industry is the largest energy-consuming manufacturing sector in the world, emitting 4&#8211;5% of the total carbon dioxide (CO2). The development of iron-based systems for CO2 capture and storage could effectively contribute to reducing CO2 emissions. A wide set of different iron oxides, such as hematite (Fe2O3), magnetite (Fe3O4), and w&#252;stite (Fe(1&#8722;y)O) could in fact be employed for CO2 capture at room temperature and pressure upon an investigation of their capturing properties. In order to achieve the most functional iron oxide form for CO2 capture, starting from Fe2O3, a reducing agent such as hydrogen (H2) or carbon monoxide (CO) can be employed. In this review, we present the state-of-the-art and recent advances on the different iron oxide materials employed, as well as on their reduction reactions with H2 and CO.</description>
      <author>Antonio Fabozzi, Francesca Cerciello, Osvalda Senneca</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071673</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New processes for the catalytic reduction of CO2 in chemicals</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393907059</link>
      <description>Sol&#232;ne Savourey, No host. None(None)] 2016. https://openalex.org/W4393907059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sol&#232;ne Savourey</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393907059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Reduction Tafel Dataset for Bayesian Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3995020</link>
      <description>Aditya Limaye, Joy S. Zeng, Adam P. Willard, Karthish Manthiram, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4393480639

                This dataset contains 344 different digitized and tagged Tafel slope datasets from the CO2 reduction literature. We re-analyze this data with a Bayesian data analysis procedure that estimates a Tafel slope and yields distributional uncertainty information about its value. We are releasing this dataset along with our study to facilitate re-analyzing and refitting our data using different models and approaches.</description>
      <author>Aditya Limaye, Joy S. Zeng, Adam P. Willard, Karthish Manthiram</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3995020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raw data for the journal article "Cracks as efficient tools to mitigate flooding in gas diffusion electrodes used for the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6421141</link>
      <description>Ying Kong, Menglong Liu, Huifang Hu, Yuhui Hou, Soma Vesztergom, Mar&#237;a de Jes&#250;s G&#225;lvez&#8208;V&#225;zquez, Ivan Montiel, Viliam Kolivo&#353;ka, Peter Broekmann, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4393675517

                This data set corresponds to the article by Kong et al. entitled "Cracks as efficient tools to mitigate flooding in gas diffusion electrodes used for the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide", published in Small Methods</description>
      <author>Ying Kong, Menglong Liu, Huifang Hu, Yuhui Hou, Soma Vesztergom, Mar&#237;a de Jes&#250;s G&#225;lvez&#8208;V&#225;zquez, Ivan Montiel, Viliam Kolivo&#353;ka, Peter Broekmann</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6421141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raw data for the journal article "Cracks as efficient tools to mitigate flooding in gas diffusion electrodes used for the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6421142</link>
      <description>Ying Kong, Menglong Liu, Huifang Hu, Yuhui Hou, Soma Vesztergom, Mar&#237;a de Jes&#250;s G&#225;lvez&#8208;V&#225;zquez, Ivan Montiel, Viliam Kolivo&#353;ka, Peter Broekmann, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4393699209

                This data set corresponds to the article by Kong et al. entitled "Cracks as efficient tools to mitigate flooding in gas diffusion electrodes used for the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide", published in Small Methods</description>
      <author>Ying Kong, Menglong Liu, Huifang Hu, Yuhui Hou, Soma Vesztergom, Mar&#237;a de Jes&#250;s G&#225;lvez&#8208;V&#225;zquez, Ivan Montiel, Viliam Kolivo&#353;ka, Peter Broekmann</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6421142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dataset to "Hydride Formation Diminishes CO2 Reduction Rate on Palladium"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6828104</link>
      <description>Emanuel Billeter, Terreni Jasmin, Andreas Borgschulte, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4393873967

                Dataset to "Hydride Formation Diminishes CO2 Reduction Rate on Palladium" as published in ChemPhysChem, 20 (2019), 1398-1403</description>
      <author>Emanuel Billeter, Terreni Jasmin, Andreas Borgschulte</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6828104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dataset to "Hydride Formation Diminishes CO2 Reduction Rate on Palladium"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6828103</link>
      <description>Emanuel Billeter, Terreni Jasmin, Andreas Borgschulte, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4393474634

                Dataset to "Hydride Formation Diminishes CO2 Reduction Rate on Palladium" as published in ChemPhysChem, 20 (2019), 1398-1403</description>
      <author>Emanuel Billeter, Terreni Jasmin, Andreas Borgschulte</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6828103</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
