<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:46:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress on the Surface and Bulk Modification of Carbon Nitrides for Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400136</link>
      <description>Sisi Ma, Shuaipeng Wang, Xin Wang, Songcan Wang, Energy technology (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393276940

                Photocatalytic CO 2 reduction has been considered as a green and sustainable approach to solve energy and environmental problems. However, the CO 2 reduction efficiency of various types of semiconductor photocatalysts studied at this stage is far from realizing practical applications. The challenge of photocatalytic CO 2 reduction is to design photocatalysts with excellent catalytic performance. This article summarizes the carbon nitride materials for efficient CO 2 reduction and obtaining high value&#8208;added products. The physicochemical properties of carbon nitride materials are discussed in terms of the photocatalytic mechanisms (bandgap tuning, high specific surface area, shorter electron&#8211;hole transmission paths, increasing the number of active sites, etc.). The present review provides the latest research progress of carbon nitride modification strategies. The prospects and challenges for the application of carbon nitride materials for CO 2 reduction are presented. This review article will provide useful guidance for further research on carbon nitride materials for efficient photocatalytic CO 2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Sisi Ma, Shuaipeng Wang, Xin Wang, Songcan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Design of Transition Metal-Based Catalysts for Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01456</link>
      <description>Liang Guo, Jingwen Zhou, Fu Liu, Xiangchuan Meng, Yangbo Ma, Fengkun Hao, Yi Xiong, Zhanxi Fan, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Guo, Jingwen Zhou, Fu Liu, Xiangchuan Meng, Yangbo Ma, Fengkun Hao, Yi Xiong, Zhanxi Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ladder type covalent organic frameworks constructed with natural units for the oxygen and carbon dioxide reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150812</link>
      <description>Minghao Liu, Shuai Yang, Yubin Fu, Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Jun He, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng, Chemical engineering journal (1996. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393282347

                Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) constructed with metallocyclophane units and organic linkers have found application as electrocatalytic systems. Nevertheless, the majority of linkers within COFs necessitate intricate design and synthesis. Conversely, the potential utilization of natural building blocks in COF construction remains largely unexplored. In this study, we constructed a natural COF (CoPc-EA-COF) by employing a natural phenolic molecule (ellagic acid (EA)) as the linker and Co-hexadecafluorophthalocyanine (CoPc) as blocks. This framework serves as an electrocatalyst for both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). The incorporation of EA units imparts the CoPc-EA-COF with elevated electronic conductivity, enhanced CO2 binding affinity, and superior reductive capacity compared to the controlled COF lacking EA units. The CoPc-EA-COF demonstrated enhanced performance in the ORR, as evidenced by a half-wave potential of 0.80 V. Moreover, it showcased elevated activity and selectivity in the CO2RR, achieving a maximum CO faradic efficiency of 97.32 % at &#8722; 0.8 V, along with turnover frequency (TOF) values reaching 2092 h&#8722;1. Theoretical calculations revealed that the presence of EA units facilitated the generation of OOH* and COOH* species, which are pivotal in the rate-determining stages of both ORR and CO2RR processes. The contribution of EA units significantly bolstered the overall catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Minghao Liu, Shuai Yang, Yubin Fu, Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Jun He, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The reduction mechanism of C1 product from carbon dioxide catalyzed by Ni-doped g-C3N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Molecular catalysis (Online). 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393305887

                This work employs density functional theory (DFT) to scrutinize the catalytic efficacy of nano nickel (Ni) clusters supported by graphitic carbon nitride (Nin@g-C3N4, where n ranges from 1 to 6) in the context of the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Structural examination revealed that Nin@g-C3N4 possesses a substantial binding energy (-1.63 eV to -7.72 eV), confirming the structural stability of the catalyst in the CO2RR. Electronic structure analysis revealed a pronounced orbital overlap near the Fermi level between the 3d orbital of Ni atoms and the 2p orbital of adjacent cavity nitrogen atoms in Nin@g-C3N4. Further insights are gleaned from the calculations of the Bader charge and energy band, indicating significant charge transfer and band gap alteration, suggesting enhanced conductivity due to Ni doping on g-C3N4. The catalytic performance in the CO2RR is predominantly influenced by the size of the doped Ni clusters. The Ni4@g-C3N4 cluster demonstrated optimal efficiency in producing formic acid (HCOOH) with a limiting potential of -0.12 V. In contrast, the Ni5@g-C3N4 cluster excels in methane (CH4) formation, with a limiting potential of -0.35 V. Additionally, these catalysts exhibit marked inhibition of the hydrogen evolution reaction, further underscoring their potential in CO2RR applications.</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of iron oxide supported on activated coke for catalytic reduction of sulfur dioxide by carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106488</link>
      <description>Shanchuan Li, Tai Feng, Qiwen Kong, Jun Li, Peiyi Liu, Peng Ni, Cuiping Wang, Journal of analytical and applied pyrolysis (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393306954

                In view of the low utilization rate of by-product in limestone-gypsum wet flue gas desulfurization process, a method of catalytic reduction of SO2 to elemental sulfur was proposed. In this work, supported iron catalyst using activated coke as supporter was prepared and characterized. Moreover, the performance of SO2 reduction using CO as reducing agent at various Fe loadings, temperatures, gaseous hourly space velocities and CO/SO2 molar ratios was studied. Research shows that, compared with other metals, the highest catalytic activity is achieved over Fe-based catalyst. The iron sulfide is the main active component during the catalytic reduction reaction, hence the catalyst needs to be presulfided before use. The micropores of activated coke become more abundant after loading Fe, whereas excessive increase of Fe loading may bloke the mesopores and weaken the catalytic activity. Higher reaction temperature, lower GHSV and a stoichiometric molar ratio are conducive to the improvement of SO2 conversion and S yield. The catalytic performance at lower temperatures was further improved by loading Co. When the Co loading is 4 wt.%, the SO2 conversion rate reaches 90.9% at 400 &#176;C because loading Co enhances the redox performance of the catalyst surface. The findings are instructive for the development of cost-effective carbon-based catalysts for resource recovery of sulfur.</description>
      <author>Shanchuan Li, Tai Feng, Qiwen Kong, Jun Li, Peiyi Liu, Peng Ni, Cuiping Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Membrane contactor-photocatalytic hybrid system for carbon dioxide capture and conversion to formic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102085</link>
      <description>Andi Rina Ayu Astuti, Wibawa Hendra Saputera, Danu Ariono, I Gede Wenten, Dwiwahju Sasongko, Results in engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393359313

                The escalating demand for Carbon Capture and Utilization (CCU) schemes to mitigate CO2 emissions has propelled research into more efficient methods of CO2 conversion, such as the production of formic acid. While traditional approaches often require harsh operating conditions and substantial energy inputs, photocatalysis offers a promising alternative by harnessing CO2, water, and light for formic acid production. This study evaluates the performance and reaction kinetics of CO2 capture and conversion to formic acid using an integrated membrane contactor and photocatalytic process. Investigation into various CO2 absorbents and reduction catalysts reveals that TEA achieves a CO2 loading of 0.957 moles of CO2/mole of solvent, while NaOH achieves 0.75 moles of CO2/mole of solvent over a 4-hour operation period. Subsequent photoreduction of CO2 results in formic acid concentration of 15.89 ppm using ZnO and 10.16 ppm using TiO2 within the same 4-hour operation period at a gas flow rate of 800 ml/min. The rate of CO2 photoreduction to formic acid emerges as the limiting factor in this integrated process, indicating a need for further optimization. Key parameters identified for optimal performance include a UV source of 500 W, a medium pH of 10, and a catalyst loading of 0.5 g/L. This study contributes to the advancement of CCU technologies by demonstrating the feasibility of integrating CO2 capture and photoreduction using membrane contactors and photocatalytic systems, paving the way for sustainable formic acid production.</description>
      <author>Andi Rina Ayu Astuti, Wibawa Hendra Saputera, Danu Ariono, I Gede Wenten, Dwiwahju Sasongko</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supported Tetra-Atom Clusters on G-Cn as Catalysts for Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4780685</link>
      <description>Wenjing Zhou, Xuxin Kang, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393376349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjing Zhou, Xuxin Kang, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4780685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size&#8208;Dependent Multi&#8208;Electron Donation in Metal&#8208;Complex Quantum Dots Hybrid Catalyst for Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315734</link>
      <description>Qian Zhao, Mohamed Abdellah, Yuehan Cao, Jie Meng, Xianshao Zou, Kasper Enemark&#8208;Rasmussen, Weihua Lin, Yang Li, Yijiang Chen, Hengli Duan, Qinying Pan, Ying Zhou, T&#246;nu Pullerits, Hong Xu, Sophie E. Canton, Yuran Niu, Kaibo Zheng, Advanced functional materials (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393436393

                Abstract The effective conversion of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) into valuable chemical fuels relies significantly on the donation of multiple electrons. Its efficiency is closely linked to both the density and lifetime of excited charge carriers. In this study, a hybrid catalyst system comprising covalently bonded InP/ZnS quantum dots (QDs) and Re&#8208;complexes is showcased. The electronic band alignment between the QDs and the Re&#8208;complexes is revealed to dominate the multi&#8208;electron transfer process for photocatalytic conversion to methane (CH 4 ). Notably, the size of the QDs is found to be a determining parameter. Among the three QD sizes investigated, transient absorption spectroscopy studies unveil that rapid multi&#8208;electron transfer from the QDs to the Re&#8208;catalyst occurs in smaller QDs (2.3 nm) due to the substantial driving force. Consequently, the photocatalytic conversion of CO 2 to CH 4 is significantly enhanced with a turnover number of 6, corresponding to the overall apparent quantum yield of &#8776;1%. This research underscores the possibilities of engineering multi&#8208;electron transfer by manipulating the electronic band alignment within a catalytic system. This can serve as a guide for optimizing photocatalytic CO 2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhao, Mohamed Abdellah, Yuehan Cao, Jie Meng, Xianshao Zou, Kasper Enemark&#8208;Rasmussen, Weihua Lin, Yang Li, Yijiang Chen, Hengli Duan, Qinying Pan, Ying Zhou, T&#246;nu Pullerits, Hong Xu, Sophie E. Canton, Yuran Niu, Kaibo Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrochemical Co&#8208;Reduction of Carbon Dioxide and Nitrate to Urea with High Faradaic Efficiency on Cobalt&#8208;Based Dual&#8208;Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202401221</link>
      <description>Xiaoya Fan, Chaozhen Liu, Xun He, Zixiao Li, Luchao Yue, Wenxi Zhao, Jun Li, Yan Wang, Tingshuai Li, Yongsong Luo, Dewen Zheng, Shengjun Sun, Qian Liu, Luming Li, Wei Chu, Feng Gong, Bo Tang, Yongchao Yao, Xuping Sun, Advanced materials (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393549453

                Abstract Renewable electricity&#8208;powered nitrate/carbon dioxide co&#8208;reduction reaction toward urea production paves an attractive alternative to industrial urea processes and offers a clean on&#8208;site approach to closing the global nitrogen cycle. However, its large&#8208;scale implantation is severely impeded by challenging C&#8208;N coupling and requires electrocatalysts with high activity/selectivity. Here, cobalt&#8208;nanoparticles anchored on carbon nanosheet (Co NPs@C) is proposed as a catalyst electrode to boost yield and Faradaic efficiency (FE) toward urea electrosynthesis with enhanced C&#8208;N coupling. Such Co NPs@C renders superb urea&#8208;producing activity with a high FE reaching 54.3% and a urea yield of 2217.5 &#956;g h &#8211;1 mg cat. &#8211;1 , much superior to the Co NPs and C nanosheet counterparts, and meanwhile shows strong stability. The Co NPs@C affords rich catalytically active sites, fast reactants diffusion, and sufficient catalytic surfaces&#8208;electrolyte contacts with favored charge and ion transfer efficiencies. The theoretical calculations reveal that the high&#8208;rate formation of *CO and *NH 2 intermediates is crucial for facilitating urea synthesis. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Xiaoya Fan, Chaozhen Liu, Xun He, Zixiao Li, Luchao Yue, Wenxi Zhao, Jun Li, Yan Wang, Tingshuai Li, Yongsong Luo, Dewen Zheng, Shengjun Sun, Qian Liu, Luming Li, Wei Chu, Feng Gong, Bo Tang, Yongchao Yao, Xuping Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202401221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo-electrochemical reduction of Water and Carbon Dioxide enhanced by molecular catalysis</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393407690</link>
      <description>A. Villagra, HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe). None(None)] 2016. https://openalex.org/W4393407690

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Villagra</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393407690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis, study and characterization of new molecular catalysts for reduction of carbon dioxide with a view to use it as a carbon source.</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393356945</link>
      <description>Marc Bourrez, HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe). None(None)] 2012. https://openalex.org/W4393356945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marc Bourrez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393356945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly-Amide Modified Copper Foam Electrodes For Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction Of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1183430</link>
      <description>Sunyhik D. Ahn, Konstantin Klyukin, Russell J. Wakeham, Jennifer A. Rudd, Aled R. Lewis, Shirin Alexander, Francesco Carl&#224;, Vitaly Alexandrov, Enrico Andreoli, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4393481976

                Dataset for the paper "Poly-Amide Modified Copper Foam Electrodes for Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide". It includes data from: Electrochemistry, Gas Chromatography, Scanning Electron Microscopy/Energy-Dispersive X-ray Spectroscopy, X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy, Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy, Ex-situ and In-situ Synchrotron X-Ray Diffraction, and DFT computations.</description>
      <author>Sunyhik D. Ahn, Konstantin Klyukin, Russell J. Wakeham, Jennifer A. Rudd, Aled R. Lewis, Shirin Alexander, Francesco Carl&#224;, Vitaly Alexandrov, Enrico Andreoli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1183430</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly-Amide Modified Copper Foam Electrodes For Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction Of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1183429</link>
      <description>Sunyhik D. Ahn, Konstantin Klyukin, Russell J. Wakeham, Jennifer A. Rudd, Aled R. Lewis, Shirin Alexander, Francesco Carl&#224;, Vitaly Alexandrov, Enrico Andreoli, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4393503201

                Dataset for the paper "Poly-Amide Modified Copper Foam Electrodes for Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide". It includes data from: Electrochemistry, Gas Chromatography, Scanning Electron Microscopy/Energy-Dispersive X-ray Spectroscopy, X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy, Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy, Ex-situ and In-situ Synchrotron X-Ray Diffraction, and DFT computations.</description>
      <author>Sunyhik D. Ahn, Konstantin Klyukin, Russell J. Wakeham, Jennifer A. Rudd, Aled R. Lewis, Shirin Alexander, Francesco Carl&#224;, Vitaly Alexandrov, Enrico Andreoli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1183429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvation Procedures Assessment of Borohydride Reduction of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4336730</link>
      <description>Alex M. Maldonado, Satoshi Hagiwara, Tae Hoon Choi, Frank Eckert, Kathleen Schwarz, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Minoru Otani, John A. Keith, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4393426326

                Pathways, structures, gas-phase and solvation energies of aqueous borohydride reduction of carbon dioxide. Contents data Computational chemistry output files for gas-phase electronic energies, solvation energies, and QM/MM MD simulations are provided. They are organized by the method used to seek the reaction pathway. neb: contains computations involved with the g-SSNEB pathway from Groenenboom and Keith. gsm: contains computations either in preparation or execution of growing string method (GSM) calculations. The lego module of ABCluster was used to generate candidate starting structures. other: contains miscellaneous computations for additional analyses. scripts: contains all Python code used to generate Chemical JSON and CSV files. qmmm: contains GAMESS QM/MM MD trajectories and WHAM analyses. Note: the QM/MM MD data is in the zip with the "qmmm" suffix. Everything else is in the other zip. figures Contains Python scripts and figures made with matplotlib. Python files are named according to the data they use; for example, figure-neb.py is the code for figures that plot the various g-SSNEB pathways. Figures are organized according to where they appear: directly in the article (article/) or as supplemental information (si/). structures XYZ files relevant to this study organized by the chain-of-states method.</description>
      <author>Alex M. Maldonado, Satoshi Hagiwara, Tae Hoon Choi, Frank Eckert, Kathleen Schwarz, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Minoru Otani, John A. Keith</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4336730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data for: "Carbon dioxide reduction by lanthanide(III) complexes supported by redox-active Schiff base ligands"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7295465</link>
      <description>Nadir Jori, Davide Toniolo, Bang C. Huynh, Rosario Scopelliti, Marinella Mazzanti, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4393645692

                RAW DATA FOR ARTICLE DATE: NOVEMBER 2022 TITLE: Carbon dioxide reduction by lanthanide(III) complexes supported by redox-active Schiff base ligands AUTHORS: Nadir Jori, Davide Toniolo, Bang C. Huynh, Rosario Scopelliti, and Marinella Mazzanti* JOURNAL: Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers (RSC) 2020 DOI: 10.1039/D0QI00801J</description>
      <author>Nadir Jori, Davide Toniolo, Bang C. Huynh, Rosario Scopelliti, Marinella Mazzanti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7295465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Iron Oxides for CO2 Capture Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071673</link>
      <description>Antonio Fabozzi, Francesca Cerciello, Osvalda Senneca, Energies (Basel). 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393388356

                The iron industry is the largest energy-consuming manufacturing sector in the world, emitting 4&#8211;5% of the total carbon dioxide (CO2). The development of iron-based systems for CO2 capture and storage could effectively contribute to reducing CO2 emissions. A wide set of different iron oxides, such as hematite (Fe2O3), magnetite (Fe3O4), and w&#252;stite (Fe(1&#8722;y)O) could in fact be employed for CO2 capture at room temperature and pressure upon an investigation of their capturing properties. In order to achieve the most functional iron oxide form for CO2 capture, starting from Fe2O3, a reducing agent such as hydrogen (H2) or carbon monoxide (CO) can be employed. In this review, we present the state-of-the-art and recent advances on the different iron oxide materials employed, as well as on their reduction reactions with H2 and CO.</description>
      <author>Antonio Fabozzi, Francesca Cerciello, Osvalda Senneca</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071673</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Reduction Tafel Dataset for Bayesian Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3995020</link>
      <description>Aditya Limaye, Joy S. Zeng, Adam P. Willard, Karthish Manthiram, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2020. https://openalex.org/W4393480639

                This dataset contains 344 different digitized and tagged Tafel slope datasets from the CO2 reduction literature. We re-analyze this data with a Bayesian data analysis procedure that estimates a Tafel slope and yields distributional uncertainty information about its value. We are releasing this dataset along with our study to facilitate re-analyzing and refitting our data using different models and approaches.</description>
      <author>Aditya Limaye, Joy S. Zeng, Adam P. Willard, Karthish Manthiram</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3995020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dataset to "Hydride Formation Diminishes CO2 Reduction Rate on Palladium"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6828103</link>
      <description>Emanuel Billeter, Terreni Jasmin, Andreas Borgschulte, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4393474634

                Dataset to "Hydride Formation Diminishes CO2 Reduction Rate on Palladium" as published in ChemPhysChem, 20 (2019), 1398-1403</description>
      <author>Emanuel Billeter, Terreni Jasmin, Andreas Borgschulte</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.6828103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Cofed Carbon Dioxide Modifies the Local Coordination Environment of Zeolite-Supported, Atomically Dispersed Chromium to Promote Ethane Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c00995</link>
      <description>Wenqi Zhou, Noah Felvey, Jiawei Guo, Adam S. Hoffman, Simon R. Bare, Ambarish Kulkarni, Ron C. Runnebaum, Coleman X. Kronawitter, Journal of the American Chemical Society (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393308679

                The reduction of CO2 is known to promote increased alkene yields from alkane dehydrogenations when the reactions are cocatalyzed. The mechanism of this promotion is not understood in the context of catalyst active-site environments because CO2 is amphoteric, and even general aspects of the chemistry, including the significance of competing side reactions, differ significantly across catalysts. Atomically dispersed chromium cations stabilized in highly siliceous MFI zeolite are shown here to enable the study of the role of parallel CO2 reduction during ethylene-selective ethane dehydrogenation. Based on infrared spectroscopy and X-ray absorption spectroscopy data interpreted through calculations using density functional theory (DFT), the synthesized catalyst contains atomically dispersed Cr cations stabilized by silanol nests in micropores. Reactor studies show that cofeeding CO2 increases stable ethylene-selective ethane dehydrogenation rates over a wide range of partial pressures. Operando X-ray absorption near-edge structure (XANES) and extended X-ray absorption fine-structure (EXAFS) spectra indicate that during reaction at 650 &#176;C the Cr cations maintain a nominal 2+ charge and a total Cr&#8211;O coordination number of approximately 2. However, CO2 reduction induces a change, correlated with the CO2 partial pressure, in the population of two distinct Cr&#8211;O scattering paths. This indicates that the promotional effect of parallel CO2 reduction can be attributed to a subtle change in Cr&#8211;O bond lengths in the local coordination environment of the active site. These insights are made possible by simultaneously fitting multiple EXAFS spectra recorded in different reaction conditions; this novel procedure is expected to be generally applicable for interpreting operando catalysis EXAFS data.</description>
      <author>Wenqi Zhou, Noah Felvey, Jiawei Guo, Adam S. Hoffman, Simon R. Bare, Ambarish Kulkarni, Ron C. Runnebaum, Coleman X. Kronawitter</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c00995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction Catalyzed By Nitrogenase Mofe And Fefe Proteins</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1078505</link>
      <description>Bo Hu, Derek F. Harris, Dennis R. Dean, Tianbiao Liu, Zhi Yong Yang, Lance C. Seefeldt, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2017. https://openalex.org/W4393434443

                Source data for figures 2 and 3 of publication in Bioelectrochemistry (DOI: 10.1016/j.bioelechem.2017.12.002). Data is in comma delimited format.</description>
      <author>Bo Hu, Derek F. Harris, Dennis R. Dean, Tianbiao Liu, Zhi Yong Yang, Lance C. Seefeldt</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1078505</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Prediction Leads to Synthesize GDY Supported InOx Quantum Dots for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202318080</link>
      <description>Feng He, Xi Chen, Yurui Xue, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393314672

                The preparation of formic acid by direct reduction of carbon dioxide is an important basis for the future chemical industry and is of great significance. Due to the serious shortage of highly active and selective electrocatalysts leading to the development of direct reduction of carbon dioxide is limited. Herein the target catalysts with high CO2RR activity and selectivity were identified by integrating DFT calculations and high&#8208;throughput screening and by using graphdiyne (GDY) supported metal oxides quantum dots (QDs) as the ideal model. It is theoretically predicted that GDY supported indium oxide QDs (i.e., InOx/GDY) is a new heterostructure electrocatalyst candidate with optimal CO2RR performance. The interfacial electronic strong interactions effectively regulate the surface charge distribution of QDs and affect the adsorption/desorption behavior of HCOO* intermediate during CO2RR to achieve highly efficient CO2 conversion. Based on the predicted composition and structure, we synthesized the advanced catalytic system, and demonstrates superior CO2&#8208;to&#8208;HCOOH conversion performance. The study presents an effective strategy for rational design of highly efficient heterostructure electrocatalysts to promote green chemical production.</description>
      <author>Feng He, Xi Chen, Yurui Xue, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202318080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Prediction Leads to Synthesize GDY Supported InOx Quantum Dots for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202318080</link>
      <description>Feng He, Xi Chen, Yurui Xue, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie (International ed. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393314720

                The preparation of formic acid by direct reduction of carbon dioxide is an important basis for the future chemical industry and is of great significance. Due to the serious shortage of highly active and selective electrocatalysts leading to the development of direct reduction of carbon dioxide is limited. Herein the target catalysts with high CO2RR activity and selectivity were identified by integrating DFT calculations and high&#8208;throughput screening and by using graphdiyne (GDY) supported metal oxides quantum dots (QDs) as the ideal model. It is theoretically predicted that GDY supported indium oxide QDs (i.e., InOx/GDY) is a new heterostructure electrocatalyst candidate with optimal CO2RR performance. The interfacial electronic strong interactions effectively regulate the surface charge distribution of QDs and affect the adsorption/desorption behavior of HCOO* intermediate during CO2RR to achieve highly efficient CO2 conversion. Based on the predicted composition and structure, we synthesized the advanced catalytic system, and demonstrates superior CO2&#8208;to&#8208;HCOOH conversion performance. The study presents an effective strategy for rational design of highly efficient heterostructure electrocatalysts to promote green chemical production.</description>
      <author>Feng He, Xi Chen, Yurui Xue, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202318080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen in aviation: A simulation of demand, price dynamics, and CO2 emission reduction potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.241</link>
      <description>Katrin Oesingmann, Wolfgang Grimme, Janina Scheelhaase, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393349720

                Aviation contributes to anthropogenic climate change by emitting both carbon dioxide (CO2) and non-CO2 emissions through the combustion of fossil fuels. One approach to reduce the climate impact of aviation is the use of hydrogen as an alternative fuel. Two distinct technological options are presently under consideration for the implementation of hydrogen in aviation: hydrogen fuel cell architectures and the direct combustion of hydrogen. In this study, a hydrogen demand model is developed that considers anticipated advancements in liquid hydrogen aircraft technologies, forecasted aviation demand, and aircraft startup and retirement cycles. The analysis indicates that global demand for liquid hydrogen in aviation could potentially reach 17 million tons by 2050, leading to a 9% reduction in CO2 emissions from global aviation. Thus, the total potential of hydrogen in aviation extends beyond this, considering that the total market share of hydrogen aircraft on suitable routes in the model is projected to be only 27% in 2050 due to aircraft retirement cycles. Additionally, it is shown, that achieving the potential demand for hydrogen in aviation depends on specific market prices. With anticipated declines in current production costs, hydrogen fuel costs would need to reach about 70 EUR/MWh by 2050 to fulfill full demand in aviation, assuming biofuels provide the cheapest option for decarbonization alongside hydrogen. If e-fuels are the sole option for decarbonization alongside hydrogen, which is the more probable scenario, the entire hydrogen demand potential in aviation would be satisfied according to this study's estimates at significantly higher hydrogen prices, approximately 180 EUR/MWh.</description>
      <author>Katrin Oesingmann, Wolfgang Grimme, Janina Scheelhaase</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Dependence of CO2 Reduction Electrocatalyzed by Metal-Nanographene Complexes: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8245274</link>
      <description>Sruthy K. Chandy, Scott Bowers, Krishnan Raghavachari, Liang-shi Li, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393426271

                Data files related to the manuscript titled 'Structure Dependence of CO2 Reduction Electrocatalyzed by Metal-Nanographene Complexes: A Computational Study,' in 'Journal of Physical Chemistry A'</description>
      <author>Sruthy K. Chandy, Scott Bowers, Krishnan Raghavachari, Liang-shi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8245274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Dependence of CO2 Reduction Electrocatalyzed by Metal-Nanographene Complexes: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8245275</link>
      <description>Sruthy K. Chandy, Scott Bowers, Krishnan Raghavachari, Liang-shi Li, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393600029

                Data files related to the manuscript titled 'Structure Dependence of CO2 Reduction Electrocatalyzed by Metal-Nanographene Complexes: A Computational Study,' in 'Journal of Physical Chemistry A'</description>
      <author>Sruthy K. Chandy, Scott Bowers, Krishnan Raghavachari, Liang-shi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8245275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental study and equilibrium analysis on thermal reduction of CO2 by CFB gasification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101623</link>
      <description>Siyuan Zhang, Chen Liang, Xiaofang Wang, Zhengwang Zhu, Journal of the Energy Institute (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393281964

                CO2 can be involved in the CFB gasification process as one of the gasifying agents and be reduced to CO. In this paper, the feasibility of using CFB gasification process to reduce CO2 was investigated by using a bench-scale CFB gasifier. The effect of gasifying agent parameters including the CO2 substitution for N2, the O2 concentration and O2/C were studied. The result of experiments was compared with the chemical equilibrium calculations. The experimental result shows that the reduction of CO2 can be realized in CFB gasification, and the yield of CO in O2/CO2 atmosphere is higher than that that in air atmosphere. When the O2 concentration is 30%, the CO2 conversion reached the maximum of 0.017 Nm3(CO2)/kg(coal). However, the conversion of CO2 is limited by temperature and char reactivity at higher CO2 concentration. The gradual increase in CO2 yield with increasing O2/C suggests that at approximate temperature, the increase in O2/C enhances the oxidation of C and CO. When O2/C is greater than 0.45, the gasification results reach equilibrium. Under other conditions, the gasification results differ from the chemical equilibrium significantly. This is due to the change in the dominant reaction of the gasification process from the combustion reactions to the Boudouard reaction.</description>
      <author>Siyuan Zhang, Chen Liang, Xiaofang Wang, Zhengwang Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational data for "On the role of metal cations in CO2 electrocatalytic reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7122466</link>
      <description>Duy Le, Talat S. Rahman, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4393553651

                This dataset is used for the analysis published in D. Le and T.S. Rahman, "On the role of metal cations in CO2 electroreduction reduction," Nature Catalysis (2022). DOI:10.1038/s41929-022-00876-2</description>
      <author>Duy Le, Talat S. Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7122466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dataset: Bioelectrocatalytic CO2 Reduction by Mo-Dependent Formylmethanofuran Dehydrogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8250712</link>
      <description>Selmihan &#350;ahin, Olivier N. Lemaire, M&#233;lissa Belhamri, Julia M. Kurth, Cornelia U. Welte, Tristan Wagner, Ross D. Milton, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393508513

                Supporting information for article https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202311981</description>
      <author>Selmihan &#350;ahin, Olivier N. Lemaire, M&#233;lissa Belhamri, Julia M. Kurth, Cornelia U. Welte, Tristan Wagner, Ross D. Milton</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8250712</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
