<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 23:59:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Cadmium sulfide nanoparticles compositing with chitosan and metal-organic framework: Enhanced photostability and increased carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-024-00837-2</link>
      <description>Ying Zhang, Hao Liang, Advanced Composites and Hybrid Materials. 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391276659

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Zhang, Hao Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-024-00837-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free&#8208;standing Stanene for High Selectivity of Formate in Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303889</link>
      <description>Xuanhao Mei, Cong Liu, Dezheng Zhang, Jing Cao, Rile Ge, Junhu Wang, Weilin Xu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391280930

                Abstract As well&#8208;known electrocatalysts with good catalytic efficiency for carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) towards the production of formate, tin (Sn)&#8208;based catalysts have aroused broad concern. Here, free&#8208;standing porous stanene is synthesized for the first time by a facile wet chemical method, and its excellent electrocatalytic performance for formate (HCOO &#8722; ) formation in CO 2 RR is demonstrated. High Faradaic efficiency (F.E., 93% at &#8722;930 mV versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE)) can be achieved in the CO 2 RR catalyzed by stanene in 0.5 m KHCO 3 aqueous solution. The in situ M&#246;ssbauer spectra reveal that zero&#8208;valent Sn aids in improving the selectivity of formate production. Furthermore, density functional theory calculations suggest that the high selectivity of HCOO &#8722; of CO 2 RR on stanene mainly originates from the edge sites on Sn (100). To further explore the practicability of the stanene&#8208;based catalysts for CO 2 RR, stanene decorated by 3 wt% BP&#8208;2000 is prepared, showing an excellent F.E. of 98% at &#8722;930 mV versus RHE due to the higher exposure of catalytic active sites. These new findings of the activity origination and reaction mechanism of stanene contribute to the deeper understanding of Sn&#8208;based catalysts for CO 2 RR, which is beneficial for the future designation of highly efficient CO 2 RR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xuanhao Mei, Cong Liu, Dezheng Zhang, Jing Cao, Rile Ge, Junhu Wang, Weilin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface gallium oxide hydroxide species adsorbing carbon dioxide to enhance the photocatalytic activity of a silver-loaded calcium titanate for carbon dioxide reduction with water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3se01390a</link>
      <description>Hongxuan Qiu, Akira Yamamoto, Hisao Yoshida, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391319608

                Photocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) has attracted considerable attention as a new method to build a carbon cycle. Particularly, photocatalytic reduction of CO 2 using water as an electron and...</description>
      <author>Hongxuan Qiu, Akira Yamamoto, Hisao Yoshida</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3se01390a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective reduction on flame soot via plasma coupled with carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.133669</link>
      <description>Dandan Qi, Mingxiao Chen, Kaixuan Yang, Tianjiao Li, Yaoyao Ying, Dong Liu, Journal of Hazardous Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391451084

                This study explored the impact of non-thermal plasma and CO2 on the flame soot characteristics within the diffusion flames. We analyzed on flame structures that were diluted with either CO2 or N2, temperature distributions, and soot characteristics, both in the presence and absence of plasma. Due to the higher specific heat capacity of CO2 compared to N2, the optical observations consistently showed lower temperatures in flames diluted with CO2 as compared to those diluted with N2. The inclusion of plasma and carbon dioxide resulted in the lowest soot concentration, indicating that plasma coupled with CO2 has a synergistic inhibitory effect on soot emissions. The findings revealed that when CO2 was used to dilute the flames and the oxygen concentration was low, the soot nanostructure appeared amorphous. Raman results showed that the level of graphitization observed in soot particles from CO2 dilution flames was lower than that from N2 dilution flames. In the presence of plasma and CO2, the soot obtained exhibited the shortest fringe length and the highest fringe tortuosity. Significant correlations were observed between the nanostructure of soot and its reactivity. The combined application of plasma and CO2 proved to be effective in reducing the soot carbonization degree. Soot particles produced during incomplete combustion not only reduce the performance of the combustion system but also cause significant environmental pollution and health problems. Oxygen-fuel combustion integrated with O2/CO2 as an oxidant instead of O2/N2 has drawn extensive attention due to its unique advantages in reducing soot and NOx generation and combining with CO2 recycling technologies. This topic provides a detailed and profound understanding of the mechanisms behind soot suppression through the combined effects of CO2 addition and plasma activation.</description>
      <author>Dandan Qi, Mingxiao Chen, Kaixuan Yang, Tianjiao Li, Yaoyao Ying, Dong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.133669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Interplay of the Br&#248;nsted Acidity of Catalyst Ancillary Groups and the Solution Components in Iron-porphyrin-Mediated Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10127</link>
      <description>Ana Sonea, Nicholas R. Crudo, Jeffrey J. Warren, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391464343

                The rapid and efficient conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) to carbon monoxide (CO) is an ongoing challenge. Catalysts based on iron-porphyrin cores have emerged as excellent electrochemical mediators of the two proton + two electron reduction of CO2 to CO, and many of the design features that promote function are known. Of those design features, the incorporation of Br&#248;nsted acids in the second coordination sphere of the iron ion has a significant impact on catalyst turnover kinetics. The Br&#248;nsted acids are often in the form of hydroxyphenyl groups. Herein, we explore how the acidity of an ancillary 2-hydroxyphenyl group affects the performance of CO2 reduction electrocatalysts. A series of meso-5,10,15,20-tetraaryl porphyrins were prepared where only the functional group at the 5-meso position has an ionizable proton. A series of cyclic voltammetry (CV) experiments reveal that the complex with &#8722;OMe positioned para to the ionizable &#8722;OH shows the largest CO2 reduction rate constants in acetonitrile solvent. This is the least acidic &#8722;OH of the compounds surveyed. The turnover frequency of the &#8722;OMe derivative can be further improved with the addition of 4-trifluoromethylphenol to the solution. In contrast, the iron-porphyrin complex with &#8722;CF3 positioned opposite the ionizable &#8722;OH shows the smallest CO2 reduction rate constants, and its turnover frequency is less enhanced with the addition of phenols to the reaction solutions. The origin of this effect is rationalized based on kinetic isotope effect experiments and density functional calculations. We conclude that catalysts with weaker internal acids coupled with stronger external acid additives provide superior CO2 reduction kinetics.</description>
      <author>Ana Sonea, Nicholas R. Crudo, Jeffrey J. Warren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts for electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00003-3</link>
      <description>Subhash Chandra Shit, Indranil Mondal, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488466

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction carries tremendous significance to tackle the exponential rising of CO2 level in the atmosphere. The development of different classes of electrocatalyst materials emerged with more understanding of the catalyst features, reaction mechanism, catalytic efficiency, and product selectivity using modern analytical tools (such as in situ techniques). Single-atom catalysts (SACs) are a new class of material that allows atom-by-atom utilization in the catalytic process, thereby influencing the CO2 reduction efficiency and product selectivity in more precise manner. In this chapter, we highlight the fundamental of CO2 electroreduction, including general mechanism for varied product formation, electrolyzer component, operational parameter, and development of SACs electrode material for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Subhash Chandra Shit, Indranil Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00003-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvation of oxygen, carbon dioxide, carbon monoxide and nitrous oxide in fluorinated liquids</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4391327398</link>
      <description>Margarida F Costa Gomes, A.A.H. Padua J. Deschamps D.-H. Menz, No host. None(None)] 2005. https://openalex.org/W4391327398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Margarida F Costa Gomes, A.A.H. Padua J. Deschamps D.-H. Menz</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4391327398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction at Different Electrocatalyst Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12020303</link>
      <description>Marcela Miranda Barcelos, Maria de Lourdes Soprani Vasconcellos, Josimar Ribeiro, Processes. 12(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391384166

                Given the environmental problems caused by burning fossil fuels, it is believed that converting carbon dioxide (CO2) into chemical inputs is a great ally to generating clean energy. In this way, investigative studies related to electrochemical CO2 reduction (CO2RE) concerning the behavior of metal catalysts have received attention about the processes involved. CO2RE can be an important tool to mitigate the presence of this gas in the Earth&#8217;s atmosphere. Given these considerations, in this review, we report the main catalysts used to act as CO2RE. Among them, we emphasize catalysts based on Ni, Zn, and Cu, which encompass the main properties related to the electrochemical conversion of CO2. Regarding the Cu-based catalyst, it presents high conversion efficiency but low selectivity. Furthermore, we also describe the main mechanisms related to the electrochemical conversion of CO2.</description>
      <author>Marcela Miranda Barcelos, Maria de Lourdes Soprani Vasconcellos, Josimar Ribeiro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12020303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Flexible Operation of a Wastewater Treatment Plant in the Reduction of Its Indirect Carbon Dioxide Emissions&#8212;A Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/w16030483</link>
      <description>Nil&#252;fer Topuz, Frank Alsmeyer, Hasancan Okutan, Hermann-Josef Roos, Water. 16(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391432666

                The increasing share of renewables in electricity grids comes with a challenge of energy surpluses and deficits, which needs be handled by demand side management (DSM) and storage options. Within this approach, wastewater treatment plants (WWTPs), with flexible energy consumption and production processes and storage units, can contribute to stabilizing the grids and integrating more renewables. In this study, the operation of a real WWTP was optimized by mixed integer linear programming (MILP) to minimize its indirect carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions. The operation of the WWTP was shown to be flexible in following the CO2 emission factor of the electricity grid, which was possible with the utilization of the WWTP&#8217;s storage units and flexible co-substrate feeding. As a result, by changing only the operational behavior of the WWTP, its indirect CO2 emissions decreased by 4.8% due to the higher share of renewables in the electricity grid. The CO2 emissions were shown to decrease further up to 6.9% by adding virtual storage units.</description>
      <author>Nil&#252;fer Topuz, Frank Alsmeyer, Hasancan Okutan, Hermann-Josef Roos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/w16030483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-organic framework composites for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126532</link>
      <description>Kayode Adesina Adegoke, Joshua O. Ighalo, Jeanet Conradie, Chinemerem Ruth Ohoro, James F. Amaku, Kabir O. Oyedotun, Nobanathi Wendy Maxakato, Kovo G. Akpomie, Emmanuel Sunday Okeke, Chijioke Olisah, Alhadji Malloum, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391515522

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) levels in the atmosphere are quickly increasing as a consequence of anthropogenic activities, which present grave hazards and dangerous circumstances to not only humanity but also the ecosystem. Currently, electrochemical CO2 conversion to chemical/fuels remains one of the best methods for minimizing CO2 concentrations. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) composite materials have been considered as new class of highly-performed electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) due to their wide surface area, higher porosity, chemical tunability and excellent stability. This article presents major approaches for electrochemical CO2RR to value-added product. These were followed by discussing the recent advancements in MOF composite electrocatalysts for CO2RR including active sites MOF-supported electrocatalysts, metal-nanoparticles-supported MOFs, conductive supported MOFs composites, and polyoxometalate-based MOF composites. Lastly, some challenges currently facing MOF composites for CO2RR as well as anticipated future advances were discussed. Research hotspot lies in the creation of highly effective CO2RR electrocatalyst such as ligand engineering in MOFs. It is believed that the current study will contribute to accelerating the fabrication of efficient MOF composite materials for abating the CO2 emission in the ecosystem and to highlight the necessity for further research to address significant environmental sustainability concerns.</description>
      <author>Kayode Adesina Adegoke, Joshua O. Ighalo, Jeanet Conradie, Chinemerem Ruth Ohoro, James F. Amaku, Kabir O. Oyedotun, Nobanathi Wendy Maxakato, Kovo G. Akpomie, Emmanuel Sunday Okeke, Chijioke Olisah, Alhadji Malloum</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes for CO2 reduction: a promising choice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95515-7.00011-x</link>
      <description>Saira Ajmal, Anuj Kumar, Tuan Anh Nguyen, Ghulam Yasin, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488885

                Fast industrialization and urban growth emit significant amounts of hazardous CO2, which not only produces environmental problems but also causes illness all over the world. Several technologies for purifying air and water have been developed over the last two decades, but they have all failed due to high costs, poor effectiveness, and the creation of secondary contaminants. The photochemical and electrochemical conversion of CO2 into energy-rich molecules is a novel method that can aid in environmental rehabilitation while also meeting the world&#8217;s expanding energy demands. These techniques, however, necessitate extremely selective, energetic, and long-lasting catalysts. Scientists have investigated numerous keen and multifunctional materials for the conversion of CO2 pollution into useful compounds in this area. MXenes, a type of two-dimensional (2D) material made of transition metal nitrides, carbides, and carbonitrides, have engrossed attention because of their extraordinary physicochemical, mechanical, and electrochemical properties. This chapter focuses on CO2 conversion by photochemical and electrochemical methods to valuable products, emphasizing MXene-based materials and their catalytic activity, as well as future prospects.</description>
      <author>Saira Ajmal, Anuj Kumar, Tuan Anh Nguyen, Ghulam Yasin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95515-7.00011-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haeckelite mediated reduction of CO2 by molecular hydrogen. A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114499</link>
      <description>Wilmer Esteban Vallejo Narv&#225;ez, C&#233;sar Gabriel Vera de la Garza, Serguei Fomine, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391487109

                In this study, we conducted a theoretical exploration of haeckelite-mediated CO2 reduction with molecular hydrogen. We used a haeckelite nanoflake (NF) consisting of 96 carbon atoms passivated with hydrogens to elucidate the reaction mechanism on the 2D surface. The most favorable reaction pathway involves the sequential formation of formic acid, formaldehyde, methanol, and ultimately methane. Notably, formic acid formation is favored over carbon monoxide. Haeckelite-mediated reactions exhibit Gibbs-free activation energies 10 to 40 kcal/mol lower compared to processes without a catalyst. This catalytic effect is attributed to the interaction of H2 with the haeckelite surface, which weakens or breaks the HH bond. This theoretical perspective provides significant insights into carbon-based materials and their potential applications in transforming CO2 into fuels and value-added chemicals.</description>
      <author>Wilmer Esteban Vallejo Narv&#225;ez, C&#233;sar Gabriel Vera de la Garza, Serguei Fomine</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancies synergistic cobalt phosphide electron bridge modulated bismuth oxychloride/carbon nitride Z-scheme junction for efficient carbon dioxide reduction coupled with tetracycline oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.149</link>
      <description>Haoyu Sun, Xuemei Jia, Jing Cao, Shifu Chen, Yong Chen, Haili Lin, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391264958

                Although great progress has been made with respect to electron bridges, the electron mobility of the state-of-the-art electron bridges is far from satisfactory because of weak electrical conductivity. To overcome the above issue, cobalt phosphide (CoP), as a model electron bridge, was modified with superficial oxygen vacancies (OVs) and embedded into a defective bismuth oxychloride/carbon nitride (BiO1-xCl/g-C3N4) Z-scheme heterojunction to obtain atomic-level insights into the effect of surface OVs on CoP electron bridges. Compared to BiO1-xCl/g-C3N4 and bismuth oxychloride/cobalt phosphide/carbon nitride (BiOCl/CoP/g-C3N4) composites, the defective bismuth oxychloride/cobalt phosphide/carbon nitride (BiO1-xCl/CoP/g-C3N4) heterojunction exhibited remarkable photocatalytic redox performance, indicating that the surface OVs-assisted CoP electron bridge effectively boosted electrical conductivity and yielded ultrafast electron transfer rates. The theoretical and experimental results demonstrate that the surface OVs play a critical role in improving the electrical conductivity of the CoP electron bridge, thereby accelerating electron mobility. This research provides insights into interfacial OVs-modified transition metal phosphide (TMP) electron bridges and their potential application in heterojunctions for energy crisis mitigation and environmental remediation.</description>
      <author>Haoyu Sun, Xuemei Jia, Jing Cao, Shifu Chen, Yong Chen, Haili Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supported copper-based gas diffusion electrodes improve the local CO2 concentration for efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11705-024-2392-6</link>
      <description>Azeem Mustafa, Bachirou Guene Lougou, Yong Shuai, Zhijiang Wang, Haseeb-ur-Rehman, Samia Razzaq, Wei Wang, Ruming Pan, Jiupeng Zhao, Frontiers of Chemical Science and Engineering. 18(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391439692

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Azeem Mustafa, Bachirou Guene Lougou, Yong Shuai, Zhijiang Wang, Haseeb-ur-Rehman, Samia Razzaq, Wei Wang, Ruming Pan, Jiupeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11705-024-2392-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Surface and Interface Structures of Copper-Based Catalysts for Enhanced Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 to Alcohols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17030600</link>
      <description>Yanbo Hua, Chiwei Zhu, Liming Zhang, Fan Dong, Materials. 17(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391253799

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction (ECR) has emerged as a promising solution to address both the greenhouse effect caused by CO2 emissions and the energy shortage resulting from the depletion of nonrenewable fossil fuels. The production of multicarbon (C2+) products via ECR, especially high-energy-density alcohols, is highly desirable for industrial applications. Copper (Cu) is the only metal that produces alcohols with appreciable efficiency and kinetic viability in aqueous solutions. However, poor product selectivity is the main technical problem for applying the ECR technology in alcohol production. Extensive research has resulted in the rational design of electrocatalyst architectures using various strategies. This design significantly affects the adsorption energetics of intermediates and the reaction pathways for alcohol production. In this review, we focus on the design of effective catalysts for ECR to alcohols, discussing fundamental principles, innovative strategies, and mechanism understanding. Furthermore, the challenges and prospects in utilizing Cu-based materials for alcohol production via ECR are discussed.</description>
      <author>Yanbo Hua, Chiwei Zhu, Liming Zhang, Fan Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17030600</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Activity and Mechanism Alterations by Pyrene Decoration on a Co(II) Macrocyclic Catalyst for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301113</link>
      <description>Weilu Zhang, Hai&#8208;Hua Huang, Zhi&#8208;Mei Luo, Fan Ma, Sergio Gonell, Zhuofeng Ke, Liang Tan, Jia&#8208;Wei Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391359187

                Mechanistic studies involving characterization of crucial intermediates are desirable for rational optimization of molecular catalysts toward CO2 reduction, while fundamental challenges are associated with such studies. Herein we present the systematic mechanistic investigations on a pyrene&#8208;appended CoII macrocyclic catalyst in comparison with its pyrene&#8208;free prototype. The comparative results also verify the reasons of the higher catalytic activity of the pyrene&#8208;tethered catalyst in noble&#8208;metal&#8208;free CO2 photoreduction with various photosensitizers, where a remarkable apparent quantum yield of 36&#177;3% at 425 nm can be obtained for selective CO production. Electrochemical and spectroelectrochemical studies in conjunction with DFT calculations between the two catalysts have characterized the key CO&#8208;bound intermediates and revealed their different CO&#8208;binding behavior, demonstrating that the pyrene group endows the corresponding CoII catalyst a lower catalytic potential, a higher stability, and a greater ease in CO release, all of which contribute to its better performance.</description>
      <author>Weilu Zhang, Hai&#8208;Hua Huang, Zhi&#8208;Mei Luo, Fan Ma, Sergio Gonell, Zhuofeng Ke, Liang Tan, Jia&#8208;Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmartPrioGIS - A Concept for Recording, Holding and Evaluating Data as a Contribution to CO2 Reduction for the Kassel University Campus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18086/eurosun.2022.10.06</link>
      <description>Swen Klau&#223;, Rolf L. Gross, Lukas Lohse, Anton Maas, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4391288199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Swen Klau&#223;, Rolf L. Gross, Lukas Lohse, Anton Maas</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18086/eurosun.2022.10.06</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly-exposed copper and ZIF-8 interface enables synthesis of hydrocarbons by electrocatalytic reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.205</link>
      <description>Bo Sun, Hao Hu, Hangchen Liu, Jun Guan, Kexing Song, Changrui Shi, Haoyan Cheng, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391515357

                Electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) to fuels and chemicals is a promising route to close the anthropogenic carbon cycle for sustainable society. The Cu-based catalysts in producing high-value hydrocarbons feature unique superiorities, yet challenges remain in achieving high selectivity. In this work, Cu@ZIF-8 NWs with highly-exposed Cu nanowires (Cu NWs) and ZIF-8 interface are synthesized via a surfactant-assisted method. Impressively, Cu@ZIF-8 NWs exhibit excellent stability and a high Faradaic efficiency of 57.5% toward hydrocarbons (CH4 and C2H4) at a potential of -0.7 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode. Computational calculations combining with experiments reveal the formation of Cu and ZIF-8 interface optimizes the adsorption of reaction intermediates, particularly stabilizing the formation of *CHO, thereby enabling efficient preference for hydrocarbons. This work highlights the potential of constructing metals and MOFs heterogeneous interfaces to enhance catalytic properties and offers valuable insights for the design of highly efficient CO2RR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Bo Sun, Hao Hu, Hangchen Liu, Jun Guan, Kexing Song, Changrui Shi, Haoyan Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing microbial CO2 electrocatalysis for multicarbon reduction in a wet amine&#8208;based catholyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301342</link>
      <description>Hui Su Kim, Sang&#8208;Min Lee, Myounghoon Moon, Hyun June Jung, Jiye Lee, Young-Hwan Chu, Eun Jung Kim, Danbee Kim, Gwon Woo Park, Chang Hyun Ko, Soo-Youn Lee, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391358979

                Microbial CO2 electroreduction (mCO2ER) offers a promising approach for producing high&#8208;value multicarbon reductants from CO2 by combining CO2 fixing microorganisms with conducting materials (i.e., cathodes). However, the solubility and availability of CO2 in an aqueous electrolyte pose significant limitations in this system. This study demonstrates the efficient production of long&#8208;chain multicarbon reductants, specifically carotenoids (~C40), within a wet amine&#8208;based catholyte medium during mCO2ER. Optimizing the concentration of the biocompatible CO2 absorbent, monoethanolamine (MEA), led to enhanced CO2 fixation in the electroautotroph bacteria. Molecular biological analyses revealed that MEA in the catholyte medium redirected the carbon flux towards carotenoid biosynthesis during mCO2ER. The faradaic efficiency of mCO2ER with MEA for carotenoid production was 4.5&#8208;fold higher than that of the control condition. These results suggest the mass transport bottleneck in bioelectrochemical systems could be effectively addressed by MEA&#8208;assissted mCO2ER, enabling highly efficient production of valuable products from CO2.</description>
      <author>Hui Su Kim, Sang&#8208;Min Lee, Myounghoon Moon, Hyun June Jung, Jiye Lee, Young-Hwan Chu, Eun Jung Kim, Danbee Kim, Gwon Woo Park, Chang Hyun Ko, Soo-Youn Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoTCPP integrates with BiOBr microspheres for improved solar-driven CO2 reduction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.01.008</link>
      <description>Lina Li, Yi Zhang, Gaopeng Liu, Tiange Wei, Junze Zhao, Bin Wang, Mengxia Ji, Yuanbin She, Jiexiang Xia, Huaming Li, Green Energy &amp; Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391482249

                CO2 photoreduction into carbon-based chemicals has been considered as an appropriate way to alleviate the energy issue and greenhouse effect. Herein, the 5, 10, 15, 20-tetra (4-carboxyphenyl) porphyrin cobalt(II) (CoTCPP) has been integrated with BiOBr microspheres and formed the CoTCPP/BiOBr composite. The as-prepared CoTCPP/BiOBr-2 shows optimized photocatalytic performance for CO2 conversion into CO and CH4 upon irradiation with 300 W Xe lamp, which is 2.03 and 2.58 times compared to that of BiOBr, respectively. The introduced CoTCPP significantly enhanced light absorption properties, promoted rapid separation of photogenerated carriers and boosted the chemisorption of CO2 molecules. The metal Co2+ at the center of the porphyrin molecules also acts as adsorption center for CO2 molecules, boosting the CO2 convert into CO and CH4. The possible mechanism of CO2 photoreduction was explored by in-situ FT-IR spectra. This work offers a new possibility for the preparation of advance photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Lina Li, Yi Zhang, Gaopeng Liu, Tiange Wei, Junze Zhao, Bin Wang, Mengxia Ji, Yuanbin She, Jiexiang Xia, Huaming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.01.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of CO2 emissions in oil pipelines through conversion of hydraulic energy into electrical energy using an HPRT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48072/2447-2069.rpc.2023.066</link>
      <description>Jhon Ussa, Heidy Monroy, Ricardo Oicat, Walter Gastelbondo, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391473709

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jhon Ussa, Heidy Monroy, Ricardo Oicat, Walter Gastelbondo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48072/2447-2069.rpc.2023.066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating interfacial charges in CTF-based metal-insulator-semiconductor promotes selective CO2 reduction to CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149027</link>
      <description>Qiaoshan Chen, Yueling Chen, Mingfei Yu, Bin Xu, Hongbin Wu, Liuyi Li, Jinhong Bi, Chemical Engineering Journal. 482(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391344528

                A metal&#8211;insulator-semiconductor (MIS) ternary photo-system was intricately crafted through precise amalgamation polyvinylpyrrolidone (PVP)-capped metal Cu with typical covalent triazine framework CTF-1 via electrostatic self-assembly. The 2 % Cu-PVP-CTF exhibited an impressive CH4 yield of 80.7 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1 with selectivity of 96.8 % under visible light, representing a 2.3-fold and 112-fold improvement over Schottky-type Cu-CTF and pristine CTF-1, respectively. In-situ XPS and VASP-diff calculations unfolded that the ultrathin PVP insulating layer significantly expedited interfacial charges tunneling, corroborated by smaller lifetime &#964;2 determined via femtosecond transient absorption spectroscopy. The intermediates of paramount importance in CO2 reduction like *COOH and *HCHO were meticulously monitored by in-situ Fourier infrared spectroscopy. DFT calculations elucidated that Cu-PVP-CTF was notably more adept at facillitating the rate-determining step (*COOH &#8594; *CO) to produce CH4 than Cu-CTF. This work tamps the groundwork for conceptional roadmap in designing novel MIS photo-system for CO2 conversion.</description>
      <author>Qiaoshan Chen, Yueling Chen, Mingfei Yu, Bin Xu, Hongbin Wu, Liuyi Li, Jinhong Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced reduction of CO2 to CH4 by novel mesoporous Ru-Fe3O4/CeOx-SiO2 catalyst in a fixed bed reactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/au.170669628.88839658/v1</link>
      <description>Swarnil Roy, Dilip Kumar Mondal, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391401348

                A novel mesoporous Ru-Fe3O4/CeOx-SiO2 (Ce3+/Ce4+, x=1.64) catalyst was synthesized via excess solution impregnation of Ru and Fe3O4 nanoparticles (NPs) on ceria-loaded mesoporous SBA-15. The reduction of CO2 to methane was performed in the presence of H2 over the catalyst in a fixed bed reactor. CO2 reduction was found to be 82% at 0.25 wt% ruthenium loading, 2.5 wt% iron loading, 573 K temperature, 20 bar pressure, 3000 mL.g.-1. h-1 gas hour space velocity and H2 to CO2 mole ratio of 5:1. The close contact between ruthenium and Fe3O4 nanoparticles facilitated the reduction of CO2 through hydrogen spill-over effect and ceria NPs acted as a promoter for reduction reaction. The catalysts were characterized thoroughly using CO chemisorption, BET, TPR, TPD, XRD, SEM, HR TEM, ICP-AES and XPS techniques. Optimal process conditions could render much higher CO2 conversion efficacy for selective methane synthesis in comparison with previous scientific investigations.</description>
      <author>Swarnil Roy, Dilip Kumar Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/au.170669628.88839658/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction enhanced by Sb doping in MOF-derived carbon-supported Bi-based materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126520</link>
      <description>Shuangchen Ma, Kai Wu, Shuaijun Fan, Ying Liu, Chen Ju, Jing Ma, Lijuan Yang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391470101

                Amidst the myriad catalysts employed in the electrochemical reduction of CO2, bimetallic materials stand out for their augmented catalytic activity and product selectivity. Bismuth (Bi), recognized for its marked selectivity towards formic acid along with attributes of low toxicity, cost-effectiveness, and widespread accessibility, emerges as a highly promising candidate with extensive research underway. Nonetheless, the catalytic attributes of Sb/Bi bimetallic composite materials incorporating antimony (Sb) elements have received limited attention. This study presents a successful synthesis of carbon-supported Sb/Bi bimetallic composite materials via the MOF templating approach, followed by a comprehensive exploration of their electrocatalytic properties for CO2 reduction. The investigation underscores the predominant integration of Sb elements in alloy configuration within the catalytic matrix. Trace Sb doping (&#8804;3.1 %) emerges as a means to effectively suppress the formation of *H species while concurrently promoting *OCHO species, leading to a substantial elevation in the formate selectivity of Bi-based materials. In contrast, excessive Sb doping, by exacerbating *H formation, inadvertently intensifies the HER process, thereby unfavorably influencing formate generation. Promisingly, in comparison to Bi@C materials, Sb/Bi@C materials doped with minute quantities of Sb showcase enhanced electrode stability and an extended catalytic lifespan within the context of electrochemical operating conditions, which can be attributed to the fact that the introduction of Sb can significantly strengthen the spherical physical structure of carbon-borne nanomaterials on the surface of Bi@C materials. Through an amalgamation of empirical characterization and DFT calculations, this inquiry elucidates the pivotal role assumed by Sb incorporation in Bi materials, consequently advancing the realm of CO2RR. The research emphasizes a strategy of phase and structure engineering, which can provide valuable insights for the development of high-performance electrocatalysts not only in CO2RR but also in other fields.</description>
      <author>Shuangchen Ma, Kai Wu, Shuaijun Fan, Ying Liu, Chen Ju, Jing Ma, Lijuan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126520</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 reduction and the production of high-value biomaterials using waste medium by Rhodobacter sphaeroides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/au.170668064.45726075/v1</link>
      <description>Juyong Park, Jaeyoung Yu, Ngoc Nguyen, Yang&#8208;Hoon Kim, Jiho Min, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391392848

                The purple non-sulfur photosynthetic bacteria, Rhodobacter sphaeroides, are capable of growing under a variety of environmental conditions. R. sphaeroides wastewater treatment has received considerable attention, since it can simultaneously realize wastewater purification and biomass recycling. In addition, poly-&#946;-Hydroxybutyrate (PHB), a biopolymer that can be used as a biodegradable thermoplastic material for waste management strategies, and other polyhydroxyalkanoates (PHAs) are accumulated by many bacteria as energy and carbon reserve material. In this study, the used culture media of Escherichia coli and Saccharomyces cerevisiae were reutilized to grow R. sphaeroides to produce PHB and reduce carbon dioxide. Moreover when using used media, photopigments, such as bacteriochlorophyll and carotenoid, was also synthesized. Finally, the co-fermentation of R. sphaeroides and S. cerevisiae showed the potential of enhancing ethanol production with higher yield than the single use of S. cerevisiae. Therefore, this approach provides a low-cost and eco-friendly process that uses waste media to fix carbon dioxide, and produce high-value biomaterials.</description>
      <author>Juyong Park, Jaeyoung Yu, Ngoc Nguyen, Yang&#8208;Hoon Kim, Jiho Min</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/au.170668064.45726075/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing deep transient testing for reservoir characterization and CO2 emission reduction in challenging geological settings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ptlrs.2024.01.014</link>
      <description>Eghbal Motaei, Tarek Al-Arbi Omar Ganat, Khairul Azhar, Hamoud Al-Hadrami, Petroleum Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391383558

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eghbal Motaei, Tarek Al-Arbi Omar Ganat, Khairul Azhar, Hamoud Al-Hadrami</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ptlrs.2024.01.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting CO2 piezo-reduction via metal-support interactions in Au/ZnO based catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.169</link>
      <description>Rundong Zhou, Di Wu, Jing Ma, Lujie Ruan, Yajie Feng, Chaogang Ban, Kai Zhou, Shuangyang Cai, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Xiaoyuan Zhou, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 661(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391467379

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rundong Zhou, Di Wu, Jing Ma, Lujie Ruan, Yajie Feng, Chaogang Ban, Kai Zhou, Shuangyang Cai, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Xiaoyuan Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.169</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
