<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 01:10:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon monoxide synthesis from carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-19235-7.00006-3</link>
      <description>Douglas S.D. Santos, Alexandre Mendon&#231;a Teixeira, Stefano Ferrari Interlenghi, Gabriel S. Bassani, Rita M.B. Alves, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401012803

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Douglas S.D. Santos, Alexandre Mendon&#231;a Teixeira, Stefano Ferrari Interlenghi, Gabriel S. Bassani, Rita M.B. Alves</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-19235-7.00006-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional reconstruction of porous CeO2 single crystal for effective electrolysis of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235088</link>
      <description>Jiaming Ma, Mengmeng Miao, Kui Xie, Kui Xie, Journal of Power Sources. 615(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401027649

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaming Ma, Mengmeng Miao, Kui Xie, Kui Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous electrochemical reduction of water and oxidation of carbon in a solid oxide cell for separately producing hydrogen and carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144792</link>
      <description>Xiaomin Yan, Mingyang Zhou, Xiaofeng Gu, Xueying Gong, Weizi Cai, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401148756

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaomin Yan, Mingyang Zhou, Xiaofeng Gu, Xueying Gong, Weizi Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Loss in Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction by Advanced Material and Electrolyzer Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400786</link>
      <description>Yue Yang, Fan He, Xiangzhou Lv, Qian Liu, Angjian Wu, Zhifu Qi, Hao Bin Wu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401151892

                Electrocatalytic CO</description>
      <author>Yue Yang, Fan He, Xiangzhou Lv, Qian Liu, Angjian Wu, Zhifu Qi, Hao Bin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting and stabilizing the electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide on Bi2O2CO3 via surface modification with p-aminobenzoic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124451</link>
      <description>Leliang Cao, Jie Huang, Xueying Wu, Qingqing Xu, Kaixuan Su, Yuanhong Zhong, Ming Sun, Lin Yu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401055636

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leliang Cao, Jie Huang, Xueying Wu, Qingqing Xu, Kaixuan Su, Yuanhong Zhong, Ming Sun, Lin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive study and design optimization of a hybrid solar-biomass system for enhanced hydrogen production and carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.124074</link>
      <description>Walid Aich, Ali Basem, Dheyaa J. Jasim, Kuwar Mausam, Ali Shawabkeh, Shuhairimi Abdullah, Yousef Mohammed Alanazi, Husam Rajab, Lotfi Ben Said, A.S. El-Shafay, Applied Thermal Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401198552

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Walid Aich, Ali Basem, Dheyaa J. Jasim, Kuwar Mausam, Ali Shawabkeh, Shuhairimi Abdullah, Yousef Mohammed Alanazi, Husam Rajab, Lotfi Ben Said, A.S. El-Shafay</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.124074</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of Tm-Based Dual-Atom Catalysts Supported by B,N-Doped Biphenylene for Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4906500</link>
      <description>Maryam Fallahzadeh, Alireza Kokabi, Zahra Nasiri, Mina Fayazi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401027800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maryam Fallahzadeh, Alireza Kokabi, Zahra Nasiri, Mina Fayazi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4906500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential reduction of CO2 emissions which is the cause of greenhouse gases during COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61511/andmej.v2i1.2024.962</link>
      <description>Arika Khusniyati, Yunita Ismail, ASEAN Natural Disaster Mitigation and Education Journal. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401191020

                Background: The implementation of education in tertiary institutions contributes significantly to greenhouse gas emissions, particularly carbon dioxide (CO2), which causes the greenhouse effect and global warming. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) identifies transportation, energy supply, and industry as the primary sectors driving CO2 emissions over the past 30 years. However, the COVID-19 pandemic unexpectedly reduced CO2 emissions globally by up to 70% due to restricted activities. In 2020, the pandemic led countries, including Indonesia, to enforce Large-Scale Social Restrictions (PSBB) to curb virus spread, which significantly limited community mobility and vehicle use. Climate change, driven by greenhouse gas emissions, is a critical development challenge for Indonesia. Method: The study uses various calculation methods from journals and websites, incorporating expert opinions and the IPCC's method, to analyze emission reductions. Findings: The findings indicate that the COVID-19 pandemic and associated lockdowns reduced CO2 emissions due to decreased fuel consumption and mobility. Conclusion: This period highlights opportunities for strategies like low-carbon development to continue reducing emissions from vehicles. Novelty/Originality of this Study: This study provides a novel contribution by quantitatively assessing CO2 emission reductions during the COVID-19 lockdown, emphasizing the unique context of an unprecedented global event. It conducts a comprehensive literature review to integrate various CO2 calculation methods, particularly highlighting the sophisticated IPCC method, and offers a comparative analysis of emission reduction techniques.</description>
      <author>Arika Khusniyati, Yunita Ismail</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61511/andmej.v2i1.2024.962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CO2 reduction with formamide-Ni@TiO2 catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.07.025</link>
      <description>Wen Zhong, Wenjing Liu, Jingjing Du, Journal of Environmental Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401215972

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen Zhong, Wenjing Liu, Jingjing Du</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.07.025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Defects Induced Polarization Manipulation in Cu2SnS3 for Boosting Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a</link>
      <description>Haihua Wang, Wen Ning, Yupeng Li, Xiuling Jiao, Yuguo Xia, Dairong Chen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401032296

                Controlling the electrocatalyst's surface polarization is crucial for the interfacial CO2 electrolysis that takes place. Here, we propose an efficient way to increase the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to formate...</description>
      <author>Haihua Wang, Wen Ning, Yupeng Li, Xiuling Jiao, Yuguo Xia, Dairong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Strategies in Rational Design of Cu-Based Catalysts for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction: From Doping of Elements to Defects creation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00321g</link>
      <description>Sheraz Yousaf, Iqbal Ahmad, Muhammad Farooq Warsi, Asad Ali, Materials Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401033694

                The rational design of copper (Cu)-based catalysts for electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction has garnered substantial attention due to its potential to mitigate climate change by converting CO2 into valuable...</description>
      <author>Sheraz Yousaf, Iqbal Ahmad, Muhammad Farooq Warsi, Asad Ali</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00321g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Production Rates of Hydrogen Generation and Carbon Dioxide Reduction Using Gallium Nitride with Nickel Oxide Nanofilm Capping Layer as Photoelectrodes for Photoelectrochemical Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03729</link>
      <description>Chin Yin Sheu, Shang-Ju Tu, Shao&#8208;Chi Chang, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401027697

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chin Yin Sheu, Shang-Ju Tu, Shao&#8208;Chi Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte Composition&#8208;Dependent Product Selectivity in CO2 Reduction with a Porphyrinic Metal&#8208;Organic Framework Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411766</link>
      <description>Shiliang Pu, Tao Huang, Duan&#8208;Hui Si, Meng-Jiao Sun, Wenwen Wang, Teng Zhang, Rong Cao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401022814

                A copper porphyrin-derived metal-organic framework electrocatalyst, FICN-8, was synthesized and its catalytic activity for CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) was investigated. FICN-8 selectively catalyzed electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO in anhydrous acetonitrile electrolyte. However, formic acid became the dominant CO2RR product with the addition of a proton source to the system. Mechanistic studies revealed the change of major reduction pathway upon proton source addition, while catalyst-bound hydride (*H) species was proposed as the key intermediate for formic acid production. This work highlights the importance of electrolyte composition on CO2RR product selectivity.</description>
      <author>Shiliang Pu, Tao Huang, Duan&#8208;Hui Si, Meng-Jiao Sun, Wenwen Wang, Teng Zhang, Rong Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte Composition&#8208;Dependent Product Selectivity in CO2 Reduction with a Porphyrinic Metal&#8208;Organic Framework Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411766</link>
      <description>Shiliang Pu, Tao Huang, Duan&#8208;Hui Si, Meng-Jiao Sun, Wenwen Wang, Teng Zhang, Rong Cao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401022535

                A copper porphyrin&#8208;derived metal&#8208;organic framework electrocatalyst, FICN&#8208;8, was synthesized and its catalytic activity for CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) was investigated. FICN&#8208;8 selectively catalyzed electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO in anhydrous acetonitrile electrolyte. However, formic acid became the dominant CO2RR product with the addition of a proton source to the system. Mechanistic studies revealed the change of major reduction pathway upon proton source addition, while catalyst&#8208;bound hydride (*H) species was proposed as the key intermediate for formic acid production. This work highlights the importance of electrolyte composition on CO2RR product selectivity.</description>
      <author>Shiliang Pu, Tao Huang, Duan&#8208;Hui Si, Meng-Jiao Sun, Wenwen Wang, Teng Zhang, Rong Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-driven constructing interface and tensile strain of derived-Cu catalyst for enhancing CO2 electrocatalytic reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01353k</link>
      <description>Fangfang Chang, Zihan Lin, Yongpeng Liu, Qing Zhang, Xiaolei Wang, Zhengyu Bai, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401056005

                The ability to adjust the composition and surface structure of Cu-based nanomaterials is important for designing catalysts to effectively convert CO2 into multi-carbon products via the electrocatalytic reduction. Herein we...</description>
      <author>Fangfang Chang, Zihan Lin, Yongpeng Liu, Qing Zhang, Xiaolei Wang, Zhengyu Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01353k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Selectivity of CO2 Reduction Reaction on Elementary Metal Particles with DFT Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104866</link>
      <description>Qiang Wang, Jia Li, Yi Liu, Pi-Guey Su, Zhaohui Zhou, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401009030

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiang Wang, Jia Li, Yi Liu, Pi-Guey Su, Zhaohui Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104866</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Surface Defects Induced Polarization Manipulation in Cu2SnS3 for Boosting Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401044114

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contribution of Coal Electricity to Global CO2 Emissions: The Existing Situation and Current Trends of Their Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s0040601524700125</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1053;. &#1058;&#1091;&#1075;&#1086;&#1074;, Thermal Engineering. 71(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401046875

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1053;. &#1058;&#1091;&#1075;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s0040601524700125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Surface Defects Induced Polarization Manipulation in Cu2SnS3 for Boosting Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401044521

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pre-reduction of Nchwaning manganese ore in CO/CO2, H2/H2O, and H2 atmospheres</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mineng.2024.108854</link>
      <description>Mathilde Ernst, Merete Tangstad, S.P. du Preez, Minerals Engineering. 216(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401026636

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mathilde Ernst, Merete Tangstad, S.P. du Preez</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mineng.2024.108854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Surface Defects Induced Polarization Manipulation in Cu2SnS3 for Boosting Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401044226

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Surface Defects Induced Polarization Manipulation in Cu2SnS3 for Boosting Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401044177

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Surface Defects Induced Polarization Manipulation in Cu2SnS3 for Boosting Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401044607

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Surface Defects Induced Polarization Manipulation in Cu2SnS3 for Boosting Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401044124

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04092a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXene quantum dots decorated g-C3N4/BiOI heterojunction photocatalyst for efficient NO deep oxidation and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128961</link>
      <description>Junli Nie, Xingmao Zhang, Ming&#8208;Sheng Wang, Yucheng Ou, Shiping Li, Peng Zhong, Weiwei Wang, Gangqiang Zhu, Xiaohua Ma, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401022868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junli Nie, Xingmao Zhang, Ming&#8208;Sheng Wang, Yucheng Ou, Shiping Li, Peng Zhong, Weiwei Wang, Gangqiang Zhu, Xiaohua Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge transfer regulates electrocatalytic CO2 reduction on one-dimensional carbon nanotube/boron nitride nanotube heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128981</link>
      <description>Qigang Chen, Huohai Yang, Peng Wang, Qiang Ke, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401022912

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qigang Chen, Huohai Yang, Peng Wang, Qiang Ke, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selection of suitable organic electrolyte for CO2 electro-reduction to CO in three-compartment electrolysis cell with NaOH and Cl2 yielded as byproducts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118535</link>
      <description>Xin Shi, Fengxia Shen, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401046554

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Shi, Fengxia Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Reaction Mechanism and Electronic, Thermodynamic, and Kinetic Parameters of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction to CO on a Copper Electrocatalyst Using First-Principle Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/proceedings2024105020</link>
      <description>Reza Gholizadeh, Bla&#382; Likozar, Matej Hu&#353;, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401179527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Reza Gholizadeh, Bla&#382; Likozar, Matej Hu&#353;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/proceedings2024105020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Emission Reduction by Geothermal-Driven CCHP Tailored with Turbine Bleeding and Regeneration CHP; Economic/Multi-aspect Comparative Analysis with GA-based Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102646</link>
      <description>Ali Basem, Hameed H. Taher, Hasan Sh. Majdi, Ahmed Salah Al-Shati, Shirin Shomurotova, Haydar A.S. Aljaafari, Laith S. Sabri, Baseem Khan, Results in Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401115617

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ali Basem, Hameed H. Taher, Hasan Sh. Majdi, Ahmed Salah Al-Shati, Shirin Shomurotova, Haydar A.S. Aljaafari, Laith S. Sabri, Baseem Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sr(Ti0&#183;3Fe0.7)O3&#8722;&#948;-based perovskite with in-situ exsolved Fe&#8211;Ru nanoparticles: A highly stable fuel electrode material for solid oxide electrochemical cells with efficient electrocatalytic CO2 reduction ability and preferential selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235087</link>
      <description>Fang-Ze Han, Yongshan Wan, Cheng&#8208;Xin Li, Shan-Lin Zhang, Journal of Power Sources. 615(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401027580

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fang-Ze Han, Yongshan Wan, Cheng&#8208;Xin Li, Shan-Lin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali-promoted indium oxide as highly active and selective catalyst for the photo-thermal CO2 hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04387a</link>
      <description>Xiupeng Wang, Alejandra Rend&#243;n&#8208;Pati&#241;o, Jean Marcel R. Gallo, Diego Mateo, Jorge Gasc&#243;n, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401025425

                Photo-thermal carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction has recently gained significant attention as a strategy to harness solar energy and address environmental challenges. Among other photo-thermal catalysts, indium oxide (In2O3) has emerged...</description>
      <author>Xiupeng Wang, Alejandra Rend&#243;n&#8208;Pati&#241;o, Jean Marcel R. Gallo, Diego Mateo, Jorge Gasc&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04387a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of Greenhouse Gas Emissions in Electrolysis for Certifying Clean Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153698</link>
      <description>Yunji Kim, In Ki Min, Ji Eun Lee, Heena Yang, Energies. 17(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401015106

                The drive for carbon neutrality has led to legislative measures targeting reduced greenhouse gas emissions across the transportation, construction, and industry sectors. Renewable energy sources, especially solar and wind power, play a pivotal role in this transition. However, their intermittent nature necessitates effective storage solutions. Green hydrogen and ammonia have gained attention for their potential to store renewable energy while producing minimal emissions. Despite their theoretical promise of zero greenhouse gas emissions during production, real-world emissions vary based on system configurations and lifecycle assessments, highlighting the need for detailed evaluations of their environmental impact. Therefore, in this study, calculations were performed for the actual amount of produced greenhouse gas emissions that are associated with the production of green hydrogen using electrolysis, from raw material extraction and processing to hydrogen production, with these assessed from well-to-gate emission estimates. Emissions were also evaluated based on various types of renewable energy sources in South Korea, as well as hydrogen production volumes, capacities, and types. Using these data, the following factors were examined in this study: carbon dioxide emissions from the manufacturing stage of electrolysis equipment production, the correlation between materials and carbon dioxide emissions, and process emissions. Current grades of clean hydrogen were verified, and the greenhouse gas reduction effects of green hydrogen were confirmed. These findings are significant against the backdrop of a country such as South Korea, where the proportion of renewable energy in total electricity production is very low at 5.51%. Based on the domestic greenhouse gas emission efficiency standard of 55 kWh/kgH2, it was found that producing 1 kg of hydrogen emits 0.076 kg of carbon dioxide for hydropower, 0.283 kg for wind power, and 0.924 kg for solar power. The carbon dioxide emissions for AWE and PEM stacks were 8434 kg CO2 and 3695 kg CO2, respectively, demonstrating that an alkaline water electrolysis (AWE) system emits about 2.3 times more greenhouse gasses than a proton exchange membrane (PEM) system. This indicates that the total carbon dioxide emissions of green hydrogen are significantly influenced by the type of renewable energy and the type of electrolysis used.</description>
      <author>Yunji Kim, In Ki Min, Ji Eun Lee, Heena Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulation of China&#8217;s Carbon Peak Path Based on Random Forest and Sparrow Search Algorithm&#8212;Long Short-Term Memory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15080907</link>
      <description>Zhoumu Yang, Xiaoying Wu, Yinan Song, Pan Jiao, Atmosphere. 15(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401173162

                How to decouple economic growth from carbon dioxide emissions and achieve low-carbon transformation of the Chinese economy has become an urgent problem that needs to be solved. Firstly, the Tapio index is used to identify China&#8217;s carbon peak status, and then the Technology Choice Index (TCI) and economic complexity are introduced into the comprehensive factor analysis framework for carbon dioxide emissions. Key influencing factors are identified using random forest and ridge regression. On this basis, a novel sparrow search algorithm&#8211;long short-term memory (SSA-LSTM) model which has more prediction accuracy compared with past studies is constructed to predict the dynamic evolution trend of carbon dioxide emissions, and in combination with scenario analysis, the path towards the carbon peak is simulated. The following conclusions are obtained: The benchmark scenario peaks in 2031, with a peak of 12.346 billion tons, and the low-carbon scenario peaks in 2030, with a peak of 11.962 billion tons. The extensive scenario peaks in 2037, with a peak of 13.291 billion tons. Under six scenarios, it can be concluded that energy intensity is the key factor in reducing the peak. These research results provide theoretical support for decision-makers to formulate emission reduction policies and adjust the carbon peak path.</description>
      <author>Zhoumu Yang, Xiaoying Wu, Yinan Song, Pan Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15080907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress in home energy management systems consideration of comfort</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/70/20240995</link>
      <description>R. H. Yuan, Applied and Computational Engineering. 70(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401032867

                According to statistics, the carbon dioxide emissions from Chinas power industry account for about 40% of the total energy consumption and carbon dioxide emissions, while residential electricity consumption accounts for 36.6% of the total social electricity consumption. However, ordinary households have low electricity efficiency and serious waste. In the context of the national strategy of carbon peak and carbon neutrality, the Home Energy Management System (HEMS) has been introduced to improve household electricity efficiency, reduce electricity consumption, and achieve energy conservation and emission reduction while ensuring the comfort of residents. This article introduces the current research status of home energy management systems that take into account user comfort, and shows some optimization models for home energy management systems that take into account user comfort. It specifically elaborates on the optimization models for household appliances and comfort, briefly outlines the relatively trendy load prediction and scheduling optimization models, and proposes some suggestions and prospects for popularizing knowledge related to home energy management systems for family members using smart homes and temperature comfort modeling based on the current development status.</description>
      <author>R. H. Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/70/20240995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPAIN&#8217;S EUROPEAN POLICY DURING ITS PRESIDENCY OF THE COUNCIL OF THE EU</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33693/2223-0092-2023-13-5-72-76</link>
      <description>A.S. SHAHBAZOV, Sociopolitical sciences. 13(5)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4401074416

                The article examines the main aspects of the Spain&#8217;s European policy as the President of the EU Council. The further course of the Kingdom&#8217;s European policy depends on the effectiveness of the Spanish government&#8217;s work in the Council in the second half of 2023. In addition to the main topic of the European agenda - geopolitical challenges - such important issues as energy independence and reduction of carbon dioxide emissions, migration, as well as taxation rules were touched upon. In addition, the integration process is discussed in the context of the new expansion policy. The Spanish government will have to balance a neutral position in the Council and the national interests of the country.</description>
      <author>A.S. SHAHBAZOV</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33693/2223-0092-2023-13-5-72-76</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Fast Frequency Response Ancillary Services in Renewable-Heavy Grids: A Global Review of Energy Storage-Based Solutions and Market Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153737</link>
      <description>Gergo Varhegyi, Mutasim Nour, Energies. 17(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401074415

                This paper addresses the growing challenges and developments in frequency control within power systems influenced by the increasing penetration of renewable energy sources. It evaluates the advancements and limitations of renewable-based control technologies and explores the critical role of diverse energy storage technologies in providing fast frequency response ancillary services. Through a comprehensive analysis of the global literature, this paper categorises energy storage solutions according to their efficacy in meeting fast frequency response demands and potential for revenue generation. It reveals significant gaps in the current research, which predominantly focuses on battery energy storage systems and microgrid applications, with insufficient attention to grid-scale storage solutions and innovative energy storage technologies. This analysis identifies a lack of detailed technical simulations and hybrid storage models for frequency control, as well as a minimal exploration of the environmental benefits, particularly in terms of carbon dioxide emission reductions, associated with deploying new energy storage technologies in ancillary service markets. The paper concludes by emphasising the urgent need for further research incorporating detailed techno-economic evaluations and the carbon dioxide reduction potential of modular, scalable energy storage technologies, which should be facilitated by advanced network simulation models and comprehensive market analysis to drive future advancements in the field.</description>
      <author>Gergo Varhegyi, Mutasim Nour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing carbon footprint by using thermal insulation materials in Palestinian buildings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35552/anujr.a.39.1.2267</link>
      <description>Rafif Hanaishy, Abdelhaleem Khader, An-Najah University Journal for Research - A (Natural Sciences). 39(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4401162346

                Buildings account for 39% of emission worldwide. The study aims to clarify the effects of thermal insulation materials used in West Bank Palestinian buildings, to demonstrate their capacity to reduce emissions and saving cost. Using a variety of records from the Engineers Syndicate and the Palestinian Central Bureau of Statistics, a thorough study of buildings in the West Bank area was carried out to determine the number and area of buildings. Additionally, data from sources of energy was collected for the study years 2018&#8211;2021. Following the use of thermal insulation materials to the buildings, computations were then equipped with thermal insulation materials, and calculations to estimate the energy savings and reductions in carbon dioxide emissions. The results show, using insulating materials reduce energy consumption by 27.23% and CO2 emissions significantly. It is anticipated that the cost recovery period for new construction is 0.39 to 1.09 years, and for repaired buildings it is between 4.34 and 7.2 years. Depending on the location and typical temperature of the area. The study recommends working for the widespread use of insulating materials in all new construction and for retrofitting existing structures. These initiatives will support international efforts to reduce emissions and achieve sustainable development goals in addition to improving energy efficiency.</description>
      <author>Rafif Hanaishy, Abdelhaleem Khader</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35552/anujr.a.39.1.2267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewable Energy Sources in The Context of Emissions Reduction: Geographical Aspects And Challenges for Sustainable Development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26437/ajar.v10i1.709</link>
      <description>M. Kovalskyi, W. Duczmal, Maryna Oleksiuk, Andrii Skomorovskyi, Zinoviy Berezivskyy, African Journal Of Applied Research. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401160271

                Purpose: The study aims to provide a nuanced understanding of renewable energy sources' geographical aspects and challenges in reducing emissions and promoting sustainable development. Design/Methodology/Approach: This study adopts a qualitative approach to investigate renewable energy sources in the context of emissions reduction, focusing on geographical aspects and challenges for sustainable development. The methodology is designed to gain in-depth insights and understand the complexities of deploying and utilising renewable energy across different geographical regions. Case studies provide detailed, context-specific insights into the practical implementation and challenges of renewable energy projects. The selection of case studies follows a purposive sampling method to ensure diversity in geographical settings, types of renewable energy, and stages of development. Reviewing project reports, policy documents, and environmental assessments related to each case study. The data was analysed by cross-verifying information from different data sources to enhance the reliability and validity of the findings. Research Limitation/Implications: It justifies the immediate construction of a &#8220;green economy&#8221; in Ukraine, drawing on theory and the experience of advanced countries. Findings: The diversity of renewable energy sources, geographical influences, technological advancements, policy and regulatory frameworks, and socio-economic impacts influenced their efforts to reduce emissions. Social Implication: The modern global economy faces significant challenges such as energy security, sustainable development of society, and climate change. Practical Implication: The paper identifies directions and outlines paths and mechanisms for accelerated development. Indeed, such a powerful carbon dioxide and methane emissions surge has never been observed. Originality/ Value: Recently, the most pressing issue is the &#8220;carbon footprint&#8221;, which refers to the total amount of carbon dioxide and methane emissions released into the environment due to human industrial activity. Measures to combat it will soon focus on modernising technologies to facilitate the transition to the sixth technological paradigm and minimise greenhouse gas emissions. Critical technical solutions may involve harnessing the potential of hydrogen energy and immobilising or preventing greenhouse gas formation technologies. As an alternative direction, the authors consider research to solve some issues related to hydrogen production using metals.</description>
      <author>M. Kovalskyi, W. Duczmal, Maryna Oleksiuk, Andrii Skomorovskyi, Zinoviy Berezivskyy</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26437/ajar.v10i1.709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to maintain environmental integrity when using state support and the VCM to co-finance BECCS projects - a Swedish case study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenvs.2024.1387138</link>
      <description>Myl&#232;ne Dufour, Kenneth M&#246;llersten, Lars Zetterberg, Frontiers in Environmental Science. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401038408

                Limiting global warming to close to 1.5&#176;C by 2100 requires deep and rapid greenhouse gas emission reductions and carbon dioxide removals (CDR) on a massive scale, presenting a remarkable scaling challenge. This paper focuses on the financing of bioenergy with carbon capture and storage (BECCS) in Sweden. BECCS is one of the most prominent CDR methods in 1.5&#176;C-compatible global emission scenarios and has been assigned a specific role in Swedish policy for net-zero. A Swedish state support system for BECCS based on results-based payments is planned. Furthermore, demand for CDR-based carbon credits is on the rise on the voluntary carbon markets (VCM) for use towards voluntary mitigation targets. Risks involved with the current Swedish policies are analysed, specifically for the co-financing of BECCS by the planned state support and revenues from the VCM. We find that with the current policies, state support systems will subsidise carbon credit prices on the VCM. We argue that such subsidisation can lower decarbonisation efforts by lowering the internal carbon price set by actors, thus undermining environmental integrity. It is concluded that proportional attribution should be applied, i.e., attributing mitigation outcomes to the state support and VCM revenue in proportion to their financial contribution to the CDR achieved. The attribution analysis should be accompanied by adjustments in national greenhouse gas accounting so that mitigation outcomes that are issued as carbon credits and used for offsetting are not double claimed (i.e., not used by both a nation and a non-state actor on the VCM towards their respective mitigation targets). If proportional attribution and adjustments in national GHG accounting are not implemented, the credibility and environmental integrity of offsetting claims made by carbon credit users are eroded. We recommend that action is taken to operationalise and implement proportional attribution to allow for co-financing of BECCS projects while maintaining environmental integrity. Wider implications for our recommendations beyond the case of Swedish BECCS are also analysed.</description>
      <author>Myl&#232;ne Dufour, Kenneth M&#246;llersten, Lars Zetterberg</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenvs.2024.1387138</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burning question: Rethinking organohalide degradation strategy for bioremediation applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1751-7915.14539</link>
      <description>Qihong Lu, Qi Liang, Zhiwei Liang, Microbial Biotechnology. 17(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401151712

                Abstract Organohalides are widespread pollutants that pose significant environmental hazards due to their high degree of halogenation and elevated redox potentials, making them resistant to natural attenuation. Traditional bioremediation approaches, primarily relying on bioaugmentation and biostimulation, often fall short of achieving complete detoxification. Furthermore, the emergence of complex halogenated pollutants, such as per&#8208; and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFASs), further complicates remediation efforts. Therefore, there is a pressing need to reconsider novel approaches for more efficient remediation of these recalcitrant pollutants. This review proposes novel redox&#8208;potential&#8208;mediated hybrid bioprocesses, tailored to the physicochemical properties of pollutants and their environmental contexts, to achieve complete detoxification of organohalides. The possible scenarios for the proposed bioremediation approaches are further discussed. In anaerobic environments, such as sediment and groundwater, microbial reductive dehalogenation coupled with fermentation and methanogenesis can convert organohalides into carbon dioxide and methane. In environments with anaerobic&#8208;aerobic alternation, such as paddy soil and wetlands, a synergistic process involving reduction and oxidation can facilitate the complete mineralization of highly halogenated organic compounds. Future research should focus on in&#8208;depth exploration of microbial consortia, the application of ecological principles&#8208;guided strategies, and the development of bioinspired&#8208;designed techniques. This paper contributes to the academic discourse by proposing innovative remediation strategies tailored to the complexities of organohalide pollution.</description>
      <author>Qihong Lu, Qi Liang, Zhiwei Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1751-7915.14539</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-Formylation of Carbon Dioxide and Amines with EDTA as a Recyclable Catalyst under Ambient Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080492</link>
      <description>Qiqi Zhou, Yu Chen, Xuexin Yuan, Hai&#8208;Jian Yang, Yu&#8208;Shi He, Juncheng Hu, Cun&#8208;Yue Guo, Catalysts. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401173145

                The reduction of CO2 is an important method to produce chemicals such as methanol, formic acid, formaldehyde, etc. In general, the reduction of CO2 is carried out at high temperatures and pressures with precious metals as catalysts, which is not favorable for industrial procedures. Thus, it will be very useful if researchers can find cost-effective catalysts for industrial application in CO2 reduction. In this work, commercially available ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA) was tested as a cheap, non-toxic, and recyclable catalyst to initiate the N-carbonylation reaction of CO2 with amines. After screening various reaction parameters, including temperature, pressure, time, solvent, and reducing agent, the optimal reaction conditions were obtained: 80 &#176;C, 2 MPa, 6 h, 50 mmol% catalyst dosage, 1 mL DMSO, and 1:1 molar ratio of amine to reducing agent. Notably, further studies confirmed that EDTA could also be effective for N-formylation even under ambient conditions (0.1 MPa and room temperature). The suitability of the catalyst for 26 kinds of substrates (including aliphatic amines, aromatic amines, and alicyclic amines) and its reusability were also investigated, with satisfactory results. Scale-up research has been performed effectively with a high conversion of amine (83%) to obtain the mono-formylated product selectively. Finally, the mechanism of the reaction between amine and CO2 has been proposed via control experiments and compared with results in the literature.</description>
      <author>Qiqi Zhou, Yu Chen, Xuexin Yuan, Hai&#8208;Jian Yang, Yu&#8208;Shi He, Juncheng Hu, Cun&#8208;Yue Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 laser-assisted sclerectomy surgery for secondary open-angle glaucoma after vitrectomy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2024.1429791</link>
      <description>Li Zheng, Ao Wang, Mingqiong Zhu, Na Zhou, Jia Li, Q Li, Guoping Kuang, Frontiers in Medicine. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401153500

                Purpose To explore the efficiency and safety of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) laser-assisted sclerectomy surgery (CLASS) in Chinese patients with glaucoma secondary to vitrectomy. Methods This retrospective study consisted of 16 eyes from 16 patients with glaucoma secondary to vitrectomy who underwent CLASS and were followed up for 12 months. Main outcome measures included preoperative and postoperative intraocular pressure, best corrected visual acuity (BCVA), number of anti-glaucoma medications, and postoperative surgical success rate and complications. Results The postoperative IOP and number of anti-glaucoma medications used at all follow-up time point were significantly lower than those preoperatively. The difference in BCVA was not significant before and after surgery. The main complicatios were peripheral anterior synechiae (PAS) and scleral reservoir reduction, which were controlled after neodymium-doped yttrium aluminum garnet (Nd:YAG) laser, 2 (12.50%) patients underwent re-operation. The complete and total success rates at 12 months were 68.75% and 87.50%, respectively. Conclusion CLASS is a safe and effective procedure for Chinese patients with glaucoma secondary to vitrectomy. PAS and scleral reservoir reduction is a major contributor to postoperative IOP elevation, and trabecular minimally invasive perforation with the Nd:YAG laser is effective in lowering IOP and increasing scleral cistern volume.</description>
      <author>Li Zheng, Ao Wang, Mingqiong Zhu, Na Zhou, Jia Li, Q Li, Guoping Kuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2024.1429791</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization research on multi-trip distribution of reverse logistics terminal for automobile scrap parts under the background of sustainable development strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-68112-4</link>
      <description>Hongyu Wang, Huicheng Hao, Mengdi Wang, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401049355

                To effectively solve the reverse logistics distribution problem caused by the increasing number of scrapped parts in the automotive market, this study constructs a multi-trip green vehicle routing problem model with time windows by comprehensively considering the coordination between carbon dioxide emissions and cost efficiency. A hybrid adaptive genetic algorithm is proposed to solve this problem, featuring innovative improvements in the nearest neighbor rule based on minimum cost, adaptive strategies, bin packing algorithm based on the transfer-of-state equation, and large-scale neighborhood search. Additionally, to efficiently obtain location data for supplier factory sites in the distribution network, a coordinate extraction method based on image recognition technology is proposed. Finally, the scientific validity of this study is verified based on the actual case data, and the robust optimization ability of the algorithm is verified by numerical calculations of different examples. This research not only enriches the study of green vehicle routing problems but also provides valuable insights for the industry to achieve cost reduction, efficiency enhancement, and sustainable development in reverse logistics.</description>
      <author>Hongyu Wang, Huicheng Hao, Mengdi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-68112-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of greenhouse gases, regions, and sectors on future temperature anomaly with the FaIR model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59720/24-067</link>
      <description>Tej Kosaraju, Paul Griffiths, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401088442

                Greenhouse gas emissions from industrial activities have resulted in global warming, threatening the human way of life. Climate modeling is crucial to the effort to combat climate change by determining the potential impacts of anthropogenic emissions and thus identifying where emission reduction efforts should focus. In this study, we hypothesized that various economic sectors, geographic regions, and greenhouse gas species could impact the future global mean surface temperature (GMST) anomaly in ways that deviate from the historical and present norm. We used the Finite Amplitude Impulse Response (FaIR) model, a reduced complexity climate model, as well as four of the Shared Socioeconomic Pathways (SSPs), SSP126, SSP245, SSP370 and SSP585, to test our hypothesis. We determined that the future impact of specific economic sectors, geographic regions, and greenhouse gas species deviates from their historical impact. We found that Asia and Africa will contribute to a greater share of the GMST anomaly in the future. We also determined that the warming from most of the greenhouse gas species, excluding carbon dioxide, is highest under the SSP370 scenario (the climate scenario that emphasizes regional rivalries related to climate policy). We concluded that the industrial sector would become more important under the SSPs that represent a lower degree of warming. This research augments the SSPs by considering specific variables not represented in the general SSP scenarios, determining the precise climate impacts of said variables. Additionally, this research helps to determine what emission reduction strategies can most efficiently reduce the GMST anomaly.</description>
      <author>Tej Kosaraju, Paul Griffiths</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59720/24-067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal energy concept for decarbonisation of sea-buckthorn processing plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52152/3926</link>
      <description>Mar&#237;a Isabel Rold&#225;n Serrano, Rushit Kansara, Renewable Energy and Power Quality Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401095571

                The decarbonisation of the industrial sector is required to achieve the objectives defined within the European Climate and Energy framework, since industry accounts for 37% of the total global energy consumption and for a quarter of global energy system CO2 emissions [1]. In this context, this work aims the decarbonisation of a sea-buckthorn processing plant using structural and operational optimisation for the analysis of proposed energy supply concepts based on the integration of renewable energy sources, energy conversion components and storage systems. Different configurations are evaluated to select the concept that leads to a minimisation of the operating costs and a CO2 emissions reduction of the industrial site with installation costs within the investment range defined and the minimum payback period. Thus, the selected decarbonisation concept is able to achieve a reduction of 25% in operation costs (OPEX) and 31% in CO2 with an investment (CAPEX) of 288.7 T&#8364; and a payback time of 5.8 years. Additionally, the developed methodology can be used for the analysis of decarbonisation concepts for other industrial processes by the integration of an adapted techno- economic definition of the components for each energy concept proposed.</description>
      <author>Mar&#237;a Isabel Rold&#225;n Serrano, Rushit Kansara</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52152/3926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bio-Char Used for Carbon Sequestration and to Balance the CO2 Concentration in Atmosphere: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51583/ijltemas.2024.130706</link>
      <description>Rakhman Sarwono, International Journal of Latest Technology in Engineering Management &amp; Applied Science. 13(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401093478

                Abstract: The Carbon concentration in earth is closed system, therefore, the contain of carbon in each elements are different. The concentration of CO2 in atmosphere is lower compared with N2 and O2 gas but CO2 concentration is great effect to the atmosphere temperature, it may cause the global warming and climate change. The CO2 concentration in atmosphere should be maintained to slower increase in order to reduce the effect of CO2 in atmosphere. Balancing of carbon positive and negative is concerned to maintain the CO2 concentration in atmosphere. Bio-chars are materials carbon that can be used as soil amendment to increase crop production. Recently, the carbon positive more than the carbon negative, resulted the CO2 concentration in atmosphere was increased gradually. Biochar has been possibility to produce in a large quantity to utilize of waste biomass. We needs a large quantity of biochar to be produced and mixed with soil and store in the ground as carbon sequestration, those biochar increase the soil fertility. Scenarios stabilization wedge represents an activity that starts at zero reduction of emissions in 2005 and increase linearly until it accounts for 1 GtC/ year or 1 wedges reduced carbon emissions in the year 2055.</description>
      <author>Rakhman Sarwono</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51583/ijltemas.2024.130706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiaspect analysis and optimization of a power and cooling cogeneration plant integrated with a multilevel waste heat recovery system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ijlct/ctae134</link>
      <description>Tao Hai, Ihab Omar, Mohamed R El-Sharkawy, Murizah Kassim, Husam Rajab, Esraa Ahmed Said, Abbas Hameed Abdul Hussein, Wesam Abed AL Hassan Alhaidry, Ameer Hassan Idan, Mehrsam Alizadeh, International Journal of Low-Carbon Technologies. 19(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401156852

                Abstract This study focuses on the development and improvement of a new combined power and cooling system called the power-cooling cogeneration system (PCCS). The PCCS incorporates a tri-tier waste heat recovery system that includes an organic Rankine cycle (ORC) system and an ejector-driven refrigeration mechanism. The cogeneration system design incorporates a thorough assessment of thermodynamic efficiency, cost-efficiency, and environmental consequences. A dual-objective optimization technique is developed to decrease expenses while simultaneously improving exergy efficiency. In addition, the complex behavior of PCCS is compared to a standard system that uses a one-stage recovery-ORC system and a compressor-based refrigeration approach. Also, the effectiveness of the PCCS was evaluated through the utilization of several environmentally friendly refrigerants. Environmental evaluations employ two metrics: total equivalent-warming impact (TE-WI) and life cycle-climate performance (LC-CP), emphasizing substantial reductions in environmental harm through improved waste heat recovery. The results demonstrate that the R1234-yf refrigerant achieves the best possible performance in both configurations, resulting in a significant increase of roughly 10.1% in exergetic efficiency compared to the standard system. Simultaneously, the PCCS experiences a decrease in exergy loss and annual costs of around 7.25% and 21.16%, respectively, as compared to the baseline. Incorporating an ejector into the refrigeration cycle has the potential to reduce carbon dioxide emissions by up to 11.41 &#215; 106 kg.</description>
      <author>Tao Hai, Ihab Omar, Mohamed R El-Sharkawy, Murizah Kassim, Husam Rajab, Esraa Ahmed Said, Abbas Hameed Abdul Hussein, Wesam Abed AL Hassan Alhaidry, Ameer Hassan Idan, Mehrsam Alizadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ijlct/ctae134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Energy Efficiency Gap for Low-Income Households in Charlottesville</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202455401005</link>
      <description>Zhigang Xue, E3S Web of Conferences. 554(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401122767

                Residential energy usage in Charlottesville, Virginia, accounts for nearly 30% of the city&#8217;s greenhouse gas emissions. Without significant changes, Charlottesville is unlikely to meet its goal of reducing emissions by 45% by 2030. Improving residential energy efficiency is key to lowering emissions and reducing energy costs for residents. However, the high upfront cost of these upgrades is unaffordable for over a third of Charlottesville households. As electricity prices rise due to Virginia&#8217;s upcoming carbon dioxide cap-and-trade program, low-income households that can&#8217;t afford efficiency upgrades will face higher energy bills and greater financial strain. This study explores the feasibility of a residential efficiency financing program designed to improve the affordability and accessibility of energy upgrades for low-income households in Charlottesville. Through a detailed benefit-cost analysis, various policy alternatives, including On-Bill Financing, Revolving Loan Fund, and Loan Loss Reserve, were evaluated for their effectiveness, equity, and implementation feasibility. The recommended option, On-Bill Financing, would allow Charlottesville Gas to cover the upfront costs of energy efficiency upgrades. Customers would repay the investment over time through their gas bills, thereby enjoying immediate reductions in energy consumption and costs. This policy would fairly enhance residential energy efficiency and provide critical financial assistance to households that otherwise couldn&#8217;t afford these upgrades.</description>
      <author>Zhigang Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202455401005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel approach to integrate CCHP systems with desalination for sustainable energy and water solutions in educational buildings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.2024.257</link>
      <description>Faizah Mohammed Bashir, Emmanuel Falude, Ibtihaj Saad Rashed Alsadun, Hakim Hamdoun, Mohamed Ahmed Said Mohamed, Nahla M. Shannan, Ahmad Usman Naibi, Water Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401019919

                ABSTRACT This study presents a novel approach to integrating combined cooling, heating, and power (CCHP) systems with water desalination for enhanced energy and water management in educational buildings. Two distinct layouts for CCHP and desalination systems are introduced: one prioritizing efficient power generation to meet electricity demands while providing waste heat for desalination, and the other focusing on balancing cooling and heating loads alongside water desalination. Both layouts are tailored to meet the building's energy and water demands while considering operational efficiency. Optimization of these layouts against traditional systems using the bat search algorithm emphasizes economic viability and the gas engine's operational flexibility, which are crucial for partial load operation. In addition, an environmental assessment compares the proposed CCHP-desalination systems with conventional setups, assessing CO2 emission reductions and overall sustainability. The evaluation encompasses key environmental metrics, such as resource consumption and the integration of renewable energy sources. Results highlight significant CO2 emission reductions across various gas engine capacities, with notable enhancements in economic and environmental performance achieved by selecting a 3,250 kW gas engine within the CCHP-desalination system. This choice not only maximizes the annual profit but also reduces CO2 emissions by 57% compared to conventional systems, underscoring the system's sustainability benefits.</description>
      <author>Faizah Mohammed Bashir, Emmanuel Falude, Ibtihaj Saad Rashed Alsadun, Hakim Hamdoun, Mohamed Ahmed Said Mohamed, Nahla M. Shannan, Ahmad Usman Naibi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.2024.257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#1040;SSESSING THE EFFECTIVENESS OF AN INVESTMENT PROJECT TO REDUCE THE CARBON FOOTPRINT IN THE ENERGY SECTOR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34925/eip.2023.161.12.141</link>
      <description>&#1053;.&#1057;. &#1051;&#1070;&#1051;&#1068;&#1063;&#1045;&#1053;&#1050;&#1054;, &#1056;. &#1042;. &#1047;&#1072;&#1081;&#1094;&#1077;&#1074;, Anna Terekhova, &#1057;.&#1056;. &#1058;&#1040;&#1064;&#1054;&#1042;&#1040;, &#1069;&#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084;&#1080;&#1082;&#1072; &#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1084;&#1072;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1086;. None(12(161))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401019753

                &#1042; &#1088;&#1072;&#1084;&#1082;&#1072;&#1093; &#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1090;&#1100;&#1080; &#1074; &#1090;&#1077;&#1086;&#1088;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1084; &#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1084; &#1082;&#1083;&#1102;&#1095;&#1077; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1084;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1099; &#1074;&#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1099; &#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1080; &#1080;&#1085;&#1074;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1094;&#1080;&#1086;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1072;, &#1089;&#1074;&#1103;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1089; &#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077;&#1084; &#1101;&#1084;&#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1080; CO2 &#1074; &#1072;&#1090;&#1084;&#1086;&#1089;&#1092;&#1077;&#1088;&#1091; &#1089;&#1074;&#1103;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1091;&#1102; &#1089; &#1076;&#1077;&#1103;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1100;&#1102; &#1086;&#1073;&#1098;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1082;&#1080;. &#1054;&#1089;&#1086;&#1073;&#1099;&#1081; &#1092;&#1086;&#1082;&#1091;&#1089; &#1089;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085; &#1085;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077; &#1101;&#1084;&#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1080; CO2 &#1080; &#1074;&#1086;&#1079;&#1084;&#1086;&#1078;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1103;&#1093; &#1073;&#1086;&#1088;&#1100;&#1073;&#1099; &#1089; &#1085;&#1080;&#1084; &#1074; &#1088;&#1072;&#1084;&#1082;&#1072;&#1093; &#1079;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1082;&#1080;. &#1042; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1077; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1084;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085; &#1082;&#1072;&#1082; &#1080;&#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1081; &#1086;&#1087;&#1099;&#1090; &#1090;&#1072;&#1082; &#1080; &#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1099; &#1074; &#1089;&#1092;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077; &#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1094;&#1077;&#1087;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1085;&#1091;&#1083;&#1077;&#1074;&#1099;&#1093; &#1074;&#1099;&#1073;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074;. &#1054;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1074;&#1072;&#1077;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1074;&#1082;&#1083;&#1072;&#1076; &#1042;&#1048;&#1069; &#1074; &#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1091;&#1102; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1082;&#1091; &#1080; &#1074;&#1072;&#1078;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1100; &#1076;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1077;&#1081;&#1096;&#1077;&#1081; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1099; &#1074; &#1089;&#1092;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077; &#1079;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1101;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1075;&#1077;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080;. Within the framework of articles on theoretical and practical key issues in assessing an investment project related to the reduction of CO2 emissions into the atmosphere associated with energy facilities. Particular focus is placed on CO2 emissions into the environment and the possibilities of combating them within the framework of green energy. The work includes both historical experience and promising projects in the field of the concept of the UK zero. The contribution of renewable energy sources to the global energy sector and further work in the field of green electricity generation are assessed.</description>
      <author>&#1053;.&#1057;. &#1051;&#1070;&#1051;&#1068;&#1063;&#1045;&#1053;&#1050;&#1054;, &#1056;. &#1042;. &#1047;&#1072;&#1081;&#1094;&#1077;&#1074;, Anna Terekhova, &#1057;.&#1056;. &#1058;&#1040;&#1064;&#1054;&#1042;&#1040;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34925/eip.2023.161.12.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Serine Shunt enables formate conversion to formaldehyde in vivo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.31.605843</link>
      <description>Karin Schann, Sebastian Wenk, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401160064

                Microbial valorization of CO2-derived substrates has emerged as a promising approach to address climate change and resource scarcity. Formate, which can be efficiently produced from CO2, shows great potential as a sustainable feedstock for biotechnological production. However, the scope of formate assimilation pathways is restricted by the limited number of natural formate-assimilating enzymes. To overcome this limitation, several new-to-nature routes for formate assimilation based on its reduction to formaldehyde have been proposed, but they suffer from low catalytic efficiencies and cannot yet support bacterial growth. Here, we propose the Serine Shunt as a novel formate reduction route and demonstrate its activity in vivo. In this pathway, formate is attached to glycine to form serine, which is subsequently cleaved into formaldehyde and glycine, thereby effectively converting formate to formaldehyde. Unlike other formate reduction routes, the Serine Shunt mainly utilizes natural reactions with favorable enzyme kinetics, while requiring the same amount of ATP and NAD(P)H as the most efficient new-to-nature route. We implemented the Serine Shunt in engineered E. coli strains using a step-wise approach by dividing the pathway into metabolic modules. After validating the individual module activities, we demonstrated the in vivo activity of the complete Serine Shunt by measuring intracellular formaldehyde production with a GFP sensor and coupling its activity to cell growth. Our results indicate that the Serine Shunt could be applied as a novel formate reduction route in methylotrophic hosts relevant for biotechnology.</description>
      <author>Karin Schann, Sebastian Wenk</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.31.605843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APPLICABILITY OF THE "TYPOLOGY OF RESIDENTIAL BUILDINGS IN BOSNIA AND HERZEGOVINA", AT A MUNICIPALITY OR CITY LEVEL, CASE STUDY - SINGLE-FAMILY HOUSES IN THE CITY DERVENTA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61892/stp202401061k</link>
      <description>Milovan Kotur, Goran Jevti&#263;, Contemporary Theory and Practice in Construction. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401087491

                &amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;ABSTRACT&amp;quot;&amp;gt;In order to make correct estimates of energy consumption for heating, reduction of energy consumption, and CO2 emissions by applying energy efficiency measures, it is necessary to know the structure and characteristics of the building stock. The Typology of residential buildings in Bosnia and Herzegovina identified the structure and characteristics of residential building stock through different periods at the level of Bosnia and Herzegovina. This paper analyses the differences between national and city or municipal typology. Conducted analysis for the City Derventa, shows that in the case of single-family houses, the application of national instead of local typology can result in certain deviations in the estimation of energy consumption, savings, and CO2 emissions.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>
      <author>Milovan Kotur, Goran Jevti&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61892/stp202401061k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Electron Donating Metal&#8208;Boron Reaction Center Boosts Electrocatalytic Urea Synthesis from N2 and CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400304</link>
      <description>Nuttapon Yodsin, Poobodin Mano, Kaito Takahashi, supawadee namuangruk, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401039536

                Urea (NH2CONH2) production by electrosynthesis at mild conditions has been hampered due to the lack of systematic evaluation of pathways in effectively activating inert N2 and CO2 molecules and facilitating the formation of C&#8208;N bonds. This work, we evaluated 16 transition metal (M) atoms anchored on a carbon nitride nanosheet with boron (B) doping (M&#8208;B@C2N) for boosting urea production by theoretical calculations. All possible urea synthesis pathways, (i) CO2 pathway, (ii) OCOH pathway, (iii) CO pathway, and (iv) NCON pathway, were comparatively studied on Cu, Fe, Co, Ni&#8208;B@C2N. This systematic calculation identified that the first reduction of *N2 is the key step for urea synthesis. We found that the bond index of *N2 shows a strong correlation with &#916;G*N2&#174;*NNH, so they are promising descriptors for screening. Through the screening, we found that Nb&#8208; and Mo&#8208;B@C2N show a low limiting potential of &#8208;0.56 and &#8208;0.53 V. Although previous studies found that spin could promote C&#8208;C bond formation on M&#8208;B@C2N, we found that for C&#8208;N coupling, such effects by spin were only active for Nb&#8208;B@C2N. Combining boron and early transition metal atoms allows for neighboring reaction sites that simultaneously donate electrons to activate inert N2 and CO2 for efficient urea synthesis.</description>
      <author>Nuttapon Yodsin, Poobodin Mano, Kaito Takahashi, supawadee namuangruk</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Combination of Net-Zero Pathways for Minimum Energy, Land, and Water Consumption in Chemical Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c01649</link>
      <description>Paolo Gabrielli, Hanne Goericke, Lorenzo Rosa, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401078439

                Net-zero chemical production can be achieved through electrification, biomass-based processes, and carbon capture, utilization, and storage. However, these net-zero pathways require more resources than business-as-usual processes. One possibility to produce net-zero chemicals at a lower resource consumption is the combination of net-zero pathways based on locally available resources. This study determines the optimal combinations of net-zero pathways for producing chemicals with net-zero emissions that minimize the use of renewable energy, land, and water while complying with local waste biomass and CO2 storage availability. Waste biomass is defined as residue biomass that does not compete for land and water with other sectors. The analysis is performed worldwide at the country level and considers the production of ammonia, methanol, and plastics, which, when combined, account for &#8764;5% of the global CO2 emissions. Findings show that, when considering net-zero pathways individually, waste biomass is preferably used for producing ammonia and methanol, whereas carbon capture and storage is preferably deployed for plastics production. At the same time, a mixed strategy using carbon capture, utilization, and storage, and waste biomass, allows one to achieve a net-zero chemical industry with a nearly 60% reduction in energy consumption and 90% reduction in land and water consumption, with respect to single-pathway strategies. Finally, we find that adopting a net-zero portfolio that minimizes water allows water consumption to be reduced by more than 90% and land consumption to be reduced by more than 70% at the cost of an energy increase of only 5%, when compared to the minimum-energy portfolio.</description>
      <author>Paolo Gabrielli, Hanne Goericke, Lorenzo Rosa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c01649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of palm oil biodiesel production: Environmental impact analysis and POME waste utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61511/aes.v2i1.2024.820</link>
      <description>Ari Kabul Paminto, Mahawan Karuniasa, Evi Frimawaty, Applied Environmental Science. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401193395

                Background: Indonesia is still an energy importer, especially in the form of crude oil and fuel products to meet the needs of its industrial sector. The reduced production of fossil energy, especially oil, as well as the global commitment to reducing greenhouse gas emissions, has prompted the Indonesian government to continue to support the role of new and renewable energy. The production of palm oil-based biodiesel is faced with a number of environmental problems, which may occur from the release of emissions during the production of FFB (Fresh Fruit Bunches), CPO (Crude Palm Oil), and biodiesel. Therefore, the purpose of this research is to compile an LCI (Life Cycle Inventory) covering the production of FFB, CPO, and biodiesel; analyze the environmental impact of the CPO bodysel production process which includes CO2 (eq) emissions, acidification and eutrophication; and develop a life cycle concept for biodiesel production from palm oil as a renewable energy. Methods: The method used in this study is a combination of quantitative LCA (Life Cycle Assessment) and AHP (Analytical Hierarchy Process) and qualitative. Findings: The results of this study are LCI in 1 ton of biodiesel consisting of NPK fertilizer of 141.1 Kg; herbicide (0.25 Kg); water (1578 m3), diesel oil (25 Kg); fresh fruit bunches of 5.67 tons; electricity of 33.8 kWh, POME (Palm Oil Mill Effluent) (3,47 m3), CPO needed for biodiesel conversion of 1.17 tons; methanol (0.41 tons), and 0.01 tons of Sodium Hydroxide. The total CO2 emission (eq) of biodiesel production from palm oil is 1489 Kg CO2 (eq), eutrophication is 1.12 Kg PO43- (eq) and acidification is 3.06 Kg SO2 (eq). With the largest contribution of CO2 (eq) emissions in CPO production and the contribution of eutrophication and acidification in oil palm plantations or FFB production (Fresh Fruit Bunches). Environmental hotspot of LCA, CO2 (eq) emissions from palm oil biodiesel production show that 53% mainly comes from POME (Palm Oil Mill Effluent) waste, other contributors are NPK fertilizers (23%), methanol (18%), and diesel oil (7%). Hotspot eutrophication showed that 61% mainly came from NPK fertilizer, methanol (20%), diesel oil (11%), and POME waste (8%). Hotspot acidification showed that 48% mainly came from NPK fertilizers, methanol (28%), POME waste (13%), and diesel oil (11%). Conclusion: The concept of a biodiesel production life cycle can be applied with the best alternative utilization of POME waste with a priority weighting of 0.357 and a CO2(eq) emission criterion of 0.494. From the optimization of the life cycle of biodiesel production with the use of POME, the potential for emission reduction is 667.2 Kg CO2 (eq). Novelty/Originality of this Study: This study's novel application of LCA evaluates the environmental impacts of biodiesel production from palm oil in Indonesia, identifying critical hotspots in CO2 emissions, eutrophication, and acidification. Additionally, it proposes an innovative optimization approach by utilizing POME to significantly reduce greenhouse gas emissions, highlighting a viable path for enhancing the sustainability of biodiesel production.</description>
      <author>Ari Kabul Paminto, Mahawan Karuniasa, Evi Frimawaty</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61511/aes.v2i1.2024.820</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic Analysis of a Hybrid Energy System for Rural Electrification for the Hasik Area, Oman</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56476/jed.v48i2.7</link>
      <description>Abdullah Al&#8208;Badi, Ahmed Al-Farsi, Tariq Al-Abri, Mohammed Al-Mamari, No host. 48(2)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4401163958

                Renewable energy resources have become the best way to solve the issues created by traditional power resources in terms of environmental effects, energy cost reduction, and high-power demand. The hybrid-based system gives a realistic economic solution where grid extension is non-feasible especially for remote areas. The main objective of this study is to determine the optimum size of a hybrid-based system to fulfill the requirements of remote sites located in the Hasik area in the southern part of Oman. The work is carried out using HOMER Pro and MATLAB software. The proposed hybrid system in the Hasik network is a combination of PV systems with existing diesel generation. Real load data as well as solar radiations were utilized in the proposed model. HOMER selected an optimum solution for the hybrid system resulting in a combination of a 2,500 kW PV system and 3,100 kW diesel generation as well as providing a reduction in the cost of energy and CO2 emissions by 13% and 22%, respectively. The optimum PV sizing for the hybrid system was determined using a genetic algorithm tool in MATLAB. The optimization was based on reducing the system power losses, improving the voltage profile, and minimizing cost. Optimization verification was done using load flow analysis by MATLAB to determine the PV sizing effects on the system power losses and voltage profile. Based on the model results, the hybrid system is feasible in the Hasik area.</description>
      <author>Abdullah Al&#8208;Badi, Ahmed Al-Farsi, Tariq Al-Abri, Mohammed Al-Mamari</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56476/jed.v48i2.7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NH&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-MIL-125 Nanosheets Prepared via Crystallization Kinetics Modulation for Ultrathin Membrane Fabrication</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/cbe.4c00103</link>
      <description>Yanwei Sun, Jiahui Yan, Mingming Wu, Jie Jiang, Yi Liu, Chem &amp; Bio Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401093599

                Regulating both crystallographic orientation and thickness of titanium metal&#8211;organic framework (Ti-MOF) membranes remains a significant challenge. In this study, we pioneered the fabrication of uniform 29 nm thick NH2-MIL-125 nanosheet seeds by employing crystallization kinetics modulation approach. Through innovating confined counter-diffusion-assisted epitaxial growth under single-mode microwave heating, a highly c-oriented 80 nm thick NH2-MIL-125 membrane was prepared. Significant reduction in thickness endowed the membrane with unprecedented H2 permeance (1350 GPU) along with considerable H2/CO2 selectivity (19.1), exceeding the performance benchmarks of state-of-the-art NH2-MIL-125 membranes.</description>
      <author>Yanwei Sun, Jiahui Yan, Mingming Wu, Jie Jiang, Yi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/cbe.4c00103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic composition and fuel influence on anodic processes characteristics of solid polymer electrolyte fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18500/1608-4039-2008-8-1-33-39</link>
      <description>&#1053;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1083;&#1077;&#1096;&#1086;&#1074;, S. V. Grigoriev, Electrochemical Energetics. 8(1)] 2008. https://openalex.org/W4401027802

                It was studied an influence of prior carbon treatment (temperature and gas conditions, mass content of waterproofing agent) on activity of platinum catalyst, synthesized on disperse carbon carrier. It was shown that characteristics of anodic processes depend on quantity of solid polymer electrolyte in catalytic composition. Optimal content of ion exchange polymer under varied degree of carbon carrier waterproofing (used for synthesis of platinum catalyst) is not equal. In a case of platinum catalyst synthesized on a base of carbon carrier with the addition of waterproofing agent (10 mass %), the highest current density of fuel cell functioning on pure oxygen corresponds to 15-20 mass % of polymer content in a layer and in a case of air &#8211; 10-15 mass %. Impurity of carbonic gas in anodic fuel leads to decrease of current density on fuel cell withdrawal not only because of partial pressure decrease. The reason of parameter worsening is partial platinum poisoning with CO, appearing after CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>&#1053;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1083;&#1077;&#1096;&#1086;&#1074;, S. V. Grigoriev</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18500/1608-4039-2008-8-1-33-39</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability of Nitrogen-Doped Activated Carbon as an Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Various Storage Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29153611</link>
      <description>Tao Zhang, Songlin Zuo, Molecules. 29(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401106446

                Besides outstanding catalytic performance, the stability of nitrogen-doped carbon materials during storage is equally crucial for practical applications. Therefore, we conducted the first investigation into the stability of highly nitrogen-doped activated carbon (AC-NC-T) obtained by modifying activated carbon with CO2/NH3 in different storage media (air, vacuum and N2). The results of the catalysis of the oxygen reduction reaction and the activation of peroxymonosulfate for degrading bisphenol A by AC-NC-T show that the catalytic activity of AC-NC-T stored in air decays most prominently, while the performance attenuated only marginally when stored in vacuum and N2. The results from N2 adsorption isotherms, Raman spectroscopy, elemental and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy indicate that the decline in catalytic activity is due to the presence of oxygen in the environment, causing a decrease in absolute contents of pyridinic N (N-6) and graphitic nitrogen (N-Q). After being stored in an air atmosphere for 28 days, the absolute contents of N-6 and N-Q in AC-NC-950 decreased by 19.3% and 12.1%, respectively. However, when stored in a vacuum or N2, the reduction in both was less than 7%. This study demonstrates that reducing oxygen concentration during storage is crucial for preserving high catalytic activity of nitrogen-containing carbon materials.</description>
      <author>Tao Zhang, Songlin Zuo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29153611</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Possible Role of Thermite Reactions in Thermal Runaway of Li-ion Cells with Layered Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6939</link>
      <description>Rodney M. LaFollette, Michael D. Eskra, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401111602

                Abstract It is often observed that some runaway Li-ion cells with layered cathode materials become much hotter internally than existing thermal runaway models predict, Further, metals originally in the positive active material (such as Co, Ni, and Mn) are often found in cells whose temperatures became very high. It has been postulated that the formation of metals can be attributed to reduction of rock salt species (MO, where M is the metal), or the reaction of lithiated active material (LiMO2) with CO2. We propose an alternate process for formation of metals that also results in very high cell temperatures, namely thermite reactions between the Al positive electrode current collector and the positive active material. These reactions are highly exothermic, in contrast with the reactions of MO and LiMO2. In this paper the thermodynamics of thermite reactions are presented. Incorporating thermite reactions in runaway models will likely improve temperature prediction of Li-ion cells in thermal runaway.</description>
      <author>Rodney M. LaFollette, Michael D. Eskra</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6939</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studi Penurunan Emisi GRK dan Analisa Ekonomi Pada Pembangkit Listrik Tenaga Surya (PLTS) Apung Tembesi 46 MWP</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47467/edu.v4i2.4325</link>
      <description>Juanda Fransiskus Lumbantobing, Atok Setiyawan, EduInovasi Journal of Basic Educational Studies. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401152940

                Based on data from the Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources, Indonesia has abundant potential for solar power development, even with relatively low irradiation times. The implementation of solar power plants can directly mitigate the negative impact of carbon emissions caused by fossil power plants, especially coal-fired power plants. This study is aimed to calculate the carbon emission reduction from the construction of FPVPP Tembesi Batam and conduct economic analysis of FPVPP construction by considering Net Present Value (NPV), and Payback Period (PBP), and Internal Rate of Return (IRR) for PLN Batam located in Tembesi Batam Islands Indonesia. This Tembesi solar power plant will be the largest solar power plant in Batam Island which is intended to replace the role of fossil power plants. The study also analyzes the financial impact of carbon credits and renewable energy certificates that PLN Batam will obtain if it fully implements the Tembesi solar power plant. Based on the results of our study, the total carbon emission reduction due to the use of FPVPP when compared to Batam's electricity carbon emission is 67,278,560-ton CO2 in a year. The use of FPVPP in Tembesi, Batam affects the savings of primary energy payments each year and from the economic analysis using the NPV, PBP, and IRR methods, the results show that the feasibility of investing in the construction of FPVPP in Tembesi, Batam is considered feasible and profitable for PT PLN (Persero), the environment, and the scope of the Indonesian state.</description>
      <author>Juanda Fransiskus Lumbantobing, Atok Setiyawan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47467/edu.v4i2.4325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Exhaust Gas Emissions of a Vehicle with an Internal Combustion Engine in High and Low Vehicular Congestion for a High Altitude City</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18502/espoch.v3i3.16623</link>
      <description>Jorge Lema, ESPOCH Congresses The Ecuadorian Journal of S T E A M. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401036584

                Pollution generated by the automotive sector is one of the biggest concerns in the city of Quito. This is due to the fact that the majority of vehicles in the automotive fleet use fossil fuels as a source of propulsion energy. In addition, the heterogeneity of the technologies of the fuel injection systems means that the control of polluting emissions is highly limited. On the other hand, due to the high number of vehicles and the topographical characteristics of the city, high traffic congestion is generated during rush hours, producing abrupt changes in acceleration and reduction of stoichiometric mixtures. Based on the above, it was pertinent to compare the exhaust gas emissions that are produced in high and low vehicular congestion for a vehicle with an internal combustion engine Likewise, the correlations of the gases for both scenarios were determined. To do this, emissions were measured in a Mazda 3 vehicle on a major city route during rush hours and on weekends. A Kane Autoplus gas analyzer was used for exhaust gas measurement, and data logging was done on the Kane Live app. The results showed that in rush hours, the vehicle emits higher amounts of CO2, CO, and HC up to 0.7%; 128.5%; and 65.5%, respectively. There are moderate and strong correlations of O2-CO2 and CO-HC in high and low vehicular congestion, with Pearson&#8217;s correlation values greater than 0.5. Keywords: exhaust gases, internal combustion engine, pollution, route, rush hours, traffic. Resumen La contaminaci&#243;n generada por el sector automotriz, es uno de los mayores problemas que enfrenta la ciudad de Quito. Esto se debe a que la mayor&#237;a de veh&#237;culos del parque automotor, utilizan combustibles f&#243;siles como fuente de energ&#237;a de propulsi&#243;n. Adem&#225;s, la heterogeneidad de las tecnolog&#237;as de los sistemas de inyecci&#243;n de combustible, hace que el control de emisiones contaminantes se limite considerablemente. Por otro lado, debido al elevado n&#250;mero de veh&#237;culos y a las caracter&#237;sticas topogr&#225;ficas de la ciudad, se genera una elevada congesti&#243;n vehicular en horas pico, produciendo cambios abruptos de aceleraciones y reducci&#243;n de las mezclas estequiom&#233;tricas. Con base a lo expuesto, fue pertinente comparar las emisiones de gases de escape que se producen en alta y baja congesti&#243;n vehicular para un veh&#237;culo con motor de combusti&#243;n interna, y as&#237; mismo, se determin&#243; las correlaciones de los gases para ambos escenarios. Para ello, se midi&#243; las emisiones en un veh&#237;culo Mazda 3 sobre una ruta importante de la ciudad en horas pico y fines de semana. Se utiliz&#243; un analizador de gases Kane Autoplus para la medici&#243;n de los gases de escape, y el registro de datos se efectu&#243; en la aplicaci&#243;n Kane Live. Los resultados mostraron que en horas pico, el veh&#237;culo emite mayores cantidades de CO2, CO, HC de hasta el 0,77%; 6,66%; 94,69%, respectivamente. Existen moderadas y fuertes correlaciones de O2-CO2 y CO-HC en alta y baja congesti&#243;n vehicular, con valores de correlaci&#243;n de Pearson superior a 0,5. Palabras Clave: contaminaci&#243;n, gases de escape, horas pico, motor de combusti&#243;n interna, ruta, tr&#225;fico.</description>
      <author>Jorge Lema</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18502/espoch.v3i3.16623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon reduction effect of digital finance in China: based on household micro data and input-output model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1108/cfri-03-2024-0083</link>
      <description>Yongbin Lv, Ying Jia, Chenying Sang, Xianming Sun, China Finance Review International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401104064

                Purpose This study investigates the causal relationship and mechanisms between the development of digital finance and household carbon emissions. Its objective is to explore how digital finance can influence the carbon footprint at the household level, aiming to contribute to the broader understanding of financial innovations' environmental impacts. Design/methodology/approach The research combines macro and micro data, employing input-output analysis to utilize data from the China Household Finance Survey (CHFS) for the years 2013, 2015, 2017, and 2019, national input-output tables, and Energy Statistical Yearbooks. This approach calculated CO2 emissions at the household level, including the growth rate of household carbon emissions and per capita emissions. It further integrates the Peking University Digital Financial Inclusion Index of China (PKU-DFIIC) for 2012&#8211;2018 and corresponding urban economic data, resulting in panel data for 7,191 households across 151 cities over four years. A fixed effects model was employed to examine the impact of digital finance development on household carbon emissions. Findings The findings reveal that digital finance significantly lowers household carbon emissions. Further investigation shows that digital transformation, consumption structure upgrades, and improved household financial literacy enhance the restraining effect of digital finance on carbon emissions. Heterogeneity analysis indicates that this mitigating effect is more pronounced in households during the nurturing phase, those using convenient payment methods, small-scale, and urban households. Sub-index tests suggest that the broadening coverage and deepening usage of digital finance primarily drive its impact on reducing household carbon emissions. Practical implications The paper recommends that China should continue to strengthen the layout of digital infrastructure, leverage the advantages of digital finance, promote digital financial education, and facilitate household-level carbon emission management to support the achievement of China's dual carbon goals. Originality/value The originality of this paper lies in its detailed examination of the carbon reduction effects of digital finance at the micro (household) level. Unlike previous studies on carbon emissions that focused on absolute emissions, this research investigates the marginal impact of digital finance on relative increases in emissions. This method provides a robust assessment of the net effects of digital finance and offers a novel perspective for examining household carbon reduction measures. The study underscores the importance of considering heterogeneity when formulating targeted policies for households with different characteristics.</description>
      <author>Yongbin Lv, Ying Jia, Chenying Sang, Xianming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1108/cfri-03-2024-0083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Alkali-Activated Mortars with Steel Slag and Eggshell Powder</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14082336</link>
      <description>Behailu Zerihun Hailemariam, Mitiku Damtie Yehualaw, Woubishet Zewdu Taffese, Duy&#8208;Hai Vo, Buildings. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401084697

                The cement industry is known for being highly energy-intensive and a significant contributor to global CO2 emissions. To address this environmental challenge, this study explores the potential of using the waste materials of steel slag (SS) and eggshell powder (ESP) as partial replacements for cement in alkali-activated mortars (AAMs) production, activated by NaOH and Na2SiO3. Mortar samples are prepared with 50% of ordinary Portland cement (OPC) as part of the total binder, and the remaining 50% is composed of ESP, incrementally replaced by SS at levels of 10%, 20%, 40%, and 50%. The activation process was performed with an 8% NaOH concentration and a silica modulus of 2. Key findings include that the workability of AAMs decreased with increasing SS content, requiring admixtures like superplasticizers or additional water to maintain workability. At 50% SS replacement, the water consistency and slump flow values were 32.56% and 105.73 mm, respectively, with a setting time reduction of approximately 36%, losing plasticity within 2 h. Both absorption capacity and porosity decreased as SS content increased from 10% to 50% of ESP. Additionally, the bulk density, compressive strength, and uniformity of the hardened mortar samples were enhanced with higher SS content, achieving maximum compressive strength (28.53 MPa) at 50% SS replacement after 56 days of curing. Furthermore, OPC-based AAMs incorporating SS and ESP demonstrate good resistance to sulfate attack and thermal heating. Microstructural analysis reveals the presence of C&#8211;S&#8211;H, C&#8211;A&#8211;S&#8211;H, and N&#8211;A&#8211;S&#8211;H phases, along with minor amounts of unreacted particles, and the microstructure shows a dense, highly compacted, and homogeneous morphology. These findings suggest that replacing eggshell powder with up to 50% steel slag enhances the hardened properties of AAMs. Further research is recommended to explore cement-free alkali-activated granular ground blast furnace slag (GGBFS) with ESP for more sustainable construction solutions.</description>
      <author>Behailu Zerihun Hailemariam, Mitiku Damtie Yehualaw, Woubishet Zewdu Taffese, Duy&#8208;Hai Vo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14082336</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
