<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 01:22:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic Electron Transfer in Heteronuclear Dual&#8208;Atom Sites Facilitates Selective Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403778</link>
      <description>Qi Tang, Qi Hao, Qian Zhu, Junxiu Wu, Keke Huang, Kai Liu, Jun L&#252;, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402993961

                Abstract The metal&#8211;metal (M 1 &#8211;M 2 ) interactions in heteronuclear dual&#8208;atom catalysts (HNDACs) significantly optimize the electronic properties of the active sites, resulting in the promotion of the reaction kinetics in electrocatalysis. However, the regulation mechanisms in these M 1 &#8211;M 2 dual&#8208;atom sites still remain unclear. Herein, the intrinsic electron transfer in Fe&#8211;Zn dual&#8208;atom sites are revealed for facilitating electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (ECO 2 R) to carbon monoxide (CO). The electronegativity difference between the Fe and Zn centers induces the specific electron transfer from Zn to Fe, which regulates the electron structures of the active Zn sites, leading to the optimized reaction pathway of CO 2 &#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion on these sites. The Fe&#8211;Zn HNDAC (FeZnNC) exhibits superior ECO 2 R performances than the single&#8208;atom Fe/Zn catalysts (FeNC and ZnNC) in the typical H&#8208;cell system, the maximum CO partial current density on FeZnNC reaches more than 3.3 and 1.8 folds of those on FeNC and ZnNC, respectively. More importantly, in a strongly acidic medium (pH = 1), FeZnNC achieves CO Faradaic efficiencies greater than 94% in the current density range of 100&#8211;400 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work uncovers the intrinsic electron transfer at the heteronuclear diatomic sites, providing new insights for the rational design of high&#8208;performance HNDACs toward industrial electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Qi Tang, Qi Hao, Qian Zhu, Junxiu Wu, Keke Huang, Kai Liu, Jun L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ugi's amine based coordination polymers as a synergistic catalysts for electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01181c</link>
      <description>Mikhail Khrizanforov, Farida F. Nailieva, Kamil Ivshin, Almaz Zagidullin, Anastasiia P. Samorodnova, Ruslan P. Shekurov, Polina Milyukova, Artem Laskin, Alexander S. Novikov, Vasili A. Miluykov, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403033444

                The escalating concentration of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere is a pressing environmental concern, necessitating the development of efficient technologies for CO 2 reduction and utilization. In this context, metal-organic frameworks...</description>
      <author>Mikhail Khrizanforov, Farida F. Nailieva, Kamil Ivshin, Almaz Zagidullin, Anastasiia P. Samorodnova, Ruslan P. Shekurov, Polina Milyukova, Artem Laskin, Alexander S. Novikov, Vasili A. Miluykov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01181c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous electrochemical upgrading of Polyethylene Terephthalate plastic and carbon dioxide into valuable chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124667</link>
      <description>Hongxia Liu, Ziqing Wang, Yanan He, Xin Hu, Lei Liu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403077498

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongxia Liu, Ziqing Wang, Yanan He, Xin Hu, Lei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover: Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Supported Low&#8208;Nuclearity Cluster Catalysts for Highly Selective Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction to Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416813</link>
      <description>Bing Shao, Du Shu Huang, Rui&#8208;Kang Huang, Xing&#8208;Lu He, Yan Luo, Yi&#8208;Lei Xiang, Linbin Jiang, Min Dong, Shixiong Li, Zhong Zhang, Jin Huang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082653

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Shao, Du Shu Huang, Rui&#8208;Kang Huang, Xing&#8208;Lu He, Yan Luo, Yi&#8208;Lei Xiang, Linbin Jiang, Min Dong, Shixiong Li, Zhong Zhang, Jin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover: Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Supported Low&#8208;Nuclearity Cluster Catalysts for Highly Selective Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction to Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416813</link>
      <description>Bing Shao, Du Shu Huang, Rui&#8208;Kang Huang, Xing&#8208;Lu He, Yan Luo, Yi&#8208;Lei Xiang, Linbin Jiang, Min Dong, Shixiong Li, Zhong Zhang, Jin Huang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082707

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Shao, Du Shu Huang, Rui&#8208;Kang Huang, Xing&#8208;Lu He, Yan Luo, Yi&#8208;Lei Xiang, Linbin Jiang, Min Dong, Shixiong Li, Zhong Zhang, Jin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Surfactant in Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction in the Absence of Metal Cations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00040</link>
      <description>Hansaem Jang, Adrian M. Gardner, Lucy Jayne Walters, Alex R. Neale, Laurence J. Hardwick, J.S. Roberts, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403084997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hansaem Jang, Adrian M. Gardner, Lucy Jayne Walters, Alex R. Neale, Laurence J. Hardwick, J.S. Roberts</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Conjugated Nickel(II)&#8208;Acetylide Framework for Efficient Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418269</link>
      <description>Yingying Qin, Yang Wang, Jian Lu, Linli Xu, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403129175

                The incorporation of transition&#8208;metal single atoms as molecular functional entities into the skeleton of graphdiyne (GDY) to construct novel two&#8208;dimensional (2D) metal&#8208;acetylide frameworks, known as metalated graphynes (MGYs), is a promising strategy for developing efficient catalysts, which can combine the tunable charge transfer of GDY frameworks, the catalytic activity of metal and the precise distribution of single metallic centers. Herein, four highly conjugated MGY photocatalysts based on NiII, PdII, PtII, and HgII were synthesized for the first time using the &#8216;bottom&#8208;up&#8217; strategy through the use of M&#8211;C bonds (&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;M&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;). Remarkably, the NiII&#8208;based graphyne (TEPY&#8208;Ni&#8208;GY) exhibited the highest CO generation rate of 18.3 mmol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1 and a selectivity of 98.8%. This superior performance is attributed to the synergistic effects of pyrenyl and &#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;Ni(PBu3)2&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211; moieties. The pyrenyl block functions as an intramolecular &#960;&#8208;conjugation channel, facilitating kinetically favorable electron transfer, while the &#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;Ni(PBu3)2&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211; moiety serves as the catalytic site that enhances CO2 adsorption and activation, thereby suppressing competitive hydrogen evolution. This study provides a new perspective on MGY&#8208;based photocatalysts for developing highly active and low&#8208;cost catalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Yingying Qin, Yang Wang, Jian Lu, Linli Xu, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of urban vegetation cover on CO2 reduction in the city</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31705/cers.2024.28</link>
      <description>H.K.P. Chanika, Nilanka Harshani Weerasinghe, R.U. Halwatura, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140935

                Rising urban carbon dioxide levels have emerged as a critical issue due to their adverse effects on public health and the environment. Trees are a natural and sustainable solution to mitigate urban carbon dioxide (CO2) concentrations, as they absorb CO2 from the atmosphere through photosynthesis. However, the specific relationship between tree density and CO2 concentration within cities is unclear. The main objectives of this research are to determine the relationship between tree density and CO2 concentration reduction in cities and to identify the optimum tree density to reduce the CO2 level in the city to obtain the required CO2 level. For this study, data were collected in the densely urbanized city of Colombo and various urban areas within the Hambantota district. Tree densities and CO2 concentration reduction data were collected from 300 sample plots, each with a fixed size of 50m x 50m, near roads in selected urban areas. When calculating tree density, it is important to calculate canopy volumes of trees. It depends on canopy height, crown diameter and canopy shape. The tree density of the sample plot was calculated by dividing the total canopy volume by the area of the sample plot. A digital portable CO2 meter was used to measure the CO2 level. First the CO2 concentration was measured at the centre of the road and then the CO2 concentration was measured at the centre of the sample plot. The reduction in CO2 level was calculated by the difference between these two readings. By analysing tree densities and CO2 concentration data collected through field data studies, a linear relationship was obtained between tree density and CO2 concentration reduction in urban areas. The plotted line got a R2 value of 0.8806 indicating a well-fitting model. Therefore, this linear plotted line can be described as a reasonable fitted line representing all collected data. Also, the data was classified based on the CO2 concentration in the centre of the road and the behaviour of the CO2 concentration reduction Vs tree density relationship was studied in each range. A linear relationship was obtained in each of those ranges. When all the collected data were classified as residential and non-residential based on the usage of the sample plots, the R2 values obtained from those graphs were higher than the R2 value of the graph drawn without classification. The R2 value of the graph for non-residential areas has increased relative to the value of the graph for residential areas. Accordingly, classifying in this manner led to an increase in the accuracy of the relationship. Using these relationships, the optimum tree density required to obtain the required CO2 reduction in urban areas can be identified. The results of this study will be valuable for policymakers and urban planners looking for ways to improve air quality and create more sustainable urban environments.</description>
      <author>H.K.P. Chanika, Nilanka Harshani Weerasinghe, R.U. Halwatura</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31705/cers.2024.28</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene-Based Photocatalysts for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-66260-7_29</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; M. Barrera&#8208;Andrade, Elim Albiter, Miguel A. Valenzuela, E. Rojas Garc&#237;a, Advanced structured materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403072741

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; M. Barrera&#8208;Andrade, Elim Albiter, Miguel A. Valenzuela, E. Rojas Garc&#237;a</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-66260-7_29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tandem electrocatalysis for CO2 reduction to multi-carbons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2144-0</link>
      <description>X. N. Li, Tianxiang Yan, Yichen Meng, Zhanpeng Liang, Tianying Zhang, Haoyuan Chi, Ziting Fan, Yifan Jin, Haoran Zhang, Sheng Zhang, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403005598

                No abstract</description>
      <author>X. N. Li, Tianxiang Yan, Yichen Meng, Zhanpeng Liang, Tianying Zhang, Haoyuan Chi, Ziting Fan, Yifan Jin, Haoran Zhang, Sheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2144-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Study of the Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 in Aprotic Ionic Liquid in Air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401832</link>
      <description>Go Iijima, Kazumitsu Sugiura, Kazuhiko Morishita, Hajime Shingai, Junichi Naruse, Atsushi Yamamoto, Yuki Fujita, Hiroaki Yoto, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140372

                The capture and electrochemical conversion of dilute CO2 in air is a promising approach to mitigate global warming. Aiming to increase the efficiency of the electrochemical reduction of CO2, we fabricated electrodes and developed a custom&#8208;designed sealed electrochemical reaction system to study the mechanism of this conversion. The performance of three metal electrodes, Ag, Cu, and SUS 316L, was compared in an aprotic ionic liquid as the electrolyte to monitor the CO2 concentration and chemical reactions using a CO2 sensor and diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy and Raman spectroscopy in CO2/N2 (400 ppm CO2 and 99.96% N2) or synthetic air (400 ppm CO2, 21% O2, and 79% N2). The CO2 concentration decreased at negative potentials and was more drastic in synthetic air than in CO2/N2. At negative potential in synthetic air, IR revealed carbon monoxide, carbonate, or peroxydicarbonate on the Ag, Cu, or SUS 316L electrodes, respectively. Reaction intermediates were identified using Raman spectroscopy. Superoxide (O2&#8226;&#8722;), produced by the reduction of O2 on each electrode, promotes the electrochemical reduction of CO2 whose reduction potential is higher on the negative side than that of O2. This research deepens our understanding of the electrochemical capture/release and conversion of dilute CO2.</description>
      <author>Go Iijima, Kazumitsu Sugiura, Kazuhiko Morishita, Hajime Shingai, Junichi Naruse, Atsushi Yamamoto, Yuki Fujita, Hiroaki Yoto</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Modified Nb2o5 Photocatalysts for High Performance of Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4974364</link>
      <description>Junli Chen, Tao Wang, Ziqi Yang, Pan Gao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403069376

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junli Chen, Tao Wang, Ziqi Yang, Pan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4974364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 electrochemical reduction to formic acid: An overview of process sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100308</link>
      <description>Zeyad M. Ghazi, Dina Ewis, Hazim Qiblawey, Muftah H. El&#8208;Naas, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. 13(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402999323

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyad M. Ghazi, Dina Ewis, Hazim Qiblawey, Muftah H. El&#8208;Naas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of copper-based catalysts for CO2 electrochemical reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.304</link>
      <description>Yan Jia, Weixiu Song, Zhenli Zhao, Manyu Zhang, Yan Jing Wu, Lianhong Zhang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 89(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403030261

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Jia, Weixiu Song, Zhenli Zhao, Manyu Zhang, Yan Jing Wu, Lianhong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Interfacial Electric Field on 2D Metal/Graphene Electrocatalysts for CO2 Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401673</link>
      <description>Jinwon Cho, Faisal M. Alamgir, Seung Soon Jang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402966995

                Understanding the influence of local electric fields on electrochemical reactions is crucial for designing highly selective electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction reactions (CO2RR). In this study, we provide a theoretical investigation of the effect of the local electric field induced by the negative&#8208;biased electrode and cations in the electrolyte on the energetics and reaction kinetics of CO2RR on 2D hybrid metal/graphene electrocatalysts. Our findings reveal that the electronic structures of the CO2 molecule undergo substantial modification, resulting in the increased adsorption energy of CO&#173;2 on metal/graphene structures, thus reducing the initial barrier of the CO2RR mechanism. This field&#8208;assisted CO2RR mechanism promotes CO production while suppressing HCOOH production. Our findings highlight the potential of manipulating electric fields to tailor the pathways of CO2RR, providing new avenues designing selective electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jinwon Cho, Faisal M. Alamgir, Seung Soon Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401673</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strained Cu(111) surface can be catalytic efficient for C&#8211;C coupling in CO2 electrochemical reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0216818</link>
      <description>Yunfang Xu, Y. L. Han, Lixin Zhang, AIP Advances. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403032159

                It is well accepted that the Cu(100) surface is catalytic active for C&#8211;C coupling in CO2 reduction. However, the (100) surface is less active for the preceding CO* formation process and, most importantly, less stable than other surfaces. In this work, we investigate the relationship between catalytic effects and general factors such as coordination number and spacing (strain) of the Cu surface atoms. We find that the former affects the CO* formation only and the latter affects both the CO* formation and the subsequent C&#8211;C coupling. Among all the strained surfaces with larger atomic spacing, the more stable Cu(111) surface is extraordinary and outperforms Cu(100) and the high index surfaces for CO2 reduction to C2 on Cu.</description>
      <author>Yunfang Xu, Y. L. Han, Lixin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0216818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT and microkinetic modeling study of pressure effects on electroreduction reduction of CO2 to ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161421</link>
      <description>Xiaowen Wang, Fei Ma, Haiqiao Wei, Jiaying Pan, Wenjia Li, Jun Zhao, Xiaotao Yang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403117340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaowen Wang, Fei Ma, Haiqiao Wei, Jiaying Pan, Wenjia Li, Jun Zhao, Xiaotao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise Synthesis of Dual&#8208;single&#8208;atom Electrocatalysts through Pre&#8208;coordination&#8208;directed in situ Confinement for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415223</link>
      <description>Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Haochen Sun, Fangyuan Wang, Ying Liang, Jing Li, Daoxiong Wu, Xiaodong Shi, Zhenye Kang, Zhengpei Miao, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402962730

                Dual&#8208;single&#8208;atom catalysts (DSACs) are the next paradigm shift in single&#8208;atom catalysts because of the enhanced performance brought about by the synergistic effects between adjacent bimetallic pairs. However, there are few methods for synthesizing DSACs with precise bimetallic structures. Herein, a pre&#8208;coordination strategy is proposed to precisely synthesize a library of DSACs. This strategy ensures the selective and effective coordination of two metals via phthalocyanines with specific coordination sites, such as &#8211;F&#8211; and &#8211;OH&#8211;. Subsequently, in&#8208;situ confinement inhibits the migration of metal pairs during high&#8208;temperature pyrolysis, and obtains the DSACs with precisely constructed metal pairs. Despite changing synthetic parameters, including transition metal centers, metal pairs, and spatial geometry, the products exhibit similar atomic metal pairs dispersion properties, demonstrating the universality of the strategy. The pre&#8208;coordination strategy synthesized DSACs shows significant CO2 reduction reaction performance in both flow&#8208;cell and practical rechargeable Zn&#8208;CO2 batteries. This work not only provides new insights into the precise synthesis of DSACs, but also offers guidelines for the accelerated discovery of efficient catalysts.</description>
      <author>Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Haochen Sun, Fangyuan Wang, Ying Liang, Jing Li, Daoxiong Wu, Xiaodong Shi, Zhenye Kang, Zhengpei Miao, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise Synthesis of Dual&#8208;single&#8208;atom Electrocatalysts through Pre&#8208;coordination&#8208;directed in situ Confinement for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415223</link>
      <description>Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Haochen Sun, Fangyuan Wang, Ying Liang, Jing Li, Daoxiong Wu, Xiaodong Shi, Zhenye Kang, Zhengpei Miao, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402962769

                Dual&#8208;single&#8208;atom catalysts (DSACs) are the next paradigm shift in single&#8208;atom catalysts because of the enhanced performance brought about by the synergistic effects between adjacent bimetallic pairs. However, there are few methods for synthesizing DSACs with precise bimetallic structures. Herein, a pre&#8208;coordination strategy is proposed to precisely synthesize a library of DSACs. This strategy ensures the selective and effective coordination of two metals via phthalocyanines with specific coordination sites, such as &#8211;F&#8211; and &#8211;OH&#8211;. Subsequently, in&#8208;situ confinement inhibits the migration of metal pairs during high&#8208;temperature pyrolysis, and obtains the DSACs with precisely constructed metal pairs. Despite changing synthetic parameters, including transition metal centers, metal pairs, and spatial geometry, the products exhibit similar atomic metal pairs dispersion properties, demonstrating the universality of the strategy. The pre&#8208;coordination strategy synthesized DSACs shows significant CO2 reduction reaction performance in both flow&#8208;cell and practical rechargeable Zn&#8208;CO2 batteries. This work not only provides new insights into the precise synthesis of DSACs, but also offers guidelines for the accelerated discovery of efficient catalysts.</description>
      <author>Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Haochen Sun, Fangyuan Wang, Ying Liang, Jing Li, Daoxiong Wu, Xiaodong Shi, Zhenye Kang, Zhengpei Miao, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co Cluster-Modified Ni Nanoparticles with Superior Light-Driven Thermocatalytic Co2 Reduction by Ch4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4976153</link>
      <description>Qian Zhang, Mei Li, Yuhua Zhang, Na Sun, Dan Cheng, Peng Sun, Shaowen Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403093962

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Zhang, Mei Li, Yuhua Zhang, Na Sun, Dan Cheng, Peng Sun, Shaowen Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4976153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous nickel-based catalyst doped with fluorine can efficiently electrocatalyze the reduction of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176771</link>
      <description>Beifang Lu, Tianxia Liu, Li Jia, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402971244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Beifang Lu, Tianxia Liu, Li Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Z-scheme ZnIn2S4/CuxO heterostructure on flexible substrate for efficient photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161369</link>
      <description>Jiping Shi, Liuqing Hua, Lu Ruan, Xingjian Zhang, Zhengdao Li, Fengyun Su, Xin Li, Haiquan Xie, Yong Zhou, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402980246

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiping Shi, Liuqing Hua, Lu Ruan, Xingjian Zhang, Zhengdao Li, Fengyun Su, Xin Li, Haiquan Xie, Yong Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zirconium-doped ultrathin copper nanowires for C1 and C2+ products in electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114591</link>
      <description>Wuyang Lin, Matteo Palma, Devis Di Tommaso, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403077551

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wuyang Lin, Matteo Palma, Devis Di Tommaso</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of mesoporous sulfated ZnO-modified g-C3N4 and TiO2 photocatalysts for CO2 reduction in gas phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115089</link>
      <description>L.A. Al-Hajji, Adel A. Ismail, M. Alsaidi, Ahmed Abdel Nazeer, Ahmed Mohamed El&#8208;Toni, S.F. Al-Ruwayeh, S.A. Ahmed, T. Al-Sharrah, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403157643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L.A. Al-Hajji, Adel A. Ismail, M. Alsaidi, Ahmed Abdel Nazeer, Ahmed Mohamed El&#8208;Toni, S.F. Al-Ruwayeh, S.A. Ahmed, T. Al-Sharrah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare-earth metal neodymium anchored into graphene as a promising CO2 reduction electrocatalyst by regulating the coordination environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105203</link>
      <description>Siying Liu, Huohai Yang, Xingbo Ge, Yingjie Feng, Xiaoyue Fu, Xin Chen, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403044828

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siying Liu, Huohai Yang, Xingbo Ge, Yingjie Feng, Xiaoyue Fu, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoirradiation-enhanced behavior via morphological manipulation of CoFe2O4/g-C3N4 heterojunction for supercapacitor and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.211</link>
      <description>Wei He, Yingpei Liu, Liang Liu, Huimin Han, Zhi&#8208;Xiang Wang, Yuguang Li, Dong Ji, L. Shen, Yirong Feng, Shuangfei Zhao, Jiming Yang, Zheng Fang, Jing Wang, Kai Guo, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403014884

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei He, Yingpei Liu, Liang Liu, Huimin Han, Zhi&#8208;Xiang Wang, Yuguang Li, Dong Ji, L. Shen, Yirong Feng, Shuangfei Zhao, Jiming Yang, Zheng Fang, Jing Wang, Kai Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Catalytic Activity of I-Mxenes for Co2 Reduction Reaction by Ordered Metal Atomic Vacancies: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4973714</link>
      <description>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403016594

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4973714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divergent Activity Shifts of Sn-Based Catalysts for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction: pH-Dependent Behavior of Single-Atom vs. Polyatomic Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-38nl4</link>
      <description>Yuhang Wang, Di Zhang, Bin Sun, Xue Jia, Linda Zhang, Hefeng Cheng, Jun Fan, Hao Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082874

                Tin (Sn)-based catalysts have been widely studied for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to produce formic acid, but the intricate influence of the structural sensitivity in single-atom Sn (e.g., Sn-N-C) and polyatomic Sn (e.g., SnOx and SnSx; x=1,2) on their pH-dependent performance remains enigmatic. Herein, we integrate large-scale data mining (with &gt;2,300 CO2RR catalysts from available experimental literature during the past decade), ab initio computations, machine learning force field accelerated molecular dynamic simulations, and pH-field coupled microkinetic modelling to unravel their pH dependence. We reveal a fascinating contrast: the electric field response of the binding strength of *OCHO on Sn-N4-C and polyatomic Sn exhibits opposite behaviors due to their differing dipole moment changes upon *OCHO formation. Such response leads to an intriguing opposite pH-dependent volcano evolution for Sn-N4-C and polyatomic Sn. Subsequent experimental validations of turnover frequency and current density under both neutral and alkaline conditions well aligned with our theoretical predictions. Most importantly, our analysis suggests the necessity of distinct optimization strategies for *OCHO binding energy on different types of Sn-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Wang, Di Zhang, Bin Sun, Xue Jia, Linda Zhang, Hefeng Cheng, Jun Fan, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-38nl4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-organic framework (MOF) integrated Ti3C2 MXene composites for CO2 reduction and hydrogen production applications: a review on recent advances and future perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1448700</link>
      <description>Beenish Tahir, Abdulrahman Alraeesi, Muhammad Tahir, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403046125

                Titanium carbide (Ti 3 C 2 ) MXenes due to their structural and optical characteristics rapidly emerged as the preferred material, particularly in catalysis and energy applications. On the other hand, because of its enormous surface/volume ratio and porosity, Metal-organic Frameworks (MOFs) show promise in several areas, including catalysis, delivery, and storage. The potential to increase the applicability of these magic compounds might be achieved by taking advantage of the inherent flexibility in design and synthesis, and optical characteristics of MXenes. Thus, coupling MOF with Ti 3 C 2 MXenes to construct hybrid composites is considered promising in a variety of applications, including energy conversion and storage. This paper presents a systematic discussion of current developments in Ti 3 C 2 MXenes/MOF composites for photocatalytic reduction of CO 2 , and production of hydrogen through water splitting. Initially, the overview and characteristics of MXenes and MOFs are independently discussed and then a detailed investigation of efficiency enhancement is examined. Different strategies such as engineering aspects, construction of binary and ternary composites and their efficiency enhancement mechanism are deliberated. Finally, different strategies to explore further in various other applications are suggested. Although Ti 3 C 2 MXenes/MOF composites have not yet been thoroughly investigated, they are potential photocatalysts for the production of solar fuel and ought to be looked into further for a range of applications.</description>
      <author>Beenish Tahir, Abdulrahman Alraeesi, Muhammad Tahir</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1448700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Capture and Storage Via Electrochemical and Bioelectrochemical Techniques: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4314/cajost.v6i2.3</link>
      <description>John Tsado Mathew, Abel Inobeme, Yakubu Azeh, Musah Monday, Abdullahi Abdulkadir, Elijah Yanda Shaba, M. B. Etsuyankpa, Tanko S. Musa, A. I. Muhammad, Hina Ismail, Abubakar Mohammed Kanwa, Amos Mamman, Jonathan Hussaini, Caliphate Journal of Science and Technology. 6(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403103147

                The urgent need to mitigate climate change has spurred innovative research in carbon capture and storage (CCS) technologies. Electrochemical approaches utilize electrocatalysis and electrochemical reduction to capture carbon dioxide (CO2) from industrial emissions, demonstrating high selectivity and enabling the production of valuable chemicals and fuels from captured CO2. Bioelectrochemical techniques leverage microorganisms to convert CO2 into biomass or biofuels, enhancing carbon capture efficiency through biological and electrochemical synergy. Integrating bioelectrochemical systems with renewable energy sources provides a carbon-negative pathway, aiding industry decarbonization. This review underscores the transformative potential of these techniques in revolutionizing CCS strategies, emphasizing their role in addressing climate change while fostering a sustainable, circular economy.</description>
      <author>John Tsado Mathew, Abel Inobeme, Yakubu Azeh, Musah Monday, Abdullahi Abdulkadir, Elijah Yanda Shaba, M. B. Etsuyankpa, Tanko S. Musa, A. I. Muhammad, Hina Ismail, Abubakar Mohammed Kanwa, Amos Mamman, Jonathan Hussaini</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4314/cajost.v6i2.3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the Serbian Energy Transition Puzzle: Driving an Electric Vehicle Result in Higher CO2 Emissions than Driving a Traditional Internal Combustion Engine Counterparty</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46793/eee24-1.22f</link>
      <description>Sergey F. Fominykh, Dusan Stanar, Energija Ekonomija Ekologija. XXVI(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402974272

                his article delves into the intriguing paradox emerging in Serbia's transportation landscape, where electric vehicles (EVs) are projected to generate more carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions than internal combustion engine (ICE) until 2030. Driving an EV within Serbia over the upcoming five years is estimated to contribute to roughly 25% more CO2 emissions compared to ICE vehicles. The study unveils the underlying factors behind this paradox, including Serbia's energy mix dominated by lignite. By contrasting this with the European Union's cleaner energy sources, the article underscores the delayed CO2 emissions reduction from EVs in Serbia. Furthermore, it explores the carbon footprint associated with EV production and highlights the challenges posed by the country's energy infrastructure and vehicle fleet. The article concludes with insights into potential solutions, emphasizing the need for Serbia to accelerate its transition to renewables, aiming to align with 2030 targets, while parity with EU emissions levels is projected by 2040.</description>
      <author>Sergey F. Fominykh, Dusan Stanar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46793/eee24-1.22f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Reservoir Characteristics of Potential Carbon Dioxide Storage Sites in the Northern South Yellow Sea Basin, Offshore Eastern China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12101733</link>
      <description>Di Luo, Yong Yuan, Jianwen Chen, Qing Li, Jie Liang, Hualin Zhao, Journal of Marine Science and Engineering. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403074530

                The geological storage of carbon dioxide (CO2) in offshore saline aquifers stands as a primary option for reducing CO2 emissions in coastal regions. China&#8217;s coastal regions, particularly Shandong and Jiangsu provinces, face significant challenges in CO2 reduction. Therefore, evaluating the feasibility of CO2 geological storage in the adjacent seas is critical. To assess the suitability of a CO2 storage site, understanding its structural and reservoir characteristics is essential to mitigate injection and storage risks. In this study, we analyzed the structural characteristics and potential traps of the Yantai Depression in the South Yellow Sea Basin based on seismic data interpretation. We further conducted well logging analysis and post-stack seismic inversion to obtain lithological data, including acoustic impedance and sandstone content percentages from the Cenozoic Funing Formation, Dainan&#8211;Sanduo Formation, and Yancheng Formation. Our findings highlight that the Yantai Depression in the South Yellow Sea Basin exhibits diverse structural traps and favorable reservoir&#8211;caprock combinations, suggesting promising geological conditions for CO2 storage. This area emerges as a suitable candidate for implementing CO2 geological storage initiatives.</description>
      <author>Di Luo, Yong Yuan, Jianwen Chen, Qing Li, Jie Liang, Hualin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12101733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemistry-climate feedback of atmospheric methane in a methane emission flux driven chemistry-climate model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2938</link>
      <description>Laura Stecher, Franziska Frank, Patrick J&#246;ckel, Michael Ponater, Mariano Mertens, M. Dameris, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403045913

                Abstract. The chemical sink of atmospheric methane (CH4) depends on the temperature and on the chemical composition. Here, we assess the feedback of atmospheric CH4 induced by changes of the chemical sink in a warming climate using a CH4 emission flux driven setup of the chemistry-climate model EMAC, in which the chemical feedback of CH4 mixing ratios can evolve explicitly. We perform idealized perturbation simulations driven either by increased carbon dioxide (CO2) mixing ratios, or by increased CH4 emission fluxes. The CH4 emission flux perturbation leads to a large increase of CH4 mixing ratios. Remarkably, the factor by which the CH4 mixing ratio increases is larger than the increase factor of the emission flux, because the atmospheric lifetime of CH4 is extended. In contrast, the individual effect of the global surface air temperature (GSAT) increase is to shorten the CH4 lifetime, which results in a significant reduction of CH4 mixing ratios in our setup. The corresponding radiative feedback is estimated at -0.041 W/m2/K and -0.089 W/m2/K for the CO2 and CH4 perturbation, respectively. The explicit adaption of CH4 mixing ratios leads to secondary feedbacks of the hydroxyl radical (OH) and ozone (O3). Firstly, the OH response includes the CH4-OH feedback, which enhances the CH4 lifetime change, and, secondly, the formation of tropospheric O3 is reduced. Our CH4 perturbation induces the same response of GSAT per effective radiative forcing (ERF) as the CO2 perturbation, which supports the applicability of the ERF framework for CH4.</description>
      <author>Laura Stecher, Franziska Frank, Patrick J&#246;ckel, Michael Ponater, Mariano Mertens, M. Dameris</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2938</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Active Learning and DFT for Fast-Tracking Single-Atom Alloy Catalysts in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-Fuel Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11695</link>
      <description>Xin Song, Pengxin Pu, Haisong Feng, Hu Ding, Yuan Deng, Zhen Ge, Sylvia Zhao, Tianyong Liu, Yusen Yang, Min Wei, Xin Zhang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403050550

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (CO</description>
      <author>Xin Song, Pengxin Pu, Haisong Feng, Hu Ding, Yuan Deng, Zhen Ge, Sylvia Zhao, Tianyong Liu, Yusen Yang, Min Wei, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light-Activated Artificial CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Reductase: Structure and Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08927</link>
      <description>Rapha&#235;l J. Labidi, Bruno Faivre, Philippe Carpentier, Julien P&#233;rard, Philipp Gotico, Yun Li, Mohamed Atta, Marc Fontecave, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403027660

                Light-dependent reduction of carbon dioxide (CO</description>
      <author>Rapha&#235;l J. Labidi, Bruno Faivre, Philippe Carpentier, Julien P&#233;rard, Philipp Gotico, Yun Li, Mohamed Atta, Marc Fontecave</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Analysis of a Renovation Project for Old Housing in Tashkent to Reduce Greenhouse Gas Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202457405007</link>
      <description>Elyor Makhmudov, Anna Zavaleeva, Ilya Zavaleev, Akmal Berdimurodov, E3S Web of Conferences. 574(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403048210

                The shift towards economic decarbonization through the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions has led to a focus on renovating and modernizing the existing buildings rather than constructing new ones. This research emphasizes the critical differences between the construction of new buildings and the modernization of the existing structures, specifically in the context of Uzbekistan. The country lacks a comprehensive methodology for accounting for the embodied carbon of building materials used in modernization projects. This research aims to bridge this gap by conducting a life cycle analysis (LCA) of a project focused on enhancing the thermal performance of the enclosing structures of a three to five-story multifamily residential building, commonly referred to as &#8220;Khrushchevka&#8221;. The analysis found that retrofitting buildings reduced greenhouse gas emissions by 13.5% through improved energy efficiency, despite the increase in initial emissions associated with the production and installation of insulation materials. The total reduction in carbon emissions over the entire life cycle of the reconstructed building was 24% (or 43.2 tons of CO&#8322;), including emissions associated with the production of insulation. The payback period for emissions, which offsets the initial emissions during reconstruction, is 17 years.</description>
      <author>Elyor Makhmudov, Anna Zavaleeva, Ilya Zavaleev, Akmal Berdimurodov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202457405007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Land Use and Land Cover Changes on Biomass and Carbon Sequestration in Coastal Kinondoni, Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i104498</link>
      <description>Luzabeth J. Kitali, Adili Y. Zella, International Journal of Environment and Climate Change. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403137310

                This study analyzes the impact of land use and land cover (LULC) alterations on biomass depletion and carbon sequestration in Kinondoni, Tanzania, over a 30-year period from 1993 to 2023. This study employs the National Forest Resources Monitoring and Assessment (NAFORMA) models and geospatial analysis to quantify the environmental and economic effects of urbanization, agricultural growth, and infrastructural development on local ecosystems. The deterioration of mangrove forests, essential for carbon sequestration, has resulted in an estimated biomass reduction of 65,600 tonnes, with mangroves representing 93.1% of the overall losses. This deterioration has markedly diminished the region's carbon storage capacity, leading to the emission of 30,830 tonnes of carbon, which is equivalent to 113,150 tonnes of carbon dioxide (CO&#8322;). The economic impact of this decrease in carbon sequestration capacity is estimated at around US$ 452,610, signifying a lost opportunity for carbon trading. The degradation of mangroves is recognized as the principal cause of these losses. The study highlights the critical necessity for conservation and restoration measures, specifically aimed at mangrove ecosystems, to alleviate additional environmental and economic deterioration. It promotes sustainable land use regulations and the incorporation of ecosystem services valuation in decision-making processes to improve resilience in coastal Tanzania.</description>
      <author>Luzabeth J. Kitali, Adili Y. Zella</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i104498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Sustainable Goals Emissions Reduction Value to Measure Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-7230-2.ch007</link>
      <description>J. Bala Murugan, L. Priya Dharsini, C. Prabakaran, P. S. Ranjit, S. Menaka, R. Senthamil Selvan, Practice, progress, and proficiency in sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403122357

                The Sustainable Development Goals, or SDGs, goal indicators and the steps taken to slow down climate change have trade-offs and synergies. Although some research has evaluated these linkages, nothing is known about how much of an interaction there is. This section illustrates how reducing CO2 emissions relates to the SDGs. They created the &#8220;marginal SDG-emissions-reduction values (MSVs),&#8221; which show how a unit decrease in CO2 emissions affects certain SDG indicators on a marginal basis. This measure was utilised and may be used for national evaluations. They discovered significant correlations between rates of CO2 emission reduction and several SDG objectives. For example, a 1% reduction in CO2 may save 0.57% of premature deaths linked to air pollution (SDG3), whereas the same CO2 reduction can result in a 0.026% drop in mean species richness (SDG15) (excluding the effects of climate change). Our results help evaluate the implications of CO2 emissions reduction objectives for the SDGs, which will assist in informing national climate strategies.</description>
      <author>J. Bala Murugan, L. Priya Dharsini, C. Prabakaran, P. S. Ranjit, S. Menaka, R. Senthamil Selvan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-7230-2.ch007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of climate change on phenology, yield, and water productivity of wheat in a semi-arid region of India using the CERES-Wheat model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2166/wcc.2024.139</link>
      <description>Himani Bisht, S.S. Punia, Bipin Kumar, Jitendra Rajput, D. K. Singh, Lata Vishnoi, Rajvir Singh, Manisha Tamta, Shweta Gautam, Journal of Water and Climate Change. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403026224

                ABSTRACT In the present study, the Crop Environment Resource Synthesis (CERES)-Wheat model was used to study the impacts of climate change on phenology, yield, and water productivity of wheat. The model was run with the baseline period (1980&#8211;2010) and three future periods, namely, the 2030s, 2050s, and 2070s under two representative concentration pathway (RCP) scenarios, namely, RCP 4.5 and RCP 8.5. The results indicated a substantial decline in phenology, grain yield, biomass, and crop water productivity (CWP) under both scenarios. The grain yield of wheat showed a decline by 12.3, 20.5, and 19.8% during the 2030s, 2050s, and 2070s, respectively, under RCP 4.5 at baseline CO2 concentration, while at elevated concentration of CO2, the reduction was 10.2, 15.7, and 14.9%, respectively. Under RCP 8.5, the yield reduction was 18.8, 26.5, and 27.3% during the 2030s, 2050s, and 2070s, respectively, with baseline concentration of CO2, while with increased CO2 the yield reduction was 7, 12.6, and 8.9%, respectively. CWP decreased at baseline CO2 by 9, 17.6, and 18.3% for RCP 4.5 and 10.6, 20.6, and 22.6% for RCP 8.5 during the 2030s, 2050s, and 2070s, respectively. However, beneficial impact of CO2 fertilization on CWP was noticed in both RCP scenarios, resulting in relatively less reduction under future CO2 concentration.</description>
      <author>Himani Bisht, S.S. Punia, Bipin Kumar, Jitendra Rajput, D. K. Singh, Lata Vishnoi, Rajvir Singh, Manisha Tamta, Shweta Gautam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2166/wcc.2024.139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrokinetic Analysis&#8208;Driven Promotion of Electrocatalytic CO Reduction to n&#8208;Propanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406345</link>
      <description>Yaqin Yan, Kunhao Liu, Chao Yang, Yangshen Chen, Ximeng Lv, Cejun Hu, Lijuan Zhang, Gengfeng Zheng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403109751

                Abstract The electrocatalytic carbon dioxide or carbon monoxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR or CORR) features a sustainable method for reducing carbon emissions and producing value&#8208;added chemicals. However, the generation of C 3 products with higher energy density and market values, such as n&#8208;propanol, remains highly challenging, which is attributed to the unclear formation mechanism of C 3+ versus C 2 products. In this work, by the Tafel slope analysis, electrolyte pH correlation exploration, and the kinetic analysis of CO partial pressure fitting, it is identified that both n&#8208;propanol and C 2 products share the same rate&#8208;determining step, which is the coupling of two C 1 intermediates via the derivation of the Butler&#8211;Volmer equation. In addition, inspired by the mechanistic study, it is proposed that a high OH &#9472; concentration and a water&#8208;limited environment are beneficial for promoting the subsequent *C 2 &#8211;*C 1 coupling to n&#8208;propanol. At 5.0 m [OH &#8722; ], the partial current density of producing n&#8208;propanol ( j n&#8208;propanol ) reached 45 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is 35 and 1.3 times higher than that at 0.01 m [OH &#8722; ] and 1.0 m [OH &#8722; ], respectively. This study provides a comprehensive kinetic analysis of n&#8208;propanol production and suggests opportunities for designing new catalytic systems for promoting the C 3 production.</description>
      <author>Yaqin Yan, Kunhao Liu, Chao Yang, Yangshen Chen, Ximeng Lv, Cejun Hu, Lijuan Zhang, Gengfeng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamical channel coupling in strong-field ionization of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1364/oe.537980</link>
      <description>Yalei Zhu, Zeyu Jiang, Zhongxue Ren, Guangru Bai, Xiaowei Wang, Dongwen Zhang, Jinlei Liu, Jing Zhao, Zengxiu Zhao, Optics Express. 32(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403065622

                We present a theoretical study employing the time-dependent density functional theory (TDDFT) to explore the effects of angle-resolved channel coupling in strong field ionization of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) molecules. Our results reveal significant angular sensitivity of both the channel-resolved ionization probabilities and the effects of laser-induced channel couplings. By applying a linearly polarized two-color field scheme, we demonstrate the ability to significantly modify the strength of the laser-induced coupling, evidenced by the changes in the population distributions among the ionic states induced by the strong-field ionization. Importantly, the two-color field optimally modulates the coupling strength at the alignment angle where ionization of the highest occupied molecular orbital (HOMO) electrons is most efficient. This optimization is attributed to the reduction of the electron shielding effect. Our research provides valuable insights into the coherent manipulation of electron distribution within the cation, paving the way for the precise control of ultrafast electron dynamics during strong-field ionization processes.</description>
      <author>Yalei Zhu, Zeyu Jiang, Zhongxue Ren, Guangru Bai, Xiaowei Wang, Dongwen Zhang, Jinlei Liu, Jing Zhao, Zengxiu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1364/oe.537980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Energy Management System for Generator&#8211;Battery Hybrid Power System in Ships: A Novel Approach with Optimal Control Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12101755</link>
      <description>EunMi Choi, Heemoon Kim, Journal of Marine Science and Engineering. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403112671

                Advancements in the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions from ships are driving the development of more efficient onboard power systems. The proposed non-equivalent parallel running operation system is explored in this study, which improves the efficiency of the main power generation source compared with traditional equal load-sharing methods used in power management systems. However, the asymmetric method reduces the efficiency of the auxiliary power sources. To address this issue, we propose a control method that integrates a battery system with an efficiency-based algorithm to optimize the overall system performance. The proposed approach involves establishing operation command values based on the characteristics of the power generation source and adjusting these commands according to the battery&#8217;s state of charge (SOC). MATLAB/Simulink simulations confirmed the effectiveness of this method across various operating modes and revealed no operational issues. When applied to a ship&#8217;s operating profile over 222 h, the method reduced fuel consumption by approximately 2.98 tons (5.57%) compared with conventional systems. Over 38 annual voyages, this reduction equates to savings of 115.96 tons of fuel or approximately 96.47 million Korean won. This study demonstrates that integrating an optimal efficiency algorithm into the energy management system significantly enhances both the propulsion and overall energy efficiency of ships.</description>
      <author>EunMi Choi, Heemoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12101755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of procurement activities in reducing the hydrocarbon footprint in the Arctic zone of the Russian Federation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24147/1812-3988.2024.22(1).50-60</link>
      <description>Alexandra A. Saitova, Enver R. Dzhemilev, Tatyana P. Bozhikova, Herald of Omsk University Series Economics. 22(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402993335

                One of the main tasks of the modern energy industry is not only to maximize the efficient use of natural energy resources and preserve their diversity, but also to increase the potential of this sector in the stable growth of the state's economy, improving the quality of life of the population and maintaining a favorable environmental situation in the country. Decarbonization, which implies a reduction in carbon dioxide (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) and methane emissions, is a key challenge facing the global energy industry. The purpose of this study is to assess greenhouse gas emissions produced as a result of the activities of the largest energy companies operating in the Arctic zone of the Russian Federation, namely PJSC LUKOIL and PJSC NOVATEK through the analysis of their policies and measures to reduce the carbon footprint, preserve biological diversity and develop the northern region of Russia, identify links between the conduct of procurement activities and support for the sustainable development of the enterprise, including in the environmental field. In the course of the work, a comparative analysis of the activities of companies in the Arctic zone was carried out, their current and prospective projects were described, data on greenhouse gas emissions of the enterprises in question were structured by year, their procurement policy, the necessary requirements for potential suppliers, implemented educational programs and activities for the development of professional skills of personnel were considered, and additional tools were proposed that they will be able to contribute not only to improving the sustainable development of companies in the Arctic, but also, as a result, conservation of natural diversity in the northern part of the Russian Federation.</description>
      <author>Alexandra A. Saitova, Enver R. Dzhemilev, Tatyana P. Bozhikova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24147/1812-3988.2024.22(1).50-60</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biochemistry of Artificial CO2-Fixation Pathways: The Exploitation of Carboxylase Enzymes Alternative to Rubisco</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100679</link>
      <description>Immacolata Tommasi, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403006956

                The last decade has registered a rapid development of new artificial CO2-bioconversion processes mirroring natural CO2-fixation by carboxylation and/or reduction reactions. The development of artificial pathways has shown that we have sufficient tools to design and implement, both in vitro and in vivo, complex reaction sequences pointing to construct microbial cell-factories to produce target chemicals at scale. This review is aimed to focus on the most efficient artificial CO2-fixing autotrophic cycles based on the use of carboxylase enzymes that, similarly to Rubisco enzyme, build a C&#8211;CO2 bond by reacting an enediolate or an enolate anion with CO2. The development of artificial CO2-fixing autotrophic cycles encompasses the analysis of the complete library of natural carboxylase enzymes taking part in the so called &#8220;central&#8221; and &#8220;assimilation&#8221; metabolism to select only those enzymes characterized by high catalytic efficiency, great stability, high substrate affinity, and oxygen tolerability. The review analyzes the biochemistry of the most efficient artificial CO2-fixation pathways implemented up today, evidencing the biosynthetic strategies adopted, the development of replenishing routes, and their integration with cell metabolism.</description>
      <author>Immacolata Tommasi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100679</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Approach for Improving Flame Retardancy of Automotive Interior Upholstery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21605/cukurovaumfd.1559895</link>
      <description>&#214;zlem Erdem Y&#305;lmaz, Ali Can Y&#305;lmaz, Ahmet &#199;o&#351;gun, &#199;ukurova &#220;niversitesi M&#252;hendislik Fak&#252;ltesi Dergisi. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403074905

                This study presents the flame retardant (FR) performance of chemically treated automotive upholstery fabrics using two different impregnation methods of Resin Transfer Molding (RTM) and supercritical carbon dioxide (scCO2). Referring to the related standards, untreated seat fabric obtained from seat upholstery of a bus (neat fabric, NF) and treated fabric samples underwent burning rate (BR) and limiting oxygen index (LOI) tests to compare effect of treatment and impregnation methods on FR performance. Thermal analysis was also conducted on the samples considering onset degradation temperatures and char yields. The results showed that BR and LOI of all samples were in acceptable range and treatment provided enhancement in FR performance of NF. The treated sample using scCO2 method gave the highest LOI value of 32% and the lowest BR of 21 mm/min subtending to 18.5% increase in LOI and 30% reduction in BR compared to those of NF. The performance of treatment in RTM was worse than that of scCO2 and better than that of NF. The results confirm that both treatment and methods used in this study give promising results for safety against fire in transportation vehicles.</description>
      <author>&#214;zlem Erdem Y&#305;lmaz, Ali Can Y&#305;lmaz, Ahmet &#199;o&#351;gun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21605/cukurovaumfd.1559895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption and Catalytic Reduction of Nitrogen Oxides (NO, N2O) on Disulfide Cluster Complexes of Cobalt and Iron&#8212;A Density Functional Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17194764</link>
      <description>Ellie L. Uzunova, Ivelina Georgieva, Materials. 17(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402990736

                The reactivity of nitrogen oxide, NO, as a ligand in complexes with [Fe2-S2] and [Co2-S2] non-planar rhombic cores is examined by density functional theory (DFT). The cobalt-containing nitrosyl complexes are less stable than the iron complexes because the Co-S bonds in the [Co2-S2] core are weakened upon NO coordination. Various positions of NO were examined, including its binding to sulfur centers. The release of NO molecules can be monitored photochemically. The ability of NO to form a (NO)2 dimer provides a favorable route of electrochemical reduction, as protonation significantly stabilizes the dimeric species over the monomers. The quasilinear dimer ONNO, with trans-orientation of oxygen atoms, gains higher stability under protonation and reduction via proton&#8211;electron transfer. The first two reduction steps lead to an N2O intermediate, whose reduction is more energy demanding: in the two latter reaction steps the highest energy barrier for Co2S2(CO)6 is 109 kJ mol&#8722;1, and for Fe2S2(CO)6, it is 133 kJ mol&#8722;1. Again, the presence of favorable light absorption bands allows for a photochemical route to overcome these energy barriers. All elementary steps are exothermic, and the final products are molecular nitrogen and water.</description>
      <author>Ellie L. Uzunova, Ivelina Georgieva</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17194764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Evaluation of CO2 + SiCl4 Binary Mixture in Recompression Brayton Cycle for Warm Climates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102155</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ehtisham Siddiqui, Khalid H. Almitani, Processes. 12(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403106930

                This work demonstrates the potential of CO2 + SiCl4 binary mixture as a working fluid for power generation cycle. Recompression Brayton cycle configuration is considered due to its proven record of high performance for medium- to high-temperature sources. The objective of this study is to assess the thermodynamic performance of a recompression Brayton cycle using a CO2 + SiCl4 binary mixture as a working fluid, particularly under warm climate conditions. The cycle is simulated using the Peng&#8211;Robinson equation of state in Aspen Hysys (v11) software, and the model is validated by comparing VLE data against experimental data from the literature. The analysis involves the assessment of cycle&#8217;s thermal efficiency and exergy efficiency under warm climatic conditions, with a minimum cycle temperature of 40 &#176;C. The results demonstrate a notable improvement in the cycle&#8217;s thermodynamic performance with CO2 + SiCl4 binary mixture compared to pure CO2. A small concentration (5%) of SiCl4 in CO2 increases the thermal efficiency of the cycle from 41.7% to 43.4%. Moreover, irreversibility losses in the cooler and the heat recovery unit are significantly lower with the CO2 + SiCl4 binary mixture than with pure CO2. This improvement enhances the overall exergy efficiency of the cycle, increasing it from 62.1% to 70.2%. The primary reason for this enhancement is the substantial reduction in irreversibility losses in both the cooler and the HTR. This study reveals that when using a CO2 + SiCl4 mixture, the concentration must be optimized to avoid condensation in the compressor, which can cause physical damage to the compressor blades and other components, as well as increase power input. This issue arises from the higher glide temperature of the mixture at increased SiCl4 concentrations and the limited heat recovery from the cycle.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ehtisham Siddiqui, Khalid H. Almitani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12102155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic CO2 Reduction to CO Catalysed by Lanthanide Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc03175j</link>
      <description>Yingzhe Zhao, Jianling Zhang, Haoxiang Wang, Renjie Zhang, Yunan Teng, Meiling Li, Yi Song, Zhonghao Tan, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403005889

                Here we demonstrate the efficient CO2 reduction to CO catalysed by lanthanide-based complexes under light irradiation, by which the highest CO evolution rate can reach 78&#177;8 &#956;mol g-1 h-1 in...</description>
      <author>Yingzhe Zhao, Jianling Zhang, Haoxiang Wang, Renjie Zhang, Yunan Teng, Meiling Li, Yi Song, Zhonghao Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc03175j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Climate Change on Plant Parasitic Nematodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69860/nobel.9786053359449.12</link>
      <description>Bet&#252;l G&#220;RKAN, Tolga G&#220;RKAN, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403108794

                Climate change is defined as permanent changes in the Earth&#8217;s weather conditions, such as temperature, precipitation, and wind. The main impacts of climate change include global warming, increase in weather events, sea level rise, damage to ecosystems, melting of glaciers, negative impacts on agriculture, water resources and human health. The biology and physiology of plant parasitic nematodes are regulated by environmental factors, (such as temperature, humidity, precipitation, and soil CO2 levels). which is one of the indicators of climate change. Climate change weather extremes such as increased temperature due to global warming, drought, forest fires, high CO2 conditions, increased rainfall, humidity conditions and storms affect the biodiversity, distribution, reproduction, survival and parasitic potential of plant parasitic nematodes. Since changes in CO2, temperature and precipitation levels caused by climate change will increase the proliferation, distribution and damage potential of plant parasitic nematode populations, there is a need to develop appropriate strategies for the control of nematodes that will be effective in situations of global warming in order to prevent significant reductions in crop yields in the future.</description>
      <author>Bet&#252;l G&#220;RKAN, Tolga G&#220;RKAN</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69860/nobel.9786053359449.12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regional impacts of solar radiation modification on surface temperature and precipitation in Mainland Southeast Asia and the adjacent oceans</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-73149-6</link>
      <description>Pornampai Narenpitak, Siriwat Kongkulsiri, Saifhon Tomkratoke, Sirod Sirisup, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402982875

                Solar radiation modification (SRM) has been proposed to temporarily reduce anthropogenic warming. This study presents an assessment of the regional impacts of SRM via solar dimming and stratospheric aerosol injection (SAI) on temperature and precipitation over 0&#176;-30&#176; N and 90&#176; E-110&#176; E, covering Mainland Southeast Asia and adjacent oceans. Using data from the Geoengineering Model Intercomparison Project Phase 6 (GeoMIP6), we examine regional impacts of SRM using three SRM experiments: (1) G6Sulfur, which reduces radiative forcing from the high-emission SSP5-8.5 scenario to the moderate-emission SSP2-4.5 scenario by injecting sulfate aerosols; (2) G6Solar, which similarly reduces radiative forcing from the high-emission to moderate-emission scenarios but by uniformly reducing the solar constant; and (3) G1ext, which reduces radiative forcing from a quadrupled carbon dioxide concentration to pre-industrial levels by uniform solar constant reduction. Our findings show that higher greenhouse gas emissions increase overall precipitation, along with tendencies to have extreme rainfall events and more dry episodes in between. While SRM can partially cool down the surface temperature warming caused by increased greenhouse gas emissions, its effects on precipitation are complex: Solar dimming in G6Solar and G1ext tends to reduce overall precipitation, and tropical sulfate injection in G6Sulfur could lead to further drying in the tropics because of the stratospheric warming associated with the injected aerosols. Different SRM strategies might result in different responses on precipitation.</description>
      <author>Pornampai Narenpitak, Siriwat Kongkulsiri, Saifhon Tomkratoke, Sirod Sirisup</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-73149-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Exhaust Emissions in Older Vehicles in the Era of New Technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17194924</link>
      <description>Maksymilian M&#261;dziel, Energies. 17(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403027898

                In response to increasing environmental demands, modeling emissions from older vehicles presents a significant challenge. This paper introduces an innovative methodology that takes advantage of advanced AI and machine learning techniques to develop precise emission models for older vehicles. This study analyzed data from road tests and the OBDII diagnostic interface, focusing on CO2, CO, THC, and NOx emissions under both cold and warm engine conditions. The key results showed that random forest regression provided the best predictions for THC in a cold engine (R2: 0.76), while polynomial regression excelled for CO2 (R2: 0.93). For warm engines, polynomial regression performed best for CO2 (R2: 0.95), and gradient boosting delivered results for THC (R2: 0.66). Although prediction accuracy varied by emission compound and engine state, the models consistently demonstrated high precision, offering a robust tool for managing emissions from aging vehicle fleets. These models offer valuable information for transportation policy and pollution reduction strategies, particularly in urban areas.</description>
      <author>Maksymilian M&#261;dziel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17194924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A-124 Sustainable Transport: Assessing Environmental Impact in Medical Sample Transit via Drones and Vehicles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.123</link>
      <description>Noel Rouven Stierlin, A Hemmerle, Martin Risch, Lorenz Risch, Clinical Chemistry. 70(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403071790

                Abstract Background This research explores the ecological implications associated with different methods of transporting medical samples, specifically focusing on drones, combustion cars, and electric cars within two laboratories in central European countries. With the primary goal of assessing and comparing CO2 consumption, delivery time, and overall environmental impact, the study aims to provide a basis for adopting sustainable practices in healthcare logistics. Methods The transportation of medical samples occurred between two laboratories in the Principality of Liechtenstein and Switzerland, utilizing authorized aerial and road routes. Various weather conditions and distances were considered for sample transports using different vehicles (8 combustion cars, two electric cars, and one drone model). Energy consumption was documented, and the CO2 footprint was calculated based on data from the Swiss Federal Office for the Environment (FOEN) for both imported and renewable electricity. Comparative analyses were conducted to quantify the environmental impact of each transportation method. Results In terms of CO2 footprint, combustion cars exhibited a CO2 release of 159.5 g/km, while electric cars showed 3.43g (2.15 to 4.08% of combustion cars). Drones demonstrated a minimal 0.09g CO2 emission per kilometer (0.066% of combustion car CO2 emission; 2.6% of electric car CO2 emission). The distance traveled by drones was significantly shorter (16.7% to 50%). Additionally, the efficiency of drone transport was emphasized by its ability to avoid traffic jams and associated detours, resulting in time savings ranging from 31.25 to 50% per delivery when comparing transport times during rush hour and regular hours in the selected setting. Conclusions The integration of drone technology emerges as a crucial strategy for establishing a &#8220;green laboratory.&#8221; The substantial reduction in CO2 emissions and enhanced delivery efficiency position drone transport as a sustainable and operationally effective solution for medical sample logistics, offering shorter delivery times. These findings highlight the potential for transformative change in healthcare logistics, aligning with the global shift towards sustainability and green practices.</description>
      <author>Noel Rouven Stierlin, A Hemmerle, Martin Risch, Lorenz Risch</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Drought Impacts on Gross Primary Productivity of Rubber Plantations Using Flux Observations and Remote Sensing in China and Thailand</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/f15101732</link>
      <description>Weiguang Li, Meiting Hou, Shaojun Liu, Jinghong Zhang, Haiping Zou, Xiaomin Chen, Rui Bai, Run Lv, Wei Hou, Forests. 15(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402995540

                Rubber (Hevea brasiliensis Muell.) plantations are vital agricultural ecosystems in tropical regions. These plantations provide key industrial raw materials and sequester large amounts of carbon dioxide, playing a vital role in the global carbon cycle. Climate change has intensified droughts in Southeast Asia, negatively affecting rubber plantation growth. Limited in situ observations and short monitoring periods hinder accurate assessment of drought impacts on the gross primary productivity (GPP) of rubber plantations. This study used GPP data from flux observations at four rubber plantation sites in China and Thailand, along with solar-induced chlorophyll fluorescence (SIF), enhanced vegetation index (EVI), normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), near-infrared reflectance of vegetation (NIRv), and photosynthetically active radiation (PAR) indices, to develop a robust GPP estimation model. The model reconstructed eight-day interval GPP data from 2001 to 2020 for the four sites. Finally, the study analyzed the seasonal drought impacts on GPP in these four regions. The results indicate that the GPP prediction model developed using SIF, EVI, NDVI, NIRv, and PAR has high accuracy and robustness. The model&#8217;s predictions have a relative root mean square error (rRMSE) of 0.22 compared to flux-observed GPP, with smaller errors in annual GPP predictions than the MOD17A3HGF model, thereby better reflecting the interannual variability in the GPP of rubber plantations. Drought significantly affects rubber plantation GPP, with impacts varying by region and season. In China and northern Thailand (NR site), short-term (3 months) and long-term (12 months) droughts during cool and warm dry seasons cause GPP declines of 4% to 29%. Other influencing factors may alleviate or offset GPP reductions caused by drought. During the rainy season across all four regions and the cool dry season with adequate rainfall in southern Thailand (SR site), mild droughts have negligible effects on GPP and may even slightly increase GPP values due to enhanced PAR. Overall, the study shows that drought significantly impacts rubber the GPP of rubber plantations, with effects varying by region and season. When assessing drought&#8217;s impact on rubber plantation GPP or carbon sequestration, it is essential to consider differences in drought thresholds within the climatic context.</description>
      <author>Weiguang Li, Meiting Hou, Shaojun Liu, Jinghong Zhang, Haiping Zou, Xiaomin Chen, Rui Bai, Run Lv, Wei Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/f15101732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Effect of Ionic Liquid Conformation on the Selective CO2 Capture of Supported Ionic Liquid-Phase Adsorbents Based on ZIFs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17194829</link>
      <description>Charitomeni M. Veziri, George V. Theodorakopoulos, K. Beltsios, George E. Romanos, Materials. 17(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402983609

                The CO2 adsorption capacity and the CO2/N2 selectivity of a series of Supported Ionic Liquid-Phase adsorbents (SILPs), including the novel inversely structured SILP &#8220;Inverse SILPs&#8221;, are thoroughly investigated. ZIF-8, ZIF-69 and ZIF-70 were involved as the solid matrix, while ILs, having tricyanomethanide (TCM) as an anion and alkyl-methylimidazolium of different alkyl chain lengths (C2, C6, C8) as a cation, were used as the liquid constituents of the SILPs. The ultimate target of the work was to ratify a few recently reported cases of enhanced CO2 absorptivity in ILs due to their incorporation in ZIFs and to corroborate phenomena of CO2/N2 selectivity improvements in ZIFs, due to the presence of ILs. This ambiguity originates from the vague assumption that the pores of the ZIF are filled with the IL phase, and the free pore volume of a SILP is almost zero. Yet, through the integration of theoretical predictions with N2 porosimetry analysis of an actual sample, it is suggested that a thin layer of IL covered the exterior surface of a ZIF crystal. This layer could act as an impermeable barrier for N2, inhibiting the gas molecules from reaching the empty cavities laying underneath the liquid film during porosimetry analysis. This consideration is based on the fact that the solubility of N2 in the IL is very low, and the diffusivity at 77 K is negligible. In this context, the observed result reflects an averaged adsorptivity of both the IL phase and the empty pores of the ZIF. Therefore, it is incorrect to attribute the adsorption capacity of the SILP solely to the mass of the IL that &#8216;hypothetically&#8217; nests inside the pore cavities. In fact, the CO2 adsorption capacity of SILPs is always less than the average adsorptivity of an ideal ZIF/IL mixture, where the two phases do not interact. This reduction occurs because some ZIF pores may become inaccessible, particularly when the IL forms a layer on the pore walls, leaving only a small empty core accessible to CO2 molecules. Additionally, the IL layer masks the active sites on the ZIF&#8217;s pore walls. It should also be noted that the CO2/N2 selectivity increases only when the ZIF&#8217;s pores are completely filled with the IL phase. This is because ILs have a higher CO2/N2 selectivity compared to the bare ZIF.</description>
      <author>Charitomeni M. Veziri, George V. Theodorakopoulos, K. Beltsios, George E. Romanos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17194829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two&#8208;Dimensional Silver&#8211;Isocyanide Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417658</link>
      <description>Kaiyue Jiang, Pu Yan, Pengfei Shi, Jichao Zhang, Xinyu Chai, Li Wang, Chenhui Zhu, Chongqing Yang, Chenbao Lu, Yi Liu, Kecheng Cao, Xiaodong Zhuang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403024022

                Metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) have been widely studied due to their versatile applications and easily tunable structures. However, heteroatom&#8208;metal coordination dominates the MOFs community, and the rational synthesis of carbon&#8211;metal coordination&#8208;based MOFs remains a significant challenge. Herein, two&#8208;dimensional (2D) MOFs based on silver&#8211;carbon linkages are synthesized through the coordination between silver(I) salt and isocyanide&#8208;based monomers at ambient condition. The as&#8208;synthesized 2D MOFs possess well&#8208;defined crystalline structures and a staggered AB stacking mode. Most interestingly, these 2D MOFs, without &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking between layers, exhibit narrow bandgaps down to 1.42 eV. As electrochemical catalysts for converting CO2 to CO, such 2D MOFs demonstrate Faradaic efficiency over 92%. Surprisingly, the CO2 reduction catalyzed by these MOFs indicates favorable adsorption of CO2 and *COOH on the active carbon sites of the isocyanide groups rather than on silver sites. This is attributed to the critical &#963; donor role of isocyanides and the corresponding ligand&#8208;to&#8208;metal charge&#8211;transfer effect. This work not only paves the way toward a new family of MOFs based on metal&#8211;isocyanide coordination but also offers a rare platform for understanding the electrocatalysis processes on strongly polarized carbon species.</description>
      <author>Kaiyue Jiang, Pu Yan, Pengfei Shi, Jichao Zhang, Xinyu Chai, Li Wang, Chenhui Zhu, Chongqing Yang, Chenbao Lu, Yi Liu, Kecheng Cao, Xiaodong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two&#8208;Dimensional Silver&#8211;Isocyanide Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417658</link>
      <description>Kaiyue Jiang, Pu Yan, Pengfei Shi, Jichao Zhang, Xinyu Chai, Li Wang, Chenhui Zhu, Chongqing Yang, Chenbao Lu, Yi Liu, Kecheng Cao, Xiaodong Zhuang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403080791

                Metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) have been widely studied due to their versatile applications and easily tunable structures. However, heteroatom&#8208;metal coordination dominates the MOFs community, and the rational synthesis of carbon&#8211;metal coordination&#8208;based MOFs remains a significant challenge. Herein, two&#8208;dimensional (2D) MOFs based on silver&#8211;carbon linkages are synthesized through the coordination between silver(I) salt and isocyanide&#8208;based monomers at ambient condition. The as&#8208;synthesized 2D MOFs possess well&#8208;defined crystalline structures and a staggered AB stacking mode. Most interestingly, these 2D MOFs, without &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking between layers, exhibit narrow bandgaps down to 1.42 eV. As electrochemical catalysts for converting CO2 to CO, such 2D MOFs demonstrate Faradaic efficiency over 92%. Surprisingly, the CO2 reduction catalyzed by these MOFs indicates favorable adsorption of CO2 and *COOH on the active carbon sites of the isocyanide groups rather than on silver sites. This is attributed to the critical &#963; donor role of isocyanides and the corresponding ligand&#8208;to&#8208;metal charge&#8211;transfer effect. This work not only paves the way toward a new family of MOFs based on metal&#8211;isocyanide coordination but also offers a rare platform for understanding the electrocatalysis processes on strongly polarized carbon species.</description>
      <author>Kaiyue Jiang, Pu Yan, Pengfei Shi, Jichao Zhang, Xinyu Chai, Li Wang, Chenhui Zhu, Chongqing Yang, Chenbao Lu, Yi Liu, Kecheng Cao, Xiaodong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How teacher behaviors and perceptions, air change rates, and portable air purifiers affect indoor air quality in naturally ventilated schools</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2024.1427116</link>
      <description>Tian Xia, Julia Raneses, Brixon Schmiesing, Raquel Garc&#237;a&#8208;Esteban, Alison Walding, Richardo DeMajo, Amy J. Schulz, Stuart Batterman, Frontiers in Public Health. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403102704

                Introduction Many school buildings have inadequate ventilation, rudimentary if any air filtration, and aging and poorly maintained mechanical systems, all of which can lead to poor indoor air quality (IAQ). These issues are especially acute in environmental justice (EJ) communities where schools are located in polluted areas. This community-based participatory research examines how IAQ in naturally ventilated school buildings is affected by the use of air purifiers, air change rates, outdoor pollution levels, and teacher and staff behavior. Methods IAQ assessments were performed at two schools in Detroit, Michigan, which included building walk-through inspections and continuous indoor and outdoor measurements of black carbon (BC), particulate matter (PM 10 and PM 2.5 ), carbon dioxide (CO 2 ), air change rates (ACRs), temperature, humidity, and sound pressure levels. Air purifiers with usage monitors were then installed, and the IAQ assessments were repeated. Teachers were surveyed before and after purifier deployment. Results At baseline, classrooms had low ACRs (0.58&#8211;1.38 h &#8722;1 ), moderate PM 2.5 levels (2.8&#8211;8.9 &#956;g/m 3 ), highly variable PM 10 concentrations (4.7&#8211;37.5 &#956;g/m 3 ), and elevated BC levels (0.3&#8211;0.7 &#956;g/m 3 ), reflecting emissions from local traffic, industry and other sources. The installation and use of purifiers reduced pollutant levels and the overall performance matched the predictions of a single compartment model. However, daily reductions varied widely among classrooms, reflecting differences in teacher behavior regarding the frequency of opening windows and the operation of purifiers, including differences in purifier fan speed settings and whether purifiers were used at night. Survey responses indicated that many teachers were aware of IAQ problems. The higher rates reported for health symptoms and dissatisfaction at one school may have lowered the teachers&#8217; tolerance to noise and reduced purifier use. Discussion The study helps explain the variation reported in prior studies using purifiers, and it reinforces the need to monitor IAQ and purifier use, use enhanced filtration and increase ventilation, and engage with teachers and school staff to support and maintain IAQ programs in schools.</description>
      <author>Tian Xia, Julia Raneses, Brixon Schmiesing, Raquel Garc&#237;a&#8208;Esteban, Alison Walding, Richardo DeMajo, Amy J. Schulz, Stuart Batterman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2024.1427116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Customized Fertilizer Formulations on Brinjal (Solanum melongena L.) under Sodic Soil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/ajsspn/2024/v10i4391</link>
      <description>Sherene Jenita Rajammal, A. Kaleeswari T, S. Maragatham, R. Arulmozhian, Asian Journal of Soil Science and Plant Nutrition. 10(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402991788

                The Customized Fertilizer Formulation (CFF) applications on growth and yield of Brinjal (Solanum melongena L.) varieties Manaparai local and CO-2 under sodic soils were studied with eleven CFF combinations. No Significant observations in growth yield and yield parameter was recorded due to the combined application of CFF and organic amendments on sodic soils. The symptoms of salt injury were well pronounced in brinjal cv. Manaparai local when compared to brinjal cv. CO2 though the sodic soil reclamation was done with gypsum @1.1 t/Ha. The salt injury was further confirmed with electrolyte leakage study conducted at field level. However, the treatment T11 i.e. CFF2 100% macro nutrients as straight fertilizers, liquid micronutrient formulation and composted Press mud @ 5 t/ha was found to have the brinjal fruit yield of 1.39 t/ha in cv. CO2 which was not a desirable yield. This might be due to the yield reduction per unit increase in salt content.</description>
      <author>Sherene Jenita Rajammal, A. Kaleeswari T, S. Maragatham, R. Arulmozhian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.9734/ajsspn/2024/v10i4391</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative study of alternative fuels for sustainable IC engine operation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30574/wjarr.2021.12.1.0407</link>
      <description>BHASKARA, World Journal of Advanced Research and Reviews. 12(1)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4403079034

                The increasing environmental concerns, coupled with the rapid depletion of conventional fossil fuels, have prompted the automotive industry to explore alternative energy sources that can support the continued operation of internal combustion (IC) engines in a more sustainable manner. The need to mitigate greenhouse gas emissions, reduce dependence on finite fossil resources, and meet stringent environmental regulations has led to extensive research and development efforts in identifying viable alternative fuels. These fuels must not only align with the performance requirements of modern IC engines but also minimize their environmental footprint.This paper presents a comprehensive comparative analysis of various alternative fuels, including biodiesel, ethanol, hydrogen, natural gas, and synthetic fuels, each of which offers unique advantages and challenges. The study evaluates these fuels across key parameters, such as fuel availability, energy content, emissions profile, required engine modifications, and overall sustainability. The analysis takes into consideration the economic feasibility and infrastructure requirements for large-scale adoption of each fuel.Furthermore, the paper highlights the technological advancements and modifications necessary to optimize IC engines for these alternative fuels. This includes the impact of alternative fuels on engine efficiency, power output, fuel economy, and maintenance requirements. Special attention is given to emissions reduction strategies, with a focus on how each fuel contributes to lowering carbon dioxide (CO&#8322;), nitrogen oxides (NO&#8339;), and particulate matter (PM) emissions.In addition to evaluating the current state of alternative fuels, the paper addresses the challenges associated with their adoption, including production scalability, distribution infrastructure, and compatibility with existing vehicle technologies. Finally, the future prospects of integrating these fuels into automotive applications are explored, considering the rapid rise of electric vehicles and other emerging technologies that may further influence the role of IC engines in the transition to sustainable transportation.The findings of this study suggest that while no single alternative fuel is likely to fully replace conventional gasoline and diesel in the near future, a combination of fuels, along with continued innovation in fuel production, engine technology, and policy support, will be necessary to achieve sustainable IC engine operation. The paper concludes by outlining the critical research areas and policy initiatives needed to promote the wider adoption of alternative fuels in the automotive sector.</description>
      <author>BHASKARA</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30574/wjarr.2021.12.1.0407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Effect of Crystal Facets and Sulfur Defects on the Product Selectivity of Various CdS Configurations for CO2 Photoreduction: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100688</link>
      <description>Shuai Liu, Jing Wang, Yu Zhong, Leiping Wang, Ding&#8208;Ming Xue, Lei Tong, Honglei Zhang, Tao Wu, Guangsuo Yu, Hang Xiao, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403084362

                CO2 photoreduction into valuable hydrocarbons, such as CO, CH4, and C2H4, delivers a promising approach to address both environmental and energy challenges. Transition metal chalcogenides, particularly cadmium sulfide (CdS), have emerged as prominent candidates due to their tunable electronic properties and availability. This study delves into a comprehensive investigation of how CdS crystalline facets and sulfur-deficient surfaces modulate the product selectivity. Through employing density functional theory (DFT), we unravel the catalytic performance of various CdS crystal orientations and sulfur vacancy configurations. The results have shown that different CdS facets exhibit unique electronic characteristics and surface energetics, which influence the adsorption dynamics and reaction pathways. The introduction of sulfur vacancies further modulates the nature of active sites, leading to substantial shifts in product selectivity. A detailed investigation on the reaction mechanisms unveils that specific facets preferentially facilitate the formation of CO, while others are more conducive to the generation of hydrocarbons such as CH4 and C2H4, due to the variations in activation barriers and intermediate stabilities. These findings underscore the importance of crystal facet engineering and defect manipulation in tailoring catalyst performance thus providing valuable insights for the rational design of efficient and selective CO2 reduction metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shuai Liu, Jing Wang, Yu Zhong, Leiping Wang, Ding&#8208;Ming Xue, Lei Tong, Honglei Zhang, Tao Wu, Guangsuo Yu, Hang Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Adaptation of Active Site Driven by Dual&#8208;side Adsorption in Single&#8208;Atomic Catalysts During CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411765</link>
      <description>Nam V. Tran, Jiyuan Liu, Shuzhou Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403041985

                Single&#8208;atom iron embedded in N&#8208;doped carbon (Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C) is among the most representative single&#8208;atomic catalysts (SACs) for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Despite the simplicity of the active site, the CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO mechanism on Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C remains controversial. Firstly, there is a long debate regarding the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) of the reactions. Secondly, recent computational and experimental studies are puzzled by the fact that the CO&#8208;poisoned Fe centers still remain highly active at high potentials. Thirdly, there are ongoing challenges in elucidating the high selectivity of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) over CO2RR at high potentials. In this work, we introduce a novel CO2RR mechanism on Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C, which was inspired by the dynamic of active sites in biological systems. By employing grand&#8208;canonical density functional theory and kinetic Monte&#8208;Carlo, we found that the RDS is not fixed but changes with the applied potential. We demonstrated that our proposed dual&#8208;side mechanisms could clarify the reason behind the high catalytic activity of CO&#8208;poisoned metal centers, as well as the high selectivity of HER over CO2RR at high potential. This study provides a fundamental explanation for long&#8208;standing puzzles of an important catalyst and calls for the importance of considering the dynamic of active sites in reaction mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Nam V. Tran, Jiyuan Liu, Shuzhou Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Adaptation of Active Site Driven by Dual&#8208;side Adsorption in Single&#8208;Atomic Catalysts During CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411765</link>
      <description>Nam V. Tran, Jiyuan Liu, Shuzhou Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403043003

                Single&#8208;atom iron embedded in N&#8208;doped carbon (Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C) is among the most representative single&#8208;atomic catalysts (SACs) for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Despite the simplicity of the active site, the CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO mechanism on Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C remains controversial. Firstly, there is a long debate regarding the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) of the reactions. Secondly, recent computational and experimental studies are puzzled by the fact that the CO&#8208;poisoned Fe centers still remain highly active at high potentials. Thirdly, there are ongoing challenges in elucidating the high selectivity of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) over CO2RR at high potentials. In this work, we introduce a novel CO2RR mechanism on Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C, which was inspired by the dynamic of active sites in biological systems. By employing grand&#8208;canonical density functional theory and kinetic Monte&#8208;Carlo, we found that the RDS is not fixed but changes with the applied potential. We demonstrated that our proposed dual&#8208;side mechanisms could clarify the reason behind the high catalytic activity of CO&#8208;poisoned metal centers, as well as the high selectivity of HER over CO2RR at high potential. This study provides a fundamental explanation for long&#8208;standing puzzles of an important catalyst and calls for the importance of considering the dynamic of active sites in reaction mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Nam V. Tran, Jiyuan Liu, Shuzhou Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Synthetic Positive Energy District (PED) in &#304;stanbul: Balancing Cost, Mobility, and Environmental Impact</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14103153</link>
      <description>Mi&#775;ne Serts&#246;z, Buildings. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403107776

                The influence of mobility modes within Positive Energy Districts (PEDs) has gained limited attention, despite their crucial role in reducing energy consumption and greenhouse gas emissions. Buildings in the European Union (EU) account for 40% of energy consumption and 36% of greenhouse gas emissions. In comparison, transport contributes 28% of energy use and 25% of emissions, with road transport responsible for 72% of these emissions. This study aims to design and optimize a synthetic PED in Istanbul that integrates renewable energy sources and public mobility systems to address these challenges. The renewable energy sources integrated into the synthetic PED model include solar energy, hydrogen energy, and regenerative braking energy from a tram system. Solar panels provided a substantial portion of the energy, while hydrogen energy contributed to additional electricity generation. Regenerative braking energy from the tram system was also utilized to further optimize energy production within the district. This system powers a middle school, 10 houses, a supermarket, and the tram itself. Optimization techniques, including Linear Programming (LP) for economic purposes and the Weighted Sum Method (WSM) for environmental goals, were applied to balance cost and CO2 emissions. The LP method identified that the PED model can achieve cost competitiveness with conventional energy grids when hydrogen costs are below $93.16/MWh. Meanwhile, the WSM approach demonstrated that achieving a minimal CO2 emission level of 5.74 tons requires hydrogen costs to be $32.55/MWh or lower. Compared to a conventional grid producing 97 tons of CO2 annually, the PED model achieved reductions of up to 91.26 tons. This study contributes to the ongoing discourse on sustainable urban energy systems by addressing key research gaps related to the integration of mobility modes within PEDs and offering insights into the optimization of renewable energy sources for reducing emissions and energy consumption.</description>
      <author>Mi&#775;ne Serts&#246;z</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14103153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewable Energy Credits Transforming Market Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198602</link>
      <description>Bankole I. Oladapo, Mattew A. Olawumi, Francis T. Omigbodun, Sustainability. 16(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403101705

                This research uses advanced statistical methods to examine climate change mitigation policies&#8217; economic and environmental impacts. The primary objective is to assess the effectiveness of carbon pricing, renewable energy subsidies, emission trading schemes, and regulatory standards in reducing CO2 emissions, fostering economic growth, and promoting employment. A mixed-methods approach was employed, combining regression analysis, cost&#8211;benefit analysis (CBA), and computable general equilibrium (CGE) models. Data were collected from national and global databases, and sensitivity analyses were conducted to ensure the robustness of the findings. Key findings revealed a statistically significant reduction in CO2 emissions by 0.45% for each unit increase in carbon pricing (p &lt; 0.01). Renewable energy subsidies were positively correlated with a 3.5% increase in employment in the green sector (p &lt; 0.05). Emission trading schemes were projected to increase GDP by 1.2% over a decade (p &lt; 0.05). However, chi-square tests indicated that carbon pricing disproportionately affects low-income households (p &lt; 0.05), highlighting the need for compensatory policies. The study concluded that a balanced policy mix, tailored to national contexts, can optimise economic and environmental outcomes while addressing social equity concerns. Error margins in GDP projections remained below &#177;0.3%, confirming the models&#8217; reliability.</description>
      <author>Bankole I. Oladapo, Mattew A. Olawumi, Francis T. Omigbodun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16198602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ionomer and Membrane Designs for Low&#8208;Temperature CO2 and CO Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401728</link>
      <description>Huihua Deng, Zhuo Chen, Li Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403146014

                Low&#8208;temperature electroreduction of CO2 and CO (CO(2)RR) into valuable chemicals and fuels offers a promising pathway to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and achieve carbon neutrality. Today's low&#8208;temperature CO(2)RR technology relies on the use of ionomers, polymers with ionized groups, primarily as catalyst layer (CL) additives. In the meantime, ionomers can assemble into ion&#8208;exchange membranes (IEMs), serving as important components of electrolyzers. According to the ion&#8208;exchange functions, ionomer additives are classified as cation&#8208;exchange ionomers (CEIs) and anion&#8208;exchange ionomers (AEIs); similarly, IEMs are divided into cation&#8208;exchange membranes (CEMs) and anion&#8208;exchange membranes (AEMs), as well as the multilayer polymer electrolytes (MPEs). Recent studies show that ionomer additives can regulate the catalytic microenvironment and thereby enhance performance towards desired products. This Review discusses the roles of ionomer additives and IEMs in CO2 and CO reduction reactions, highlighting the latest mechanistic insights and performance advances. It outlines challenges in designing ionomer additives and IEMs to improve product selectivity, energy efficiency (EE), and operational lifetime of CO(2)RR electrolyzers, while also providing perspectives on future research directions. The aim is to connect the current status of ionomer and membrane development with performance metrics analysis, offering insights for the advancement of commercially relevant low&#8208;temperature CO(2)RR electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Huihua Deng, Zhuo Chen, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Conjugated Nickel(II)&#8208;Acetylide Framework for Efficient Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418269</link>
      <description>Yingying Qin, Yang Wang, Jian L&#252;, Linli Xu, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403129176

                The incorporation of transition&#8208;metal single atoms as molecular functional entities into the skeleton of graphdiyne (GDY) to construct novel two&#8208;dimensional (2D) metal&#8208;acetylide frameworks, known as metalated graphynes (MGYs), is a promising strategy for developing efficient catalysts, which can combine the tunable charge transfer of GDY frameworks, the catalytic activity of metal and the precise distribution of single metallic centers. Herein, four highly conjugated MGY photocatalysts based on NiII, PdII, PtII, and HgII were synthesized for the first time using the &#8216;bottom&#8208;up&#8217; strategy through the use of M&#8211;C bonds (&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;M&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;). Remarkably, the NiII&#8208;based graphyne (TEPY&#8208;Ni&#8208;GY) exhibited the highest CO generation rate of 18.3 mmol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1 and a selectivity of 98.8%. This superior performance is attributed to the synergistic effects of pyrenyl and &#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;Ni(PBu3)2&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211; moieties. The pyrenyl block functions as an intramolecular &#960;&#8208;conjugation channel, facilitating kinetically favorable electron transfer, while the &#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211;Ni(PBu3)2&#8211;C&#8801;C&#8211; moiety serves as the catalytic site that enhances CO2 adsorption and activation, thereby suppressing competitive hydrogen evolution. This study provides a new perspective on MGY&#8208;based photocatalysts for developing highly active and low&#8208;cost catalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Yingying Qin, Yang Wang, Jian L&#252;, Linli Xu, Wai&#8208;Yeung Wong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Quantum Mechanical MP2 Study of the Electronic Effect of Nonplanarity on the Carbon Pyramidalization of Fullerene C60</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14191576</link>
      <description>Yuemin Liu, Yunxiang Gao, Tariq Altalhi, Di&#8208;Jia Liu, Boris I. Yakobson, Nanomaterials. 14(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402994082

                Among C60&#8217;s diverse functionalities, its potential application in CO2 sequestration has gained increasing interest. However, the processes involved are sensitive to the molecule&#8217;s electronic structure, aspects of which remain debated and require greater precision. To address this, we performed structural optimization of fullerene C60 using the QM MP2/6&#8211;31G* method. The nonplanarity of the optimized icosahedron is characterized by two types of dihedral angles: 138&#176; and 143&#176;. The 120 dihedrals of 138&#176; occur between two hexagons intersecting at C&#8211;C bonds of 1.42 &#197;, while the 60 dihedrals of 143&#176; are observed between hexagons and pentagons at C&#8211;C bonds of 1.47 &#197;. NBO analysis reveals less pyramidal sp1.78 hybridization for carbons at the 1.42 &#197; bonds and more pyramidal sp2.13 hybridization for the 1.47 &#197; bonds. Electrostatic potential charges range from &#8722;0.04 a.u. to 0.04 a.u. on the carbon atoms. Second-order perturbation analysis indicates that delocalization interactions in the C&#8211;C bonds of 1.42 &#197; (143.70 kcal/mol) and 1.47 &#197; (34.98 kcal/mol) are 22% and 38% higher, respectively, than those in benzene. MP2/Def2SVP calculations yield a correlation energy of 13.49 kcal/mol per electron for C60, slightly higher than the 11.68 kcal/mol for benzene. However, the results from HOMO-LUMO calculations should be interpreted with caution. This study may assist in the rational design of fullerene C60 derivatives for CO2 reduction systems.</description>
      <author>Yuemin Liu, Yunxiang Gao, Tariq Altalhi, Di&#8208;Jia Liu, Boris I. Yakobson</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14191576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Hydrogen on Flame Characteristics and Pollutant Emissions in Natural Gas Industrial Combustion Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17194959</link>
      <description>Yamei Lan, Li Wang, Jingxiang Xu, Yi Wang, Energies. 17(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140808

                To improve energy savings and emission reduction in industrial heating furnaces, this study investigated the impact of various molar fractions of hydrogen on natural gas combustion and compared the results of the Non-Premixed Combustion Model with the Eddy Dissipation Combustion Model. Initially, natural gas combustion in an industrial heating furnace was investigated experimentally, and these results were used as boundary conditions for CFD simulations. The diffusion flame and combustion characteristics of natural gas were simulated using both the non-premixed combustion model and the Eddy Dissipation Combustion Model. The results indicated that the Non-Premixed Combustion Model provided simulations more consistent with experimental data, within acceptable error margins, thus validating the accuracy of the numerical simulations. Additionally, to analyze the impact of hydrogen doping on the performance of an industrial gas heater, four gas mixtures with varying hydrogen contents (15% H2, 30% H2, 45% H2, and 60% H2) were studied while maintaining constant fuel inlet temperature and flow rate. The results demonstrate that the Non-Premixed Combustion Model more accurately simulates complex flue gas flow and chemical reactions during combustion. Moreover, hydrogen-doped natural gas significantly reduces CO and CO2 emissions compared to pure natural gas combustion. Specifically, at 60% hydrogen content, CO and CO2 levels decrease by 70% and 37.5%, respectively, while NO emissions increase proportionally; at this hydrogen content, NO concentration in the furnace chamber rises by 155%.</description>
      <author>Yamei Lan, Li Wang, Jingxiang Xu, Yi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17194959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study of The Energy, Economic, Environmental, and Thermal Comfort Impact of The Integration of Hemp Concrete and Hemp Plaster in a Residential Building Envelope in Morocco</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37934/arnht.23.1.127</link>
      <description>H. Kaddouri, Abderrahim Abidouche, Mohamed Saidi Hassani Alaoui, I. Driouch, Said Hamdaoui, Abdelouahad Ait Msaad, Journal of Advanced Research in Numerical Heat Transfer. 23(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403062885

                In the building sector, the majority of efforts are aimed at achieving greater energy efficiency, a low carbon footprint, and optimum thermal comfort to make buildings more efficient, more sustainable, and more pleasant to live in. In this context, this paper aims to assess the impact of integrating environmentally friendly and green materials (lime-hemp plaster and hemp concrete) into the envelope of an existing residential building. A numerical simulation study was carried out using TRNSYS 18, in four Moroccan climates: Mediterranean, cold semi-arid, hot semi-arid, and hot and dry desert, to study the energy, economic, and environmental impact, as well as that of the thermal comfort. The proposed construction scenarios are compared with the reference scenario in terms of heating and cooling requirements, electricity bills, carbon footprint, and percentage of annual thermal discomfort. The results show that energy savings are highest in the cold semi-arid climate (Oujda) at around 24%. Hemp concrete construction is more effective in reducing heating requirements, with a reduction of up to 39.4%. For cooling, the reduction is only 15.5%. The economic and environmental study shows that using materials such as hemp concrete in an optimal construction and climatic context can reduce electricity bills by 25% and CO2 emissions by around 23.7%. However, the reduction in terms of hours of discomfort is not yet significant enough. Hence the need to combine this technique with other strategies based on bioclimatic design. The use of hemp plaster and concrete for renovating existing buildings or constructing new ones represents a very promising alternative from several points of view: energy, economic, and environmental.</description>
      <author>H. Kaddouri, Abderrahim Abidouche, Mohamed Saidi Hassani Alaoui, I. Driouch, Said Hamdaoui, Abdelouahad Ait Msaad</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37934/arnht.23.1.127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Regional Development In The Area of Renewable Energy Sources In Poland</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5171/2024.4314224</link>
      <description>M. Filipowicz, Communications of International Proceedings. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403039097

                This article examines the challenges of power grid congestion in a municipality located in central Poland and presents potential solutions in the form of a photovoltaic farm project or prosumer group installation. In the context of growing demand for electricity and an increasing number of households producing energy from renewable sources, there is a need to upgrade the energy infrastructure to meet the needs of the local community. A planned photovoltaic farm or group prosumer installations are not only a way to relieve stressed grids, but also a step towards sustainable energy production and reduction of CO2 emissions. In the article, I also discuss the economic, social and environmental aspects of implementing these projects and the possible benefits for the municipality and its residents. My analysis indicates the potential for solar energy development in the region and presents effective tools that can help modernize energy infrastructure and promote sustainable development in local communities.</description>
      <author>M. Filipowicz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5171/2024.4314224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of Energy-saving Technologies in House construction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21822/2073-6185-2024-51-3-189-194</link>
      <description>E. I. Krupnov, Irina A. Zaytseva, Svetlana Andreyevna Loginova, Aleksandr Vladimirovich Simagin, Herald of Dagestan State Technical University Technical Sciences. 51(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403088596

                Objective. Over the past decades, heat pumps have gained great popularity due to their advantages in energy efficiency and environmental friendliness, becoming one of the most attractive alternatives to replace traditional heating systems running on fossil fuels. Heat pump efficiency is a decisive factor that should be taken into account when selecting and optimizing a heat pump system. The aim of the study was to evaluate the efficiency of air source heat pumps of the air-to-water system in the climatic conditions typical of the regions of the Central Federal District. Method . To evaluate the efficiency of air source heat pumps, a mathematical model is used that takes into account the multifactorial nature of the process under study. Result. To adequately compare the obtained research results with the passport performance indicators, the transformation coefficient (COP) was used, showing the ratio of the energy received to the expended work. As a result, the method of heating rooms with an air source heat pump with a combined operation mode was recognized as more preferable. Conclusion. Currently, the potential of heat pumps in the field of energy saving and CO2 emission reduction remains largely untapped, which sets the vector for further research.</description>
      <author>E. I. Krupnov, Irina A. Zaytseva, Svetlana Andreyevna Loginova, Aleksandr Vladimirovich Simagin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21822/2073-6185-2024-51-3-189-194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size&#8208;dependent Copper Nanoparticles Supported on Carbon Nanotubes with Balanced Cu+ and Cu0 Dual Sites for the Selective Hydrogenation of Ethylene Carbonate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402699</link>
      <description>Wanghua Chen, Dahye Ji, Yanfei Zhang, Yuanyuan Cui, Yinfeng Cheng, Songlin Wang, Wei&#8208;Lin Dai, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403081561

                Cyclic carbonate hydrogenation offers an alternative for the efficient indirect CO2 utilization. In this study, a series of carbon nanotubes (CNTs) supported xCu/CNTs catalysts with different Cu loadings were fabricated using a convenient impregnation method, and exhibited excellent catalytic activity for the hydrogenation of ethylene carbonate to methanol and ethylene glycol. The structural and physicochemical properties revealed that acid treatment of CNTs resulted in plentiful oxygen&#8208;containing functional groups, providing sufficient anchoring sites for copper species. The calcination process conducted under an inert atmosphere resulted in the formation of ternary CuO, Cu2O, and Cu composites, enhancing the metal&#8208;support interaction and facilitating the formation of balanced Cu0 and Cu+ dual sites as well as high active surface area after reduction. Contributed to the synergetic effect of balanced Cu+ and Cu0 species proved by density functional theory calculation and the electron&#8208;rich CNTs surface, the 40Cu/CNTs catalyst achieved strengthened catalytic performance with methanol yield of 83%, ethylene glycol yield of 99% at ethylene carbonate conversion of &gt;99%, and 150 h of long&#8208;term running stability. Consequently, CNTs supported Cu serve as efficient non&#8208;silica based catalyst for ester hydrogenation.</description>
      <author>Wanghua Chen, Dahye Ji, Yanfei Zhang, Yuanyuan Cui, Yinfeng Cheng, Songlin Wang, Wei&#8208;Lin Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402699</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of high&#8208;entropy oxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401663</link>
      <description>Qian Zhang, Xuexue Wang, Xiaomeng Lv, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403073360

                High&#8208;entropy oxides (HEOs), similar to high&#8208;entropy materials (HEMs), have "four&#8208;core effects", i.e., high&#8208;entropy effect, delayed diffusion effect, lattice distortion effect and cocktail effect, which have attracted more and more attention in the scientific field of renewable energy technology due to their unique structural characteristics, variable chemical composition and corresponding functional properties. HEOs have become potential candidates for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is a key half reaction for electrolytic CO2, nitrogen reduction, and water electrolysis. However, the precise synthesis of HEOs with a wide range of components and structures is challenging, not to mention their active and stable operation for OER. In this paper, we review the recent advancements in the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution facilitated by HEOs in water electrolysis. We analyze these developments from the perspectives of activity and stability in acid and alkaline conditions, respectively. Furthermore, we summarize the design from the aspect of element composition, structure, morphology, and catalyst&#8208;support interactions, along with related reaction mechanism of HEOs. Additionally, we discuss the current challenges faced by HEOs in the field of OER and suggest potential directions for the future development of HEOs beyond water electrolysis application.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhang, Xuexue Wang, Xiaomeng Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Efficiency and Sustainability in Food Retail Buildings: Introducing a Novel Assessment Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17194882</link>
      <description>Simone Forastiere, Cristina Piselli, Andrea Silei, Fabio Sciurpi, Anna Laura Pisello, Franco Cotana, Carla Balocco, Energies. 17(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402964044

                One of the primary global objectives is to decrease building energy consumption to promote energy efficiency and environmental sustainability. The large-scale food retail trade sector accounts for over 15% of total primary energy consumption in Europe, posing a significant challenge to the transition towards green energy. This study proposes a simple method for energy efficiency, environmental sustainability, and cost-saving assessment and improvement in large-scale food retail trade buildings. It aims to analyze the energy and environmental performance of building&#8211;plant systems, establishing an interactive network to assess intervention potential for the energy transition. The investigation focuses on the proper selection and analysis of the benefits of retrofit solution implementation, emphasizing potential energy savings in current and future climate change scenarios. Dynamic simulation with the Building Energy Model (BEM) was used to evaluate the impacts of building&#8211;plant system retrofit solutions, such as high thermal insulation, photovoltaic (PV) panels, Light Emitting Diode (LED) installation, waste heat recovery, and improvement in refrigeration units. The results show a reduction in annual energy consumption for the PV panel installation by up to 29% and lighting systems with high-quality LED to 60%. Additionally, CO2 emissions can be decreased by up to 41% by combining these two strategies.</description>
      <author>Simone Forastiere, Cristina Piselli, Andrea Silei, Fabio Sciurpi, Anna Laura Pisello, Franco Cotana, Carla Balocco</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17194882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous Nanobelts for Efficient Electrocatalytic Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416878</link>
      <description>Ziming Su, Xiangyu Chen, Mingke Sun, Xiuyi Yang, Jianxin Kang, Zhi Cai, Xiaotian Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140466

                One&#8208;dimensional (1D) amorphous nanomaterials combine the advantages of high active site concentration of amorphous structure, high specific surface area and efficient charge transfer and mass transport of 1D materials, so they present promising opportunities for catalysis. However, a significant challenge involves achieving a balance between the high orientation of 1D morphology and the isotropy of amorphous structure, which severely obstructs the controllable preparation of 1D amorphous materials. Guided by the hard&#8208;soft acids&#8208;bases theory, here we develop a general strategy for preparing 1D amorphous nanomaterials through the precise modulation of bond strength between metal ions and organic ligands for a moderated fastness. The soft base dodecanethiol (DT) is multifunctionally served as both structure&#8208;regulating agent and morphology&#8208;directing agent. Compared with the borderline acids (e.g. Fe2+, Co2+, Ni2+) to construct amorphous structure, soft acid of Cu+ which produced crystalline nanobelts can still be amorphized by reducing the hardness of Cu ions through redox reaction to weak Cu&#8208;SR bond. Due to the combined advantages of amorphous structure and one&#8208;dimensional morphology, amorphous CuDT nanobelts exhibited excellent electrocatalytic activity in electrochemical nitrate reduction, outperformed the most of the reported Cu&#8208;based catalysts. This work will effectively bridge the gap between traditional 1D crystalline nanomaterials and amorphization preparation.</description>
      <author>Ziming Su, Xiangyu Chen, Mingke Sun, Xiuyi Yang, Jianxin Kang, Zhi Cai, Xiaotian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416878</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extended emission footprint analysis of dispatchable gas-based power generation technologies with exhaust aftertreatment technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33737/gpps24-tc-088</link>
      <description>Christian Go&#223;rau, Nils Holger Petersen, L. de la Cruz-May, Manfred Wirsum, Alexander Lampkowski, Ariel Sch&#246;nberger Alvarez, J. Classen, Stefan Pischinger, Proceedings. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403007972

                The mitigation of climate change poses severe pressure on the rapid replacement of conventional power generation technologies by renewables. Due to the inherent volatility of renewable power generation technologies, dispatchable power generation units, such as gas turbines (GT) and gas-based reciprocating internal combustion engines (RICE), must be operated to maintain grid stability. While RICE are equipped with exhaust aftertreatment (EAT) technologies as standard to meet regulatory emission limits, this may also become important for GT in the near future. The present study therefore investigates the influence of EAT on emissions, taking into account oxidation catalysts (OC) and selective catalytic reduction (SCR) catalysts. Single-cycle power plant configurations for both technologies are studied under different operation scenarios, with emphasis on start-ups and partial load operation. Emissions are assessed as &#8220;generated mass per electrical output&#8221; (g=kWhel), considering both greenhouse gases and local pollutants. To holistically assess the environmental footprint, emissions are converted into impact categories such as Global Warming Potential (GWP), Respiratory Inorganics (RI), Photochemical Ozone Formation (POF) and Human Toxicity Potential (HTP). The increasing variability of operation demands of gas-based power generation technologies leads to a significant increase of emissions and environmental impact without EAT, highlighting the overall need for EAT systems to meet regulatory limits in the future. Both technologies show a significant reduction in the environmental impact factors (RI: &gt; 46 %, POF: &gt; 87 %, HTP: &gt; 86 %) with EAT deployment in all load profile scenarios. With CO2 largely unaffected by EAT, RICE has a lower GWP100 than GT for all load scenarios (-2.6 to -11.4 %) because of the higher average plant efficiency. Due to their modularity, RICE plants can be operated over most of the plant load range without excessive emissions, whereas GT plants are limited to operation above 30 %.</description>
      <author>Christian Go&#223;rau, Nils Holger Petersen, L. de la Cruz-May, Manfred Wirsum, Alexander Lampkowski, Ariel Sch&#246;nberger Alvarez, J. Classen, Stefan Pischinger</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33737/gpps24-tc-088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous Nanobelts for Efficient Electrocatalytic Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416878</link>
      <description>Ziming Su, Xiang&#8208;Yu Chen, Mingke Sun, Xiuyi Yang, Jianxin Kang, Zhi Cai, Lin Guo, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403141185

                One&#8208;dimensional (1D) amorphous nanomaterials combine the advantages of high active site concentration of amorphous structure, high specific surface area and efficient charge transfer and mass transport of 1D materials, so they present promising opportunities for catalysis. However, a significant challenge involves achieving a balance between the high orientation of 1D morphology and the isotropy of amorphous structure, which severely obstructs the controllable preparation of 1D amorphous materials. Guided by the hard&#8208;soft acids&#8208;bases theory, here we develop a general strategy for preparing 1D amorphous nanomaterials through the precise modulation of bond strength between metal ions and organic ligands for a moderated fastness. The soft base dodecanethiol (DT) is multifunctionally served as both structure&#8208;regulating agent and morphology&#8208;directing agent. Compared with the borderline acids (e.g. Fe2+, Co2+, Ni2+) to construct amorphous structure, soft acid of Cu+ which produced crystalline nanobelts can still be amorphized by reducing the hardness of Cu ions through redox reaction to weak Cu&#8208;SR bond. Due to the combined advantages of amorphous structure and one&#8208;dimensional morphology, amorphous CuDT nanobelts exhibited excellent electrocatalytic activity in electrochemical nitrate reduction, outperformed the most of the reported Cu&#8208;based catalysts. This work will effectively bridge the gap between traditional 1D crystalline nanomaterials and amorphization preparation.</description>
      <author>Ziming Su, Xiang&#8208;Yu Chen, Mingke Sun, Xiuyi Yang, Jianxin Kang, Zhi Cai, Lin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416878</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring and adjustments of combustion parameters in reheating furnaces using a digital tool</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.70342/dyin3512</link>
      <description>K&#225;ssio Nogueira Can&#231;ado, Aristides Almeida Rocha, Rafaela Rapalo, Paula Pomaro, Lis Nunes Soares, No host. 1(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402964415

                Improving the energy efficiency of a reheating furnace is not a simple task because it involves a large number of parameters that, most of the time, are connected in a complex way. To be feasible, the evaluation of such a vast number of variables must be supported by digital tools that are embedded with artificial intelligence. The SMS group has developed a digital tool that effectively supports operators and engineers in enhancing energy efficiency within the reheating furnaces of hot rolling mills. This paper presents a quick study case of the use of Viridis Performance, an application of Viridis Energy &amp; Sustainability Suite, in the analysis and correction of the deviations in the air-gas ratio of a reheating furnace. In this study, a production period of 8 hours was evaluated, during which the air-gas ratio presented a significant deviation. Analysis showed that the probable cause of the deviation was a production stoppage where the furnace control was set to manual mode. A reduction potential of 0.26 Gcal/h and a 13 kg/h decrease in CO2 emissions were identified. Viridis Performance would support the process by guiding the decisions of the operator in a way that energy losses would be avoided or minimized. The potential economic savings were also quantified. This task is performed in the system by Viridis Moneybox, which is another application of Viridis Energy &amp; Sustainability Suite. The results showed potential savings of 13 US $/h. In addition to the gains and savings outlined in this study, the utilization of Viridis Performance encompasses numerous other advantages, such as enhanced operational standardization and improved process capability, to name just a few.</description>
      <author>K&#225;ssio Nogueira Can&#231;ado, Aristides Almeida Rocha, Rafaela Rapalo, Paula Pomaro, Lis Nunes Soares</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.70342/dyin3512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated training of deep learning surrogate models for surface
  displacement and flow, with application to MCMC-based history matching of CO2
  storage operations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.10717</link>
      <description>Yifu Han, Fran&#231;ois P. Hamon, Louis J. Durlofsky, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403007308

                Deep learning surrogate modeling shows great promise for subsurface flow applications, but the training demands can be substantial. Here we introduce a new surrogate modeling framework to predict CO2 saturation, pressure and surface displacement for use in the history matching of carbon storage operations. Rather than train using a large number of expensive coupled flow-geomechanics simulation runs, training here involves a large number of inexpensive flow-only simulations combined with a much smaller number of coupled runs. The flow-only runs use an effective rock compressibility, which is shown to provide accurate predictions for saturation and pressure for our system. A recurrent residual U-Net architecture is applied for the saturation and pressure surrogate models, while a new residual U-Net model is introduced to predict surface displacement. The surface displacement surrogate accepts, as inputs, geomodel quantities along with saturation and pressure surrogate predictions. Median relative error for a diverse test set is less than 4% for all variables. The surrogate models are incorporated into a hierarchical Markov chain Monte Carlo history matching workflow. Surrogate error is included using a new treatment involving the full model error covariance matrix. A high degree of prior uncertainty, with geomodels characterized by uncertain geological scenario parameters (metaparameters) and associated realizations, is considered. History matching results for a synthetic true model are generated using in-situ monitoring-well data only, surface displacement data only, and both data types. The enhanced uncertainty reduction achieved with both data types is quantified. Posterior saturation and surface displacement fields are shown to correspond well with the true solution.</description>
      <author>Yifu Han, Fran&#231;ois P. Hamon, Louis J. Durlofsky</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.10717</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B-031 A new Ready to use Bio-Rad Quality Control to Streamline Daily Workflow</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.395</link>
      <description>A M Yagoot, Hassan A. Khalil, Mohammed A. Alharbi, G. Almalayo, Anwar Borai, Clinical Chemistry. 70(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403048859

                Abstract Background A comprehensive Quality Management System starts with performing a daily Quality Control (Q.C.) process. The daily Q.C. process monitors the Instrument&#8217;s optimal performance and detects shifts and trends. However, the existing traditional daily Q.C. process is not only prone to manual errors, but also time consuming, costly and labor intensive. We evaluated a Bio-Rad InteliQTM Load and go Quality Control that comes in a barcoded tube ready to be loaded. We monitored the workflow efficiency gained in comparison to the traditional quality control material that comes in glass vials. Methods We evaluated the new quality control material ready to load on the instrument. This new Q.C. (Bio-Rad InteliQ Assayed Multiqual Control - 3 levels) were processed in parallel with our routine Q.C. (Bio-Rad Assayed Chemistry Lyphocheck vials - 2 levels). We performed the evaluation on Abbott Architect c8000 Chemistry analyzers in our central Laboratory (NGHA-Jeddah). The Q.C. was stored frozen. Before testing it was thawed at room temperature as per the insert instruction. Over a 5 days period, in parallel with our routine quality control, we run the new Q.C. Two times per day for 33 analytes. We monitored the processing time difference between the new and current approaches. We monitored the stability of all the analytes in the tube after Two days and again after Five days. We also monitored the cost effectiveness, labor intensiveness, probability of operator error and the overall improvement in workflow and Turn Around Time. Results Over the evaluation period, we observed the following: - Saving 40 minutes in average per week only for chemistry Q.C (time spent in reconstituting, mixing and aliquoting old Q.C) - 100% reduction in waste of plastic consumables such as pipette and plastic tubes. - Save an average of 1.0 ml dead volume in every 5.0 ml old Q.C. vial (20% of the volume, hence saving 20% of the total Q.C. cost). The dead volume wasted due to aliquoting step using the old Q.C. - 100% Eliminated delays caused by operator error such as wrong reconstitution, inadequate mixing and wrong Q.C. aliquoting. Not needed for the InteliQ. - High score of staff satisfaction. - Stability of the 32 analytes was excellent except that of Co2, which deteriorated by 14% after Two days as indicated in the insert package. Co2 day five result deteriorated by 34%. Conclusions Bio-Rad InteliQ is easy to use. It saves time and cost. When combined with Unity Q.C. data management solution it can streamline Q.C. workflow, eliminate operator errors, reduce T.A.T. and increase the overall laboratory performance. It may also work optimally with Instruments that have on-board fridge for Q.C.</description>
      <author>A M Yagoot, Hassan A. Khalil, Mohammed A. Alharbi, G. Almalayo, Anwar Borai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.395</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12201 Ketogenic-diet As A Trigger Of First Episode Diabetic Ketoacidosis In A Woman Living With Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1210/jendso/bvae163.826</link>
      <description>Margarida Cruz, Alex N Gonzalez Bossolo, Gabriel Jose Mora Osoria, Journal of the Endocrine Society. 8(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403153887

                Abstract Disclosure: M.E. Chacon Cruz: None. A.N. Gonzalez Bossolo: None. G.J. Mora Osoria: None. A number of dietary patterns have been proposed as an effective method for weight reduction. A keto diet is a strict low-carbohydrate and high-fat diet. The reduction in carbohydrates enables the body to rely on fat as a predominant energy source leading to a state of ketosis. However, a serious but rare complication of the ketogenic diet is ketoacidosis associated with low carbohydrate intake, which should be cautiously monitored in people with a predisposition to the condition, such patient with diabetes mellitus type 1. We report the case of a female patient living with type 1 diabetes mellitus female who developed her first episodes of diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA) as the following the course of ketogenic diet. A 53 y/o Female patient with past medical history diabetes mellitus type 1 and pernicious anemia went emergency department complaining pelvic pain associated with weakness, nausea and vomiting for about 1 day of evolution. Patient also refers that during the past 2 weeks she has been doing a detox and taking some herbal and tea. Other physical examinations were unremarkable except for moderate dehydration. The initial testing revealed patients meet criteria for severe diabetes ketoacidosis (DKA) with a pH: 7.04, CO2 15, serum central bicarbonate in 6 mmol/L and elevated blood glucose in 504 mg/dl and positive urine and serum ketones, C-Peptide less than 0.02 ng/ml. and glycosylated hemoglobin in 8.25%. She was admitted to the intensive care unit and treated with intravenous saline, intravenous insulin infusion, and electrolyte repletion. Blood glucose levels and metabolic acidosis improved. After DKA resolved patient refers that week started with Keto-diet and was restricting carbohydrates. Patient was discharge home with multiple injection insulin and followed by Endocrinologist services in the external clinic for a follow up. This case illustrates the challenges and the importance of dietary history providing clues to the diagnosis. If we had never asked her about her diet, we would not have found the reason that brought her to the DKA. This case demonstrates the development of DKA following ketogenic diet in a patient with type 1 diabetes. It is important for physicians to be aware of this rare potential complication of ketogenic diet which is infrequently reported in literature. Therefore, physicians should be cognizant of the complications and risks, and benefits of the ketogenic diet. Risks and benefits of the ketogenic diet should be discussed with patients before initiation of this diet. The patient was followed in an outpatient clinic with Endocrinologist service for evaluation for an insulin pump. Presentation: 6/1/2024</description>
      <author>Margarida Cruz, Alex N Gonzalez Bossolo, Gabriel Jose Mora Osoria</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1210/jendso/bvae163.826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Hybrid Physics/Data-Driven Model for Fractured Reservoir Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/219110-pa</link>
      <description>Billal Aslam, Bicheng Yan, Knut&#8211;Andreas Lie, Stein Krogstad, Olav M&#248;yner, Xupeng He, SPE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403091249

                Summary Fractured reservoir simulation plays a crucial role in understanding various subsurface geo-energy recovery and storage processes, including shale gas/oil extraction, enhanced geothermal systems, and CO2 sequestration in basaltic rocks. However, such simulations often entail significant computational expenses due to the high contrast in permeability and pore volume (PV) between matrix and fractures. To address this challenge, we introduce a reduced-order model (ROM) tailored for fractured reservoir simulation that offers flexible fracture representations by generating coarse matrix nodes based on reservoir outlines and adding extra diagonal connections between unconnected matrix nodes, whose corresponding volumes are intersected by fractures. This approach avoids the need for additional fracture nodes, effectively reducing computational costs. Dimensionality reduction methods, such as principal component analysis (PCA), are used to give quality priors for sampling matrix transmissibility and PV arrays. Tuning to well observation data, such as flow rates and bottomhole pressures (BHPs), is achieved through a gradient-based optimization method within a general automatic-differentiable simulator framework. Our results demonstrate robust calibration using synthetic well observation data from a fine-scale reference simulation model. Incorporating dominant flow physics, such as water breakthrough, from observation data improves history-matching (HM) convergence and prediction accuracy. Additionally, PCA for parameterization enhances the convergence rate of model calibration compared with random initialization. Calibrated transmissibilities align with high-connectivity regions from the fine-scale reference model, rendering the model interpretable in terms of reservoir connectivity or geology. This feature enables our method to be used effectively for reservoir HM and optimization using field observation data.</description>
      <author>Billal Aslam, Bicheng Yan, Knut&#8211;Andreas Lie, Stein Krogstad, Olav M&#248;yner, Xupeng He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/219110-pa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A-198 ESG Opportunities Harnessed During Pathology Transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.196</link>
      <description>T Ellison, Louise Hughes, R. F. G. Booth, Garry M. Walsh, David Dunn, Clinical Chemistry. 70(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403071086

                Abstract Background Synnovis (a SYNLAB business) is in the process of delivering one of the largest Pathology transformation programmes in the UK, moving to a seven-site hub and spoke model from 89 laboratories over a dispersed geography. This remit also presented an opportunity for SYNLAB to deliver on its Environmental Social Governance (ESG) ambitions, by embedding ESG principles into programme delivery. There are several examples within each ESG pillar that demonstrate the benefits to be leveraged during transformation. Methods SYNLAB&#8217;s vision is to deliver sustainable diagnostic services. The integration of ESG into both the decision-making process and transformation structure ties these ambitions into programme benefits realisation. As well as setting performance level targets, the delivery of ESG benefits provide measures of success throughout the transformation journey, motivating stakeholders and building confidence along the way. Results Environment: The efficient use of space and LEAN principle design has consolidated the fragmented laboratory services spanning 15,000m2 into a bespoke, cutting-edge Pathology Hub with 6 spokes (hospital based services). The new hub building was designed to achieve BREEAM Excellent standards which measure performance against criteria such as energy management and efficiency, sustainable design and materials. The hub&#8217;s energy is from renewable-backed sources, and we will achieve a 47% reduction in CO2 equivalent (CO2e) emissions by unifying a significant proportion of its legacy footprint in this way. Further energy savings will be achieved through the associated analytical equipment consolidation, including a decrease from 50 to 14 microtomes, a decrease of 29 to 15 ventilated benches and a reduction of over 200 fridges and freezers across the service. In addition, substantial CO2e emissions savings are also being delivered by moving to a greener logistics provider, utilising electric vehicles and bikes. 2023 saw such emissions fall by 60% across Synnovis, helping to keep London&#8217;s air cleaner. Social: The transformation programme enables the hand back of over 6,000m2 of real estate to Synnovis&#8217; NHS partners to use for critical hospital services (the equivalent of over 150 operating theatres). Governance Both internally and externally, ESG is integrated within the Synnovis organisational culture. For example, internally it applies mandatory sustainability metrics to its solution selection processes. These influenced the selection of Abbott&#8217;s Indexor solution to support the transformation of Blood Sciences, delivering a saving of over 2.8 million plastic sample bags every year. Externally, SYNLAB works with its partners to manage this substantial and complex transformation programme. Risk management is assured through transparency, securing confidence in the good use of public funds, ensuring responsiveness to customer and partner feedback, and ensuring accountability for and the delivery of targeted healthcare outcomes. Conclusions The integration of SYNLAB&#8217;s ESG strategy within the transformation programme is delivering tangible benefits across all ESG pillars. It has highlighted that in addition to the core outcome of services transformation, there are many more opportunities that can be realised as a result of making ESG an integral part of the pathology transformation programme.</description>
      <author>T Ellison, Louise Hughes, R. F. G. Booth, Garry M. Walsh, David Dunn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making of an Indigenous and Efficient Powertrains for EV, HEV &amp;amp; FCEV&#8217;s</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37285/ajmt.4.3.0</link>
      <description>S. S. Ramdasi, ARAI Journal of Mobility Technology. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403077243

                Rise in greenhouse gas emissions which is resulting into ozone layer depletion and global warming effect is alarming to control CO2 emissions by drastically reducing fossil fuel consumption from the vehicles. This need has already started trend towards extreme downsizing and down speeding of Internal Combustion Engines (ICE) for making them highly efficient. In addition to this use of after treatment devices viz. Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (DOC), Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF), Lean NOx Catalyst (LNT), Selective Catalytic Reduction (SCR) are helping to a great extent for meeting emission norms till Euro - VI for automotive sector, Tier&#8211;IV F and Stage V for Off Highway Power sector. However, to address present greenhouse effect along with exponential decay of fossil fuels, there is need to achieve CO2 emissions less than 100 g/km or to achieve practically zero carbon footprint using an alternate powertrain. Electrification is one of the promising solutions and which is three-fold in present situation. The first level of electrification comes in the form of Hybrid Electric Vehicle (HEV) technology followed by Battery Electric Vehicles and Fuel Cell Electric Vehicles as second and third level of electrification respectively. In all these technologies a common thread is running in the form of an efficient electric drive train. Several efforts have been taken to improve torque per unit ampere by use of efficient motor and motor control algorithms viz PMSM powered with FOC, by developing controls which take care of parametric variations and external force disturbances by use of back stepping techniques which are based on rotor resistance estimation by fuzzy logic, FOC techniques based on adaptive input-output feedback linearization, by shifting towards high voltage systems, by going for higher switching frequencies for inverters which uses silicon carbide based MOSFET switches, by exploring use of multilevel inverters for Total Harmonic Distortion (THD) control etc. Use of E Axle based powertrains in EV, HEV and FCEV offers additional complimentary benefits apart from technology options described above. E Axle based powertrains offers flexibility in generating three variants of vehicle using one electric drive train architecture viz. making EV, HEV &amp; FCEV. Compactness, modularity, scalability, flexibility along with efficient cooling system management and control over active current losses due to use of bus bars are the implicit advantages of E Axle based powertrains. These advantages further get multiplies if we go for 3 in 1 (gearbox + Stator housing + Inverter) architectures which are predominantly used in independent suspension-based vehicles. Lot of efforts are going on to inherit this technology for rigid axle suspension based commercial vehicles. Research in this area is getting further extended to make 5 in 1 E Axles where there will addition of DC - DC converter and On-Board Charger (OBC) apart from components present in 3 in 1 configuration. Two major challenges need to be addressed and to be resolved while designing E Axle based powertrains by doing concurrent vehicle engineering. This is mainly due to increased unsprang weight that need to be handled by suspension system and exposed electric drive components to excitation loads coming from roads. Fig: Indigenously Developed E Axle Based Powertrain for Small Commercial VehiclesBy proper lay outing for effective vehicle mass distribution and required CG location which is essential from overall vehicle dynamics, more space can be offered by E Axle based powertrains for increasing battery energy density for getting more electric range in case of BEV&#8217;s. This add on space benefit extend help in packaging of hydrogen fuel cell integrated with power cells in case of FCEV&#8217;s. Thus, E Axle based powertrains proves to be modern and most efficient way of making EV, HEV &amp; FCEV&#8217;s.</description>
      <author>S. S. Ramdasi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37285/ajmt.4.3.0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comments: Global Implications and Challenges of Electrification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/1024-0014-jpt</link>
      <description>Pam Boschee, Journal of Petroleum Technology. 76(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402970937

                _ Electrification is widely seen as crucial for decarbonization. To be successful on a global scale, a mix of complex challenges require coordinated efforts across the diversification of the energy mix, technology development, infrastructure investment, policy support, and regional planning. The International Energy Agency&#8217;s (IEA) Net Zero Emissions by 2050 Scenario suggests electricity should account for nearly 30% of final energy consumption by 2030, up from an estimated 20% in 2023, to progress to net zero. Are net zero emissions achievable by 2050? SPE President Olivier Houz&#233; delves into the IEA&#8217;s three main energy transition scenarios in this month&#8217;s vodcast and column. Among his conclusions: &#8220;Beyond 2050, the anticipation is a decline of around 50% for oil and 25% for gas in the following 20 years. The one thing everybody agrees on is that no one really knows.&#8221; The following updates offer a glimpse at efforts to electrify oil and gas assets and bring clean energy solutions to remote and underserved communities. Norway&#8217;s Offshore Success Electrifying upstream oil and gas production facilities using renewable energy or otherwise flared natural gas could reduce emissions by more than 80%. Rystad Energy&#8217;s recent analysis highlighted Norway as currently leading the way, thanks to its wealth of renewable resources and production sites&#8217; proximity to them. Electrification of rigs and other assets on Norway&#8217;s Continental Shelf (NCS) has resulted in a drop from 8.4 kg to 1.2 kg CO2/BOE&#8212;an 86% reduction in the same assets&#8217; emissions before electrification. Norway&#8217;s literal powerhouse is hydroelectric energy, tallying more than 1,500 hydropower plants, normally producing 133 TWh annually, or 96% of the country&#8217;s total power production. This supply has made the transition of many of its offshore facilities to cleaner energy more feasible than in other regions of the world, particularly for power-from-shore projects such as Troll A, Martin Linge, and Johan Sverdrup. As of 2 years ago, Norway had seven fields fully or partially electrified from shore. Onshore Electrification&#8212;Drilling With Clean(er) Energy Other players in the industry grapple with less advantageous scenarios, facing hurdles such as facilities located far from renewable energy sources, which may be limited, and inadequate grid infrastructure. SPE 218649, presented at the SPE Conference at Oman Petroleum &amp; Energy Show in April, discussed using electrical utility power in drilling operations. The authors noted that a drilling rig typically consumes 6 to 50 MWh of energy per day, averaging around 20 MWh. Diesel-powered rigs emit about 1.0 metric tonne of CO2e/MWh, totaling roughly 20 metric tonnes of CO2e per day. In contrast, grid-powered rigs emit about 0.39 metric tonnes of CO2e/MWh, less than half the emissions of diesel-powered rigs. An example from the paper illustrates how incremental changes can reduce emissions intensity, even when the solution is a step toward &#8220;cleaner&#8221; energy, though not yet fully aligned with ideal clean energy standards. Comparing drilling operations in North Dakota, where 57% of the state&#8217;s power generation uses coal, to Texas where 18% uses coal, the authors noted that the &#8220;emissions intensity on a North Dakota rig tied to the grid is higher than that of an electrified rig working in Texas but is still notably lower than the intensity of an average drilling rig powered by a diesel generator, which is approximately 1.0 metric tonnes CO2e/MWh.&#8221; Broader Implications and Challenges of Electrification The upfront costs of electrification are substantial, especially for entities in remote areas with limited grid access. This challenge affects not only the oil and gas industry but also efforts to bring electricity to underserved communities. A paper presented at the SPE Nigeria Annual International Conference and Exhibition in August (SPE 221709) studied the viability and impact of solar mini-grid systems for electrification of rural communities in Sub-Saharan Africa where approximately 600 million people lack electricity, and around 690 million lack access to clean cooking stoves. The authors wrote, &#8220;In Nigeria, about 45% of the population, more than 90 million people, do not have electricity, with 60% of these individuals residing in rural areas. Nigeria also has one of the lowest per capita electricity generation rates globally, with an installed grid-connected capacity of about 13,000 MW but an average actual output of just 4,000 MW.&#8221; The authors included a table showing a cost summary including capital, the cost of installation, and other specifications for an 87.5-kWp (kilowatt peak) solar-power system. They calculated a levelized cost of electricity of 47.1 cents/kWh over the system&#8217;s estimated lifetime of 25 years&#8212;approximately six times that of a US residential solar system and roughly three times more than an average US residential utility rate of 16 cents/kWh (although this varies significantly by state and region). In the end, achieving a more electrified and sustainable energy future depends on a combination of factors: strategic investment, robust infrastructure, accessible energy resources, collaboration among key stakeholders, ongoing technological innovation, and supportive policy frameworks.</description>
      <author>Pam Boschee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/1024-0014-jpt</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
