<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:20:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>NiNC Catalysts in CO2-to-CO Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01595-y</link>
      <description>Hao Zhang, Menghui Qi, Yong Wang, Nano-Micro Letters. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405820244

                Abstract CO 2 -to-CO electrolyzer technology converts carbon dioxide into carbon monoxide using electrochemical methods, offering significant environmental and energy benefits by aiding in greenhouse gas mitigation and promoting a carbon circular economy. Recent study by Strasser et al. in Nature Chemical Engineering presents a high-performance CO 2 -to-CO electrolyzer utilizing a NiNC catalyst with nearly 100% faradaic efficiency, employing innovative diagnostic tools like the carbon crossover coefficient (CCC) to address transport-related failures and optimize overall efficiency. Strasser&#8217;s research demonstrates the potential of NiNC catalysts, particularly NiNC-IMI, for efficient CO production in CO 2 -to-CO electrolyzers, highlighting their high selectivity and performance. However, challenges such as localized CO 2 depletion and mass transport limitations underscore the need for further optimization and development of diagnostic tools like CCC. Strategies for optimizing catalyst structure and operational parameters offer avenues for enhancing the performance and reliability of electrochemical CO 2 reduction catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hao Zhang, Menghui Qi, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01595-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of titanium dioxide-based electrocatalysts using in-liquid plasma method for carbon dioxide reduction and hydrogen formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115242</link>
      <description>Kai Takagi, Y.M. Hunge, Izumi Serizawa, Chiaki Terashima, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405835076

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Takagi, Y.M. Hunge, Izumi Serizawa, Chiaki Terashima</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of energy-related carbon dioxide intensity in China's major non-ferrous metal producing regions: Spatio-temporal decomposition and emission reduction strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.134299</link>
      <description>Zhu Su, Xin Li, Zhuang Zhang, Peng Zheng, Weihua Xu, Chang Zhang, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405847590

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhu Su, Xin Li, Zhuang Zhang, Peng Zheng, Weihua Xu, Chang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.134299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Effects in Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404057</link>
      <description>Siying Zhang, Weidong Ruan, Jingqi Guan, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405852538

                Abstract As a frontier method for adjusting the electronic and geometric configurations of metal sites, lattice strain engineering plays a key role in regulating the interaction between catalytic surface and adsorbed molecules. Here, the research progress of strain effects in electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction (CO 2 RR) is reviewed. Starting from the basic principles of strain effects in the CO 2 RR, the advanced in situ characterization techniques are summarized. The key effect of strain on the structure&#8211;activity relationship in CO 2 RR is comprehensively discussed. Subsequently, the electrocatalysts with different properties rich in strain are classified, including core&#8211;shell structure catalysts, alloys, transition metal compounds, and single&#8208;atom catalysts. Finally, the obstacles encountered in the practical application of strain effect are proposed, and the future research direction of this emerging field is prospected.</description>
      <author>Siying Zhang, Weidong Ruan, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of Copper Doping and Carbon Defect Engineering in Promoting C&#8211;C Coupling for Enhanced CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoreduction to Ethanol Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16101</link>
      <description>Yi Zhou, Yaqi Wang, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu, Yan Su, Xie Quan, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405884010

                Photocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) to fuel provides an ideal pathway to achieving carbon neutrality. One significant hindrance in achieving the reduction of CO2 to higher energy density multicarbon products (C2+) was the difficulty in coupling C&#8211;C bonds efficiently. Copper (Cu) is considered the most suitable metal catalyst for C&#8211;C coupling to form C2+ products in the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), but it encounters challenges such as low product selectivity and slow catalytic efficiency. Herein, we constructed a carbon defect on Cu-doped carbon nitride (Cu&#8211;CvN), as an efficient catalyst for photocatalytic CO2RR. The optimized catalyst (Cu&#8211;CvN-550) with a carbon defect shows high photocatalytic activity for CO2 reduction to ethanol, with an ethanol production rate of 122.6 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 and a selectivity of 93.7%. The yield was 4.5 times higher than that of the Cu&#8211;CN-550 without carbon defect. The ratio of Cu+/Cu0 in Cu species changes regularly with calcination temperature, which was linearly correlated with the selectivity of the liquid product of CO2RR. DFT calculations combined with experimental results revealed that Cu doping promoted CO2 activation, followed by enhanced *CO adsorption and weakened hydrogenation and desorption. Carbon defects lower the free energy and greatly accelerate the *CO transfer process by promoting the formation of a six-membered ring intermediate state, serving as an intramolecular catalyst for *CO dimerization. Synergistic thermodynamic and kinetic interactions were realized through Cu doping and the introduction of carbon defects, thereby enhancing the catalytic performance of photocatalytic reduction of CO2 for ethanol production.</description>
      <author>Yi Zhou, Yaqi Wang, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu, Yan Su, Xie Quan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow core-shell heterojunction TAPB-COF@ZnIn2S4 as high efficient photocatalysts for carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc07077a</link>
      <description>Hui-Tao Fan, Minglin Hu, Yabing Duan, Ronggui Yu, Zhuwei Li, Qi Liu, Lu-Yang Zuo, Bo Li, Liya Wang, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405890404

                The conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into carbon-neutral fuels using solar energy is crucial for achieving energy sustainability. However, the high carrier charge recombination and low CO2 adsorption capacity of...</description>
      <author>Hui-Tao Fan, Minglin Hu, Yabing Duan, Ronggui Yu, Zhuwei Li, Qi Liu, Lu-Yang Zuo, Bo Li, Liya Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc07077a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Dipole Moment Enhanced CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Adsorption on Copper Surface: Achieving 68.9% Catalytic Ethylene Faradaic Efficiency at 1.0 A cm&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;2&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202415092</link>
      <description>Chenbao Lu, Qichuan He, Senhe Huang, Pengfei Shi, Chongqing Yang, Jichao Zhang, Jinhui Zhu, Juan Zhang, Tianfu Wang, Xiaodong Zhuang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405890556

                Abstract The electrochemical conversion of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) into hydrocarbon products emerges as a pivotal sustainable strategy for carbon utilization. Cu&#8208;based catalysts are currently prioritized as the most effective means for this process, yet it remains a long&#8208;term goal to achieve high product selectivity at elevated current densities. This study delved into exploring the influence of a topological poly(2&#8208;aminoazulene) with a substantial dipole moment on modulating the Cu surface dipole field to augment the catalytic activity involved in CO 2 reduction. The resulting Cu/poly(2&#8208;aminoazulene) heterojunction showcases a remarkable ethylene Faradaic efficiency of 68.9% even at a substantial current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 . Through in situ Raman and in situ Fourier&#8208;transform infrared spectroscopy, poly(2&#8208;aminoazulene)&#8208;modified Cu electrode exhibits a heightened concentration of intermediates as compared to the bare Cu, proving advantageous for C&#8722;C dimerization. Theoretical calculations demonstrate the reduced energy barrier for C&#8722;C dimerization, and meanwhile impeding hydrogen evolution reaction on Cu/poly(2&#8208;aminoazulene) heterojunction, which are beneficial to CO 2 reduction. The catalyst design in this study, incorporating dipole moment considerations, not only investigates the influence of dipole moment on electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction but also pioneers an innovative strategy to augment catalytic activity by elevating the micro&#8208;concentration of reactants on catalyst surfaces.</description>
      <author>Chenbao Lu, Qichuan He, Senhe Huang, Pengfei Shi, Chongqing Yang, Jichao Zhang, Jinhui Zhu, Juan Zhang, Tianfu Wang, Xiaodong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202415092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green synthesis of two-dimensional copper nanomaterials using biomass for the reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61173/zc8fdz27</link>
      <description>Siyan Chen, Science and Technology of Engineering Chemistry and Environmental Protection. 1(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405930003

                The problem of greenhouse gas emissions has become increasingly severe, so energy conservation and emissions reduction have become a critical challenge for our society. In response to the challenge of lowering carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions and transforming them into valuable energy molecules, this work explores the eco-friendly preparation of two-dimensional (2D) nanocopper-based catalysts. In this study, biomass was utilized as both the reductant and the capping reagent to prepare these catalysts. The structure and morphology of the resulting products were analyzed using scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM). Their crystal structures were characterized by X-ray diffraction (XRD). The synthesis process of this type of nanomaterials was also studied. These copper-based catalysts were then evaluated for their efficiency in reducing CO2 into small energy molecules of HCOOH. A significant innovation of this study is using biomass as the reductant and capping agent, which guarantees the green synthesis process and exhibits great potential in converting CO2 into valuable energy molecules. This research is significant for creating new energy sources and protecting the environment.</description>
      <author>Siyan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61173/zc8fdz27</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CARBON DIOXIDE EMISSION REDUCTION USING COMBINED CLEANER PRODUCTION STRATEGY AND CARBON EMISSION PINCH ANALYSIS IN AN OFFSET PRINTING PLANT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31436/cnrej.v7i1.69</link>
      <description>Razuana Rahim, Raja Shazrin Shah Raja Ehsan Shah, Sarina Sulaiman, Roslan Abd. Rahman, No host. 7(1)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4405793952

                In this study, Cleaner Production (CP) strategy and Carbon Emission Pinch Analysis (CEPA) were used to reduce carbon dioxide (CO2) emission generated in printing industry. CP audit was conducted in a printing premise to quantify the consumption of materials and energy, waste generated and other aspect such as safety and productivity. The amount of CO2 emission generated from the operations and activities in the premise was estimated to identify key issues. Subsequently, CP options were identified to overcome the issues. Feasibility studies were conducted for each option identified to evaluate the reduction of CO2 emission and monetary returns. The study revealed that a total of 0.8 kg CO2 emission was generated per kg of paper processed, where electricity consumption was the main contributor. A total of eight CP options were identified and evaluated to reduce CO2 emission generated from the electricity consumption and solid waste generation. Implementations of the suggested CP options are expected to potentially reduce the CO2 emission to 0.7 tons CO2/kg of processed paper, which is a reduction of 78%. The CEPA study also demonstrated that a saving of 211,194 kWh/month of electricity and a reduction of CO2 emission of 141.5 tons/month (68%) from the total emission of 209 tons/month could be achieved. There are four CP options can be implemented without any cost incurred, with expected CO2 emission reduction of 96.5 tons/month. Hence, the case study proves that it is possible to reduce CO2 emission in printing premise by implementing CP and CEPA.</description>
      <author>Razuana Rahim, Raja Shazrin Shah Raja Ehsan Shah, Sarina Sulaiman, Roslan Abd. Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31436/cnrej.v7i1.69</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving factors and reduction paths dynamic simulation optimization of carbon dioxide emissions in China's construction industry under the perspective of dual carbon targets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eiar.2024.107789</link>
      <description>Yujie Xian, Huihui Wang, Zeyu Zhang, Yunsong Yang, Yuhao Zhong, Environmental Impact Assessment Review. 112(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405839007

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Xian, Huihui Wang, Zeyu Zhang, Yunsong Yang, Yuhao Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eiar.2024.107789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Volcanic Relationship of Model Molecular Catalysts in CO2 Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03912b</link>
      <description>Jin&#8208;Zhao Wang, Yang Xu, Anqi Wei, Julian Skagfj&#246;rd Reinhold, Wei Li-xin, Lei Shi, Yushuo Zhang, Shaofeng Liu, Chong Wang, Bo Zhang, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405902991

                We have constructed a series of model metal phthalocyanine (MPc) for the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR), constructed a volcano relationship through density functional theory (DFT) and experiments, and obtained...</description>
      <author>Jin&#8208;Zhao Wang, Yang Xu, Anqi Wei, Julian Skagfj&#246;rd Reinhold, Wei Li-xin, Lei Shi, Yushuo Zhang, Shaofeng Liu, Chong Wang, Bo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03912b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of carbon dioxide anion radical by UV/small molecular monocarboxylic acid system for reductive dechlorination of chlorinated alkanes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.12.025</link>
      <description>Li-Zhi Huang, Jingjing Lin, Weiguo Chen, Wei Wang, Yitao Dai, Ivan P. Pozdnyakov, Bingbing Hu, Journal of Environmental Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405808681

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li-Zhi Huang, Jingjing Lin, Weiguo Chen, Wei Wang, Yitao Dai, Ivan P. Pozdnyakov, Bingbing Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2024.12.025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approach to setting the attribution of CO2 reductions for CCU fuels &#8212; Toward a system counting fuel selection as an emission reduction effort</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31223/x5c139</link>
      <description>Naoki Matsuo, Kiyoto Tanabe, EarthArXiv (California Digital Library). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405813753

                As the global economy transitions towards carbon neutrality, innovative secondary energy sources are becoming increasingly pivotal. Hydrogen derived from zero-carbon power and synthetic fuels produced by bonding carbon dioxide (CO2) with hydrogen&#8212;hereafter referred to as Carbon Capture and Utilisation (CCU) fuels in this article&#8212;are expected to complement electricity as critical components in this transition. However, to incentivise the use of these alternatives, mechanisms must be in place to ensure that their adoption effectively translates into reductions in CO2 emissions for users. With this in mind, this paper reviews the current issues related to the &#8216;attribution&#8217; of GHG emissions or emission reductions for CCU fuels, reviews the current status and developments of the various relevant schemes, and identifies their challenges. It then categorises and proposes solutions: CCU fuel characteristics and challenges arising from its counting methods: CCU fuels are attracting attention for their potential as a new energy source that does not require changes to existing fossil fuel infrastructure and utilisation equipment. Although CCU fuels emit CO2 during combustion, their CO2 is recovered from what would otherwise be in the atmosphere, so long as the carbon content (C) of the fuel is focused on, fuel use does not increase global CO2 emissions. However, as long as the conventional counting rule&#8212;emissions are attributed to the physical emitting point&#8212;is applied, the fuel users are not incentivised to choose CCU fuels since they are identical to the fossil fuels under the rule. In order to design a system that promotes the use of CCU fuels, it is necessary to consider how to count the CO2 emissions associated with the production and use of CCU fuels, not bound by conventional approaches. In particular, clear international rules need to be set on which countries get the value of the emission reductions when they are traded crossing national borders. Approaches to international rule-making: Currently, the IPCC, ISO, EU, Japan and others are working on guidelines and rules directly or indirectly related to the handling of CCU fuels. Based on theoretical considerations and taking into account the content of these developments, this paper proposes the following approach: &#8226; Basically, CCU fuels are counted by the user as fuels with zero emission factor during combustion. At the same time, at the origin of the CCU fuel, the counting method is adopted: &#8216;CO2 captured and used for CCU fuel synthesis is considered as not captured for convenience&#8217;; &#8226; At the national level, possible approaches include (1) rule setting on the National GHG Inventory (IPCC Guidelines and relevant CMA decisions), which is used for accounting for the achievement of NDC targets; (2) adoption of national rules; and (3) transfer of ITMOs through bilateral agreements; &#8226; It is best to set national rules for companies in each country that are also consistent with them; and &#8226; Technically, the key point is how to guarantee &#8220;being CCU fuel&#8221; in the rules, such as certification of origin, and its emittability of captured CO2 in the baseline. The potential of CCU fuels can be maximised if the rules are set up in a way that is as easy to understand, common and workable as possible. To this end, instead of simply waiting for the completion of the IPCC methodology report and the subsequent discussions in the CMA of the Paris Agreement, it is desirable to continue to provide opportunities for all stakeholders, including governments and industry, to engage in dialogue and harmonise the rules, and to support discussions in the IPCC and UNFCCC.</description>
      <author>Naoki Matsuo, Kiyoto Tanabe</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31223/x5c139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acids: A Groundbreaking Approach to Converting CO2 into Fuels and Feedstocks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34133/research.0589</link>
      <description>Wenbo Wei, Haifei Liu, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu, Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405828441

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenbo Wei, Haifei Liu, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34133/research.0589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 reduction based on advanced Cu-based materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14711/thesis-991013340443503412</link>
      <description>Yinuo Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405916652

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) has exhibited great potential in alleviating the issue of global warming and producing value-added products within industrial production levels. Nevertheless, diversified reaction preferences on the catalyst and tedious reaction pathways for several target products impede the progress towards industrialization. Therefore, it is particularly important to obtain a comprehensive understanding of the relationship between the reaction preference (pathways and intermediates) and the structure of the catalyst and interface reaction, aiming to achieving effective generation of target product with high selectivity, high conversion rate and low overpotential. Cu has been considered as an extremely promising candidate for electrochemical CO2RR owing...[ Read more ]</description>
      <author>Yinuo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14711/thesis-991013340443503412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction for the selective production of liquid oxygenates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.022</link>
      <description>Jiapeng Ji, Junnan Chen, Juxia Xiong, Xiaolong Zhang, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405865361

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiapeng Ji, Junnan Chen, Juxia Xiong, Xiaolong Zhang, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameter sensitivity analysis for CO2 electrochemical reduction electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.174</link>
      <description>Yao Jiang, Tianzi Bi, Ming Cheng, Rui Xue, Shuiyun Shen, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 100(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405894773

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Jiang, Tianzi Bi, Ming Cheng, Rui Xue, Shuiyun Shen, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A bibliometric analysis of advances in CO2 reduction technology based on patents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.125193</link>
      <description>Ming-Yeah Hu, Yi Mu, Huile Jin, Applied Energy. 382(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405862519

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming-Yeah Hu, Yi Mu, Huile Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.125193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-modified Nb2O5 photocatalysts for high performance of CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113288</link>
      <description>Junli Chen, Tao Wang, Ziqi Yang, Pan Gao, Materials Research Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405915916

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junli Chen, Tao Wang, Ziqi Yang, Pan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning CO2 reduction selectivity via structural doping of TiO2 photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.103008</link>
      <description>Hana Kmentov&#225;, Miroslava Edelmannov&#225;, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Radek Zbo&#345;il, Lucie Obalov&#225;, &#352;t&#283;p&#225;n Kment, Kamila Ko&#269;&#237;, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 91(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405866146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hana Kmentov&#225;, Miroslava Edelmannov&#225;, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Radek Zbo&#345;il, Lucie Obalov&#225;, &#352;t&#283;p&#225;n Kment, Kamila Ko&#269;&#237;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.103008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando NMR quantifies liquid product, water crossover and carbonates for electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mdvvl-v2</link>
      <description>Zhengjun Zhu, Kaan &#199;olakhasano&#285;lu, Ruud L. E. G. Aspers, Joris Meurs, Simona M. Cristescu, Thomas Burdyny, Evan Wenbo Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405818327

                Operando analysis is crucial for understanding the selectivity and stability of the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR). Existing operando techniques normally adapt single-compartment cells operating at low currents. However, high current densities on the order of 100 mA cm-2 are required for practical applications, and under these conditions, selectivity and reaction pathways can differ. Here, we developed an inline operando NMR method compatible with high-current reaction conditions. Demonstrating on a copper-catalyzed eCO2RR at a current of 100 mA cm-2, our NMR study revealed a fast decrease of Faradaic efficiency for formate and ethanol within the first few hours of reaction, accompanied by a pH decrease from 14 to 8 within the first hour and a continuous concentration increase of bicarbonate. At 200 mA cm-2, the bicarbonate concentration reached the saturation point of 3.34 M within five hours. Water crossover was simultaneously observed and quantified via a deuteration technique and showed a strong current dependency. Our NMR observations revealed a highly dynamic environment of copper-catalyzed eCO2RR at high currents and will further aid the design and optimization of this reaction. Using on a common flow cell and a benchtop NMR system, the new operando approach is accessible by non-NMR experts and readily applicable to a wide range of catalysts, electrolyte compositions and reactor designs for eCO2RR.</description>
      <author>Zhengjun Zhu, Kaan &#199;olakhasano&#285;lu, Ruud L. E. G. Aspers, Joris Meurs, Simona M. Cristescu, Thomas Burdyny, Evan Wenbo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mdvvl-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Cu-Based Catalyst for Electrochemical Co2 Reduction Using Incorporated Ni</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5076335</link>
      <description>Jianping Li, Siyu Kuang, Yaxin Jin, Haoyuan Chi, Sheng Zhang, Xinbin Ma, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405891310

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianping Li, Siyu Kuang, Yaxin Jin, Haoyuan Chi, Sheng Zhang, Xinbin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5076335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Use of an Rh-Intercalated Sic/Graphene Interface for Co2 Electrochemical Reduction: A Theoretical Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5073567</link>
      <description>Karin Larsson, M. R. Ashwin Kishore, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405834455

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karin Larsson, M. R. Ashwin Kishore</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5073567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for dopant selection in Cu catalysts to promote the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction for ethylene production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.030</link>
      <description>Dogyeong Kim, Seohyeon Ka, Man Ho Han, Woong Kim, Seungho Yu, Jae&#8208;Young Choi, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Woong Hee Lee, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405926186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dogyeong Kim, Seohyeon Ka, Man Ho Han, Woong Kim, Seungho Yu, Jae&#8208;Young Choi, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Woong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zinc oxides by thermal decomposition synthesis and parameters affecting electrocatalyst activity for CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oceram.2024.100733</link>
      <description>El&#237;as Rodr&#237;guez-Jara, Margherita Cavallo, Ryosuke Nakazato, Matthias Quintelier, Keeko Matsumoto, Joke Hadermann, Jadra Mosa, Francesca Bonino, Kiyoharu Tadanaga, M. Aparicio, Nataly Carolina Rosero&#8208;Navarro, Open Ceramics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405865362

                No abstract</description>
      <author>El&#237;as Rodr&#237;guez-Jara, Margherita Cavallo, Ryosuke Nakazato, Matthias Quintelier, Keeko Matsumoto, Joke Hadermann, Jadra Mosa, Francesca Bonino, Kiyoharu Tadanaga, M. Aparicio, Nataly Carolina Rosero&#8208;Navarro</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oceram.2024.100733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DMSO catalyzed CO2 reduction with 9-BBN: selective formation of either formoxy- or methoxyborane under mild conditions and C-methylenation of indoles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a</link>
      <description>Ganesan Mani, Ashok Kumar, Rohit Gupta, Vasudevan Subramaniyan, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405859581

                An efficient and selective reduction of CO2 to formoxy- and methoxyboranes under mild conditions paves the way to economically produce formic acid and methanol, which are alternative sources of energy....</description>
      <author>Ganesan Mani, Ashok Kumar, Rohit Gupta, Vasudevan Subramaniyan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimation for Reduction Potential Evaluation of CO2 Emissions from Individual Private Passenger Cars Using Telematics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010064</link>
      <description>Masahiro Mae, Ziyang Wang, Shoma Nishimura, Ryuji Matsuhashi, Energies. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405832138

                CO2 emissions from gas-powered cars have a large impact on global warming. The aim of this paper is to develop an accurate estimation method of CO2 emissions from individual private passenger cars by using actual driving data obtained by telematics. CO2 emissions from gas-powered cars vary depending on various factors such as car models and driving behavior. The developed approach uses actual monthly driving data from telematics and vehicle features based on drag force. Machine learning based on random forest regression enables better estimation performance of CO2 emissions compared to conventional multiple linear regression. CO2 emissions from individual private passenger cars in 24 car models are estimated by the machine learning model based on random forest regression using data from telematics, and the coefficient of determination for all 24 car models is R2=0.981. The estimation performance for interpolation and extrapolation of car models is also evaluated, and it keeps enough estimation accuracy with slight performance degradation. The case study with actual telematics data is conducted to analyze the relationship between driving behavior and monthly CO2 emissions in similar driving record conditions. The result shows the possibility of reducing CO2 emissions by eco-driving. The accurate estimation of the reduced amount of CO2 estimated by the machine learning model enables valuing it as carbon credits to motivate the eco-driving of individual drivers.</description>
      <author>Masahiro Mae, Ziyang Wang, Shoma Nishimura, Ryuji Matsuhashi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deficient Moo2 Facilitating Photothermal Synergetic Catalytic Co2 Reduction Selectively to Co Over P-Doped G-C3n4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5073509</link>
      <description>Hailong Cao, Fengyun Su, Linbo Wang, Yezhen Zhang, Yonghao Xiao, Xiaoli Jin, Xin Li, Haiquan Xie, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405848695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hailong Cao, Fengyun Su, Linbo Wang, Yezhen Zhang, Yonghao Xiao, Xiaoli Jin, Xin Li, Haiquan Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5073509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-stable catalyst for enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction: g-C3N4-derived porous C/N-modified ZnNi2O4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-06032-z</link>
      <description>Xinming Yang, Ya Gao, Liang Li, Jinglei Yang, Yufei Yan, Xuejiao Huang, Ling Wang, Zheng Yuan, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405887305

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinming Yang, Ya Gao, Liang Li, Jinglei Yang, Yufei Yan, Xuejiao Huang, Ling Wang, Zheng Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-06032-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An integrated design method for CO2 emission reduction based on industrial metabolism:Hybrid carbon-hydrogen metallurgy manufacturing process (HCHMP)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144595</link>
      <description>J. Chen, Qiang Sun, Qingshan Gong, Mengzhen Wang, Teng Hu, Zhenyu Huang, Gang Zhao, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405846973

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Chen, Qiang Sun, Qingshan Gong, Mengzhen Wang, Teng Hu, Zhenyu Huang, Gang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "DMSO catalyzed CO2 reduction with 9-BBN: selective formation of either formoxy- or methoxyborane under mild conditions and C-methylenation of indoles"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864226

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "DMSO catalyzed CO2 reduction with 9-BBN: selective formation of either formoxy- or methoxyborane under mild conditions and C-methylenation of indoles"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864244

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT study on the structural properties and CO2 electrocatalytic reduction activity of monolayer graphitic carbon nitride supported Ag/Au single atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122692</link>
      <description>Hui-Ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405882115

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui-Ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "DMSO catalyzed CO2 reduction with 9-BBN: selective formation of either formoxy- or methoxyborane under mild conditions and C-methylenation of indoles"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864374

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "DMSO catalyzed CO2 reduction with 9-BBN: selective formation of either formoxy- or methoxyborane under mild conditions and C-methylenation of indoles"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Ganesan Mani, Ashok Kumar, Rohit Gupta, Vasudevan Subramaniyan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864236

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ganesan Mani, Ashok Kumar, Rohit Gupta, Vasudevan Subramaniyan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "DMSO catalyzed CO2 reduction with 9-BBN: selective formation of either formoxy- or methoxyborane under mild conditions and C-methylenation of indoles"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864445

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "DMSO catalyzed CO2 reduction with 9-BBN: selective formation of either formoxy- or methoxyborane under mild conditions and C-methylenation of indoles"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v3/response1</link>
      <description>Ganesan Mani, Ashok Kumar, Rohit Gupta, Vasudevan Subramaniyan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864451

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ganesan Mani, Ashok Kumar, Rohit Gupta, Vasudevan Subramaniyan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v3/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "DMSO catalyzed CO2 reduction with 9-BBN: selective formation of either formoxy- or methoxyborane under mild conditions and C-methylenation of indoles"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v3/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864503

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v3/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "DMSO catalyzed CO2 reduction with 9-BBN: selective formation of either formoxy- or methoxyborane under mild conditions and C-methylenation of indoles"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864228

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01327a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantification Of Greenhouse Gas Emissions in a Cement Company and System Dynamics Modeling Toward Carbon Neutral</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.23969/jcbeem.v9i1.20395</link>
      <description>Rizky Tazkia Arethusya Harijanto, Kania Dewi, Agus Wahyudi, Journal of Community Based Environmental Engineering and Management. 9(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405860512

                The cement industry is one of the sectors that produces carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions due to its raw material processing and energy requirements. CO2, as a greenhouse gas (GHG) emission, contributes to global warming, leading to environmental, health, and economic losses. To address these issues, Indonesia is committed to reducing GHG emissions in the industrial sector by 2050. To effectively plan for the reduction of GHG emissions generated by companies, this study aims to quantify emissions from a cement company, representing the cement industry in Indonesia, to understand the current state of the company's carbon footprint and identify feasible mitigation measures. The cement industry utilizes a GHG quantification system to calculate emissions from raw material processing, thermal energy consumption, and electricity purchases. The calculation results from a cement company are used for system dynamics modeling with Vensim PLE software for the period from 2021 to 2050, under business-as-usual (BAU) conditions with various emission reduction strategies. The results show that GHG emissions under BAU conditions with emission reduction strategies do not achieve carbon neutrality by 2050. More intensive adoption of decarbonization technologies, research on process optimization, and government policies such as carbon taxes and carbon trading are required to achieve carbon neutral goals.</description>
      <author>Rizky Tazkia Arethusya Harijanto, Kania Dewi, Agus Wahyudi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.23969/jcbeem.v9i1.20395</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Analysis of an Ammonia Combustion System for Future Two-Stroke Low-Speed Marine Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse13010039</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Serrano, Ricardo Novella, H&#233;ctor Climent, F.J. Arnau, Alejandro Calvo, Lauge Thorsen, Journal of Marine Science and Engineering. 13(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405934084

                Ammonia, being 17.6% hydrogen by mass, is regarded as a hydrogen carrier and carbon-free fuel as long as its production methods rely on renewable energy sources. The production and combustion of green ammonia do not generate carbon dioxide, offering a promising avenue for substantial reductions in greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from a well-to-wake perspective. This paper presents a comprehensive methodology for the development and validation of a thermodynamic model for a two-stroke low-speed marine engine incorporating a hybrid ammonia-diesel diffusion combustion system. The simulation tools are rigorously validated using experimental data obtained during diesel operation. Subsequently, the study explores various aspects of the novel ammonia-diesel combustion system, addressing combustion and emissions characteristics. The investigation incorporates diverse simulation scenarios involving direct fuel injection through dedicated valves into the cylinder head of a six-cylinder, turbocharged compression-ignition engine. The engine features two diesel injection valves, employed to initiate the combustion process, and two ammonia injection valves. Simulation scenarios include variations in the injection timing of the pilot diesel injector and the relative orientation of diesel and ammonia sprays. Case C emerges as the preferred configuration, demonstrating superior metrics in terms of combustion stability, air-fuel mixing, and emissions profile compared to other cases. The results indicate a reduction of CO2 emissions of approximately 95% in mass compared to the baseline diesel operation. Furthermore, notable reductions in NOx emissions are observed, preliminarily attributed to the lower flame temperature of ammonia. Despite the appearance of N2O emissions as a result of ammonia oxidation, the overall potential reduction in GHG emissions, in CO2-equivalent terms, exceeds 85% at selected operating points. This work contributes valuable insights into the optimization of cleaner propulsion systems for maritime applications, facilitating the industry&#8217;s transition toward more sustainable and environmentally friendly practices.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Serrano, Ricardo Novella, H&#233;ctor Climent, F.J. Arnau, Alejandro Calvo, Lauge Thorsen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse13010039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palm Oil Biomass Supply Chain Multi-Objective Two-Echelon Location-Routing Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47836/mjms.18.4.12</link>
      <description>F. Y. Foo, Zaitul Marlizawati Zainuddin, Seepheng Hang, Malaysian Journal of Mathematical Sciences. 18(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405793851

                Malaysia generates substantial agricultural residues annually, endowing the country with significant biomass energy potential. Palm oil biomass stands out as a promising feedstock. However, its high humidity, bulkiness, low energy density, and dispersed resource locations (mills) pose challenges. A network that consisting collection facilities incorporating pretreatment operations as intermediaries between mills and biorefineries is a plausible solution. Nevertheless, the facility locations directly impact travel distance, overall expenses, and the nearby population. Moreover, vehicle routing during biomass collection influences transportation costs and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions. Consequently, this research designs a model to address the location-routing intricacies within a two-echelon biomass supply chain. The model operates as a multi-objective optimization framework, encompassing three-dimensional sustainability assessment, quantified respectively as total cost minimization, CO2 emissions reduction, and minimization of the population affected. The research initially optimizes each objective function individually and subsequently advances to multi-objective optimization employing the weighted sum approach. While single-objective optimization yields optimal outcomes for each dimension, enhancements in one aspect may hinder performance in others. Nonetheless, the multi-objective optimization provides insight into the trade-offs among the sustainability objectives. The computational findings demonstrate the model could adapt the network configuration in alignment with distinct sustainability aspirations.</description>
      <author>F. Y. Foo, Zaitul Marlizawati Zainuddin, Seepheng Hang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47836/mjms.18.4.12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unintended consequences: market integration and enterprise carbon emissions &#8212;&#8212;based on the analytical perspective of county-to-district reform</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/14631377.2024.2437730</link>
      <description>Jun Liu, Shengjun Zhu, Canfei He, Yan Xu, Haoxiang Shen, Post-Communist Economies. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405795329

                The county-to-district reform, as an important measure to break down administrative barriers between cities and counties and promote market integration, raises the question of whether it influences enterprise carbon emissions behaviour. By utilising data from 1992 to 2019 and matching it with patent data for Chinese listed companies, this paper examines the impact of the county-to-district reform on enterprise carbon emissions. The findings show that the reform accelerates market integration, facilitates the free flow of production factors, thus expanding the scale of enterprise production and increasing total carbon dioxide emissions from enterprises. Meanwhile, this process alleviates financing constraints for enterprises and increases the proportion of research and development investment on one hand; on the other hand, the reform intensifies market competition, thereby improving enterprise productivity. Ultimately, this leads to a reduction in overall carbon emission intensity. This phenomenon is particularly evident in non-state-owned enterprises, non-carbon trading pilot regions, northern regions, and small and medium-sized enterprises. This paper explores the impact of changes in China's government power structure on enterprise carbon emissions behaviour, adding to the research on the role of micro-level enterprises in carbon reduction during the county-to-district reform process.</description>
      <author>Jun Liu, Shengjun Zhu, Canfei He, Yan Xu, Haoxiang Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/14631377.2024.2437730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Effectiveness of Ocean Iron Fertilization for the Carbon-Uptake Efficacy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.173557508.81096097/v1</link>
      <description>Kyung Min Noh, Xiao Liu, Charles A. Stock, John P. Dunne, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405892727

                Rapidly increasing carbon dioxide emissions over the past decades and the possibility of further increases in coming decades has motivated global efforts to remove and sequester carbon from atmosphere. Among recent proposals for marine-based Carbon Dioxide Removal (mCDR), ocean iron-fertilization has been revisited, although its efficacy on a global scale remains uncertain. We thus assessed the carbon uptake efficacy in small (~GgC) and large (~PgC) scales in the global coupled earth system model, GFDL-ESM4.1. Our simulations indicate that large-scale fertilization yields greater carbon uptake efficacies than small-scale fertilization. Efficacies in large-scale fertilization are from 179% to 225% higher than small-scale fertilization in the Equatorial Pacific and Southern Ocean, but were more comparable in the North Pacific. Higher carbon uptake efficacies in large-scale fertilization are attributed to greater accumulation of dissolved iron within the fertilized region. While our results emphasize the carbon uptake efficacy benefits of a large-scale approach over the fertilized area, some of additional carbon uptake is compensated by reduced uptake in the non-fertilized oceans. This study finds that 80% and 85% of the carbon taken up in the Equatorial and North Pacific are compensated by decreases in carbon uptake elsewhere, implying that outside of the Southern Ocean major nutrients would have been taken up in non-fertilized regions, leaving little carbon additionality. This study puts into serious question the net benefits and further exposes risks iron fertilization, such as reduction of productions in the Equatorial Pacific, as a large scale mCDR approach outside of the Southern Ocean.</description>
      <author>Kyung Min Noh, Xiao Liu, Charles A. Stock, John P. Dunne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.173557508.81096097/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[N</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202401277</link>
      <description>S. Y. Huang, Xiuhong Liu, Xi Cao, Junxia L&#252;, Cheng Huang, PubMed. 46(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405857066

                To achieve non-carbon dioxide greenhouse gas emission reduction and control in municipal wastewater treatment plants &#65288;WWTPs&#65289;, this study conducted one-year long-term monitoring of nitrous oxide &#65288;N</description>
      <author>S. Y. Huang, Xiuhong Liu, Xi Cao, Junxia L&#252;, Cheng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202401277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest Cover and Above Ground Carbon Stock Dynamics Assessment and Mapping over Middle Awash River Basin, Ethiopia: Implications for Climate Change Resilience</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202412.2066.v1</link>
      <description>Bereket Abera Bedada, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405782540

                The objective of this study is to investigate the temporal variation of forest cover and carbon stock change within the Middle Awash River Basin in Ethiopia, focusing on the years 1995, 2010, and 2023. The study utilized multi-temporal Landsat imagery and Google Earth Engine cloud API platform and employed the Random Forest Algorithm for LULC classification. The above-ground carbon stock in the present study was computed from total forest cover of the basin. The results indicate a significant decline in forest cover within the Basin, which decreased from 1,521.88 km&amp;sup2; in 1995 to 1,174.10 km&amp;sup2; in 2010 and further to 825.20 km&amp;sup2; by 2023. Alongside this reduction, total wood volume and dry matter biomass also experienced declines, with wood volume falling from 876.28 m&amp;sup3; to 676.03 m&amp;sup3;, and then to 475.14 m&amp;sup3;, while dry matter biomass decreased from 376.80 tons to 290.69 tons, and finally to 204.31 tons. These trends highlight a troubling reduction in carbon stock and an increase in carbon dioxide emissions. Overall, the gradual decline in carbon stocks and the loss of forest cover within the basin highlight the urgent need to implement effective conservation strategies aimed at restoring and safeguarding the remaining forest ecosystems.</description>
      <author>Bereket Abera Bedada</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202412.2066.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A study on elevated carbon dioxide (eCO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;), elevated temperature (eT) and their interactive effect on chickpea (&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Cicer arietinum&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; L.) yield and seed mineral nutrients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31018/jans.v16i4.6162</link>
      <description>Sadhna Maurya, A. K. Chopra, Journal of Applied and Natural Science. 16(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405840008

                Continuously increasing carbon dioxide concentration is predicted to elevate the earth&#8217;s temperature. Elevated temperature is a severe problem for the cultivation of chickpea (Cicer arietinum L ). Therefore, the present study aimed to assess the effect of elevated carbon dioxide (eCO2), elevated temperature (eT) and their interactive effect on yield and seed mineral nutrients of two genotypes, i.e., ICC 4958 (desi) and Flip 90-166 (kabuli) of chickpea (C. arietinum L ). The pot experiments were conducted in Open Top Chamber (OTC) for two consecutive years (2019-20 and 2020-21), along with the control placed in ambient natural conditions. The eCO2 (650&#177;50 &#181;l/l) and eT (~4oC) were given individually and in combination. The gaseous exchange was measured at the flowering stage. After harvesting, yield and its parameters, seed protein and mineral nutrients were determined using standard methods. Under eCO2, the photosynthesis of both genotypes was positively affected, ultimately converting to yield (8.8-17.5% increase). However, the effect was more prominent in ICC 4958 than Flip 90-166. Higher temperature only positively affected dry biomass, but that effect was not converted to yield; instead, a reduction occurred in yield (- 12.0 to -26.9% ). In combination with eCO2 and eT, the negative effect of high temperature was ameliorated by eCO2 on yield, augmenting the effects on seed nutrient reduction. Among the seed mineral nutrients, Na, K, Fe and Zn were most reduced (-20.3 to -30.0%) under interactive effect. The findings will help to enhance seed yield with improved mineral nutrient content of chickpea.</description>
      <author>Sadhna Maurya, A. K. Chopra</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31018/jans.v16i4.6162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Systematic Analysis of Progress in Doping Combustion Characterization of Ammonia-Fueled Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/66z1jh50</link>
      <description>Zicong Wang, Qingjun Zhou, Highlights in Science Engineering and Technology. 120(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405902207

                In the global environment of carbon emission reduction, diesel engine emissions of carbon dioxide, nitrogen oxide and other harmful gases seriously polluting the environment has been boycotted by governments around the world. Ammonia, as a clean, environment-friendly, easy-to-transport green energy, has broad application prospects. However, due to its poor combustion performance and high calorific value, there are some limitations in its application. In this paper, the mechanism, combustion characteristics and emission characteristics of an engine fueled with ammonia-hydrogen fuel and ammonia-carbon-based fuel are reviewed. Hydrogen fuel and diesel fuel with low ignition energy and fast laminar flame spread characteristics, can make up the shortage of pure ammonia fuel, reduce nitrogen oxide emissions. Among them, hydrogen ammonia fuel has become the mainstream and the most promising fuel, compared with pure ammonia fuel and ammonia diesel fuel has the advantages of clean, low transport costs, fast combustion and so on, will become the future engine main application fuel.</description>
      <author>Zicong Wang, Qingjun Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/66z1jh50</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulation and Pathway Selection for China&#8217;s Carbon Peak: A Multi-Objective Nonlinear Dynamic Optimization Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010154</link>
      <description>Liang Shen, Qiheng Yuan, Qi He, Peng Jiang, H. Ji, Junyi Shi, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405920264

                This study innovatively develops a multi-objective Markal-Macro model, which simultaneously considers three objectives: minimizing carbon emissions from energy consumption, minimizing carbon emissions from production processes, and maximizing societal welfare. Based on the Cobb&#8211;Douglas production function, we construct a production function of carbon emission and use it as a coupling equation of the Markal-Macro model (Markal is the abbreviation of market allocation, and Macro is the abbreviation of macroeconomy). This enables the coupling of the endogenous variables of carbon emissions and those related to maximizing societal welfare. By collecting relevant data on energy consumption, production outputs, and key economic indicators, five different scenarios are established. To enhance the computational efficiency of the simulation, we introduce a Firefly Algorithm into the penalty function method. The objective of our simulation is to explore the optimal carbon peak pathway for China. The results indicate that under the baseline scenario, China can achieve its carbon peak by 2029, with the peak value reaching approximately 12.5 billion tons of carbon dioxide. Finally, based on the simulation results, this study provides specific policy recommendations for China&#8217;s carbon peak pathway, addressing aspects such as industrial structure, energy consumption structure, the share of clean energy, economic growth targets, and the growth of emission reduction expenditures, while considering regional five-year plans and regional carbon peak strategies. From the aspect of the practical contributions, this article not only provides a set of methods for policymakers to make the Carbon Peak Implementation Plan but also offers an optimal path to improve the sustainable development for China.</description>
      <author>Liang Shen, Qiheng Yuan, Qi He, Peng Jiang, H. Ji, Junyi Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ENHANCING URBAN MICRO-MOBILITY: ENVIRONMENTAL IMPACT OF INTEGRATED BIKE SHARING AT COMMUTER RAIL STATIONS IN YOGYAKARTA URBANIZED AREA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14710/jpk.12.1.74-85</link>
      <description>Damar Pratita Dewayanto, Derin Marshall, Jurnal Pengembangan Kota. 12(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405877477

                Climate change, particularly CO2 emissions from the transportation sector, poses a significant global challenge. Promoting micro-mobility services, especially bike sharing programs, is crucial in addressing this issue. This study examines the environmental benefits of integrating bike sharing programs with public transportation by estimating the potential CO2 emission reductions through the avoided motorized trips approach. Data were collected via a commuter line passenger survey in the Yogyakarta Urbanized Area, resulting in 157 valid responses. The estimation considered specific data inputs: trip distance, emission factor, energy factor of transportation mode, and the number of people traveling by mode. Two scenarios related to bike sharing demand and commuter line ridership were employed. The findings reveal that bike sharing demand ranges from 16.03% to 48.08%. In terms of CO2 emissions reduction, the study indicates that avoided motorized trips through bike sharing as an egress mode can potentially reduce cumulative CO2 emissions by up to 567,158.35 tons CO2e by 2030. This reduction corresponds to 0.487% and 160.113% of the national and provincial reduction targets, respectively. These findings provide insightful information to promote sustainable transportation provision.</description>
      <author>Damar Pratita Dewayanto, Derin Marshall</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14710/jpk.12.1.74-85</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid CIGS&#8208;Cobalt Quaterpyridine Photocathode with Backside Illumination: a New Paradigm for Solar Fuel Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423727</link>
      <description>Marc Robert, Hichem Ichou, L&#233;o Choubrac, Garen Suna, Debashrita Sarkar, Paulo Jorge Marques Cordeiro, St&#233;phane Diring, Fabien Pineau, Julien Bonin, Nicolas Barreau, Fabrice Odobel, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405927295

                Chalcogenide&#8208;based thin&#8208;film solar cell optimized for rear illumination and used for CO2 reduction is presented. Central to this innovation is a thinner, Cu(In,Ga)S2 chalcopyrite absorber coated with a robust metallic top layer, which potentially surpasses the performance of conventional front&#8208;illuminated designs. Using cobalt quaterpyridine molecular catalyst, photocurrent densities for CO2 reduction exceeding 10 mA/cm2 at 0.0 V vs. RHE under 1 Sun illumination, and ca. 16 mA/cm2 at &#8208;0.25 V vs. RHE were achieved in voltammetry experiments. Controlled potential electrolysis showed catalytic activity over 20 h with selectivity for CO ranging from &gt; 92% (first 4 hours) to 86% at the end of the experiment. This approach opens limitless possibilities for employing various reduction catalysts, extending far beyond CO2 reduction. It imposes minimal constraints on absorption properties, immobilization methods, and catalyst nature, setting the stage for high&#8208;performance, adaptable PEC devices.</description>
      <author>Marc Robert, Hichem Ichou, L&#233;o Choubrac, Garen Suna, Debashrita Sarkar, Paulo Jorge Marques Cordeiro, St&#233;phane Diring, Fabien Pineau, Julien Bonin, Nicolas Barreau, Fabrice Odobel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Dicarboxylation of Vinyl Epoxide with CO2 for the Facile and Selective Synthesis of Diacids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419702</link>
      <description>Deyong Yang, Ying Sun, Nan Feng, Yuqing Zhong, Jian Zhou, Feng Zhou, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405868065

                We present a novel electrochemical dicarboxylation of epoxides with CO2, characterized by the cleavage of two C&#8211;O single bonds. Not only are vinyl epoxides viable, but cyclic carbonates also serve as effective substrates, facilitating the synthesis of E&#8208;configured adipic and octanedioic acids with high chemo&#8208;, regio&#8208;, and stereoselectivity. The synthetic practicality is further highlighted by the diverse functionalizations of the resulting multifunctional diacids. Mechanistic studies support the single&#8208;electron transfer reduction of CO2 to its radical anion, which undergoes radical addition to the vinyl moiety of epoxides. The subsequent reductive cleavage of two C&#8211;O bonds, coupled with a nucleophilic attack on CO2, culminates in the formation of the desired diacid products.</description>
      <author>Deyong Yang, Ying Sun, Nan Feng, Yuqing Zhong, Jian Zhou, Feng Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Dicarboxylation of Vinyl Epoxide with CO2 for the Facile and Selective Synthesis of Diacids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419702</link>
      <description>Deyong Yang, Ying Sun, Nan Feng, Yuqing Zhong, Jian Zhou, Feng Zhou, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405868524

                We present a novel electrochemical dicarboxylation of epoxides with CO2, characterized by the cleavage of two C&#8211;O single bonds. Not only are vinyl epoxides viable, but cyclic carbonates also serve as effective substrates, facilitating the synthesis of E&#8208;configured adipic and octanedioic acids with high chemo&#8208;, regio&#8208;, and stereoselectivity. The synthetic practicality is further highlighted by the diverse functionalizations of the resulting multifunctional diacids. Mechanistic studies support the single&#8208;electron transfer reduction of CO2 to its radical anion, which undergoes radical addition to the vinyl moiety of epoxides. The subsequent reductive cleavage of two C&#8211;O bonds, coupled with a nucleophilic attack on CO2, culminates in the formation of the desired diacid products.</description>
      <author>Deyong Yang, Ying Sun, Nan Feng, Yuqing Zhong, Jian Zhou, Feng Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of driving restrictions on air pollution and public health in Beijing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/pb7epv23</link>
      <description>Tianxin Lu, Highlights in Science Engineering and Technology. 121(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405810940

                This paper investigates the impact of road traffic-related air pollution on public health in Beijing and evaluates the effectiveness of driving restriction policies in mitigating both traffic congestion and environmental pollution. With Beijing facing severe air quality challenges due to rapid urbanization and increased vehicle use, various measures have been implemented over the years to improve air quality. The 2008 Beijing Olympics served as a catalyst for stricter emissions controls and vehicle restrictions, leading to a reduction in pollutants such as nitrogen dioxide (NO2) and particulate matter (PM). This study traces the evolution of these policies, assesses their effectiveness in reducing air pollution and carbon emissions, and examines the broader public health implications. The paper concludes that while significant progress has been made, further innovations such as low-emission zones and congestion pricing could help address the remaining challenges of air pollution and traffic congestion in the city.</description>
      <author>Tianxin Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/pb7epv23</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life cycle GHG emissions reduction of an integrated CCUS system for combined heat and power plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4491/eer.2024.446</link>
      <description>Sora Yi, Junbeum Kim, Environmental Engineering Research. 30(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405913875

                The carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS) technologies have shown promise for directly reducing the amount of CO2 released into the atmosphere from significant point sources. This study aims to evaluate an integrated CCUS system in South Korea using three technologies: microalgae photocultivation, CO2 membrane separation, and carbon mineralization. LCAs showed the total GHG emissions, excluding carbon offset effects, were 358 kg CO2 eq/ton, with 95.8% from CO2 membrane separation. Microalgae and mineralization emitted 14.6 kg CO2 eq/ton (4.1%) and 0.371 kg CO2 eq/ton (0.1%), respectively. Including carbon offsets from CaCO3 production and CO2 utilization, the system's net emissions were -745 kg CO2 eq/ton. Further economic studies are needed, but the study confirmed the system's high GHG reduction efficiency through LCA, enhancing the potential use of CCUS technologies in urban CHP plants.</description>
      <author>Sora Yi, Junbeum Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4491/eer.2024.446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving factors of CO2 emissions in southeast China: Comparative study of long-term trends, short-term fluctuations, and spatial variations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1525/elementa.2023.00028</link>
      <description>Yimin Huang, Wei-Sheng Lin, Yuan Wang, Haiping Luo, Zhu Lin, Yanmin He, Feng Wang, Wen-ting Lai, Rui Shi, Elementa Science of the Anthropocene. 12(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405935317

                This study explores the factors driving CO2 emissions related to energy use in Fujian Province from 2000 to 2019, with an emphasis on long-term trends, short-term fluctuations, and spatial disparities. Utilizing annual data on CO2 emissions and various influencing factors from multiple cities within Fujian Province, we examine the factors driving long-term changes in CO2 emissions. To analyze short-term emission trajectories, we employ a temporal decomposition model, while spatial decomposition techniques are used to assess the variability in emission drivers across 9 prefecture-level cities over different years. Our findings reveal an inverted U-shaped relationship between CO2 emissions and urbanization over the 20-year study period. Furthermore, short-term fluctuations indicate a gradual reduction in the impact of urbanization on the increase in CO2 emissions within the industrial, transportation, and household sectors in Fujian Province. Additionally, economic development, measured as per capita gross domestic product, is shown to significantly influence CO2 emissions. Efforts to reduce energy intensity, which refers to the amount of energy consumed per unit of economic output, in both the industrial and household sectors are identified as potential strategies for emission reduction. The variability in CO2 emissions among cities is primarily attributed to differences in energy intensity and population sizes. These insights are critical for formulating policies aimed at promoting low-carbon development, reducing carbon emissions, and enhancing sustainability throughout Fujian Province.</description>
      <author>Yimin Huang, Wei-Sheng Lin, Yuan Wang, Haiping Luo, Zhu Lin, Yanmin He, Feng Wang, Wen-ting Lai, Rui Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1525/elementa.2023.00028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How formation water impacts CO2 miscible flooding in low-permeability reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0243596</link>
      <description>Ying Dai, Hu Jia, Zili Zhou, Hao Hu, Physics of Fluids. 36(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405829457

                Carbon capture, utilization, and storage for enhanced oil recovery (CCUS-EOR) is a key technology for mitigating carbon emissions. The effects of CO2 miscible flooding on EOR after water flooding in low-permeability reservoirs are highly uncertain. This work establishes a comprehensive model for CO2 miscible flooding in low-permeability reservoirs, taking into account processes such as dissolution and trapping of formation water. The model simulates the miscible behavior of CO2 and crude oil under various formation water conditions. The conclusions are as follows: formation water exhibits dissolution and trapping phenomena with injected CO2 and crude oil, leading to a loss of effective CO2 volume, a reduction in recoverable crude oil volume, and a delay of response of CO2 miscible flooding; a minimal quantity of movable water can limit CO2 fingering, while an abundant amount can hinder CO2-oil contact; ignoring the microscopic mechanisms between water, CO2, or oil can overestimate the CO2-oil miscible process, miscible degree, and miscible flooding efficiency. These conclusions help further understand the mechanisms of CO2 miscible flooding to enhance oil recovery in high-water saturation low-permeability reservoirs and provide references and insights for CO2 capture and reservoir development.</description>
      <author>Ying Dai, Hu Jia, Zili Zhou, Hao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0243596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Economic and Environmental Factors on the Consumption of Renewable Energy: The Case of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47703/ejebs.v68i4.443</link>
      <description>Akmaral Smatayeva, Zhansaya Temerbulatova, &#1058;&#1086;&#1083;&#1082;&#1099;&#1085; &#1050;&#1072;&#1082;&#1080;&#1078;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Eurasian Journal of Economic and Business Studies. 68(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405885347

                The article examines the impact of economic and environmental factors on the consumption of renewable energy sources (RES) in Kazakhstan. The study is based on a quantitative analysis of data, including adjusted net savings (ANS), the share of renewable electricity output (REO), and carbon dioxide (CO&#8322;) emissions per capita. The dependent variable in this analysis is the share of renewable energy in the total final energy consumption. The results of the regression analysis revealed the following relationships: an increase in the share of electricity production from renewable energy sources (REO) by 1% leads to an increase in their consumption by 0.119% (p &lt; 0.01), which is associated with reduced production costs and improved accessibility. Adjusted net savings (ANS) also have a positive effect: their growth by 1% increases renewable energy consumption by 0.055% (p &lt; 0.05), confirming the role of economic stability and investment in the development of green energy. At the same time, an increase in CO&#8322; emissions negatively affects renewable energy consumption, decreasing it by 0.154% for each additional ton of CO&#8322; per capita (p &lt; 0.01), which is explained by the predominance of traditional hydrocarbon energy sources. The study highlights that the sustainable development of renewable energy sources requires a comprehensive approach, including the stimulation of its production, reduction of carbon emissions, and maintenance of economic stability. The results have practical value for the formation of Kazakhstan's state policy aimed at transition to sustainable energy and reducing environmental pressure.</description>
      <author>Akmaral Smatayeva, Zhansaya Temerbulatova, &#1058;&#1086;&#1083;&#1082;&#1099;&#1085; &#1050;&#1072;&#1082;&#1080;&#1078;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47703/ejebs.v68i4.443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constraining CO2 Coverage on Copper Promotes CO2 Electroreduction to Multi&#8208;carbon Products in Strong Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422082</link>
      <description>Wanfeng Yang, Yong Zhao, Yiqing Chen, Hangjuan Ren, Jiameng Sun, Zhangsheng Shi, Xindie Jin, Zhonghua Zhang, Xin Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405796876

                Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2R) to multi&#8208;carbon (C2+) products in strong acid presents a promising approach to mitigate the CO2 loss commonly encountered in alkaline and neutral systems. However, this process often suffers from low selectivity for C2+ products due to the competing C1 (e.g., CO and HCOOH) formation and complex C&#8208;C coupling kinetics. In this work, we report a CO2 coverage constraining strategy by diluting CO2 reactant feed to modulate the intermediate distribution and C&#8208;C coupling pathways for an enhanced electrosynthesis of C2+ products in strong acid. Lowering the CO2 feed concentration reduces CO2 coverage on copper catalyst, enriching the surface coverage and optimizing the adsorption configuration of the key CO intermediate for C&#8208;C coupling. This approach efficiently suppresses the formation of undesired C1 products. By employing a 20% CO2 feed, we achieved a significant improvement in C2+ Faradaic efficiency, reaching 68% at 100 mA cm&#8208;2, approximately 1.7 times higher than the 41% obtained using pure CO2. We demonstrated the direct electroreduction of a 30% CO2 feed &#8211; representative CO2 concentration of typical industrial flue gases &#8211; in a full electrolyzer, achieving a C2+ selectivity of 78% and an energy efficiency of 23% at 200 mA cm&#8208;2.</description>
      <author>Wanfeng Yang, Yong Zhao, Yiqing Chen, Hangjuan Ren, Jiameng Sun, Zhangsheng Shi, Xindie Jin, Zhonghua Zhang, Xin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constraining CO2 Coverage on Copper Promotes CO2 Electroreduction to Multi&#8208;carbon Products in Strong Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422082</link>
      <description>Wanfeng Yang, Yong Zhao, Yiqing Chen, Hangjuan Ren, Jiameng Sun, Zhangsheng Shi, Xindie Jin, Zhonghua Zhang, Xin Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405796915

                Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2R) to multi-carbon (C2+) products in strong acid presents a promising approach to mitigate the CO2 loss commonly encountered in alkaline and neutral systems. However, this process often suffers from low selectivity for C2+ products due to the competing C1 (e.g., CO and HCOOH) formation and complex C-C coupling kinetics. In this work, we report a CO2 coverage constraining strategy by diluting CO2 reactant feed to modulate the intermediate distribution and C-C coupling pathways for an enhanced electrosynthesis of C2+ products in strong acid. Lowering the CO2 feed concentration reduces CO2 coverage on copper catalyst, enriching the surface coverage and optimizing the adsorption configuration of the key CO intermediate for C-C coupling. This approach efficiently suppresses the formation of undesired C1 products. By employing a 20% CO2 feed, we achieved a significant improvement in C2+ Faradaic efficiency, reaching 68% at 100 mA cm-2, approximately 1.7 times higher than the 41% obtained using pure CO2. We demonstrated the direct electroreduction of a 30% CO2 feed - representative CO2 concentration of typical industrial flue gases - in a full electrolyzer, achieving a C2+ selectivity of 78% and an energy efficiency of 23% at 200 mA cm-2.</description>
      <author>Wanfeng Yang, Yong Zhao, Yiqing Chen, Hangjuan Ren, Jiameng Sun, Zhangsheng Shi, Xindie Jin, Zhonghua Zhang, Xin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CalTrans: Implementation of advanced technology and materials recycling techniques for the use of alternative materials in concrete as plain or reinforced materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5399/osu/1179</link>
      <description>Fengyin Du, Julien Hubert, Keshav Bharadwaj, Krishna Siva Teja Chopperla, Gopakumar Kaladaram, Jason H. Ideker, O. Burkan Isgor, Werner Weiss, Larry Sutter, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405909913

                The manufacture of ordinary portland cement (OPC) is responsible for approximately 4-8% of the total global Greenhouse Gases (GHG) emissions. Recent CalTrans research resulted in changes to specifications to reduce the clinker content of OPC by using ground limestone creating a Portland Limestone Cement (PLC) that is compliant with ASTM C595-IL as one method to reduce the carbon footprint (approximately a 10% CO2 reduction) [1]. Supplementary Cementitious Materials (SCMs) may be able to be used to further reduce the clinker content in concrete, providing an additional 20 to 40% CO2 reduction depending on the volume of cement replaced and the SCM used. This project focused on reducing the carbon content using alternative SCMs.</description>
      <author>Fengyin Du, Julien Hubert, Keshav Bharadwaj, Krishna Siva Teja Chopperla, Gopakumar Kaladaram, Jason H. Ideker, O. Burkan Isgor, Werner Weiss, Larry Sutter</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5399/osu/1179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 sequestration potential in Depleted Hydrocarbon fields &#8211; A geochemical approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31219/osf.io/3yuwg</link>
      <description>Eleni Gianni, Pavlos Tyrologou, Dounya Behnous, M&#225;rton P&#225;l Farkas, Paula Fern&#225;ndez&#8208;Canteli &#193;lvarez, Jes&#250;s Garc&#237;a-Crespo, Ricardo Chacartegui, Nikolaos Koukouzas, J&#250;lio Carneiro, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405838307

                The reduction of CO2 emissions is crucial for the energy transition. New technologies for the CO2 capture and storage are under development to achieve this goal. CO2 based electrothermal energy and geological storage system (CEEGS) is a novel technology trying to combine renewable energy storage system based on the transcritical CO2 cycle with CO2 storage in geological formations and geothermal heat extraction. Porous media and rock caverns are the geological formations of high interest for such technology. Among them, depleted hydrocarbon fields gain ground due to the experience of reservoir characterisation, sealing performance, storage operability, and already established oil or gas well infrastructure which critically decreases the cost. However, one of the major problems caused during the CO2 storage in depleted hydrocarbon fields is the interactions between the injected CO2 and the remaining fluids. In this study, the potential CO2 storage in the depleted gas fields was investigated and the Marismas 3 was used as an hypothetical model area for the examination of CO2 interactions with a reservoir representing by carbonate-silisiclastic rocks and sands.PHREEQC computer simulation software was used for the investigation of reservoir rock/water/remained gas (CH4) interactions followed by the interactions taking place after the CO2 injection. Two different scenarios were used for the CO2 concentration in the reservoir representing the minimum and the maximum ratio of reservoir storage efficiency factor. During the CO2 injection, carbonic acid was formed, causing a dissolution of several minerals, leading to the precipitation of siderite and clay minerals such as kaolinite, Ca-montmorillonite and illite, which may cause problems related to the permeability of the system. The colloidal nature of siderite and the swelling properties of Ca-montmorillonite are of high concern for the pore throats clogging. However, in this study area, the other new formed mineralogical phases are not threatening the reservoir quality. To make the system more complex and generic, the CMG software utilized to combine dynamic fluid flow and geochemistry, examining the long-term sequestration of CO2 through dissolution trapping, residual trapping, and lateral migration.</description>
      <author>Eleni Gianni, Pavlos Tyrologou, Dounya Behnous, M&#225;rton P&#225;l Farkas, Paula Fern&#225;ndez&#8208;Canteli &#193;lvarez, Jes&#250;s Garc&#237;a-Crespo, Ricardo Chacartegui, Nikolaos Koukouzas, J&#250;lio Carneiro</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31219/osf.io/3yuwg</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heating Dictates the Scalability of CO2 Electrolyzer Types</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00190g</link>
      <description>Jan-Willem Hurkmans, Henri M. Pelzer, Thomas Burdyny, Jurriaan Peeters, David A. Vermaas, EES Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405824875

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction offers a promising method of converting renewable electrical energy into valuable hydrocarbon compounds vital to hard-to-abate sectors. Significant progress has been made on the lab scale, but...</description>
      <author>Jan-Willem Hurkmans, Henri M. Pelzer, Thomas Burdyny, Jurriaan Peeters, David A. Vermaas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00190g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A STUDY ON THE UTILIZATION OF WASTEWATER TREATMENT SLUDGE IN THE CONSTRUCTION SECTOR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62301/usmtd.1592727</link>
      <description>Yusuf Tahir ALTUNCI, Uluslararas&#305; s&#252;rd&#252;r&#252;lebilir m&#252;hendislik ve teknoloji dergisi.. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405874085

                Sewage sludge is a type of waste generated during the wastewater treatment process. If not properly disposed of, this waste can pose a risk to human health. This study explores the use of wastewater treatment sludge in the construction sector, with a focus on evaluating its impact on CO2 emissions and its contribution to sustainability. The findings indicate that after undergoing the calcination process, wastewater treatment sludge acquires pozzolanic properties and can be partially utilized in cement and concrete production. Moreover, the incorporation of wastewater treatment sludge into cement and concrete will contribute to both the reduction of CO2 emissions and the promotion of sustainability.</description>
      <author>Yusuf Tahir ALTUNCI</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62301/usmtd.1592727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scenario-based Assessment of Decarbonized Transport Sector in Thailand towards Carbon Neutrality 2050</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56261/built.v22.256385</link>
      <description>Bundit Limmeechokchai, Rathana Lorm, International Journal of Building Urban Interior and Landscape Technology (BUILT). 22(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405870630

                Thailand's transport sector has been one of the highest CO2 emitters for several decades in the country due to the excessive increase in transport service demand and the high reliance on high-carbon-intensity petroleum fuels. This article discusses the potential of CO2 reduction in the transport sector in Thailand to achieve carbon neutrality by 2050. The Low Emissions Analysis Platform (LEAP) is adopted to estimate the future energy demand and CO2 emission between 2020 and 2050. This study designs two main scenarios, namely the Baseline (BAS) and the Decarbonization (DEC) scenarios. The BAS scenario is developed in a business-as-usual approach with frozen technologies, while the DEC scenario is constructed as a CO2 countermeasure by including multiple low carbon technologies such as i) improving fuel economy efficiency of engines, ii) promoting electric vehicles (EVs), iii) utilizing fuel cell electric vehicles (FCEVs), and iv) promoting mass transportation. The results indicate that by 2050, the transport sector's total energy demand will significantly increase to approximately 49,906 ktoe, with diesel, gasoline, and jet kerosene accounting for the majority of fuel consumption. In the BAS scenario, total CO2 emissions in the transport sector are estimated to be 119,737 ktCO2eq. By full implementation of the CO2 countermeasures and low carbon technologies in the decarbonization scenario, the total carbon emission in the transport sector is estimated to be 30,582 ktCO2 by 2050, which is in line with carbon neutrality pathways of Thailand. However, the nation-wide transport action plan should be developed in order to promote such sustainable transport technologies.</description>
      <author>Bundit Limmeechokchai, Rathana Lorm</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56261/built.v22.256385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of preventive maintenance in the design of photovoltaic plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35429/jad.2024.8.19.3.8</link>
      <description>Alberto Chavira-&#193;lvarez, Eva Claudia P&#233;rez-Ortega, Mar&#237;a Del Carmen Esparza-Delgado, Revista de Arquitectura y Dise&#241;o. 8(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405862237

                Two of the biggest problems worldwide are electrical energy and water, in this context the use of photovoltaic systems for the generation of electrical energy is increasingly profitable due to the constant reduction of prices in terms of the dollar watt and that supports the solution to the problem of energy supply at increasingly affordable prices. In this same scenario we have a reduction in CO2 emissions, contributing to the reduction of greenhouse gases, supporting the Kyoto protocol and the Paris agreement. On the other hand, the incorporation of ionized air for cleaning the photovoltaic modules allows the use of natural and demineralized water to be reduced to levels of around 98%, which allows us to be on par in saving solutions for this vital liquid.</description>
      <author>Alberto Chavira-&#193;lvarez, Eva Claudia P&#233;rez-Ortega, Mar&#237;a Del Carmen Esparza-Delgado</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35429/jad.2024.8.19.3.8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive effects of salinity, redox, and colloids on greenhouse gas production and carbon mobility in coastal wetland soils</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0316341</link>
      <description>Nicholas Ward, Madison Bowe, Katherine A. Muller, Xingyuan Chen, Qian Zhao, Rosalie Chu, Zezhen Cheng, Thomas Wietsma, Ravi Kukkadapu, PLoS ONE. 19(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405910050

                Coastal wetlands, including freshwater systems near large lakes, rapidly bury carbon, but less is known about how they transport carbon either to marine and lake environments or to the atmosphere as greenhouse gases (GHGs) such as carbon dioxide and methane. This study examines how GHG production and organic matter (OM) mobility in coastal wetland soils vary with the availability of oxygen and other terminal electron acceptors. We also evaluated how OM and redox-sensitive species varied across different size fractions: particulates (0.45&#8211;1&#956;m), fine colloids (0.1&#8211;0.45&#956;m), and nano particulates plus truly soluble (&lt;0.1&#956;m; NP+S) during 21-day aerobic and anaerobic slurry incubations. Soils were collected from the center of a freshwater coastal wetland (FW-C) in Lake Erie, the upland-wetland edge of the same wetland (FW-E), and the center of a saline coastal wetland (SW-C) in the Pacific Northwest, USA. Anaerobic methane production for FW-E soils were 47 and 27,537 times greater than FW-C and SW-C soils, respectively. High Fe 2+ and dissolved sulfate concentrations in FW-C and SW-C soils suggest that iron and/or sulfate reduction inhibited methanogenesis. Aerobic CO 2 production was highest for both freshwater soils, which had a higher proportion of OM in the NP+S fraction (64&#177;28% and 70&#177;10% for FW-C and FW-E, respectively) and organic C:N ratios reflective of microbial detritus (5.3&#177;5.3 and 5.3&#177;7.0 for FW-E and FW-C, respectively) compared to SW-C, which had a higher fraction of particulate (58&#177;9%) and fine colloidal (19&#177;7%) OM and organic C:N ratios reflective of vegetation detritus (11.4 &#177; 1.7). The variability in GHG production and shifts in OM size fractionation and composition observed across freshwater and saline soils collected within individual and across different sites reinforce the high spatial variability in the processes controlling OM stability, mobility, and bioavailability in coastal wetland soils.</description>
      <author>Nicholas Ward, Madison Bowe, Katherine A. Muller, Xingyuan Chen, Qian Zhao, Rosalie Chu, Zezhen Cheng, Thomas Wietsma, Ravi Kukkadapu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0316341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Promoter Breaks the Linear Scaling Relationship: Ultra&#8208;Rapid High&#8208;Temperature Synthesis of Heterostructured CoS/SnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@C as a Bifunctional Oxygen Catalyst for Li&#8208;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406516</link>
      <description>Nan Wang, Tingxue Fang, Tinghui An, Yuhao Wang, Jiaqi Li, Shuming Yu, Honghai Sun, Dong Xiang, Xiangjie Bo, Kedi Cai, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405879994

                Abstract Li&#8208;O 2 batteries urgently needs high discharge capacity and stable cycling performance, requiring effective and reliable bifunctional catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, Hovenia acerba Lindl &#8208;like heterostructure composed of cobalt sulfide and tin dioxide supported on carbon substrate (CoS/SnO 2 @C) is prepared via CO 2 laser irradiation technology. The half&#8208;wave potential of CoS/SnO 2 @C for the ORR is 0.88 V, while the overpotential of the OER at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 is as low as 270 mV. The Li&#8208;O 2 batteries employing the bifunctional CoS/SnO 2 @C catalyst displays a high discharge specific capacity of 3332.25 mAh g &#8722;1 and long cycling life of 226 cycles. Additionally, theory calculations demonstrate that the construction of heterostructure decreases energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) for both ORR and OER. Notably, SnO 2 behaves as the electronic promoter to optimize the electronic structure of heterostructure interface and triggers charge redistribution of CoS, which weakens the adsorption strength of the * O&#8208;intermediates and allows to break the linear scaling relationship, thus further enhancing the catalytic performance of CoS/SnO 2 @C. This research furnishes directions for the design of heterogeneous catalysts, highlighting its great potential for application in rechargeable Li&#8208;O 2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Nan Wang, Tingxue Fang, Tinghui An, Yuhao Wang, Jiaqi Li, Shuming Yu, Honghai Sun, Dong Xiang, Xiangjie Bo, Kedi Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Solar Desalination Efficiency with Combined Techniques: Evacuated Tubes, Corrugated Fins, and Blue Metal Stones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4028/p-dj5coh</link>
      <description>Kasi S. Maheswari, K. Mayandi, S. Joe Patrick Gnanaraj, Vanthana Jeyasingh, Key engineering materials. 1006(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405819172

                Solar desalination efficiency can be significantly altered by combining several approaches to improve evaporation rate. The objective of this research is to find a way to make solar stills (SS) more efficient by combining evacuated tube solar collectors, blue metal stones, and corrugated fins. An investigation into a six-tube evacuated solar collector was conducted to increase the system's evaporation rate. Corrugated fins were thought of to rise the surface area of heat transfer between the water and absorber. Blue metal stone was proposed to keep the water at a maximum temperature even when solar radiation is minimal. Separate displays of the cumulative distillate output (DO) numbers and hourly values for each time period provide a comprehensive view. Based on the findings, the peak period for DO moves from 1 p.m. on a sample day in May 2024, which is six months into the project. In comparison to CSS, MSS temperature values are over 55 &#176;C higher at the peak and nearly 26 &#176;C higher on average. On top of that, the total DO during the day can reach 2.64 to 6.82 L, while at night it rises from 0.067 to 0.96 L. In addition, there is a 146.3% improvement in the average DO during the six months, going from 3.02 to 7.22 L. Additionally, MSS is 0.43&#8377; per liter and CSS is 0.47&#8377; per liter, in that order. The net amount of carbon dioxide reduction achieved by modified solar stills was approximately 2.44 times greater than that of conventional solar stills.</description>
      <author>Kasi S. Maheswari, K. Mayandi, S. Joe Patrick Gnanaraj, Vanthana Jeyasingh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4028/p-dj5coh</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GREEN ECONOMY: ECONOMETRIC ANALYSIS OF THE IMPLEMENTATION OF ECO-INNOVATIONS IN UKRAINE AND THE EU</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33111/sedu.2024.55.128.141</link>
      <description>Vladyslav Yaremenko, Strategy of Economic Development of Ukraine. None(55)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405917404

                In the article, the state and dynamics of eco-innovation development in Ukraine and the European Union (EU) countries are examined, focusing on comparing the two regions. In the context of growing environmental challenges, such as climate change, eco-innovations are essential for achieving sustainable development, reducing CO2 emissions, and enhancing economic efficiency. The EU demonstrates a high level of research and development (R&amp;D) investment and a transition to renewable energy sources. In Ukraine, there is a positive trend, although the pace of development is slower. The study conducts a regression analysis to determine the impact of R&amp;D expenditures, the share of renewable energy, and CO2 emission levels on the eco-innovation index, confirming the significance of emission reduction as a key factor in stimulating ecological innovations. The results highlight the need to improve Ukraine&#8217;s state policy in the field of ecoinnovations, taking into account the European experience.</description>
      <author>Vladyslav Yaremenko</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33111/sedu.2024.55.128.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled Multi-Dimensional Assembly of Calcium Carbonate Particles with Industrial By-Product Carbide Slag and CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15010016</link>
      <description>Yuke Shen, Xiaoli Jiang, Tang Chengcai, Wei Ma, Jay J. Cheng, Hongxu Wang, Hongyu Zhu, Lin Zhao, Yagang Zhang, Panfeng Zhao, Nanomaterials. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405810762

                The utilization of carbide slag, an industrial by-product, as a resource to prepare value-added products has a profound impact not only for sustainable synthesis and the circular economy but also for CO2 reduction. Herein, we report the very first example of the controlled multi-dimensional assembly of calcium carbonate particles at the micrometer scale with industrial by-product carbide slag and CO2. Calcium carbonate particles of distinctly different sizes, shapes, and morphologies are obtained by finely tuning the assembly conditions. This strategy yields diverse assembled structures, including simple cubic, mulberry-like assembled unit, stacked cubic polycrystalline, and rotated polycrystalline structures, using the same starting materials. This innovative approach not only highlights the adaptability and efficiency of utilizing industrial by-products via multi-dimensional assembly but also provides new insights into the potential applications of the resulting calcium carbonate.</description>
      <author>Yuke Shen, Xiaoli Jiang, Tang Chengcai, Wei Ma, Jay J. Cheng, Hongxu Wang, Hongyu Zhu, Lin Zhao, Yagang Zhang, Panfeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15010016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic CoNi@N-Doped Carbon Composite for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrochemical Reduction to CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Associated with Methanol Oxidation to Methylal in an Ionic Liquid Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02973</link>
      <description>Hongyan Li, Bairui Yang, Hui Kong, Jingxiang Zhao, Qinghai Cai, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405803097

                The electrochemical reduction reaction of CO2 (CO2eRR) to high value-added chemicals in an aqueous electrolyte usually faces challenges, including sluggish oxygen evolution at the anode and the competing reaction of hydrogen evolution at the cathode. A novel CoNi@NC composite with high saturation magnetization, prepared by facile pyrolysis, was used as the cathode and a Pt sheet as the anode in an ionic liquid (IL)-methanol electrolyte to conduct the CO2eRR to produce CH4 and CO, and oxidation of methanol to generate methylal (dimethoxymethane, DMM). A magnetic CoNi alloy nanomaterial (CoNi@NC) with a nitrogen-doped carbon layer-coated structure was synthesized by a one-pot method. The system achieved an associative strategy for synchronous production of high-valued chemicals via two half-reactions at the cathode and anode, respectively. The optimal CoNi@NC composite exhibited efficient catalytic activity, obtaining an average of 54.5% faradaic efficiency (FE) for DMM within 48 h and 91.9% of momentary FE for CO and CH4 at 24 h under lower energy consumption. The electrode catalyst and ionic liquid electrolyte also exhibited good recyclability and stability in the CO2eRR. Mechanism studies indicated that magnetic CoNi alloy species served as adsorption and active sites for CO2 conversion. In addition, the carbon layer coating enhanced the stability of the CoNi alloy, and N-doping introduced surface defects on the carbon layer, thereby promoting CO2 adsorption and electrocatalytic activity. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations demonstrated that the magnetic CoNi (1 1 1) species was conducive to CO2 adsorption and activation, exhibiting high selectivity for the CO2eRR.</description>
      <author>Hongyan Li, Bairui Yang, Hui Kong, Jingxiang Zhao, Qinghai Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous High Current Density and Selective Electrocatalytic CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 through Intermediate Balancing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423915</link>
      <description>Bilu Liu, Shuqi Hu, Yumo Chen, Zhiyuan Zhang, Heming Liu, Xin Kang, Jiarong Liu, Shanlin Li, Yuting Luo, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405802211

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CH4 is promising for carbon neutrality and renewable energy storage but confronts low CH4 selectivity, especially at high current densities. The key challenge lies in promoting *CO intermediate and *H coupling while minimizing side reactions including C&#8208;C coupling or H&#8208;H coupling, which is particularly difficult at high current density due to abundant intermediates. Here we report a cooperative strategy to address this challenge using Cu&#8208;based catalysts comprising Cu&#8208;N coordination polymer and CuO component that can simultaneously manage the key intermediates *CO and *H. A fast CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 conversion rate of 3.14 mmol cm&#8208;2 h&#8208;1 is achieved at 1,300 mA cm&#8722;2 with a Faradaic efficiency of 51.7%. In&#8208;situ spectroscopy and theoretical calculations show that the increased Cu&#8208;Cu distance in the Cu&#8208;N coordination polymer component favors multistep *CO hydrogenation over the dimerization, and the CuO component ensures an adequate supply of *H, together contributing to the selective CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 conversion at high current densities. This work develops a cooperative strategy for the electrosynthesis of CH4 with simultaneous high current density and high selectivity by rational catalyst design, paving the way for its applications.</description>
      <author>Bilu Liu, Shuqi Hu, Yumo Chen, Zhiyuan Zhang, Heming Liu, Xin Kang, Jiarong Liu, Shanlin Li, Yuting Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous High Current Density and Selective Electrocatalytic CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 through Intermediate Balancing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423915</link>
      <description>Bilu Liu, Shuqi Hu, Yumo Chen, Zhiyuan Zhang, Heming Liu, Xin Kang, Jiarong Liu, Shanlin Li, Yuting Luo, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405802130

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CH4 is promising for carbon neutrality and renewable energy storage but confronts low CH4 selectivity, especially at high current densities. The key challenge lies in promoting *CO intermediate and *H coupling while minimizing side reactions including C&#8208;C coupling or H&#8208;H coupling, which is particularly difficult at high current density due to abundant intermediates. Here we report a cooperative strategy to address this challenge using Cu&#8208;based catalysts comprising Cu&#8208;N coordination polymer and CuO component that can simultaneously manage the key intermediates *CO and *H. A fast CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 conversion rate of 3.14 mmol cm&#8208;2 h&#8208;1 is achieved at 1,300 mA cm&#8722;2 with a Faradaic efficiency of 51.7%. In&#8208;situ spectroscopy and theoretical calculations show that the increased Cu&#8208;Cu distance in the Cu&#8208;N coordination polymer component favors multistep *CO hydrogenation over the dimerization, and the CuO component ensures an adequate supply of *H, together contributing to the selective CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CH4 conversion at high current densities. This work develops a cooperative strategy for the electrosynthesis of CH4 with simultaneous high current density and high selectivity by rational catalyst design, paving the way for its applications.</description>
      <author>Bilu Liu, Shuqi Hu, Yumo Chen, Zhiyuan Zhang, Heming Liu, Xin Kang, Jiarong Liu, Shanlin Li, Yuting Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Reduction of Iron Oxide Powder in Thin Layers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03138</link>
      <description>Antonio D&#8217;Angelo, Emiliano Salucci, Vincenzo Russo, Henrik Gr&#233;nman, Henrik Sax&#233;n, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405799505

                The steel industry is responsible for a very large environmental impact because more than 70% of the production of iron is done in blast furnaces, where the reduction of iron oxides (ore) is performed with carbon monoxide obtained from coke and coal. Their partial oxidation produces CO used to reduce the iron oxides, simultaneously yielding huge amounts (approximately 2GT/a) of CO2. It is necessary to find new alternatives to decarbonize the steelmaking process. The present work studies the reduction kinetics of iron oxides using hydrogen as a reductant. The overall reaction displays complex behavior that explains the versatile and partly contradictory interpretations found in the literature on hydrogen reduction of iron oxides. Experiments in thin layers of powder were performed under various experimental conditions to investigate the kinetics with both pure iron oxide and an industrial feedstock. To support the interpretation of the data, morphological and chemical-physical characterization was performed, and a comparison between pure hematite and commercial ironmaking pellets was reported.</description>
      <author>Antonio D&#8217;Angelo, Emiliano Salucci, Vincenzo Russo, Henrik Gr&#233;nman, Henrik Sax&#233;n</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03138</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyaniline&#8208;modified anodes for brewery waste treatment in microbial fuel cells: insights into inoculum selection, cell configuration, and lactic acid valorization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jctb.7805</link>
      <description>I. Rafael Gardu&#241;o&#8208;Ibarra, Shruti Tanga ., Alexandra Tsitouras, Chris Kinsley, Elena A. Baranova, Journal of Chemical Technology &amp; Biotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405884646

                Abstract BACKGROUND This study focuses on the treatment of brewery waste slurries (BWS) with high chemical oxygen demand (COD) using a single&#8208;chamber microbial fuel cell (MFC) inoculated with heat&#8208;treated anaerobic seed sludge. A co&#8208;substrate of 5 g L &#8722;1 glycerol was added, and carbon felt ( CF ) was employed as the anode material, enhanced through in situ polymerization of aniline (PANI/ CF ). Additionally, the adsorption of ruthenium dioxide nanoparticles onto the modified CF was assessed (PANI&#8208;RO/ CF ). RESULTS Tests conducted at room temperature (19 &#176;C to 22 &#176;C) achieved an average COD reduction of 36%. The PANI&#8208;RO/ CF electrode accumulated 24% more charge, resulting in the highest coulombic efficiency of 75.1%, significantly exceeding similar studies. However, the PANI&#8208;modified anode generated more energy, exceeding that of the bare CF by more than double, reaching 57.1 mW m &#8722;2 . An optimized working volume was identified in relation to other reported works. Microbial population analysis revealed an interaction between Staphylococcus epidermidis and a rarely reported psychrophilic Bacillus species. After 30 h, lactic acid emerged as the main by&#8208;product, with a concentration of 7.5 &#177; 0.6 g L &#8722;1 . CONCLUSIONS These findings highlight an optimization approach based on cell configuration and inoculum selection, as well as a significant valorization pathway that is frequently overlooked in the existing literature on brewery wastewater treatment using MFCs, particularly regarding the attractiveness of lactic acid production. &#169; 2024 The Author(s). Journal of Chemical Technology and Biotechnology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Society of Chemical Industry (SCI).</description>
      <author>I. Rafael Gardu&#241;o&#8208;Ibarra, Shruti Tanga ., Alexandra Tsitouras, Chris Kinsley, Elena A. Baranova</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jctb.7805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte Anions Suppress Hydrogen Generation in Electrochemical CO Reduction on Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421196</link>
      <description>Lee Fuller, Gong Zhang, Seonmyeong Noh, Reid C. Van Lehn, Marcel Schreier, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405803898

                In this study, we employed EC&#8208;MS to elucidate the role of halide anions in electrochemical CO2 and CO reduction. We found that the undesired hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) was significantly suppressed by the anion used. Specifically, the rates of H2 production decreased in the order KF &gt; KCl &gt; KI, meaning that I&#8722; most strongly suppressed HER. Interestingly, CO reduction products showed an inverse relationship to HER, with KI leading to the highest rate of CO reduction. By pairing our experimental findings with classical molecular dynamics simulations, we propose a mechanism wherein halide anions influence the dynamic interplay between CO reduction and HER by modulating the competition of H* and CO* for active sites on the Cu surface. We propose that this interaction is enabled by the interfacial concentration of K+ being greater in the presence of F&#8722; than in I&#8722;. Our results highlight the need to more broadly consider the properties of ions at electrocatalytic interfaces and they point to thus far underappreciated avenues to optimize hydrocarbon production while suppressing hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Lee Fuller, Gong Zhang, Seonmyeong Noh, Reid C. Van Lehn, Marcel Schreier</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#1044;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080;&#1082;&#1072; &#1075;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1086;&#1081; &#1092;&#1072;&#1079;&#1099; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1073;&#1072;&#1088;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072;&#1078;&#1077; &#1074; &#1084;&#1086;&#1088;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1081; &#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;, &#1089;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1088;&#1078;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;-&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1074;&#1077;&#1097;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1072;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37220/mit.2024.66.4.019</link>
      <description>&#1040;.&#1053;. &#1044;&#1103;&#1076;&#1080;&#1082;, &#1044;.&#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1082;, &#1052;.&#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1095;&#1072;, &#1052;&#1054;&#1056;&#1057;&#1050;&#1048;&#1045; &#1048;&#1053;&#1058;&#1045;&#1051;&#1051;&#1045;&#1050;&#1058;&#1059;&#1040;&#1051;&#1068;&#1053;&#1067;&#1045; &#1058;&#1045;&#1061;&#1053;&#1054;&#1051;&#1054;&#1043;&#1048;&#1048;. 1(4(66))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405827186

                &#1056;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072; &#1087;&#1086;&#1089;&#1074;&#1103;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072; &#1074;&#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1072;&#1084; &#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1086;&#1086;&#1073;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1072;&#1087;&#1087;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1074; &#1089;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1074;&#1077; &#1074;&#1086;&#1079;&#1076;&#1091;&#1093;&#1086;&#1085;&#1077;&#1079;&#1072;&#1074;&#1080;&#1089;&#1080;&#1084;&#1099;&#1093; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1091;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1086;&#1082; &#1089; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1077;&#1081; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1086;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1076;&#1080;&#1086;&#1082;&#1089;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072; &#1074; &#1084;&#1086;&#1088;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1081; &#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1084; &#1072;&#1073;&#1089;&#1086;&#1088;&#1073;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080;. &#1057; &#1094;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1102; &#1076;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1079;&#1072;&#1076;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1084;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086; &#1085;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1080;&#1077; &#1073;&#1080;&#1086;&#1075;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1087;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;-&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1074;&#1077;&#1097;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074; (&#1055;&#1040;&#1042;) &#1074; &#1084;&#1086;&#1088;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1081; &#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;, &#1103;&#1074;&#1083;&#1103;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1093;&#1089;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080; &#1078;&#1080;&#1079;&#1085;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1103;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1084;&#1086;&#1088;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1086;&#1088;&#1075;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1084;&#1086;&#1074;. &#1053;&#1072; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077; &#1083;&#1080;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1072;&#1090;&#1091;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1087;&#1086; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1073;&#1080;&#1086;&#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1099; &#1074; &#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1077;&#1084; &#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1077; &#1052;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1086;&#1082;&#1077;&#1072;&#1085;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1083;&#1086;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072; &#1079;&#1072;&#1074;&#1080;&#1089;&#1080;&#1084;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1100; &#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1055;&#1040;&#1042; &#1086;&#1090; &#1088;&#1072;&#1081;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072; &#1080; &#1074;&#1099;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086; &#1089;&#1088;&#1072;&#1074;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1089; &#1101;&#1082;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084;&#1080; &#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084;&#1080;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1083;&#1091;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1099; &#1079;&#1072;&#1074;&#1080;&#1089;&#1080;&#1084;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1085;&#1072; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077; &#1092;&#1080;&#1079;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;-&#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1074;&#1086;&#1079;&#1085;&#1080;&#1082;&#1072;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1093; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1073;&#1072;&#1088;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072;&#1078;&#1077; &#1075;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072; &#1080; &#1072;&#1076;&#1089;&#1086;&#1088;&#1073;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1084;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1091;&#1083; &#1073;&#1080;&#1086;&#1075;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1055;&#1040;&#1042; &#1085;&#1072; &#1087;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1087;&#1091;&#1079;&#1099;&#1088;&#1100;&#1082;&#1072;. &#1059;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1085;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1080;&#1077; &#1073;&#1080;&#1086;&#1075;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1055;&#1040;&#1042; &#1074; &#1084;&#1086;&#1088;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1081; &#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1090; &#1082; &#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1082;&#1086;&#1101;&#1092;&#1092;&#1080;&#1094;&#1080;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1072; &#1087;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1085;&#1072;&#1090;&#1103;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1074; &#1089;&#1074;&#1086;&#1102; &#1086;&#1095;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1100; &#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1078;&#1072;&#1077;&#1090; &#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1100; &#1076;&#1074;&#1080;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1075;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1086;&#1081; &#1092;&#1072;&#1079;&#1099;, &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077;&#1079;&#1085;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084; &#1087;&#1086;&#1085;&#1080;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1082;&#1086;&#1101;&#1092;&#1092;&#1080;&#1094;&#1080;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1072; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1086;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080;, &#1074; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103;&#1093; &#1091;&#1074;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1086;&#1073;&#1097;&#1077;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1086;&#1086;&#1073;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072;. &#1054;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1074; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103;&#1093; &#1082;&#1086;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077;&#1089;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1080; &#1076;&#1088;&#1086;&#1073;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1075;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1099;&#1093; &#1087;&#1091;&#1079;&#1099;&#1088;&#1100;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074; &#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1086;&#1073;&#1098;&#1077;&#1084;&#1072; &#1075;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1099;&#1093; &#1087;&#1091;&#1079;&#1099;&#1088;&#1100;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1074;&#1099;&#1079;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077;&#1084; &#1084;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1084;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1080; &#1084;&#1072;&#1082;&#1089;&#1080;&#1084;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1076;&#1080;&#1072;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074; &#1075;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1087;&#1091;&#1079;&#1099;&#1088;&#1100;&#1082;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1090; &#1082; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1086;&#1073;&#1083;&#1072;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1076;&#1088;&#1086;&#1073;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1085;&#1072;&#1076; &#1082;&#1086;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077;&#1089;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1094;&#1080;&#1077;&#1081;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1090; &#1082; &#1091;&#1074;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1087;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1086;&#1086;&#1073;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077; &#1095;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1072; &#1087;&#1091;&#1079;&#1099;&#1088;&#1100;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;. The work is dedicated to the modeling of mass transfer apparatuses within air-independent power systems, focusing on the dissolution of carbon dioxide in seawater through the absorption method. To achieve this goal, the presence of biogenic surfactants in seawater, which are products of marine organisms' life activities, is considered. Based on literature data on biomass distribution in the upper layer of the World Ocean, a dependency of surfactant concentration on the region is proposed and compared with experimental data. Dependencies are derived based on the physicochemical processes that occur during gas sparging and the adsorption of biogenic surfactant molecules on the bubble surface. It is established that the presence of biogenic surfactants in seawater leads to a reduction in surface tension, which in turn decreases the velocity of the gas phase, with a slight reduction in the mass transfer coefficient, under conditions of increased overall mass transfer surface area. It is determined that under conditions of coalescence and fragmentation of gas bubbles, the reduction in gas bubble volume, caused by the decrease in minimum and maximum bubble diameters, leads to the predominance of fragmentation over coalescence, resulting in an increase in the mass transfer surface area as the number of bubbles increases.</description>
      <author>&#1040;.&#1053;. &#1044;&#1103;&#1076;&#1080;&#1082;, &#1044;.&#1057;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1082;, &#1052;.&#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1095;&#1072;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37220/mit.2024.66.4.019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle CO2 Emissions and Techno-Economic Analysis of Wood Pellet Production and CHP with Different Plant Scales and Sawdust Drying Processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010140</link>
      <description>Kenji Koido, Daichi Konno, Michio Sato, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405920559

                This study presents a life cycle assessment (LCA) and economic analysis of wood pellet production and utilisation in gasification combined heat and power (CHP) systems, focusing on optimising the drying process and evaluating the impacts of varying plant scales. In line with Japan&#8217;s target of achieving net-zero emissions by 2050, the research examines primary energy demand (PED), CO2 emissions, and financial viability across the wood pellet production (gate-to-gate) and CHP energy generation (gate-to-grave) stages. The results reveal that the drying process accounts for 35&#8211;39% of the total energy consumption in wood pellet production, with the heat source significantly influencing PED and CO2 emissions. Systems employing wood-fired boilers and wood pellet CHP for drying achieve reductions in PED by 12&#8211;26% and CO2 emissions by 14&#8211;31% compared to the conventional grid-supplied drying process. Economic analysis reveals that scaling up production enhances financial performance, with net income increasing by up to 20% and payback periods reducing to approximately 10 years in facilities producing 2.5 tons of wood pellets per hour. These findings highlight the critical role of optimised drying processes, plant scalability, and efficient supply chains in advancing sustainable wood pellet-based bioenergy systems that support Japan&#8217;s renewable energy targets.</description>
      <author>Kenji Koido, Daichi Konno, Michio Sato</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte Anions Suppress Hydrogen Generation in Electrochemical CO Reduction on Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421196</link>
      <description>Lee Fuller, Gong Zhang, Seonmyeong Noh, Reid C. Van Lehn, Marcel Schreier, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405803899

                In this study, we employed EC&#8208;MS to elucidate the role of halide anions in electrochemical CO2 and CO reduction. We found that the undesired hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) was significantly suppressed by the anion used. Specifically, the rates of H2 production decreased in the order KF &gt; KCl &gt; KI, meaning that I&#8722; most strongly suppressed HER. Interestingly, CO reduction products showed an inverse relationship to HER, with KI leading to the highest rate of CO reduction. By pairing our experimental findings with classical molecular dynamics simulations, we propose a mechanism wherein halide anions influence the dynamic interplay between CO reduction and HER by modulating the competition of H* and CO* for active sites on the Cu surface. We propose that this interaction is enabled by the interfacial concentration of K+ being greater in the presence of F&#8722; than in I&#8722;. Our results highlight the need to more broadly consider the properties of ions at electrocatalytic interfaces and they point to thus far underappreciated avenues to optimize hydrocarbon production while suppressing hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Lee Fuller, Gong Zhang, Seonmyeong Noh, Reid C. Van Lehn, Marcel Schreier</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trend Projections of Greenhouse Gas Emission Reduction Potentials: A Bootstrap-Based Nonparametric Efficiency Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.17718</link>
      <description>Larissa Fait, Jens J. Kr&#252;ger, Moritz Tarach, Heike Wetzel, International Journal of Energy Economics and Policy. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405835584

                We use nonparametric methods to compute the environmental inefficiency of 100 countries over the period 1990-2017 on the macro-level. The inefficiency is expressed as the potential reduction of GHG emissions, holding economic output constant. Based on that, we estimate different trend functions and project the trends further until 2050. Confidence intervals to indicate the uncertainty inherent in the long-run projections are obtained by bootstrapping. We compare the efficient emissions remaining after subtracting the potential reductions with the official EU climate targets. It becomes apparent that a sizable contribution could be made by reducing inefficiency. However, even after removing the entire inefficiency, the results also indicate that this alone is probably not sufficient to break the increasing trend of GHG (and especially CO2) emissions. Thus, further policy measures are required for breaking the trend.</description>
      <author>Larissa Fait, Jens J. Kr&#252;ger, Moritz Tarach, Heike Wetzel</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.17718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVALUATION OF ENERGY SAVING EFFICIENCY OF BOILER COMBINED WITH HEAT PUMP FOR SUPPLEMENTARY FEED WATER HEATING</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54644/jte.2024.1705</link>
      <description>Kien Quoc Vo, Tuan B.H. Nguyen, Technical Education Science/Gia&#769;o du&#803;c Ky&#771; thua&#803;&#770;t. 19(06)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405878489

                This paper investigates the integration of heat pumps for heating boiler feedwater and evaluates the impacts of feedwater temperature and condensate recovery rates on fuel consumption, energy efficiency, and CO2 emissions. The results show that using heat pumps significantly reduces boiler fuel consumption, especially when the feedwater temperature increases and the condensate recovery rate is high. The COP (Coefficient of Performance) of the heat pump gradually decreases as the water temperature rises; however, heating the water at lower temperatures yields better economic and energy efficiency. Economically, heat pumps provide substantial benefits, with maximum cost savings achieved at a water temperature of 75&#176;C. Additionally, integrating heat pumps reduces CO2 emissions, particularly in boilers without condensate recovery, with the highest emission reduction reaching 17.8 kgCO2 per ton of steam. These findings demonstrate that using heat pumps is not only energy-efficient and cost-effective but also contributes to environmental protection by reducing greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
      <author>Kien Quoc Vo, Tuan B.H. Nguyen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54644/jte.2024.1705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Specific Carbon Footprint (SCF) Theory of Flow Rate and Energy Consumption Variations of an Industrial Internal Gear Pump</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46519/ij3dptdi.1563398</link>
      <description>Osman &#214;zdamar, Burak &#214;zt&#252;rk, International Journal of 3D Printing Technologies and Digital Industry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405822318

                Pumps in fuel oil systems are mechanical equipment used for the transfer of liquid fluid from one place to another. In particular, pumps are required to transfer the maximum flow rate in the transfer units in minimum time. They consume a very high amount of energy for this transfer. In this research, research studies were carried out to ensure the transfer of the highest possible amount of fuel oil by consuming energy at optimal rates. In this experimental study, the energy consumption and flow rate were measured across a range of engine speeds (100-700 RPM) and varying gear lengths (90-100 mm). According to the findings, energy consumption reached ideal levels at 600 RPM engine speed. In addition, it was determined that the lowest CO2 emission was obtained in the range of 600-700 RPM and by using long gear length. In addition, it is observed that the effect of gear length on energy efficiency is significant and energy consumption decreases as the gear length gets shorter. The results show that minimum energy consumption can be obtained with maximum flow rate at 609 RPM engine speed and 100 mm gear length. The ANOVA analysis used in the study reveals that the flow rate changes are 98% related to the engine speed, while the gear length is 78% effective in CO2 emission reduction. This research provides an important contribution to energy efficiency and carbon emission reduction in industrial applications. This study provides an innovative method that can be used to achieve energy saving and environmental sustainability goals and makes valuable contributions to the literature on optimising internal gear pump designs.</description>
      <author>Osman &#214;zdamar, Burak &#214;zt&#252;rk</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46519/ij3dptdi.1563398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GC-DFT-Based Dynamic Product Distribution Reveals Enhanced CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-Methanol Electrocatalysis Durability by Heterogeneous CoPc</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02755</link>
      <description>Zhiyuan Xu, Chao Ma, Beibei Tang, Jing Dong, Qi Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405813274

                Heterogeneous cobalt phthalocyanine has emerged as a promising molecular catalyst for electrochemical reduction of CO2 to methanol. Boosting both electrocatalytic durability and selectivity remains a great challenge, which is more difficult with unknown regulation factors for the HER side reaction. Herein, to discover the key to balancing the durability and selectivity, as well as HER regulation, we carried out GC-DFT calculations, based on which dynamic product distribution modeling was conducted to visually present the variation of the product distribution within the applied voltage range. The strongly electron-donating NMe2-substituted CoPc is found to be an excellent candidate. The dynamic product distribution reveals that the key to selectivity and durability balance is to regulate both the potential of the highest methanol Faradaic efficiency and the corresponding energy barrier of the selectivity-determining step for hydrogenated CoPc. The pivotal factor in HER regulation stems from hindered H adsorption due to ligand hydrogenation, arising from the decreased Co-to-H charge transfer. The dynamic product distribution analysis provides intuitive theoretical guidance for highly selective and durable CO2 electroreduction.</description>
      <author>Zhiyuan Xu, Chao Ma, Beibei Tang, Jing Dong, Qi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Typical Case of Converter Smelting with High Cooling Ratio in Chinese Iron and Steel Enterprises: CO2 Emission Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18010065</link>
      <description>Huapeng Yang, Chao Feng, Yubin Li, Feihong Guo, Rong Zhu, M Y Zhang, Xing Wang, Du Xin, Li&#8208;Jun Huo, Fuqiang Wen, Tao Ren, Guangsheng Wei, Fuhai Liu, Materials. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405827834

                In this study, the effects of using different scrap ratios in a converter on carbon emissions were analyzed based on life cycle assessment (LCA) theory, and the carbon emissions from the converter were evaluated with the use of coke and biochar as heating agents at high scrap ratios. In this industrial experiment, the CO2 emissions during the converter smelting process decreased with the increase in the scrap steel ratio. For every 1% increase in the scrap steel ratio, the carbon emissions during the steelmaking process decreased by 14.09 kgCO2/t steel. Based on statistical data for the actual use of a charcoal heating agent in the converter, the relationship between the utilization coefficient of the heating agent and the scrap ratio was calculated as &#951;=7.698&#215;102x&#8722;2.596. When biochar was used as a converter heating agent, the scrap ratio required to achieve the lowest carbon emissions was 36%, and the converter emissions could be reduced by 172 kgCO2/t&#183;steel relative to the use of coke. The use of biochar as a converter heating agent can contribute to the elimination of 330 million tons of scrap through furnace&#8211;converter long-process steelmaking, yielding an annual reduction in CO2 emissions of 158 million tons.</description>
      <author>Huapeng Yang, Chao Feng, Yubin Li, Feihong Guo, Rong Zhu, M Y Zhang, Xing Wang, Du Xin, Li&#8208;Jun Huo, Fuqiang Wen, Tao Ren, Guangsheng Wei, Fuhai Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18010065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Energy Management in Electric Vehicles Through a Fuzzy Logic-Based Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010089</link>
      <description>Efe Savran, Esin Karpat, Fatih Karpat, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405810484

                The purpose of this study was to develop a fuzzy logic controller (FLC)-based energy management strategy for battery electric vehicles that enables them to reduce their energy consumption and carbon emission levels without sacrificing their performance. An electric vehicle model was developed in MATLAB/Simulink using a virtual battery and validated with real-world driving tests to save time and money. An in-depth investigation is conducted on both virtual and real vehicles to confirm the effectiveness of the proposed energy management strategy. This study shows that by using FLC-based energy management, an energy consumption advantage of 9.16% can be achieved while maintaining acceptable performance levels in real-world driving conditions. This advantage results in significant reductions annually: 1044.09 tons of CO2 emissions, USD 164,770.65 in savings for electric bus lines, and 5079 battery cycles. For European passenger electric vehicles, this corresponds to 405,657.6 tons of CO2 emissions reduced, USD 64,017,840 saved, and 5.071 battery cycles per vehicle. This strategy not only enhances energy efficiency but also contributes to long-term sustainability in public transportation systems, particularly for electric bus fleets, which play a critical role in urban mobility.</description>
      <author>Efe Savran, Esin Karpat, Fatih Karpat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EXPERIMENTAL EVALUATION OF THE EFFECTIVENESS OF CO2 APPLICATION IN A CARRAGEENAN MODEL OF INFLAMMATION: NEW PERSPECTIVES IN THE TREATMENT OF OSTEOARTHRITIS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15674/0030-59872024458-63</link>
      <description>V. V. Shtroblia, ORTHOPAEDICS TRAUMATOLOGY and PROSTHETICS. None(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405813363

                Osteoarthritis (OA) is a chronic degenerative joint disease that leads to pain and limited mobility. Inflammation is a key pathogenetic factor in OA, which is accompanied by the activity of pro-inflammatory cytokines. One of the most promising methods of treating inflammation is carboxytherapy (CO2), which has low toxicity and physiological safety, but its interaction with other anti-inflammatory drugs is not well understood. Objective. To evaluate the anti-inflammatory effect of CO2 in animal models of carrageenan inflammation and to study its combined use with diclofenac and chondroitin. Methods. The study was conducted on 56 Wistar rats, which were randomly divided into 7 groups. Inflammation was modelled by injecting carrageenan into the limb of the animals. Prophylactic injections of anti-inflammatory drugs (diclofenac, chondroitin) were performed intraperitoneally and CO2 subcutaneously one hour later. The size of the edema was analysed 1, 2, 3 and 5 hours after the injection. The rectal temperature of the animals was also measured to determine the overall inflammation. Results. One hour after the administration of carrageenan, the volume of the limb in group VII decreased to (0.429 &#177; 0.020) ml (p &lt; 0.001), and in group VI &#8212; to (0.441 &#177; 0.017) ml (p &lt; 0.001). After 2 hours, the maximum decrease in limb edema was observed in group VII &#8212; (0.491 &#177; 0.017) ml (by 52 %, p &lt; 0.001), and in group VI &#8212; (0.495 &#177; 0.012) ml (by 38 %, p &lt; 0.001). After 5 hours, the size of the limb edema in group VI decreased to (0.559 &#177; 0.030) ml (by 51 %, p &lt; 0.001), and in group VII &#8212; to (0.571 &#177; 0.016) ml (by 46 %, p &lt; 0.001). Rectal temperature in group VI decreased to (37.7 &#177; 0.3) &#176;C (by 1.5 &#176;C, p &lt; 0.001), and in group VII &#8212; to (38.3 &#177; 0.2) &#176;C (by 0.9 &#176;C, p &lt; 0.001). Conclusions. Carboxytherapy has a pronounced anti-inflammatory effect, which is manifested in the reduction of edema and temperature, especially when combined with diclofenac or chondroitin. Further research may be aimed at studying the possible mechanisms of the positive effect of CO2, optimising therapeutic regimens and determining the long-term effects of carboxytherapy.</description>
      <author>V. V. Shtroblia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15674/0030-59872024458-63</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel dynamic route optimization method and its implementation using Python to optimize ship voyages sailing time based on weather routing techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5707487/v1</link>
      <description>Ahmad A. Moussa, Amman A. Ali, Mohi Eldeen El sayeh, Ahmad S. Shehata, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405839097

                Abstract Energy conservation, emission reduction, and voyage time optimization are critical concerns in the marine sector, where enhancing ship energy efficiency and sailing duration is essential for significant decreases in energy consumption and CO2 emissions. Existing studies generally focus on either sailing speed or route optimization, sometimes overlooking their interplay under continuously variable weather conditions, hence reducing the precision and quality of proposed solutions. This research presents an advanced Time Boundary Semicircles (TBS) Algorithm, which provides a robust and precise optimization model that incorporates involuntary speed reduction based on real-time weather data from the Copernicus Marine Environment Monitoring Service (CMEMS), subject to deterministic time boundaries. The TBS algorithm employs mathematical modeling to compute speed reductions dynamically and integrates Python libraries such as NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, and Cartopy to enhance waypoint optimization and software interactivity. This research compares the TBS algorithm to the SIMROUTE software, demonstrating its superior effectiveness in heavy weather scenarios with sailing time reductions ranging from 7&#8211;27.25%. Case studies validate the algorithm's efficacy through comprehensive simulation outputs, including map plots and detailed reports. They also highlight its potential for broader applications in aviation and land transport for route optimization. By bridging the gaps in maritime routing optimization, the TBS algorithm represents a significant advancement in sustainable and efficient transportation.</description>
      <author>Ahmad A. Moussa, Amman A. Ali, Mohi Eldeen El sayeh, Ahmad S. Shehata</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5707487/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Circular Nutrient Solution Management System Using a Cost Function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy15010051</link>
      <description>Yeong-Hyeon Shin, In-Su Kim, Myongkyoon Yang, Young-Kyun Jang, Ronaldo B. Saludes, Hak-Jin Kim, Woo-Jae Cho, Agronomy. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405934008

                In this study, an ion monitoring system using ion-selective electrodes (ISEs) was developed to maintain nutrient solutions in closed-loop hydroponic systems within plant factories. Based on this monitoring system, an algorithm and individual ion supplementation system were developed to calculate the optimal amounts of ion replenishment for crop growth. The developed algorithms adopt distinct cost functions to achieve their respective goals. The ion balance-prioritized algorithm minimizes the cost function, which is defined as the sum of the squared differences between the target ion concentrations and the calculated ion concentrations. In contrast, the carbon emission reduction algorithm minimizes the cost function defined as the total carbon emissions, which are calculated by multiplying the individual salt supplementation amounts by their respective carbon emission coefficients. Simulation results demonstrated that the ion balance-prioritized algorithm achieved average errors of 5.5 &#177; 5.5%, 0.4 &#177; 0.5%, and 5.0 &#177; 11.2% for Ca, NO3, and K, respectively, showing superior performance in maintaining ion balance. Meanwhile, the carbon emission reduction algorithm achieved a total of 0.064 kg CO2, representing a 50.19% reduction compared to the ion balance-prioritized type. The developed algorithms and system are expected to reduce costs by minimizing nutrient and water usage through the recycling of waste nutrient solutions. Furthermore, they are anticipated to improve crop productivity by maintaining an optimal ion composition and to contribute to sustainable agriculture through carbon emission reduction.</description>
      <author>Yeong-Hyeon Shin, In-Su Kim, Myongkyoon Yang, Young-Kyun Jang, Ronaldo B. Saludes, Hak-Jin Kim, Woo-Jae Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy15010051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-based electrocatalysts for hydrocarbon production via CO&#8322; reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14711/thesis-991013340341903412</link>
      <description>Juhee Jang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405880584

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is considered as one of the promising technologies because of the selective synthesis of fuels including methanol, methane, and ethylene. Particularly, Copper (Cu) has garnered huge interest as a CO2RR catalyst among other metal element due to its unique binding energy with reactive intermediates. In this study, the intricate connection between surface oxidation state, superficial transformation, and catalytic efficiency is investigated, with a focus on oxide-derived copper (OD-Cu) and Cu-based MOFs (Cu-MOFs) catalysts in particular. To enhance the understanding of their oxidation state, a novel microwave-assisted synthesis method for generating OD-Cu nanosheet is introduced. This method allows precise manipulation of the oxidation sta...[ Read more ]</description>
      <author>Juhee Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14711/thesis-991013340341903412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Digitalization on Manufacturing Firms&#8217; Competitiveness, Environmental Sustainability, and Social Inclusiveness</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61242/ijabo.24.427</link>
      <description>Rashid Shabir Abbasi, Abdul Saboor, Auns Azhar, Sajid Khan, International Journal Administration Business and Organization. 5(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405886943

                Manufacturing is a crucial driver of economic growth, contributing approximately 17% to global GDP. This research investigates the impact of digitalization on manufacturing firms' competitiveness, environmental sustainability, and social inclusiveness, using Canon Inc.&#8217;s operations globally as a case study. Existing literature underscores the transformative potential of digital economics in the manufacturing industry; however, a comprehensive exploration of its impact on sustainability remains to be explored in detail. Employing a mixed-methods approach and Systems Theory as a theoretical framework, data was gathered from Canon's sustainability reports, financial statements, and online sources, focusing on the years 1997 to 2018. The study analyzes the implementation of digital technologies and their effects on profitability and sustainability outcomes. The research results indicate positive results with sustainable firms able to beat the competition in the long-run, as demonstrated by Canon&#8217;s revenue of approximately $36 billion in 2018 alongside significant reductions in CO2 emissions by 435,000 tonnes and a reduction in raw material usage by 314,000 tonnes. Additionally, Canon&#8217;s social initiatives, such as the Miraisha Programme, underscore its commitment to inclusivity. This study highlights the multifaceted benefits of integrating digital technologies in manufacturing, offering insights for firms aiming to balance profitability with sustainability.</description>
      <author>Rashid Shabir Abbasi, Abdul Saboor, Auns Azhar, Sajid Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61242/ijabo.24.427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility and safety of ultra-low volume ventilation (&#8804; 3 ml/kg) combined with extra corporeal carbon dioxide removal (ECCO2R) in acute respiratory failure patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-024-05168-8</link>
      <description>Cl&#233;ment Monet, Thomas Renault, Yassir Aarab, Joris Pensier, Albert Prades, In&#232;s Lakbar, Cl&#233;ment Le Bihan, Mathieu Capdevila, Audrey De Jong, Nicolas Molinari, Samir Jaber, Critical Care. 28(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405827757

                Ultra-protective ventilation is the combination of low airway pressures and tidal volume (Vt) combined with extra corporeal carbon dioxide removal (ECCO2R). A recent large study showed no benefit of ultra-protective ventilation compared to standard ventilation in ARDS (Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome) patients. However, the reduction in Vt failed to achieve the objective of less than or equal to 3 ml/kg predicted body weight (PBW). The main objective of our study was to assess the feasibility of the ultra-low volume ventilation (Vt &#8804; 3 ml/kg PBW) facilitated by ECCO2R in acute respiratory failure patients. Retrospective analysis of a prospective cohort of patients with either high or low blood flow veno-venous ECCO2R devices. A session was defined as a treatment of ECCO2R from the start to the removal of the device (one patient could have one more than one session). Primary endpoint was the proportion of sessions during which a Vt less or equal to 3 ml/kg PBW at 24 h after the start of ECCO2R was successfully achieved for at least 12 h. Secondary endpoints were respiratory variables, rate of adverse events and outcomes. Forty-five ECCO2R sessions were recorded among 41 patients. Ultra-low volume ventilation (tidal volume &#8804; 3 ml/kg PBW, success group) was successfully achieved at 24 h in 40.0% sessions (18 out of 45 sessions, confidence interval 25.3&#8211;54.6%). At 24 h, tidal volume in the failure group was 4.1 [3.8&#8211;4.5] ml/kg PBW compared to 2.1 [1.9&#8211;2.5] in the success group (p &lt; 0.001). After multivariate analysis, blood flow rate was significantly associated with success of ultra-low volume ventilation (adjusted OR per 100 ml/min increase 1.51 (95%CI 1.21&#8211;1.90, p = 0.0003). Ultra-low volume ventilation (&#8804; 3 ml/kg PBW) was feasible in 18 out of 45 sessions. Higher blood flow rates were associated with the success of ultra-low volume ventilation.</description>
      <author>Cl&#233;ment Monet, Thomas Renault, Yassir Aarab, Joris Pensier, Albert Prades, In&#232;s Lakbar, Cl&#233;ment Le Bihan, Mathieu Capdevila, Audrey De Jong, Nicolas Molinari, Samir Jaber</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-024-05168-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Green Finance in Harmonizing Economic and Environmental Goals: A Moroccan Perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24857/rgsa.v18n12-186</link>
      <description>Nabil Dahhou, Bahetta Soufiyan, Oulakhmis Abdellah, Massiki Ayoub, Revista de Gest&#227;o Social e Ambiental. 18(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405844554

                Objective: The objective of this study is to examine the relationship between green finance and sustainable development in Morocco, focusing on its dual impact on economic growth and environmental preservation during the 2016&#8211;2022 perio[1]d. Theoretical Framework: The research is grounded in the theoretical frameworks of green growth and sustainable development, emphasizing the synergies between economic prosperity and environmental sustainability. The concepts of renewable energy consumption and green finance as catalysts for economic and ecological balance are central to the study. Method: A quantitative approach was adopted, employing a correlation matrix and the Granger causality test to analyze the interplay between green finance, GDP growth, and CO2 emissions. Data from 2016 to 2022 were used, capturing Morocco&#8217;s progress in renewable energy adoption and green finance initiatives. Results and Discussion: The findings highlight a significant positive correlation between renewable energy consumption, green finance, and economic growth, alongsFDI a reduction in CO2 emissions. The results underscore the strategic importance of green finance in fostering sustainable growth while mitigating environmental impacts. The discussion contextualizes these findings within Morocco&#8217;s sustainability agenda, emphasizing the potential for green finance to drive ecological and economic transformation in other emerging economies. Research Implications: This study provFDIs practical insights for policymakers and stakeholders, advocating for expanded green finance frameworks and renewable energy integration to support sustainable development. Originality/Value: By addressing the empirical gap in linking green finance with economic and environmental outcomes, this research contributes tothe literature and offers a roadmap for leveraging financial systems to achieve green growth.</description>
      <author>Nabil Dahhou, Bahetta Soufiyan, Oulakhmis Abdellah, Massiki Ayoub</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24857/rgsa.v18n12-186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of a diesel engine performance and emission using biogas in dual fuel mode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31603/mesi.11407</link>
      <description>Amar Kumar Das, Manas Ranjan Padhi, Debashree Debadatta Behera, Shiv Sankar Das, Mechanical Engineering for Society and Industry. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405903110

                Environmental pollution and the gradual depletion of fossil fuels have recently shifted the focus to alternate fuels. Hence, more diversified research on alternate fuels is necessary to deal with the global energy crisis. Biogas extracted from biomass is an excellent alternative to fossil fuels due to its low cost and good mixing ability. It is mainly generated by anaerobic digestion of organic waste products in a digester tank. The present paper investigates the performance and emission characteristics of diesel engine in dual fuel mode with biogas as main fuel and diesel as pilot fuel without any engine modification. The main aspect of the paper is to critically study the effect of supplementation of biogas on diesel engine efficiency and emission level of important constituent gases such as CO2 and NOX. Our findings demonstrate that the essential performance result of engine, such as Brake Thermal Efficiency (BTE) and Mechanical Efficiency for the biogas-air mixture of 20% (DB20), was slightly decreased. At the same time, there was a reduction in brake-specific fuel consumption (BSFC) compared to pure diesel. Furthermore, the exhaust emission of NOX and CO2 was lowered when the engine was operated in dual fuel induction mode. The results of engine performance were found to be better than the results of other researchers for engines of same specifications and operating conditions. Hence, biogas serves as a viable alternative fuel and contributes to cleaner combustion, offering a promising solution for reducing the environmental impact of diesel engines. The study provides critical insights into optimizing dual fuel systems for enhanced performance and sustainability.</description>
      <author>Amar Kumar Das, Manas Ranjan Padhi, Debashree Debadatta Behera, Shiv Sankar Das</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31603/mesi.11407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size&#8208;adjustable High&#8208;Entropy Alloy Nanoparticles as an Efficient Platform for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423765</link>
      <description>Huizhu Cai, Hengpan Yang, Shijie He, Da Ping Wan, Deliang Li, Xingxing Jiang, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405858797

                The high entropy alloy (HEA) possesses distinctive thermal stability and electronic characteristics, which exhibits substantial potential for diverse applications in electrocatalytic reactions. However, accurately controlling the size of HEA still remains a challenge, especially for the ultrasmall HEA nanoparticles. Herein, we firstly calculate and illustrate the size impact on the electronic structure of HEA and the adsorption energies of crucial intermediates in typical electrocatalytic reactions, such as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), CO2 electroreduction (CO2RR) and NO3&#8211; electroreduction (NO3RR). Under the guidance of theoretical calculations, we synthesize a range of ultrasmall PtRuPdCoNi HEA nanoparticles with adjustable sizes (1.7, 2.3, 3.0, and 3.9 nm) using a one&#8208;step spatially confined approach. Specifically, HEA nanoparticles with 1.7 nm size (HEA&#8208;1.7) endows a 16 mV overpotential at current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, yielding a mass activity of 31.9 A mgNM&#8208;1 of noble metal in HER, significantly outperforming commercial Pt/C catalyst. This strategy can also be easily applicable to other reduction reactions attributed to the richness of metal components and size adjustability, presenting a promising platform for various electrocatalytic applications as advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Huizhu Cai, Hengpan Yang, Shijie He, Da Ping Wan, Deliang Li, Xingxing Jiang, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size&#8208;adjustable High&#8208;Entropy Alloy Nanoparticles as an Efficient Platform for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423765</link>
      <description>Huizhu Cai, Hengpan Yang, Shijie He, Da Ping Wan, Deliang Li, Xingxing Jiang, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405858796

                The high entropy alloy (HEA) possesses distinctive thermal stability and electronic characteristics, which exhibits substantial potential for diverse applications in electrocatalytic reactions. However, accurately controlling the size of HEA still remains a challenge, especially for the ultrasmall HEA nanoparticles. Herein, we firstly calculate and illustrate the size impact on the electronic structure of HEA and the adsorption energies of crucial intermediates in typical electrocatalytic reactions, such as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), CO2 electroreduction (CO2RR) and NO3&#8211; electroreduction (NO3RR). Under the guidance of theoretical calculations, we synthesize a range of ultrasmall PtRuPdCoNi HEA nanoparticles with adjustable sizes (1.7, 2.3, 3.0, and 3.9 nm) using a one&#8208;step spatially confined approach. Specifically, HEA nanoparticles with 1.7 nm size (HEA&#8208;1.7) endows a 16 mV overpotential at current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, yielding a mass activity of 31.9 A mgNM&#8208;1 of noble metal in HER, significantly outperforming commercial Pt/C catalyst. This strategy can also be easily applicable to other reduction reactions attributed to the richness of metal components and size adjustability, presenting a promising platform for various electrocatalytic applications as advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Huizhu Cai, Hengpan Yang, Shijie He, Da Ping Wan, Deliang Li, Xingxing Jiang, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the C&#8211;C Coupling Mechanism on Dual-Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CO Reduction Reaction: The Critical Role of CO Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03123</link>
      <description>Minghao He, Changshuang Jiang, Huimin Yan, Guofeng Wang, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405850979

                The electrochemical reduction reaction (RR) of CO to high value multicarbon products is highly desirable for carbon utilization. Dual transition metal atoms dispersed by N-doped graphene are able to be highly efficient catalysts for this process due to the synergy of the bimetallic sites for C&#8211;C coupling. In this work, we screened homonuclear dual-atom catalysts dispersed by N-doped graphene to investigate the potential in CO reduction to C2+ products by employing density functional theory calculations. We have demonstrated that the two adsorbed CO species on bimetallic sites cannot directly couple unless one of the CO molecules is hydrogenated. All the dual metal atom catalysts prefer a similar coupling mechanism, i.e., the asymmetric coupling of *CO on the bridged site and *CHO on the top site, while the Ni2 and Cu2 catalysts exhibit much better performance with moderate adsorption energies and low energy barriers. The enhanced activities are attributed to the decrease of the energy levels of *CO 2p states that weakens the metal&#8211;C bonding and thus facilitates the feasible C&#8211;C coupling with both low reaction energies and low barriers. These insights have revealed the significant role of the hydrogenation of CO species prior to the coupling step and may provide a theoretical perspective to understand the generation of C2+ products in the CO2/CORR.</description>
      <author>Minghao He, Changshuang Jiang, Huimin Yan, Guofeng Wang, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Allocation of Community Distributed Energy and Storage Based on Regional Autonomous Balance and Sharing Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010021</link>
      <description>Jiangping Liu, Jing Wang, Xue Cui, Peng Liu, Pingzheng Tong, Xueping Dang, Energies. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405781963

                In the context of new power systems, the rapid development of distributed renewable energy and the drive of dual carbon targets have prompted community-level clean energy and energy storage configuration to become the key to improving energy efficiency and reducing carbon emissions. Based on the regional autonomy balance and sharing mechanism, this paper establishes a community distributed energy and energy storage optimization configuration model. With the goal of minimizing the total operating cost of the community, the established model is linearized by using the Big-M method and the McCormick method and transformed into a mixed integer linear programming model that is easy to solve. In order to comprehensively evaluate the comprehensive benefits of the established optimization scheme, this paper introduces the indicators of clean energy self-consumption rate, load self-supply rate, static investment payback period, and static CO2 investment payback period from the aspects of energy utilization, the economy, and the environment. Finally, a calculation example analysis is conducted, and the results show that, compared with the scenario where energy storage is configured separately and distributed energy resources are not shared, the configuration strategy proposed in the article can reduce the energy storage configuration capacity by 46.6% and the distributed energy configuration capacity by 21.1%. Investment costs can be reduced by 15.6%. At the same time, 91.75% of distributed energy self-consumption and 96.80% of load self-supply are achieved, reducing grid interaction and promoting regional autonomy and balance. The static CO2 investment payback period is also significantly shortened, and the carbon emission reduction effect is significant, providing an important reference for community energy system optimization planning and green and low-carbon development.</description>
      <author>Jiangping Liu, Jing Wang, Xue Cui, Peng Liu, Pingzheng Tong, Xueping Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en18010021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Various Foaming Agents on Ceramic Foam from Solid Waste</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15010032</link>
      <description>Chenglin Zhao, Chunmin Wang, Z. Xia, Congcong Jiang, Yiran Dong, Zhiguo Lan, Crystals. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405927356

                Due to the significant amount of solid waste generated annually in China, the rational use of these wastes has become increasingly important. The production of foam ceramics is considered an effective method for the large-scale utilization of such solid waste. In this study, granite sawing mud was selected as the raw material, with SiC and MnO2 serving as foaming agent to prepare foam ceramics. The foaming behavior of sintered samples using different foaming agent was investigated to determine the most suitable type and amount of foaming agent for obtaining foam ceramics with excellent pore structures. Additionally, the effects of the foaming agent on the pore structure and physical mechanical properties of the foam ceramics were studied in detail. The results showed that SiC and MnO2 both resulted in the pronounced expansion to different extent, and increasing the content of foaming agent enhances foam expansion. The best dosage of SiC was 1%, the optimum additive amount of MnO2 is 2&#8211;3%. For SiC, the oxidation reduction reaction occurred between SiC and O2 to generate CO2/CO. For MnO2, firstly, the reduction of MnO2 to Mn2O3 occurred, and then the Mn2O3 dissolved in the glass melt and, subsequently, Mn3+ was reduced to Mn2+, leading to gas formation and foaming. Under the same dosage of foaming agent and preparation conditions, the sample prepared with SiC as the blowing agent has higher compressive strength, lower water absorption, and a more uniform pore structure.</description>
      <author>Chenglin Zhao, Chunmin Wang, Z. Xia, Congcong Jiang, Yiran Dong, Zhiguo Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15010032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-Driven Ventilation and Energy Optimization in Smart Office Buildings: Insights from a High-Resolution Occupancy and Indoor Climate Dataset</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010058</link>
      <description>Haidar Hosamo, Silvia Mazzetto, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405781739

                This paper explores innovative approaches to reducing energy consumption in building ventilation systems through the implementation of adaptive control strategies. Using a publicly available high-resolution dataset spanning a full year, the study integrates real-time data on occupancy, CO2 levels, temperature, window state, and external environmental conditions. Notably, occupancy data derived from computer vision-based detection using the YOLOv5 algorithm provides an unprecedented level of granularity. The study evaluates five energy-saving strategies: Demand-Controlled Ventilation (DCV), occupancy-based control, time-based off-peak reduction, window-open control, and temperature-based control. Among these, the occupancy-based strategy achieved the highest energy savings, reducing power consumption by 50%, while temperature-based control yielded a significant 37.27% reduction. This paper&#8217;s originality lies in its holistic analysis of multiple dynamic control strategies, integrating diverse environmental and operational variables rarely combined in prior research. The findings highlight the transformative potential of integrating real-time environmental data and advanced control algorithms to optimize HVAC performance. This study establishes a new benchmark for energy-efficient building management through offering practical recommendations and laying the groundwork for predictive models, renewable energy integration, and occupant-centric systems.</description>
      <author>Haidar Hosamo, Silvia Mazzetto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Assessment of Mine Water Resource Utilization in China: A Case Study of Xiegou Coal Mine in Shanxi Province</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010229</link>
      <description>Xuan Wang, Chi Zhang, Jin Yuan, Xin Sui, Di Su, Haoyu Wang, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405921753

                Climate change and water scarcity are two global challenges. Coal mining is the main source of carbon emissions. The utilization of mine water resources and its carbon footprint calculation are of paramount significance in promoting water conservation and carbon reduction in mining areas. However, research on the carbon footprint and other environmental indicators across the life cycle of mine water in developing countries, such as China, remains limited. This study focuses on a representative mine water resource utilization system in China and describes the method used to calculate carbon emissions associated with mine water resource utilization throughout its life cycle. Based on life cycle assessment (LCA) and using on-site investigations and analysis of environmental indicators, the study evaluates the environmental impacts at different stages of mine water resource utilization, identifies key processes, and provides some improvement suggestions. The research results indicate that the life cycle carbon emissions of mine water amount to 2.35 kg CO2 eq per 1 m3. The water extraction stage highlights the potential environmental impact, including water use (WU) and ozone depletion potential (ODP). By substituting traditional power generation methods and incorporating intelligent dosing equipment to optimize chemical usage, the global warming potential (GWP) has been decreased by over 90%, and the GWP of chemical consumption has also witnessed respective reductions of 21.5% and 10.1%. This study can serve as a basis for calculating carbon emissions in mining areas and formulating strategies to reduce their environmental impact.</description>
      <author>Xuan Wang, Chi Zhang, Jin Yuan, Xin Sui, Di Su, Haoyu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electrification of Transport: Key Drivers, Challenges, and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/12kcke97</link>
      <description>Zeyu Li, Highlights in Science Engineering and Technology. 121(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405781793

                The electrification of transport is increasingly recognized as a pivotal strategy in global efforts to mitigate climate change, reduce greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, and decrease dependency on fossil fuels. This paper investigates the key drivers behind the shift toward electric transportation, emphasizing environmental benefits, energy security, and technological advancements. Notable environmental advantages include significant reductions in CO2 emissions and air pollution, while energy security is enhanced by diminished reliance on oil and improved integration of electric vehicles (EVs) with renewable energy sources. Technological progress in battery systems, electric drivetrains, and smart grid infrastructure has accelerated the feasibility of widespread EV adoption. Despite these advances, the transition to electric transport faces several challenges, including the need for extensive charging infrastructure, sustainable sourcing of critical materials like lithium and cobalt, and the economic impacts on industries and labor markets. The paper explores strategies to overcome these challenges, such as advancements in recycling technologies, enhanced grid management, and supportive economic policies. By analyzing both the drivers and barriers, this paper provides a comprehensive assessment of the current landscape and future prospects for sustainable transport electrification.</description>
      <author>Zeyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/12kcke97</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Resource Extraction and Recycling from Waste: A Pathway to Sustainable Resource Conservation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/resources14010001</link>
      <description>Inna Pitak, &#1040;&#1085;&#1072;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1089;&#1110;&#1103; &#1064;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1093;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Ar&#363;nas Baltu&#353;nikas, Rita Kri&#363;kien&#279;, Resources. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405782156

                This study examines calcium extraction from Bottom Ash (BA) and the use of Solid Residue (SR) as a substitute for White Lump Clay (WLC) in brick production. Experimental analyses identified calcium and silicon as the main elements in BA, with 50% of calcium carbonate recovered through leaching. SR was a viable alternative to WLC in ceramic bricks, as SEM-EDS and FTIR analyses revealed changes in composition and microstructure. This approach promotes circular economy principles by recovering resources and reducing waste. Calcium extraction from BA can produce 29,000 tons of CaCO3 annually for industrial use, while substituting SR for WLC in brick production could replace 30% of clay, saving 1500 tons of clay and producing millions of bricks annually. Less than 50% of incinerated Municipal Solid Waste (MSW) would require landfilling. The process supports sustainable construction by conserving natural resources, reducing landfill waste, and lowering CO2 emissions. It offers annual cost savings of 2,639,250 USD and preserves 74,812.5 tons of resources through waste and clay reduction. By demonstrating a scalable model for waste valorization, this research aligns with global goals for sustainable development, resource efficiency, and ecological balance.</description>
      <author>Inna Pitak, &#1040;&#1085;&#1072;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1089;&#1110;&#1103; &#1064;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1093;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Ar&#363;nas Baltu&#353;nikas, Rita Kri&#363;kien&#279;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/resources14010001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why issue green bonds? Examining their dual impact on environmental protection and economic benefits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-024-04318-1</link>
      <description>Di Zhou, Andrew P. Kythreotis, Humanities and Social Sciences Communications. 11(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405925707

                Abstract This article explores two primary questions: first, whether the issuance of green bonds contributes to environmental protection, particularly regarding their performance after the adoption of net-zero emission policies; and second, whether issuers of green bonds can have economic benefits. Using the Difference-in-Differences (DID) model to analyze green and conventional bonds issued from 2013 to 2023, the study finds no significant correlation between green bond issuance and CO 2 emissions following net-zero adoption. Nevertheless, our findings are important and deserve attention as they indicate that the carbon reduction policies have not exerted sufficient pressure on bond issuers to reduce emissions. At the same time, however, a closer examination of issuing entities reveals that those issuing only green bonds tend to have higher ESG ratings, lower CO2 emissions, and lower financing costs. This suggests that such issuers achieve substantial environmental benefits and economic advantages. In contrast, entities issuing both conventional and green bonds do not demonstrate the same environmental benefits. This finding raises concerns about potential greenwashing, suggesting that entities issuing both green and conventional bonds may engage in practices that contradict environmental protection while presenting their activities as environmentally friendly through green bonds. The study also highlights that the impact of bond features on ESG scores and CO 2 emissions varies significantly across different types of issuers. Finally, the paper recommends that policymakers strengthen carbon reduction policies, establish mechanisms to prevent greenwashing, and integrate CO 2 emissions and ESG factors into assessment systems. Additionally, it calls for special attention to the carbon emissions of entities in low- and middle-income countries, as well as those in the manufacturing sector, to support the healthy development of green finance.</description>
      <author>Di Zhou, Andrew P. Kythreotis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-024-04318-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mechanism and Effects of the Digital Economy on Urban Resilience: An Empirical Test Based on 110 Cities in the Yangtze River Economic Belt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010030</link>
      <description>Yuqing Zhang, Zhimo Sun, Xiaolong Chen, Sustainability. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405781637

                Cities encounter increasing risks and challenges under new development patterns, and digital economy (DE) can drive cities&#8217; improved resilience to natural and social uncertainties. Based on data collected on the Yangtze River Economic Belt from 2011 to 2021, the development situation of the regional DE and urban resilience (UR) was measured, and the impact mechanisms of the DE on UR were analysed theoretically and empirically using a benchmark regression model. The findings are as follows: The benchmark test revealed that the DE development contributed significantly to UR in the region. The mediating effect test revealed that the DE improved UR through two pathways: industrial structure upgradation and energy restructuring. The moderating effect test suggested that environmental pollutant emissions had a negative moderating effect between the impact mechanisms of the DE, industrial structure, and energy structure and between the effects of industrial structure, energy structure, and UR, whereas CO2 emissions had a positive moderating effect between the impact mechanisms of DE and industrial structure. Heterogeneity analysis indicated that the DE contributed positively to the UR except in the upstream region, where the coefficient of the DE was insignificant. Overall, this study highlights the crucial role of the DE in improving UR and elucidates the theoretical impact mechanisms of environmental pollution control and carbon reduction measures on UR.</description>
      <author>Yuqing Zhang, Zhimo Sun, Xiaolong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su17010030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ketjenblack-Supported and Unsupported ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;ZrN Nanoparticle Systems for Enabling Efficient Electrochemical Nitrogen Reduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17137</link>
      <description>Mitu Sharma, Kotaro Sasaki, Gary P. Halada, Krishnakumari Pamula, Taejin Kim, Stanislaus S. Wong, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405801273

                Artificial N2 fixation via the electrocatalytic nitrogen (N2) reduction reaction (NRR) has been recently promoted as a rational route toward reducing energy consumption and CO2 emission as compared with the traditional Haber&#8211;Bosch process. Nevertheless, optimizing NRR relies on developing highly efficient electrocatalysts. Herein, we report on the reliable and reproducible synthesis of two promising electrocatalysts in either the presence or absence of Ketjenblack (KB), namely, ZrO2&#8211;ZrN@KB and ZrO2&#8211;ZrN systems, synthesized through the nitriding of Zr. Both materials had never previously been considered for NRR, to the best of our knowledge. Nevertheless, both of these electrocatalysts incorporated a combination of tetragonal ZrO2, ZrON, and cubic ZrN and showed excellent activity and durability toward NH3 formation. Moreover, the maximum NH3 production rate of 84.1 &#956;g h&#8211;1 mg&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.7 V vs a reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) was achieved with the ZrO2&#8211;ZrN electrocatalyst with an impressive Faradaic efficiency of 21.2% at &#8722;0.6 V vs RHE, indicating a high selectivity associated with the NRR. Additionally, the catalysts demonstrated excellent stability during the electrolysis process and recycling tests. We postulate that the combination of exposed active sites of ZrN and ZrO2 likely contributes to the enhanced NRR performance attributed to ZrO2&#8211;ZrN.</description>
      <author>Mitu Sharma, Kotaro Sasaki, Gary P. Halada, Krishnakumari Pamula, Taejin Kim, Stanislaus S. Wong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plant disease dynamics in a changing climate: impacts, molecular mechanisms, and climate-informed strategies for sustainable management</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44279-024-00144-w</link>
      <description>Md. Motaher Hossain, Farjana Sultana, Mahabuba Mostafa, Humayra Ferdus, Mridula Rahman, Jesleen Rana, Sayed Shahidul Islam, Shanta Adhikary, Anamika Sannal, Md. Al Emran Hosen, Jannatun Nayeema, Nusrat Jahan Emu, Mrinmoy Kundu, Sudhangshu Kumar Biswas, LABIBA FARZANA, Md. Abdullah Al Sabbir, Discover Agriculture. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405828840

                Climate change is increasingly conceded as a significant menace to global agricultural productivity, with plant diseases emerging as a critical challenge in this context. Plant diseases can result in an annual reduction of approximately US$220 billion in agricultural productivity, impacting global economies and socio-economic stability. To address these challenges, it is crucial to explore the intricate relationship between climatic variables and the occurrence, intensity, and geographic distribution of plant diseases, highlighting how shifts in temperature, CO2 levels, and precipitation patterns exacerbate pathogen virulence and alter disease dynamics. This review examines the historical and projected impacts of climate change on vulnerable crops and regions, emphasizing the heightened risk to food security. The molecular basis of climate-modulated plant defense mechanisms and pathogen virulence is dissected, offering insights into the underlying biological processes that govern these interactions. In response to this escalating threat, we discuss climate-informed plant disease management strategies, including early warning systems, adaptive surveillance, and the development of resilient crops through biotechnological advancements such as genetic engineering, gene silencing, and genome editing. Additionally, we explore the role of resource-saving technologies and precision agriculture in mitigating the adverse repercussions of climate change on plant health. The review concludes with an exploration of critical research needs and future perspectives, underscoring the urgent need for interdisciplinary approaches to safeguard sustainable agricultural productivity in a rapidly changing climate.</description>
      <author>Md. Motaher Hossain, Farjana Sultana, Mahabuba Mostafa, Humayra Ferdus, Mridula Rahman, Jesleen Rana, Sayed Shahidul Islam, Shanta Adhikary, Anamika Sannal, Md. Al Emran Hosen, Jannatun Nayeema, Nusrat Jahan Emu, Mrinmoy Kundu, Sudhangshu Kumar Biswas, LABIBA FARZANA, Md. Abdullah Al Sabbir</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44279-024-00144-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MANAGERIAL CHALLENGES OF INDUSTRIAL ENTERPRISES IN THE CONTEXT OF DECARBONIZATION AND EUROPEAN INTEGRATION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33111/sedu.2024.55.160.173</link>
      <description>Oleksandr Vostriakov, Denys Stepura, Strategy of Economic Development of Ukraine. None(55)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405922793

                The article addresses the managerial challenges faced by Ukrainian industrial enterprises in the context of decarbonization and European integration. It systematically examines the key aspects of transitioning to low-carbon technologies and strategies required to align with European Union (EU) environmental goals, standards, and policies. Special emphasis is placed on the EU&#700;s carbon reduction targets, the Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM), and their impact on exporters of industrial goods, including Ukrainian companies. The study identifies strategic, operational, financial, and technological challenges that hinder decarbonization processes while highlighting opportunities for enterprises to adopt sustainable practices. The research underscores the importance of optimizing production processes through renewable energy sources, carbon capture technologies, and emission monitoring systems. Enterprises must address the costeffectiveness of transitioning to low-carbon technologies, ensure transparent CO2 emission reporting, and attract financial support for sustainable projects. Furthermore, the paper discusses the global carbon footprint and EU climate neutrality plans, including reducing emissions by 55% by 2030 and achieving net-zero emissions by 2050. The study concludes that Ukrainian industrial enterprises need to integrate environmental management systems and prioritize innovation-driven solutions to maintain competitiveness in the EU market. Collaboration with international consulting firms, securing financing for decarbonization projects, and fostering corporate sustainability cultures are critical steps toward achieving compliance with EU standards and advancing environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>Oleksandr Vostriakov, Denys Stepura</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33111/sedu.2024.55.160.173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Late Middle to Late Ordovician Phosphate Accumulation of the Moyero River Section (Siberia): A Record of Upwelling and Global Cooling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2205/2024es000946</link>
      <description>Nikita Lykov, Yuliana Rostovtseva, A. V. Dronov, Rossijskij &#382;urnal nauk o zemle/Russian journal of earth sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405801689

                The phosphate-bearing rocks (phosphate rocks and phosphorites) were studied over a 45-meter interval of the Moyero river section, covering the upper part of the Darriwilian and the lower part of the Sandbian stages of the Ordovician. These rocks were investigated by field observations and laboratory methods, including optic and scanning electron microscopy, X-ray diffraction analyses. The accumulation of phosphatic matter is manifested in carbonates, sandstones, and aleurolites in the form of grains (ooids and peloids), intraclasts, phosphatic and phosphatized shells. In argillites, it is represented by cryptocrystalline matter. Phosphate matter consists of fluorapatite. The peaks of phosphate accumulation are associated with the formation of layers of physically reworked granular phosphorites (condensation horizons) directly above the depositional sequence boundaries. The formation of the studied phosphate-bearing rocks during the Darriwilian-Sandbian transition was influenced by a combination of global (Great Ordovician Biodiversification Event (GOBE), reduction in sea surface temperature, atmospheric CO2, high sea level, flooding of craton margins) and regional (equatorial position of Siberia, arid climate, facies) factors. Global conditions led to the enrichment of seawater with phosphorus and the effect of upwelling. Regional conditions determined the characteristics of phosphate formation. Studied phosphate-bearing rocks can be considered as a record of upwelling on the Siberian craton during the Middle-Late Ordovician transition and one of the manifestations of long-term global cooling started early in the Middle Ordovician.</description>
      <author>Nikita Lykov, Yuliana Rostovtseva, A. V. Dronov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2205/2024es000946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Exhaust Emissions from Palm Oil Biodiesel Diesel Engines by Adding Hydrogen Gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31603/ae.12404</link>
      <description>Kuntang Winangun, Yoyok Winardi, Indah Puspitasari, Nanang Suffiadi Akhmad, Rizki Dwi Ardika, Salih &#214;zer, Automotive Experiences. 7(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405846800

                The application of hydrogen enrichment of palm oil-based biodiesel in a compression ignition engine was examined in this work. Synthesized from crude palm oil (CPO), biodiesel was first fed into a single-cylinder diesel engine. The intake manifold received hydrogen gas at flows of 2.5 L/min, 5 L/min, 7.5 L/min, and 10 L/min. Operating at a constant speed of 2,000 rpm, the single-cylinder, direct-injection diesel engine used The aim of this work is to assess the performance and emissions of a diesel engine utilizing hydrogen gas and CPO biodiesel fuels. This work examined engine performance and exhaust emissions using smoke emissions, exhaust temperature, power, thermal efficiency, and fuel economy. Addition of hydrogen improved emissions and performance. Optimal engine performance was achieved by adding 2.5 L/min of hydrogen, which resulted in a 20.12% increase in brake thermal efficiency (BTE) and a 27.57% reduction in fuel consumption compared to biodiesel. The addition of hydrogen gas has a positive impact on exhaust emissions (HC, CO2, and smoke opacity), but has a negative impact on NO emissions. At elevated loads of 2.5 lpm hydrogen flow, emissions measured were 40.00 ppm, 0.04%, 4.20%, and 44.20%, respectively, alongside a 45.72% increase in NO emissions. Including hydrogen gas improves the diesel engines running on biodiesel's performance and exhaust pollutants.</description>
      <author>Kuntang Winangun, Yoyok Winardi, Indah Puspitasari, Nanang Suffiadi Akhmad, Rizki Dwi Ardika, Salih &#214;zer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31603/ae.12404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing the post-repair resource of the wheels attachment bolts of transport machinery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30977/bul.2219-5548.2024.107.0.37</link>
      <description>&#1030;. &#1042;. &#1044;&#1086;&#1097;&#1077;&#1095;&#1082;&#1110;&#1085;&#1072;, Bulletin of Kharkov National Automobile and Highway University. None(107)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405892311

                Abstract. Problem. The state of war in our country and a significant reduction in the production of new vehicles exacerbated the problem of increasing their operational resource due to repairs. Improving the quality and increasing the efficiency of transport vehicles involves, first of all, the fight against wear and tear, because the reason for their premature failure (from 75 to 90%) is significant wear and tear of parts. A significant number of parts of the main structural units of vehicles are exposed to cyclic loads, so it is quite reasonable to pay attention to the issue of increasing the fatigue strength of products. Considering the significant shortage and high cost of spare parts, an expedient and economically beneficial solution to these problems is the restoration and strengthening of the surface layers of products during repair The parts that mostly fail prematurely and require repair using rational methods of recovery include the bolts of fastening the wheels of buses - a very common vehicle that is intensively operated in very difficult conditions. The development of effective technological processes for the restoration of bolts with a simultaneous increase in the post-repair resource at the lowest costs is definitely an urgent issue, because it will prevent another possible premature failure in operation Goal. The purpose of the work is to restore and increase the post-repair resource of the bolts for fastening the disks of the rear wheels of the bus. Methodology. The subject of the study were the serial bolts for fastening the discs of the rear wheels of the bus made of 40X steel after quenching and tempering at 500-550&#186; C with a trostite-bainite structure and a hardness of 35-37 &#1053;&#1056;&#1057;. For vibro-arc surfacing, electrode wire &#1053;&#1087;-30&#1061;&#1043;&#1057;&#1040; with a diameter of 1.2 mm was used. Food carbon dioxide was used as a protective gas, and a 5% solution of soda ash in water was used as an accelerating coolant. After surfacing, the surface was subjected to bombardment with low-energy (up to 3 keV) titanium ions in an argon environment at the Bulat - 3t installation. After the specified methods of bolt processing, the roughness and surface profile were evaluated, the microstructure was studied, and the mechanical properties were determined. The strength limit of the slotted part of the bolt was determined using special samples on the CD10 universal machine (made in Germany). Cyclic tests of welded samples were carried out according to the scheme "tension during rotation of the cantilever-loaded sample" on the UMP-02 machine. Tensile tests were performed according to standard methods. Originality. To increase the cyclic durability and wear resistance of bolts, a modern method of surface modification was used - ion bombardment with low-energy ions (without coating), which made it possible to strengthen the surface layer without losing plasticity. An increase in the resource was achieved due to a change in the state of the surface (obtaining ultrafine crystalline nano-sized grain, healing of surface stress concentrators), and a change in the mechanism of plastic deformation - from dislocation to rotational with grain-boundary sliding of ultra-fine grains. Practical value. The recommended mode of vibro-arc surfacing provides surface hardness for the possibility of further mechanical processing without additional thermal weakening, which increases the cost-effectiveness of the process of compensation of the worn surface layer. Modification of the surface by ion brombarbing after surfacing made it possible to increase the cyclic durability by 2 times, significantly increase the static strength without loss of plasticity, and increase the hardness to ensure wear resistance.</description>
      <author>&#1030;. &#1042;. &#1044;&#1086;&#1097;&#1077;&#1095;&#1082;&#1110;&#1085;&#1072;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30977/bul.2219-5548.2024.107.0.37</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Global Warming Potential and Acidification in Smoked Fish Production at University of Ibadan Fish Farm: A Life Cycle Assessment Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5455/jrafs.20241110085505</link>
      <description>Abdulfatai Aremu, bernard Igomu, Taiwo Oluwatoyin Ajao, Journal of Research in Agriculture and Food Sciences.. 2(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405906893

                Abstract Aim: Life cycle assessment (LCA) is an ISO-standardized analytical tool developed to evaluate environmental performance of products and processes. The aquaculture industry is one of the largest and fast-growing industries in the agricultural sector because of its health benefits. However, this growth comes with fuel combustion technologies and other operations. Therefore, quantifying the level of impact caused by these processes is imperative. The study was aimed at carrying out an LCA for the production and processing of smoked fish using the University of Ibadan Fish Farm as a case study to identify environmentally detrimental production and processing hotspots. Methods: The approach employed for this study is the cradle-to-gate approach, which involves the operations from breeding/hatching to the packaging of smoked fish. Relevant data was obtained through site visitation and physical interviews. The data on energy and material resources used in the processes were modeled on GaBi9 (Holistic Balancing) software. The tool used to analyze the life cycle inventories of smoked fish production is TRACI (Tool for the Reduction and Assessment of Chemical and other Environmental Impacts) midpoint assessment and modeling was for 1kg functional unit of smoked fish. Four scenarios were drawn out for assessing the impact by varying the energy and material resources. Results: The total energy used in the smoking kiln for the one month under study was 35,660.16MJ. Six impact categories were measured for all four scenarios and the following categories had the highest impact in order of ascension; Global Warming Potential (GWP) (0.438, 0.243, 0.609, 0.624) kg CO2-Eqiv., Smog Air (0.0702, 0.288, 0.478, 0.277) kg O3-Equiv., Human Health Criteria Air (4.173e-03, 3.502e-04, 1.503e-03, 3.443e-03) kg PM10-Equiv. and Acidification Potential (AP) (2.19e-04, 2.88e-04, 3.37e-04, 5.68e-04) kg SO2-Equiv. The unit process with the highest impact on the environment for all four scenarios is the fish smoking process. Transportation and burning of charcoal also contributed to the emission of gases such as CO2, CO, CH4, N2O, SO2, NOx, VOCs, PMs, etc. Also, the use of Polyethylene (PE) and Low-Density Polyethylene (LDPE) plastics as packaging materials contribute to the release of heavy metals such; Cr, Cd, Ar, Zn, Cu, Pb, etc. into the environment for all four scenarios. Conclusion: The fish smoking process has the highest impact on the environment for all four scenarios. However other unit processes also have contributory effect. At the end of the study, it was recommended that renewable energy sources as well as energy from bio-waste should be explored for the smoking kilns to achieve cleaner production.</description>
      <author>Abdulfatai Aremu, bernard Igomu, Taiwo Oluwatoyin Ajao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5455/jrafs.20241110085505</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active Carbonic Anhydrase of the Thylakoid Lumen of Chlamydomonas reinhardtii</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants14010055</link>
      <description>Vasily V. Terentyev, Liubov I. Trubitsina, Anna K. Shukshina, Ivan V. Trubitsin, Natalia N. Rudenko, Plants. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405847777

                The green unicellular algae Chlamydomonas reinhardtii contains 12&#8211;13 carbonic anhydrases (CAs). For a long time, the two closely related &#945;-CAs of the periplasmic membrane CAH1 and CAH2 were considered to be the CAs with the highest CO2 hydration activity. The recombinant protein &#945;-CA CAH3 (rCAH3) from the thylakoid lumen obtained in the present study showed more than three times higher activity compared to CAH1 and more than 11 times higher compared to previous studies with rCAH3. Long-term sustainability of the enzyme was observed at alkaline pH (&gt;8), with maintenance of half of its activity at 4 &#176;C for up to 50 days. Thermostability of rCAH3 indicated the retention of the activity at 20 &#176;C for one hour at pH 9&#8211;10 with its ~50% decrease at pH 6&#8211;7. However, the residual activity of rCAH3 after incubation at an extremely high temperature (75 &#176;C) for 15 min led to the formation of the double-hump graph with maxima at pH 6 and 9. The enzyme demonstrated high sensitivity to ethoxyzolamide and acetazolamide at nM concentrations, to Zn2+ and Cu2+ cations at 1 mM concentrations, and L-cysteine was able to completely inhibit CA activity of rCAH3 through reduction of sulfhydryl groups. Esterase activity of rCAH3 was well detected with values comparable to those of bovine CAII, but with a maximum at pH 8 instead of pH 9, which is usual for bovine CAII. The results indicated that CAH3 may be the most active CA of C. reinhardtii and that its role in the photosynthetic apparatus function could have been underestimated in previous works.</description>
      <author>Vasily V. Terentyev, Liubov I. Trubitsina, Anna K. Shukshina, Ivan V. Trubitsin, Natalia N. Rudenko</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants14010055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic model for integrating biogas a framework for sustainable energy integration in agro-industries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-83181-1</link>
      <description>Ahmad Nahwani, Soeprijanto Soeprijanto, Erwin Widodo, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405865792

                The framework of the methodology presented in this study is an effort to integrate and optimize the agro-industry sector, especially energy in biogas. In this study, the technique of the system in functional analysis is shown systematically to translate various energy requirements in the factory as criteria for performance and functional design to be integrated, optimized, and energy efficient. The case study results indicated that biogas power plants, with a capacity of 1.5 MW, can produce around 13,140 MWh per year. The annual return on investment (ROI) is around 37.13%. With this ROI value, the payback period is 31 months. The overall reduction of greenhouse gases is approximately 77,826 tons CO2 eq/year. The potential value of carbon trading is about USD 3,113,040 per year. This strategic model presents a novel approach by integrating biogas energy production with a customized wastewater treatment system adapted to biodigesters' effluent characteristics. It offers a sustainable, economically feasible, and scalable solution, combining resource recovery, waste minimization, and potential for carbon trading into a unified system. The novelty of this research lies in maximizing the utility of biogas plants by efficiently treating and reusing wastewater, creating a closed-loop, zero-waste process. Future research on hybrid systems integrating Biogas power plants by focusing on efficiency optimization, economic feasibility, environmental impacts, and innovative approaches like AI and blockchain could make the hybrid system a more robust, scalable, and sustainable solution. Thus, the framework based on the results of this study finds tools that can maximize and integrate energy sources, especially biogas, in the agro-industrial sector.</description>
      <author>Ahmad Nahwani, Soeprijanto Soeprijanto, Erwin Widodo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-83181-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Assessment of the Strategies for Energy Transition in Kenya as a Climate Change Mitigation Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47772/ijriss.2024.815ec0015</link>
      <description>Bertha Othoche, International Journal of Research and Innovation in Social Science. VIII(XV)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405891467

                Climate change is a global issue affecting communities in different parts of the world. Climate change is associated with extreme weather and climate patterns that affect the general health of the environment and humanity. The causes of climate change are both natural and anthropogenic. The human induced climate change has accelerated the emission of greenhouse gases that in turn cause global warming and climate change. The international community have initiated various interventions to minimize emission of greenhouse gases in order to maintain a healthier environment for sustainable development. One such initiative and/or interventions is the energy transition strategy that involves transition from a purely fossil fuel based to renewable energy-based economy. This paper therefore looks at the energy transition in Kenya. Specifically, the paper covers energy demand and supply, Mt CO2 emission; energy transitions process; constraints and opportunities. Kenya is going through a transition period in the energy sector and at the same time the country is striving to industrialize by the year 2023 being guided by the Country&#8217;s 2010 Constitution and the Vision 2030 which aims at transforming the country into a middle level economy. It is important that as the country strives to industrialize, the energy that drives the economy should be clean to enhance cleaner energy production. The country is a signatory to the landmark agreement of COP21 held in Paris, France in 2015. The country committed to observe the requirements of the Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) to ensure the reduction of emission of greenhouse gases and has put in place various institutional and legal frameworks towards this end. One of the most recent frameworks is the Climate Change Amendment Act, 2023. The main objective of the study is to assess the energy transition process and associated challenges. The study uses an exploratory design and employed descriptive statistics in data analysis. Data was presented in the form of tables, graphs, and themes. The result indicates that energy transition in Kenya is ongoing through specific processes and technologies. The results also confirm existing challenges and recommends sustained effort for sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Bertha Othoche</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47772/ijriss.2024.815ec0015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate Energy Consumption Prediction for Cleaner Fused Deposition Modeling (FDM)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/msec2024-124948</link>
      <description>Vincenzo Ferraro, Corrado Sciancalepore, Adrian H. A. Lutey, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405899437

                Abstract Additive Manufacturing (AM) has revolutionized rapid prototyping and mechanical production in a range of different fields, including e-mobility and aerospace, as well as personalized medical devices. In an era dominated by increasing environmental awareness, requirements to reduce CO2 emissions and climate change associated with manufacturing energy consumption are paramount, further to the development of clean energy systems. With the aim of achieving cleaner production, accurate prediction of energy consumption during additive manufacturing processes is the first step in obtaining tangible reductions in manufacturing-related emissions. Energy optimization not only promotes environmental sustainability, but also gives an additional competitive advantage to additive manufacturing processes in today&#8217;s market, bringing considerable benefits to these technologies. The present work provides an in-depth study into energy consumption during additive manufacturing, applying a novel and highly accurate methodology for evaluating electrical energy usage during Fused Deposition Modeling (FDM) as a test case for applying this approach to a wider range of additive manufacturing technologies such as Laser Powder Bed Fusion (LPBF), Selective Laser Sintering (SLS), Stereolithography (SLA) and others. FDM is renowned for its popularity in multiple sectors due to its versatility in achieving customized results at low cost with relative ease and safety. To date, the vast majority of scientific literature relating to additive manufacturing has focused on the mechanical properties of printed objects, topology optimization, support structures and energy consumption. Investigations into the energy consumption during additive manufacturing have mainly focused on the measurement and estimation of total energy consumption over the entire printing process based on general considerations and, in some cases, machine learning algorithms. The present study distinguishes itself from previous works by providing precise and detailed analysis of each individual step in the printing process. Experimental evaluation of each machine action was performed, allowing translation of the machine instructions (G-code) employed for printing an object into distinct energy contributions for each action during the process. This approach makes it possible to estimate the total energy consumption very accurately as the sum of all energy contributions, allowing an additional energy optimization parameter to be introduced. Such a detailed analysis allows the main drivers of energy consumption during FDM to be identified, leading to relatively simple solutions to dramatically reduce energy consumption during the process. The presented approach was developed as a test bed for detailed evaluation of energy consumption during additive manufacturing, with potential for application over a wide range of different technologies with similar approaches.</description>
      <author>Vincenzo Ferraro, Corrado Sciancalepore, Adrian H. A. Lutey</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/msec2024-124948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Climate Change on Forest Resources in Mexico: Regional Projections and Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/jgeesi/2024/v28i12849</link>
      <description>Ram&#237;rez-S&#225;nchez Hermes Ulises, Fajardo-Montiel A&#237;da Lucia, Journal of Geography Environment and Earth Science International. 28(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405856516

                Anthropogenic climate change can affect forest ecosystems and is one of the causes of deforestation, which leads to desertification. Deforestation is one of the main drivers of climate change due to the release of large amounts of CO2 stored in forests and jungles. Rising temperatures, decreased rainfall and drought have negative impacts on the diversity of forest species, as well as on forest ecosystem goods and services. Thus, this research focuses on climate change and its impact on Mexico's forests, evaluating deforestation and its effects on climate change and, subsequently, the effects of that climate change on forests; and the role of forests in carbon sequestration. Aims: The objective of this study is to present a set of regional temperature, precipitation, and drought projections for Mexico under the IPCC's AR6 climate change scenarios, and to estimate the potential impacts on Mexico's forest resources. Methodology: The methodology consists of obtaining a set of regional projections of temperature, precipitation, vegetation, drought and soil moisture under the conditions of the IPCC AR6 climate change scenarios for Mexico, with the changes of the aforementioned variables the vulnerability of the forestry sector in Mexico will be evaluated through models of the influence of these factors. Results: Regional models for Mexico show temperature increases ranging from 0.5 to 5 &#176;C, while the percentage change in precipitation will range from -20.3% to 13.5% depending on the scenario and period of analysis. The low soil moisture (mm), the negative changes of the NDVI and the SPEI12 show that the North, West and Baj&#237;o zones will present reductions in precipitation and temperature increase that will cause a severe deficit of soil moisture and water stress in the plants, considering these areas with scarce vegetation and the presence of semi-permanent meteorological drought. Under these scenarios, it is expected that practically the entire country will be subject to moderate droughts (Central and South) to extremely severe droughts (North) that will last and worsen between now and the end of the century. These conditions have already been recorded in Mexico's main forest areas and if adaptation and mitigation measures are not adopted, the country's forest resources are at risk. Likewise, in addition to the decrease in rainfall, it is estimated that it will be more intense with the presence of extreme events, which will increase the vulnerability of some basins throughout the country, in the Central and Northern areas with extreme drought events, while in the Southeast with floods. Conclusion: Temperate and cloud forests, xerophilous scrub and grasslands will be the most affected forest ecosystems in Mexico, to reduce the effects of climate change on forest resources, it is necessary to design and prioritize adaptation actions and implement mitigation measures that prevent the effects of climate change from intensifying in the most vulnerable regions of the country.</description>
      <author>Ram&#237;rez-S&#225;nchez Hermes Ulises, Fajardo-Montiel A&#237;da Lucia</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.9734/jgeesi/2024/v28i12849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Neutron Stars from &lt;i&gt;Insight&lt;/i&gt;-HXMT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1142/9789819800643_0009</link>
      <description>M. Y. Ge, WORLD SCIENTIFIC eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405810146

                Pulsar Astronomy, pp. 185-206 (2025) No AccessChapter 9: Advances in Neutron Stars from Insight-HXMTMingyu GeMingyu GeInstitute of High Energy Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100049, Chinahttps://doi.org/10.1142/9789819800643_0009Cited by:0 (Source: Crossref) PreviousNext AboutFiguresReferencesRelatedDetailsPDF/EPUB ToolsAdd to favoritesDownload CitationsTrack CitationsRecommend to Library ShareShare onFacebookTwitterLinked InRedditEmail Cite Recommend Abstract: Though great progress has been achieved from the multi-band observations and theoretical work since the discovery of pulsars more than 50 years ago, some basic problems, such as radiation process in pulsating ultraluminous X-ray source, the origins of fast radio burst and so on. X-ray observations could supply crucial information to understand the characteristics and behaviors of pulsars. Recently, some progress for these basic problems has been achieved via the observations of Insight-HXMT. Keywords: PulsarsX-ray pulsarMagnetarType-I burstMagnetic field We recommendExtraction of carbon nanotubes with porphyrin- and pyrene-based nanotweezers and nanocalipers: Insight from the association constantsAlejandro L&#243;pez-Moreno, Journal of Porphyrins and Phthalocyanines, 2020Advances in Anti-Osteoporosis Polysaccharides Derived from Medicinal Herbs and Other Edible SubstancesZefeng Zhao, The American Journal of Chinese Medicine, 2022Recent Advances in Drug Delivery System for Bioactive Glycosides from Traditional Chinese MedicineLei Li, The American Journal of Chinese Medicine, 2019A Systematic Review on Polysaccharides from Dendrobium Genus: Recent Advances in the Preparation, Structural Characterization, Bioactive Molecular Mechanisms, a...The American Journal of Chinese Medicine, 2022Recent advances in the rational designing of metalloporphyrinoid-based CO2 reduction catalysts: From molecular structural tuning to the application in catalysisBeatriu Domingo-Tafalla, Journal of Porphyrins and Phthalocyanines, 2023From Finite Nuclei to Neutron Stars: The Essential Role of High-Order Density Dependence in Effective Forces Chong-Ji Jiang&#33931;&#23815;&#22522;, Chinese Physics LettersAdvances in spinal cord injury: insights from non-human primates Ga&#235;tan Poulen, Florence E. Perrin, Neural Regeneration Research, 2024Generation of brain vascular heterogeneity: recent advances from the perspective of angiogenesis Nathanael J. Lee, Ryota Matsuoka, Neural Regeneration Research, 2024Liquid&#8211;liquid phase separation in plants: Advances and perspectives from model species to crops Qianwen Liu, Wenxuan Liu, Yiding Niu, et al., Plant Communications, 2024Novel insight into the formation and inhibition mechanism of dipeptidyl peptidase-&#8547; inhibitory peptides from fermented mandarin fish (Chouguiyu) Yang Daqiao, Food Science and Human Wellness, 2023Powered by Privacy policyGoogle Analytics settings FiguresReferencesRelatedDetailsNone Recommended Recommended MAGNETARS: FACT OR FICTION?HAO TONG and REN-XIN XUInternational Journal of Modern Physics EVol. 20, No. supp02Compact stars and the evolution of binary systemsE. P. J. van den HeuvelFluid Flows to Black HolesFORMATION AND APPEARANCE OF PULSAR-LIKE WHITE DWARFSN. R. IKHSANOV and N. G. BESKROVNAYAThe Thirteenth Marcel Grossmann MeetingUltra-stripped supernovae and double neutron star systemsBy (author): Thomas M. TaurisThe Fourteenth Marcel Grossmann MeetingMAGNETIC ACCRETION IN X-RAY PULSARSN. R. IKHSANOV, YU. S. LIKH, N. G. BESKROVNAYA, and L. A. PUSTIL'NIKThe Thirteenth Marcel Grossmann MeetingTHE SPIN-UP OF ACCRETING NEUTRON STARS IN BINARY SYSTEMSJ. WANG, C. M. ZHANG, and Y. H. ZHAOInternational Journal of Modern Physics DVol. 20, No. 10On the origin of the unique isolated X-Ray pulsar 1E 161348-5055 with 6.7 hr. spin periodBy (author): V. Yu. KimThe Sixteenth Marcel Grossmann MeetingInvestigating gamma-ray bursts by joining Insight-HXMT and other gamma-ray spacecraftBy (author): C. Guidorzi, R. Martone, M. Marongiu, F. Frontera, P. Rosati, E. Virgilli, L. Amati, M. Orlandini, J. Stephen, C. Giuri, S.-N. Zhang, and S. XiongThe Fifteenth Marcel Grossmann Meeting Pulsar AstronomyMetrics History KeywordsPulsarsX-ray pulsarMagnetarType-I burstMagnetic fieldPDF download</description>
      <author>M. Y. Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1142/9789819800643_0009</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
