<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 01:21:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of Platinum&#8211;Copper Alloy/Titanium Dioxide for Enhanced Photocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120191</link>
      <description>Xin Wang, Wei Tan, Bo Peng, Shangcong Sun, Xue Li, Kaiqiang Wang, Jiawei Ji, Haohong Liao, Jingfang Sun, Qing Tong, Haiqin Wan, Lin Dong, Environmental Research. 263(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403531303

                To develop an efficient photocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO</description>
      <author>Xin Wang, Wei Tan, Bo Peng, Shangcong Sun, Xue Li, Kaiqiang Wang, Jiawei Ji, Haohong Liao, Jingfang Sun, Qing Tong, Haiqin Wan, Lin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing In-Situ Oxidation of Nanostructured MXene to Modulate the Electronic Structure for Improved Selectivity for Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110385</link>
      <description>Guangxin Sun, Yimin Zhang, Haonan Xie, Ya He, Caiwei Zhang, Yukun Hu, Enzuo Liu, Chunnian He, Andrew Barnabas Wong, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403559337

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guangxin Sun, Yimin Zhang, Haonan Xie, Ya He, Caiwei Zhang, Yukun Hu, Enzuo Liu, Chunnian He, Andrew Barnabas Wong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repurposing First-Row Transition Metal Carbon Dioxide Reduction Electrocatalysts for Electrochemical Carboxylation of Benzyl Chloride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsorginorgau.4c00051</link>
      <description>Pornwimon Kongkiatkrai, Thana Anusanti, Teera Chantarojsiri, ACS Organic &amp; Inorganic Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403572803

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pornwimon Kongkiatkrai, Thana Anusanti, Teera Chantarojsiri</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsorginorgau.4c00051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Effect of rGO Addition on Photocatalytic Activity of TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in Reducing Carbon Dioxide Using Electrochemical Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2866/1/012089</link>
      <description>Tri Komala Junita, Ferry Faizal, Norman Syakir, Annisa Aprilia, Lathifah Puji Hastuti, Fitrilawati Fitrilawati, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2866(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403658040

                Abstract Increasing the carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) concentration every year can cause various environmental problems. One of the technologies to reduce CO 2 is carbon capture. The semiconductor of TiO 2 is widely used as a photocatalyst to reduce CO 2 . However, TiO 2 has limitations in absorbing light in the visible region because it has a large band gap value. Besides, TiO 2 has a fast recombination of electron-hole pairs so it can reduce photocatalytic activity. An addition of rGO is expected to cover the shortcomings of TiO 2 because rGO has good conductivity and a small band gap. We synthesized rGO-TiO 2 photocatalyst and measured its activity in capturing and converting CO 2 using an electrochemical method. By using voltage difference as an electron driver in reacting with CO 2 we observe the reaction between electrons and CO 2 . The measurements were carried out under irradiated and unirradiated conditions. The CV measurements show that the rGO-TiO 2 electrode with 60% rGO content has reduction and oxidation peaks. Based on the electrochemical half-reaction table, the reduction peaks in unirradiated conditions indicate the conversion of CO 2 to CH 4 and (COOH) 2 , while under irradiated the reduction peak indicates the formation of HCOO &#8722; and CH 2 CH 2 . The results show that by using the rGO-TiO 2 composite as an electrode not only reduces CO 2 but also converts the CO 2 into hydrocarbon.</description>
      <author>Tri Komala Junita, Ferry Faizal, Norman Syakir, Annisa Aprilia, Lathifah Puji Hastuti, Fitrilawati Fitrilawati</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2866/1/012089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanomaterials Toward CO2 Reduction and Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14201676</link>
      <description>Rafael Camarillo, Nanomaterials. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403610630

                The increasing concentration of CO2 in the atmosphere is one of the main factors contributing to global climate change [...]</description>
      <author>Rafael Camarillo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14201676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu2O-based catalysts applied for CO2 electrocatalytic reduction: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06287f</link>
      <description>Cong Liu, Rui&#8208;tang Guo, Hao&#8208;wen Zhu, Heng-fei Cui, Mingyang Liu, Wei-guo Pan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629403

                The application of sustainable energy-driven electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (CO2RR) technology enables the synthesis of valuable chemicals and feedstocks. This offers a promising pathway to effectively reduce greenhouse gas emissions...</description>
      <author>Cong Liu, Rui&#8208;tang Guo, Hao&#8208;wen Zhu, Heng-fei Cui, Mingyang Liu, Wei-guo Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06287f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physicochemical Analysis of Cu(II)&#8208;Driven Electrochemical CO2 Reduction and its Competition with Proton Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403321</link>
      <description>Sk Samim Akhter, Diship Srivastava, Aman Mishra, Niladri Patra, Pankaj Kumar, Sumanta Kumar Padhi, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403608291

                The reduction of CO2 has become a key role in reducing greenhouse gas emissions in efforts to search for long&#8208;term responses to climate change. We report a a couple of CO2&#8208;reducing molecular catalysts based on earth&#8208;abundant copper complexes. These are [Cu(DPA)(PyNAP)] (1) and [Cu(DPA)(PyQl)] (2) (where, DPA = pyridine&#8208;2,6&#8208;dicarboxylic acid, PyNAP = 2&#8208;(pyridin&#8208;2&#8208;yl)&#8208;1,8&#8208;naphthyridine, and PyQl = 2&#8208;(pyridin&#8208;2&#8208;yl)quinoline). The copper metal&#8208;catalysed 2&#8208;electron reduction of CO2 to CO in the presence of 2&#8208;protons is challenging. These catalysts exhibit the production of CO gas in DMF/water mixtures, achieving an impressive faradaic efficiency of 84% and 72% for complex 1 and 2 at &#8208;1.7 V vs. SCE, respectively, for selective CO2 reduction. The production of H2 due to 2H+ + 2e&#8208; was also observed as a byproduct through the competitive proton reduction reaction. This was cross&#8208;verified by online gas and mass analysis. Our investigations confirmed the stability of the electrocatalysts under the electrocatalytic conditions. The mechanistic pathways were proposed to work with the EECC and ECEC (E: electrochemical and C: chemical) mechanisms. A CO2 insertion into an in&#8208;situ generated hydride from the Cu&#8208;center generates CO through the favourable path.</description>
      <author>Sk Samim Akhter, Diship Srivastava, Aman Mishra, Niladri Patra, Pankaj Kumar, Sumanta Kumar Padhi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supercritical carbon dioxide foamed thermoplastic polyester elastomer with poly(lactic acid) blending: shrinkage reduction and expansion ratio improvement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00396-024-05329-9</link>
      <description>Zongquan Gu, Bo Zhao, Li Zhang, Jin-Biao Bao, Colloid &amp; Polymer Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403515043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongquan Gu, Bo Zhao, Li Zhang, Jin-Biao Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00396-024-05329-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethane-oxidising archaea couple CO2 generation to F420 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53338-7</link>
      <description>Olivier N. Lemaire, Gunter Wegener, Tristan Wagner, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403612519

                Abstract The anaerobic oxidation of alkanes is a microbial process that mitigates the flux of hydrocarbon seeps into the oceans. In marine archaea, the process depends on sulphate-reducing bacterial partners to exhaust electrons, and it is generally assumed that the archaeal CO 2 -forming enzymes (CO dehydrogenase and formylmethanofuran dehydrogenase) are coupled to ferredoxin reduction. Here, we study the molecular basis of the CO 2 -generating steps of anaerobic ethane oxidation by characterising native enzymes of the thermophile Candidatus Ethanoperedens thermophilum obtained from microbial enrichment. We perform biochemical assays and solve crystal structures of the CO dehydrogenase and formylmethanofuran dehydrogenase complexes, showing that both enzymes deliver electrons to the F 420 cofactor. Both multi-metalloenzyme harbour electronic bridges connecting CO and formylmethanofuran oxidation centres to a bound flavin-dependent F 420 reductase. Accordingly, both systems exhibit robust coupled F 420 -reductase activities, which are not detected in the cell extract of related methanogens and anaerobic methane oxidisers. Based on the crystal structures, enzymatic activities, and metagenome mining, we propose a model in which the catabolic oxidising steps would wire electron delivery to F 420 in this organism. Via this specific adaptation, the indirect electron transfer from reduced F 420 to the sulphate-reducing partner would fuel energy conservation and represent the driving force of ethanotrophy.</description>
      <author>Olivier N. Lemaire, Gunter Wegener, Tristan Wagner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53338-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to HCO2H by protic NHC-Ir complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2024.123422</link>
      <description>Saswati Ray, Sanajit Kumar Mandal, Joyanta Choudhury, Journal of Organometallic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403566238

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saswati Ray, Sanajit Kumar Mandal, Joyanta Choudhury</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2024.123422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CO2 Reduction Efficiency through Electrolyte Immersion in Hierarchical Bismuth-Nickel Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02441a</link>
      <description>Y AN, Yong&#8208;Ju Lee, Yujing Ji, Young Dok Kim, Hyun Ook Seo, Duk&#8722;Young Jung, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403657309

                Nanostructures are critical to improve contact area with an electrolyte and catalytic efficiency for the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). However, their hydrophobicity conflicts with the intended increase in contact area...</description>
      <author>Y AN, Yong&#8208;Ju Lee, Yujing Ji, Young Dok Kim, Hyun Ook Seo, Duk&#8722;Young Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02441a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene-Based Single-Atom Catalysts for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction: Unraveling the Roles of Metals and Dopants in Tuning Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-gm3h4</link>
      <description>Colin Gallagher, Manish Kothakonda, Qing Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403649311

                Discovering electrocatalysts that can efficiently convert carbon dioxide (CO2) to valuable fuels and feedstocks using excess renewable electricity is an emergent carbon-neutral technology. A single metal atom embedded in doped graphene, i.e., single-atom catalyst (SAC), possesses high activity and selectivity for electrochemical CO2 reduction (CO2R) to CO, yet further reduction to hydrocarbons is challenging. Here, using density functional theory calculations, we investigate stability and reactivity of a broad SAC chemical space with various metal centers (3d transition metals) and dopants (2p dopants of B, N, O; 3p dopants of P, S) as electrocatalysts for CO2R to methane and methanol. We observe that the rigidities of these SACs depend on the type of dopants, with 3p-coordinating SACs exhibiting more severe out-of-plane distortion than 2p-coordinating SACs. Using CO adsorption energy as a descriptor for CO2R reactivity, we narrow down the candidates and identify seven SACs with near-optimal CO binding strength. We then elucidate full reaction mechanisms towards methane and methanol generation on these identified candidates and observe highly dopant-dependent activity and rate-limiting steps, divergent from conventional mechanistic understanding on metallic surfaces, calling into question whether previous design principles established on metals are directly transferrable to SACs. Consequently, we find that zinc embedded in boron-doped graphene (Zn-B-C) is a highly active catalyst for electrochemical CO2R to C1 hydrocarbons. Our work reveals the opportunities of tuning SAC reactivity via engineering dopants and metals and highlights the importance of re-elucidating CO2R reaction mechanisms on SACs towards unearthing new design principles for SAC chemistry.</description>
      <author>Colin Gallagher, Manish Kothakonda, Qing Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-gm3h4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab initio calculations of high-entropy clusters for oxygen reduction and evolution as well as CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161555</link>
      <description>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403561270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Reduction by Transition&#8208;Metal Complex Systems: Effect of Hydrogen Bonding on the Second Coordination Sphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401394</link>
      <description>Xiangming Liang, Zhijun Ruan, Guiquan Guo, Junqi Lin, Di&#8208;Chang Zhong, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403612058

                Homogeneous electrocatalysts typified by transition&#8208;metal complex show transcendent potency in efficient energy catalysis through molecular design. For example, metal complexes with elaborate design performed wonderful activity and selectivity for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction. Primary coordination sphere of metal complexes plays a key role in regulating its intrinsic redox properties and catalytic activity. However, the overall reduction efficiency of CO2 is also bound up with the substrate activation process. Transition&#8208;metal complexes are hoped to exhibit reasonable redox potential, reactive activity, and stability, while binding and activating CO2 molecules to achieve efficient CO2 reduction. Construction of second coordination sphere, especially hydrogen&#8208;bonding network of transition metal complexes, is reported to be the &#8220;kill two birds with one stone&#8221; strategy to realize efficient CO2 reduction catalysis via systematic catalyst properties modulation and substrate activation. Herein, we present recent progress on the construction of hydrogen&#8208;bonding network in the second coordination sphere of metal complexes by ligand modification or the introduction of exogenous organic ligand, and the resulted productive enhancement of the catalytic performance of metal complexes by the improvement of adsorption capacity and activation of CO2, proton transfer rate, and stability of reaction intermediates, etc.</description>
      <author>Xiangming Liang, Zhijun Ruan, Guiquan Guo, Junqi Lin, Di&#8208;Chang Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Impact of Water Content in Solvent Systems on Photochemical CO2 Reduction Catalyzed by Ruthenium Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29204960</link>
      <description>Yusuke Kuramochi, Masaya Kamiya, Hitoshi Ishida, Molecules. 29(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403603221

                To achieve artificial photosynthesis, it is crucial to develop a catalytic system for CO2 reduction using water as the electron source. However, photochemical CO2 reduction by homogeneous molecular catalysts has predominantly been conducted in organic solvents. This study investigates the impact of water content on catalytic activity in photochemical CO2 reduction in N,N-dimethylacetamide (DMA), using [Ru(bpy)3]2+ (bpy: 2,2&#8242;-bipyridine) as a photosensitizer, 1-benzyl-1,4-dihydronicotinamide (BNAH) as an electron donor, and two ruthenium diimine carbonyl complexes, [Ru(bpy)2(CO)2]2+ and trans(Cl)-[Ru(Ac-5Bpy-NHMe)(CO)2Cl2] (5Bpy: 5&#8242;-amino-2,2&#8242;-bipyridine-5-carboxylic acid), as catalysts. Increasing water content significantly decreased CO and formic acid production. The similar rates of decrease for both catalysts suggest that water primarily affects the formation efficiency of free one-electron-reduced [Ru(bpy)3]2+, rather than the intrinsic catalytic activity. The reduction in cage-escape efficiency with higher water content underscores the challenges in replacing organic solvents with water in photochemical CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Yusuke Kuramochi, Masaya Kamiya, Hitoshi Ishida</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29204960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P-tuned FeN2 binuclear sites for boosted CO2 electro-reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.011</link>
      <description>Cao Guo, Sanshuang Gao, Jing Wang, Menglin Zhou, Abdukader Abdukayum, Qingquan Kong, Yingtang Zhou, Guangzhi Hu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403628965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cao Guo, Sanshuang Gao, Jing Wang, Menglin Zhou, Abdukader Abdukayum, Qingquan Kong, Yingtang Zhou, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H2/CO2 metabolism in the human gut : In vitro study of the relationships between methanogens ans reductive acetogens</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4403617096</link>
      <description>C Del&#8217;homme, Christophe Chassard, A Bernaliert-Donadille, HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe). None(None)] 2004. https://openalex.org/W4403617096

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C Del&#8217;homme, Christophe Chassard, A Bernaliert-Donadille</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4403617096</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ Imaging and Time-resolved Investigation of Local pH in Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124727</link>
      <description>Zezhong Xie, Qiushi Wang, Rongge Yang, Jingnan Zhang, S P Ou, Gangfeng Ouyang, Mingyang Li, Jianxin Shi, Yexiang Tong, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zezhong Xie, Qiushi Wang, Rongge Yang, Jingnan Zhang, S P Ou, Gangfeng Ouyang, Mingyang Li, Jianxin Shi, Yexiang Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic reduction of imines with silylformates: Formation of silyl carbamates through CO2 insertion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-hfwdz</link>
      <description>Neethu Thyagarajan, Ruqaya Buhaibeh, Emmanuel Nicolas, Thibault Cantat, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403541356

                Silylformates are emerging surrogates of hydrosilanes, able to reduce carbonyl groups in transfer hydrosilylation reactions, with the concomitant release of CO2. In this work, a new reactivity is revealed for silylformates, in the presence of imines. Using ruthenium catalysts, and lithium iodide as a co-catalyst, imines are shown to undergo hydrocarboxysilylation by formal insertion of CO2 to the N-Si bond of silyl amine to yield silyl carbamates in excellent yields.</description>
      <author>Neethu Thyagarajan, Ruqaya Buhaibeh, Emmanuel Nicolas, Thibault Cantat</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-hfwdz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing the Stability of Ultra-Thin Metal Oxide Catalyst Films in Non-thermal Plasma CO2 Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k0svz</link>
      <description>Samuel K. Conlin, Joseph Joel Muhanga, David N. Parette, Robert H. Coridan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403540654

                The use of metal oxide catalysts to enhance plasma CO2 reduction has seen significant recent development towards processes to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and produce renewable chemical feedstocks. While plasma reactors are effective at producing the intended chemical transformations, the conditions can result in catalyst degradation. Atomic layer deposition (ALD) can be used to synthesize complex, hierarchically structured metal oxide plasma catalysts that, while active for plasma CO2 reduction, are particularly vulnerable to degradation due to their high surface area and nanoscopic thickness. In this work, we characterized the effects of extended non-thermal, glow-discharge plasma exposure on ALD synthesized, ultra-thin film (&lt; 30 nm) TiO2 and ZnO catalysts. We used x-ray diffraction, reflectivity, and spectroscopy to compare films exposed to a CO2 plasma to ones exposed to an Ar plasma and to ones annealed in air. We found that the CO2 plasma exposure generated some surface reduction in TiO2 and increased surface roughening by a small amount, but did not initiate any phase changes or crystallite growth. The results suggest that ALD-deposited metal oxide films are robust to low pressure CO2 plasma exposure and are suitable as catalysts or catalyst supports in extended reactions.</description>
      <author>Samuel K. Conlin, Joseph Joel Muhanga, David N. Parette, Robert H. Coridan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k0svz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal synthesis of pure-phase IB-group Sn-based alloys with modulable electrocatalytic CO2 reduction products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05317f</link>
      <description>Luyao Yang, Wenqing Zhang, Xianshun Lv, Qianqian Zhao, Xiaojing Liu, Shulin Zhao, Yuhui Chen, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403652785

                We present a universal method for synthesizing a range of pure-phase IB-group Sn-based alloy catalysts (Cu3Sn, Ag4Sn, and AuSn) for electrochemical reduction of CO2 to C1 product. The selectivity can...</description>
      <author>Luyao Yang, Wenqing Zhang, Xianshun Lv, Qianqian Zhao, Xiaojing Liu, Shulin Zhao, Yuhui Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05317f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Structural Dynamics of Cu@Ag Core-Shell Nanoparticles during CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926022</link>
      <description>Daniel Arenas Esteban, Lien Pacquets, Daniel Choukroun, Saskia Hoekx, Ajinkya Kadu, Jonathan Schalck, Nick Daems, Tom Breugelmans, Sara Bals, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496461

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel Arenas Esteban, Lien Pacquets, Daniel Choukroun, Saskia Hoekx, Ajinkya Kadu, Jonathan Schalck, Nick Daems, Tom Breugelmans, Sara Bals</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis of WCu-C/N for Effective Catalyst toward Electrochemical Reduction of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3740/mrsk.2024.34.9.409</link>
      <description>Chaoyu Chen, Ze-Da Meng, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Yilei Sun, Liang Yuan, Won&#8208;Chun Oh, Korean Journal of Materials Research. 34(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403581781

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoyu Chen, Ze-Da Meng, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Yilei Sun, Liang Yuan, Won&#8208;Chun Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3740/mrsk.2024.34.9.409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-controlled formation of NixPy catalyst using environmental TEM for potential application in CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926038</link>
      <description>Kshipra Sharma, Tianyi Hu, Kimberly A. Dick, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496672

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kshipra Sharma, Tianyi Hu, Kimberly A. Dick</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ TEM/EELS and spatially resolved XAS/XRF analysis of CuO electrocatalyst for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412925028</link>
      <description>M. Schuster, Gea T. van de Kerkhof, Angela E. Goode, Ur&#353;a Podbev&#353;ek, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496016

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Schuster, Gea T. van de Kerkhof, Angela E. Goode, Ur&#353;a Podbev&#353;ek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412925028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A cluster-nanozyme-coenzyme system mimicking natural photosynthesis for CO2 reduction under intermittent light irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53377-0</link>
      <description>Xiaofeng Cui, Hui Bai, Jun Zhang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Haiyan Yu, Y.Q. Wang, Tingting Kong, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Zhou Lu, Yujie Xiong, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403560302

                Natural photosynthesis utilizes solar energy to convert water and atmospheric CO2 into carbohydrates through all-weather light/dark reactions based on molecule-based enzymes and coenzymes, inspiring extensive development of artificial photosynthesis. However, development of efficient artificial photosynthetic systems free of noble metals, as well as rational integration of functional units into a single system at the molecular level, remain challenging. Here we report an artificial system, the assembly system of Cu6 cluster and cobalt terpyridine complex, that mimics natural photosynthesis through precise integration of nanozyme complexes and ubiquinone (coenzyme Q) on Cu6 clusters. This biomimetic system efficiently reduces CO2 to CO in light reaction, achieving a production rate of 740.7 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1 with high durability for at least 188 hours. Notably, our system realizes the decoupling of light and dark reactions, utilizing the phenol-evolutive coenzyme Q acting as an electron reservoir. By regulating the stabilizer of coenzyme Q, the dark reaction time can be extended up to 8.5 hours, which fully meets the natural day/night cycle requirements. Our findings advance the molecular design of artificial systems that replicate the comprehensive functions of natural photosynthesis. Natural photosynthesis converts H2O and CO2 into carbohydrates through all-weather reactions based on enzymes and coenzymes. Here, the authors report an artificial photosynthesis system under intermittent light irradiation by integrating nanozyme complexes and ubiquinone on a copper nanocluster.</description>
      <author>Xiaofeng Cui, Hui Bai, Jun Zhang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Haiyan Yu, Y.Q. Wang, Tingting Kong, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Zhou Lu, Yujie Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53377-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Low-Carbon Fuels and Carbon Capture in Decarbonizing the U.S. Clinker Manufacturing for Cement Production: CO2 Emissions Reduction Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17205233</link>
      <description>Ikenna J. Okeke, Dipti Kamath, Sachin Nimbalkar, Joseph Cresko, Energies. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403602833

                Low-carbon fuels, feedstocks, and energy sources can play a vital role in the decarbonization of clinker production in cement manufacturing. Fuel switching with renewable natural gas, green hydrogen, and biomass can provide a low-carbon energy source for the high-temperature process heat during the pyroprocessing steps of clinker production. However, up to 60% of CO2 emissions from clinker production are attributable to process-related CO2 emissions, which will need the simultaneous implementation of other decarbonization technologies, such as carbon capture. To evaluate the potential of fuel switching and carbon capture technologies in decarbonizing the cement industry, a study of the facility-level CO2 emissions is necessary. This study evaluates the potential for using a single low-carbon fuel as an energy source in clinker production for cement manufacturing compared to conventional clinker production (which uses a range of fuel mixes). In addition, conventional carbon capture (operated with natural gas-based steam for solvent regeneration) and electrified carbon capture configurations were designed and assessed for net-zero emission targets. Carbon emissions reductions with and without biogenic emissions credits were analyzed to ascertain their impact on the overall carbon accounting. Results show that carbon emissions intensity of cement can vary from 571 to 784 kgCO2eq/metric ton of cement without carbon capture and from 166.33 to 438.66 kgCO2eq/metric ton of cement with carbon capture. We find that when biogenic carbon credits are considered, cement production with a sustainably grown biomass as fuel source coupled with conventional carbon capture can lead to a net-negative emission cement (&#8722;271 kgCO2eq/metric ton of cement), outperforming an electrified capture design (35 kgCO2eq/metric ton of cement). The carbon accounting for the Scope 1, 2, and biogenic emissions conducted in this study is aimed at helping researchers and industry partners in the cement and concrete sector make an informed decision on the choice of fuel and decarbonization strategy to adopt.</description>
      <author>Ikenna J. Okeke, Dipti Kamath, Sachin Nimbalkar, Joseph Cresko</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17205233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancies Induce the Enhancement of Co2 Photothermal Reduction with Water Vapor Via Zro2@Zns Composite Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4997528</link>
      <description>Z. Hu, Jinlong Wen, Yiqi Wang, Jing Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403667922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Z. Hu, Jinlong Wen, Yiqi Wang, Jing Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4997528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring electrochemical CO2 reduction selectivity over CuSn by modulating surface oxidation state with infrared laser treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156752</link>
      <description>Yunji Gwon, Seon Young Hwang, So Young Kim, Gaeun Yun, Sooyeon Bae, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn, Chemical Engineering Journal. 499(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403510825

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunji Gwon, Seon Young Hwang, So Young Kim, Gaeun Yun, Sooyeon Bae, Choong Kyun Rhee, Youngku Sohn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encapsulation of an Au25 Nanocluster inside a Porphyrin Nanoring Enhances Singlet Oxygen Generation and Photo&#8208;Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414908</link>
      <description>Abolfazl Ziarati, Henrik Gotfredsen, Arnulf Rosspeintner, Jiangtao Zhao, Harry L. Anderson, Thomas B&#252;rgi, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403604970

                The synthesis of molecular host&#8208;guest complexes with enhanced performance, relative to those of their components, is a central theme in supramolecular chemistry. Here we explore a host&#8208;guest system consisting of an atomically precise gold nanocluster bound inside a zinc porphyrin nanoring. UV&#8208;vis absorption and fluorescence titrations with different sized nanorings revealed strong binding between a pyridinethiol&#8208;coated Au25 nanocluster and a nanoring consisting of six zinc porphyrin units, and complexation is confirmed by mass spectrometry. Formation of this assembly enhances the stability of the gold nanocluster. The host&#8208;guest complex also exhibits remarkable activity and selectivity for photochemical CO2 to CO conversion and singlet oxygen generation.</description>
      <author>Abolfazl Ziarati, Henrik Gotfredsen, Arnulf Rosspeintner, Jiangtao Zhao, Harry L. Anderson, Thomas B&#252;rgi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encapsulation of an Au25 Nanocluster inside a Porphyrin Nanoring Enhances Singlet Oxygen Generation and Photo&#8208;Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414908</link>
      <description>Abolfazl Ziarati, Henrik Gotfredsen, Arnulf Rosspeintner, Jiangtao Zhao, Harry L. Anderson, Thomas B&#252;rgi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403612296

                The synthesis of molecular host&#8208;guest complexes with enhanced performance, relative to those of their components, is a central theme in supramolecular chemistry. Here we explore a host&#8208;guest system consisting of an atomically precise gold nanocluster bound inside a zinc porphyrin nanoring. UV&#8208;vis absorption and fluorescence titrations with different sized nanorings revealed strong binding between a pyridinethiol&#8208;coated Au25 nanocluster and a nanoring consisting of six zinc porphyrin units, and complexation is confirmed by mass spectrometry. Formation of this assembly enhances the stability of the gold nanocluster. The host&#8208;guest complex also exhibits remarkable activity and selectivity for photochemical CO2 to CO conversion and singlet oxygen generation.</description>
      <author>Abolfazl Ziarati, Henrik Gotfredsen, Arnulf Rosspeintner, Jiangtao Zhao, Harry L. Anderson, Thomas B&#252;rgi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO2 Reduction via S-Scheme Heterojunction of Amorphous/Crystalline Metal-free Carbon Nitride Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156777</link>
      <description>Liting Wu, Dingyi Yang, Yalin Dong, Ze Wang, Yu Zhang, Tingting Wang, Liang Cheng, Yong Wang, Yizhang Wu, Chemical Engineering Journal. 500(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403503972

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liting Wu, Dingyi Yang, Yalin Dong, Ze Wang, Yu Zhang, Tingting Wang, Liang Cheng, Yong Wang, Yizhang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando TEM Studies of Re@Cu2O-SnO2 catalysts during CO2 reduction reaction with optimized liquid flow configuration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926012</link>
      <description>Cecilia Irene Gho, Katarzyna Bejtka, Marco Fontana, Maria J. Lopez Tendero, Alberto Lopera L&#243;pez, Roger Mir&#243;, Miriam D&#237;az de los Bernardos, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Stefan Merkens, Andrey Chuvilin, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Angelica Chiodoni, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403497223

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cecilia Irene Gho, Katarzyna Bejtka, Marco Fontana, Maria J. Lopez Tendero, Alberto Lopera L&#243;pez, Roger Mir&#243;, Miriam D&#237;az de los Bernardos, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Stefan Merkens, Andrey Chuvilin, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Angelica Chiodoni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412926012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Molecular Dispersion of Crown Ether&#8208;Decorated Cobalt Phthalocyanineon Carbon Nanotubes for Robust CO2 Reduction through Host&#8208;Guest Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418156</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403494193

                Immobilizing molecular catalysts on electro&#8208;conductive supports (for example, multi&#8208;walled carbon nanotubes, CNTs) represent a promising way to well&#8208;defined catalyst/support interfaces, which has shown appreciable performance for catalytic transformation. However, their full potential is far from achieved due to insufficient utilization of the intrinsic activity for each immobilized molecular catalyst, especially at loadings that should allow decent current densities. In the present work, we discover host&#8208;guest interaction between tetra&#8208;crown ether substituted cobalt phthalocyanine and metal ions, for example K+ ions, not only eliminate catalyst aggregation at immobilization procedures but also reinforce catalyst/support interactions by additional electrostatic attractions under operational conditions. Through simple dip&#8208;coating procedures, a successful single&#8208;molecular dispersion is achieved. Such a catalyst/electrode interface is stable and can selectively catalyze CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion (&#65310;96%) with almost unchanged turnover frequency (TOF) at all loading conditions, which implies a full utilization of the intrinsic activity of supported molecular catalysts. Therefore, a simultaneous achievement of high TOF and high current density (TOF of 111 s&#8208;1 at 38 mA/cm2) is achieved, in an aqueous H&#8208;type electrolyzer at an overpotential of 570 mV.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Molecular Dispersion of Crown Ether&#8208;Decorated Cobalt Phthalocyanineon Carbon Nanotubes for Robust CO2 Reduction through Host&#8208;Guest Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418156</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403494457

                Immobilizing molecular catalysts on electro&#8208;conductive supports (for example, multi&#8208;walled carbon nanotubes, CNTs) represent a promising way to well&#8208;defined catalyst/support interfaces, which has shown appreciable performance for catalytic transformation. However, their full potential is far from achieved due to insufficient utilization of the intrinsic activity for each immobilized molecular catalyst, especially at loadings that should allow decent current densities. In the present work, we discover host&#8208;guest interaction between tetra&#8208;crown ether substituted cobalt phthalocyanine and metal ions, for example K+ ions, not only eliminate catalyst aggregation at immobilization procedures but also reinforce catalyst/support interactions by additional electrostatic attractions under operational conditions. Through simple dip&#8208;coating procedures, a successful single&#8208;molecular dispersion is achieved. Such a catalyst/electrode interface is stable and can selectively catalyze CO2&#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion (&#65310;96%) with almost unchanged turnover frequency (TOF) at all loading conditions, which implies a full utilization of the intrinsic activity of supported molecular catalysts. Therefore, a simultaneous achievement of high TOF and high current density (TOF of 111 s&#8208;1 at 38 mA/cm2) is achieved, in an aqueous H&#8208;type electrolyzer at an overpotential of 570 mV.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Yixuan Wang, Lijuan Chen, Jian Li, Shuai Zhou, Qingqing Yang, Xu&#8208;Zhe Wang, Chen-Ho Tung, Li&#8208;Zhu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the synergistic potential of 2D&#8208;2D nanosheet based S&#8208;scheme heterojunction: Cooperative boosting of CO2 reduction to solar fuel and biomass valorization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401657</link>
      <description>Shivali Dhingra, Ayushi Jain, Arpna Jaryal, Chandan Bera, Kamalakannan Kailasam, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403612276

                Harnessing inexhaustible solar energy for CO2 valorization is substantial step toward achieving carbon&#8208;neutral energy cycle. However, CO2 conversion often exhibits slow kinetics, necessitating the utilization of sacrificial agents making the process economically unfeasible. In the ongoing quest for sustainable and economically feasible CO2 valorization, herein the photoreduction of CO2 to CO coupled with biomass&#8208;based alcohol oxidation to fine chemicals is reported via Bi2WO6/g&#8208;C3N4 (BWO/g&#8208;CN) 2D&#8208;2D nanosheet based S&#8208;scheme heterojunction. Importantly, BWO/g&#8208;CN&#8208;60 exhibits highest photocatalytic activity with CO production rate of 6.87 mmol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1, accompanied by &gt;98% selectivity and selective oxidation of veratryl alcohol to veratraldehyde, with notable yield of 42% in 6 h under simulated solar light. The apparent quantum yield (AQY) of 14.3% is achieved for CO production at the wavelength of 420 nm. Additionally, the formed heterostructure results in enhanced charge separation and accelerated charge transfer kinetics as validated by PL, EIS, and photocurrent studies. EPR, 13CO2 labeling, DFT studies, and various controlled experiments provided deeper insight into the mechanism of underlying photo&#8208;redox process. Thus, the current study presents a sustainable paradigm for CO2 mitigation by converting it into solar fuel, while synergistically producing the fine chemicals through effectively harnessing the full potential of charge carriers.</description>
      <author>Shivali Dhingra, Ayushi Jain, Arpna Jaryal, Chandan Bera, Kamalakannan Kailasam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of climate change technology spillovers on carbon emissions across European countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122972</link>
      <description>Jaana Rahko, Andrew Adewale Alola, Journal of Environmental Management. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403561586

                To unravel the challenges in the global diffusion of climate-friendly technologies, this investigation analyzes the diffusion of climate change-related technologies across countries. By using an unbalanced panel of selected European countries over the period 1990-2020, this investigation quantifies the carbon dioxide (CO2) emission effects of the diffusion of climate change-related technologies that are mediated by imports, geographical and technological proximity and free diffusion of technologies. In this study, the effects of domestic development of climate change-related technologies, population and affluence are also accounted for, and the emission effects are estimated using a fixed-effects panel model with instrumental variables. The instrumental variable for foreign technology spillovers is based on the technology support policies adopted in foreign countries. As expected, international spillovers of climate-friendly technologies are negatively linked to CO2 emissions, thus promoting emission reductions across the region. Importantly, emission reductions in Europe are more strongly influenced by international technology spillovers than by domestic innovation activities. Moreover, while all the analyzed technology diffusion channels appear relevant, the results are the most robust regarding import-mediated technology spillovers. Insights from this study support policy recommendations, especially in the trade policy context.</description>
      <author>Jaana Rahko, Andrew Adewale Alola</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling of Carbon Footprint Emissions in Sugarcane Production Using System Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24857/rgsa.v18n10-279</link>
      <description>Juan Gabriel Mollocana Lara, Jeyson Alexander O&#241;a Toaquiza, Pamela Abigail Brice&#241;o Chugchil&#225;n, Nathaly Johanna Chamorro Vinueza, Revista de Gest&#227;o Social e Ambiental. 18(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403630407

                Objective: This study proposes a model aimed at estimating and reducing carbon emissions in sugarcane cultivation and juice extraction, designed for potential application in real-world systems. Method: The model grounded in a hypothetical case study of a 60-hectare sugarcane plantation in a warm climate with a 7-month growth cycle and a three-year simulation period, focuses on estimate and evaluate mitigation scenarios to decrease emissions from fuel and electricity usage in activities such as plowing, sowing, harvesting, and irrigation. Utilizing Vensim PLE, a System Dynamics model that combine event and dynamic simulation. Results and Discussion: Utilizing Vensim PLE, a System Dynamics model that combine event and dynamic simulation estimated a 3060.81 tons CO2 equivalent carbon footprint. Two scenarios aimed at footprint reduction were tested: substituting electrical energy with solar power reduced the footprint by 86% to 450.092 tons, demonstrating clean energy's efficacy. Conversely, replacing an industrial mill with the traditional trapiche technique for juice extraction yielded a mere 1% reduction, indicating its ineffectiveness for real-world application. Research Implications: This study emphasizes the development of a simulation model based on system dynamics to estimate the carbon footprint emissions in sugar cane production considering its cultivation and juice extraction. The results support that through simulations, it is possible to determine the factors that influence the generation of carbon dioxide, offering a broader vision to establish and implement mitigation measures such as adopting clean energies and reducing fuel consumption. Originality/Value: This research contributes to the understanding of the application of system dynamics by using software such as Vensim PLE to estimate the carbon footprint emissions in sugar cane production, considering its cultivation and juice extraction. The results found through simulations suggest the implementation of mitigation measures such as the adoption of clean energies and the reduction of fuel consumption.</description>
      <author>Juan Gabriel Mollocana Lara, Jeyson Alexander O&#241;a Toaquiza, Pamela Abigail Brice&#241;o Chugchil&#225;n, Nathaly Johanna Chamorro Vinueza</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24857/rgsa.v18n10-279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re-Imagining Trade Policy and Energy Efficiency: Groundbreaking Pathways to Strengthen Environmental Sustainability in South Korea</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14209443</link>
      <description>Dongxue Wang, Yugang He, Applied Sciences. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403491441

                This study explores the long-term interplay between trade policy, energy efficiency, and carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions in South Korea, using data spanning from 1985 to 2023. By applying the Fourier autoregressive distributed lag (FARDL) model, the analysis reveals that while trade liberalization initially leads to a 0.23% increase in CO2 emissions for each 1% rise in trade openness&#8212;driven by the energy demands of industrial expansion&#8212;integrating energy efficiency standards within trade agreements helps mitigate these effects over time; this results in a 0.26% reduction in emissions for every 1% improvement in energy efficiency. The study also highlights the dual role of foreign direct investment (FDI), which contributes to a short-term 0.08% rise in emissions but significantly reduces carbon intensity in the long term by facilitating the adoption of cleaner technologies. These findings underscore the importance of innovation and FDI in decoupling economic growth from environmental degradation. The study advocates for the incorporation of energy efficiency measures into trade agreements and the prioritization of green technologies, recommending strategies that could enable South Korea to reduce its CO2 emissions by up to 40% by 2030. This research positions South Korea as a key actor in achieving global climate goals while maintaining economic competitiveness, offering valuable insights into the balance between sustainable development and industrial growth.</description>
      <author>Dongxue Wang, Yugang He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14209443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaching machine learning leverage to advance performance of electrocatalytic CO2 conversion in non-aqueous deep eutectic electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74893-5</link>
      <description>Ahmed Halilu, Mohamed Kamel Hadj-Kali, Hanee F. Hizaddin, Mohd Ali Hashim, Emad Ali, Suresh K. Bhargava, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403601943

                Deep eutectic electrolytes (DEEs) show promise for future electrochemical systems due to their adjustable buffer capacities. This study utilizes machine learning algorithms to analyse the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) in DEEs with a buffer capacity of approximately 10.21 mol/pH. The objective is to minimize undesired hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) and render CO2RR dominant in a membrane cell. The CO2RR process was found to be non-adiabatic, as the time of nuclear motion for CO32&#8722; in K2CO3 product, through CO2&#9679;&#8722; trapping, is 0.368 femtoseconds shorter than the 1.856 &#215; 10&#8722;3s charge transfer relaxation time. Microkinetic analysis reveals that the rate of CO2RR to CO2&#9679;&#8722; is 2.14 &#215; 103 mol/cm2/s2 with a rate constant of 2.1 &#215; 1010 cm/s. Our findings demonstrate that ensemble and k-Nearest Neighbours algorithms learn the CO2RR dataset, achieving a prediction accuracy of over 99%. The models were verified visually and quantitatively by overlaying predicted and experimental dataset. Diagnostic and SHAP analyses highlighted the gradient boost ensemble algorithm, predicting asymptotic current densities of -4.114 mA/cm2 or -13.340 mA/cm2, with high turnover frequencies (TOF) of 3.79 &#215; 1010 h-1 or 12.30 &#215; 1010 h-1 for CO2&#9679;&#8722; or K2CO3 generation on silver electrodes, respectively. These results consider both accuracy and robustness against overfitting, providing an opportunity to optimize future non-aqueous electrolytes for convenient TOF measurements at industrially relevant current densities.</description>
      <author>Ahmed Halilu, Mohamed Kamel Hadj-Kali, Hanee F. Hizaddin, Mohd Ali Hashim, Emad Ali, Suresh K. Bhargava</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74893-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon footprints: Uncovering spatiotemporal dynamics of global container ship emissions during 2015&#8211;2021</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marpolbul.2024.117165</link>
      <description>Hongchu Yu, Qinglong Fang, Zhixiang Fang, Lei Xu, Jingxian Liu, Marine Pollution Bulletin. 209(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403523302

                The proposed "peak carbon" and "carbon neutral" targets have catapulted the reduction of carbon dioxide (CO</description>
      <author>Hongchu Yu, Qinglong Fang, Zhixiang Fang, Lei Xu, Jingxian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marpolbul.2024.117165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag nanoparticles induced abundant Cu&#948;+ sites in Cu2Se nanoflower rods to promote efficient carbon dioxide electroreduction to ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.055</link>
      <description>Zheng Tang, Chenxi Li, Chenyu Yan, Qian Zhang, Zhe Piao, Honggui Wang, Ya Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403524417

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (eCO</description>
      <author>Zheng Tang, Chenxi Li, Chenyu Yan, Qian Zhang, Zhe Piao, Honggui Wang, Ya Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide injection into the Achimov formations using reinjection technology by the example of Ach3-4 formation in the Novo-Urengoy area of the Urengoy field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31660/0445-0108-2024-5-80-103</link>
      <description>A. S. Rusanov, A.V. Strekalov, A. S. Romanov, E. A. Reitblat, M. Moskalets, Ashley C. Karp, &#1044;. &#1053;. &#1043;&#1083;&#1091;&#1084;&#1086;&#1074;, Oil and Gas Studies. None(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403575323

                The prerequisites for the study are the calculation results for the cycling process, where carbon dioxide is proposed as the injection agent into the Achimov formations instead of dry gas, with the goal of increasing the condensate recovery factor. The work is focused on the efficiency assessment of carbon dioxide reinjection technology and reducing carbon footprint at a late stage of field development. The research object is the &#1040;ch 3-4 formation within the Novo-Urengoy license area of the Urengoy field. The leading method to identify this problem is the results of the full-scale composite dynamic model in the ECLIPSE 300 format. The model takes into account the history of field development on depletion. The articles deals with two schemes for injecting carbon dioxide into the formation. In the first scheme, pure carbon dioxide is injected in a closed-loop system, but carbon neutrality through storage is not achieved. In the second scheme, carbon dioxide is injected using reinjection technology. Once injection begins, gas production stops. Only the condensate separated from the formation gas during low-temperature separation is sold and sent for further processing. After allocation of the condensate, the mixture of natural gas and carbon dioxide, in a specific proportion, is sent to the compressor station for reinjection into the formation in a gaseous state. Injecting pure carbon dioxide achieves a condensate recovery factor similar to that of gas injection with a 30 % carbon dioxide mixture. However, this option is less economically viable compared to the base and other scenarios due to high capital costs for upgrading the existing gas processing equipment (requiring the construction of an amine treatment unit). With carbon dioxide injection using reinjection technology, in addition to recovering extra condensate that had condensed during natural depletion, a reduction in the carbon footprint is also achieved. To maximize the condensate recovery factor, the optimal concentration of carbon dioxide in the injection mixture has been determined. The optimal timing for the start of injection was identified to maximize gas recovery. Economic efficiency is expected from the additional recovery of condensate trapped in the reservoir and from achieving carbon neutrality through the monetization and storage of carbon dioxide.</description>
      <author>A. S. Rusanov, A.V. Strekalov, A. S. Romanov, E. A. Reitblat, M. Moskalets, Ashley C. Karp, &#1044;. &#1053;. &#1043;&#1083;&#1091;&#1084;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31660/0445-0108-2024-5-80-103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Collaborative Pollutant and Carbon Emissions Reduction through Digital Governance: Evidence from Chinese Enterprises</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120197</link>
      <description>Shaohui Zou, Xiangbo Fan, Yinuo Zhou, Yuanzheng Cui, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403566236

                Under China's dual carbon goals, it is imperative for enterprises to effectively reduce carbon emissions while achieving pollutant reduction. This article explores the potential role of government-implemented digital governance in facilitating these objectives. Utilizing a quasi-natural experiment on digital governance, we established an analytical framework to thoroughly examine how digital governance can help Chinese enterprises realize synergistic effects in pollution control and carbon reduction. Our study reveals that digital governance significantly reduces enterprises' emissions of carbon dioxide and pollutants, with emission intensities of the carbon dioxide, air pollutant and water pollutant being decreased by approximately 6.9%, 7.3%, and 7.0%, respectively. These reductions are primarily driven by improvements in energy efficiency, the promotion of green innovation, digital transformation, and enhanced role of media. However, it is important to note that digital governance also negatively impacts overall corporate productivity and widens the digital divide between large and small-to-medium enterprises. The research results have practical significance for promoting the achievement of emission reduction goals and sustainable development for enterprises.</description>
      <author>Shaohui Zou, Xiangbo Fan, Yinuo Zhou, Yuanzheng Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EFFECT EVALUATION OF TYPICAL MEASURES FOR ENERGY CONSERVATION AND EMISSION REDUCTION IN POWER TRANSMISSION AND TRANSFORMATION PROJECTS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36871/ek.up.p.r.2024.09.05.007</link>
      <description>Chen Xuzhi, EKONOMIKA I UPRAVLENIE PROBLEMY RESHENIYA. 9/5(150)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403603793

                As global climate change intensifies, countries face serious challenges. In response to this issue, various industries are actively promoting green development and energy conservation measures, with the electricity sector being particularly important. As a major emitter of carbon dioxide, China&#8217;s construction of transmission infrastructure has a significant impact on global climate change. In this context, research on energy conservation and emission reduction measures is urgently needed. Taking the 500 kV transmission project in Jiande, Zhejiang Province as an example, this study analyzes its carbon emissions in detail and quantifies the effects of 18 energy conservation and emission reduction measures. The results show that adopting energy conservation and emission reduction technologies can significantly reduce carbon emissions, especially in terms of raw materials and equipment. However, there are still issues such as data gaps and unclear quantification methods that need further research and improvement. Therefore, it is recommended to continue researching energy conservation and emission reduction technologies, establish relevant standards, and promote the development of more environmentally friendly raw materials and equipment by power enterprises to facilitate the green and low-carbon development of transmission engineering.</description>
      <author>Chen Xuzhi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36871/ek.up.p.r.2024.09.05.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Single Atom Cu/TiO2 Photocatalyst for Advanced Redox Processes: Reactive Oxygen Species Generation Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-24brt</link>
      <description>Naizhen Yu, Xu Zhang, Mita Dasog, Collins Nganou, Andrew Carrier, Dongchang Yang, Ken D. Oakes, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403610550

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) of copper dispersed in anatase TiO2 (Cu/TiO2) have attracted significant attention in various sustainable chemical processes, including water splitting, carbon monoxide oxidation, carbon dioxide reduction, chemical synthesis, and advanced oxidation processes for water treatment. Reactive oxygen species (ROS) are involved in these processes, but a mechanistic understanding of ROS generation on Cu/TiO2 SAC surfaces has not been established. Combining experimental investigation and computational simulation, this work provides unequivocal evidence for superoxide radical anion (O2&#8226;&#8211;) formation via reduction of the adsorbed oxygen by Cu+ and hydroxyl radical (&#8226;OH) production by oxidation of lattice oxygen within the bridging Cu-O-Ti structure on the SAC surface. The superior performance of the SAC has been demonstrated through its organic dye degradation, bactericidal activity, and biofilm disruption, indicating its wide applicability in water treatment and disinfection. The results and the methodologies will benefit the wide field of heterogeneous redox chemistry.</description>
      <author>Naizhen Yu, Xu Zhang, Mita Dasog, Collins Nganou, Andrew Carrier, Dongchang Yang, Ken D. Oakes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-24brt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pioneering Sustainable Well Cementing in Brunei: Reduced Portland Cement Blends With Locally Sourced Fly Ash</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/223280-ms</link>
      <description>Chitra Charan Suri, Chun Kiat Yeo, Kory Hugentobler, Dinesh Simmadorai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403586899

                Abstract The oil and gas industry in Brunei is increasingly focused on sustainable practices, particularly in well cementing, which is a crucial operation with environmental considerations. To contribute to this effort, the service company has introduced a novel reduced Portland cement (RPC) blend system. This system incorporates locally sourced fly ash, which provides a high-performance and environmentally responsible solution that aligns with the commitment to sustainable development. The RPC system prioritizes environmental stewardship with a decrease in carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions associated with clinker production through a 25% reduction in Class G Portland cement content. Additionally, the system uses readily available fly ash, a recycled material, to minimize reliance on imported ordinary Portland cement (OPC) and strengthen supply chain efficiency. This focus on localization not only reduces transportation emissions but also fosters a more adaptable and resilient supply network in Brunei. Rigorous laboratory tests have qualified the RPC blend system and have demonstrated that RPC blends maintain or even exceed the compressive strength of conventional, higher-density OPC systems. This helps ensure effective wellbore isolation, despite the lower density of the RPC blend, a crucial factor for long-term well integrity. Additionally, RPC blends exhibit lower equivalent circulating densities, which makes pressure management during wellbore construction simpler and enhances operational efficiency. The RPC system provides several advantages beyond its environmental benefits. The enhanced ductility and toughness of these blends, compared to traditional cement, allow the cement sheath to better withstand downhole stresses and strain throughout the well's life. This promotes long-term zonal isolation and helps mitigate the potential risk of leakage. Furthermore, the lower permeability of RPC blends provides superior resistance to corrosive fluid and gas that migrate through the wellbore to help ensure the long-term integrity and production efficiency of the well. Since May 2023, the RPC blend system has been successfully implemented in Brunei. This innovative approach not only minimizes the environmental impact but also delivers strong wellbore integrity. The RPC blend system represents a significant advancement in sustainable well cement operations, which paves the way for a more environmentally acceptable future for the oil and gas industry in Brunei.</description>
      <author>Chitra Charan Suri, Chun Kiat Yeo, Kory Hugentobler, Dinesh Simmadorai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/223280-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Response of soil carbon dioxide emission, soil organic carbon andmicrobial community to biochar addition with nitrogen optimizing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5205540/v1</link>
      <description>Weijun Yang, Liyue Zhang, Qian Zhang, Pengying Li, Hongtao Jia, Lili Su, Sheng Wang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403606028

                Abstract A three-year field study was conducted to investigate the CO2 emissions from irrigation wheat fields in response to biochar addition and nitrogen optimizing. Eight treatments were established: (1) control (without any fertilizers or biochar addition, CK), (2) nitrogen fertilizer application alone (300kg/hm2, N1), (3) biochar application alone (20t/hm2, B), (4) nitrogen fertilizer applied with biochar (N1B), (5) nitrogen fertilizer applied with 15% reduction (255kg/hm2, N2), (6) 15% reduction of nitrogen fertilizer + biochar (N2B), (7) nitrogen fertilizer applied with 30% reduction (210kg/hm2, N3), and (8) 30% reduction of nitrogen fertilizer + biochar (N3B), each treatment has three replicates. The objective of this study was to assess the impact of biochar addition and nitrogen optimized levels on soil carbon dioxide emission, soil organic carbon and microbial community. The findings indicated that the application of biochar and/or nitrogen fertilizer, particularly in combination, was observed to increase soil organic carbon and soil active organic carbon. Biochar application decreased CO2 emissions in wheat fields, compared with the non-amendment treatment. Biochar addition combined with optimized nitrogen also make a different CO2 emission rate. This improvement was attributed to the capacity of biochar to regulate soil microbial community composition, like soil functional diversity, soil microorganisms (fungi and bacterial), soil properties (pH, soil bulk density). In conclusion, biochar addition with nitrogen optimizing (B1N2) regime was determined to be the optimal approach for wheat field in irrigated region northern Xinjiang, resulting in enhanced soil organic carbon and the mitigation of carbon emissions. Nevertheless, further investigation of its long-term impact on farmland is recommended.</description>
      <author>Weijun Yang, Liyue Zhang, Qian Zhang, Pengying Li, Hongtao Jia, Lili Su, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5205540/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In&#8208;situ Reconstruction of Catalyst in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411688</link>
      <description>Jinxian Feng, X.&#8208;S. Wang, Hui Pan, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403645863

                Abstract Reconstruction of catalysts is now well recognized as a common phenomenon in electrocatalysis. As the reconstructed structure may promote or hamper the electrochemical performance, how to achieve the designed active surface for highly enhanced catalytic activity through the reconstruction needs to be carefully investigated. In this review, the genesis and electrochemical effects of reconstruction in various electrochemical catalytic processes, such as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), and nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) are first described. Then, the strategies for optimizing the reconstruction, such as valence states control, active phase retention, phase evolution engineering, and surface poisoning prevention are comprehensively discussed. Finally, the general rules of reconstruction optimization are summarized and give perspectives for future study. It is believed that the review shall provide deep insights into electrocatalytic mechanisms and guide the design of pre&#8208;catalysts with highly improved activity.</description>
      <author>Jinxian Feng, X.&#8208;S. Wang, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate mitigation potential of natural climate solutions and clean energy on The Nature Conservancy properties in California, USA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0311195</link>
      <description>Kristen N. Wilson, Daniel W. Salzer, Michelle C. Passero, PLoS ONE. 19(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403587984

                Natural climate solutions (NCS) and transitioning to clean energy can reduce greenhouse gases and contribute to mitigating climate change. Private landowners with large holdings, such as conservation organizations like The Nature Conservancy, have set ambitious goals to reduce net emissions and increase sequestration on their lands by implementing NCS. We assessed the potential carbon dioxide-equivalent (CO2e) reduction from feasible NCS, specifically implementing new restoration and agricultural management activities, and transitions to clean energy on The Nature Conservancy, California chapter&#8217;s fee-owned and conservation easement properties. We compared the total CO2e reduction from potential new NCS activities to the impact from ongoing NCS activities, the chapter&#8217;s 2030 goal, and the state&#8217;s reduction goal for natural and working lands to understand how the organization can contribute to climate mitigation. We found that implementing NCS on 37 fee-owned properties (63,175 MTCO2e year &#8211;1) and clean energy on 10 fee-owned properties (488 MTCO2e year &#8211;1) combined would not reach the chapter&#8217;s 2030 goal (72,000 MTCO 2 e year &#8211;1), and there can be tradeoffs between maximizing CO2e reduction and protecting conservation values. However, ongoing changes to forest management on a single conservation easement property, where another non-profit harvests timber and sells carbon credits, currently contributes 147,749 MTCO2e year &#8211;1, more than two times the 2030 goal and representing 7.4% of the state&#8217;s annual goal. Our results suggest that The Nature Conservancy, California chapter would need to implement NCS on some of the conservation easements or consider future land protection deals with carbon rich ecosystems or high impact NCS to reach their CO2e reduction goal.</description>
      <author>Kristen N. Wilson, Daniel W. Salzer, Michelle C. Passero</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0311195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whole-life greenhouse gas emission reduction and removal strategies for buildings: Impacts and diffusion potentials across EU Member States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122915</link>
      <description>Nicolas Alaux, Csaba Marton, Jacob Steinmann, Dominik Maierhofer, Alessio Mastrucci, D. Petrou, Tajda Potr&#269; Obrecht, Delphine Ramon, Xavier Le Den, Karen Allacker, Alexander Passer, Martin R&#246;ck, Journal of Environmental Management. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403527689

                As the European Union (EU) is aiming to realize climate neutrality by 2050, there is a need to investigate greenhouse gas (GHG) reduction and carbon dioxide removal strategies (CRRS) from a life cycle perspective. Existing literature lacks harmonization of building-related strategies considering the whole-life cycle of buildings and the interlinkages across life cycle stages. The aim and novelty of this study was to systematically identify, classify and quantify the impacts of CRRS, as well as assess their applicability in different EU Member States. We identified a total of 35 measures grouped in 11 CRRS for the whole-life cycle of buildings. We classified these measures according to various criteria, such as the avoid-shift-improve framework or the life cycle stages influenced. We then assessed the potential diffusion of these strategies in each EU Member State up to 2050 via qualitative assessment criteria. We could achieve notable short-term reductions in GHG emissions by improving use-phase energy use, selecting low-carbon materials or reducing the per capital space demand. In the medium to long term, the applicability and reduction potential of strategies such as circularity and prioritizing renovation over new construction will increase as supply chains and skills develop across the EU. Due to their different potentials and times of implementation, the entire range of strategies is needed to support building and construction transition efforts.</description>
      <author>Nicolas Alaux, Csaba Marton, Jacob Steinmann, Dominik Maierhofer, Alessio Mastrucci, D. Petrou, Tajda Potr&#269; Obrecht, Delphine Ramon, Xavier Le Den, Karen Allacker, Alexander Passer, Martin R&#246;ck</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of Foam with Novel CO2-Soluble Surfactants for Improved Mobility Control in Tight Oil Reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.1588.v1</link>
      <description>Fajun Zhao, M. SUN, Yong Liu, Wenjing Sun, Qinyuan Guo, Zian Yang, Changjiang Zhang, Meng Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403594808

                CO2-soluble surfactant foam systems have garnered significant attention in the fields of enhanced oil and gas recovery, environmental protection, and greenhouse gas emission reduction. This review provides a comprehensive explanation of the basic theory of CO2-soluble surfactant foam, the mechanism of enhanced oil recovery, and the classification and application of various CO2-soluble surfactants.The mechanism of enhanced oil recovery by CO2-soluble surfactant foam involves the effective reduction of CO2 fluidity, the decrease in oil-air flow ratio, and the stabilization of the displacement front. Foam plays a vital role in mitigating the issues of channeling and gravity separation often caused by simple CO2 injection. The reduction in gas fluidity can be attributed to the increase in apparent viscosity and trapped gas fraction.Future research should prioritize the development of more efficient and environmentally-friendly CO2-soluble surfactants. It is essential to further explore the advantages and challenges associated with their practical applications in order to maximize their potential impact.</description>
      <author>Fajun Zhao, M. SUN, Yong Liu, Wenjing Sun, Qinyuan Guo, Zian Yang, Changjiang Zhang, Meng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.1588.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of Mn-based low-temperature SCR denitrification catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05140h</link>
      <description>Jiadong Zhang, Zengyi Ma, Ang Cao, Jianhua Yan, Li Wang, Miao Yu, Linlin Hu, Shaojing Pan, RSC Advances. 14(44)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403492703

                Selective catalytic reduction (SCR) is a efficiently nitrogen oxides removal technology from stationary source flue gases. Catalysts are key component in the technology, but currently face problems including poor low-temperature activity, narrow temperature windows, low selectivity, and susceptibility to water passivation and sulphur dioxide poisoning. To develop high-efficiency low-temperature denitrification activity catalyst, manganese-based catalysts have become a focal point of research globally for low-temperature SCR denitrification catalysts. This article investigates the denitrification efficiency of unsupported manganese-based catalysts, exploring the influence of oxidation valence, preparation method, crystallinity, crystal form, and morphology structure. It examines the catalytic performance of binary and multicomponent unsupported manganese-based catalysts, focusing on the use of transition metals and rare earth metals to modify manganese oxide. Furthermore, the synergistic effect of supported manganese-based catalysts is studied, considering metal oxides, molecular sieves, carbon materials, and other materials (composite carriers and inorganic non-metallic minerals) as supports. The reaction mechanism of low-temperature denitrification by manganese-based catalysts and the mechanism of sulphur dioxide/water poisoning are analysed in detail, and the development of practical and efficient manganese-based catalysts is considered.</description>
      <author>Jiadong Zhang, Zengyi Ma, Ang Cao, Jianhua Yan, Li Wang, Miao Yu, Linlin Hu, Shaojing Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05140h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the design of integrated methane sensing networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad893d</link>
      <description>Lekha Patel, Jake P Zenker, Environmental Research Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403596063

                Abstract While methane is the second largest contributor to global warming after carbon dioxide, it has a larger warming effect over a much shorter lifetime. Despite accelerated technological efforts to radically reduce global carbon dioxide emissions, rapid reductions in methane emissions are needed to limit near-term warming. Being primarily emitted as a byproduct from agricultural activities and energy extraction, methane is currently monitored via bottom-up (i.e., activity level) or top-down (via airborne or satellite retrievals) approaches. However, significant methane leaks remain undetected and emission rates are challenging to characterize with current monitoring frameworks. In this paper, we study the design of a layered monitoring approach that combines bottom-up and top-down approaches as an integrated sensing network. By recognizing that varying meteorological conditions and emission rates impact the efficacy of bottom-up monitoring, we develop a probabilistic approach to optimal sensor placement in its bottom-up network. Subsequently, we derive an inverse Bayesian framework to quantify the improvement that a design-optimized integrated framework has on emission-rate quantifications and their uncertainties. We find that under realistic meteorological conditions, the overall error in estimating the true emission rates is approximately 1.3 times higher, with their uncertainties being approximately 2.4 times higher, when using a randomized network over an optimized network, highlighting the importance of optimizing the design of integrated methane sensing networks. Further, we find that optimized networks can improve scenario coverage fractions by more than a factor of 2 over experimentally-studied networks, and identify a budget threshold beyond which the rate of optimized-network coverage improvement exhibits diminishing returns, suggesting that strategic sensor placement is also crucial for maximizing network efficiency.</description>
      <author>Lekha Patel, Jake P Zenker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad893d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharing is caring for the environment: But why would managers resist shared mobility?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bse.4006</link>
      <description>Alex Ntsiful, Business Strategy and the Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403507016

                Abstract The debate on carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) reduction strategies for a sustainable environment continues unabated. Thus, this study proposes and validates a model for understanding essential factors that can explain resistance to managers' bus&#8208;sharing system (MBS). MBS is a sustainability strategy where organizations have well&#8208;maintained buses to transport 10&#8211;15 managers to and from work. By drawing on an extended status quo bias theory, the study sampled and analyzed 234 responses from managers using the partial least square structural equation modeling. The results show that perceived switching benefits (PSWB) and perceived switching costs (PSWC) relate to perceived value and influence resistance to the proposed MBS. Meanwhile, managers' family/personal life conflicts and perceived prestige concerns increase the PSWC. These findings have essential theoretical implications for sustainability scholarship and inform organizations to adopt family&#8208;friendly policies to reduce resistance to MBS.</description>
      <author>Alex Ntsiful</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bse.4006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and swift heating technique for crafting highly graphitized carbon and crystalline silicon (Si@GC) composite anodes for lithium&#8208;ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240025</link>
      <description>Chinmayee Padwal, Xijue Wang, Hong Duc Pham, Thi My Linh Hoang, Sagadevan Mundree, Deepak P. Dubal, Battery energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403484794

                Abstract The synthesis of battery materials from biomass as feedstock is not only effective but also aligns with sustainable practices. However, current methods like slow pyrolysis/heating are both energy&#8208;intensive and economically impractical. Hence, integrating energy&#8208;efficient technologies becomes imperative to curtail substantial energy consumption and, consequently, minimize carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) emissions during electricity usage. Herein, we employed a one&#8208;step pyrolysis/reduction based on the microwave heating method to synthesize a composite of high&#8208;purity silicon and highly graphitized carbon (Si@GC) from rice husk as feedstock. Compared to the conventional heating methods, the Si@GC samples prepared via the microwave heating method required less time (30&#8211;50 min). Benefiting from ultrahigh heating rates, the highly graphitized carbon and crystalline silicon composite was successfully synthesized. The synthesis by microwave irradiation showed homogenous material, excellent surface area, essential functional groups, and crystallinity revealing the outstanding reaction kinetics to form the material. The as&#8208;synthesized Si@GC composite anode material delivered a high discharge capacity of 799 mAh/g with high cyclic stability of ~71% over 120 cycles. The ex situ ToF&#8208;SIMS revealed great inorganic SEI composition, mainly consisting of the fluorinated species and carbonate species produced at the initial cycle. This investigation provides a novel rapid heating method for the synthesis of battery materials, which can also be extended for other materials and applications.</description>
      <author>Chinmayee Padwal, Xijue Wang, Hong Duc Pham, Thi My Linh Hoang, Sagadevan Mundree, Deepak P. Dubal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mechanical and hydrochemical properties of cemented calcareous soil under long-term soaking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-75540-9</link>
      <description>Peng Feng, Piergiorgio Cao, Sili Ren, Junping Ren, Ying Dong, Gao&#8208;Lin Wu, Ran Tang, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403523263

                This study investigates the impact of long-term water immersion on the mechanical and hydrochemical properties of cemented calcareous soil, emphasizing the critical role of carbonate content in mechanical performance. Utilizing hydrochemical analysis and triaxial testing, the research revealed that prolonged immersion disrupts the acid-base balance of the solution, resulting in an increased concentration of ions and chemicals. Significant dissolution of carbonates and soluble minerals occurs, which reacts with carbon dioxide to generate bicarbonate ions, thereby elevating the alkalinity of the soaking solution. Additionally, the gradual dissolution of clay minerals compromises the cementitious structure, leading to particle reorientation and interlocking. The study quantitatively assesses the changes in soil properties, demonstrating a substantial reduction in soil cohesion by up to 86.1% and an increase in the internal friction angle by 37.5%. Furthermore, the gradual dissolution of clay minerals compromises the cementitious structure, resulting in particle reorientation and interlocking that contribute to the observed mechanical changes. The findings underscore the importance of understanding the effects of extended immersion on the stability and engineering applicability of cemented calcareous soils.</description>
      <author>Peng Feng, Piergiorgio Cao, Sili Ren, Junping Ren, Ying Dong, Gao&#8208;Lin Wu, Ran Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-75540-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Emission Reduction Associated With Utilisation Of Telehealth In Outpatient Clinics In An Australian Quaternary Health Service</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24083/apjhm.v19i2.3665</link>
      <description>Jessica Redmond, Timothy Fazio, Phoebe Darlison, Barbara Ioppi, Matthew J. Page, Katherine A. Barraclough, Kudzai Kanhutu, Ben Dunne, Asia Pacific Journal of Health Management. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403573715

                Objective: To assess the impact of implementing telehealth in outpatient clinics on the carbon emissions associated with the delivery of health care. Design &amp; Setting: Retrospective cohort study in large metropolitan quaternary referral health service from January 2021- December 2022. Participants: All patients who attended an outpatient clinic appointment during the study period, either in-person, via telehealth or via telephone. Main outcome measures: The estimation of carbon emissions in tonnes (t) of CO2-equivalent (CO2-e) associated with in-person and telehealth appointments based on emissions associated with travel, telehealth platform usage and N95 mask usage. Results: There were 571,121 outpatient clinic appointments during the study period. Of the appointments, 251,458 (44%) were conducted remotely, resulting in an estimated reduction in 3,629t of CO2-e emissions in the two-year period. Telehealth consultations in this time contributed 4.5t of CO2-equivalent emissions. The total emission usage of telehealth clinic was only 0.12% of emissions generated from face-to-face clinic appointments. Conclusion: Telehealth offers the opportunity of substantial carbon emissions reduction within the healthcare sector, while also providing cost and time-saving benefits for healthcare services and patients. Limitations include generalisation of transportation modes and the retrospective nature of the data collection.</description>
      <author>Jessica Redmond, Timothy Fazio, Phoebe Darlison, Barbara Ioppi, Matthew J. Page, Katherine A. Barraclough, Kudzai Kanhutu, Ben Dunne</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24083/apjhm.v19i2.3665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascade Conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Ethylene Carbonate under Ambient Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11390</link>
      <description>Zhaoyu Wen, Mengjing Wang, Chen&#8208;Jui Liang, Bolun Fan, Yuchen Yan, Fan Jia, Na Han, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403553455

                Ethylene carbonate (EC) is the simplest cyclic carbonate with great industrial significance, most importantly as the vital electrolyte component for lithium-ion batteries. Its conventional synthesis generally involves the use of toxic precursors and requires elevated temperatures and pressures. Herein, we propose a cascade catalytic route for converting CO2 to EC under ambient conditions. Such a hybrid reaction scheme consists of the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to ethylene catalyzed by copper in a membrane electrode assembly reactor, the bromine-mediated conversion of ethylene to bromoethanol catalyzed by WO3 nanoarrays grown on carbon cloth, and the reaction between bromoethanol and CO2 to form EC. By separately optimizing individual catalytic steps and then integrating them together in series, we achieved the conversion of CO2 to EC at a good yield under room temperature and atmospheric pressure. Our study also represents the first demonstration about the successful synthesis of organic carbonates from CO2 as the exclusive carbon source.</description>
      <author>Zhaoyu Wen, Mengjing Wang, Chen&#8208;Jui Liang, Bolun Fan, Yuchen Yan, Fan Jia, Na Han, Yuhang Wang, Yanguang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BetterFuture Co. and its CO2 Footprint: A Case to Learn About ESG (Environmental, Social and Governance)/GHG (Greenhouse Gas)/CO2, Compliance, and SMART Goal Setting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/21649987241291014</link>
      <description>Melinda Ratkai, A. van Rheede, Journal of Hospitality &amp; Tourism Cases. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403520215

                The case study delves into the complex issue of CO2 footprint from three distinct viewpoints: sustainability, legislative, and managerial. Each perspective offers unique insights into the challenges and opportunities of mitigating greenhouse gas emissions using scope 1, 2, and 3 data. From a sustainability viewpoint, students are encouraged to explore the concept of CO2 footprint within the broader context of ESG considerations. Key questions delve into understanding sustainability frameworks, assessing the impact of CO2 emissions on ecosystems and communities, and exploring strategies for carbon footprint reduction aligned with sustainability goals. From the legislative perspective, students examine the regulatory landscape governing CO2 emissions. Students learn how legal frameworks shape corporate behavior by studying global sustainability goals such as the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), the Global Reporting Initiative (GRI), and national legislation. Discussion questions focus on analyzing the effectiveness of existing regulations, identifying gaps, and proposing regulatory strategies to incentivize carbon reduction. The managerial perspective emphasizes decision-making and goal-setting within organizations. Students explore how managers can leverage data on CO2 footprint to set SMART (Specific, Measurable, Achievable, Relevant, Time-bound) goals for departments or individuals. This involves understanding the role of carbon accounting, evaluating trade-offs in sustainability initiatives, and exploring best practices in integrating sustainability into organizational strategy. The case encourages critical thinking and data analysis, allowing educators to pose additional questions based on student interests and course objectives. The rich dataset allows for extensive exploration beyond the core questions, facilitating interdisciplinary learning across various courses. Ultimately, the case is a versatile teaching tool that can be applied to courses focusing on sustainability, environmental studies, business ethics, managerial decision-making, and public policy. It equips students with the knowledge and skills to navigate the multifaceted challenges of reducing their CO2 footprint while advancing sustainable practices within organizations and society.</description>
      <author>Melinda Ratkai, A. van Rheede</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/21649987241291014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cradle-To-Gate Analyses of Biochar Produced from Agricultural Crop Residues by Vacuum Pyrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ce/zkae069</link>
      <description>Nakum Divyangkumar, N. L. Panwar, Chitranjan Agrawal, Trilok Gupta, G. L. Meena, Manjeet Singh, Clean Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403517028

                Abstract Agricultural waste, if not managed efficiently, can pose significant environmental threats. Biochar production, a cost-effective solution, offers a potential to significantly reduce carbon dioxide emissions and thereby combat climate change. However, the environmental impact of this process is not uniform and varies depending on the agricultural residue used. These impacts, spanning the entire lifecycle from cultivation to disposal, underscore the necessity of a thorough assessment before biochar can be widely adopted for practical applications. This study employs a cradle-to-gate approach to evaluate the life cycle assessment of producing biochar from various agro-residues, such as rice husk, sugarcane bagasse, and corn cob. The life cycle assessment was conducted using SimaPro software, version 9.5.0.1, and the ReCiPe impact assessment method. The results indicate that corn cob cultivation has the highest impact across most categories, while rice husks exhibit higher water consumption (2.8&#215;103 m3). Using diesel, electricity, and fertilizers significantly contributes to global warming potential. Sugarcane bagasse shows the most negligible impact during biomass cultivation. However, pyrolysis processes exhibit high implications on various indicators. Applying biochar to soil for carbon sequestration and improvement can reduce global warming potential. Sensitivity analysis demonstrates a notable reduction in global warming potential and cumulative energy demand, approximately 10-24 % and 4-11 MWh, respectively. Paddy cultivation and rice husk biochar production have a lesser environmental impact. Changing energy sources during biomass growth and biochar production significantly influences environmental factors.</description>
      <author>Nakum Divyangkumar, N. L. Panwar, Chitranjan Agrawal, Trilok Gupta, G. L. Meena, Manjeet Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ce/zkae069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accounting Method and Indicators of Multilevel CO2 Emissions Based on Cost During Construction of Shield Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14209552</link>
      <description>Shuihua Zheng, Xiongyao Xie, Biao Zhou, Applied Sciences. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403598525

                With the rapid expansion of shield tunnel projects in China, precise accounting of CO2 emissions throughout the entire process is essential for advancing green and low-carbon construction practices. This paper introduces an innovative CO2 accounting methodology utilizing a cost-based carbon emission coding system. It adopts a multilevel approach to carbon emission accounting, aligned with this coding system, which facilitates a detailed examination of carbon emission ratios and characteristics across various construction techniques. The analysis includes six typical shield tunnel projects varying in diameter, focusing on sub-projects to scrutinize CO2 emissions and establish specific indicators. The findings indicate that CO2 emissions per 10,000 yuan of investment, approximately 30.25% (or 3025 kgCO2e/10,000 yuan), are more consistent than those per unit of length. Moreover, the study highlights differing CO2 emission trends among sub-projects compared to whole tunnel projects, assessing emission indicators and distribution patterns in four sub-projects: shield excavation, segmental lining, internal structure, and tunnel reinforcement. From these findings, the paper suggests more precise and tailored strategies for CO2 reduction. This research provides a theoretical basis for future construction planning and carbon management strategies.</description>
      <author>Shuihua Zheng, Xiongyao Xie, Biao Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14209552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coaxially Bi/ZnO@ZnSe array photocathode enables highly efficient CO2 to C1 conversion via long&#8208;lived high&#8208;energy photoelectrons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401436</link>
      <description>Wei Ma, Haiqiang Mu, Zhenli Lv, Jia-Xing Guo, Shengli Zhu, Yonghong Li, Xiaozhong Wang, Jing Li, Feng Li, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533548

                The key aspect of the photoelectrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (PEC CO2 RR) lies in designing cathode materials that can generate high&#8208;energy photoelectrons, enabling the activation and conversion of CO2 into high&#8208;value products. In this study, a coaxially wrapped ZnO@ZnSe array heterostructure was synthesized using a simple anion exchange strategy and metallic Bi nanoparticles (NPs) were subsequently deposited on the surface to construct a Bi/ZnO@ZnSe photocathode with high CO2 conversion capability. This array photocathode possesses a large aspect ratio, which simultaneously satisfies a low charge carrier migration path and a large specific surface area that facilitates mass transfer. Additionally, the barrier formed at the n&#8208;n heterojunction interface hinders the transfer of high&#8208;energy photoelectrons from ZnSe to lower energy levels, resulting in their rapid capture by Bi while maintaining a relatively long lifetime. These captured electrons act as active sites, efficiently converting CO2 into CO with a Faradaic efficiency above 88.9% at &#8208;0.9 V vs. RHE and demonstrating superior stability. This work provides a novel approach for synthesizing high&#8208;energy photoelectrode materials with long lifetimes.</description>
      <author>Wei Ma, Haiqiang Mu, Zhenli Lv, Jia-Xing Guo, Shengli Zhu, Yonghong Li, Xiaozhong Wang, Jing Li, Feng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of calcined mud on the rheological properties of eco-friendly concretes using the equivalent mortar method (CEM)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54021/seesv5n2-371</link>
      <description>Mohammed Yacine Kiboub, Souad Malab, Akram Salah Eddine Bela&#239;di, Kaouthar Takhi, STUDIES IN ENGINEERING AND EXACT SCIENCES. 5(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403638424

                In order to harmonise technical and environmental aspects, people today focus not only on concrete's technical characteristics but also on environmental imperatives. Thus, the emphasis is on the development of concrete and cements that offer ecological and sustainable advantages. Commonly, people use various natural materials as cement additives, demonstrating their effectiveness by replacing a significant portion of the cement in the hardened state of concrete. This substitution leads to a substantial and remarkable reduction in carbon dioxide emissions. However, when it comes to the physical properties of the material in its fresh state, challenges may arise. Indeed, the rheological changes induced by these additives may hinder the on-site use of this eco-concrete. The main purpose of this study is to find out how adding minerals to environmentally friendly concrete changes its rheological parameters (yield stress, plastic viscosity) and fresh properties (slump, flow time). We will approach this using the concept of mortar equivalent to concrete (CEM). We developed five formulations of CEM&#8217;s by substituting cement with calcined mud (CM) in binary mixing systems at a temperature of 20 &#176;C. The results showed that adding binary cements with calcined mud had a negative effect on the fresh properties and rheological parameters. However, when substitution happens at a low rate, it behaves almost like control mortar (OPC).</description>
      <author>Mohammed Yacine Kiboub, Souad Malab, Akram Salah Eddine Bela&#239;di, Kaouthar Takhi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54021/seesv5n2-371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of CO2 Storage Capacity Potentiality as a Secondary Driving Mechanism in Enhanced Oil Recovery in East Bahariya Field, Bahariya Concession, Western Desert, Egypt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/223285-ms</link>
      <description>A. Dahman, Hazem Mohamd, Reda Abd El-Rahman, Mohamed Abdelwahab Ataallah, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403586983

                Abstract Egypt formulated its sustainable development strategy "Egypt Vision 2030" in 2015. This strategy aims to protect the environment in the development process by integrating environmental aspects into economic and social development plans to manage natural resources, conserve natural capital, and develop to protect the environmental rights of future generations. According to the IEA (International Energy Agency) CO2 emission reduction projects to track advances in carbon capture, utilization, storage as well as use of naturally occurring CO2 for EOR (Enhanced Oil Recovery) of depleted reservoirs. This paper proposes a methodology for evaluating underground CO2 storage capacity according to the facies of different formations applicable to the CO2 EOR projects. The methods proposed in this document will not only help third parties create reports and inventories of greenhouse gas emissions from companies, but also help governments to encourage companies to reduce their CO2 emissions. It would be beneficial for the industry implementing CCUS (Carbo Capture Utilize and Storage) projects to provide key evaluation parameters and implement the necessary monitoring techniques. Due to advantages and vast resource capacity, onshore CO2 storage provides an attractive option. Bahariya concession is located at the eastern trough of Abu Gharadig basin, Western Desert, Egypt. By Using the available data, a subsurface geologic evaluation and 3D modelling was carried out in terms of thickness variation, lithofacies, structural setting and depositional environment of the studied rock unit in the encountered basin. This study presents both depleted reservoir and shallow non-reservoir formations as preliminary targets for CO2 storage potential. It was concluded that both clastic and non-clastic Cretaceous formations have a high-quality potential geological reservoir repository for CO2 storage capacity.</description>
      <author>A. Dahman, Hazem Mohamd, Reda Abd El-Rahman, Mohamed Abdelwahab Ataallah</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/223285-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iodine Assessment of Carbon Dioxide Angiography in Iliac Branched Repair</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/15266028241289012</link>
      <description>Roberta Vaccarino, Angelos Karelis, Bharti Singh, Elisabet Marinko, Kalliopi-Maria Tasopoulou, Timothy Resch, Bj&#246;rn Sonesson, Nuno Dias, Journal of Endovascular Therapy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403646617

                Objective: The objective of this study was to investigate whether the use of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) angiography decreases the intraoperative use of iodine contrast medium (ICM), thereby decreasing the risk of developing postoperative renal damage in patients undergoing iliac branch device (IBD) implantation. Methods: Patients undergoing IBD implantation at a single tertiary center between May 2013 and August 2019 were screened for inclusion in the study. A cohort of patients in whom an intraoperative imaging protocol using predominantly CO 2 was compared with a control group in whom ICM was used (CO 2 and ICM groups). Fusion imaging was used in both groups. Retrospective review of the medical charts and all imaging was performed. Variables were expressed as median with interquartile range (IQR) or absolute number and percentage. Wilcoxon-Mann-Whitney and &#967; 2 tests were used to compare continuous and categorical variables, respectively. P values of &lt;0 .05 were considered statistically significant. Results: Twenty-three patients were included in the CO 2 group and 21 in the ICM group without significant differences in patient characteristics between the groups. Intraoperative iodine exposure was lower in the CO 2 group than in the ICM group (8.2 g [IQR, 7.1-10.9 g) vs 15.8 g (IQR 7.6-21 g); P = 0.015, respectively). There were no differences in technical success, clinical success, fluoroscopy time, and dose-area product in the 2 groups. There were no adverse events that could be related to the intraoperative use of CO 2. There was no difference in postoperative survival nor renal function assessment between the groups despite the higher number of accessory renal arteries embolized in the CO 2 group ( P = 0.221). Conclusions: Reduction of intraoperative ICM exposure during IBD implantation is feasible through the predominant use of CO 2 automated angiography. This can be done safely without affecting the technical success or radiation exposure. The immediate postoperative renal damage was low when a modern intraoperative imaging protocol with ICM was used and was not significantly reduced by the use of CO 2 . Further and larger studies are needed to investigate the long-term effects. Clinical Impact This study aimed to investigate how to minimize intraoperative risk during iliac branched repair exploring the intraoperative use of automated carbon dioxide angiography in order to decrease the use of contrast media protecting renal function and thereby potentially impacting long-term survival</description>
      <author>Roberta Vaccarino, Angelos Karelis, Bharti Singh, Elisabet Marinko, Kalliopi-Maria Tasopoulou, Timothy Resch, Bj&#246;rn Sonesson, Nuno Dias</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/15266028241289012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Precision to Ethylene and Ethanol: The Role of Additional Boron Catalytic Sites in Cu&#8208;Based Tandem Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202410118</link>
      <description>Fuqing Yu, Minxing Shu, Guangyao Zhang, Qiming Yu, Hongming Wang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403611551

                Abstract The electrocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) into valuable multicarbon (C 2+ ) compounds offers a promising approach to mitigate CO 2 emissions and harness renewable energy. However, achieving precise selectivity for specific C 2+ products, such as ethylene and ethanol, remains a formidable challenge. This study shows that incorporating elemental boron (B) into copper (Cu) catalysts provides additional adsorption sites for * CO intermediates, enhancing the selectivity of desirable C 2+ products. Additionally, using a nickel single&#8208;atom catalyst (Ni&#8208;SAC) as a * CO source increases local * CO concentration and reduces the hydrogen evolution reaction. In situ experiments and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that surface&#8208;bound boron units adsorb and convert * CO more efficiently, promoting ethylene production, while boron within the bulk phase of copper influences charge transfer, facilitating ethanol generation. In a neutral electrolyte, the bias current density for ethylene production using the B&#8208;O&#8208;Cu2@Ni&#8208;SAC0.05 hybrid catalyst exceeded 300 mA cm &#8722;2 , and that for ethanol production with B&#8208;O&#8208;Cu5@Ni&#8208;SAC0.2 surpassed 250 mA cm &#8722;2 . This study underscores that elemental doping in Cu&#8208;based catalysts not only alters charge and crystalline phase arrangements at Cu sites but also provides additional reduction sites for coupling reactions, enabling the efficient synthesis of distinct C 2+ products.</description>
      <author>Fuqing Yu, Minxing Shu, Guangyao Zhang, Qiming Yu, Hongming Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202410118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of welding gas mixtures on weld material and bead geometry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1757-899x/1315/1/012007</link>
      <description>Michael A. Unger, Jo&#227;o R. Neves, Martin Schnall, IOP Conference Series Materials Science and Engineering. 1315(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403545844

                Abstract Shielding gas is an essential parameter in welding processes, serves to shield the molten material from the atmosphere and external contaminations while providing a stable electric-arc pathway during the process, thus influencing the quality of the weld bead and several other aspects of the process. Therefore, any welding-based process, such as wire-arc additive manufacturing, could benefit from shielding gas mixture optimisation to selectively improve the processing and possibly the final mechanical properties of the welded material. In this study welding of EN AW 5183 aluminium (single weld bead and wire-arc additive manufacturing build-up) was conducted using several gas mixtures and their influence on final geometry defects, and microstructure measured. The gas mixtures used were a combination of varying amounts of carbon dioxide, nitrogen, and oxygen. These were added to commercially available argon gas. It was observed that: CO 2 additions led to an unfavourable bonding defect and increased mean grain size; nitrogen additions caused a decrease in mean grain size, decreased pore count while maintaining a similar pore volume fraction to the reference argon mixture samples; oxygen additions showed slight reduction of mean grain size, decreased pore count and decreased pore volume fraction. These results further showcase that varying shielding gas mixtures influence the final material properties and should be considered as an additional improvement route for conventional welding and additive manufacturing.</description>
      <author>Michael A. Unger, Jo&#227;o R. Neves, Martin Schnall</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1757-899x/1315/1/012007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lower grass stomatal conductance under elevated CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; can decrease transpiration and evapotranspiration rates despite carbon fertilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pld3.70013</link>
      <description>Sate Ahmad, Charilaos Yiotis, Weimu Xu, Jan Knappe, Laurence Gill, Jennifer C. McElwain, Plant Direct. 8(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403617022

                Abstract Anthropogenic increase in carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) affects plant physiology. Plant responses to elevated CO 2 typically include: (1) enhanced photosynthesis and increased primary productivity due to carbon fertilization and (2) suppression of leaf transpiration due to CO 2 &#8208;driven decrease in stomatal conductance. The combined effect of these responses on the total plant transpiration and on evapotranspiration (ET) has a wide range of implications on local, regional, and global hydrological cycles, and thus needs to be better understood. Here, we investigated the net effect of CO 2 &#8208;driven perennial ryegrass ( Lolium perenne ) physiological responses on transpiration and evapotranspiration by integrating physiological and hydrological (water budget) methods, under a controlled environment. Measurements of the net photosynthetic rate, stomatal conductance, transpiration rate, leaf mass per area, aboveground biomass, and water balance components were recorded. Measured variables under elevated CO 2 were compared with those of ambient CO 2 . As expected, our results show that elevated CO 2 significantly decreases whole&#8208;plant transpiration rates (38% lower in the final week) which is a result of lower stomatal conductance (57% lower in the final week) despite a slight increase in aboveground biomass. Additionally, there was an overall decline in evapotranspiration (ET) under elevated CO 2 , indicating the impact of CO 2 &#8208;mediated suppression of transpiration on the overall water balance. Although studies with larger sample sizes are needed for more robust conclusions, our findings have significant implications for global environmental change. Reductions in ET from ryegrass&#8208;dominated grasslands and pastures could increase soil moisture and groundwater recharge, potentially leading to increased surface runoff and flooding.</description>
      <author>Sate Ahmad, Charilaos Yiotis, Weimu Xu, Jan Knappe, Laurence Gill, Jennifer C. McElwain</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pld3.70013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>d&#8208;Electrons of Platinum Alloy Steering CO Pathway for Low&#8208;charge Potential Li&#8208;CO2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415728</link>
      <description>Limin Liu, Shenyu Shen, Jiatian Li, Ning Zhao, Xiangkai Yin, Jing Wang, Wei Yu, Yaqiong Su, Bao Yu Xia, Shujiang Ding, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403550087

                Aprotic Li&#8208;CO2 batteries suffer from sluggish solid&#8208;solid co&#8208;oxidation kinetics of C and Li2CO3, requiring extremely high charging potentials and leading to serious side reactions and poor energy efficiency. Herein, we introduce a novel approach to address these challenges by modulating the reaction pathway with tailored Pt d&#8208;electrons and develop an aprotic Li&#8208;CO2 battery with CO and Li2CO3 as the main discharge products. Note that the gas&#8208;solid co&#8208;oxidation reaction between CO and Li2CO3 is both kinetically and thermodynamically more favorable. Consequently, the Li&#8208;CO2 batteries with CoPt alloy&#8208;supported on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanofiber (CoPt@NCNF) cathode exhibit a charging potential of 2.89 V at 50 &#181;A cm&#8208;2, which is the lowest charging potential to date. Moreover, the CoPt@NCNF cathode also shows exceptional cycling stability (218 cycles at 50 &#181;A cm&#8208;2) and high energy efficiency up to 74.6%. Comprehensive experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that the lowered d&#8208;band center of CoPt alloy effectively promotes CO desorption and inhibits further CO reduction to C. This work provides promising insights into developing efficient and CO&#8208;selective Li&#8208;CO2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Limin Liu, Shenyu Shen, Jiatian Li, Ning Zhao, Xiangkai Yin, Jing Wang, Wei Yu, Yaqiong Su, Bao Yu Xia, Shujiang Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>d&#8208;Electrons of Platinum Alloy Steering CO Pathway for Low&#8208;charge Potential Li&#8208;CO2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415728</link>
      <description>Huijuan Liu, Shenyu Shen, Jiatian Li, Ning Zhao, Xiangkai Yin, Jing Wang, Wei Ma, Yaqiong Su, Bao Yu Xia, Shujiang Ding, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403550209

                Aprotic Li&#8208;CO2 batteries suffer from sluggish solid&#8208;solid co&#8208;oxidation kinetics of C and Li2CO3, requiring extremely high charging potentials and leading to serious side reactions and poor energy efficiency. Herein, we introduce a novel approach to address these challenges by modulating the reaction pathway with tailored Pt d&#8208;electrons and develop an aprotic Li&#8208;CO2 battery with CO and Li2CO3 as the main discharge products. Note that the gas&#8208;solid co&#8208;oxidation reaction between CO and Li2CO3 is both kinetically and thermodynamically more favorable. Consequently, the Li&#8208;CO2 batteries with CoPt alloy&#8208;supported on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanofiber (CoPt@NCNF) cathode exhibit a charging potential of 2.89 V at 50 &#181;A cm&#8208;2, which is the lowest charging potential to date. Moreover, the CoPt@NCNF cathode also shows exceptional cycling stability (218 cycles at 50 &#181;A cm&#8208;2) and high energy efficiency up to 74.6%. Comprehensive experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that the lowered d&#8208;band center of CoPt alloy effectively promotes CO desorption and inhibits further CO reduction to C. This work provides promising insights into developing efficient and CO&#8208;selective Li&#8208;CO2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Huijuan Liu, Shenyu Shen, Jiatian Li, Ning Zhao, Xiangkai Yin, Jing Wang, Wei Ma, Yaqiong Su, Bao Yu Xia, Shujiang Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Effects in Stock Markets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/430kvj67</link>
      <description>Yang Ju, Highlights in Business Economics and Management. 41(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403572021

                Climate change significantly impacts global stock markets through both short-term extreme weather events and long-term climate shifts. This study examines the relationship between CO2 emissions and stock returns across 19 countries from 2001 to 2020 using regression analysis. The findings also reveal a positive correlation between CO2 emissions and stock returns, indicating that investors anticipate higher returns to offset climate-related risks. This suggests that higher CO2 emissions drive investor expectations for increased returns to compensate for potential economic losses. The study highlights the importance of balanced emission reduction strategies and promoting green finance to support sustainable economic growth. Additionally, it underscores the need to integrate climate risks into financial decision-making, offering valuable insights into the financial implications of climate change and guiding policymakers and investors in addressing these challenges. By providing empirical evidence on the link between CO2 emissions and stock returns, this research enriches existing knowledge and emphasizes the financial risks and opportunities presented by climate change. The study's results align with the carbon risk premium theory, which posits that investors demand higher returns from companies with higher carbon emissions. This study advocates for policies that balance economic growth with environmental sustainability, promoting green finance initiatives to facilitate the transition to a low-carbon economy and mitigate the adverse effects of climate change on financial markets.</description>
      <author>Yang Ju</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/430kvj67</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Assessments of Low- and Medium-Pressure CO2 Transport At-Sea and Inland</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.1671.v1</link>
      <description>Ingeborg Treu R&#248;e, Pauline Oeuvray, Marco Mazzotti, Simon Roussanaly, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403627324

                Developing cost-efficient systems for transporting CO2 is key to accelerate the deployment of carbon capture and storage. The present work explores the impact of reducing the pressure of tank-based inland and at-sea transport on their techno-economic performance. The study uses established techno-economic models for CO2 transport, adjusted with the most up-to-date knowledge on costs of low-pressure containment and transport. Particularly, the impact of cargo tank material and design on the transport costs shows that low-pressure cargo tank systems can be 50% less expensive than medium-pressure systems if materials with similar price and strength can be used. This results in reductions in transport costs as high as 30% for long distances. This is partly driven by the currently suggested size limitation on medium-pressure shipping which limits its economies of scale. If this limitation is alleviated, the cost advantage of low-pressure shipping compared to medium-pressure is more limited (10-20%) although it remains advantageous. The same scaling effects on capacity were not found for truck and barge inland transport, thus yielding 1-10% cost reductions of low- relative to medium-pressure transport. These results imply that future systems may combine medium-pressure inland and low-pressure at-sea transport, and that efficient solutions connecting the two must be investigated.</description>
      <author>Ingeborg Treu R&#248;e, Pauline Oeuvray, Marco Mazzotti, Simon Roussanaly</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202410.1671.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification and Evaluation of Synergy Between Carbon Emissions and Air Pollutants in Inter-Industrial Trade Among Provinces in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16209067</link>
      <description>Liying Niu, Jiaoyue Wang, Hongyan Zhao, Mingjing Ma, Fengming Xi, Sustainability. 16(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403599343

                With the vigorous promotion in China of efforts to reduce pollution and carbon emissions, examining their synergies becomes increasingly crucial. This study used the multi-regional input&#8211;output (MRIO) table to build the consumption-based industrial emissions inventories of CO2 and three major air pollutants (PM2.5, NOx, and SO2) and constructed synergistic emission indices of the intensity and magnitude to identify and evaluate the synergy between carbon emissions and air pollutants in inter-industrial trade among 30 provinces in mainland China. The results show that more than 85% and 40% of inter-provincial and inter-industrial trades have synergistic emissions between CO2 and air pollutants, respectively. We identified 77 inter-provincial trades and 84 inter-industrial trades among provinces with strong synergistic emissions. They are mainly reflected in the demand of the construction industry in Zhejiang and Guangdong for the nonmetal mineral products manufacturing industry in Henan, and the metal smelting and processing industry in Hebei, along with the demand of the service industry in Beijing for the electric power, steam, and hot water production and supply industry in Inner Mongolia. Our study provides new insights into the synergistic reduction of CO2 and air pollutants within the supply chain, thereby enriching the discourse on regional and industrial synergies in achieving sustainable development goals.</description>
      <author>Liying Niu, Jiaoyue Wang, Hongyan Zhao, Mingjing Ma, Fengming Xi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16209067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative analysis of Environmental Impact of Each Building Material using Life Cycle assessment(LCA)_Focusing on Types of Construction Wood and Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4491/ksee.2024.46.10.570</link>
      <description>Soon Gil Kwon, Yoon-Seong Chang, H. Choi, Journal of Korean Society of Environmental Engineers. 46(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403667543

                Objectives:The construction sector is a very important sector in achieving carbon neutrality. In modern society, construction has grown rapidly, and basic materials such as cement and concrete have contributed greatly to the development of construction. These materials emit a large amount of global warming substances during the raw material extraction and production process, causing serious environmental pollution. In order to establish a carbon reduction strategy to slow down global warming, we compared the environmental impacts of each building material and showed the current situation.Methods:The LCI DB for the construction materials used in the two-story wooden house (Building area 128.67m2, total floor area 235.73m2) located in the National Institute of Forest Science was extracted. Then, the data for LCA was processed and performed through the life cycle assessment methodology for the resources consumed from raw material collection, material production, and transportation stages. Then, based on the environmental performance labeling impact assessment method, a study was conducted on the environmental impact categories of the actual construction materials used and comparisons with other construction materials.Results and Discussion:When analyzing the environmental impact of concrete [25-21-120] and construction wood used in wooden house, the environmental impact was found to be 98.79% higher on average in the pre-manufacturing stage than in the manufacturing stage, and construction wood was confirmed to have a reduction effect of 62.21 kg CO2-eq per 1 m3 compared to concrete. Through the scenario, there was a carbon reduction effect of up to 36% when the entire area was replaced with wood. In addition, the environmental impact by major construction material was quantitatively quantified.Conclusion:When building a wooden house, reducing the amount of concrete equivalent to the amount of wood is expected to have a greenhouse gas reduction effect, so it is time to activate construction wood from the production process to the post-production stage to replace concrete. In addition, follow-up research on the development of construction technology with low environmental impact during construction should be continued. This study is expected to be used as a useful indicator for R&amp;D and policies in the construction field in the future, as it quantitatively quantified the amount of CO2 reduction per m3 when replacing concrete with construction wood and numerically compared and analyzed six major environmental impact categories by major construction materials.</description>
      <author>Soon Gil Kwon, Yoon-Seong Chang, H. Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4491/ksee.2024.46.10.570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMPACT OF DIGITALIZATION ON THE IMPLEMENTATION OF CARBON-FREE ECONOMY PRINCIPLES IN UKRAINE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32782/2524-0072/2024-66-109</link>
      <description>&#1050;&#1072;&#1088;&#1110;&#1085;&#1072; &#1058;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1102;&#1082;, Olena Kasian, &#1045;&#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084;&#1110;&#1082;&#1072; &#1090;&#1072; &#1089;&#1091;&#1089;&#1087;&#1110;&#1083;&#1100;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1086;. None(66)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403605805

                This study explores the role of digitalization in implementing carbon-free economy principles in Ukraine, with a particular focus on how digital technologies contribute to enhancing energy efficiency and reducing CO2 emissions. Digitalization serves as a critical enabler of sustainable development by providing tools for optimizing energy consumption, improving resource management, and minimizing the environmental footprint of economic activities. Through correlation and regression analyses, the research investigates the relationship between investments in digital technologies, environmental protection measures, and CO2 emissions for the period from 2007 to 2020. The results reveal that while digitalization has the potential to improve energy efficiency, its current impact on reducing CO2 emissions remains limited. The findings indicate that increased investments in renewable energy sources and more comprehensive integration of digital technologies into the energy sector are essential to achieve significant reductions in emissions. Additionally, the study highlights the positive effect of innovation-driven activities on energy efficiency but points to the need for further development and deployment of environmentally friendly digital solutions. The research also underscores the importance of continued financial support for green technologies and emphasizes the necessity of improving greenhouse gas monitoring systems. Practical recommendations include increasing investment in renewable energy, expanding the use of smart technologies across industries, and promoting long-term innovation strategies aimed at achieving carbon neutrality. Overall, the research concludes that digital innovation plays a supporting role in achieving energy efficiency but requires stronger policy frameworks, investment, and coordination to realize its full potential in contributing to environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>&#1050;&#1072;&#1088;&#1110;&#1085;&#1072; &#1058;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1102;&#1082;, Olena Kasian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32782/2524-0072/2024-66-109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy-Derived Synthesis of the CuPd Sub-1nm Alloy for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-acetate Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07711</link>
      <description>Siyang Nie, Liang Wu, Qingda Liu, Xun Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403560250

                Bimetallic alloys exhibit remarkable properties in catalysis and energy storage, while their precise synthesis at the subnanoscale remains a formidable challenge due to their immiscible nature in thermodynamics. In this study, we engineer an atomically dispersed CuPd alloy with an average size of 1.5 nm loaded on CuO and phosphomolybdic acid (PMA) coassembly subnanosheets (CuO-PMA SNSs). Driven by the high vibrational entropy, Cu atoms could escape from CuO supports and bond with adjacent Pd single atoms, leading to the in situ formation of CuPd alloys. Furthermore, this strategy can also be utilized for synthesizing the ZnPt alloy with an average size of 1 nm, thereby providing a general pathway for the design of immiscible subnanoalloys. The fully exposed Cu&#8211;Pd pairs in CuPd subnanoalloys significantly enhance the adsorption and coverage of surface *CO during the electrochemical reduction of CO2, thereby leading to enhanced stability of ethenone intermediates and facilitating the production of C2 compounds. The resulting CuPd subnanoalloy exhibits a remarkable Faradaic efficiency of 46.5 &#177; 2.1% for CO2-to-acetate electroreduction and achieves a high acetate productivity of 99 &#177; 2.8 &#956;mol cm&#8211;2 at &#8722;0.7 V versus RHE.</description>
      <author>Siyang Nie, Liang Wu, Qingda Liu, Xun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07711</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Optimising Renewable Energy and Grid Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15101250</link>
      <description>Bankole I. Oladapo, Mattew A. Olawumi, Francis T. Omigbodun, Atmosphere. 15(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403611208

                This research investigates the application of machine learning models to optimise renewable energy systems and contribute to achieving Net Zero emissions targets. The primary objective is to evaluate how machine learning can improve energy forecasting, grid management, and storage optimisation, thereby enhancing the reliability and efficiency of renewable energy sources. The methodology involved the application of various machine learning models, including Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM), Random Forest, Support Vector Machines (SVMs), and ARIMA, to predict energy generation and demand patterns. These models were evaluated using metrics such as Mean Absolute Error (MAE) and Root Mean Squared Error (RMSE). Key findings include a 15% improvement in grid efficiency after optimisation and a 10&#8211;20% increase in battery storage efficiency. Random Forest achieved the lowest MAE, reducing prediction error by approximately 8.5%. The study quantified CO2 emission reductions by energy source, with wind power accounting for a 15,000-ton annual reduction, followed by hydropower and solar reducing emissions by 10,000 and 7500 tons, respectively. The research concludes that machine learning can significantly enhance renewable energy system performance, with measurable reductions in errors and emissions. These improvements could help close the &#8220;ambition gap&#8221; by 20%, supporting global efforts to meet the 1.5 &#176;C Paris Agreement targets.</description>
      <author>Bankole I. Oladapo, Mattew A. Olawumi, Francis T. Omigbodun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15101250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially Explicit Life Cycle Global Warming and Eutrophication Potentials of Confined Dairy Production in the Contiguous US</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/environments11110230</link>
      <description>Xiaobo Xue Romeiko, Wangjian Zhang, Xue-Song Zhang, Jun&#8208;Ki Choi, Environments. 11(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403637701

                Assessing the spatially explicit life cycle environmental impacts of livestock production systems is critical for understanding the spatial heterogeneity of environmental releases and devising spatially targeted remediation strategies. This study presents the first spatially explicit assessment on life cycle global warming and eutrophication potentials of confined dairy production at a county scale in the contiguous US. The Environmental Policy Integrated Climate model was used to estimate greenhouse gases (GHGs), NH3, and aqueous nutrient releases of feed production. The Greenhouse gases, Regulated Emissions, and Energy use in Transportation model and Commodity Flow Survey were used to assess GHGs and NH3 from feed transportation. Emission-factor-based approaches were primarily used to calculate GHGs from enteric fermentation, and GHGs, NH3, and aqueous nutrient releases from manure management. Characterization factors reported by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change and Tool for Reduction and Assessment of Chemicals and other Environmental Impacts model were used to compute global warming and eutrophication potentials, respectively. The analyses revealed that life cycle global warming and eutrophication potentials of confined dairy production presented significant spatial heterogeneity among the US counties. For example, the life cycle global warming potential ranged from 462 kg CO2-eq/head to 14,189 kg CO2-eq/head. Surprisingly, sourcing feed locally cannot effectively reduce life cycle global warming and eutrophication potentials of confined dairy production. The feed supply scenarios with the lowest life cycle environmental impacts depend on the life cycle environmental impacts of feed production, geographic locations of confined dairy production, and specific impact categories. In addition, installing buffer strips in feed-producing hotspots can effectively reduce life cycle nutrient releases of confined dairy production. If 200 counties with the highest life cycle EP of corn adopt buffer strips, the reduction in life cycle EP of confined dairy production could reach 24.4%.</description>
      <author>Xiaobo Xue Romeiko, Wangjian Zhang, Xue-Song Zhang, Jun&#8208;Ki Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/environments11110230</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Impact of Phase-Change Materials on Enhancing the Thermal Efficiency of Buildings in Tropical Climates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17205212</link>
      <description>T&#225;ssio Luiz dos Santos, Arthur Santos Silva, Diogo Duarte dos Reis, Energies. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403602927

                Civil construction and buildings account for a significant 36% of worldwide energy consumption, contributing to 37% of global CO2 emissions. In Brazil, buildings consume a substantial 51.2% of the nation&#8217;s electricity production. Remarkably, approximately one-third of this energy is allocated specifically for maintaining thermal comfort within these structures. The thermal performance of a building has a significant impact on its energy efficiency; in this way, technologies developed to contribute to the energy efficiency of envelopes can directly contribute to the reduction in the building&#8217;s overall energy consumption. PCMs are technologies capable of absorbing heat without increasing temperature and can contribute to the better energy performance of envelopes. PCMs are used as a thermal performance solution in cold climate regions, and studies show that they are likely to work in buildings in tropical climates. The objective of this work is to analyze the performance of PCMs in tropical regions of the southern hemisphere, specifically in Brazil, and their behavior according to the constructive system used. Computer simulation contributes to an analysis closer to the reality of the implementation of this technology in these regions. This work is carried out with simulations in the software EnergyPlusTM version 24.1. The results demonstrate that PCMs can effectively contribute to a reduction in energy consumption for the thermal comfort of buildings in tropical climates, demonstrating the possible feasibility of the development of this technology for tropical climates.</description>
      <author>T&#225;ssio Luiz dos Santos, Arthur Santos Silva, Diogo Duarte dos Reis</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17205212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of NOx Generation and Ammonia Fuel Utilization in a Solid Oxide Fuel Cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/power2024-138521</link>
      <description>Cole Wilhelm, Aliza M. Willsey, Jeongmin Ahn, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403647298

                Abstract Decreasing the generation of CO2 from energy production is a key area in energy research and environmental sustainability. Fuel cells represent a solution to reducing CO2 generation through the use of hydrogen fuel to generate electricity. However, the widespread use of hydrogen fueled fuel cells is generally limited by difficulty of hydrogen storage, transportation, and synthesis. The primary issue with hydrogen storage is that gaseous hydrogen contains low volumetric energy density. One promising option to address these difficulties is the use of ammonia (NH3) in solid oxide fuel cells (SOFCs), which allows for storage of a liquid fuel source, rather than the highly compressed gaseous fuel. Previous work has shown that a SOFC using ammonia fuel is highly capable of generating electricity at levels comparable to that of pure hydrogen fuel. The nickel within the SOFC, along with the high operating temperatures, assists in the thermal cracking of ammonia. However, one missing piece from our previous work is an investigation of ammonia utilization. As such, this work will seek to evaluate the utilization though an exhaust gas analysis using mass spectroscopy and gas chromatography. Additionally, the exhaust gas composition is monitored for the presence of NOx group gases. With the use of ammonia as the fuel source, there is a possibility that we see nitrogen bonding to oxygen ions at the triple-phase boundary (TPB), leading to NOx formation. Given the danger presented by these gases, we must be certain that the concentrations are negligible, or that there will be sufficient NOx reduction strategies in the exhaust stream. SOFC performance results will be briefly discussed, along with an analysis of exhaust composition using gas chromatography and mass spectroscopy to demonstrate utilization of ammonia and evaluate NOx generation relative to fuel cell electrical performance at various operating temperature.</description>
      <author>Cole Wilhelm, Aliza M. Willsey, Jeongmin Ahn</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/power2024-138521</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Sewage Sludge Stabilization, Pathogen Removal, and Biomass Production through Indigenous Microalgae Promoting Growth: A Sustainable Approach for Sewage Sludge Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling9050097</link>
      <description>Hajer Ben Hamed, Antoine Debuigne, Hetty KleinJan, Dominique Toye, Ang&#233;lique L&#233;onard, Recycling. 9(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403490659

                Sewage sludge (SS), a byproduct of wastewater treatment plants, poses significant environmental and health risks if not properly handled. Conventional approaches for SS stabilization often involve costly and energy-consuming processes. This study investigated the effect of promoting native microalgae growth in SS on its stabilization, pathogen bacteria removal, and valuable biomass production. The effect on settleability, filterability, and extracellular polymeric substances (EPSs) was examined as well. Experiments were conducted in photobioreactors (PBRs) without O2 supply and CO2 release under controlled parameters. The results show a significant improvement in SS stabilization, with a reduction of volatile solids (VSs) by 47.55%. Additionally, fecal coliforms and E. coli were efficiently removed by 2.25 log and 6.72 log, respectively. Moreover, Salmonella spp. was not detected after 15 days of treatment. The settleability was improved by 71.42%. However, a worsening of the sludge filterability properties was observed, likely due to a decrease in floc size following the reduction of protein content in the tightly bound EPS fraction. Microalgae biomass production was 16.56 mg/L/day, with a mean biomass of 0.35 g/L at the end of the batch treatment, representing 10.35% of the total final biomass. These findings suggest that promoting native microalgal growth in SS could be sustainable and cost-effective for SS stabilization, microalgal biomass production, and the enhancement of sludge-settling characteristics, notwithstanding potential filtration-related considerations.</description>
      <author>Hajer Ben Hamed, Antoine Debuigne, Hetty KleinJan, Dominique Toye, Ang&#233;lique L&#233;onard</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling9050097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Impact of Deforestation on Global Warming using System Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202458101023</link>
      <description>Balpreet Singh, Valerie Reddy, K. Ramakrishna Reddy, Pratibha Sharma, Mansi Nautiyal, S. Bhatnagar, Raisul Islam, Haider Alabdeli, E3S Web of Conferences. 581(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403613528

                This study aims to analyze the evolving dynamics of environmental sustainability via a thorough investigation of deforestation, atmospheric carbon levels, ecological equilibrium, and global climate trends. A conclusion reached is that a positive association exists between deforestation and increasing global temperatures, shown by a twenty percent rise in CO2 emissions. The loss of forests has markedly contributed to ecological imbalance, leading to detrimental impacts on biodiversity, with a total increase of fifteen percent in habitat damage. Initiatives aimed at reducing deforestation have resulted in a major 10% decrease in global carbon absorption rates, emphasizing forest regeneration and markedly diminishing carbon sequestration capabilities. The major focus is on the degradation of ecosystems, illustrating a collective struggle, shown by a 12% reduction in forest coverage and a 15% increase in global warming indices. These discoveries enhance the knowledge of environmental changes that may impact future climate systems. Furthermore, they provide crucial direction for environmental policy-makers and establish a basis for further research initiatives.</description>
      <author>Balpreet Singh, Valerie Reddy, K. Ramakrishna Reddy, Pratibha Sharma, Mansi Nautiyal, S. Bhatnagar, Raisul Islam, Haider Alabdeli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202458101023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging clean technologies: policy-driven cost reductions, implications
  and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.10824</link>
      <description>Mohamed Atouife, Jesse Jenkins, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403619772

                Hydrogen production from water electrolysis, direct air capture (DAC), and synthetic kerosene derived from hydrogen and CO2 (`e-kerosene') are expected to play an important role in global decarbonization efforts. So far, the economics of these nascent technologies hamper their market diffusion. However, a wave of recent policy support in the United States, Europe, China, and elsewhere is anticipated to drive their commercial liftoff and bring their costs down. To this end, we evaluate the potential cost reductions driven by policy-induced scale-up of these emerging technologies through 2030 using an experience curves approach accounting for both local and global learning effects. We then analyze the consequences of projected cost declines on the competitiveness of these nascent technologies compared to conventional fossil alternatives, where applicable, and highlight some of the tradeoffs associated with their expansion. Our findings indicate that enacted policies could lead to substantial capital cost reductions for electrolyzers. Nevertheless, electrolytic hydrogen production at $1-2/kg would still require some form of policy support. Given expected costs and experience curves, it is unlikely that liquid solvent DAC (L-DAC) scale-up will bring removal costs to stated targets of $100/tCO2, though a $200/tCO2 may eventually be within reach. We also underscore the importance of tackling methane leakage for natural gas-powered L-DAC: unmitigated leaks amplify net removal costs, exacerbate the investment requirements to reach targeted costs, and cast doubt on L-DAC's role in the clean energy transition. Lastly, despite reductions in electrolysis and L-DAC costs, e-kerosene remains considerably more expensive than fossil jet fuel. The economics of e-kerosene and the resources required for production raise questions about the fuel's ultimate viability as a decarbonization tool for aviation.</description>
      <author>Mohamed Atouife, Jesse Jenkins</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.10824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is methane the 'climate culprit'? Fixing the 'Broken Record' while
  unmasking the dangers of using imprecise, long-term GWP for methane to
  address the climate emergency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.06212</link>
      <description>Roger W. Bryenton, Farrukh Chishtie, Mujtaba Hassan, Tom P. Mommsen, Devyani Singh, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403593251

                Methane (CH4) is a potent greenhouse gas (GHG) with a short atmospheric half-life (~8.4 years) and a high short-term impact on global warming, significantly higher than CO2 (Kleinberg, 2020; Balcombe et al., 2018). Traditional metrics such as the 100-year Global Warming Potential (GWP100) obscure methane's short-term, negative climatic effects, potentially leading to inadequate policy responses (Kleinberg, 2020). This letter examines the limitations of GWP100 in capturing methane's true climate impact, explores alternative metrics, and discusses the implications of underreporting methane emissions. We highlight the necessity of adopting a more immediate perspective on methane to accelerate climate emergency action, while noting the adverse effects of the rapid growth rate of methane emissions on reduction efforts. Additionally, we hope that in the immediate future, during COP29, policymakers will adopt actions that give appropriate attention to methane's short-term warming potential to dramatically reduce emissions and address the immediate climate crisis.</description>
      <author>Roger W. Bryenton, Farrukh Chishtie, Mujtaba Hassan, Tom P. Mommsen, Devyani Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.06212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melatonin Rinsing Treatment Associated with Storage in a Controlled Atmosphere Improves the Antioxidant Capacity and Overall Quality of Lemons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/foods13203298</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Eric Zheng, Ziqin Lin, Ze Miao, Yuhang Li, Shenqiang Hu, Yanan Gao, Yuqian Jiang, Lingling Pang, Xihong Li, Foods. 13(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403484294

                Antioxidant capacity is one of the most important biological activities in fruits and vegetables and is closely related to human health. In this study, &#8216;Eureka&#8217; lemons were used as experimental materials and stored at 7&#8211;8 &#176;C MT (melatonin, 200 &#956;mol, soaked for 15 min) and CA (controlled atmosphere, 2&#8211;3% O2 + 15&#8211;16% CO2) individually or in combination for 30 d. The changes in lemon fruits&#8217; basic physicochemical properties, enzyme activities, and antioxidant capacities were studied. Comparing the combined treatment to the control, the outcomes demonstrated a significant reduction in weight loss, firmness, stomatal opening, and inhibition of polyphenol oxidase (PPO) and peroxidase (POD) activities. Additionally, the combined treatment maintained high levels of titratable acidity (TA), vitamin C (VC), total phenolic content (TPC), and antioxidant capacity and preserved the lemon aroma. Meanwhile, the correlation between fruit color, aroma compounds, and antioxidant capacity was revealed, providing valuable insights into the postharvest preservation of lemons. In conclusion, the combined treatment (MT + CA) was effective in maintaining the quality and antioxidant capacity of lemons.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Eric Zheng, Ziqin Lin, Ze Miao, Yuhang Li, Shenqiang Hu, Yanan Gao, Yuqian Jiang, Lingling Pang, Xihong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/foods13203298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use of Edaphic Bioindicators to Mitigate Environmental Impact and Improve Agricultural Research and Training</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/soilsystems8040107</link>
      <description>Ana Cano-Ort&#237;z, Jos&#233; Carlos Pi&#241;ar Fuentes, J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Eus&#233;bio Cano, Soil Systems. 8(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403516759

                The world is currently experiencing unsustainable development, which poses significant risks to global society. In response, there is a growing advocacy for sustainable development across all sectors, driven by social resilience. This shift is fostering substantial socio-environmental tensions. However, the combined power of scientific research and social education has the potential to reverse this trend. Transitioning from an unsustainable territorial model to a sustainable one is both feasible and economically profitable. This transition can be achieved through knowledge of soil bioindicators, which provide valuable information about soil nutrient content. By understanding these indicators, nutrient inputs can be tailored, reducing or eliminating pollutants such as excessive fertilizers, herbicides, and pesticides. Training experts and raising social awareness through education on new research are essential steps in this process. For decades, it has been recognized that globalization, industrialization, and population growth have driven unsustainable development, leading to degraded agroecosystems. To address this issue, government institutions are promoting sustainability through ecological agriculture and CO2 reduction, both of which can be supported by the use of soil bioindicators.</description>
      <author>Ana Cano-Ort&#237;z, Jos&#233; Carlos Pi&#241;ar Fuentes, J. Pe&#241;a&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Eus&#233;bio Cano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/soilsystems8040107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-pronged strategies for enhancing building envelopes toward nearly-zero energy in hot climatic regions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2631-8695/ad898a</link>
      <description>Mohanad M. Ibrahim, Micheal A. William, A. A. Salama, Mona F.Moussa, Mar&#237;a Jos&#233; Su&#225;rez&#8208;L&#243;pez, Engineering Research Express. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403590010

                Abstract Growing concerns about climate change and rising energy demands necessitate advancements in building energy efficiency. This study investigates the effectiveness of radiative coatings and thermal insulation, both individually and combined, in reducing energy consumption and carbon footprint for buildings in hot and humid climates. This research contributes to a growing body of knowledge by comprehensively evaluating the combined effects of these strategies. A comparative analysis was conducted using data on energy usage and carbon emissions.&amp;#xD;The research highlights the effectiveness of envelope-enhancing techniques in reducing energy consumption and carbon emissions. The application of radiative coating led to a significant 13.1% decrease in energy usage, totaling 681.95 MWh, and corresponding emissions of 482.14 tons of CO2. Radiative coating offers the most cost-effective solution with an LCOS of $0.045/kWh. When integrating thermal insulation with radiative coating, there was a substantial 12.0% reduction in energy consumption, amounting to 690.39 MWh, and emissions of 488.11 tons of CO2. The integrated model provides significant energy savings at a slightly higher LCOS of $0.052/kWh, making it a balanced choice between efficiency and cost-effectiveness compared to using thermal insulation alone. Moreover, the study emphasizes that the combination of Glazing Integrated Photovoltaic (GIPV) with radiative coating can lead to the creation of nearly zero-energy buildings, resulting in a significant energy savings of 34.9%. These results underscore the efficacy of these technologies in achieving significant energy savings and environmental benefits.&amp;#xD;This study demonstrates that radiative coatings significantly reduce energy consumption and carbon footprints. The combined method with thermal insulation reduces energy, suggesting further optimization strategies in hot and humid conditions. The results of this investigation recommend utilizing Glazing Integrated Photovoltaic (GIPV) to achieve nearly zero-energy buildings. Such integrated solutions not only improve energy efficiency but also make a substantial contribution to environmental sustainability in the building sector.&amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Mohanad M. Ibrahim, Micheal A. William, A. A. Salama, Mona F.Moussa, Mar&#237;a Jos&#233; Su&#225;rez&#8208;L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2631-8695/ad898a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental and Socio-Economic Impact Assessment of Renewable Energy Using Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32996/jefas.2024.6.5.13</link>
      <description>Md Fakhrul Islam Sumon, Md Osiujjaman, MD Azam Khan, Arifur Rahman, Md. Shazib Uddin, Laxmi Prasad Pant, Pravakar Debnath, Journal of Economics Finance and Accounting Studies. 6(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403567651

                Renewable energy sources, such as solar, hydro, wind, and geothermal energy, have emerged as key alternatives to fossil fuels in combating climate change and addressing energy security concerns in the USA and ad worldwide. Strategic use of this renewable resource is important not only for carbon emission reduction and improvement of environmental sustainability but also for maintaining future energy supplies. At the same time, such transition raises thorough assessments of environmental and socio-economic impacts. Machine learning (ML) models offer a powerful tool for predicting and analyzing such impacts, allowing for more efficient decision-making and long-term planning. These models are supposed to analyze patterns in energy production, land use, and emissions to make a more dynamic and predictive understanding of how renewable energy adoption influences CO2 levels. The principal aim of this research project was to develop and curate machine learning algorithms for predicting CO2 emissions based on renewable energy data, using the knowledge to better understand how solar, wind, hydro, and geothermal energy systems affect environmental outcomes. The predictive models developed in this research would serve as useful tools for the policymakers and major stakeholders in decision-making on investments in energy infrastructure and characterization of regulatory frameworks. These datasets for this research project were retrieved from several prominent institutions, including governmental agencies, international organizations such as the International Energy Agency-IEA and the World Bank, satellite data repositories, and USA environmental monitoring agencies. For this research project, 3 machine learning algorithms in the experiment were used, namely Logistic Regression, XG-Boost, and Random Forest. Amongst these three, the linear regression model gave the best performance, as it had the least MSE; indicating that its predictive capability was impressive. The comparative analysis of renewable energy projects in Germany, China, and California underlines that effective policy-making plays a very decisive role in the transition toward sustainable energy.</description>
      <author>Md Fakhrul Islam Sumon, Md Osiujjaman, MD Azam Khan, Arifur Rahman, Md. Shazib Uddin, Laxmi Prasad Pant, Pravakar Debnath</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32996/jefas.2024.6.5.13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Greenhouse Gas Emissions in Oil Extraction: A Case Study of Solar Energy Utilization in PetroFarah</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/223370-ms</link>
      <description>Amr El Bosaty, Shady Khafagy, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403586936

                Abstract Oil extraction emits considerable amounts of greenhouse gases (GHG), which is the main driver of climate change, as GHG emissions trap heat in the atmosphere and contribute significantly to global warming and climate change phenomena. Climate change is a crucial challenge facing the globe that requires urgent and coordinated action from all countries. The United Nations took the lead in addressing climate change and its consequences, through various conventions, agreements and initiatives. The most important ones are the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), the Kyoto Protocol, and the Paris Agreement. The Paris Agreement aims to limit global warming to well below 2&#176;C above pre-industrial levels, and pursue efforts to limit it to 1.5&#176;C. In this endeavor, Egypt is committed to share in the implementation of climate actions. Accordingly, Egypt has prepared a national sustainable development strategy (Egypt Vision 2030) in alignment with the global agenda of the sustainable development goals (SDGs) and the Paris Agreement on climate change. The vision has set various indicators and targets to measure the progress of implementation, in which the target of increasing the share of renewable energy in electricity production to 37% by 2030 is proposed to limit the impact of climate change. Most recently, Egypt has organized the Conference of Parties (COP 27) in Sharm el-Sheikh with the aim of discussing and taking action regarding the implementation of the Paris Agreement and the progress of achieving SDGs. One of the main results of COP 27 is to call for accelerating the deployment of renewable energy resources. In that context and being aware of the climate change impacts potentially resulting from the operations of their assets, PetroFarah (PF) in a joint venture with Apex International Energy, and with the support of the Egyptian Petroleum Company (EGPC), has initiated a pilot project to utilize solar energy in the artificial pumping of oil in one of its operating wells. The project entailed the installation of a PV solar unit with a capacity of 72.9 kW, without a battery system, to operate a sucker rod pump (SRP) at Farah-8 well. The main aim of the project is to reduce the diesel consumption utilized in the diesel generator at the well location and subsequently, reduce the GHG emissions associated with the operation of the diesel generator. Calculations of GHG emissions from the pilot project indicated that implementing the PV solar project could save about 44% of generators&#8217; diesel consumption at well sites and subsequently 44% of GHG emissions resulting from the emissions of these generators. It should be pointed out that these results should be taken with caution, as the studied well is a small producer using a Sucker Rod Pump (SRP) working at a slow round per minute (RPM), while other wells may be working at different RPMs resulting in different fuel consumption. Also, the estimated GHG reduction is for one type of oil pumping system, which is SRP, and this case study could not be generalized for other types of pumps such as electrostatic submersible pumps (ESP). The estimated GHG reduction is based on the daily and annual consumption and production data obtained from 2022 data, which could be subject to change with the variation in production. The estimated GHG reduction is also based on the operation of the PV solar unit during the daytime, as the current setting does not include a battery for operating during night-time. Accordingly, the installation of a battery system may further reduce Scope 1 GHG emissions. Moreover, the efficiency of the diesel generator and power transmission is not taken as a factor in the provided estimate. Accordingly, variable savings could be obtained from the different diesel generators / SRPs connections depending on their efficiency. Overall, the pilot project was found to have the potential to have a net reduction of 0.5 kg CO2 eq. for each barrel of oil produced (bop) which is equivalent to approximately 50 tons of CO2 eq. for each 100,000 bop.</description>
      <author>Amr El Bosaty, Shady Khafagy</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/223370-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warm Arctic-Cold Eurasia pattern helps predict spring wildfire burned area in West Siberia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53470-4</link>
      <description>Zhicong Yin, Yijia Zhang, Shengping He, Huijun Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403556988

                Extreme wildfires have devastating impacts on multiple fronts, and associated carbon greatly heats the earth's climate. Whether and how to predict wildfires becomes a critical question. In this study, we find that the preceding-winter "warm Arctic-cold Eurasia" (WACE) pattern significantly enlarges the spring burned area in West Siberia. The winter WACE and accompanying snow reduction result in dryness and vegetation exposure in West Siberia in spring, increasing fire risks. A multiple linear regression model is constructed that successfully predicts the spring burned area in West Siberia one season in advance (R-squared coefficient=0.64). The same predictors also well predict the corresponding fire carbon emissions. Independent predictions for spring burned area in 2019 and 2020 are very close to observations, with a mean absolute percentage error of only 3.0%. The findings of this study provide a possibility for guarding humans against extreme wildfires and predicting sharp rises in carbon emissions. The authors show that the winter "warm Arctic-cold Eurasia" pattern significantly enhances spring fire activity in West Siberia, contributing to the prediction of wildfire burned area, and resulting CO2 emissions, one season in advance.</description>
      <author>Zhicong Yin, Yijia Zhang, Shengping He, Huijun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53470-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Fuels for Decarbonising UK Rural Transport</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/encyclopedia4040101</link>
      <description>Al-Amin Abba Dabo, Andrew Gough, F. Frank Alparslan, Encyclopedia. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403513454

                Decarbonising transport is a crucial element of the UK&#8217;s strategy to achieve net-zero carbon emissions by 2050, as the transport sector is currently the largest contributor to the UK&#8217;s greenhouse gas emissions. Rural communities face distinct challenges in this effort due to their reliance on internal combustion engines (ICEs) across vehicles and machinery essential for daily life, including farming equipment and private transport. While the upcoming ban on new petrol and diesel vehicles paves the way for the adoption of Electric Vehicles (EVs), this solution may not fully address the unique needs of rural areas where infrastructure limitations and specific mobility requirements pose significant barriers. In this context, synthetic fuels, produced using renewable energy sources, offer a potential alternative. These fuels can be used directly in existing internal combustion engines without requiring major modifications and have the added benefit of reducing overall greenhouse gas emissions by capturing CO2 during production. This entry explores the potential advantages of adopting synthetic fuels, particularly in rural areas, and examines how community-based buying cooperatives could support their wider use through bulk purchasing, cost reduction, and community empowerment.</description>
      <author>Al-Amin Abba Dabo, Andrew Gough, F. Frank Alparslan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/encyclopedia4040101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Nigerian residential dwellings: bottom-up approach and scenario analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5334/bc.452</link>
      <description>Chibuikem Chrysogonus Nwagwu, &#350;ahin Ak&#305;n, Edgar G. Hertwich, Buildings and Cities. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403650024

                Nigeria&#8217;s residential buildings consume a substantial amount of the country&#8217;s energy, so achieving a net-zero building sector with a rapidly growing population is a key challenge. To bridge the gap in research at a national level and support Nigeria&#8217;s commitment to an unconditional 20% reduction in emissions by 2030, this study develops bottom-up archetype models of different residential building typologies to estimate the energy and material use of Nigerian residential buildings. This creates an overview of the residential stock and how different archetypes perform. The study calculates a baseline energy and material use of Nigeria&#8217;s residential building stock using the BuildME tool and converts these data into CO2 emissions using a life-cycle assessment. Scenarios are modelled for 2020. Nigeria&#8217;s residential dwellings use approximately 0.3 kt of material per dwelling over a lifetime of 50 years and 2404 kWh/yr of energy per dwelling. Annualised, dwellings emit 2500 kgCO2-eq per dwelling due to material and energy use. Scenarios proposed for meeting Nigeria&#8217;s emissions targets will require improved energy efficiency, decarbonising the building envelope through a shift in construction materials and decarbonising grid electricity. Policy relevance This study provides a comprehensive analysis of the energy and material use of residential buildings in Nigeria, focusing on achieving the country&#8217;s commitment to a 20% reduction in emissions by 2030. It employs a bottom-up approach to model energy and material use, revealing the peculiarities of the dwelling stock across Nigeria&#8217;s four climatic zones. The study explores the implications of different policy scenarios on sustainable housing. The research suggests that meeting Nigeria&#8217;s emissions targets requires improved energy efficiency, a shift in construction materials and decarbonisation of grid electricity. It also highlights the potential benefits of a policy switch to materials such as timber, earthen blocks, adobe bricks and clay, which could significantly reduce construction-related emissions. These changes could improve the quality of life of households in Nigeria, combat climate change on a global scale and bring economic advantages to Nigeria.</description>
      <author>Chibuikem Chrysogonus Nwagwu, &#350;ahin Ak&#305;n, Edgar G. Hertwich</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5334/bc.452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Freight Transport Emissions Responsibility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c05658</link>
      <description>Jacob Fry, Keiichiro Kanemoto, Alastair Fraser, Keisuke Nansai, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403549224

                The transportation of freight by land, sea and air underpins the complex network of global trade in physical commodities. Greenhouse gas emissions from freight transportation are a significant component of global emissions and are predicted to grow in coming decades. However, the inclusion of freight transport in emissions accounts and environmental impact studies is often incomplete. Both data availability and difficulties in allocating freight emissions to specific commodity trades contributes to this. In this study, international freight movements by transport mode are estimated from the bottom-up by imputing global freight transport routes. Emissions are estimated from these freight movements and integrated with a global multiregional input&#8211;output model. This enables the calculation of carbon footprints that are complete with respect to freight emissions. We estimate that global freight transport emissions contributed 2.8 Gt CO2-equiv in 2012, or about 41% of total transport emissions. In general, freight footprints contribute about 9% to national emissions footprints. While trade in physical commodities (such as construction materials, food and fossil fuels) are associated with the largest embodied freight emissions, services (such as public administration, education and health) also require significant freight transport. Using a consumption-based allocation of freight transport emissions allows the decarbonisation of other sectors to be complementary to the decarbonisation of transport through reduction in demand, for example through material efficiency strategies. To drive decarbonisation in maritime transport it is critical to include bunker emissions in national emissions inventories, thereby completing the system boundary.</description>
      <author>Jacob Fry, Keiichiro Kanemoto, Alastair Fraser, Keisuke Nansai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c05658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Pulsed Neutron Logging Behind Casing in Rig-Less Operations Enables Bypass Pay Identification and Hydrocarbon Quantification for Abu Qir in Offshore Egypt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/223355-ms</link>
      <description>Renata Gomes, Maria Leticia Vazquez, Amr Labib, Mohamed El-Dabbour, Hany Shalaby, Khaled Elshater, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403587016

                Abstract Objectives/Scope This paper exemplifies how a sophisticated pulsed neutron logging technology has proven extremely valuable in locating and analyzing a gas-bearing reservoir in an environment with complex completions and low-formation water salinity. For oilfield operating companies, the most promising sources of future earnings are wells that have already been drilled and are producing. These wells must continue to produce at optimal economic rates throughout their lives. Understanding reservoirs' current fluid saturation situation is a pivotal step in planning a well workover to boost production when required. This understanding is often obtained through formation evaluation based on cased-hole (CH) logging. Traditionally, Abu Qir-ENERGEAN operations are conducted by offshore rigs. Mobilizing a jack-up rig without full assurance of economic gain is costly, inefficient, and increases the company's CO2 footprint. An existing targeted well comprises two reservoir sections; Abu-Qir is required to evaluate the potential of the reservoir situation and re-complete the well to add the upper reservoir section. The targeted well was crucial to the client, and the confirmation of bypassed hydrocarbon would be the client's trigger for re-completing the well. Due to the complexity of the environment, a new generation of pulsed neutron logging tool providing fast neutron cross-section measurement (FNXS) that is sensitive to gas volume was the best option for the job. Methods, Procedures, Process The proven strategy of employing an innovative pulsed neutron logging and interpretation technology lowers operational risks and costs as it could be deployed in a rig-less environment. A rich dataset was obtained, which included capture and inelastic elemental spectroscopy, fast neutron cross section (FNXS), and self-compensated sigma and neutron porosity logs. The logs were interpreted by combining the neutron porosity and FNXS with matrix characteristics and mineral dry weight fractions from elemental spectroscopy processing. Results, Observations, Conclusions The logging objectives were successfully met, and valuable information about the reservoir was determined efficiently in a rig-less environment. This allowed the operator to plan for the workover operations while reducing the cost of rig operations. The production of this well had significantly increased after the implementation of the workover plan. The collaboration and technical discussion to run the new generation pulsed neutron logging tool directly resulted in eliminating uncertainty in operations and reducing emissions, as the tool was deployed rig-less. This was also a great cost savings and a key de- risking factor for proceeding with the well activity, knowing that the hydrocarbon saturation still existed behind the casing. The direct results of running the new generation pulsed neutron logging tool rig-less were time-saving and accurate hydrocarbon estimation, which positively impacted suitability and resulted in a major reduction of CO2.</description>
      <author>Renata Gomes, Maria Leticia Vazquez, Amr Labib, Mohamed El-Dabbour, Hany Shalaby, Khaled Elshater</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/223355-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different Approaches for Hybridization Between Solid Oxide Fuel Cells and Internal Combustion Engines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/power2024-138460</link>
      <description>Ahmed G. Elkafas, M. Rivarolo, Luca Mantelli, Stefano Barberis, Jos&#233; Col&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Nana Zhou, David Tucker, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403647392

                Abstract The paper explores the hybridization of Solid Oxide Fuel Cell (SOFC) and Internal combustion Engine (ICE), It addresses design point analysis for SOFC-ICE hybrid system applications, considering the early adoption of technology. The study investigates different design cases for a 1 MW turbocharged SOFC-ICE system for marine applications in which the SOFC&#8217;s power contribution is fixed at 20% to reduce the risk and expenses associated with early technology adoption. The results show that the maximum efficiency of the SOFC-ICE system is 49.4% at 70% fuel utilization and 1.1% methane concentration at the anode inlet of SOFC. This integration provides an efficiency improvement of 5% over the standalone ICE. Moreover, the results demonstrated that the SOFC-ICE system might provide a maximum reduction in CO2 emissions of 17.6% over existing marine natural gas engines. However, the results prove the insensitivity of system efficiency to both SOFC fuel utilization and methane composition in the anode inlet. Because the system efficiency variation is no more than 1.41% or 1.1% when varying fuel utilization from 70% to 90% or varying methane concentration from 1.1% to 30.7%, respectively. Based on these findings, a SOFC-ICE hybrid system with complete external reforming and very low fuel consumption can be designed for optimal performance. Both would lengthen the SOFC stacks&#8217; lifetime and lower SOFC design complexity and cost. These results are compared to an optimized hybrid design for stationary applications where the SOFC represented between 78% and 93% of the total system power. Intuitively, optimizing the power split in the system design at the highest fuel utilization (90%) provides higher efficiencies by 13% than fixing the SOFC power share at 20%.</description>
      <author>Ahmed G. Elkafas, M. Rivarolo, Luca Mantelli, Stefano Barberis, Jos&#233; Col&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Nana Zhou, David Tucker</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/power2024-138460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underwater Techniques in Gastrointestinal Endoscopy: Diving into the Depths</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers16203535</link>
      <description>Sandro Sferrazza, Giulio Calabrese, Roberta Maselli, Rui Morais, Antonio Facciorusso, Georgios Mavrogenis, Roberto Di Mitri, Alessandro Repici, Marcello Maida, Cancers. 16(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403604675

                The endoscopic resection of gastrointestinal tract lesions embraces different types of techniques, ranging from conventional polypectomy/endoscopic mucosal resection (EMR) to the field of third-space endoscopy, including endoscopic submucosal dissection (ESD), full-thickness resection and peroral endoscopic myotomy (POEM). Parallelly, the advent of underwater techniques has served as an add-on for both basic and advanced procedures, since its first report in 2012. We aimed to provide a comprehensive update on the state of the art about the feasibility of underwater basic and advanced techniques for GI endoscopy. Underwater EMR (U-EMR) has proved effective and safe in treating &gt; 10 mm sessile or flat or all-size recurrent colonic lesions. Conversely, although data show good effectiveness and safety for &lt;10 mm lesions, it is preferred when high-grade dysplasia is suspected, favouring cold snare polypectomy for all other cases. Moreover, promising data are emerging regarding the feasibility of U-ESD for difficult-to-resect colonic lesions. U-EMR represents a standard of care for treating &lt; 25 mm superficial non-ampullary duodenal epithelial tumours. Data regarding oesophageal, gastric and ampullary lesions remains limited to small cohorts. Finally, using water immersion for POEM has shown a reduction in procedure time compared to the CO2 insufflation technique for vessel coagulation, albeit in a single-centre experience. Based on these results, U-EMR has become a standard for treating intermediate-size colonic and non-ampullary duodenal lesions, as highlighted also in the European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy guidelines. Promising results have been shown in third-space endoscopy studies, even though further prospective studies are awaited to standardise the technique for both ESD and POEM.</description>
      <author>Sandro Sferrazza, Giulio Calabrese, Roberta Maselli, Rui Morais, Antonio Facciorusso, Georgios Mavrogenis, Roberto Di Mitri, Alessandro Repici, Marcello Maida</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers16203535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Productivity and Fruit Quality of &#8216;Mutsu&#8217; Apple Orchard by Dwarfing Treatments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14101838</link>
      <description>Maria Ma&#322;achowska, Tomasz Majak, Tomasz Krupa, K. Tomala, Agriculture. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403585169

                The aim of this 2022 study was to evaluate the effect of tree growth-limiting treatments on the tree yield and quality of &#8216;Mutsu&#8217; apples. The experiment was established on 7-year-old trees on M.9 rootstock in a commercial orchard in Wilga near Warsaw. Growth-limiting treatments included unilateral root pruning, spraying the trees with Regalis Plus 10 WG at various times, and spraying with Flordimex 480 SL. Eight combinations were used, with four replicates of 20 trees per repetition. The measurements included fruit set, length of this year&#8217;s shoots, yield per tree, average fruit weight, and the size structure of the yield. The distinctive physiological status of the apples was assessed directly after harvest, directly after 8 months of storage under CA conditions (1.5% CO2, 1.5% O2, 1 &#176;C, &gt;92% RH) and after an additional 7 days of shelf-life. Spraying trees with Regalis Plus 10 WG from the balloon stage onwards, irrespective of the treatment with root pruning, was most effective in both inhibiting long-stem growth and increasing tree yield (by almost two times) by increasing the number of apples per tree. The growth response of long-stemmed apple trees to both unilateral root pruning and Ethephon spray was significantly lower than it was to Regalis Plus 10 WG spray and had relatively little effect on their yield. Regalis Plus 10 WG resulted in a clear reduction in average fruit weight (by about 100 g), which, in the case of the large-fruited cultivar &#8216;Mutsu&#8217;, should be seen as an advantage. Its application from the balloon stage onwards promoted higher apple firmness at harvest and after simulated handling preceded by long-term storage.</description>
      <author>Maria Ma&#322;achowska, Tomasz Majak, Tomasz Krupa, K. Tomala</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14101838</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
