<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:43:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Digitalization and net-zero carbon: The role of industrial robots towards carbon dioxide emission reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141820</link>
      <description>Weizhi Yao, Liang Liu, Hidemichi Fujii, Lianshui Li, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393039058

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weizhi Yao, Liang Liu, Hidemichi Fujii, Lianshui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141820</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom anchored on curved boron nitride fullerene surface as efficient electrocatalyst for carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114040</link>
      <description>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Molecular Catalysis. 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393116736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium carbide sealed cadmium sulfide quantum dots on carbon, oxygen-doped boron nitride for enhanced and durable photochemical carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.139</link>
      <description>Zhangfeng Shen, Yang Yang, LI Yu-ji, Xiaohua Cheng, Huayang Zhang, Xuhui Zou, Ming Qiu, Hong Huang, Hongge Pan, Qineng Xia, Ge Zhang, Yongyong Cao, Jing Gao, Yangang Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393131989

                Despite great efforts that have been made, photocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction still faces enormous challenges due to the sluggish kinetics or disadvantageous thermodynamics. Herein, cadmium sulfide quantum dots (CdS QDs) were loaded onto carbon, oxygen-doped boron nitride (BN) and encapsulated by titanium carbide (Ti3C2, MXene) layers to construct a ternary composite. The uniform distribution of CdS QDs and the tight interfacial interaction among the three components could be achieved by adjusting the loading amounts of CdS QDs and MXene. The ternary 100MX/CQ/BN sample gave a productive rate of 2.45 and 0.44 &#956;mol g-1 h&#8722;1 for carbon monoxide (CO) and methane (CH4), respectively. This CO yield is 1.93 and 6.13 times higher than that of CdS QDs/BN and BN counterparts. The photocatalytic durability of the ternary composite is significantly improved compared with CdS QDs/BN because MXene can protect CdS from photocorrosion. The characterization results demonstrate that the excellent CO2 adsorption and activation capabilities of BN, the visible light absorption of CdS QDs, the good conductivity of MXene and the well-matched energy band alignment jointly promote the photocatalytic performance of the ternary catalyst.</description>
      <author>Zhangfeng Shen, Yang Yang, LI Yu-ji, Xiaohua Cheng, Huayang Zhang, Xuhui Zou, Ming Qiu, Hong Huang, Hongge Pan, Qineng Xia, Ge Zhang, Yongyong Cao, Jing Gao, Yangang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction via DNA-Directed Catalyst Immobilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.3c00823</link>
      <description>Gang Fan, Nathan Corbin, Minju Chung, Thomas M. Gill, Evan G. Moore, Amruta A. Karbelkar, Ariel L. Furst, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393150984

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gang Fan, Nathan Corbin, Minju Chung, Thomas M. Gill, Evan G. Moore, Amruta A. Karbelkar, Ariel L. Furst</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.3c00823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineered &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; Whole Cell-Mediated Electro-Biocatalysis for Carbon Dioxide to Formic Acid Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08129</link>
      <description>Hongbo Shi, Meng-Xi Fu, Shu Yuan, Yao Lu, Yang Zhuan, Chao Ye, Lunguang Yao, Chuang Xue, Cun-Duo Tang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393164149

                The conversion of CO2 into a valuable chemical fuel could help reduce its effect on global warming. However, the utilization of CO2 by biological transformations is challenging because of the lack of enzymes exhibiting high catalytic activity toward CO2 reduction. In this work, three NAD+/W-containing formate dehydrogenases (FDHs) were discovered, expressed, and characterized. In addition, we used PbFDH, which displays high catalytic activity toward CO2 reduction, as a biocatalyst to convert CO2 to formic acid through whole-cell biocatalysis and electro-biocatalysis. The specific activities of DaFDH, PbFDH, and CsFDH increased by 68.1, 100.0, and 18.7 times, respectively, compared with that of ClFDH reported with high catalytic efficiency. Furthermore, this paper presents a preliminary discussion of the catalytic mechanism of FDHs for CO2 reduction based on their structures. The yield of formic acid obtained from CO2 reduction using electro-biocatalysis under aerobic conditions reaches up to 4.1 mmol/L/h, without any cofactor NADH and hydrogen gas. This study also demonstrates and compares the performances of NAD+/W-containing and NAD+-dependent FDHs in whole-cell biocatalysis and electro-biocatalysis. The findings of this study provide a meaningful foundation for the conversion of CO2 into a value-added chemical fuel.</description>
      <author>Hongbo Shi, Meng-Xi Fu, Shu Yuan, Yao Lu, Yang Zhuan, Chao Ye, Lunguang Yao, Chuang Xue, Cun-Duo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas Diffusion Electrodes (GDEs) for Carbon Dioxide (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) Reduction in Microfluidic Cells: Towards a Fluid Dynamics Assisted Rational Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad377f</link>
      <description>Melanie Colet-Lagrille, Sergio Gonz&#225;lez-Poggini, Carol Salazar-Espinoza, Benito S&#225;nchez, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393164782

                Abstract The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) for the generation of multicarbon (C2+) products with high commercial value &#8211; e.g., ethanol and ethylene &#8211; is gaining growing interest due to the successful implementation of laboratory scale technologies that can reach high current densities (&gt;500 mA cm-2) and Faradaic efficiencies (&gt;60%), using a simplified approach in terms of configuration and cost. This is the case of microfluidic cells, low-temperature electrochemical flow systems which optimal operation sustains on the enhancement of the mass and charge transfer phenomena taking place at the gas diffusion electrode (GDE) | aqueous electrolyte interface where CO2 molecules are selectively transformed at the surface of the catalyst layer. &amp;#xD;This work presents an up-to-date overview of materials and operational conditions for microfluidic-type systems, providing significant enlightenment on the effects that the phenomena occurring at the GDE | electrolyte interface have over the CO2 reduction reaction kinetics towards the generation of C2+ products. It is shown that the integration of computational methods (particularly, density functional theory and computational fluid dynamics) to conventional experimental approaches is an effective strategy to elucidate the reactions mechanisms and mass/charge transfer trends determining the enhanced design of GDEs and the GDE | electrolyte interface.</description>
      <author>Melanie Colet-Lagrille, Sergio Gonz&#225;lez-Poggini, Carol Salazar-Espinoza, Benito S&#225;nchez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad377f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyzer and Catalyst Engineering for Acidic CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393057305</link>
      <description>Alessandro Perazio, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393057305

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alessandro Perazio</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393057305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical Catalytic Co2 Reduction Enhanced by In-Doped Gan and Combined with Vibration Energy Harvester Driving Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4772115</link>
      <description>Mingxiang Zhang, Li Wen, Shanghao Gu, Weihan Xu, Zhouguang Lu, Fei Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393143337

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingxiang Zhang, Li Wen, Shanghao Gu, Weihan Xu, Zhouguang Lu, Fei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4772115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic reduction of simulated industrial CO2 and CO mixtures: Revising chronoamperometry to enable selective gas mixture reduction via cyclic voltammetry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150602</link>
      <description>Wen Qian Chen, Foo Jit Loong Cyrus, Li Ya Ge, Andrei Veksha, Wei Ping Chan, Yafei Shen, Grzegorz Lisak, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393088089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen Qian Chen, Foo Jit Loong Cyrus, Li Ya Ge, Andrei Veksha, Wei Ping Chan, Yafei Shen, Grzegorz Lisak</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond CO2 Reduction: Electrochemical C&#8210;N Coupling Reaction for Organonitrogen Compound Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101491</link>
      <description>Dohun Kim, Jungsu Eo, Siak Piang Lim, Dohun Kim, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393071276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dohun Kim, Jungsu Eo, Siak Piang Lim, Dohun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Engineered Catalyst Microenvironments using Conductive Polymers during Electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101490</link>
      <description>Suyun Lee, Jun-Hee Seo, Chanyeon Kim, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393084614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suyun Lee, Jun-Hee Seo, Chanyeon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101490</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO in flow cell device by a pristine Cu5tz6-cluster-based metal-organic framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00189c</link>
      <description>Zijing Li, Yingtong Lv, Haoliang Huang, Zijian Li, Tao Li, Linjuan Zhang, Jianqiang Wang, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393060748

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO is a powerful approach to achieve carbon neutrality. Herein, we report a five-nuclear copper cluster-based metal&#8211;azolate framework CuTz-1 as an electrocatalyst for the...</description>
      <author>Zijing Li, Yingtong Lv, Haoliang Huang, Zijian Li, Tao Li, Linjuan Zhang, Jianqiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00189c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot two-step reduction of CO2 with amines and NaBH4 to N-substituted compounds at atmospheric pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102741</link>
      <description>Junhong Wang, B. P. Wang, Xuehong Wei, Zhiqiang Guo, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393124559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junhong Wang, B. P. Wang, Xuehong Wei, Zhiqiang Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-dopant and O-vacancy of mesoporous ZnO nanosheets induce high efficiency and selectivity of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coco.2024.101890</link>
      <description>Ying Wang, Youngeun Kang, Yuanxin Miao, Min Jia, S. Alice Long, Lipeng Diao, Lijie Zhang, Daohao Li, Guanglei Wu, Composites Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393166182

                Surface engineering can adjust the electronic properties of catalysts, thereby boosting their electrocatalytic performances. Herein, S-doped and O-vacant mesoporous ZnO nanosheets (ZnO-VO-S) were synthesized through the plasma-treatment method, exhibiting highly electrocatalytic selectivity and activity in the conversion of CO2 to CO. Synchrotron X-ray absorption fine structure (XAFS) investigations were used to further clarify the valence state and local coordination structure of Zn, concretely affirming the reduced electron density of Zn in ZnO-VO-S. Specifically, at &#8722;1.1 V vs. RHE, the as-prepared ZnO-VO-S demonstrated a high Faradaic efficiency of 90%. Experiments and density functional theory (DFT) suggest that the electron deficiency of Zn caused by the introduction of S dopant and O vacancy, reduces the energy barrier of CO2 to CO by improving the adsorption behavior of the intermediate *COOH.</description>
      <author>Ying Wang, Youngeun Kang, Yuanxin Miao, Min Jia, S. Alice Long, Lipeng Diao, Lijie Zhang, Daohao Li, Guanglei Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coco.2024.101890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faster Kinetics and High Selectivity for Electrolytic Reduction of CO2 with Zn0/Zn2+ Interface of ZnO/ZnAl2O4 Derived from Hydrotalcite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04648-4</link>
      <description>Ling Wang, Ya Gao, Shuxiu Yu, Yangying Sun, Yan Zheng, Yifan Liang, Liang Li, Catalysis Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393111610

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Wang, Ya Gao, Shuxiu Yu, Yangying Sun, Yan Zheng, Yifan Liang, Liang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04648-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0D/2D Bi2MoO6 quantum dots /rGO heterojunction boosting full solar spectrum-driven photothermal catalytic CO2 reduction to solar fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119079</link>
      <description>Rui Feng, Mingnv Guo, Zhongqing Yang, Jiaqi Qiu, Ziqi Wang, Yongliang Zhao, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393114428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Feng, Mingnv Guo, Zhongqing Yang, Jiaqi Qiu, Ziqi Wang, Yongliang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial-temporal Dynamics and Driving Forces of Provincial CO2 Emission Responsibilities in China from Multiple Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47260/amae/1447</link>
      <description>Tie Dai, Yazhou Zhao, Advances in Management and Applied Economics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393116592

                Abstract A comprehensive analysis of the carbon emission profile of Chinese provinces from multiple perspectives is required to develop equitable and effective policies to reduce carbon emissions. This study estimates the carbon dioxide (CO2) emission responsibilities of China&#8217;s 30 provinces and 22 sectors from production, consumption, and income-based perspectives from 2012 to 2017. Structural decomposition analysis (SDA) is used to determine the driving forces of changes in CO2 emissions in China from 2012 to 2017. The results indicate the following. (1) The dominant CO2 emission sectors are the Electric Power, Steam, and Hot Water industry and the Smelting and Pressing of Metals industry. (2) The scale effect of the initial input is the dominant factor affecting the growth of CO2 emissions, followed by the scale effect of the final demand from 2012 to 2017. (3) The structural effect of the production output is the primary carbon reduction factor, followed by the structural effect of the intermediate product input and the carbon intensity effect. Based on these results, recommendations are provided to reduce CO2 emissions, such as developing green and low-carbon technologies, revising and optimizing the energy composition, accelerating the green transition, and a science-based approach to investment. Keywords: Multiple perspectives, China&#8217;s Provinces, Spatial-temporal evolution, MRIO model, SDA model.</description>
      <author>Tie Dai, Yazhou Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47260/amae/1447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The carbon emission reduction effect of renewable resource utilization: From the perspective of green innovation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apr.2024.102121</link>
      <description>Jin-Long Xiao, Siying Chen, Jingwei Han, Zhongfu Tan, Shengjing Mu, Jiayi Wang, Atmospheric Pollution Research. 15(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393135358

                In the face of pressing global challenges posed by climate change, resource constraints, and environmental pollution, understanding the role of renewable resource utilization in carbon emission reduction has become paramount. This study aims to investigate this relationship, particularly within the context of the dual carbon goals, which emphasizes both carbon peak and carbon neutrality. Focusing on the national "urban mineral" demonstration bases as a case study, this research employs the directional distance function incorporating non-expected output alongside the Malmquist index to assess the dynamic changes in urban carbon dioxide emission performance. A multi-period difference-in-difference model is utilized to examine the impact of these demonstration bases on CO2 emissions. The Baseline results reveal that renewable resource utilization significantly enhances carbon emission performance. The channel analysis indicate that the establishment of national "urban mineral" demonstration bases positively influences carbon emission performance through three primary pathways: green technology agglomeration, green technology spillover, and energy structure optimization. Based on these findings, this study advocates for policies that promote renewable resource utilization and carbon emission reduction. Specifically, it highlights the need for increased investment in green technology innovation and diffusion, as well as the optimization of energy structures to mitigate carbon emissions. These findings provide valuable policy implications for governments and stakeholders seeking to reduce carbon emissions and promote sustainable development.</description>
      <author>Jin-Long Xiao, Siying Chen, Jingwei Han, Zhongfu Tan, Shengjing Mu, Jiayi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apr.2024.102121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Influence of Supercritical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with High Temperature and Pressure on Pore-Throat Structure and Minerals of Shale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c09698</link>
      <description>Xiangzeng Wang, Xin Sun, Xing Min Guo, Liange Zheng, Ping Luo, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393156566

                Injection of carbon dioxide offers substantial social and economic advantages for reduction of carbon emission reduction. Utilizing CO2 in shale formations can significantly enhance the extraction of shale oil or gas. Conducting fundamental research on how CO2 affects shale rock's physical properties is crucial for enhancing its porosity and permeability. Particularly for deep shale layers, the effects of supercritical CO2 on shale physical properties should be investigated at a high temperature and pressure, differing from the standard conditions applied in shallower layers. A study examined the impact of supercritical CO2 under such conditions on the pore-throat structure and mineral composition of the shale. The experimental parameters included immersing shale rock in supercritical CO2 at pressures ranging from 10 to 70 MPa and temperatures between 55 and 95 &#176;C. This study evaluated changes in mineral composition, pore-throat structure (using scanning electron microscopy and nitrogen adsorption tests), and the porosity and permeability of the shale rocks. Findings indicated that the dissolution of CO2 altered the relative content of certain minerals. The average quartz content rose and, potassium feldspar and the average contents of plagioclase declined conversely. When increasing the pressure, an increase in the relative content of I/S mixed layer and a decrease in illite content were observed and kaolinite content experienced minor changes. When increasing the temperature, kaolinite, I/S mixed layer, and chlorite all exhibited a decreasing trend with increasing temperature, while the relative contents of illite increased. Some of the pores become rounded in a high-magnification view under the impact of CO2 dissolution. Additionally, the Brunauer&#8211;Emmett&#8211;Teller specific surface area, pore volume, porosity, and permeability generally improved with increasing pressure and temperature. With the temperature and pressure of CO2 increased, the curves of nitrogen absorption had moved first upward and then downward. However, under specific CO2 conditions, the permeability enhancement effect could diminish or even negatively impact the shale's permeability. These findings underscore the need to optimize supercritical CO2 injection parameters under high-temperature and high-pressure conditions. This research aims to provide theoretical guidance for the efficient use of CO2 in deep shale applications to increase the shale gas output.</description>
      <author>Xiangzeng Wang, Xin Sun, Xing Min Guo, Liange Zheng, Ping Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c09698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel combined process for enhancing soluble salt recovery and reducing pollutant diffusion in municipal solid waste incineration fly ash</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141892</link>
      <description>Xin Huang, Lei Wang, Xiaotao Bi, Dahai Yan, Jonathan W C Wong, Yuezhao Zhu, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393131722

                There is a limited body of research on the recovery of soluble salts from fly ash from municipal solid wastes (MSWI-FA), with challenges stemming from the effective management of residual heavy metals and dioxins. In this investigation, we propose using water-washing treatment for fly ash dechlorination and using CO2 aeration carbonation combined with ceramic membrane filtration to recover soluble salt resources from fly ash. This study investigated the impact of combined processes on fly ash soluble salt recovery, carbon dioxide capture and sequestration, heavy metal removal, and dioxin diffusion reduction. The findings revealed that the combined process can significantly enhance the rate of carbonation and the removal of heavy metals. Specifically, the removal rates of Pb and Zn reach 100%. The resulting CaCO3 precipitation particle size is smaller, averaging only approximately 4 &#956;m, with greater surface porosity, higher heavy metal and dioxin content, and dioxin toxic equivalents as high as 8.11 ng TEQ/kg. Moreover, the dioxin content in the recovered mixed salt decreased, and its dioxin toxic equivalent was only 3.228.11 ng TEQ/kg. Consequently, the combined process of CO2 aeration combined with ceramic membrane filtration was used in conjunction to significantly reduce pollutants (heavy metals and dioxins) in the MSWI-FA recovered salt. This approach enhances the recyclable resource utilization of MSWI-FA and reduces the risk of pollution dispersal during MSWI-FA disposal and resource utilization.</description>
      <author>Xin Huang, Lei Wang, Xiaotao Bi, Dahai Yan, Jonathan W C Wong, Yuezhao Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Study of the Effect of Molecular Collision Frequency and Adsorption Capacity on Gas Seepage Flux in Coal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/219733-pa</link>
      <description>Gao Yang, Qingchun Yu, Spe Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393165922

                Summary The differences in the transport behavior and adsorption capacity of different gases in coal play crucial roles in the evolution of coal permeability. Previous studies of coreflooding experiments failed to explain the mechanism of gas flow and have attributed the variation in gas seepage flux (flow rate) at the beginning of the experiment to the change in effective stress, while the differences in the microscopic properties of different gases, such as molar mass, molecular diameter, mean molecular free path, and molecular collision frequency, were ignored. To research the effect of these gas properties on seepage flux while circumventing the effective stress, coreflooding experiments with helium (He), argon (Ar), nitrogen (N2), methane (CH4), and carbon dioxide (CO2) were designed. The results show that the gas transport velocity in coal is affected by the combination of molecular collision frequency and dynamic viscosity, and the transport velocities follow the order of &#957; (CH4) &amp;gt; &#957; (He) &amp;gt; &#957; (N2) &amp;gt; &#957; (CO2) &amp;gt; &#957; (Ar). A permeability equation corrected by the molecular collision frequency is proposed to eliminate differences in the permeabilities measured with different gases. The adsorption of different gases on the coal matrix causes different degrees of swelling, and the adsorption-induced swelling strains follow the order of &#949; (CO2) &amp;gt; &#949; (CH4) &amp;gt; &#949; (N2) &amp;gt; &#949; (Ar) &amp;gt; &#949; (He). The reduction in seepage flux and irreversible alterations in pore structure caused by adsorption-induced swelling are positively correlated with their adsorption capacities. The gas seepage fluxes after adsorption equilibrium of coal follow the order of Q (He) &amp;gt; Q (CH4) &amp;gt;Q (N2) &amp;gt; Q (Ar) &amp;gt; Q (CO2). Like supercritical CO2 (ScCO2), conventional CO2 can also dissolve the organic matter in coal. The organic molecules close to the walls of the cleats along the direction of gas flow are preferentially dissolved by CO2, and the gas seepage flux increases when the dissolution effect on the cleat width is greater than that on adsorption swelling.</description>
      <author>Gao Yang, Qingchun Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/219733-pa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealkalinization Effect of Carbon Dioxide in Flue Gas on Bayer Red Mud</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-50308-5_14</link>
      <description>Chaojun Fang, Yuanlong Jia, Ruixue Lou, Yongping Wang, Xiaotie Deng, Bo Lv, The minerals, metals &amp; materials series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393107226

                Red mudRed mud is a bulk solid waste generated by the aluminaAlumina industry, which is difficult to use on a large scale due to its strong alkalinity. Meanwhile, carbon dioxideCarbon dioxide in flue gas is one of the main factors contributing to global warmingGlobal warming. Therefore, this paper employs flue gas carbon dioxideCarbon dioxide to neutralize the alkaline substances in red mudRed mud. The results showed that with the introduction of carbon dioxideCarbon dioxide into the red mudRed mud at 35 &#176;C, a liquid-to-solid ratio of 10, and an aeration capacity of 20 L/h for 30 min, the dealkalinizationDealkalinization rate of red mudRed mud reached 33.12%. The reduction in alkalinity was due to the acid&#8211;alkali neutralization reaction of carbon dioxideCarbon dioxide with alkali compound in red mudRed mud. The carbon dioxideCarbon dioxide in the flue gas has a dealkalinizationDealkalinization effect on red mudRed mud, which can realize the dual purpose of red mudRed mud dealkalinizationDealkalinization and carbon dioxideCarbon dioxide neutralization.</description>
      <author>Chaojun Fang, Yuanlong Jia, Ruixue Lou, Yongping Wang, Xiaotie Deng, Bo Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-50308-5_14</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accounting for Greenhouse Gas Emissions in the Agricultural System of China Based on the Life Cycle Assessment Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16062594</link>
      <description>Jing Ning, Chunmei Zhang, Meng-Yan Hu, Tiancheng Sun, Sustainability. 16(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393036763

                Agricultural systems contribute nearly one-third of global anthropogenic GHG emissions and are an important source of GHGs globally. The clarification of the GHG emission pattern from agriculture is of paramount importance in the establishment of an agricultural emission reduction mechanism and the realization of China&#8217;s dual-carbon target. Based on the life cycle assessment method (LCA), this paper comprehensively quantifies the greenhouse gas emissions from the agricultural system in China, encompassing rice, wheat, and corn cultivation as well as animal husbandry including cows, horses, donkeys, mules, camels, pigs, and sheep. The analysis covers the period 2000&#8211;2020 and examines the spatial distribution, temporal trends, and structural changes in the greenhouse gas emissions within China&#8217;s agriculture sector. The main results are as follows: (1) from 2000 to 2020, China witnessed a consistent upward trajectory in its total agricultural GHG emissions, exhibiting an average annual growth rate of 0.73%. Notably, methane (CH4) emissions emerged as the largest contributor, displaying an overall fluctuating pattern. Carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions demonstrated intermittent increases with a noteworthy annual growth rate of 3%, signifying the most rapid expansion within this context. Conversely, nitrous oxide (N2O) emissions experienced decline over the specified period. (2) GHG emissions from cultivation demonstrate an upward trajectory, primarily driven by the CH4 emissions originating from rice cultivation and CO2 resulting from straw incineration. Conversely, GHG emissions stemming from animal husbandry declined, with the primary source being CH4 emissions arising from animal enteric fermentation. Agricultural N2O emissions predominantly arise due to manure management and nitrogen fertilizer application. (3) Agricultural greenhouse gas emissions exhibit significant variations in spatial distribution, gradually concentrating towards the North China Plain, the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River, and the northeast. Specifically, agricultural CH4 emissions are progressively concentrated in China&#8217;s pivotal rice-growing regions, encompassing the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River Plain, as well as livestock breeding areas like Inner Mongolia. Agricultural CO2 emissions primarily concentrate in dryland crop production zones such as North China and Northeast China. Meanwhile, Agricultural N2O emissions predominantly occur in Inner Mongolia and the North China Plain. China&#8217;s agricultural greenhouse gas emissions in 2020 show a significant spatial clustering effect, with hotspots primarily concentrated in Shandong, Anhui, Henan, and other regions and cold spots focused in the western and southern areas. The emission patterns of agricultural GHGs are closely intertwined with farming practices, regional development levels, and national policy; hence, tailored measures for emission reduction should be formulated based on specific crop types, livestock categories, agricultural production activities, and regional development characteristics.</description>
      <author>Jing Ning, Chunmei Zhang, Meng-Yan Hu, Tiancheng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16062594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Synthetic Fuel Co-firing of Heavy Fuel Oil for Marine User</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1299/jsmepes.2023.27.d226</link>
      <description>Ken-ichi Sakurai, Masaya Terada, Doryoku, Enerugi Gijutsu Shinpojiumu koen ronbunshu. 2023.27(0)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393134423

                Ships are required to improve their environmental performance, and fuel consumption regulations such as the EEXI regulations require the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions. These regulations require the same environmental performance from ships currently in service as from newbuildings, and conventional ships in service are reducing their maximum power output to reduce carbon dioxide emissions. Therefore, we investigated the effects of co-firing C fuel oil and synthetic fuel. Under the condition of 30[%] synthetic fuel blending, the engine speed was 265[rpm] at low speed, and the ignition time was 1[deg. In the presentation, combustion analysis will be presented along with exhaust gas characteristics.</description>
      <author>Ken-ichi Sakurai, Masaya Terada</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1299/jsmepes.2023.27.d226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/cen-10209-reactions</link>
      <description>, C&amp;EN Global Enterprise. 102(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393162112

                CLIMATE CHANGE Reactions ShareShare onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InRedditEmail C&amp;EN, 2024, 102 (9), p 3March 25, 2024Cite this:C&amp;EN 102, 9, 3Letters to the editorCarbon capture from fermentation processesTwo items in the Feb. 12/19, 2024, issue (the letter "Direct Air Capture," page 5, and the article "Researchers Caution about Reliance on CO2 Removal," page 17) discuss some economic and sustainability issues related to the reduction of atmospheric carbon dioxide, which is needed to achieve goals on mitigating global warming. Ultimately, multiple approaches will be required. One approach that I hear little about is the capture and reuse of CO2 generated as a by-product of fermentation processes, including the anaerobic digestion of food and sewage waste. The CO2 is derived from various forms of biomass and generated in enclosed spaces at higher concentrations than air, which should make capture more efficient. I believe that the CO2 produced is typically just vented into the air.Anaerobic digestion facilities are already separating the digestion-generated CO2 from the biogas before the methane is used to generate renewable electricity. More CO2 could be captured from the flue gas. The Quantum Biopower anaerobic digestion facility where I send my food waste processes about 36,000 metric tons (t) of material annually and has reported that it avoids roughly 4,500 t of CO2 emissions annually. I've read that anaerobic digestion of sewage sludge at Boston's regional sewage treatment facility on Deer Island produces about 5 million ft3 (about 142,000 m3) of biogas daily, which I calculate as resulting in over 10 times as much CO2 (from the biogas and burning of methane) as the total CO2 produced from the Quantum Biopower facility. Scaling such facilities widely and capturing and using the generated CO2 in the production of, for example, aviation and other transportation fuels could significantly contribute to reducing fossil CO2 emissions and eventually to reducing atmospheric CO2 levels.William C. HorneBranford, ConnecticutSafety in imagesI read with interest the article by Geoffrey Kamadi "C&amp;EN Talks with Stephen Cochrane, Antibiotics Researcher" (C&amp;EN, Feb. 12/19, 2024, page 26). It looks like Dr. Cochrane is in a lab without his personal protective equipment (PPE). I recommend that future publications respect lab safety protocols by either showing people in lab with their PPE or adding a qualifying statement that all chemicals, etc. have been removed&#8212;as is done in the current American Chemical Society RAMP (recognize hazards, assess risks, minimize risks, and prepare for emergencies) lab safety videos. C&amp;EN should set the correct example. We faculty have enough trouble getting students to comply with lab safety regulations. C&amp;EN's support is requested. Thank you!Ruth Ann Cook MurphyAustin, TexasDownload PDF</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/cen-10209-reactions</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating the Effect of Carbon Dioxide Contamination on Oil Cement Slurry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-43807-3_27</link>
      <description>Thomas Ayotunde Adebayo, Abdalla Alqhatani, Ahmed Alkhemieri, Advances in science, technology &amp; innovation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393107509

                Carbon dioxide contaminates cement slurry and changes the hardened cement physical properties such as porosity, permeability and flow properties. The effects of additives such as diesel and lime in various proportions to the cement slurry to reduce the effect of the carbon dioxide contamination of cement slurry was studied. Also, the possibility of replacing the Portland cement with a white Portland cement was studied. The permeability of the carbonized cement was reduced, on the average for diesel cement and white cement given a minimum reduction of about 29.8% and 4.6% respectively when compared to the minimum porosity of carbonized Portland cement. This is a good indication that the addition of white cement and diesel as additives enhanced a good cement job in terms of sealing off unwanted zone. It was discovered that while diesel additive to the cement slurry has a positive effect on mitigating the effect of the carbon dioxide contamination; the addition of small quantities of lime has adverse effects on the cement if it is contaminated with carbon dioxide leading to the carbonization of the Portland cement. Therefore, whenever there is the possibility of carbonization of cement slurry, diesel cement is recommended to be used instead of the normal Portland cement. For all the additives, carbonization increased the porosity as compared to the uncontaminated cement and this is expected. Increased porosity due to the cement carbonization is a measure of weakened strength of the cement but the observed permeability when the used diesel or white cement is so small that there is possibility that the cement will retain its integrity of isolating unwanted zones. For improved strength, there is a need to add a strength improver to the cement slurry whenever there is a possibility of carbon dioxide contamination.</description>
      <author>Thomas Ayotunde Adebayo, Abdalla Alqhatani, Ahmed Alkhemieri</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-43807-3_27</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamically Efficient, Low-Emission Gas-to-Wire for Carbon Dioxide-Rich Natural Gas: Exhaust Gas Recycle and Rankine Cycle Intensifications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040639</link>
      <description>Israel Bernardo S. Poblete, Jos&#233; Luiz de Medeiros, Of&#233;lia de Queiroz Fernandes Ara&#250;jo, Processes. 12(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393141920

                Onshore gas-to-wire is considered for 6.5 MMSm3/d of natural gas, with 44% mol carbon dioxide coming from offshore deep-water oil and gas fields. Base-case GTW-CONV is a conventional natural gas combined cycle, with a single-pressure Rankine cycle and 100% carbon dioxide emissions. The second variant, GTW-CCS, results from GTW-CONV with the addition of post-combustion aqueous monoethanolamine carbon capture, coupled to carbon dioxide dispatch to enhance oil recovery. Despite investment and power penalties, GTW-CCS generates both environmental and economic benefits due to carbon dioxide&#8217;s monetization for enhanced oil production. The third variant, GTW-CCS-EGR, adds two intensification layers over GTW-CCS, as follows: exhaust gas recycle and a triple-pressure Rankine cycle. Exhaust gas recycle is a beneficial intensification for carbon capture, bringing a 60% flue gas reduction (reduces column&#8217;s diameters) and a more than 100% increase in flue gas carbon dioxide content (increases driving force, reducing column&#8217;s height). GTW-CONV, GTW-CCS, and GTW-CCS-EGR were analyzed on techno-economic and environment&#8211;thermodynamic grounds. GTW-CCS-EGR&#8217;s thermodynamic analysis unveils 807 MW lost work (79.8%) in the combined cycle, followed by the post-combustion capture unit with 113 MW lost work (11.2%). GTW-CCS-EGR achieved a 35.34% thermodynamic efficiency, while GTW-CONV attained a 50.5% thermodynamic efficiency and 56% greater electricity exportation. Although carbon capture and storage imposes a 35.9% energy penalty, GTW-CCS-EGR reached a superior net value of 1816 MMUSD thanks to intensification and carbon dioxide monetization, avoiding 505.8 t/h of carbon emissions (emission factor 0.084 tCO2/MWh), while GTW-CONV entails 0.642 tCO2/MWh.</description>
      <author>Israel Bernardo S. Poblete, Jos&#233; Luiz de Medeiros, Of&#233;lia de Queiroz Fernandes Ara&#250;jo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040639</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
