<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 01:16:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Highly selective conversion of carbon dioxide to methane by copper single atom electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401314</link>
      <description>Yixian Liu, Mengling Zhang, Kaili Bao, Hui Huang, Zhenhui Kang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402307925

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction into high&#8208;value chemicals is one of the important solutions to the greenhouse effect and energy crisis. However, the slow kinetic process of eight electrons requires the development of efficient catalysts to improve the yields. Single atom catalysts (SACs) with high activity and selectivity have become an emerging research frontier in the field of heterogeneous catalysis. Herein, a catalyst comprised of Cu single atoms loaded on carbon substrate (Cu&#8208;NC) is developed for highly selective electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to methane (CH4). The optimal catalyst (Cu&#8208;NC&#8208;1&#8208;4) exhibits a faradaic efficiency (FE) of over 50% for CH4 within a wide potential window from &#8208;1.3 V to &#8208;1.8 V (vs. RHE) and the highest FE of CH4 is up to 67.22% at &#8208;1.6 V (vs. RHE). Meanwhile, the product selectivity of CH4 among all the carbon products reaches 93.00%, and the activity decay can be negligible via the 70&#8208;hour&#8208;stability&#8208;test. The existence of atomic dispersed Cu&#8208;N3 sites was verified by high&#8208;angle annular dark field scanning transmission electron microscopy (HAADF&#8208;STEM) and X&#8208;ray absorption near edge structure (XANES). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that the effective adsorption of the key intermediate *CO on Cu&#8208;N3 sites prompts the generation of CH4.</description>
      <author>Yixian Liu, Mengling Zhang, Kaili Bao, Hui Huang, Zhenhui Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Strongly Coupled Metal/Hydroxide Heterostructure Cascades Carbon Dioxide and Nitrate Reduction Reactions toward Efficient Urea Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410105</link>
      <description>Wei Ye, Ye Zhang, Liang Chen, Fangfang Wu, Yuanhui Yao, Wei Wang, Genping Zhu, Gan Jia, Zhongchao Bai, Shi Xue Dou, Peng Gao, Nana Wang, Guoxiu Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402329286

                The direct coupling of nitrate ions and carbon dioxide for urea synthesis presents an appealing alternative to the Bosch-Meiser process in industry. The simultaneous activation of carbon dioxide and nitrate, however, as well as efficient C-N coupling on single active site, poses significant challenges. Here, we propose a novel metal/hydroxide heterostructure strategy based on synthesizing an Ag-CuNi(OH)2 composite to cascade carbon dioxide and nitrate reduction reactions for urea electrosynthesis. The strongly coupled metal/hydroxide heterostructure interface integrates two distinct sites for carbon dioxide and nitrate activation, and facilitates the coupling of *CO (on silver, where * denotes an active site) and *NH2 (on hydroxide) for urea formation. Moreover, the strongly coupled interface optimizes the water splitting process and facilitates the supply of active hydrogen atoms, thereby expediting the deoxyreduction processes essential for urea formation. Consequently, our Ag-CuNi(OH)2 composite delivers a high urea yield rate of 25.6 mmol gcat.-1 h-1 and high urea Faradaic efficiency of 46.1%, as well as excellent cycling stability. This work provides new insights into the design of dual-site catalysts for C-N coupling, considering their role on the interface.</description>
      <author>Wei Ye, Ye Zhang, Liang Chen, Fangfang Wu, Yuanhui Yao, Wei Wang, Genping Zhu, Gan Jia, Zhongchao Bai, Shi Xue Dou, Peng Gao, Nana Wang, Guoxiu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Strongly Coupled Metal/Hydroxide Heterostructure Cascades Carbon Dioxide and Nitrate Reduction Reactions toward Efficient Urea Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410105</link>
      <description>Wei Ye, Ye Zhang, Liang Chen, Fangfang Wu, Yuanhui Yao, Wei Wang, Genping Zhu, Gan Jia, Zhongchao Bai, Shi Xue Dou, Peng Gao, Nana Wang, Guoxiu Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402332725

                The direct coupling of nitrate ions and carbon dioxide for urea synthesis presents an appealing alternative to the Bosch&#8211;Meiser process in industry. The simultaneous activation of carbon dioxide and nitrate, however, as well as efficient C&#8211;N coupling on single active site, poses significant challenges. Here, we propose a novel metal/hydroxide heterostructure strategy based on synthesizing an Ag&#8208;CuNi(OH)2 composite to cascade carbon dioxide and nitrate reduction reactions for urea electrosynthesis. The strongly coupled metal/hydroxide heterostructure interface integrates two distinct sites for carbon dioxide and nitrate activation, and facilitates the coupling of *CO (on silver, where * denotes an active site) and *NH2 (on hydroxide) for urea formation. Moreover, the strongly coupled interface optimizes the water splitting process and facilitates the supply of active hydrogen atoms, thereby expediting the deoxyreduction processes essential for urea formation. Consequently, our Ag&#8208;CuNi(OH)2 composite delivers a high urea yield rate of 25.6 mmol gcat.&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 and high urea Faradaic efficiency of 46.1%, as well as excellent cycling stability. This work provides new insights into the design of dual&#8208;site catalysts for C&#8211;N coupling, considering their role on the interface.</description>
      <author>Wei Ye, Ye Zhang, Liang Chen, Fangfang Wu, Yuanhui Yao, Wei Wang, Genping Zhu, Gan Jia, Zhongchao Bai, Shi Xue Dou, Peng Gao, Nana Wang, Guoxiu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Atomic&#8208;scale Explanation For The High Selectivity Towards Carbon Dioxide Reduction Observed On Liquid Metal Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407124</link>
      <description>Charlie Ruffman, Krista G. Steenbergen, Nicola Gaston, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402396607

                The low&#8208;temperature liquid metals Ga&#8208;In and Ga&#8208;Sn have previously showcased &gt;95% selectivity towards the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to formate, occuring only when the alloys are melted, not solid. Here, density functional theory molecular dynamics and metadynamics simulations reveal that CO2 does not directly adsorb to the Ga&#8208;alloy surface, but instead is reduced indirectly by reaction with an adsorbed hydrogen. The reaction barrier is vastly more favourable when this process occurs at In or Sn sites (average: 0.26 eV), than when it occurs on Ga (average: 0.47 eV). However, there is no difference in barrier between solid and liquid surfaces. Instead, we find that Hads is mobile only on the liquid surface, travelling due to the motion of the liquid beneath. This process drives Hads to In/Sn sites, allowing low&#8208;barrier CO2 reduction to occur only on the liquid. Therefore, the dynamic motion of liquid metal catalysts can underpin their unique reactivity. The result has far reaching implications for any protonation reaction conducted with a liquid metal catalyst.</description>
      <author>Charlie Ruffman, Krista G. Steenbergen, Nicola Gaston</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives of nickel-based catalysts in carbon dioxide electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.07.054</link>
      <description>Xiaoxue Li, You Young Song, Weijie Li, Deliang He, Anqiang Pan, Cong Han, Journal of Material Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402423860

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoxue Li, You Young Song, Weijie Li, Deliang He, Anqiang Pan, Cong Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.07.054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-driven carbon dioxide reduction: a review of recent developments and future prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11696-024-03636-7</link>
      <description>Omar H. AL-Zoubi, S. A. Ameen, Farag M. A. Altalbawy, Carlos Rodriguez-Benites, Soumya Menon, Mandeep Kaur, I. B. Sapaev, Merwa Alhadrawi, G.V. Sivaprasad, Hussam Abdali Abdulridui, Chemical Papers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402350015

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Omar H. AL-Zoubi, S. A. Ameen, Farag M. A. Altalbawy, Carlos Rodriguez-Benites, Soumya Menon, Mandeep Kaur, I. B. Sapaev, Merwa Alhadrawi, G.V. Sivaprasad, Hussam Abdali Abdulridui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11696-024-03636-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Atomic&#8208;scale Explanation For The High Selectivity Towards Carbon Dioxide Reduction Observed On Liquid Metal Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407124</link>
      <description>Charlie Ruffman, Krista G. Steenbergen, Nicola Gaston, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402414963

                The low&#8208;temperature liquid metals Ga&#8208;In and Ga&#8208;Sn have previously showcased &gt;95% selectivity towards the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to formate, occuring only when the alloys are melted, not solid. Here, density functional theory molecular dynamics and metadynamics simulations reveal that CO2 does not directly adsorb to the Ga&#8208;alloy surface, but instead is reduced indirectly by reaction with an adsorbed hydrogen. The reaction barrier is vastly more favourable when this process occurs at In or Sn sites (average: 0.26 eV), than when it occurs on Ga (average: 0.47 eV). However, there is no difference in barrier between solid and liquid surfaces. Instead, we find that Hads is mobile only on the liquid surface, travelling due to the motion of the liquid beneath. This process drives Hads to In/Sn sites, allowing low&#8208;barrier CO2 reduction to occur only on the liquid. Therefore, the dynamic motion of liquid metal catalysts can underpin their unique reactivity. The result has far reaching implications for any protonation reaction conducted with a liquid metal catalyst.</description>
      <author>Charlie Ruffman, Krista G. Steenbergen, Nicola Gaston</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Stability and Catalytic Activity of Monoethanolamine Functionalized CuO Electrode in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01919a</link>
      <description>J&#233;ssica C. de Almeida, Osmando F. Lopes, Meital Shviro, Gelson T. S. T. da Silva, Cau&#234; Ribeiro, Vagner Romito de Mendon&#231;ca, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402278088

                Electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reactions (eCO2RR) have emerged as promising strategies for both mitigating CO2 emissions and converting them into valuable products. Despite the promise, challenges such as stability, efficiency,...</description>
      <author>J&#233;ssica C. de Almeida, Osmando F. Lopes, Meital Shviro, Gelson T. S. T. da Silva, Cau&#234; Ribeiro, Vagner Romito de Mendon&#231;ca</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01919a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Salts on the CO2 Reduction Product Distribution in an Aprotic Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400589</link>
      <description>Iris Burgers, Boris Wortmann, Amanda C. Garcia, Connor Deacon-Price, Elena P&#233;rez&#8208;Gallent, Earl Goetheer, Ruud Kortlever, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402255197

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction in non&#8208;aqueous solvents is promising due to the increased CO2 solubility of organic&#8208;based electrolytes compared to aqueous electrolytes. Here the effect of nine different salts in propylene carbonate (PC) on the CO2 reduction product distribution of polycrystalline Cu is investigated. Three different cations (tetraethylammonium (TEA), tetrabutylammonium (TBA), and tetrahexylammonium (THA)) and three different anions (chloride (Cl), tetrafluoroborate (BF4), and hexafluorophosphate (PF6)) were used. Chronoamperometry and in&#8208;situ FTIR measurements show that the size of the cation has a crucial role in the selectivity. A more hydrophobic surface is obtained when employing a larger cation with a weaker hydration shell. This stabilizes the CO2&#8208;&#183; radical and promotes the formation of ethylene. CO2 reduction in 0.7 M THACl/PC shows the highest hydrocarbon formation. Lastly, we hypothesize that the hydrocarbon formation pathway is not through C&#8208;C coupling, as the CO solubility in PC is very high, but through the dimerization of the COH intermediate.</description>
      <author>Iris Burgers, Boris Wortmann, Amanda C. Garcia, Connor Deacon-Price, Elena P&#233;rez&#8208;Gallent, Earl Goetheer, Ruud Kortlever</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu MOF-based electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction to multi-carbon products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05059b</link>
      <description>Lixia Liu, Chengyu Qin, Taojiang Deng, Liming Sun, Zifan Chen, Xiguang Han, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402321307

                The electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) shows great promise in realizing a carbon-neutral cycle by converting CO2 into value-added chemicals and fuels, especially multi-carbon products (C2+) with higher energy density....</description>
      <author>Lixia Liu, Chengyu Qin, Taojiang Deng, Liming Sun, Zifan Chen, Xiguang Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05059b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated &#8220;Two&#8208;in&#8208;One&#8221; Strategy for High&#8208;Rate Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415726</link>
      <description>Peng&#8208;Xia Lei, Shaoqing Liu, Qing Wen, Jiayi Wu, Xiaoxiao Wei, Shuwen Wu, Renfei Feng, Yunming Li, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402307276

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (ECR) is a promising pathway to producing valuable chemicals and fuels. Despite extensive studies reported, improving CO2 adsorption for local CO2 enrichment or water dissociation to generate sufficient H* is still not enough to achieve industrial&#8208;relevant current densities. Herein, we report a &#8220;two&#8208;in&#8208;one&#8221; catalyst, defective Bi nanosheets modified by CrOx (Bi&#8208;CrOx), to simultaneously promote CO2 adsorption and water dissociation, thereby enhancing the activity and selectivity of ECR to formate. The Bi&#8208;CrOx exhibits an excellent Faradic efficiency (&#8776; 100 %) in a wide potential range from &#8210;0.4 to &#8210;0.9 V. In addition, it achieves a remarkable formate partial current density of 687 mA cm&#8210;2 at a moderate potential of &#8210;0.9 V without iR compensation, the highest value at &#8210;0.9 V reported so far. Control experiments and theoretical simulations revealed that the defective Bi facilitates CO2 adsorption/activation while the CrOx accounts for enhancing the protonation process via accelerating H2O dissociation. This work presents a pathway to boosting formate production through tuning CO2 and H2O species at the same time.</description>
      <author>Peng&#8208;Xia Lei, Shaoqing Liu, Qing Wen, Jiayi Wu, Xiaoxiao Wei, Shuwen Wu, Renfei Feng, Yunming Li, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated &#8220;Two&#8208;in&#8208;One&#8221; Strategy for High&#8208;Rate Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415726</link>
      <description>Peng&#8208;Xia Lei, Shaoqing Liu, Qiye Wen, Jiayi Wu, Xiaoxiao Wei, Shuwen Wu, Renfei Feng, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402306902

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (ECR) is a promising pathway to producing valuable chemicals and fuels. Despite extensive studies reported, improving CO2 adsorption for local CO2 enrichment or water dissociation to generate sufficient H* is still not enough to achieve industrial&#8208;relevant current densities. Herein, we report a &#8220;two&#8208;in&#8208;one&#8221; catalyst, defective Bi nanosheets modified by CrOx (Bi&#8208;CrOx), to simultaneously promote CO2 adsorption and water dissociation, thereby enhancing the activity and selectivity of ECR to formate. The Bi&#8208;CrOx exhibits an excellent Faradic efficiency (&#8776; 100 %) in a wide potential range from &#8210;0.4 to &#8210;0.9 V. In addition, it achieves a remarkable formate partial current density of 687 mA cm&#8210;2 at a moderate potential of &#8210;0.9 V without iR compensation, the highest value at &#8210;0.9 V reported so far. Control experiments and theoretical simulations revealed that the defective Bi facilitates CO2 adsorption/activation while the CrOx accounts for enhancing the protonation process via accelerating H2O dissociation. This work presents a pathway to boosting formate production through tuning CO2 and H2O species at the same time.</description>
      <author>Peng&#8208;Xia Lei, Shaoqing Liu, Qiye Wen, Jiayi Wu, Xiaoxiao Wei, Shuwen Wu, Renfei Feng, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Sensitivity and Catalyst Restructuring for CO2 Electro-reduction on Copper</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-z3dlp-v2</link>
      <description>Dongfang Cheng, Khanh&#8208;Ly C. Nguyen, Vaidish Sumaria, Ziyang Wei, Zisheng Zhang, Winston Gee, Yichen Li, Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, Markus Heyde, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Philippe Sautet, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402277367

                Cu is the most promising metal catalyst for CO2 electroreduction (CO2RR) to multi-carbon products, but the structure sensitivity of the reaction and the stability versus restructuring of the catalyst surface under reaction conditions are still controversial. Here, atomic scale simulations of surface energies and reaction pathway kinetics supported by experimental evidence unveil that CO2RR does not take place on perfect planar Cu(111) and Cu(100) surfaces but rather on steps or kinks defects, and that these planar surfaces tend to restructure in reaction conditions to the active stepped surfaces. By combining basin hopping global sampling and grand canonical density functional theory, we show that the extremely low CO coverage on (111) and (100) surfaces, originating from sluggish CO2 conversion and unfavorable CO binding, limits the ability of these surfaces to reduce CO2 to multi-carbon products. Steps and kinks at surfaces, despite the lack of decrease in C-C coupling barriers on these sites, exhibit a significant increase in activity arising from beneficial CO2 activation and higher CO coverage. Notably, the square motifs adjacent to defects, not the defects themselves, are the active sites for CO2RR via synergistic effect. In addition, the strong binding of CO on defective sites acts as a thermodynamic driving force for the restructuring of planar surfaces to active stepped terminations under reactive conditions. We evaluate these mechanisms against experiments of CO2RR on UHV-prepared ultraclean Cu surfaces. Overall, our findings highlight the structural sensitivity in steering CO2RR and elucidate the origin of in situ restructuring of Cu catalysts during the reaction. We furthermore feature that the active sites for CO2RR are created under reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>Dongfang Cheng, Khanh&#8208;Ly C. Nguyen, Vaidish Sumaria, Ziyang Wei, Zisheng Zhang, Winston Gee, Yichen Li, Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, Markus Heyde, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-z3dlp-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding oxidation state of Cu-based catalysts for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.08.029</link>
      <description>Ping Zhu, Yan Qin, X. Z. Cai, Wen&#8208;Min Wang, Hua Yin, Linlin Zhou, Penghui Liu, Peng L&#252;, Wenlong Wang, Qian-Yuan Wu, Journal of Material Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402327514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ping Zhu, Yan Qin, X. Z. Cai, Wen&#8208;Min Wang, Hua Yin, Linlin Zhou, Penghui Liu, Peng L&#252;, Wenlong Wang, Qian-Yuan Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.08.029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Selective Methanol Synthesis Using Electrochemical CO2 Reduction with Defect-Engineered Cu58 Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-d9zmf</link>
      <description>Sourav Biswas, Tomoya Tanaka, Hooyoung Song, Masaki Ogami, Yamato Shingyouchi, Sakiat Hossain, M. Kamiyama, Taiga Kosaka, Riki Nakatani, Yoshiki Niihori, Saikat Das, Tokuhisa Kawawaki, De&#8208;en Jiang, Yuichi Negishi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402273669

                Atomically precise copper nanoclusters (Cu NCs) exhibit significant potential as catalysts for the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2. However, the range of products achievable with these NCs has been somewhat constrained. This study introduces an innovative design strategy to enhance the catalytic activity of Cu NCs by engineering their active sites. We achieve this by creating defects on a cubic Cu58 NC through the partial dislocation of Cu atoms at its vertices, leading to the ligand vacancies that exposes multiple Cu sites. Additionally, the dislocation of Cu atoms finely tunes the inner cationic geometries through altered cuprophilic interactions, resulting in discernable changes in their edges and vertices. When tested, these unique arrangements of Cu(I) atoms within the cluster prove effective in determining product specificities during electrochemical CO2 reduction. Density functional theory calculations correlate the product selectivity toward CH3OH for [Cu58H20(SPr)36(PPh3)7]2+ (Pr = CH2CH2CH3) NC to the enhanced edge Cu reactivity in binding CO and CHO intermediates, compared to [Cu58H20(SPr)36(PPh3)8]2+ and [Cu58H20(SEt)36(PPh3)6]2+ (Et = CH2CH3) NCs. This work underscores the potential of tailored structural designs of atomically precise nanocatalysts in steering electrochemical CO2 reduction toward unconventional products.</description>
      <author>Sourav Biswas, Tomoya Tanaka, Hooyoung Song, Masaki Ogami, Yamato Shingyouchi, Sakiat Hossain, M. Kamiyama, Taiga Kosaka, Riki Nakatani, Yoshiki Niihori, Saikat Das, Tokuhisa Kawawaki, De&#8208;en Jiang, Yuichi Negishi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-d9zmf</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gapped and Rotated Grain Boundary Revealed in Ultra&#8208;small Au Nanoparticles for Enhancing Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410109</link>
      <description>Wenying Wang, Dong Chen, Victor Fung, Shengli Zhuang, Yue Zhou, Chengming Wang, Guo&#8208;Qing Bian, Yan Zhao, Nan Xia, Jin Li, Haiteng Deng, Lingwen Liao, Jun Yang, De&#8208;en Jiang, Zhikun Wu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402277438

                Although gapped grain boundaries have often been observed in bulk and nanosized materials, and their crucial roles in some physical and chemical processes have been confirmed, their acquisition at ultrasmall nanoscale presents a significant challenge. To date, they had not been reported in metal nanoparticles smaller than 2 nm owing to the difficulty in characterization and the high instability of grain boundary (GB) atoms. Herein, we have successfully developed a synthesis method for producing a novel chiral nanocluster Au78(TBBT)40 (TBBT = 4&#8208;tert&#8208;butylphenylthiol) with a 26&#8208;atom gapped and rotated GB. This nanocluster was precisely characterized using single&#8208;crystal X&#8208;ray crystallography and mass spectrometry. Additionally, an offset atomic defect linked to the peripheral Au(TBBT)2 staple was found in the structure. Comparing it to similarly face&#8208;centered cubic&#8208;structured Au36(TBBT)24, Au44(TBBT)28, Au52(TBBT)32, Au92(TBBT)44, and ~5 nm nanocrystals, the bridging Au78(TBBT)40 nanocluster exhibits higher catalytic activity in the reduction of CO2 to CO. This enhanced activity is well interpreted using density functional theory calculations and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy analysis, highlighting the influence of GBs and point defects on the properties of metal nanoclusters.</description>
      <author>Wenying Wang, Dong Chen, Victor Fung, Shengli Zhuang, Yue Zhou, Chengming Wang, Guo&#8208;Qing Bian, Yan Zhao, Nan Xia, Jin Li, Haiteng Deng, Lingwen Liao, Jun Yang, De&#8208;en Jiang, Zhikun Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart Port Sustainability: A Business Intelligence Framework for CO2 Reduction in Cargo Truck Operations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-71622-5_21</link>
      <description>Marco Hegger, Adriana Saraceni, IFIP advances in information and communication technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402302092

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marco Hegger, Adriana Saraceni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-71622-5_21</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gapped and Rotated Grain Boundary Revealed in Ultra&#8208;small Au Nanoparticles for Enhancing Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410109</link>
      <description>Wenying Wang, Dong Chen, Victor Fung, Shengli Zhuang, Yue Zhou, Chengming Wang, Guo&#8208;Qing Bian, Yan Zhao, Nan Xia, Jin Li, Haiteng Deng, Lingwen Liao, Jun Yang, De&#8208;en Jiang, Zhikun Wu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402277219

                Although gapped grain boundaries have often been observed in bulk and nanosized materials, and their crucial roles in some physical and chemical processes have been confirmed, their acquisition at ultrasmall nanoscale presents a significant challenge. To date, they had not been reported in metal nanoparticles smaller than 2 nm owing to the difficulty in characterization and the high instability of grain boundary (GB) atoms. Herein, we have successfully developed a synthesis method for producing a novel chiral nanocluster Au78(TBBT)40 (TBBT = 4&#8208;tert&#8208;butylphenylthiol) with a 26&#8208;atom gapped and rotated GB. This nanocluster was precisely characterized using single&#8208;crystal X&#8208;ray crystallography and mass spectrometry. Additionally, an offset atomic defect linked to the peripheral Au(TBBT)2 staple was found in the structure. Comparing it to similarly face&#8208;centered cubic&#8208;structured Au36(TBBT)24, Au44(TBBT)28, Au52(TBBT)32, Au92(TBBT)44, and ~5 nm nanocrystals, the bridging Au78(TBBT)40 nanocluster exhibits higher catalytic activity in the reduction of CO2 to CO. This enhanced activity is well interpreted using density functional theory calculations and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy analysis, highlighting the influence of GBs and point defects on the properties of metal nanoclusters.</description>
      <author>Wenying Wang, Dong Chen, Victor Fung, Shengli Zhuang, Yue Zhou, Chengming Wang, Guo&#8208;Qing Bian, Yan Zhao, Nan Xia, Jin Li, Haiteng Deng, Lingwen Liao, Jun Yang, De&#8208;en Jiang, Zhikun Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphology Dependence of Oxygen Vacancies in Nano-Ceo2 and Effect on Non-Reductive Conversion Activity of Co2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4946533</link>
      <description>Yuying Yang, Junjie Ma, Liu Na, Xueli Huang, Lijun Jin, He Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402220452

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuying Yang, Junjie Ma, Liu Na, Xueli Huang, Lijun Jin, He Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4946533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Mechanisms, Pathways, and Kinetic Expressions for Direct CO2 Conversion to Methanol: In Reduction Using H2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15740-0.00105-1</link>
      <description>Chandira Mendis, Nathasha H. Govinnage, Dinusha N. Udukala, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402296932

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chandira Mendis, Nathasha H. Govinnage, Dinusha N. Udukala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15740-0.00105-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing pyroelectric energy in planar catalysts for dual-pathway CO2 reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/scimeetings.5c10753</link>
      <description>Maryam Mokhtarifar, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402222704

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maryam Mokhtarifar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/scimeetings.5c10753</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed nickel-bismuth dual-atom sites for high rate electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nantod.2024.102477</link>
      <description>Xiaoxiong Huang, Shengli Wu, Zhichang Xiao, Linjie Zhi, Sheng Wang, Nano Today. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402330941

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoxiong Huang, Shengli Wu, Zhichang Xiao, Linjie Zhi, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nantod.2024.102477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c</link>
      <description>K. Yamini Yasoda, Mani Balamurugan, Ki Tae Nam, Buvaneswari Gopal, Annamalai Senthil Kumar, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402358098

                Due to the detrimental effects of CO2 on the atmosphere, including climate change, the development of environmentally friendly electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction is crucial for mitigation. Inspired by carbon monoxide...</description>
      <author>K. Yamini Yasoda, Mani Balamurugan, Ki Tae Nam, Buvaneswari Gopal, Annamalai Senthil Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism investigation of direct electrochemical reduction of CO2-loaded 2-(ethylamino)ethanol solution into CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129575</link>
      <description>Ru&#8208;Ping Dai, Lijuan Zhang, Khuyen Viet Bao Tran, Suchada Sirisomboonchai, Hiroshi Machida, Koyo Norinaga, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402290811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ru&#8208;Ping Dai, Lijuan Zhang, Khuyen Viet Bao Tran, Suchada Sirisomboonchai, Hiroshi Machida, Koyo Norinaga</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-driven structural distortion in cobalt phthalocyanine for electrocatalytic CO2/CO reduction towards methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52168-x</link>
      <description>Haozhou Yang, Na Guo, Shibo Xi, Wei Xing Zheng, Bingqing Yao, Qian He, Chun Zhang, Lei Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402237305

                Cobalt phthalocyanine immobilized on carbon nanotube has demonstrated appreciable selectivity and activity for methanol synthesis in electrocatalytic CO</description>
      <author>Haozhou Yang, Na Guo, Shibo Xi, Wei Xing Zheng, Bingqing Yao, Qian He, Chun Zhang, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52168-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Printing Strategy Achieves Precise Anchoring of Dual&#8208;Copper Atoms on C2N Structure for Efficient CO2 Reduction to Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405778</link>
      <description>Zhiyi Sun, Xuan Luo, Huishan Shang, Ziding Wang, Liang Zhang, Wenxing Chen, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402350690

                Isolated metal sites catalysts (IMSCs) play crucial role in electrochemical CO2 reduction, with potential industrial applications. However, tunable synthesis strategies for IMSCs are limited. Herein, we present an atomic printing strategy that draws inspiration from the ancient Chinese "movable&#8208;type printing technology". Selecting customizable combinations of metal atoms as metal precursors form an extensive binuclear metal library. A series of dual&#8208;atom catalysts were prepared by utilizing the edge nitrogen atoms in the C2N cavity as anchoring "pincers" to capture metal atoms. To prove utility, the dual atom catalyst Cu2&#8208;C2N is investigated as electrocatalytic CO2RR catalyst. The synergistic interaction of dual Cu atoms promotes C&#8208;C coupling and guarantees FEC2+ (90.8%) and FEC2H4. (71.7%) at &#8208;1.10 V vs RHE. DFT calculations revealed the Cu2 site would be subtly flipped during CO2RR for enhancing *CO adsorption and dimerization. We validate that atomic printing strategies are applicable to wide range of metal combinations, representing a significant advancement in the development of IMSCs.</description>
      <author>Zhiyi Sun, Xuan Luo, Huishan Shang, Ziding Wang, Liang Zhang, Wenxing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Printing Strategy Achieves Precise Anchoring of Dual&#8208;Copper Atoms on C2N Structure for Efficient CO2 Reduction to Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405778</link>
      <description>Zhiyi Sun, Xuan Luo, Huishan Shang, Ziding Wang, Liang Zhang, Wenxing Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402350533

                Isolated metal sites catalysts (IMSCs) play crucial role in electrochemical CO2 reduction, with potential industrial applications. However, tunable synthesis strategies for IMSCs are limited. Herein, we present an atomic printing strategy that draws inspiration from the ancient Chinese "movable&#8208;type printing technology". Selecting customizable combinations of metal atoms as metal precursors form an extensive binuclear metal library. A series of dual&#8208;atom catalysts were prepared by utilizing the edge nitrogen atoms in the C2N cavity as anchoring "pincers" to capture metal atoms. To prove utility, the dual atom catalyst Cu2&#8208;C2N is investigated as electrocatalytic CO2RR catalyst. The synergistic interaction of dual Cu atoms promotes C&#8208;C coupling and guarantees FEC2+ (90.8%) and FEC2H4. (71.7%) at &#8208;1.10 V vs RHE. DFT calculations revealed the Cu2 site would be subtly flipped during CO2RR for enhancing *CO adsorption and dimerization. We validate that atomic printing strategies are applicable to wide range of metal combinations, representing a significant advancement in the development of IMSCs.</description>
      <author>Zhiyi Sun, Xuan Luo, Huishan Shang, Ziding Wang, Liang Zhang, Wenxing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional RhIII-complex catalyzed CO2 reduction and NADH regeneration for direct bioelectrochemical synthesis of C3 and C4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4865792/v1</link>
      <description>Yajie Wang, Hailong Li, Yizhou Wu, Yuxuan Wang, Kai Zhang, Jing Zhu, Yukui Zhang, Tao Gu, Weixuan Nie, Licheng Sun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402220892

                Abstract Bioelectrochemical synthesis is emerging as an eco-friendly method for CO2 fixation. These systems typically rely on electrochemically regenerated NAD(P)H to provide the necessary reducing equivalents for formate dehydrogenase (FDH) to convert CO2 into formate. However, the efficiency of these systems is currently unsatisfactory due to the unfavorable dynamics of the CO2-to-formate conversion by FDH. In this study, we developed a one-pot cooperative bioelectrochemical system featuring a rhodium-based catalyst [Cp*Rh(bpy)Cl]2+ (RhIII-complex or [RhIII-H2O]2+) working cooperatively with enzymatic cascades of acetyl-CoA synthase (ACS), acetaldehyde dehydrogenase (ACDH), alcohol dehydrogenase (ADH), formolase (FLS), and d-fructose-6-phosphate aldolase mutant FSAA129S to convert CO2 into several C2+ chemicals. The bifunctional RhIII-complex concurrently catalyzes the reduction of CO2 to formate at a rate of 15.8 mM/h and NADH regeneration at a rate of 0.24 mM/min. The formation of formate is 83.2 times faster than using one of the best aerobic FDH from Clostridium ljungdahlii (ClFDH), resulting in a 3.6 times enhanced methanol production rate of 0.43 mM/h in the bioelectroenzymatic system (RhIII-complex-ACS-ACDH-ADH) compared to that of 0.12 mM/h in tandem enzymatic system (ClFDH-ACS-ACDH-ADH). Bifunctional RhIII-complex also works cooperatively with tandem enzymatic cascades to produce dihydroxyacetone (C3) and L-erythrulose (C4) at the yield of 2.63 mM, and 1.93 mM, respectively. This study leveraged the synthetic capabilities of both electrochemical catalysis and enzymatic catalysis, offering an alternative for electroenzymatic CO2 reduction to yield value-added compounds with enhanced productivity.</description>
      <author>Yajie Wang, Hailong Li, Yizhou Wu, Yuxuan Wang, Kai Zhang, Jing Zhu, Yukui Zhang, Tao Gu, Weixuan Nie, Licheng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4865792/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling, Parameter Estimation and Optimization of Fluidized Bed-Based Alternative Ironmaking Process for CO2 Emission Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.09.008</link>
      <description>Jae Hwan Choi, Songhak Yoon, Sunyoung Kim, Myung K. Shin, Jong Min Lee, Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402397472

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jae Hwan Choi, Songhak Yoon, Sunyoung Kim, Myung K. Shin, Jong Min Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.09.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An eco-friendly system of thermally regenerative battery-driven electrochemical CO2 reduction: In-situ harvesting of low-grade heat as electrical power for reducing CO2 emissions of flue gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.119029</link>
      <description>S.J. Li, Zhenchong Xiao, Yu Shi, Liang Zhang, Jun Li, Zhuo Li, Xun Zhu, Qiang Liao, Energy Conversion and Management. 321(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402329047

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S.J. Li, Zhenchong Xiao, Yu Shi, Liang Zhang, Jun Li, Zhuo Li, Xun Zhu, Qiang Liao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.119029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Salt Precipitation and Water Flooding Intrinsic to Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acidic Membrane Electrode Assemblies: Fundamentals and Remedies"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402212917

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Salt Precipitation and Water Flooding Intrinsic to Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acidic Membrane Electrode Assemblies: Fundamentals and Remedies"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402211010

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Salt Precipitation and Water Flooding Intrinsic to Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acidic Membrane Electrode Assemblies: Fundamentals and Remedies"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402210927

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Versatile Functions of Ni-doped Zn2SnO4 Integrated with Zinc-Based MOFs: Unveiling Enhanced Paths for Efficient CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176347</link>
      <description>Yanlong Yu, Mariusz Oleksy, Zhu Ding, Dekun Shi, Ziying Li, Sai Yan, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402217370

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanlong Yu, Mariusz Oleksy, Zhu Ding, Dekun Shi, Ziying Li, Sai Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Salt Precipitation and Water Flooding Intrinsic to Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acidic Membrane Electrode Assemblies: Fundamentals and Remedies"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402212877

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Salt Precipitation and Water Flooding Intrinsic to Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acidic Membrane Electrode Assemblies: Fundamentals and Remedies"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402211586

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Salt Precipitation and Water Flooding Intrinsic to Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acidic Membrane Electrode Assemblies: Fundamentals and Remedies"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402212665

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Salt Precipitation and Water Flooding Intrinsic to Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acidic Membrane Electrode Assemblies: Fundamentals and Remedies"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402212443

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential for nutrients reuse, carbon sequestration, and CO2 emissions reduction in the practice of domestic and industrial wastewater recycling into agricultural soils: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122443</link>
      <description>Thais Girardi Carpanez, Jonathas Batista Gon&#231;alves Silva, Marcelo Henrique Ot&#234;nio, M&#237;riam Cristina Santos Amaral, Victor Rezende Moreira, Journal of Environmental Management. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402339247

                This review assesses the feasibility of reusing treated wastewater for irrigation in agricultural soils as a strategy for nutrients recycling and mitigation of CO</description>
      <author>Thais Girardi Carpanez, Jonathas Batista Gon&#231;alves Silva, Marcelo Henrique Ot&#234;nio, M&#237;riam Cristina Santos Amaral, Victor Rezende Moreira</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Salt Precipitation and Water Flooding Intrinsic to Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acidic Membrane Electrode Assemblies: Fundamentals and Remedies"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v3/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402211065

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v3/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Salt Precipitation and Water Flooding Intrinsic to Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction in Acidic Membrane Electrode Assemblies: Fundamentals and Remedies"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v3/response1</link>
      <description>Qianqian Bai, Likun Xiong, Yongjia Zhang, Mutian Ma, Zhenyang Jiao, Fenglei Lyu, Zhao Deng, Peng Yang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402213085

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianqian Bai, Likun Xiong, Yongjia Zhang, Mutian Ma, Zhenyang Jiao, Fenglei Lyu, Zhao Deng, Peng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00170b/v3/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fostering a Green Tomorrow: Exploring the Impact of Economic Fitness on CO2 Reduction Along the Environmental Kuznets Curve with Capital and Renewable Energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15244/pjoes/188187</link>
      <description>Xuewen Su, Kashif Raza, Liaqat Ali Waseem, Rida Waheed, Polish Journal of Environmental Studies. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402235411

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuewen Su, Kashif Raza, Liaqat Ali Waseem, Rida Waheed</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15244/pjoes/188187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402388521

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402388149

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Green Steel-Energy and CO2 Assessment of Low Carbon Steelmaking Via Hydrogen Based Shaft Furnace Direct Reduction Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.133080</link>
      <description>Shaofeng Lu, Qiang Cheng, Yaozu Wang, Jianliang Zhang, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402225536

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaofeng Lu, Qiang Cheng, Yaozu Wang, Jianliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.133080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v3/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402399164

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v3/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402398997

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v3/response1</link>
      <description>K. Yamini Yasoda, Mani Balamurugan, Ki Tae Nam, Buvaneswari Gopal, Annamalai Senthil Kumar, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402398901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Yamini Yasoda, Mani Balamurugan, Ki Tae Nam, Buvaneswari Gopal, Annamalai Senthil Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v3/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v3/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402398896

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v3/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Dft Study on the Structural Properties and Co2 Electrocatalytic Reduction Activity of Monolayer Graphitic Carbon Nitride Supported Ag/Au Single Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4949570</link>
      <description>Hui-Ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402331817

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui-Ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4949570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402429479

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v2/response1</link>
      <description>K. Yamini Yasoda, Mani Balamurugan, Ki Tae Nam, Buvaneswari Gopal, Annamalai Senthil Kumar, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402388519

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Yamini Yasoda, Mani Balamurugan, Ki Tae Nam, Buvaneswari Gopal, Annamalai Senthil Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Enzyme-Mimicking Redox-Active Vitamin B12 Functionalized MWCNT-Catalyst for Nearly 100% Faradaic Efficiency in Electrochemical CO2 Reduction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402429546

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04145c/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ti F bridged IL-CuCQDs-F/TiO2 inverse opal composite for boosting CO2 visible-photo reduction via slow photon effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.071</link>
      <description>Mengying Tao, Zhaowei Jia, Hui He, Yanhu Han, Xin Yu, Yaofei Ren, Yuewei Wu, Yinyin Lin, Zhongfeng Shi, Zhenxia Zhao, Zhongxing Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402425069

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengying Tao, Zhaowei Jia, Hui He, Yanhu Han, Xin Yu, Yaofei Ren, Yuewei Wu, Yinyin Lin, Zhongfeng Shi, Zhenxia Zhao, Zhongxing Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the interfacial reaction environment via pH-dependent and induced ions to understand C&#8211;N bonds coupling performance in NO3&#8722; integrated CO2 reduction to carbon and nitrogen compounds over dual Cu-based N-doped carbon catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.049</link>
      <description>Tianhang Zhou, Chen Shen, Zhenghao Wu, Xingying Lan, Yi Xiao, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402222208

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianhang Zhou, Chen Shen, Zhenghao Wu, Xingying Lan, Yi Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research On CCUS Emission Reduction Methodology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61935/acetr.3.1.2024.p386</link>
      <description>Qilin Wu, Yanhui Gao, Yan Qi, H Chen, Dashu Li, Advances in Computer and Engineering Technology Research. 1(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402282186

                Climate warming has become a global environmental problem, more and more governments and people's attention. At present, most scientists generally agree that carbon dioxide released by human activities is the most important greenhouse gas causing global warming. Reducing carbon dioxide emissions from coal burning is an important measure to reduce global warming. This paper analyzes the significance of CCUS and CO2 transport, explores the CO2 transport mode, studies and discusses the methodological issues, and summarizes the types of CO2 emission reduction technologies.</description>
      <author>Qilin Wu, Yanhui Gao, Yan Qi, H Chen, Dashu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61935/acetr.3.1.2024.p386</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Oil Price on Carbon Dioxide Emissions in the Transport Sector: The Threshold Effect of Environmental Policy Stringency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174496</link>
      <description>Xingong Ding, Mengzhen Wang, Energies. 17(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377146

                Carbon dioxide emissions from the transport sector make a significant contribution to global greenhouse gases, and understanding the factors that influence these emissions is beneficial for devising effective emission reduction policies. Oil prices are an important influencing factor since the fuel used in the transport sector is primarily based on oil, and fluctuations in oil prices directly impact the sector&#8217;s CO2 emissions. Additionally, environmental policies, as a key means of controlling CO2 emissions, can affect the relationship between oil prices and CO2 emissions in the transport sector. Therefore, this study aims to examine the impact of oil prices on CO2 emissions in the transport sector and explore the nonlinear role of environmental policy stringency in this relationship. Based on data from 27 OECD member countries and 6 non-member countries from 1990 to 2019, we used the environmental policy stringency index as a threshold variable to construct a panel threshold regression model. The analysis results indicate a double-threshold effect: when the environmental policy stringency index is low, the impact of oil prices on CO2 emissions in the transport sector is not significant. However, when the index reaches the first threshold, the impact of oil prices significantly increases; upon reaching the second threshold, the effect is further intensified. This paper also analyzes the three subindicators&#8212;market-based policies, non-market-based policies, and technology support policies&#8212;to clarify the distinct impact mechanisms of different types of environmental policies. Finally, based on the research findings, we propose policy recommendations to achieve carbon dioxide emission reduction targets in the transport sector.</description>
      <author>Xingong Ding, Mengzhen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of ZnCdS Quantum-Dot-Modified CeO2 (0D&#8211;2D) Heterojunction for Enhancing Photocatalytic CO2 Reduction and Mechanism Insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14090599</link>
      <description>Junzhi Yan, Yuming Sun, Jinfa Cai, Ming Cai, Bo Hu, Yan Yan, Qian Zhang, Xu Tang, Catalysts. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402319773

                It is important to improve the separation ability of photogenerated electrons and the adsorption capacity of carbon dioxide (CO2) for efficient photoreduction of CO2. Here, we synthesized ZnCdS quantum dots (ZCS-QDs) and cerium dioxide nanosheets (CeO2) using the solvothermal method and calcination method. We combined CeO2 and ZCS-QDs to effectively enhance the charge separation efficiency, and the lifetime of photogenerated electrons was increased 4.5 times. The CO evolution rate of the optimized composite (ZCS-QDs/CeO2) was up to 495.8 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1, and it had 100% product selectivity. In addition, the stability remained high after five cycles. The CO2 adsorption capacity of the catalyst surface was observed by in situ FTIR. The test results showed that improving CO2 capture ability and promoting photogenic electron separation had positive effects on enhancing photoreduction of CO2. This study provides a reference for constructing a zero-dimensional&#8211;two-dimensional (0D&#8211;2D) heterojunction and explores potential CO2 reduction reaction mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Junzhi Yan, Yuming Sun, Jinfa Cai, Ming Cai, Bo Hu, Yan Yan, Qian Zhang, Xu Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14090599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Neighborhood Effects of National Climate Legislation: Learning or Competition?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177800</link>
      <description>Ying Liu, Uma Murthy, Chao Feng, Sustainability. 16(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402373795

                This study aims to explore the spatial spillover effects of national climate legislation on carbon emission reduction by using cross-country panel data from 2002 to 2021. The results show the following: First, the estimation outcomes confirm the presence of spatial correlations between carbon dioxide emissions and climate legislation across countries. Second, the study shows that the spillover effect of climate legislation on CO2 emissions is significantly negative. Hence, the outcomes indicate that being surrounded by nations with more climate laws positively impacts environmental quality. Third, regarding direct impact and spillover effects, the carbon reduction impact of parliamentary legislative acts is stronger than that of governmental executive orders. Finally, even with the spillover effect, we uncover robust evidence supporting an inverted-U-shaped EKC linkage between carbon emissions and GDP per capita, even under the spatial spillover effect.</description>
      <author>Ying Liu, Uma Murthy, Chao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efektifitas arang aktif tongkol jagung dalam menurunkan emisi kendaraan bermotor berbahan bakar ganda</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29303/dtm.v14i2.829</link>
      <description>Hendry Sakke Tira, Yesung Allo Padang, Arif Mulyanto, Syahrul Syahrul, S. Salman, Dian Pramana Putra, Dinamika Teknik Mesin. 14(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402394338

                Emission reduction through after treatment processes has become one of the options to minimize the adverse effects of two-wheeler emissions. Activated charcoal adsorbents have been proven effective in reducing emissions to a certain extent. In this study, corn cob charcoal activated with a 15% NaCl solution serves as the adsorbent. The adsorbent used is shaped into particles with a mesh size of 10. The adsorbent is placed in the modified motorcycle muffler. Testing is conducted on two-wheeled vehicles operated using the dual-fuel method, where biogas and pertalite are used as fuels. With this method, fuel concentrations are obtained significantly smaller compared to vehicles without emission reduction methods. Testing is carried out for 2 hours to determine the durability of the adsorbent in absorbing exhaust gas emissions. Based on the test results, where data collection is conducted every 10 minutes, the concentrations of emissions including hydrocarbons (HC), carbon monoxide (CO), and carbon dioxide (CO2) initially decrease and then rise again after several minutes. This indicates that the adsorbent effectively reduces emissions in a relatively short duration. However, the effectiveness of corn cob activated charcoal in reducing these three emissions varies, with the adsorbent showing good performance in reducing HC</description>
      <author>Hendry Sakke Tira, Yesung Allo Padang, Arif Mulyanto, Syahrul Syahrul, S. Salman, Dian Pramana Putra</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29303/dtm.v14i2.829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of a Management System to Mitigate Carbon Dioxide Emissions from Light Vehicles Transportation Through Improved Driving Behavior in the State of Kuwait</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/220345-ms</link>
      <description>B. M. Al-Hadhrami, No host. 133(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402397577

                Abstract This study investigates the effects of improved driving behaviors on greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions reduction from light vehicles in Kuwait. There has been a steady increase in Greenhouse Gases (GHG) emission to the atmosphere globally since the industrial revolution. Human activities, such as the burning of fossil fuels, transportation, and changes in land use are major contributors to the increase in concentrations of atmospheric GHGs. According to the latest estimates, Kuwait being a major oil producing country, annual increase in GHG emissions has been recorded for the past two decades, with 21.2 MT per capita emitted in 2020, increased from 21.1 compared to 2019. Implementing practical and feasible reduction strategies to the significant emission contributors is essential. This study proposes a management system targeting the transportation sector through enhanced driving behaviors in a transportation fleet, using a monitoring hardware and software, to collect data from 25 light vehicles. To assess the solution's effectiveness, we compared pre- and post-intervention periods of fuel consumption in light vehicles through monitoring and enhancing the driving behavior variables, harsh acceleration, harsh braking, over-speeding, and idling, thus reducing carbon emissions that was determined based on the US EPA conversion factor. Our results show significant improvements in several key parameters, a 15% reduction in fuel consumption resulting in 15% and 18% carbon dioxide emissions (CO2) and cost reduction, respectively. This should represent huge environmental and economic benefit associated with the measures implemented. In the post-intervention phase, where controls and interventions were implemented to enhance drivers' behaviors, there was a significant reduction in idling hours, decreasing by 8,167.38 hours with a (P &amp;lt; 0.003). These results clearly illustrate the need for more stringent national regulations at improving driving behaviors, which not only contribute to environmental quality improvement but also offer substantial economic advantages.</description>
      <author>B. M. Al-Hadhrami</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/220345-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small States, Big Impact: A Review of Rising Greenhouse Gases Emission from the Energy Sector in India</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3233/jcc240022</link>
      <description>Avinash Dass, Amit Kumar Mishra, Rajesh Kumar Ranjan, Journal of Climate Change. 10(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402306882

                Emissions of greenhouse gases (GHGs) are a prime concern that needs our attention, not only in megapolitan states but also in developing small states. The increase in GHGs-emission could lead to severe climate change scenarios and global warming. In India, it is measured that the energy sector (68.7%) accounts for a significant GHGs-emission, followed by agriculture (19.6%), industry (6.0%), land use change and forestry (3.8%), and waste sector (1.9%). This article aims to investigate temporal changes and trends in greenhouse gases (GHGs) emissions in the energy sector of India. We have used GHGs-emission as Carbon dioxide (CO2) equivalent and compared the top per capita emitting states versus their total emissions and vice versa. Most of this increase has occurred in small states, where urbanisation, population growth, and economic expansion have been significant factors. Odisha and Maharashtra were listed as top-emitting states releasing more than 240 million tonnes of carbon dioxide equivalent (MtCO2e), mainly through industrial energy and electricity-related emissions, respectively, followed by Chhattisgarh, Gujarat, Uttar Pradesh, Madhya Pradesh, Andhra Pradesh, and West Bengal. In contrast, Chhattisgarh was recorded as the top per-capita emitting state, followed by Odisha. Among all the states studied, Lakshadweep has shown a significant trend in GHGs per capita reduction, while the other shows an increasing trend due to a lack of robust and effective legislation. This review will help to seek the attention of policymakers and the government towards the increasing emissions from the small states which are emerging in day to day life.</description>
      <author>Avinash Dass, Amit Kumar Mishra, Rajesh Kumar Ranjan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3233/jcc240022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Implementation and Optimization of Carbon Mitigation Mechanisms in Oil and Gas Industry Using Multi-Criteria Decision Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24815/jr.v7i3.39124</link>
      <description>Luthfiyah Revi Sukmasari, Gunawan Nugroho, Riwayat Educational Journal of History and Humanities. 7(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402313651

                Indonesia signed the Paris Agreement in 2016, thus actively contributing to tackling climate change has an obligation to reduce greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. The main factor of global climate change is the increase of GHG, especially carbon dioxide (CO2) and methane (CH4). PT X is committed to supporting Net Zero Emission 2060 by encouraging programs that have a good impact on the environment and Sustainable Development Goals (SDG's) 13 and supporting the government in handling the climate crisis. The ranking of alternatives is carried out using two structured methods, quantitative analysis using Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP) and Technique for Order Preference by Similarity to Ideal Solution (TOPSIS), considering environmental, economic, and social aspects. used to help make decisions for the implementation of carbon mitigation mechanisms. From the observation of the previous implementation, carbon emissions in the production process were quite high. So it is necessary to make effective carbon mitigation efforts. There are three criteria that influence action decisions, namely environmental criteria, economic criteria and social criteria. The results of the weight value of each criterion are that the environment has the highest weight (0.61), followed by economic criteria (0.20) and social criteria (0.19) from these values indicate that environmental criteria are the most important criteria in decision making. The ranking results show that the Piston Modification Program and the Diesel Engine to Gas Engine Replacement Program are optimal options for short-term implementation. The Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS) program should be considered for long-term investment, with the potential for large emission reductions and long-term cost savings.</description>
      <author>Luthfiyah Revi Sukmasari, Gunawan Nugroho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24815/jr.v7i3.39124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction and melting behaviours of carbon &#8211; iron oxide composite using iron carbides and free carbon obtained by vapour deposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/wewm2079</link>
      <description>Ryota Higashi, Daisuke Maruoka, Y. Iwami, T. Murakami, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383332

                The ironmaking industry consumes a large amount of fossil fuel derived carbon as heat source, reducing agent of iron ores and carburising agent of reduced iron. Although the demand for drastic decrease of carbon dioxide emission, carbon is an essential element for smelting process of molten iron. The carbon recycling ironmaking process by circulating CO has been already proposed to achieve carbon neutrality. However, the production of molten hot metal is not considered in this process because sufficient amount of carbon does not dissolve in reduced iron by CO. Therefore, our group has suggested a new carbon recycling ironmaking process which can produce hot metal. In this process, free carbon and iron carbides produced by carbon deposition reaction using metallic iron as a catalyst are used. It is known that only Fe3C is obtained as iron carbide by using CO gas, however, Fe5C2 is also produced by adding H2 gas. The composite agglomerated with these carbonaceous materials and fine iron ore (Deposited Carbon-Iron oxide Composite: DCIC) is reduced and melted in a furnace. It is reported that Fe3C in DCIC accelerates the reduction reaction and melting of the composite. In this study, the effects of iron carbides and free carbon on the melting behaviour of DCIC are investigated. Fe3C, Fe5C2 and free carbon were produced by vapour deposition using porous iron whiskers and CO-CO2-H2 gas. These were agglomerated with hematite reagent at a certain ratio to prepare DCIC samples with and without Fe5C2. The samples were heated up to 1300&#176;C in inert atmosphere. The DCIC containing Fe5C2 completely melted and iron nuggets were obtained after the experiment. This behaviour was not observed in the composite without Fe5C2. This indicates that using Fe5C2 is more preferable than Fe3C for molten iron production using DCIC.</description>
      <author>Ryota Higashi, Daisuke Maruoka, Y. Iwami, T. Murakami</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/wewm2079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of fly ash and ground granulated blast furnace slag into palm oil fuel ash based geopolymer concrete: a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54113/j.sust.2024.000050</link>
      <description>Ying Yi Tan, Hanizam Awang, Noor Haida Mohd Kaus, Sustainable Structures. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402226535

                The construction industry significantly depends on concrete due to its mechanical attributes and economy efficiency. The increase demand for building materials, particularly concrete, has resulted in overproduction of ordinary portland cement (OPC) and consequent significant release of carbon dioxide (CO2) into the atmosphere. For addressing these issues, alternative innovative and sustainable materials, such as geopolymer concrete, which utilised waste materials as binding agents have been introduced, leading to a reduction in CO2 emissions. Palm oil fuel ash (POFA) contains abundant silicates and aluminates, making it well-suited for use as binder in geopolymer concrete. On the other hand, POFA geopolymer concrete with high volume exhibits reduced early strength development, decreased workability, and an extended setting time. Therefore, this review paper emphasizes the need of including fly ash (FA) and ground granulated blast furnace slag (GGBS) into POFA-based geopolymer concrete. A notable result of the review is that the inclusion of aluminium oxide and iron (III) oxide in FA improves the chloride binding capability, resulting to a dense microstructure with high strength. In addition, the presence of calcium oxide in FA and GGBS enhances the creation of C-S-H, N-A-S-H, and C-A-S-H gels, resulting in a decrease in porosity and an enhancement of the fresh and mechanical characteristics. Furthermore, the use of FA improves the insulation and thermal efficiency of the geopolymer concrete. Therefore, integration of FA and GGBS in POFA geopolymer may enhanced the mechanical and durability qualities. Further study is required to optimize the composition of POFA, FA and GGBS in the mix, and researching new, cost-effective alkaline activators obtained from waste products offers another avenue for boosting the efficiency of geopolymer synthesis.</description>
      <author>Ying Yi Tan, Hanizam Awang, Noor Haida Mohd Kaus</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54113/j.sust.2024.000050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Control of Ships&#8217; Oil-Fired Boilers Using Flame Image-Based IMC-PID and Deep Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12091603</link>
      <description>Chang-Min Lee, Byung-Gun Jung, Journal of Marine Science and Engineering. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402412729

                The control system of oil-fired boiler units on ships plays a crucial role in reducing the emissions of atmospheric pollutants such as nitrogen oxides (NOx), sulfur dioxides (SO2), and carbon dioxide (CO2). Traditional control methods using conventional measurement sensors face limitations in real-time control due to response delays, which has led to the growing interest in combustion control methods using flame images. To ensure the precision of such combustion control systems, the system model must be thoroughly considered during controller design. However, finding the optimal tuning point is challenging due to the changes in the system model and nonlinearity caused by environmental variations. This study proposes a controller that integrates an internal model control (IMC)-based PID controller with the deep deterministic policy gradient (DDPG) algorithm of deep reinforcement learning to enhance the adaptability of image-based combustion control systems to environmental changes. The proposed controller adjusts the PID parameter values in real-time through the learning of the determination constant lambda (&#955;) of the IMC internal model. This approach reduces computational resources by shrinking the learning dimensions of the DDPG agent and limits transient responses through constrained learning of control parameters. Experimental results show that the proposed controller exhibited rapid adaptive performance in the learning process for the target oxygen concentration, achieving a reward value of &#8722;0.05 within just 105 episodes. Furthermore, when compared to traditional PID tuning methods, the proposed controller demonstrated superior performance, achieving a target value error of 0.0032 and a low overshoot range of 0.0498 to 0.0631, providing the fastest response speed and minimal oscillation. Additionally, experiments conducted on an actual operating ship verified the practical feasibility of this system, highlighting its potential for real-time control and pollutant reduction in marine applications.</description>
      <author>Chang-Min Lee, Byung-Gun Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12091603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The key stages of injecting carbon dioxide into oil reservoirs in order to enhance oil recovery and stimulate oil production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31660/0445-0108-2024-4-119-135</link>
      <description>D.G. Afonin, Svetlana Gracheva, A.A. Ruchkin, A. &#1040;. Maximov, G. &#1040;. Shutskiy, Oil and Gas Studies. None(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402319961

                Solving the world-class problem of reducing greenhouse gas emissions into the atmosphere and potential utilization of carbon dioxide (CO 2 ), the article provides an overview of technologies for injecting CO 2 into the oil and gas reservoirs to enhance oil recovery and stimulate oil production. Two main methods of carbon dioxide (CO&#8322;) injection are proposed and described in detail. These are the Huff and Puff method, which involves the injection of CO&#8322; into production wells, and CO&#8322; injection into injection wells. The technology of injecting carbon dioxide into production wells has a number of advantages, such as the lack of capital costs and low operating costs, quick effect manifested in increased oil rates and efficient use of CO 2 . The general principle of the technology is the controlled supply of carbon dioxide through the mouth of a shut-in production well into the bottomhole formation zone. The efficiency of the technology is achieved primarily through the reduction of oil viscosity and volumetric expansion of oil, the decrease of interfacial tension, and the reduction of relative phase permeability by water. Consequently, residual oil saturation is reduced by the increase in the amount of trapped gas. The second technology for injecting carbon dioxide into injection wells to achieve a positive technological effect requires a larger volume of injection agent and a longer period for evaluation of the effect. The efficiency of the technology and the increase in the oil displacement ratio are achieved through the distribution of large volumes of injected carbon dioxide through low-permeability reservoir channels and involvement of residual oil. The article presents the necessary conditions and main stages of CO 2 injection process organization using the proposed technologies, and describes the composition of the required equipment. Special attention is paid to the necessity of using inhibitors to protect downhole equipment, as well as to the selection of suitable inhibitors, taking into account their physical and chemical characteristics, compatibility with other reagents and reservoir properties. The authors of the article have conducted an expert survey of the market for the availability of specialized equipment in Russia and the services of domestic manufacturers in the field of gas injection technologies. The conclusion of the article highlights the importance of CO 2 injection careful planning and monitoring, as well as the potential of gas-enhanced methods to improve production and reduce environmental impact.</description>
      <author>D.G. Afonin, Svetlana Gracheva, A.A. Ruchkin, A. &#1040;. Maximov, G. &#1040;. Shutskiy</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31660/0445-0108-2024-4-119-135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilized Cu0 -Cu1+ dual sites in a cyanamide framework for selective CO2 electroreduction to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52022-0</link>
      <description>Kaihang Yue, Yanyang Qin, Honghao Huang, Zhuoran Lv, Mingzhi Cai, Yaqiong Su, Fuqiang Huang, Ya Yan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402289288

                Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide to produce high-value ethylene is often limited by poor selectivity and yield of multi-carbon products. To address this, we propose a cyanamide-coordinated isolated copper framework with both metallic copper (Cu</description>
      <author>Kaihang Yue, Yanyang Qin, Honghao Huang, Zhuoran Lv, Mingzhi Cai, Yaqiong Su, Fuqiang Huang, Ya Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52022-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Carbon Reduction Technology Trends and Application Cases : About the Park and the Forest</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59386/jadr.2024.27.1.1</link>
      <description>Woo Ju Lee, S. Kim, Institute of Art &amp; Design Research. 27(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402379943

                As the threat of climate change due to global warming intensifies, the world is increasingly experiencing extreme weather phenomena. Consequently, the importance of achieving carbon neutrality is expected to grow. Parks and forests play a crucial role in capturing and storing carbon, offering the most eco-friendly spaces that provide convenience and relaxation for users, as well as resilience for cities. They also serve as essential elements of carbon neutrality with their scenic and touristic value. This study focuses on these aspects, reviewing the trends in existing carbon reduction technologies and investigating carbon dioxide capture and utilization technologies that can increase the amount of carbon that parks and forests can capture. These technologies were classified according to six principles, identifying bioconversion technology as the most applicable and dry capture and mineral carbonation technologies as relatively superior. The study analyzes the current policy foundation and shortcomings for the commercialization and business application of these technologies, along with future improvements that need to be addressed. The purpose of this research is to establish a foundation for creating carbon-neutral parks and forests by identifying applicable technologies, assessing policy hurdles, and suggesting improvements, thereby enabling faster and more efficient carbon absorption and storage. According to the findings of this study, by identifying and expanding the application of technologies suitable for parks and forests and improving policies accordingly, it is expected that a more eco-friendly and efficient reduction of carbon dioxide can be achieved.</description>
      <author>Woo Ju Lee, S. Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59386/jadr.2024.27.1.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide Absorption And Channelling In Closed Circuit Rebreather Scrubbers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34719/conf8104</link>
      <description>Shona Cunningham, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402232145

                "Closed Circuit Rebreathers (CCRs) are a type of Self Contained Underwater Breathing Apparatus (SCUBA) used predominantly by the diving community. CCR technologies have become prevalent within the commercial, military and technical diving communities over recent years. CCRs work by recycling breathing gas, by-passing the gas through a carbon dioxide (CO2)chemical scrubber and topping the resultant scrubbed gas up with pure oxygen to maintain the oxygen content at a level which supports life. One of the main dangers currently faced by divers using this equipment is the risk of CO2 poisoning if the scrubber fails. This failure occurs due to CO2 breakthrough - where breakthrough is defined as the time until the canister effluent passes through the chemical absorbent unscrubbed. There are a variety of reasons for CO2 breakthrough, and not all of the reasons can be identified by the operator. A better understanding of CO2 absorption within CCRs would lead to a reduction in failures. There are a variety of potential causes of CO2 breakthrough, where breakthrough is defined as the time until the canister effluent passes through the chemical absorbent unscrubbed. Not all of the causes can be compensated for by the operator. A transient computational fluid dynamic (CFD) model investigating the kinetics of flow and CO2 absorption focusing on the chemical reaction between the absorbent soda lime and CO2 is presented in the thesis. It presents the first reported mixture model theory simulation of the CCR scrubber using Ansys CFX 13.0. An extensive review of the design of CCRs, their applications and current modelling techniques identified a need to enhance the simulation of CCRs using the mixture model theory to simulate the chemical reactions occurring within the scrubber system of the CCR. The application of CFD techniques on CCRs allows the in depth analysis of the reaction between soda lime and CO2 using the graphical display provided by the simulated model. The simulation studies undertaken present a transient model with the ability to investigate seven key parameters affecting scrubber performance; geometry, wall temperature, inlet velocity, pressure, CO2 absorption, granule size and material selection. Analyses of the results demonstrate the sensitivity of the parameters to their behaviour on CO2 breakthrough. Due to the requirement of strong coupling between the phases of CO2 and soda lime, the mixture model is the best suited model for the liquid-particle mixture. Analysis of mesh size, mesh type and inflation are made to independently characterise the accuracy of the presented model by means of convergence before further comparisons with experimental data. The importance of mesh refinement is demonstrated as well as the contribution of inflation and grid independence to the accuracy of the model. A versatile model simulating chemical reactions within a CCR canister for different geometrical scrubber designs has been shown to be capable of analysing the design parameters of interest. A CCR scrubber model will bring new learning into the kinetics of CO2 absorption. It may also further the technology of monitoring scrubber duration in real time for a user. Data collected from a user may be fed into the system to allow a visual analysis of the scrubber. The first section of this thesis describes the operational requirements of the CCR system and in order to validate the CFD model, an experimental program was designed where an experimental test rig was manufactured to undertake experiments to study the impact of CO2 breakthrough of various parameters. The system incorporated CO2, O2, humidity and temperature sensors where the rig tested the scrubber&#8217;s capacity to absorb CO2 which is pumped in a controlled environment to benchmark the initial designs against existing literature. A review of the state of the art identified five feasible parameters important to scrubber kinetics; (i) geometry, (ii) material selection, (iii) inlet gas velocity, (iv) granule size and (v) packaging of the granules. These results gave an indication to the scrubber&#8217;s capacity to absorb CO2. CO2 absorption can be further inferred by placing thermocouples at various places within the canister and using relationship between the reaction and temperature to give an indication of absorption within the scrubber. As the chemical reaction occurs, the temperature rises and water vapour is produced. Through measuring both temperature and humidity, it was found that temperature gave the most consistent indication of CO2&gt; absorption rather than humidity as the higher the humidity levels, the more erratic the humidity results became. The result of the experimental testing is a body of data benchmarked off current literature for validation which is used to compare with a transient CFD model to further the knowledge of CO2 absorption. The development of a CFD model for the CCR scrubber allows the simulation to assist in future designs of CCR system. It allows the simulation of alternative scrubber geometries which may be subjected to external parameters to assess their performance. The advantage to implementing a design through CFD allows the user to simulate alternative CCR scrubber designs before incorporating a manufacturing cost to assess the performance of a given design. This reduces cost, time and can assist the decision of manufacturing a given CCR scrubber. The results demonstrate that the CFD simulation using the mixture model theory is sufficiently reliable to simulate the reaction between CO and soda lime in CCR scrubbers."</description>
      <author>Shona Cunningham</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34719/conf8104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decarbonisation Innovation Approach to Address Global Methane Pledge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/220323-ms</link>
      <description>Fatima AlRaeesi, D. Bandopadhyay, S. AlMazrouie, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402426351

                Abstract Aligned with UAE&#8217;s Net Zero Pledge and ADNOC&#8217;s Sustainability Targets 2030, ADNOC Gas has developed a robust decarbonization roadmap to accomplish 25%+ GHG emission reduction by 2030 compared to baseline year of 2019, through Innovation and technological interventions. In addition, ADNOC has endorsed the "Oil &amp; Gas Methane Partnership (OGMP 2.0)", undertaking methane monitoring from all its sources and taking actions to reduce methane emissions, a key contributor to overall GHG emissions. Towards its commitment to achieve zero methane emission by 2030, ADNOC Gas has implemented state-of-the-art flare.IQ technology, an Advance Process Control (APC) application to optimize flare operations, demonstrating real-time improvement in the combustion efficiency and steam/fuel savings, thereby reducing methane and overall GHG emissions. The paper explains how Baker Hughes arrived at its flare.IQ solution. Having developed the flare.IQ solution, the paper will go on to describe how complex its technology works. In short, using an advanced analytics platform, operators can pull critical information about their flare system, including temperature, pressure, vent gas velocities and gas composition to calculate the optimum levels of flare performance and ensure 98%+ high-efficiency flare combustion. To address this challenge and in line with ADNOC commitment towards Oil and Gas Methane Partnership (OGMP) 2.0 Gold Standard, ADNOC Gas, in partnership with M/s Baker Hughes, introduced a state-of-the-art flare.IQ technology, an integrated hardware, software, and service solution for the management of flare gas. It functions as an Advanced Process Controller taking flare conditions (flow, temperature, pressure, BTU) as inputs, calculating against a model and outputs set points to the Distributed Control System (DCS) for air assist flow rate and fuel gas flow rate to achieve required destruction efficiency of the flare system. This control-based solution significantly improves flare combustion efficiency, reduces the cover gas consumption, and provides smokeless flaring. ADNOC Gas successfully implemented the flare.IQ technology in one of its facilities to optimize flare operations, monitor and reduce emissions in real time resulting in smokeless flaring and operational savings. Flare.IQ Technology supports ADNOC Digitalization, having its solution development, the complex technology works using an advanced analytics platform where operators can pull critical information about their flare system including temperature, pressure, vent gas. The key benefits of the flare.IQ Technology include: Optimizing the combustion efficiency to Combustion Efficiency (CE)% &amp;gt;98% in assisted flares Methane (CH4) Emission quantification and reduction in compliance to OGMP 2.0 Level 4 monitoring Improve overall flare operational efficiency by optimizing steam and fuel consumption resulting in savings. Achieve smokeless flare operation when operated in cascade mode. Real-time monitoring of combustion efficiency, Net Heating Value (NHV), Carbon Dioxide Equivalent (CO2eq), Carbon Dioxide (CO2), Carbon Monoxide (CO), Volatile Organic Compounds (VOC). Replace static emissions factors with real-time CE / DRE measurement. Identify issues early and intervene quickly by having access to real-time combustion efficiency data on the production floor. Methane emission is one of the most critical focus areas to combat climate change and are a prevalent talking point in the public domain. Flare.IQ is an emerging solution that is easy to deploy, cost effective and is being rapidly deployed by the industry. With the oil and gas industry keen to raise awareness of its response to combatting emissions, flare.IQ is a largely untold positive story. Methane is a major greenhouse gas with a Global Warming Potential (GWP) of 27-30 over 100 years. Oil and Gas sector is responsible for around +30% of global methane emissions and poses huge challenge to limit these emissions towards the global battle against climate change [2]. At ADNOC, unburnt combustion in the flares contributes more than 50% of total methane emissions. Further, uncontrolled consumption of cover gas or steam (high fuel consumption) in association with flaring leads to higher GHG emissions. Accordingly, ADNOC is striving to leverage innovation and technological interventions to address this challenge.</description>
      <author>Fatima AlRaeesi, D. Bandopadhyay, S. AlMazrouie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/220323-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should electric vehicle purchase subsidies be linked with scrappage requirements?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pam.22639</link>
      <description>Kevin Ankney, Benjamin Leard, Journal of Policy Analysis and Management. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402239004

                Abstract We build a vehicle purchase and disposal model to analyze a policy that links a new electric vehicle (EV) purchase subsidy with a used gasoline vehicle scrappage requirement. We evaluate the policy based on changes in sales, scrappage, subsidy dollars spent, and emissions reductions. We find that linking a purchase subsidy with a scrappage requirement is expected to result in fewer new EV sales and carbon dioxide emissions reductions relative to a policy without linking. Our modeling reveals that these effects are due to trade&#8208;in vehicle eligibility requirements and opportunity costs lowering additional participation in the linked policy. However, the linked policy significantly increases used vehicle scrappage and is more progressive than the unlinked policy. We find that emissions reductions due to additional scrappage are sensitive to how remaining miles of scrapped vehicles are replaced.</description>
      <author>Kevin Ankney, Benjamin Leard</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pam.22639</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interaction of Carbon Dioxide with Hydrogen on Supported Fe,Cr-Containing Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34984/scftp.2021.16.3.006</link>
      <description>Oh-Joong Kim, &#1058;.&#1042;. &#1041;&#1086;&#1075;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;, &#1040;.&#1045;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1082;&#1083;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1042;.&#1048;. &#1041;&#1086;&#1075;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;, No host. 16(3(3))] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4402273946

                &#1048;&#1079;&#1091;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086; &#1074;&#1086;&#1089;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1076;&#1080;&#1086;&#1082;&#1089;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072; &#1084;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1091;&#1083;&#1103;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084; &#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1084; &#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1089;&#1091;&#1090;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1080;&#1080; Fe, Cr-&#1082;&#1072;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1085;&#1072;&#1085;&#1077;&#1089;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1085;&#1072; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1084;&#1072;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1072;&#1083; &#1057;&#1080;&#1073;&#1091;&#1085;&#1080;&#1090;, &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; 400 &#176;&#1057; &#1080; &#1076;&#1072;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;&#1093;) 0,1 &#1080; 8,5 &#1052;&#1055;&#1072;. &#1057;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1077; &#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1084;&#1086;&#1085;&#1086;&#1086;&#1082;&#1089;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072; &#1074;&#1086;&#1079;&#1084;&#1086;&#1078;&#1085;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1089;&#1086;&#1086;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074; Fe/Cr &#1074; &#1082;&#1072;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1077;, &#1088;&#1072;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084; 1-5. &#1055;&#1088;&#1080; &#1091;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1100;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1089;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1088;&#1078;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1093;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;&#1072; (&#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1077;&#1094; 5Fe-0,25Cr/C) &#1085;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1091; &#1089; CO &#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1091;&#1102;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1099; C-C &#1089; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1086;&#1073;&#1083;&#1072;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077;&#1084; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1072;. &#1052;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1084; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1074;&#1077;&#1095;&#1080;&#1074;&#1072;&#1102;&#1097;&#1077;&#1081; &#1101;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1084;&#1080;&#1082;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1087;&#1080;&#1080; &#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1092;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1081; &#1074; &#1082;&#1072;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1077; 5Fe-5Cr/C &#1103;&#1074;&#1083;&#1103;&#1077;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1093;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;&#1080;&#1090; &#1078;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1079;&#1072; FeCrO (&#1089;&#1090;&#1088;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1091;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1090;&#1080;&#1087; &#1096;&#1087;&#1080;&#1085;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;), &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1087;&#1103;&#1090;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1091;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1081; &#1074;&#1086;&#1089;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1078;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1079;&#1072; &#1080; &#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1077;&#1075;&#1086; &#1082;&#1072;&#1088;&#1073;&#1080;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1082;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1099;&#1077;, &#1074; &#1089;&#1074;&#1086;&#1102; &#1086;&#1095;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1100;, &#1086;&#1073;&#1077;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1095;&#1080;&#1074;&#1072;&#1102;&#1090; &#1089;&#1080;&#1085;&#1090;&#1077;&#1079; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1072;&#1080;&#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1080;&#1080; &#1057;O &#1080; &#1053;. The reduction of carbon dioxide with molecular hydrogen in the presence of Fe,Cr-containing catalysts supported on Sibunit carbon material at 400C and pressures of 0,1 and 8,5 MPa was studied. Selective formation of carbon monoxide is possible over the catalysts with the ratio Fe: Cr = 1-5. C-C hydrocarbons with a predominance of methane are formed along with CO at decreasing chromium content in the catalyst (5Fe-0,25Cr/C sample). It was shown by transmission electron microscopy that the main phase in 5Fe-5Cr/C catalyst is iron chromite FeCrO (spinel structural type), which prevents the reduction of iron and the formation of its carbides, which, in turn, provide the formation of hydrocarbons upon the interaction of CO and H.</description>
      <author>Oh-Joong Kim, &#1058;.&#1042;. &#1041;&#1086;&#1075;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;, &#1040;.&#1045;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1082;&#1083;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1042;.&#1048;. &#1041;&#1086;&#1075;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34984/scftp.2021.16.3.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on Transition Metal-Doped Cu Clusters: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/9789815274042124010005</link>
      <description>Ambrish Kumar Srivastava, Ruby Srivastava, BENTHAM SCIENCE PUBLISHERS eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402322943

                Activation of CO2 is the first step towards its reduction to more useful chemicals. Electrochemical CO2 reduction reactions can lead to high value-added chemical and materials production while helping decrease anthropogenic CO2 emissions. In studies, it was found that copper metal clusters can reduce CO2 to more than thirty different hydrocarbons and oxygenates, yet they lack the required selectivity. Density functional theory (DFT)-based studies are carried out on copper clusters, doped clusters, nano-structures and Cu-based alloy catalysts to assess the activity and selectivity of CO2 reduction to generate carbon monoxide (CO), formic acid (HCOOH), formaldehyde (H2C=O), methanol (CH3OH) and methane (CH4 ). In this chapter, we will discuss the effect of the adsorption of CO2 on (Sc, Ti, V) metaldoped clusters. DFT studies carried out for these clusters showed a high CO2 adsorption energy, a low activation barrier for its dissociation, and a facile regeneration of the clusters. The reaction energies (dopant-dependent), the mechanisms for reaction, dissociation barriers for CO2, and less desorption energies (dopant dependent) for carbon monoxide (CO) during the activation of CO2 with Cu3X clusters (X= first row transition metals) are discussed in the chapter. C6Li6 is not capable of capturing CO2 molecules but is effective in their storage. The interaction of CO2with superalkalis such as FLi2 , OLi3 , and NLi4 and non-metallic superalkalis such as F2H3 , O2H5, and N2H7 is also included due to its applications.</description>
      <author>Ambrish Kumar Srivastava, Ruby Srivastava</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/9789815274042124010005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Not to Reduce Carbon Dioxide Emissions: An Unbalanced Focus on Energy Efficiency in Germany&#8217;s Building Rehabilitation Policies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174524</link>
      <description>Ray Galvin, Energies. 17(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402363897

                Germany needs to reduce CO2 emissions from space heating in its old buildings to net zero by 2045 to fulfil its climate goals. However, direct CO2 reduction measures in existing buildings receive relatively little subsidy support from the federal government&#8217;s German Development Bank, compared to generous subsidies for energy efficiency measures. This interdisciplinary paper evaluates this phenomenon by comparing costs and CO2 abatement effects of ever higher energy efficiency measures, alongside the costs of direct CO2 reduction through heat pumps and onsite photovoltaics. It uses a set of carefully selected reports on the costs and benefits of renovation to a range of energy efficiency standards in three common types of multi-apartment buildings in Germany, updating these for 2024 construction, energy, and finance costs. The cost of the CO2 saved is extremely high with energy efficiency measures and absurdly high with the highest energy efficiency standards, up to 20 times the cost of CO2 abatement through other means, such as offsite renewables. This reduces markedly with onsite CO2 reduction measures. This paper sets this analysis in the context of asking what social, cultural, and discursive factors extol energy efficiency so highly that policy tends to thwart its own stated goal of deeply reducing CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Ray Galvin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aluminothermic production of silicon using different raw materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/kzgl1297</link>
      <description>Katarina Jakovljevi&#263;, N Simkhada, Ming Zhu, Maria Wallin, Gabriella Tranell, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383192

                Silicon is a vital element in many products today, such as electronic components, solar devices, high-quality alloys, and many others. The growing global demand highlights the need for the development of sustainable production methods to meet this demand as an alternative to the current carbothermic reduction, submerged arc furnace (SAF) based process. An alternative to this is the aluminothermic reduction of quartz in a CaO-SiO2 slag, which not only reduces direct carbon dioxide emissions but also promotes the utilisation of secondary raw materials such as quartz fines, aluminium dross and scrap as well as secondary alumina (SA) from dross recycling. In the current study, the effects of SA and CaF2 additions to slag on the resulting metal composition and metal yield were explored. Results were compared with thermodynamic simulations using FactSage&#8482; 8.1. Experimental results show that, in agreement with thermodynamic simulations, the silicon content of the alloy is increased, while the Ca is decreased for starting slags where CaO-SiO2 is partly replaced by CaF2. Similarly, the addition of SA to the initial slag results in an alloy with a higher silicon content.</description>
      <author>Katarina Jakovljevi&#263;, N Simkhada, Ming Zhu, Maria Wallin, Gabriella Tranell</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/kzgl1297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Residential Hydrogen Facilities with Waste Heat Recovery: Economic Feasibility across Various European Cities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091933</link>
      <description>Evangelos Pompodakis, Arif Ahmed, Georgios I. Orfanoudakis, Emmanuel Karapidakis, Processes. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402368349

                The European Union has established ambitious targets for lowering carbon dioxide emissions in the residential sector, aiming for all new buildings to be &#8220;zero-emission&#8221; by 2030. Integrating solar generators with hydrogen storage systems is emerging as a viable solution for achieving these goals in homes. This paper introduces a linear programming optimization algorithm aimed at improving the installation capacity of residential solar&#8211;hydrogen systems, which also utilize waste heat recovery from electrolyzers and fuel cells to increase the overall efficiency of the system. Analyzing six European cities with diverse climate conditions, our techno-economic assessments show that optimized configurations of these systems can lead to significant net present cost savings for electricity and heat over a 20-year period, with potential savings up to EUR 63,000, which amounts to a 26% cost reduction, especially in Southern Europe due to its abundant solar resources. Furthermore, these systems enhance sustainability and viability in the residential sector by significantly reducing carbon emissions. Our study does not account for the potential economic benefits from EU subsidies. Instead, we propose a novel incentive policy that allows owners of solar&#8211;hydrogen systems to inject up to 20% of their total solar power output directly into the grid, bypassing hydrogen storage. This strategy provides two key advantages: first, it enables owners to profit by selling the excess photovoltaic power during peak midday hours, rather than curtailing production; second, it facilitates a reduction in the size&#8212;and therefore cost&#8212;of the electrolyzer.</description>
      <author>Evangelos Pompodakis, Arif Ahmed, Georgios I. Orfanoudakis, Emmanuel Karapidakis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of Metal-Hypercrosslinked Polystyrene Composites in a Supercritical Carbon Dioxide Medium and their Catalytic Properties in the Hydrogenation of Diphenyl Acetylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34984/scftp.2021.16.4.001</link>
      <description>A. E. Lazhko, &#1052;.&#1054;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Ekaterina Ponomareva, &#1054;.&#1054;. &#1055;&#1072;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072;&#1075;&#1086;, &#1043;. &#1054;. &#1041;&#1088;&#1072;&#1075;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, O. P. Parenago, No host. 16(4(4))] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4402274192

                &#1048;&#1084;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1075;&#1085;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1077;&#1081; &#1089;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1089;&#1096;&#1080;&#1090;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1080;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1083;&#1072; (&#1057;&#1057;&#1055;) &#1089;&#1086;&#1077;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;&#1084;&#1080; &#1087;&#1072;&#1083;&#1083;&#1072;&#1076;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080; &#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074; &#1089;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077; &#1089;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1082;&#1088;&#1080;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1076;&#1080;&#1086;&#1082;&#1089;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072; (&#1057;&#1050;-&#1057;0) &#1089; &#1080;&#1093; &#1087;&#1086;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1091;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1084; &#1074;&#1086;&#1089;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077;&#1084; &#1076;&#1086; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1089;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1103;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1084;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1091;&#1083;&#1103;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084; &#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1084; &#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1091;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1099; &#1082;&#1086;&#1084;&#1087;&#1086;&#1079;&#1080;&#1090;&#1099; &#171;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1083;-&#1057;&#1057;&#1055;&#187;, &#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1074; &#1075;&#1080;&#1076;&#1088;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072;&#1089;&#1099;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;. &#1054;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086; &#1074;&#1083;&#1080;&#1103;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1091;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1082;&#1086;&#1084;&#1087;&#1086;&#1079;&#1080;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1085;&#1072; &#1080;&#1093; &#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1100; &#1080; &#1089;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1100; &#1074; &#1075;&#1080;&#1076;&#1088;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1076;&#1080;&#1092;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1083;&#1072;&#1094;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072; (&#1044;&#1060;&#1040;). &#1042;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1074;&#1099;&#1077; &#1080;&#1079;&#1091;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072; &#1072;&#1076;&#1089;&#1086;&#1088;&#1073;&#1094;&#1080;&#1103; &#1075;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1072;&#1092;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1072;&#1094;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1083;&#1072;&#1094;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;&#1090;&#1072; &#1087;&#1072;&#1083;&#1083;&#1072;&#1076;&#1080;&#1103; &#1085;&#1072; &#1057;&#1057;&#1055; &#1080;&#1079; &#1089;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1099; &#1057;&#1050;-&#1057;0 &#1089; &#1080;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077;&#1084; &#1089;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1082;&#1088;&#1080;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1081; &#1092;&#1083;&#1102;&#1080;&#1076;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1093;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1075;&#1088;&#1072;&#1092;&#1080;&#1080; (&#1057;&#1050;&#1060;-&#1093;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;&#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1075;&#1088;&#1072;&#1092;&#1080;&#1103;); &#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1088;&#1072;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1089;&#1080;&#1077; &#1072;&#1076;&#1089;&#1086;&#1088;&#1073;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1086;&#1087;&#1080;&#1089;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072;&#1077;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1091;&#1088;&#1072;&#1074;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077;&#1084; &#1051;&#1077;&#1085;&#1075;&#1084;&#1102;&#1088;&#1072;. Metal - hyper-cross-linked polystyrene (HCP) composites active in the hydrogenation of unsaturated hydrocarbons were obtained by impregnation of HCP with palladium and rhodium compounds in supercritical carbon dioxide (SC-CO) followed by their reduction to the metallic state with molecular hydrogen. The influence of the conditions for the preparation of composites on their activity and selectivity in the hydrogenation of diphenylacetylene (DFA) was evaluated. The adsorption of palladium hexafluoroacetylacetonate on HCP from the SC-CO medium was studied for the first time using supercritical fluid chromatography; it is shown that the adsorption equilibrium is described by the Langmuir equation.</description>
      <author>A. E. Lazhko, &#1052;.&#1054;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Ekaterina Ponomareva, &#1054;.&#1054;. &#1055;&#1072;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072;&#1075;&#1086;, &#1043;. &#1054;. &#1041;&#1088;&#1072;&#1075;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, O. P. Parenago</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.34984/scftp.2021.16.4.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecularly Woven Cationic Covalent Organic Frameworks for Highly Selective Electrocatalytic Conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408152</link>
      <description>Fentahun Wondu Dagnaw, Karim Harrath, Tao Zheng, Xudong Wu, Yuren Liu, Rui&#8208;Qi Li, Luo&#8208;Han Xie, Jia Li, Xuezhong He, Qing&#8208;Xiao Tong, Jing&#8208;Xin Jian, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402393801

                Abstract Coupling carbon capture with electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (CO 2 R) to yield high&#8208;value chemicals presents an appealing avenue for combating climate change, yet achieving highly selective electrocatalysts remains a significant challenge. Herein, two molecularly woven covalent organic frameworks (COFs) are designed, namely CuCOF and CuCOF + , with copper(I)&#8208;bisphenanthroline complexes as building blocks. The metal&#8211;organic helical structure unit made the CuCOF and CuCOF + present woven patterns, and their ordered pore structures and cationic properties enhanced their CO 2 adsorption and good conductivity, which is confirmed by gas adsorption and electrochemical analysis. In the electrocatalytic CO 2 R measurements, CuCOF + decorated with extra ethyl groups exhibit a main CO product with selectivity of 57.81%, outperforming the CuCOF with 42.92% CO at the same applied potential of 0.8 V RHE . After loading Pd nanoparticles, CuCOF&#8208;Pd and CuCOF + &#8208;Pd performed increased CO selectivity up to 84.97% and 95.45%, respectively. Combining the DFT theoretical calculations and experimental measurements, it is assumed that the molecularly woven cationic COF provides a catalytic microenvironment for CO 2 R and ensures efficient charge transfer from the electrode to the catalytic center, thereby achieving high electrocatalytic activity and selectivity. The present work significantly advances the practice of cationic COFs in real&#8208;time CO 2 capture and highly selective conversion to value&#8208;added chemicals.</description>
      <author>Fentahun Wondu Dagnaw, Karim Harrath, Tao Zheng, Xudong Wu, Yuren Liu, Rui&#8208;Qi Li, Luo&#8208;Han Xie, Jia Li, Xuezhong He, Qing&#8208;Xiao Tong, Jing&#8208;Xin Jian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Investigation of a Water&#8211;Air Heat Recovery System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177686</link>
      <description>Robert &#536;tefan Vizitiu, &#536;tef&#259;nica Eliza Vizitiu, Andrei Burlacu, C. Abid, Marius Costel B&#259;lan, Nicoleta Elena Kaba, Sustainability. 16(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402227907

                The implementation of energy-saving measures has a substantial and beneficial impact on the preservation of energy resources as well as the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions. This study focuses on the design and experimental analysis of a water-to-air heat recovery system aimed at capturing waste heat from wastewater and transferring it to a fresh cold air stream using heat pipe technology. The research problem addressed in this study is the efficient recovery of low-grade thermal energy from wastewater, which is often underutilized. The prototype heat recovery unit was designed, manufactured, and tested in the laboratory to assess its performance across various operating conditions. The experimental setup included a system where the primary agent, hot water, was heated to 60 &#176;C and circulated through the evaporator section of the heat recovery unit, while the secondary agent, fresh air, was forced through the condenser section. The system&#8217;s performance was evaluated under different air velocities, ranging from 3.5 m/s to 4.5 m/s, corresponding to airflow rates of 207.1 m3/h and 268.6 m3/h, respectively. The study employed analytical methods alongside empirical testing to determine the effectiveness of the heat recovery system, with the global heat transfer coefficient calculated for different scenarios. The efficiency of the system varied between 25% and 51.6%, depending on the temperature and speed of the fresh air stream. The most significant temperature difference observed between the inflow and outflow of the fresh air stream was 16.8 &#176;C, resulting in a thermal output of 1553 W. Additionally, the average (mean) overall heat transfer coefficient of the unit was calculated to be 49 W/m2 K, which aligns with values reported in the literature for similar systems. The results demonstrate the potential of the designed system for practical applications in energy conservation and carbon emission reduction.</description>
      <author>Robert &#536;tefan Vizitiu, &#536;tef&#259;nica Eliza Vizitiu, Andrei Burlacu, C. Abid, Marius Costel B&#259;lan, Nicoleta Elena Kaba</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>l-Lactate dehydrogenase from Cyanidioschyzon merolae shows high catalytic efficiency for pyruvate reduction and is inhibited by ATP</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11103-024-01495-0</link>
      <description>Mai Sugiyama, Takashi Osanai, Shoki Ito, Plant Molecular Biology. 114(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402407183

                Abstract l -Lactate is a commodity chemical used in various fields. Microorganisms have produced l -lactate via lactic fermentation using saccharides derived from crops as carbon sources. Recently, l -lactate production using microalgae, whose carbon source is carbon dioxide, has been spotlighted because the prices of the crops have increased. A red alga Cyanidioschyzon merolae produce l -lactate via lactic fermentation under dark anaerobic conditions. The l -lactate titer of C. merolae is higher than those of other microalgae but lower than those of heterotrophic bacteria. Therefore, an increase in the l -lactate titer is required in C. merolae . l -Lactate dehydrogenase ( l -LDH) catalyzes the reduction of pyruvate to l -lactate during lactic fermentation. C. merolae possesses five isozymes of l -LDH. The results of previous transcriptome analysis suggested that l -LDHs are the key enzymes in the lactic fermentation of C. merolae . However, their biochemical characteristics, such as catalytic efficiency and tolerance for metabolites, have not been revealed. We compared the amino acid sequences of C. merolae l -LDHs ( Cm LDHs) and characterized one of the isozymes, Cm LDH1. BLAST analysis revealed that the sequence similarities of Cm LDH1 and the other isozymes were above 99%. The catalytic efficiency of Cm LDH1 under its optimum conditions was higher than those of l -LDHs of other organisms. ATP decreased the affinity and turnover number of Cm LDH1 for NADH. These findings contribute to understanding the characteristics of l -LDHs of microalgae and the regulatory mechanisms of lactic fermentation in C. merolae .</description>
      <author>Mai Sugiyama, Takashi Osanai, Shoki Ito</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11103-024-01495-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing CO2 Emissions by Off-Grid Photovoltaic Systems: A Case Study in the Departamento del Magdalena - Colombia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.15750</link>
      <description>Carlos Robles-Algar&#237;n, Diego Restrepo-Leal, Maryam Carrillo-Reales, International Journal of Energy Economics and Policy. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402334455

                This paper presents projections on the reduction of CO2 emissions through the implementation of off-grid PV systems on 33 farms located in rural areas of the Departamento del Magdalena, where horticultural activities are performed by small local producers. To achieve this, the emission reduction was estimated for a period of 25 years using the installed PV peak power on each farm, data from the Global Solar Atlas, the emission factor in Colombia for electricity generation and information established in the harmonization project of the National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL). In order to compare the estimations, temperature and solar irradiance data were obtained from 10 farms near the installations, located in 8 municipalities within the department. With these data and through mathematical modeling, the energy generated by each PV system and the projection of non-emitted CO2 emissions were calculated. The results obtained demonstrated that, in both cases, the projections for emission reduction are similar, highlighting that the municipalities of Ci&#233;naga and Sitio Nuevo contribute the highest amount of saved CO2 due to the projections of higher energy production in these locations.</description>
      <author>Carlos Robles-Algar&#237;n, Diego Restrepo-Leal, Maryam Carrillo-Reales</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.15750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A study of heat and material balances in direct reduction plant with various conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/eswo9966</link>
      <description>Min Sun, Hyunyong Kim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383718

                Global steel companies are actively combating climate change by reducing carbon emissions. Traditional steel production, using the blast furnace (BF) &#8211; basic oxygen furnace (BOF) process, heavily depends on coal and emits substantial CO2. To mitigate this, companies are transitioning to the more eco-friendly DRP (direct reduction plant) &#8211; EAF (electric arc furnace) process, which lowers CO2 emissions. This study quantitatively evaluates the impact of increased hydrogen consumption on the carbon footprint of product (CFP) through an analysis of direct reduction process heat and mass balances. The study prioritises a comprehensive material balance based on mass conservation principles. The heat balance is calculated using differences in enthalpy through state energy properties, avoiding heat consumption. Validation using operational data from Hyundai Steel Dangjin works&#8217; blast furnaces shows close alignment between calculated results and actual data, with less than 1 per cent error. This methodology facilitates a detailed analysis of the direct reduction process, offering insights into its feasibility and efficiency. Analysis of the operational impact by increasing the hydrogen ratio demonstrates reduced CO2 emissions and increased heat requirements due to the endothermic nature of hydrogen reduction, in contrast to the exothermic CO reduction. Possible solutions include raising reducing gas temperature or enhancing flow rate. The study effectively utilises designed heat and mass balances to assess material quantities and thermal balance under different operational conditions. It lays the foundation for the initial direct reduction process design, aiding in deriving and optimising operational parameters. Additionally, it provides valuable insights into the challenges of increased hydrogen, contributing to the production of greener steel by addressing these issues.</description>
      <author>Min Sun, Hyunyong Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/eswo9966</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolytic reduction of metal sulfides/oxides in molten salts for sustainable metal production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/unyj2040</link>
      <description>Xiang Hu, Lena Sundqvist &#214;kvist, Johan Bj&#246;rkvall, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402384129

                The metal production industry is a significant contributor to global CO2 emissions due to the use of fossil fuels such as coal and coke. To mitigate these emissions and meet climate goals, innovative and sustainable technologies are required. Molten salt electrolysis is a promising technology that directly produces metals from their precursor sulfides or oxides using electricity. When combined with renewable electricity and an inert anode, the electrolysis process can be carbon neutral. This paper presents the results of two pilot-scale studies on the electrolytic reduction of metal oxides and sulfides in molten salts. The first study focuses on the electrolytic reduction of chalcopyrite in molten NaCl-KCl salt. The results demonstrate that in situ separation of copper, iron, and sulfur is possible, enabling the extraction of all valuable elements without CO2 emissions. Furthermore, the findings underscore the capability to eliminate impurities like zinc, antimony, arsenic, and mercury from the electrolysis product. The second study investigates the electrolytic reduction of pure/synthetic chemicals of w&#252;stite, hematite, and magnetite, as well as a magnetite-type iron ore in molten NaOH salt. The findings reveal a stepwise reduction of iron oxides from high valence to low valence, ultimately leading to the production of metallic iron electrolytically. Notably, this study underscores the challenges associated with the selection of an economically viable and durable inert anode material for efficient oxygen generation. These results indicate that molten salt electrolysis provides a sustainable and green route for base metal production. The use of this technology has the potential to significantly reduce CO2 emissions in the metal production industry, contributing to achieving climate goals.</description>
      <author>Xiang Hu, Lena Sundqvist &#214;kvist, Johan Bj&#246;rkvall</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/unyj2040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specific features of production and use of transport biofuels in selected developing countries (part I)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35854/1998-1627-2024-7-781-790</link>
      <description>Maksim Golovin, N. N. Dudkin, A. S. Pechatnova, Economics and Management. 30(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402266928

                Aim. To identify specific features of production and use of transportation biofuels in selected developing countries, as well as to assess the potential of bioethanol industry development in the Russian Federation (RF). Objectives . To generalize the experience of production and use of transport biofuels in Brazil, China and Indonesia; to determine the specifics of biofuel industry development in the mentioned developing countries. Methods. The methods of system analysis, comparative analysis, method of expert evaluations, mathematical, statistical methods were applied in the process of research. Results. The specificity of biofuel industry development in Brazil, China and Indonesia is shown. The production and use of transportation biofuels in these countries is carried out within the framework of a systemic state policy focused on diversification of energy consumption, promotion of renewable energy sources, reduction of pollutant emissions and stimulation of economic growth. Opportunities and risks for the development of production and use of transportation biofuels have been identified. The opportunities include, first of all, the formation of additional demand for agricultural products (including waste) and reduction of carbon dioxide emissions from the transport sector. At the same time, the production of first-generation transportation biofuels can negatively affect food security, reorienting agricultural producers from the production of &#8220;food&#8221; to the production of &#8220;raw materials for the energy sector&#8221;, and natural ecosystems, contributing to the involvement of new land plots in agricultural turnover. Conclusions. System analysis of the accumulated experience of production and use of transport biofuels in Brazil, China and Indonesia indicates the promising development of bioethanol industry in Russia. At the same time, the realization of this direction should not contribute to the strengthening of anthropogenic impact on the environment and adversely affect the availability of food.</description>
      <author>Maksim Golovin, N. N. Dudkin, A. S. Pechatnova</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35854/1998-1627-2024-7-781-790</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Composition of Exogenous Dissolved Organic Matter Regulates Dissimilatory Iron Reduction and Carbon Emissions in Paddy Soil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0323.v1</link>
      <description>Li Wang, X. Liu, Yuchen Shu, Gang Li, Cen Sun, Davey L. Jones, Yong&#8208;Guan Zhu, Xianyong Lin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402288064

                Soil carbon (C) cycling under anoxic conditions is mechanistically linked to dissimilatory iron (Fe) reduction, which could be regulated by exogenous dissolved organic matter (DOM). However, the impact of complex exogenous DOM on soil microbial activity and C-Fe coupling in paddy soils remains underexplored. With a 100-day microcosm experiment, we determined that the molecular composition of DOM derived from organic fertilizers and biochar on paddy soil affects soil microbial community, Fe reduction, and C emissions. Our results indicated that biochar-DOM significantly promoted Fe reduction and accelerated CH4 and CO2 emissions, and organic manure-DOM increased soil CO2 emissions, which was closely related to the molecular composition of exogenous DOM. DOM molecules with high aromaticity (AImod) and high DBE, including lignins-vascular plant-derived polyphenols, lignins-polycyclic aromatics (PA), and condensed aromatics-PA, promoted soil Fe reduction and CH4 emissions by enriching soil Fe-reducing bacteria (FeRB), reducing methanotrophs, and facilitating r-strategists at the early stage of incubation. Conversely, DOMs with low AImod, low DBE and high H/C, such as lignins-highly unsaturated and phenolic compounds and proteins-aliphatic compounds, enhanced CO2 emissions by facilitating recalcitrant C degradation and CH4 oxidation at the late stage of incubation. In conclusion, our study highlights the importance of the molecular composition of DOMs derived from organic amendments in regulating soil Fe reduction and C emissions. The findings offer novel insights into the effective utilization of agricultural resources and the mitigation of soil C emissions.</description>
      <author>Li Wang, X. Liu, Yuchen Shu, Gang Li, Cen Sun, Davey L. Jones, Yong&#8208;Guan Zhu, Xianyong Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0323.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Influential Operational Parameters in the Mitigation of CO2 Emissions in a Power Plant: Case Study in Portugal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cleantechnol6030057</link>
      <description>V&#237;tor Balanuta, Patr&#237;cia Baptista, Fernando Carreira, Gon&#231;alo Duarte, C. Casaca, Clean Technologies. 6(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402316577

                The European decarbonization goals and requirement for energy independence are mostly relying on intermittent renewable energy sources for electrification. A numerical model was developed to simulate the operation of a steam generator, allowing a study of the potential impacts of retrofitting existing coal-fired power plants to operate with biomass or coal&#8211;biomass mixtures on combustion parameters and CO2 emissions. The results obtained using the operational parameters of the Sines power plant indicate that a mixture of 25% coal and 75% pine sawdust allow operation at &#955; = 1.8, demonstrating that a small amount of coal allows operation near the coal combustion parameters (&#955; = 1.9). These conditions have the drawback of a reduction of 8.7% in adiabatic flame temperature but a significant reduction of 57.5% in CO2 emissions, considering the biomass as carbon-neutral.</description>
      <author>V&#237;tor Balanuta, Patr&#237;cia Baptista, Fernando Carreira, Gon&#231;alo Duarte, C. Casaca</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cleantechnol6030057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Criteria Analysis of Technology that Ensure Environmental Safety in Waste Incineration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4028/p-4jezno</link>
      <description>Alexander Krot, O. V. Pukhovoi, Nataliia Kosenko, Yulia Levashova, Advances in science and technology. 156(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402379418

                The article discusses solutions for environmental safety of solid waste incineration technology. Methods of flue gases purification have been evaluated, and two directions of an air purification technology have been considered. The first direction is the precipitation method to remove fly ash, the second direction is the using physic-chemical treatment of toxic substances. Municipal solid waste is a multicomponent mixture, when it is burned, diverse group of substances with different physic-chemical properties produces into the exhaust gases: carbon monoxide, sulfur dioxide, nitrogen oxides, fluorine and chlorine compounds, polychlorinated biphenyls, chlorophenols, polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons and dioxins. The fly ash that is produced in furnaces contains heavy metal particles. The chemical composition of emissions from waste incineration plants depends on the incineration technology, the morphological composition of waste, and the effective protection against exposure to hazardous chemicals. The authors propose a new approach to the selection of treatment equipment using multi-criteria analysis. Fabric filters, cyclones, scrubbers, electrostatic precipitators, wet cleaning devices were compared to eight criteria. The same criteria were used to compare the efficiency of absorption, adsorption, thermocatalytic treatment, selective catalytic reduction and thermal afterburning.</description>
      <author>Alexander Krot, O. V. Pukhovoi, Nataliia Kosenko, Yulia Levashova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4028/p-4jezno</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Adsorption on Solid and Liquid Surfaces of Ga&#8211;Sn and Ga&#8211;In</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400456</link>
      <description>Charlie Ruffman, Samuel R. B. Case, Timothy P. Grayson, Nicola Gaston, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402396019

                Abstract Dynamic liquid metal catalysts have remarkable activity and selectivity toward certain reactions, such as carbon dioxide reduction. The surface hydrogen coverage may play a role in this, including controlling competing reactions such as hydrogen evolution. Using a novel method of statistically selecting relevant snapshots from a dynamic liquid metal trajectory, the hydrogen adsorption energy is reported across liquid surfaces of Ga&#8211;Sn and Ga&#8211;In via density functional theory. A fully dynamic sampling of hydrogen adsorption to the liquid metal is also conducted with ab initio molecular dynamics at temperature. The results indicate that hydrogen only associates weakly with Ga&#8211;Sn and Ga&#8211;In surfaces, with minimal difference between the two materials. Hydrogen adsorbs only slightly more stably (&#8776;0.1 eV) to the liquid surfaces compared to the solid. A low hydrogen coverage is predicted on the liquid metal of &#8776;0.03 H &#197; &#8722;2 at potentials of around &#8211;1.15 V (vs RHE). However, the mobility of hydrogen on the liquid surface is much greater due to a novel mechanism whereby the dynamic surface rearranges, opening pathways for diffusion. The results suggest that the unique catalytic behavior of these liquid metal materials may be due to changes in adsorbate diffusivity when the metals are melted.</description>
      <author>Charlie Ruffman, Samuel R. B. Case, Timothy P. Grayson, Nicola Gaston</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteroatom&#8208;Containing Zeolites as Solid Lewis Acid Catalysts for the Cycloaddition of CO2 to Epoxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401385</link>
      <description>Bo-Hai Gao, Weijie Li, Yuchao Chai, Guangjun Wu, Landong Li, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402382027

                The catalytic cycloaddition of CO2 to epoxides to produce valuable cyclic carbonates represents a simple and promising strategy for CO2 utilization, circumventing the ineffective CO2 reduction process. Despite current progresses, there remains an impending demand for highly&#8208;active, cost&#8208;effective and stable catalysts especially the ideal heterogeneous catalytic systems. Herein, we report the preparation of heteroatom&#8208;containing zeolites through a two&#8208;step process comprising of framework dealumination and subsequent heteroatom incorporation, and their catalytic applications in CO2 cycloaddition to epoxides. Characterization results reveal the successful incorporation of heteroatoms into framework to derive Lewis acidic M&#8208;Beta zeolites (M=Ti, Zr or Hf). The as&#8208;prepared M&#8208;Beta Lewis acids show remarkable performance in the model reaction of CO2 cycloaddition to propylene oxide with the assistance of potassium iodide under solvent&#8208;free conditions. The reaction parameters have been optimized employing Ti&#8208;Beta catalyst and the substrate scope has been investigated. Finally, the impact of Lewis acidity on the cycloaddition reaction is discussed and the actual bifunctional Ti&#8208;Beta/KI catalyst system is proposed, which is of important significance for the understanding of CO2 catalytic cycloaddition to epoxides.</description>
      <author>Bo-Hai Gao, Weijie Li, Yuchao Chai, Guangjun Wu, Landong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy performance of integrated CO2 refrigeration, heating and cooling system in real appli-cations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17816/rf635369</link>
      <description>Nishant Karve, Kathleen Van de Velde, S. Vandaele, Refrigeration Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402355956

                Conveni-pack, a Daikin product, is an integrated refrigeration, cooling and heating system that recovers heat from the refrigeration to heat up the space. It additionally functions as a heatpump when additional heating is needed in winter and provides cooling in summer. In 2019, Daikin launches a new model that uses CO2 as refrigerant, next to the existing R-410A model. The CO2 version has comparable COP to the R-410A model so that TEWI is considerably lower and therefore an excellent product to reduce CO2 emissions and meet the requirements set by the European F-gas regulation. Daikin Europe N.V. has engaged in an EU funded project (LIFE) in which the reduction of the CO2 emissions using an integrated system in real shops across Europe and the impact of the raw materials used will be investigated. During 2020 &#8211; 2022, DENV will monitor 20 systems in real applications and research the potential of thermal storage to further reduce emissions.</description>
      <author>Nishant Karve, Kathleen Van de Velde, S. Vandaele</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17816/rf635369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic Globalization, Renewable Energy, and CO2 Emissions in Selected Emerging Countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15826/vestnik.2024.23.3.024</link>
      <description>Xenaneira Shodrokova, Anna Yulianita, Abdul Bashir, Journal of Applied Economic Research. 23(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402396017

                The phenomenon of economic globalization (EG) has a significant impact on CO2 emissions in emerging countries. This research seeks to examine the influence of EG and renewable energy consumption (REC) on CO2 emissions by utilizing secondary data from the World Bank spanning the years 2000 to 2022. The study hypothesizes that EG contributes to higher CO2 emissions, whereas the REC leads to a reduction in CO2 emissions. This study uses the Data Regression Results Panel with a Random Effect Model to analyze the data. The results show that EG contributes to economic growth accompanied by increased CO2 emissions. Rapid increases in economic activity and industrialization, often driven by FDI and international trade, lead to increased use of fossil energy and CO2 emissions. These findings support the pollution haven hypothesis that suggests that high-polluting production tends to move to countries with looser environmental regulations. However, the study also found that increased REC is associated with a decrease in CO2 emissions. The theoretical significance of the results of this study shows that while EG can drive economic growth, it also has a negative impact on the environment. In practical terms, this research underscores the necessity for policies that promote the use of renewable energy, enhance energy efficiency, and enforce stringent environmental regulations to mitigate the adverse environmental effects of economic globalization. Measures such as the promotion of renewable energy, the transfer of green technologies, increasing public awareness of environmental sustainability, diversifying the economy into greener sectors, and developing green infrastructure are essential.</description>
      <author>Xenaneira Shodrokova, Anna Yulianita, Abdul Bashir</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15826/vestnik.2024.23.3.024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversion of hard-to-use wastes to new raw materials for low-energy glass/mineral-wool manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/tdaa6553</link>
      <description>Zhihong Yan, Theint Theint Htet, Song Zhang, Jia Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383286

                During the pyrometallurgical processes, a substantial quantity of high-temperature ironmaking and steelmaking slags, generated at temperatures ranging from 1400 to 1600&#176;C, is wasted, as the heat contained in these slags is released into the environment during the tapping process without effective utilisation. On the other hand, a significant amount of energy is required to reheat the cold materials for the manufacturing of glass and mineral-wool, often necessitating the addition of high-silica materials to facilitate the production process. In this study, an innovative approach is presented to harness the heat present in molten metallurgical slags to directly produce new raw materials for glass and mineral-wool manufacturing while simultaneously reducing energy consumption and mitigating CO2 emissions. The theoretical amount of waste glass that can be effectively added in the process has been estimated via thermodynamic calculation. Experimental assessments were conducted to examine the impact of high-silica waste materials on the dissolution, melting and fluidity. Potential recipes for glass and mineral-wool manufacturing were suggested and an assessment of the energy savings, and reduction in CO2 emissions with manufacturing of glass and mineral-wool using this innovative approach were included. It was determined that the processes could lead to a reduction of over 26 kg of CO2 emissions per 100 kg of new material used, primarily due to the utilisation of heat from slag and the accelerated smelting process.</description>
      <author>Zhihong Yan, Theint Theint Htet, Song Zhang, Jia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/tdaa6553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Safety Tunneling Technology of Secondary Outburst Elimination by CO2 Gas Fracturing in High-Outburst Coal Seam</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091925</link>
      <description>Zongwei Xu, Junsheng Zhang, Yunxing Cao, Zhenzhi Wang, Xinsheng Zhang, Processes. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402373156

                The No. 3 coal seam in the Yuxi Coal Mine has a measured maximum gas content of 25.59 m3/t, along with a maximum gas pressure of 2.9 MPa, indicating its high risk to gas and outbursts. To mitigate outburst risks of the coal seam, the 1301 working face has been implemented with gas pre-drainage measures by grid boreholes from underlying roadways. After one year of extraction, it was confirmed that the gas content at all 33 test sites was below 8 m3/t, meeting the outburst prevention standards. However, during subsequent coal tunnel excavation, the gas desorption index K1 value frequently exceeded the standard, resulting in numerous occurrences of abnormal gas emission or small-scale outbursts. To tackle the challenges associated with safe excavation following the first-round regional outburst prevention measures, a research and industrial trial of CO2 gas fracturing (CO2-Frac) technology for secondary outburst prevention and rapid excavation was completed. The results show that the dual-hole and high-pressure (185 MPa) CO2-Frac considerably contributes to outburst prevention. K1 exceedances per hundred meters of tunnel excavations were from an average of 2.54 without CO2-Frac to an average of 0.28 after the new technology was implemented, leading to an eight-fold reduction. Additionally, the monthly excavation footage increased from an average of 81.64 m without CO2-Frac to an average of 162.42 m with CO2-Frac, resulting in a two-fold improvement. The dual-hole and high-pressure CO2-Frac is an advanced technology for safe and efficient excavation for secondary outburst elimination in highly outburst-prone coal seams in the Yuxi Coal Mine, with potential for widespread application in similar coal seam conditions.</description>
      <author>Zongwei Xu, Junsheng Zhang, Yunxing Cao, Zhenzhi Wang, Xinsheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091925</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research for the Enhanced Oil Recovery Mechanism of Heavy Oil after Composite Huff and Puff Assisted by Edge-Bottom Water Displacement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4066458</link>
      <description>Lei Tao, Mengjun Wu, Na Zhang, Wenyang Shi, Lina Cao, YoungHoon Song, Jiajia Bai, Zhengxiao Xu, Qi&#8208;Yong Zhu, Journal of Energy Resources Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402353914

                Abstract In the late stage of exploiting heavy oil reservoirs with edge-bottom water, we are faced with problems such as high crude oil viscosity, channeling of bottom water, and rapid rise in water cut. To clarify the synergistic effect of N2, CO2, N2 foam, and viscosity reducer in water control and oil increase, and solve the problem of edge-bottom water rushing into production wells, one-dimensional sand-pack huff and puff experiments were carried out. First, the N2 foam huff and puff experiment evaluated the effect of N2 foam on controlling bottom water. Then the viscosity reducer assisted CO2 huff and puff experiment analyzed the synergistic viscosity reduction ability between the two to mobilize the remaining heavy oil. Next, the N2 foam-viscosity reducer-CO2 huff and puff experiment clarified the synergistic effect between the three. Finally, the N2 foam-viscosity reducer-CO2-N2 huff and puff experiment solved the problem of insufficient reservoir energy based on synergistic precipitation and oil increase. Experimental results show that N2 foam-viscosity reducer-CO2-N2 huff and puff is the optimal water control and oil increase solution. This solution can significantly reduce water production and increase oil production. In the one-dimensional sand-pack experiment, this technical solution reduced the water content by 68% and increased the recovery rate by 16.09%. The research results provide a reference for the development of exploitation technology schemes for similar edge-bottom water heavy oil reservoirs after entering high water cut.</description>
      <author>Lei Tao, Mengjun Wu, Na Zhang, Wenyang Shi, Lina Cao, YoungHoon Song, Jiajia Bai, Zhengxiao Xu, Qi&#8208;Yong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4066458</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Synergistic Effect of CeO2 and Micron-Cu Enhances the Hydrogenation of CO2 to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091912</link>
      <description>Bowen Lu, Huiying Sang, Liang Liu, Zhijian Yu, Frank Rasche, Yongqing Xu, Processes. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402317561

                The catalytic applications of micron Cu powder are limited due to its large particle size and small specific surface area. Modifying micro-Cu powder to achieve a high catalytic performance is a challenge in the application of micron copper. In this work, micro-Cu was used to synthesize a CeO2&#8211;Cu catalyst, and the phase composition and surface pore structure were analyzed using XRD, BET, etc. The CO2 hydrogenation performance of the CeO2&#8211;Cu catalyst was analyzed in comparison with CeO2 and Cu, and we found that the CeO2&#8211;Cu catalyst exhibited a synergistic effect between Cu and cerium, resulting in a much higher hydrogenation performance at 500 &#176;C than CeO2 or Cu alone. H2-TPR and TEM characterization revealed that the CeO2&#8211;Cu catalyst formed interfacial interactions with a relatively large Ce&#8211;Cu interface, where cerium oxide could promote the reduction of CuO and lower the reduction temperature. Additionally, cerium oxide formed a confinement structure for Cu, and the CeO2&#8211;Cu catalyst exhibited a higher oxygen vacancy concentration, thereby promoting the CO2 hydrogenation performance. Cu&#8211;CeO2 interaction provides valuable insights into the catalytic application of micron Cu powder.</description>
      <author>Bowen Lu, Huiying Sang, Liang Liu, Zhijian Yu, Frank Rasche, Yongqing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Industrial Decarbonization: Harnessing Emerging Technologies and Digitalization for Net-Zero</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/220459-ms</link>
      <description>Renato Finol, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402426474

                Abstract We describe and compare several options for decarbonisation of Oil &amp; Gas operations, from low hanging fruits to significant design changes to the addition of complete, major processes such as CCUS or electrification of large crackers. The comparison includes elements of feasibility in brownfield &amp; greenfield, technology availability, implementation costs, timeline &amp; risks, as well as ROI (Return On Investment) and CO2_OI (CO2 reduction impact On Investment). The analysis and recommendations in this paper are based on the experience of the author and are illustrated by several actual customer projects. The analysis on Low Hanging fruits is confirmed by a developing literature and third-party sources (eg Concawe Report 18/9, IHSMarkit&#8230;). The design paradigm shift suggestions are still a nascent domain. The analysis on large projects such as CCUS, Green or Blue Hydrogen or process electrification is also a first of a kind attempt to assess real long-term financial sustainability of these approaches and position them properly versus other decarbonization tracks. We describe a dozen &#8216;low hanging&#8217; decarbonization tracks. These start with the right GHG assessment and performance tool, based on the saying that you can't improve what you don't measure. These tracks are technically available and feasible today. They are compared in terms of feasibility in brownfield &amp; greenfield, implementation costs, timeline &amp; risks, as well as ROI and CO2_OI (Return On Investment and CO2 impact reduction On Investment). We also identify a number of design paradigm shifts, applicable for all greenfield projects. We provide some practical examples, from fully remote operations to flaring elimination. These design paradigm shifts are evaluated in terms of feasibility, ease of deployment. Suggestions are made on how to integrated them in design and operations philosophy. We eventually analyze approaches such as CCUS, Green or Blue Hydrogen or process electrification. These are often the only ones considered for process decarbonization, and benefit from major thought leadership and press coverage. We identify the pros and cons of these approaches and assess their real long-term financial sustainability. This paper reminds that Low Hanging fruits, mainly relied to Energy Efficiency and usually facilitated by Digital Transformation, present both a very favorable ROI and CO2-OI. The paper also presents a number of design paradigm shifts that are considered necessary to ensure carbon neutral infrastructure and operations. Last but not least, this paper reminds that some approaches like CCUS may have a significant impact on CO2 reduction, but the CO2_OI as well as all risk elements need to be carefully evaluated.</description>
      <author>Renato Finol</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/220459-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferroalloy extraction from a Zimbabwean chrome ore using a closed DC furnace</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/pwnq7247</link>
      <description>Samuel Opoku Dandi, Malbenia John Masamvu, S M Masuka, Stephen Bright, Edson Kugara Chiwandika, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402384101

                The depletion of high-grade hard and lumpy chrome ores has forced Zimbabwean ferrochrome producers to resort to low-grade friable ores that have an average of 28 per cent fines against a set limit of 12 per cent. Submerged open arc furnaces currently in use are associated with eruptions within the furnace because of the high amounts of fines, high energy consumption, as well as high SO2 and CO2 emissions. Traditionally employed agglomeration methods such as pelletising and the use of coke in the furnace have been discarded because of the pressure to lower operational costs and to achieve higher profit margins. This research aims to develop a method to incorporate low-grade friable ore fines and unprocessed coal into production while lowering CO2 and SO2 emissions through a closed direct current (DC) arc furnace. The closed DC arc furnace could incorporate the friable ores and coal while maintaining above 90 per cent reduction rates. Preliminary findings also show that energy consumption could be reduced by up to 35 per cent by incorporating a pre-heating and pre-reduction system using the flue gases from the furnace. In the proposed circuit, the cost of production per ton of ferrochrome might be potentially lowered by an average of 30 per cent.</description>
      <author>Samuel Opoku Dandi, Malbenia John Masamvu, S M Masuka, Stephen Bright, Edson Kugara Chiwandika</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/pwnq7247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migration of a Leaky-Dielectric Droplet in the Fringe Electric Fields of Parallel Plate Capacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/fedsm2024-131614</link>
      <description>Julie Melbye, Danling Wang, Yechun Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402413526

                Abstract This work numerically studies the dynamics of a droplet, uncharged and freely suspended in an immiscible fluid, driven to move by the fringe electric field generated by parallel plate capacitors. Both the droplet and the suspending fluid are considered as leaky dielectrics. The deformation and migration of the droplet through the fringe electric field into or away from the parallel plate capacitors is our focus. A three-dimensional spectral boundary element method for interfacial dynamics in electrical fields is modified and adopted for the current study. The influences of the material properties of the pair of immiscible fluids including the viscosity ratio, surface tension, conductivity, and permittivity on the direction and velocity of the droplet migration will be investigated. The effects of operational and design parameters on droplet motion, including the electrical field strength and the parallel plates&#8217; gap width will be explored as well. In this preliminary study the numerical method will then be applied to investigate the entrapment processes of fine CO2 bubbles in two-dimensional MXene-membranes, a novel membrane technology newly developed for CO2 sensing, capture and reduction. This technology is being developed for an over-arching goal of understanding changes in ocean carbon cycle and controlling CO2 level globally. The efficiency of such a device will be discussed from the view point of fluid dynamics.</description>
      <author>Julie Melbye, Danling Wang, Yechun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1115/fedsm2024-131614</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing CO2 emissions from the ferro-alloy and silicon production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/pjew9367</link>
      <description>Merete Tangstad, Gabriella Tranell, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383184

                The CO2 footprints in the production of Mn-ferroalloys and silicon/ferrosilicon are correlated with the fossil carbon consumption. The CO2 emissions may be reduced in the Mn-ferroalloy process by increasing the degree of prereduction and reduction of carbonate materials, while the silicon/ferrosilicon process is optimised based on silicon yield. By changing the fossil reductant into biogenic reductants, the global warming potential will be decreased even more. Even if the reductants are biogenic reductants, there will still be a global warming potential (GWP) in eg the electrode consumption and the CH4 emissions in the charcoal production. To reduce the use of fossil reductants there are also more disruptive technologies like the use of H2 that at least for the silicon production is on a very low technology readiness level (TRL). Using metallothermic processes will reduce the use of carbon but requires carbon neutral metal reductants. Electrowinning can have low CO2 emissions, and the electrowinning of pure Mn is a technology of high TRL. Salt and oxide electrolysis is under investigation for both Mn and Si production however the research is still on a low TRL. The use of CCS/CCU (carbon capture storage/utilisation) is a part of obtaining carbon neutral processes. Last, the energy mix used for these energy demanding processes is discussed.</description>
      <author>Merete Tangstad, Gabriella Tranell</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/pjew9367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Emission Accounting and Reduction Evaluation in Sponge City Residential Areas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/w16172535</link>
      <description>Yulong Ma, Xuefeng Liu, Jianlin Liu, Congcong Du, Liang Mei, Wei Li, Lianbao Cao, Deqi Wang, Li Wang, Tingting Zhang, Bigui Wei, Water. 16(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377876

                This paper aims to establish a more standardized and regulated carbon emission accounting model for sponge cities by unifying the accounting content for carbon emissions and clarifying the relationships between carbon reduction benefits, carbon reduction effects, and carbon sequestration, in order to evaluate the carbon reduction outcomes and mechanisms of sponge city construction. Based on a Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) carbon emission accounting model using the carbon emission factor method, a newly constructed residential area in Tianshui City, Gansu Province, was selected as a case study, and the carbon emission reduction effect of sponge city construction was then investigated. Results indicated that the 30-year full life cycle carbon emissions for sponge city construction in the newly constructed residential area amounted to 828.98 tons, compared to 744.28 tons of CO2 reduction in traditional construction, representing a 47.31% reduction in carbon emissions. Over a 30-year life cycle, this equated to a total carbon emission reduction effect of 1460.31 tons. Additionally, under various rainfall scenarios in a typical year, the carbon emission reduction effect of sponge city construction exceeded the carbon emissions, achieving carbon neutrality within 22 to 30 years of operation. This demonstrates that the carbon emission reduction effect of sponge city communities is significant. The findings of this study provide data and a theoretical basis for the low-carbon construction of sponge cities in China.</description>
      <author>Yulong Ma, Xuefeng Liu, Jianlin Liu, Congcong Du, Liang Mei, Wei Li, Lianbao Cao, Deqi Wang, Li Wang, Tingting Zhang, Bigui Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/w16172535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Elevated CO2 and a Nitrogen Supply on the Growth of Faba Beans (Vicia faba L.) and the Nitrogen-Related Soil Bacterial Community</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13172483</link>
      <description>Xingshui Dong, Hui Lin, Li Wang, Songmei Shi, Zhihui Wang, Sharifullah Sharifi, Junwei Ma, Xinhua He, Plants. 13(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402278435

                Ecosystems that experience elevated CO2 (eCO2) are crucial interfaces where intricate interactions between plants and microbes occur. This study addressed the impact of eCO2 and a N supply on faba bean (Vicia faba L.) growth and the soil microbial community in auto-controlled growth chambers. In doing so, two ambient CO2 concentrations (aCO2, daytime/nighttime = 410/460 ppm; eCO2, 550/610 ppm) and two N supplement levels (without a N supply&#8212;N0&#8212;and 100 mg N as urea per kg of soil&#8212;N100) were applied. The results indicated that eCO2 mitigated the inhibitory effects of a N deficiency on legume photosynthesis and affected the CO2 assimilation efficiency, in addition to causing reduced nodulation. While the N addition counteracted the reductions in the N concentrations across the faba beans&#8217; aboveground and belowground plant tissues under eCO2, the CO2 concentrations did not significantly alter the soil NH4+-N or NO3&#8722;-N responses to a N supply. Notably, under both aCO2 and eCO2, a N supply significantly increased the relative abundance of Nitrososphaeraceae and Nitrosomonadaceae, while eCO2 specifically reduced the Rhizobiaceae abundance with no significant changes under aCO2. A redundancy analysis (RDA) highlighted that the soil pH (p &lt; 0.01) had the most important influence on the soil microbial community. Co-occurrence networks indicated that the eCO2 conditions mitigated the impact of a N supply on the reduced structural complexity of the soil microbial communities. These findings suggest that a combination of eCO2 and a N supply to crops can provide potential benefits for managing future climate change impacts on crop production.</description>
      <author>Xingshui Dong, Hui Lin, Li Wang, Songmei Shi, Zhihui Wang, Sharifullah Sharifi, Junwei Ma, Xinhua He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13172483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active Cerium Oxide Supported Solution Combustion Cu/Mn Catalysts for CO-PrOx in a Hydrogen-Rich Stream</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14090603</link>
      <description>Sbusiso Motha, Abdul S. Mahomed, Sooboo Singh, Holger B. Friedrich, Catalysts. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402370992

                Mono- and di-substituted cerium oxide catalysts, viz. Ce0.95Cu0.05O2-&#948;, Ce0.90Cu0.10O2-&#948;, Ce0.90 Cu0.05Mn0.05O2-&#948;, Ce0.85Cu0.10Mn0.05O2-&#948;, and Ce0.80Cu0.10Mn0.10O2-&#948;, were synthesized via a one-step urea-assisted solution combustion method. The elemental composition and textural and structural properties of the catalysts were determined by various physical, electronic, and chemical characterization techniques. Hydrogen temperature-programmed reduction showed that co-doping of copper and manganese ions into the CeO2-&#948; lattice improved the reducibility of copper. Powder XRD, XPS, HR-TEM, and Raman spectroscopy showed that the catalysts were a singled-phased, solid-solution metal oxide with a cerium oxide cubic fluorite (cerianite) structure, and evidence of oxygen vacancies was observed. Catalytic results in the preferential oxidation of CO in a hydrogen-rich stream showed that complete CO conversion occurred between 150 and 180 &#176;C. Furthermore, at 150 &#176;C, Ce0.90Cu0.05Mn0.05O2-&#948;, Ce0.90 Cu0.10O2-&#948;, and Ce0.85Cu0.10Mn0.05O2-&#948; catalysts were the most active, achieving complete CO conversion and CO2 selectivity of 81, 79, and 71%, respectively. The catalysts performed moderately in the presence of CO2 and water, with the Ce0.90Cu0.05Mn0.05O2-&#948; catalyst giving a CO conversion of 80% in CO2, which decreased to about 60% when water was added.</description>
      <author>Sbusiso Motha, Abdul S. Mahomed, Sooboo Singh, Holger B. Friedrich</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14090603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the future of land reclamation for mining areas: plant species responses to climate change- related events in the Brazilian Legal Amazon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47328/ufvbbt.2024.337</link>
      <description>Ma&#237;sa Quintiliano Alves, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402350079

                The increase in atmospheric CO2 concentrations triggers a transient response in climate, leading to global temperature rise. As the climate warms, extreme events intensify. Given the global significance of the Amazon and the increasing efforts for environmental recovery in the region, this study aimed to understand the relationship between local land-use changes and the occurrence of extreme climate events in an area influenced by mining activities within the Brazilian Legal Amazon. Additionally, it sought to assess the impact of water deficit on the photosynthesis and growth of fast-growing species used in the reclamation of mining areas, growing under elevated atmospheric CO2 levels. Results suggested that large-scale deforestation has a regional impact occasionally outweighing local effect. Significant trends reveal a general pattern of drought that has been more intense in the north of the study area, regardless of land cover, whether preserved or deforested. Moreover, the dry season is getting drier, but the wet season is not getting wetter over the entire area, and extreme events are becoming more frequent. Regarding the impact on vegetation, our findings do not provide substantial evidence that the assessed species used in the reclamation of mining areas in the region will be profoundly impacted by the rise in atmospheric CO2 and intense drought events&#8212; particularly concerning plant growth and biomass production. Nonetheless, they might be affected by extreme heat. Ultimately, notable attention is directed towards a considerable reduction in the emergence of Pigeon pea individuals, which declined by half in resource-rich environments (elevated atmospheric CO2 and irrigation). This decline is likely a consequence of interspecific competition within the chambers and may indicate a shift in the composition of developing vegetation. Keywords: Climate-change. Drought. Land-reclamation. The-Amazon. Mining.</description>
      <author>Ma&#237;sa Quintiliano Alves</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47328/ufvbbt.2024.337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and properties of catalytic chemisorbents based on titanium oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14529/chem240109</link>
      <description>N E Sal'nikova, Evgeny Smirnov, &#1044;. &#1040;. &#1055;&#1088;&#1086;&#1079;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Andrey V. Afineevskiy, &#1044;. &#1040;. &#1057;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Kirill Nikitin, Bulletin of the South Ural State University series Chemistry. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402351025

                In this work, we studied the synthesis and properties of catalytic chemisorbents based on titanium dioxide with additions of ZnO and &#947;-Al2O3. The goal was to obtain chemisorbents with desired performance characteristics and evaluate their potential in destructive hydrogenation of organo-sulfur compounds. Their sulfur capacity and hydrogenating capacity were measured by the static method with carbon disulfide absorption. Textural and morphological characteristics were deter-mined with the use of X-ray phase analysis, low-temperature nitrogen adsorption/desorption, and scanning electron microscopy. It was also found that addition of alumina did not give additional reflections on the X-ray pattern, in contrast to introduction of zinc oxide. It was found that addi-tion of zinc oxide significantly increased the values of the specific surface area, many times more than expected, according to additivity principle. Conversely, addition of alumina did not give the expected increase in surface area. The one and the other were explained through active interaction of phases. The ratios of components for obtaining chemisorbents with optimal strength properties were established. It was found that a composite consisting of titanium and aluminum oxides was more resistant to sulfurization than one with additions of zinc oxide. SEM and low-temperature ni-trogen adsorption/desorption methods confirmed the mesoporous structure of the studied samples, while the sample containing gamma alumina showed a more pronounced desorption branch to-gether with the surface consisting of spherical formations arranged in a regular order. The sample with zinc oxide had slit-like pores in its volume. Hydrogenation of thiophene with gaseous hydro-gen was carried out for the studied composites. Chromatographic analysis of the resulting product was performed. It was proven that composites based on titanium, zinc, and aluminum oxides not only had sorption properties with respect to organosulfur compounds, but also catalyzed their de-structive hydrogenation. Thus, it was established that the studied samples were chemisorbents. The study provides insight into synthesis and properties of catalytic titania-based chemisorbents, high-lighting the influence of additives and their potential for organosulfur reduction reactions.</description>
      <author>N E Sal'nikova, Evgeny Smirnov, &#1044;. &#1040;. &#1055;&#1088;&#1086;&#1079;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Andrey V. Afineevskiy, &#1044;. &#1040;. &#1057;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Kirill Nikitin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14529/chem240109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low latency carbon budget analysis reveals a large decline of the land
  carbon sink in 2023</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.12447</link>
      <description>Piyu Ke, P. Ciais, Stephen Sitch, Wei Li, Ana Bastos, Zhu Liu, Yidi Xu, Xiang Gui, Jiang Bian, Daniel Goll, Yi Xi, Wanjing Li, Michael O&#8217;Sullivan, Juander Ant&#244;nio de Oliveira Souza, Pierre Friedlingstein, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Chevallier, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402345875

                In 2023, the CO2 growth rate was 3.37 +/- 0.11 ppm at Mauna Loa, 86% above the previous year, and hitting a record high since observations began in 1958, while global fossil fuel CO2 emissions only increased by 0.6 +/- 0.5%. This implies an unprecedented weakening of land and ocean sinks, and raises the question of where and why this reduction happened. Here we show a global net land CO2 sink of 0.44 +/- 0.21 GtC yr-1, the weakest since 2003. We used dynamic global vegetation models, satellites fire emissions, an atmospheric inversion based on OCO-2 measurements, and emulators of ocean biogeochemical and data driven models to deliver a fast-track carbon budget in 2023. Those models ensured consistency with previous carbon budgets. Regional flux anomalies from 2015-2022 are consistent between top-down and bottom-up approaches, with the largest abnormal carbon loss in the Amazon during the drought in the second half of 2023 (0.31 +/- 0.19 GtC yr-1), extreme fire emissions of 0.58 +/- 0.10 GtC yr-1 in Canada and a loss in South-East Asia (0.13 +/- 0.12 GtC yr-1). Since 2015, land CO2 uptake north of 20 degree N declined by half to 1.13 +/- 0.24 GtC yr-1 in 2023. Meanwhile, the tropics recovered from the 2015-16 El Nino carbon loss, gained carbon during the La Nina years (2020-2023), then switched to a carbon loss during the 2023 El Nino (0.56 +/- 0.23 GtC yr-1). The ocean sink was stronger than normal in the equatorial eastern Pacific due to reduced upwelling from La Nina's retreat in early 2023 and the development of El Nino later. Land regions exposed to extreme heat in 2023 contributed a gross carbon loss of 1.73 GtC yr-1, indicating that record warming in 2023 had a strong negative impact on the capacity of terrestrial ecosystems to mitigate climate change.</description>
      <author>Piyu Ke, P. Ciais, Stephen Sitch, Wei Li, Ana Bastos, Zhu Liu, Yidi Xu, Xiang Gui, Jiang Bian, Daniel Goll, Yi Xi, Wanjing Li, Michael O&#8217;Sullivan, Juander Ant&#244;nio de Oliveira Souza, Pierre Friedlingstein, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Chevallier</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.12447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Speed Limit Change on Emissions: A Systematic Review of Literature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177712</link>
      <description>Stephen Kome Fondzenyuy, Blair Matthew Turner, Alina F. Burlacu, Chris Jurewicz, Davide Shingo Usami, Steffel Ludivin Feudjio Tezong, Luca Persia, Sustainability. 16(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402280772

                In the pursuit of sustainable mobility and the decarbonization of transport systems, public authorities are increasingly scrutinizing the impact of travel speed on emissions within both low-speed and high-speed environments. This study critically examines the evidence concerning emission impacts associated with speed limit changes in different traffic environments by conducting a systematic review of the literature in accordance with the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines. A total of 25 studies that met the eligibility criteria were assessed. The results reveal mixed evidence for reducing emissions through speed limit reductions in low-speed areas. However, emerging evidence suggests that reduced urban speeds may abate emissions through enhanced traffic flow and a shift in modal preferences away from personal vehicle use. Additionally, in urban areas, minor observed emission reduction per vehicle can add up to large overall reductions due to the high number of vehicles. In high-speed contexts, the evidence is much clearer, showing that reduced speed limits correlate with significant reductions in NOx, CO2, and particulate matter emissions. The extent of these reductions is highly variable and contingent upon the specific speed limits or limit reductions, the local context, the vehicle type, and the baseline types and levels of pollutants. Notably, there is a lack of research on the effects of speed on emissions, especially in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs), highlighting a critical area for future investigation. The findings of this study underscore the potential environmental benefits of speed management policies and advocate for the promotion of smoother and less aggressive driving behavior to mitigate emissions and enhance sustainable mobility in both low-speed and high-speed settings.</description>
      <author>Stephen Kome Fondzenyuy, Blair Matthew Turner, Alina F. Burlacu, Chris Jurewicz, Davide Shingo Usami, Steffel Ludivin Feudjio Tezong, Luca Persia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of liquefaction controlling components in carbon-free mould powder for the continuous casting of ultra-low carbon steels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/ypix4601</link>
      <description>Nicolas Gruber, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383147

                In the continuous casting of ultralow carbon (ULC) steels, free carbon is used to control the melting behaviour of mould powders. If the carbon is not completely removed during melting, it is enriched at the top of the slag pool. Liquid steel may come into contact with this layer because of the turbulence of the molten metal, resulting in its recarburisation, which negatively affects the desired product quality. Thus, a reduction in carbon input is desirable. For this purpose, SiC and/or Si3N4 with and without antioxidants were selected as melt-control additives to replace carbon in the mould powders. Thermodynamic calculations were performed to quantify their effect on the melting behaviour based on the chemical composition of a flux already applied to ULC steels. To experimentally assess the liquefaction behaviour, laboratory mould powders were prepared and annealed in steel crucibles closed with a lid. Crucibles were inserted into a furnace that was already preheated to selected temperatures between 900&#8211;1200&#176;C for 10 mins and quenched to room temperature. Subsequently, the samples were mineralogically investigated. The results confirmed those obtained from the thermodynamic calculations. Si3N4, and SiC in particular, are suitable raw materials for delaying the solid-solid reactions of raw material components during melting. Owing to their stability at high temperatures, the necessary SiO2 content to form a liquid phase is not available, resulting in lower amounts of the liquid phase. The addition of antioxidants to delay the oxidation of SiC further reduces this positive effect. Attempts to decrease the SiC content without negatively affecting the melting behaviour resulted in a reduction in the CO2 emission by at least 27 g CO2/kg of mould powder when compared to the carbon-containing standard mould powder. These investigations revealed differences in the melting behaviours of granules and loose powders, which are related to their respective production processes.</description>
      <author>Nicolas Gruber</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/ypix4601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating soil atmosphere exchanges and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; fluxes for a restored peatland</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2679</link>
      <description>Hongxing He, Ian B. Strachan, Nigel T. Roulet, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402312441

                Abstract. Restoration of drained and extracted peatlands can potentially return them to carbon (C) sinks, thus acting as significant climate change mitigation. However, whether the restored sites will remain C sinks or switch to sources with a changing climate is unknown. Therefore, we adapted the CoupModel to simulate soil atmosphere exchanges and the associated ecosystem CO2 fluxes of a restored bog. The study site was a peatland in eastern Canada that was extracted for eight years before restoration. The model outputs were first evaluated against three years (representing 14&#8211;16 years post restoration) of eddy covariance measurements of net ecosystem exchange (NEE), surface energy fluxes, soil temperature profiles, and water table depth data. A sensitivity analysis was conducted to evaluate the response of the simulated CO2 fluxes to the thickness of the newly grown mosses. The validated model was then used to assess the sensitivity of changes in climate forcing. CoupModel reproduced the measured surface energy fluxes and showed high agreement with the observed soil temperature, water table depth, and NEE data. The simulated NEE varied slightly when changing the thickness of newly grown mosses and acrotelm from 0.2 to 0.4 m but showed significantly less uptake for a 1 m thickness. The simulated NEE was -95 &#177; 19 g C m-2 yr-1 over the three evaluation years, and -101 &#177; 64 g C m-2 yr-1, ranging from -219 to +54 g C m-2 yr-1 with an extended 28-year climate data. After 14 years of restoration, the peatland has a mean C uptake rate similar to pristine sites, but with a much larger interannual variability, and under dry years, the restored peatland can switch back to a temporary C source. The model predicts a moderate reduction of CO2 uptake, but still a reasonable sink under future climate change conditions if the peatland is ecologically and hydrologically restored. The ability of CoupModel to simulate the CO2 dynamics and its thermal-hydro drivers for restored peatlands has important implications for emission accounting and climate-smart management of drained peatlands.</description>
      <author>Hongxing He, Ian B. Strachan, Nigel T. Roulet</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-2679</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FP8.3 - Reducing Waste with Remanufactured Harmonic Devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/bjs/znae197.417</link>
      <description>Caitlin Gordon, Steven D. Gardner, Abhijeet Beniwal, Anne Pullyblank, British journal of surgery. 111(Supplement_8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402374273

                Abstract The NHS produces an estimated 590,000 tonnes of waste per annum and disposable harmonic scalpels are costly both financially and environmentally. The average cost of a new harmonic device nationally is &#163;460. Remanufactured harmonic devices are not only recommended by the Intercollegiate Green Theatre Checklist and NHS England but also the Department of Health Med Tech Strategy. North Bristol NHS Trust has engaged with the initiative from Vanguard to reduce clinical waste as well as utilise remanufactured harmonic devices. Initially the project began in January 2023 with collecting used devices only, but this was followed by the rollout and use of remanufactured devices within colorectal surgery in May 2023. The initiative has resulted in a reduction of clinical waste produced as well as a significant cost saving. 56 devices used so far in colorectal surgery have saved &#163;12,880 and the estimated CO2 saving is 97 kilograms. There have been no incidents regarding the use of remanufactured devices or concerns raised. The project&#8217;s success has resulted in recent expansion into gynaecological surgery where the first remanufactured devices are in use. Based on previous harmonic device usage within NBT of 618 per annum, projected savings of using remanufactured devices are likely to reach &#163;71,070 and half a tonne of CO2 in the next year. This represents a significant financial and environmental initiative to continue the drive to reduce disposable waste within surgical theatres.</description>
      <author>Caitlin Gordon, Steven D. Gardner, Abhijeet Beniwal, Anne Pullyblank</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/bjs/znae197.417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis reveals heterogeneous changes in the metabolism and emission of greenhouse gases of drying rivers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad786e</link>
      <description>Margot Sepp, Juan David Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Trujillo, Rafael Marc&#233;, Sergi Sabater, Environmental Research Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402346928

                Abstract More than half of the world&#8217;s rivers experience occasional, seasonal, or permanent drying, and this may increase because of climate change. Drying, i.e., severe reduction in water flow even leading to streambed desiccation, can have a profound impact on the available aquatic habitat, biodiversity, and functions of rivers. Yet, to date, it is unclear whether similar drying events in comparable climate zones result in similar changes in ecosystem processes, such as river metabolism or greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Here, we synthesise the detected effects of drying on gross primary production (GPP) and ecosystem respiration (ER), as well as on the emissions of GHGs (CO2 , CH4 , and N2 O) in rivers and streams. We examined the current available scientific literature detailing the impact of drying on these variables when measured either in the field or in the laboratory. We extracted data from 30 studies analysing GPP and ER responses, and data on GHG emissions from another 35 studies. Then, we conducted a meta-analysis to determine whether the magnitude and direction of the effects varied across the systems and climate zones studied, or according to the type (natural or human-induced) and severity of drying. In general, drying enhanced GPP (under low flows) and CH4 emissions, and decreased CO2 and N2 O emissions. The hydrological phases throughout streambed drying (low water flow, isolated pools, or desiccation) had differential effects on metabolism and GHG emissions. The effects of drying were generally more severe when it induced desiccation, rather than just periods of low flow. Desiccation strongly reduced GPP, likely because of the die-off of algae, while its negative effect on ER was smaller. Greater decrease in GPP than in ER under desiccation would lead to increase in CO2 emissions; our results showed accordingly that desiccation increased CO2 emissions. Furthermore, the magnitude and direction of the effects varied depending on the study type. Experimental studies conducted in micro- and mesocosms demonstrated greater effects than field studies, thus the extrapolation of results from these to real conditions should be done with caution. Overall, the effects&#8217; direction was inconsistent across climate zones, except for the Mediterranean climate zone, where drying was showing a negative effect on both metabolism and GHG emissions. Our synthesis may contribute to identifying the worldwide trends and patterns of drying on riverine functions associated to global change impacts on river and stream ecosystems.</description>
      <author>Margot Sepp, Juan David Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Trujillo, Rafael Marc&#233;, Sergi Sabater</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad786e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Over-Sintering on Cyclic Calcination and Carbonization of Natural Limestone for CO2 Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091926</link>
      <description>Jiangtao Chen, Jinxing Wang, Huawei Jiang, Xuerong Zuo, Wei Zhao, Processes. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402372588

                To know the sustainable performance of calcium-based adsorbents is one of the important aspects to realize efficient and economical carbon capture, and to systematically study the properties of natural adsorbents is conducive to their industrialization. The cyclic calcination and carbonation characteristics of a typical natural limestone were investigated using a thermal gravimetric analyzer. Two kinds of over-sintering conditions were selected to emphatically study the cyclic separation of CO2 from limestones through prolonging the calcination time and increasing the calcination temperature. The results showed that the untimely end of the chemical reaction control stage caused by excessive sintering is the direct reason for the reduction in cyclic carbonation conversion, and the changes in surface morphology of calcined products due to pore collapse and fusion are the fundamental reasons for the reduction in cyclic carbonation conversion. The excessive sintering caused by extending the calcining time or increasing the calcining temperature has great inhibition on this cycle only; the inhibition decreases rapidly in subsequent cycles. In addition, SEM and BET&#8211;BJH tests further confirm the influence of the over-sintering phenomenon. With the further increase in cycle number, the early excessive sintering has certain stimulative effects on the subsequent carbonation reaction. It is expected to provide a reference for the subsequent research and development of natural calcium-based adsorbents.</description>
      <author>Jiangtao Chen, Jinxing Wang, Huawei Jiang, Xuerong Zuo, Wei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12091926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Value Through the Adoption of Technologies to Ensure Near Zero Methane Emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/220438-ms</link>
      <description>Adnan A Madhi, Vijaya Bhaskar Reddy, Mahmoud Abdelmobdy, Khalid Yousef Al Awadhi, Pierre Bouilhol, Marie Morazzani, Amal Omar AlAwlaqi, Deo Kumar Chauhan, Angela Fandino, Paramjeet Singh, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402397573

                Abstract There is a wide agreement among scientists that methane emissions are under reported / counted or overlooked. Methane emissions are generally calculated using a combination of standard emission factors and engineering calculations. Oil and gas companies are under pressure to decarbonize their value chain. According to IPCC, "deep reductions" in non-CO2 emissions like methane are necessary to keep global average temperature rise within 1.5&#176;C. Company with an objective of reduction in methane emissions and enhancement of associated reporting is investing in a suite of technologies to reduce methane emissions and monitoring, measurement programs to minimize uncertainty in tracking and reporting of methane emissions. The best practices include various engineering solutions i.e. flare recovery systems, green completion, electrification of drives and deploying advanced aerial technologies such as satellite tracking and in-plant measurements using IR cameras, fixed sensors, spectrophotometers for accurate monitoring and measurement of methane emissions. Continuous emission monitoring system by top-down aerial surveys combined with source level emission monitoring assisted in identifying methane hotspots and developing emission reduction plans. These efforts will support ADNOC to achieve near zero methane emissions from our operated oil and gas assets by 2030 and will encourage our partners to achieve similar results. In recognition of efforts, OGMP has certified ADNOC as Gold Standard Reporting company. This certification demonstrates company commitment and our leadership role towards enhancing both quality and transparency of methane data reporting and identify intervention actions required to tackle global methane emissions.</description>
      <author>Adnan A Madhi, Vijaya Bhaskar Reddy, Mahmoud Abdelmobdy, Khalid Yousef Al Awadhi, Pierre Bouilhol, Marie Morazzani, Amal Omar AlAwlaqi, Deo Kumar Chauhan, Angela Fandino, Paramjeet Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/220438-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stomatal and Non-Stomatal Leaf Responses during Two Sequential Water Stress Cycles in Young Coffea canephora Plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/stresses4030037</link>
      <description>Danilo For&#231;a Baroni, Guilherme Augusto Rodrigues de Souza, Wallace de Paula Bernado, Anne Reis Santos, Larissa Cris&#243;stomo de Souza Barcellos, Let&#237;cia Fernantes Tavares Barcelos, La&#237;sa Zanelato Correia, Claudio Martins de Almeida, Abra&#227;o Carlos Verdin Filho, Weverton Pereira Rodrigues, Jos&#233; C. Ramalho, Miroslava Rako&#269;evi&#263;, Eliemar Campostrini, Stresses. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402416559

                Understanding the dynamics of physiological changes involved in the acclimation responses of plants after their exposure to repeated cycles of water stress is crucial to selecting resilient genotypes for regions with recurrent drought episodes. Under such background, we tried to respond to questions as: (1) Are there differences in the stomatal-related and non-stomatal responses during water stress cycles in different clones of Coffea canephora Pierre ex A. Froehner? (2) Do these C. canephora clones show a different response in each of the two sequential water stress events? (3) Is one previous drought stress event sufficient to induce a kind of &#8220;memory&#8221; in C. canephora? Seven-month-old plants of two clones (&#8217;3V&#8217; and &#8216;A1&#8217;, previously characterized as deeper and lesser deep root growth, respectively) were maintained well-watered (WW) or fully withholding the irrigation, inducing soil water stress (WS) until the soil matric water potential (&#936;msoil) reached &#8773; &#8722;0.5 MPa (&#8722;500 kPa) at a soil depth of 500 mm. Two sequential drought events (drought-1 and drought-2) attained this &#936;msoil after 19 days and were followed by soil rewatering until a complete recovery of leaf net CO2 assimilation rate (Anet) during the recovery-1 and recovery-2 events. The leaf gas exchange, chlorophyll a fluorescence, and leaf reflectance parameters were measured in six-day frequency, while the leaf anatomy was examined only at the end of the second drought cycle. In both drought events, the WS plants showed reduction in stomatal conductance and leaf transpiration. The reduction in internal CO2 diffusion was observed in the second drought cycle, expressed by increased thickness of spongy parenchyma in both clones. Those stomatal and anatomical traits impacted decreasing the Anet in both drought events. The &#8216;3V&#8217; was less influenced by water stress than the &#8216;A1&#8217; genotype in Anet, effective quantum yield in PSII photochemistry, photochemical quenching, linear electron transport rate, and photochemical reflectance index during the drought-1, but during the drought-2 event such an advantage disappeared. Such physiological genotype differences were supported by the medium xylem vessel area diminished only in &#8216;3V&#8217; under WS. In both drought cycles, the recovery of all observed stomatal and non-stomatal responses was usually complete after 12 days of rewatering. The absence of photochemical impacts, namely in the maximum quantum yield of primary photochemical reactions, photosynthetic performance index, and density of reaction centers capable of QA reduction during the drought-2 event, might result from an acclimation response of the clones to WS. In the second drought cycle, the plants showed some improved responses to stress, suggesting &#8220;memory&#8221; effects as drought acclimation at a recurrent drought.</description>
      <author>Danilo For&#231;a Baroni, Guilherme Augusto Rodrigues de Souza, Wallace de Paula Bernado, Anne Reis Santos, Larissa Cris&#243;stomo de Souza Barcellos, Let&#237;cia Fernantes Tavares Barcelos, La&#237;sa Zanelato Correia, Claudio Martins de Almeida, Abra&#227;o Carlos Verdin Filho, Weverton Pereira Rodrigues, Jos&#233; C. Ramalho, Miroslava Rako&#269;evi&#263;, Eliemar Campostrini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/stresses4030037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Successful bevacizumab therapy in a 25-year-old patient with recurrent respiratory papillomatosis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12890/2024_004840</link>
      <description>Gita Dambrova, Zaiga Kravale, Dace &#381;enti&#326;a, A. Krumina, European Journal of Case Reports in Internal Medicine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402311660

                Background: Recurrent respiratory papillomatosis (RRP) is a chronic condition caused primarily by human papilloma virus (HPV) types 6 and 11, leading to recurrent growths in the respiratory tract. These types of papilloma can cause significant morbidity due to airway obstruction, often requiring frequent surgical interventions. Traditional treatments, including surgical removal and adjunctive therapies like antivirals and immune modulators, often fail to prevent recurrence, impacting the patient&#8217;s quality of life. Case description: This report presents a 25-year-old female with a long-standing history of RRP, diagnosed at age 2. Despite numerous interventions, including CO2 laser ablations, interferon therapy, HPV vaccination, and a laryngotomy with tracheal reconstruction, the patient continued to experience severe airway obstruction requiring frequent surgeries. In 2023, intravenous therapy with bevacizumab, vascular endothelial growth factor inhibitor was introduced, leading to a significant reduction in the frequency of surgical interventions from 8 to 4 per year. This reduction improved the patient&#8217;s respiratory function and quality of life, highlighting bevacizumab&#8217;s therapeutic potential. Conclusion: The case underscores the debilitating nature of RRP and the challenges of its management. Bevacizumab, by targeting vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF), has shown promise in reducing papilloma growth and the need for frequent surgeries. This case supports the inclusion of bevacizumab as an adjunctive therapy in RRP treatment, warranting further research to confirm its long-term efficacy and safety.</description>
      <author>Gita Dambrova, Zaiga Kravale, Dace &#381;enti&#326;a, A. Krumina</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12890/2024_004840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An attempt towards ferrochromium production using molten oxide electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/njrr1937</link>
      <description>Jhuma Biswas, Lassi Klemettinen, Dmitry Sukhomlinov, W Malan, Daniel M. Lindberg, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383082

                In order to mitigate the effects of climate change, our society must be able to drastically reduce its CO2 emissions. As the metallurgical industry is a considerable contributor to these emissions, new greener technologies must be invented and developed. One option could be the direct production of metals from oxides using renewable electricity. The aim of this study was to investigate the possibility of using high-temperature molten oxide electrolysis (MOE) for iron and ferrochrome production. FactSage&#8482;, ver 8.2 (by Thermfact Ltd and GTT-Technologies) was utilised for estimating a feasible equilibrium electrolyte composition, and the experiments were conducted at 1550&#8211;1580&#176;C in conical alumina crucibles with iridium wire as the cathode and platinum wire as the anode. The sources of iron and chromium were either pure FeO powder or industrial chromite pellets. Voltage was applied to the electrolysis cell for 6 hrs and the resulting current was measured, along with oxygen concentration in the off-gas line. The electrolyte comprised of SiO2, Al2O3, MgO and CaO. First, the effect of FeO concentration on iron reduction efficiency was investigated using only pure oxide powders as starting materials. The results indicated that 10 wt per cent FeO mixed with the electrolyte resulted in more efficient iron reduction compared to 20 wt per cent. In further experiments, industrial chromite pellets were ground and mixed with the CaO-free electrolyte. Iron and chromium reduction efficiencies were higher when approximately 19 wt per cent of the total sample mass consisted of pellets compared to increasing the pellet amount to 37 wt per cent. Generally, the chromium solubility in the liquid electrolyte was relatively low, and most of the chromium was confined to the spinel solid solution, from where its dissolution to the liquid electrolyte was very slow, resulting in slow reduction kinetics. For larger scale applications, economically more viable electrode materials should be investigated.</description>
      <author>Jhuma Biswas, Lassi Klemettinen, Dmitry Sukhomlinov, W Malan, Daniel M. Lindberg</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/njrr1937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determinants of Hotel Business Success in Rural Areas of the Western Balkan Countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177704</link>
      <description>Miroslav Pimi&#263;, Zoran Simonovi&#263;, Nikola Radivojevi&#263;, Iuliana Nicolae, Nikola &#262;ur&#269;i&#263;, Sustainability. 16(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402283450

                This paper examines the impact of ten microeconomic factors on hotel business success. This research encompassed a sample of 115 small, family-operated hotels situated in rural regions of the Western Balkan countries (WBC). This research was based on the assumption that factors such as the size of the hotel, age, solvency, liquidity, labour productivity, capital productivity, CSR, and reduction of CO2 emissions exhibit a positive influence on business success, whereas leverage, indebtedness, and energy consumption have a negative effect on the business success of hotels. The findings revealed that business success from the previous period, size, liquidity, and CSR exhibit a positive influence on business success, whereas leverage, capital productivity, and indebtedness demonstrate a negative effect. Conversely, the age of the hotel and labour productivity were not found to significantly influence business success, as did energy consumption. In the context of sustainable development, a positive CSR impact means that tourists value this behaviour of the hotel, while a lack of a statistically significant impact of energy consumption implies either that hotels do not implement efficient measures of energy efficiency or that energy efficiency may not be a crucial factor in attracting guests or influencing their loyalty. The findings also show that labour productivity expressed conventionally does not have a statistically significant impact on hotel business success. However, when expressed in a way that respects the concept of sustainable development and CSR, workforce productivity is a significant factor in hotel business success. Due to the problem of multicollinearity, the influence of CO2 emissions was not examined. The findings suggest the following two groups of key measures: 1. Policymakers must work on ensuring more favourable conditions under which hotels can borrow, as well as on ensuring adequate infrastructure; 2. They must work on improving the strategy for maintaining liquidity to avoid the high costs of short-term loans and increasing size in order to further utilise economies of scale. These two microeconomic factors have the greatest impact on the business success of hotels.</description>
      <author>Miroslav Pimi&#263;, Zoran Simonovi&#263;, Nikola Radivojevi&#263;, Iuliana Nicolae, Nikola &#262;ur&#269;i&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Fuzzy Traffic Signal Control System for Complex Intersections Using Fuzzy Rule Base Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/sym16091177</link>
      <description>Tamrat D. Chala, L&#225;szl&#243; T. K&#243;czy, Symmetry. 16(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402373510

                In this study, the concept of symmetry is employed to implement an intelligent fuzzy traffic signal control system for complex intersections. This approach suggests that the implementation of reduced fuzzy rules through the reduction method, without compromising the performance of the original fuzzy rule base, constitutes a symmetrical approach. In recent decades, urban and city traffic congestion has become a significant issue because of the time lost as a result of heavy traffic, which negatively affects economic productivity and efficiency and leads to energy loss, and also because of the heavy environmental pollution effect. In addition, traffic congestion prevents an immediate response by the ambulance, police, and fire brigades to urgent events. To mitigate these problems, a three-stage intelligent and flexible fuzzy traffic control system for complex intersections, using a novel hybrid reduction approach was proposed. The three-stage fuzzy traffic control system performs four primary functions. The first stage prioritizes emergency car(s) and identifies the degree of urgency of the traffic conditions in the red-light phase. The second stage guarantees a fair distribution of green-light durations even for periods of extremely unbalanced traffic with long vehicle queues in certain directions and, especially, when heavy traffic is loaded for an extended period in one direction and the short vehicle queues in the conflicting directions require passing in a reasonable time. The third stage adjusts the green-light time to the traffic conditions, to the appearance of one or more emergency car(s), and to the overall waiting times of the other vehicles by using a fuzzy inference engine. The original complete fuzzy rule base set up by listing all possible input combinations was reduced using a novel hybrid reduction algorithm for fuzzy rule bases, which resulted in a significant reduction of the original base, namely, by 72.1%. The proposed novel approach, including the model and the hybrid reduction algorithm, were implemented and simulated using Python 3.9 and SUMO (version 1.14.1). Subsequently, the obtained fuzzy rule system was compared in terms of running time and efficiency with a traffic control system using the original fuzzy rules. The results showed that the reduced fuzzy rule base had better results in terms of the average waiting time, calculated fuel consumption, and CO2 emission. Furthermore, the fuzzy traffic control system with reduced fuzzy rules performed better as it required less execution time and thus lower computational costs. Summarizing the above results, it may be stated that this new approach to intersection traffic light control is a practical solution for managing complex traffic conditions at lower computational costs.</description>
      <author>Tamrat D. Chala, L&#225;szl&#243; T. K&#243;czy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/sym16091177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting salt tolerance, growth, and phytochemical responses in coriander (Coriandrum sativum L. cv. Balady) via eco-friendly Bacillus subtilis and cobalt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12870-024-05517-3</link>
      <description>Sary H. Brengi, Maneea Moubarak, Hany M. El-Naggar, Amira R. Osman, BMC Plant Biology. 24(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402403258

                Abstract In plant production, evaluation of salt stress protectants concerning their potential to improve growth and productivity under saline stress is critical. Bacillus subtilis (Bs) and cobalt (Co) have been proposed to optimize salt stress tolerance in coriander ( Coriandrum sativum L. cv. Balady) plants by influencing some physiological activities. The main aim of this work is to investigate the response of (Bs) and (Co) as eco-safe salt stress protectants to resist the effect of salinity, on growth, seed, and essential oil yield, and the most important biochemical constituents of coriander produced under salt stress condition. Therefore, in a split-plot factorial experiment design in the RCBD (randomized complete block design), four levels of salinity of NaCl irrigation water (SA) were assigned to the main plots; (0.5, 1.5, 4, and 6 dS m &#8722;1 ); and six salt stress protectants (SP) were randomly assigned to the subplots: distilled water; 15 ppm (Co1); 30 ppm (Co2); (Bs); (Co1 + Bs); (Co2 + Bs). The study concluded that increasing SA significantly reduced coriander growth and yield by 42.6%, which could be attributed to ion toxicity, oxidative stress, or decreased vital element content. From the results, we recommend that applying Bs with Co (30 ppm) was critical for significantly improving overall growth parameters. This was determined by the significant reduction in the activity of reactive oxygen species scavenging enzymes: superoxide dismutase (SOD), catalase (CAT), and malondialdehyde (MDA) and non-enzyme: proline by 5, 11.3, 14.7, and 13.8% respectively, while increasing ascorbic acid by 8% and preserving vital nutrient levels and enhancing plant osmotic potential to buffer salt stress, seed yield per plant, and essential oil yield increased by 12.6 and 18.8% respectively. The quality of essential oil was indicated by highly significant quantities of vital biological phytochemicals such as linalool, camphor, and protein which increased by 10.3, 3.6, and 9.39% respectively. Additional research is suggested to determine the precise mechanism of action of Bs and Co's dual impact on medicinal and aromatic plant salt stress tolerance.</description>
      <author>Sary H. Brengi, Maneea Moubarak, Hany M. El-Naggar, Amira R. Osman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12870-024-05517-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic growth in developed and developing countries in the context of the transition to renewable energy sources</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0424738824020049</link>
      <description>O. V. Kudryavtseva, Sergey V. Chernyavskiy, Anna Utkina, Economics and Mathematical Methods. 60(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402214700

                Today, economic development is inseparably linked with global environmental problems. So, the search for their solutions without adverse influence on economic growth became relevant. The energy transition can ambiguously affect the pace and dynamics of economic growth. The purpose of this work is to identify the influence of the dynamics of investment in renewable energy on economic growth for groups of developed and developing countries and verification of the following hypotheses: for developing countries, the growth of investments in the renewable energy stimulates economic growth. For developed countries, the growth of investments in the renewable energy inhibits economic growth. Research results: with an increase in the share of income invested in the capital of renewable energy by 1% in developed countries the rate of economic growth will decrease by 0.0001%; while in developing countries &#8212; will increase by 0.0001%. The indicated reduction in the rate of economic growth for developed countries can be considered as a &#8220;payment&#8221; for the preference of the future state of ecology before the current receipt of additional release. As for developing countries, the energy transition positively affects the pace of economic growth. The fourth energy transition is a solution for global environmental problems caused by the CO2 emissions. The fourth energy transition based on the expansion of renewable energy sources and the displacement of fossil fuel is necessary since it is important for sustainable development of current and future generations.</description>
      <author>O. V. Kudryavtseva, Sergey V. Chernyavskiy, Anna Utkina</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0424738824020049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategical Resilient Approach Leading Towards Sustainability and Net Zero</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/220496-ms</link>
      <description>S. M. Ahmed, A. Al Ketbi, G. Al Katheiri, M. K. Al Mazrouei, Muhammad Aslam, F. Haider, M. S. Ahmed, Yousof Al-Hammadi, Mohammed Amir, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402397556

                Abstract Availability of essential relief systems at Oil Processing facilities is highly required to ensure safe handling of hydrocarbons during depressurization scenarios to avoid escalation of emergency situations. During maintenance of close drain systems, facilities are isolated, drained &amp; depressurized. Innovative methodology and strategic initiative piloted by ADNOC-Onshore Asset that enabled uninterrupted operations without close drain system by managing makeshift arrangements, avoided 45 days Station shutdown along with flaring of 3 MMscf gas/ 168 Tons CO2. To ensure essential relief system availability during maintenance and keeping station operational, all technical aspects utilizing external equipment reviewed. Key challenges were collaboratively evaluated in detail to enlist backup equipment requirements. To develop and execute this sustainable production approach, following method employed: Different emergency scenarios evaluated due to unavailability of drain system.Arranged backup draining/venting system (Containing Portable test separator, storage tank and pump arrangement).Performed comprehensive risk assessments and developed operational strategy to operate remote station with temporary arrangements.Work instructions revised.Requisite training imparted to operations staff to handle backup system.Mock drills conducted to verify workforce readiness. During the unavailability of essential relief systems, stations are depressurized to avoid any unforeseen scenarios that may escalate the unforeseen emergency situation. However, with the intention of keeping the station in operation to meet mandated &amp; sustainable production targets and ensuring safety of the facility and with the mindset of Net Zero flaring, this strategic resolution was piloted and implemented in house, in line with management of change procedures and protocols. Following benefits pertaining to Sustainability-Enabling Net zero were realized from this piloted novel approach: Production gain of 450,000 Barrel of Oil (10,000 barrels of oil per day for 45 days)Avoided 3 MMscf gas flaring &#8211; Reduction in GHG Emissions &#8211; 168 Tons CO2.Reduction in operational risk due to handling of hazardous hydrocarbons while carrying out depressurization activity. Implementation of this innovative and strategic solution has ensured continuous production from remote station, even in during the unavailability of essential relief system with the help of tailored made solution, that also eradicated the flaring of huge volumes of gas. The implemented solution is highly effective in ensuring continuous production with the mindset of Net zero flaring and can be replicated to other existing remote facilities in the company as well as Worldwide as best industry practice. This implementation will enhance the availability of relief system as well as ensuring the integrity of network and facilities thus avoiding flaring and liquid carry over during depressurization. This paper also demonstrates how the different approach can result in gaining continuous production form the facility and how the gas flaring can be abated for minimizing the environmental impacts. Technical challenges and solutions for alternate equipment, installing, and operating the system along with an insight using in house resources. The paper also highlights equipment selection and best practices for future replication by other Oil &amp; Gas Producers.</description>
      <author>S. M. Ahmed, A. Al Ketbi, G. Al Katheiri, M. K. Al Mazrouei, Muhammad Aslam, F. Haider, M. S. Ahmed, Yousof Al-Hammadi, Mohammed Amir</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/220496-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatio-Temporal Evolution and Multi-Scenario Modeling Based on Terrestrial Carbon Stocks in Xinjiang</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/land13091454</link>
      <description>Xiaohuang Liu, Zijing Xue, Jiufen Liu, Xiaofeng Zhao, Yanguang Fu, Ran Wang, Xinping Luo, Liyuan Xing, Chao Wang, Honghui Zhao, Land. 13(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402373528

                The increase in atmospheric CO2 leads to global warming and ecological environment deterioration. Carbon storage modeling and assessment can promote the sustainable development of the ecological environment. This paper took Xinjiang as the study area, analyzed the spatial and temporal evolution of land use in four periods from 1990 to 2020, explored the spatial relationship of carbon stocks using the InVEST model, and coupled the GMOP model with the PLUS model to carry out multiple scenarios for the future simulation of land use in the study area. We found (1) Over time, the types with an increasing area were mainly impervious and cropland, and the types with a decreasing area were grassland, snow/ice, and barren; spatially, the types were predominantly barren and grassland, with the conversion of grassland to cropland being more evident in the south of Northern Xinjiang and north of Southern Xinjiang. (2) The evolutionary pattern of terrestrial carbon stocks is increasing and then decreasing in time, and the carbon sink areas are concentrated in the Tarim River Basin and the vicinity of the Ili River; spatially, there are differences in the aggregation between the northern, southern, and eastern borders. By analyzing the transfer in and out of various categories in Xinjiang over the past 30 years, it was obtained that the transfer out of grassland reduced the carbon stock by 5757.84 &#215; 104 t, and the transfer out of Barren increased the carbon stock by 8586.12 &#215; 104 t. (3) The land use layout of the sustainable development scenario is optimal under the conditions of satisfying economic and ecological development. The reduction in terrestrial carbon stocks under the 2020&#8211;2030 sustainable development scenario is 209.79 &#215; 104 t, which is smaller than the reduction of 830.79 &#215; 104 t in 2010&#8211;2020. Land optimization resulted in a lower loss of carbon stocks and a more rational land-use layout. Future planning in Xinjiang should be based on sustainable development scenarios, integrating land resources, and achieving sustainable economic and ecological development.</description>
      <author>Xiaohuang Liu, Zijing Xue, Jiufen Liu, Xiaofeng Zhao, Yanguang Fu, Ran Wang, Xinping Luo, Liyuan Xing, Chao Wang, Honghui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/land13091454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental issue of sustainable textile industry: Examples of good manufacturing practices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5937/ct_iti24060z</link>
      <description>Darja B. &#381;arkovi&#263;, Marija Vu&#269;i&#263;evi&#263;, Milica Vlahovi&#263;, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402323931

                Growing impact on the environment and the rising demand for water, energy and raw materials that has resulted from the worldwide expansion of industry, put the principles of sustainability and cleaner production in a front line, as emergent activity. The textile industry consumes a high amount of energy and generates an enormous quantity of wastewater-worldwide, it generates 20 % of industrial wastewater and 8 % of greenhouse gas (GHG), while cotton production uses large amounts of pesticides, water and fertilizers. Many aspects of sustainable textile industry are not related only to production process itself (product quality and its market price, production process, supply of raw materials and its costs), but also to nus products, energy and water consumption, equipment service time, occupational health, and environmental issue. Thus, successful companies in textile production are driven by the basic principles of sustainable development and implementation of good manufacturing practice and cleaner production principles. This paper presents main principles of environmental protection in textile industry to be adopted toward sustainable production; these principles consider minimization of water, energy, virgin raw materials and chemicals usage, which results in reduction of the CO2 emissions, toward climate neutral production and business. Described company increases the share of sustainable/renewable materials and recycled materials, by accomplishing its own sustainability goals concerning environmental issue.</description>
      <author>Darja B. &#381;arkovi&#263;, Marija Vu&#269;i&#263;evi&#263;, Milica Vlahovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5937/ct_iti24060z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transport-Related Emissions and Transition Strategies for Sus-Tainability &#8211; a Case Study of the Fast Fashion Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0211.v1</link>
      <description>Alina Matuszak-Flejszman, Anna Preisner, Joanna K. Banach, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402249785

                The fast fashion industry has a significant impact on the environment at every stage of the product life cycle. There is a lack of research in the literature on the impact of fast fashion on the environment through logistics and transport. In this area, the greatest environmental impact is caused by air emissions, which is very important from the point of view of climate change. Therefore, this article deals with the analysis of the carbon footprint resulting from the fast fashion logistics process. The identification and assessment of fast fashion companies&amp;#039; sustainability efforts in the area of transport-related emissions and sustainable transformation strategies was conducted using a case study method for selected brands (H&amp;amp;M Group; Inditex, Shein). The study uses secondary data available in non-financial reports from 2023. After analyzing the data and content in non-financial reports on transport-related emissions, sev-eral important conclusions emerge. As a dominant practice, companies emphasize their reliance on external frameworks and standards, in particular the Global Reporting Initiative and the Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures. Companies prioritize reducing emissions from significant factors, such as production processes. The data disclosed in the reports (scope 1, 2, 3) are not clearly formulated, but they can be used to calculate the level of CO2 emission reduction/increase. The ar-ticle contains recommendations for companies to improve their reporting by including additional indicators expressing the efficiency of transport-related emissions.</description>
      <author>Alina Matuszak-Flejszman, Anna Preisner, Joanna K. Banach</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0211.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aficamten and Cardiopulmonary Exercise Test Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2024.2781</link>
      <description>Matthew M.Y. Lee, Ahmad Masri, Michael E. Nassif, Roberto Barriales&#8208;Villa, Theodore P. Abraham, Brian Claggett, Caroline Coats, Juan R. Gimeno, Ian J. Kulac, Isabela Landsteiner de Sampaio Am&#234;ndola, Chang-Sheng Ma, Martin S. Maron, Iacopo Olivotto, Anjali Owens, Scott D. Solomon, Josef Veselka, Daniel Jacoby, Stephen B. Heitner, Stuart Kupfer, Fady I. Malik, Lisa Meng, Amy Wohltman, Gregory B. Lewis, Andrew Wang, Mark V. Sherrid, Jacob P. Kelly, Ali J. Marian, Anjali Owens, Omar Wever&#8208;Pinzon, David S. Owens, Matthew T. Wheeler, Sherif F. Nagueh, Florian Rader, Frank McGrew, Timothy C. Wong, Thomas P. O&#8217;Neill, Richard G. Bach, Matthew N. Martinez, John L. Jefferies, Elias Collado, Aslan T. Turer, M Y, Zainal Hussain, Albree Tower&#8208;Rader, Bashar Hannawi, Jeffrey B. Geske, Sara Saberi, Dermot Phelan, Christopher M. Kramer, Nitasha Sarswat, Ferhaan Ahmad, Lubna Choudhury, Jeremy Markowitz, Sounok Sen, Patrick Bering, Martin S. Maron, Sandeep M. Jani, D. Marshall Brinkley, Srihari S. Naidu, Matthew J. Maurer, Noah Moss, Ozlem Bilen, Jorge Silva Enciso, Robert J Fraser, Ola Akinboboye, Craig R. Asher, Sitaramesh Emani, Abhinav Sharma, David Fermin, Melissa Lyle, David Raymer, Andrew Darlington, Frederic S. Resnic, Christopher D. Nielsen, Marco Metra, Beatrice Musumeci, Michele Emdin, Mattia Targetti, Marco Canepa, Michelle Michels, Chanakya Nath Kundu, Ahmad S. Amin, Roberto Barriales&#8208;Villa, Pablo Garc&#237;a Pav&#237;a, Juan R. Gimeno, Rafael Jesus Hidalgo Urbano, Luis Alonso-Pulp&#243;n, Tom&#225;s Vicente Vera, Ana Garc&#237;a &#193;lvarez, David Zem&#225;nek, Martin Bach Jensen, Jens Mogensen, Jens Jakob Thune, Henning Bundgaard, Philippe Charron, Jean&#8208;No&#235;l Trochu, Frank Kober, Thibault Lhermusier, Patricia R&#233;ant, Antoine Lafont, JAMA Cardiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402221290

                Importance Impaired exercise capacity is a cardinal manifestation of obstructive hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM). The Phase 3 Trial to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Aficamten Compared to Placebo in Adults With Symptomatic Obstructive HCM (SEQUOIA-HCM) is a pivotal study characterizing the treatment effect of aficamten, a next-in-class cardiac myosin inhibitor, on a comprehensive set of exercise performance and clinical measures. Objective To evaluate the effect of aficamten on exercise performance using cardiopulmonary exercise testing with a novel integrated measure of maximal and submaximal exercise performance and evaluate other exercise measures and clinical correlates. Design, Setting, and Participants This was a prespecified analysis from SEQUOIA-HCM, a double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized clinical trial. Patients were recruited from 101 sites in 14 countries (North America, Europe, Israel, and China). Individuals with symptomatic obstructive HCM with objective exertional intolerance (peak oxygen uptake [pVO 2 ] &#8804;90% predicted) were included in the analysis. Data were analyzed from January to March 2024. Interventions Randomized 1:1 to aficamten (5-20 mg daily) or matching placebo for 24 weeks. Main Outcomes and Measures The primary outcome was change from baseline to week 24 in integrated exercise performance, defined as the 2-component z score of pVO 2 and ventilatory efficiency throughout exercise (minute ventilation [VE]/carbon dioxide output [VCO 2 ] slope). Response rates for achieving clinically meaningful thresholds for change in pVO 2 and correlations with clinical measures of treatment effect (health status, echocardiographic/cardiac biomarkers) were also assessed. Results Among 282 randomized patients (mean [SD] age, 59.1 [12.9] years; 115 female [40.8%], 167 male [59.2%]), 263 (93.3%) had core laboratory&#8211;validated exercise testing at baseline and week 24. Integrated composite exercise performance improved in the aficamten group (mean [SD] z score, 0.17 [0.51]) from baseline to week 24, whereas the placebo group deteriorated (mean [SD] z score, &#8722;0.19 [0.45]), yielding a placebo-corrected improvement of 0.35 (95% CI, 0.25-0.46; P &amp;amp;lt;.001). Further, aficamten treatment demonstrated significant improvements in total workload, circulatory power, exercise duration, heart rate reserve, peak heart rate, ventilatory efficiency, ventilatory power, and anaerobic threshold (all P &amp;amp;lt;.001). In the aficamten group, large improvements (&#8805;3.0 mL/kg per minute) in pVO 2 were more common than large reductions (32% and 2%, respectively) compared with placebo (16% and 11%, respectively). Improvements in both components of the primary outcome, pVO 2 and VE/VCO 2 slope throughout exercise, were significantly correlated with improvements in symptom burden and hemodynamics (all P &amp;amp;lt;.05). Conclusions and Relevance This prespecified analysis of the SEQUOIA-HCM randomized clinical trial found that aficamten treatment improved a broad range of exercise performance measures. These findings offer valuable insight into the therapeutic effects of aficamten. Trial Registration ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT05186818</description>
      <author>Matthew M.Y. Lee, Ahmad Masri, Michael E. Nassif, Roberto Barriales&#8208;Villa, Theodore P. Abraham, Brian Claggett, Caroline Coats, Juan R. Gimeno, Ian J. Kulac, Isabela Landsteiner de Sampaio Am&#234;ndola, Chang-Sheng Ma, Martin S. Maron, Iacopo Olivotto, Anjali Owens, Scott D. Solomon, Josef Veselka, Daniel Jacoby, Stephen B. Heitner, Stuart Kupfer, Fady I. Malik, Lisa Meng, Amy Wohltman, Gregory B. Lewis, Andrew Wang, Mark V. Sherrid, Jacob P. Kelly, Ali J. Marian, Anjali Owens, Omar Wever&#8208;Pinzon, David S. Owens, Matthew T. Wheeler, Sherif F. Nagueh, Florian Rader, Frank McGrew, Timothy C. Wong, Thomas P. O&#8217;Neill, Richard G. Bach, Matthew N. Martinez, John L. Jefferies, Elias Collado, Aslan T. Turer, M Y, Zainal Hussain, Albree Tower&#8208;Rader, Bashar Hannawi, Jeffrey B. Geske, Sara Saberi, Dermot Phelan, Christopher M. Kramer, Nitasha Sarswat, Ferhaan Ahmad, Lubna Choudhury, Jeremy Markowitz, Sounok Sen, Patrick Bering, Martin S. Maron, Sandeep M. Jani, D. Marshall Brinkley, Srihari S. Naidu, Matthew J. Maurer, Noah Moss, Ozlem Bilen, Jorge Silva Enciso, Robert J Fraser, Ola Akinboboye, Craig R. Asher, Sitaramesh Emani, Abhinav Sharma, David Fermin, Melissa Lyle, David Raymer, Andrew Darlington, Frederic S. Resnic, Christopher D. Nielsen, Marco Metra, Beatrice Musumeci, Michele Emdin, Mattia Targetti, Marco Canepa, Michelle Michels, Chanakya Nath Kundu, Ahmad S. Amin, Roberto Barriales&#8208;Villa, Pablo Garc&#237;a Pav&#237;a, Juan R. Gimeno, Rafael Jesus Hidalgo Urbano, Luis Alonso-Pulp&#243;n, Tom&#225;s Vicente Vera, Ana Garc&#237;a &#193;lvarez, David Zem&#225;nek, Martin Bach Jensen, Jens Mogensen, Jens Jakob Thune, Henning Bundgaard, Philippe Charron, Jean&#8208;No&#235;l Trochu, Frank Kober, Thibault Lhermusier, Patricia R&#233;ant, Antoine Lafont</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2024.2781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical properties optimisation of the Zimbabwean limonite ore-carbon composite pellets as a sustainable feed for pig iron production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/pdzr2358</link>
      <description>S M Masuka, D.J. Simbi, Stavroula Maritsa, Edson Kugara Chiwandika, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402384080

                The steel industry is facing challenges on a global scale that include depletion of resources, huge energy consumption, and the emission of CO2. The demand for iron products is increasing due to the increased infrastructural development. Zimbabwe produced cast iron from scrap metals. However, there is currently a shortage of scrap, and yet Zimbabwe is rich in limonite ores that are currently being underutilised. The possibility of using limonite ore as a sustainable feed for pig iron production was investigated by preparing some limonite ore carbon composite pellets. The results showed that the addition of coal to the limonite ore and calcium carbonate mix to form the composite pellets resulted in a decrease in the drop number as well as the dry compressive strength of the composite pellets. This research aims to improve the physical properties of the green pellets by the careful addition of hydroxyethyl cellulose as a binder that was found to improve the physical properties of the green pellet. This is important for materials handling during the production process of the composite pellets. Results showed that the drop number was substantially improved by the addition of 0.4 wt per cent hydroxyethyl cellulose while the dry compression strength improved from 2.5 kg/pelIet to around 23 kg/pellet irrespective of the amount of binder added. The binder improved the physical strength of the iron-carbon composite pellets enough to allow for large-scale production of the pellets that can be an alternative and sustainable feed for cast iron production. However more results on the indurated compression strength and other properties such as the reduction degradation index, swelling index, and the reducibility test are required.</description>
      <author>S M Masuka, D.J. Simbi, Stavroula Maritsa, Edson Kugara Chiwandika</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/pdzr2358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transport-Related Emissions and Transition Strategies for Sustainability&#8212;A Case Study of the Fast Fashion Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177749</link>
      <description>Alina Matuszak-Flejszman, Anna Preisner, Joanna K. Banach, Sustainability. 16(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402320474

                The fast fashion industry significantly impacts the environment at every stage of, a product&#8217;s life cycle. The transport of products to wholesalers and stores, as one of the stages of the product life cycle, is often overlooked during the analysis of their carbon footprint. Therefore, research is needed on the impact of fast fashion on the environment through its logistics and transport, especially in relation to air emissions. This article attempts to determine how extensively fast fashion companies disclose the impact of their transport operations on their overall corporate carbon footprint, determine the proportion of total emissions attributed to transport, and evaluate the effectiveness of companies&#8217; efforts to mitigate their transport-related environmental impact. This research used a case study method on selected brands (H&amp;M Group, Inditex, Shein), using secondary data available in non-financial reports for 2023. As a result of the analysis of their non-financial reports on transport emissions, several key findings have been presented. Companies predominantly rely on external frameworks and standards, particularly the Global Reporting Initiative. However, the level of detail of the data presented varies. The priority for the surveyed companies is to reduce emissions from significant sources, such as production processes. The data disclosed in the reports (scope 1, 2, 3) must be clearly formulated and can be used to calculate the level of their CO2 emission reduction or increase. Companies should improve their environmental reporting by including indicators of their transport-related emissions. This approach provides a comprehensive view of their environmental impact, highlighting absolute values and efficiency metrics.</description>
      <author>Alina Matuszak-Flejszman, Anna Preisner, Joanna K. Banach</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Manual Maneuver on Shoulder Pain of Laparoscopic Gynecology Surgery, a Randomized Clinical Trial Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5812/fga-147734</link>
      <description>Fatemeh Salehi, Saeideh Shams Zamenjani, Saum Rahimi, Mina Fatehnejad, Elham Feizabad, Sara Saeedi, Fertility Gynecology and Andrology. 4(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402414016

                Background: Shoulder pain following gynecological laparoscopy is a common complication that requires treatment. Objectives: This study aimed to evaluate the effect of manual maneuvers on shoulder pain following laparoscopic surgery in women. Methods: This parallel clinical trial was conducted with 77 female laparoscopy candidates referred to Yas Hospital in Tehran in 2023. After the laparoscopic procedure, the intervention group had CO2 gas actively removed from the abdomen during a two-handed abdominal massage, while the control group received only traditional passive gas evacuation. The intensity of pain was assessed 6- and 24-hours post-operation using the Visual Analogue Scale (VAS), and the number of painkillers and anti-nausea medications used was recorded in each patient's chart. All data were entered into SPSS software and analyzed using appropriate statistical tests. Results: The average age of the women was 39.4 &#177; 10.1 years, and the average body mass index (BMI) was 27.5 &#177; 2.5 kg/m&#178;. No significant difference was observed between the two groups in these characteristics. Six hours after the operation, the pain intensity was 4.6 &#177; 0.86 in the intervention group and 6.2 &#177; 1.1 in the control group, with a significant reduction in the intervention group (P = 0.001). Twenty-four hours post-operation, pain intensity was 2.7 &#177; 0.79 in the intervention group and 4.2 &#177; 1.1 in the control group, again showing a significant decrease in the intervention group (P = 0.001). Additionally, the need for analgesics was significantly lower in the intervention group (P = 0.001). Conclusions: The results of this study indicate that manual abdominal massage following laparoscopic surgery can significantly reduce shoulder pain, decrease the need for analgesics, and enhance patient satisfaction.</description>
      <author>Fatemeh Salehi, Saeideh Shams Zamenjani, Saum Rahimi, Mina Fatehnejad, Elham Feizabad, Sara Saeedi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5812/fga-147734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Different Straw Return Modes on Soil Carbon, Nitrogen, and Greenhouse Gas Emissions in the Semiarid Maize Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13172503</link>
      <description>Hua Lu, Zhenxing Yang, Wenqian Li, Yidong Zhao, Jie Xia, Wenyi Dong, Baoqing Chen, Plants. 13(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402316776

                Returning straw to the field is a crucial practice for enhancing soil quality and increasing efficient use of secondary crop products. However, maize straw has a higher carbon-to-nitrogen ratio compared to other crops. This can result in crop nitrogen loss when the straw is returned to the field. Therefore, it is crucial to explore how different methods of straw return affect maize (Zea mays L.) farmland. In this study, a field experiment was performed with three treatments (I, no straw returned, CK; II, direct straw return, SR; and III, straw returned in deep furrows, ISR) to explore the effects of the different straw return modes on soil carbon and nitrogen content and greenhouse gas emissions. The results indicated that the SR and ISR treatments increased the dissolved organic carbon (DOC) content in the topsoil (0&#8211;15 cm). Additionally, the ISR treatment boosted the contents of total nitrogen (TN), nitrate nitrogen (NO3&#8722;-N), ammonium nitrogen (NH4+-N), dissolved organic nitrogen (DON), and DOC in the subsurface soil (15&#8211;30 cm) compared with CK. When it comes to greenhouse gas emissions, the ISR treatment led to an increase in CO2 emissions. However, SR and ISR reduced N2O emissions, with ISR showing a more pronounced reduction. The ISR treatment significantly increased leaf and grain biomass compared to CK and SR. The correlation analyses showed that the yield was positively correlated with soil DOC, and soil greenhouse gas emission was correlated with soil NO3&#8722;-N. The ISR technology has great potential in sequestering soil organic matter, improving soil fertility, and realizing sustainable agricultural development.</description>
      <author>Hua Lu, Zhenxing Yang, Wenqian Li, Yidong Zhao, Jie Xia, Wenyi Dong, Baoqing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13172503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Archive-Based Micro Genetic Algorithm Approach for Optimizing Wheel Bearing Performance and Reducing Friction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-01-3046</link>
      <description>Fabio Bogliacino, Paolo Re, Alessandro Ferrero, SAE technical papers on CD-ROM/SAE technical paper series. 1(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402344909

                &lt;div class="section abstract"&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;Cars and vans are accountable for 14.5% of the total CO2 emissions in the European Union, exerting a significant impact on public health and the environment. To align with the climate objectives set by the Council and the European Parliament, the Fit for 55 package encompasses a series of proposals aimed at revising and modernizing EU legislation while introducing new initiatives. The ultimate goal is to ensure that EU policies are in harmony with the climate targets, specifically the EU&#8217;s aspiration to reduce greenhouse gases (GHGs) by at least 55% by 2030 compared to 1990 levels and achieve climate neutrality by 2050. To meet the fleet average emissions targets, automotive Original Equipment Manufacturers (OEMs) are compelled to reduce emissions from their vehicles by addressing various components. The urgent need for car makers to reduce their carbon footprint, combined with the imperative to improve the mileage range of electric vehicles, has led to the creation of a novel methodology.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;This approach focuses on optimizing car wheel bearing performance, with a particular emphasis on reducing friction. In contrast to traditional methodologies relying on Design of Experiments (DOE) investigations, the newly developed tool leverages an Archive-based Micro Genetic Algorithm (AMGA) for optimization. This algorithm excels in identifying the optimal bearing design within a constrained timeframe and significantly reduces the number of calculations required. Consequently, this innovation leads to a streamlined customer response process with a notably reduced lead time and fully customized design. The tool comprehensively improves bearing performance by evaluating the internal design geometry to assess ball set friction and identifying optimal dimensions for the seal design.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;The objective of this paper is to delineate the comprehensive process involved in setting up and executing optimization, beginning with the identification of the most suitable algorithm. The paper further details the formulation of the optimization strategy tailored to meet customer requirements, highlights the key design factors identified for optimization and concludes by presenting the optimization results that underscore the potential for friction reduction. This holistic exploration covers the entire spectrum of optimization, offering insights into algorithm selection, strategy customization, and the tangible benefits achieved through friction reduction in the outcomes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <author>Fabio Bogliacino, Paolo Re, Alessandro Ferrero</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-01-3046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling the dust and gas contributions of the JWST/MIRI spectrum
  of Sz28</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.06077</link>
      <description>T. Kaeufer, P. Woitke, I. Kamp, J. Kanwar, Mengtao Min, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402387311

                Recent spectra of protoplanetary disks around very low-mass stars (VLMS), captured by the Mid-InfraRed Instrument (MIRI) on board the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), reveal a rich carbon chemistry. Current interpretations of these spectra are based on 0D slab models and provide valuable estimates for molecular emission temperatures and column densities in the innermost disk. However, the established fitting procedures and simplified models are challenged by the many overlapping gas features. We aim to simultaneously determine the molecular and the dust composition of the disk around the VLMS Sz28 in a Bayesian way. We model the JWST/MIRI spectrum of Sz28 up to $17\,\rm \mu m$ using the Dust Continuum Kit with Line emission from Gas (DuCKLinG). Systematically excluding different molecules from the Bayesian analysis allows for an evidence determination of all investigated molecules and isotopologues. We continue by examining the emission conditions and locations of all molecules, analysing the differences to previous 0D slab fitting, and analysing the dust composition. We find very strong Bayesian evidence for the presence of C2H2, HCN, C6H6, CO2, HC3N, C2H6, C3H4, C4H2, and CH4 in the JWST/MIRI spectrum of Sz28. Additionally, we identify CH3 and find tentative indications for NH3. There is no evidence for water in the spectrum. However, we show that column densities of up to $2\times10^{17}\,\rm cm^{-2}$ could be hidden in the observational noise if assuming similar emission conditions of water as the detected hydrocarbons. Contrary to previous 0D slab results, a C4H2 quasi-continuum is robustly identified. We expect some of the stated differences to previous 0D slab fitting results to arise from an updated data reduction of the spectrum, but also due to the different modelling process. The latter reason underpins the need for more advanced models and fitting procedures.</description>
      <author>T. Kaeufer, P. Woitke, I. Kamp, J. Kanwar, Mengtao Min</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.06077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Differently &#8211; Energy Optimization and Flaring Reduction Approach Improvising Sustainable Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/220346-ms</link>
      <description>Sajjad Akhtar, A. Al Ketbi, G. Al Katheiri, M. K. Al Mazrouei, Muhammad Aslam, Yousof Al-Hammadi, F. Haider, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402426170

                Abstract This paper presents the innovative practice and tactical initiative adapted by ADNOC-Onshore Asset to ensure sustainable production from the facility by thinking differently and avoiding standby pump startup with mindset of optimizing energy and avoiding flaring gas volumes. As per operational conditions and to meet production mandate, the deem necessity of 2nd pump startup reevaluated and avoided by implementing this innovative approach and resulted in energy consumption optimization and avoided huge volume of gas flaring. The alternate approach adapted due to following main challenges: MPP High energy consumption at flowing wells extra loadHigh water flow envisaged the requirement of operating two pumps specially in summer when MPP suction temperature rises.Suction pressure increases upon MPP trip. To re start pump with minimum suction pressure permissive it requires to depressurize suction header. Consequently, list of high potential wells developed, MPPs turndown capacities analyzed. Hence high potential wells operated through MPP bypass and low potential wells kept flowing through MPP. It resulted in not only reducing load on running MPP but also 2nd MPP operation avoided. This strategic resolution was implemented in house without extra cost. Following benefits were obtained from this exercise and will remain beneficial in future also: Energy conservation due to less load on running MPP and hence avoiding the operation of 2nd MPP &#8211; daily use of extra 1000kW (18k USD per annum considering power cost 190 AED/1000kwh) was saved. 3000 Metric Ton CO2 Saved due to Green Power saving.Less corrective maintenance due to single MPP operationSuction strainer maintenance and also new strainer cost was avoided - 20k AEDMeeting monthly targets without compromising production allowableMin GHG emissions (54 tons eq CO2) while draining/depressurization during MPP trip &#8211; suction pressure increases due to MPP trip because of non-smart wells. In order to re start pump and to obtain min suction pressure start up permissive it was required to depressurize header.No extra cost in this project but cost saving with continuous production.Continuous &#172;4000 BOPD production in case of MPP trip over the night or daytime - considering 2 trips per annum. This in-house completed strategic solution resulted in ensuring continuous production from the station and thus avoiding flaring. The implemented pilot solution is highly effective in ensuring continuous production, optimizing energy consumption and can be replicated to other existing facilities in the company. This implementation will enhance the availability of facility with Standby equipment and also proved helpful in contributing under the pillar of Sustainability &#8211; Reduction in flaring/optimizing energy. The characteristics and sustainable production of the high potential wells were evaluated and listed down. The effect of back pressure on the flow of the wells assessed. MPP operation at low throughput provided confidence to reduce the suction flow. Following the minimum flow requirement of MPP, potential of the wells to be taken on MPP bypass and mindset to reduce GHG emissions through any opportunity assisted to finalize the mode of remote field operation. Taking the advantage of production cushion, MPP was further utilized to divert more flow from future wells. Due to high water cut and increase in suction temperature of MPP, it was required to curtail the production through certain wells to overcome temperature issue. High water flow envisaged the requirement of operating two pumps specially in summer when MPP suction temperature was rising up. Diverting the high potential wells, avoided the start-up of 2nd pump hence reducing the extra power consumption of 1000kwh. Resulted in optimizing the energy from running MPP also. In case of pump of any running pump tripping, suction pressure goes up due to connectivity of non smart wells with the suction header. MPP constitutes certain suction pressure permissive. In order to achieve suction pressure, it is envisaged to depressurize suction pressure to relief/close drain system which lead to flaring / GHG emissions.</description>
      <author>Sajjad Akhtar, A. Al Ketbi, G. Al Katheiri, M. K. Al Mazrouei, Muhammad Aslam, Yousof Al-Hammadi, F. Haider</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/220346-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Different Amounts of Exogenous Surfactant Differently Influence Cerebrovascular Instability in a Consecutive Group of Preterm Babies? Preliminary Results from a Single-Center Experience</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/children11091088</link>
      <description>Andrea Calandrino, Samuele Caruggi, Francesco Vinci, Marcella Battaglini, Paolo Massirio, Gaia Cipresso, Chiara Andreato, Giorgia Brigati, Boubou Hallberg, Giulia Polleri, Diego Minghetti, Luca A. Ramenghi, Children. 11(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402269619

                Background: Thirty years ago, the first attempt by Saliba and colleagues was made to reduce the negative effects (hypercarbia) of exogenous surfactant (ES) by slowing its administration. Sixteen years later, we observed the first less invasive surfactant administration (LISA) attempt by Kribs and colleagues. Many studies, since that time, have tried to minimize the invasiveness of ES and subsequent cerebral blood flow perturbations through studies using near-infrared spectroscopy (NIRS). We sought to address this medical challenge by identifying a less problematic modality of ES administration by delivering multiple aliquots of ES instead of a single one, as typically performed. The aim of this study was to test the hypothesis that a different way of administering ES using more aliquots could be a safe alternative that should be assessed in further studies. Methods: Patients between 26 + 0 and 35 + 6 weeks of gestational age (GA) requiring ES administration were enrolled (April 2023&#8211;February 2024). Differently fractioned doses were delivered according to an arbitrary standard dosage (0.3 mL per aliquot in babies &lt; 29 weeks; 0.6 mL in babies &#8805; 29 weeks), while NIRS and transcutaneous CO2 (tCO2) monitoring were always performed. ES&#8217;s effectiveness was assessed based on the reduction in the Oxygen Saturation Index (OSI) after administration. Persistent desaturation, bradycardia, and airway obstruction were defined as adverse effects and used to evaluate safety during ES administration, as well as variability in NIRS-rSO2 values and tCO2. Results: Twenty-four patients were enrolled with a median GA of 29 weeks (IQR 4.5) and BW of 1223 &#177; 560 g. In addition, 50% of the cohort received fewer than three aliquots, whereas the other 50% received more than three. Monitoring was started before the procedure and continued 30&#8242; after the last ES aliquot administration. The variability in NIRS-SpO2 values was significantly higher in the group (p = 0.007) with a lower number of aliquots administered. Similarly, increased NIRS-rSO2 values (p = 0.003) and increased tCO2 levels (p = 0.005) were observed in infants who underwent an ES split after the administration of a low number of aliquots. Conclusions: Our data obtained from the group with &gt; 3 fractionated doses of ES seem to justify the preparation of a more robust study, as the combination of reduced NIRS variability and reduced tCO2 maximum levels is consistent with more stable cerebral blood flow during the challenging time of ES administration.</description>
      <author>Andrea Calandrino, Samuele Caruggi, Francesco Vinci, Marcella Battaglini, Paolo Massirio, Gaia Cipresso, Chiara Andreato, Giorgia Brigati, Boubou Hallberg, Giulia Polleri, Diego Minghetti, Luca A. Ramenghi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/children11091088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Carbon Footprint: A Field Study of Low Carbon, Cement-Free Well Construction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/220420-ms</link>
      <description>Mark Meade, Veronica Richter McDonald, Normann Fischer, Saurabh Kapoor, William Smith, Yeukayi Nenjerama, Ronal Bejarano, R. Angel, Chris Parton, Guillaume Landry, No host. 28(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402426187

                Abstract Well construction includes hard-to-abate emissions, notably from its well cementing operations. Reducing carbon emissions associated with cement is a priority because cement is used in nearly every well drilled today, with an impact of approximately one ton of carbon emissions per ton of cement used. This paper presents an innovative technology: making well cementing without Portland cement at scale a reality. Geopolymers made from aluminosilicates comprising industrial waste materials are considered a sustainable alternative to Portland cement. Existing geopolymer formulations found in academia are not scalable for land-based well construction cementing operations, as they are unmixable using standard equipment and have increased health, safety, and environmental risks (HSE). Thus, a novel geopolymer blend was engineered for well construction applications that is mixable with existing equipment and reduces HSE risk through eliminating the onsite handling of corrosive liquids. Additionally, a Sustainability Assessment Tool was created to quantify and compare carbon emissions at different steps such as manufacturing materials, transportation, and onsite operations. Field trials of the novel geopolymer blend in the fast-paced Permian Basin confirmed this technology could be implemented within the oilfield cementing process with the same efficiency and efficacy as the conventional cement-based operation. During the field trials, the geopolymer system was deployed without any changes to the field mixing equipment and without any HSE incidents. Sonic logs of a subset of wells confirmed conventional logging equipment can detect set geopolymer within the wellbore and validates industry-standard simulators to predict placement. Using the Sustainability Assessment Tool confirmed that the emissions from the slurry components are more significant than the emissions related to logistics and operations. The quality and availability of the emission factors of slurry components are key, with multiple data sources considered for reliable quantification. The proposed low-carbon geopolymer cement-free system in current field application eliminates up to 85% of Scope 3 CO2 emissions compared with conventional Portland cement systems. The industry can capitalize on these benefits with no change in operations or increased HSE risks. Decarbonizing the well construction process while maintaining safety and performance standards is critical to the oil and gas industry's pathway to meeting emissions reduction targets. This geopolymer cement-free system is a breakthrough that delivers industry-standard zonal isolation capabilities while significantly minimizing environmental impact from upstream oil and gas production.</description>
      <author>Mark Meade, Veronica Richter McDonald, Normann Fischer, Saurabh Kapoor, William Smith, Yeukayi Nenjerama, Ronal Bejarano, R. Angel, Chris Parton, Guillaume Landry</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/220420-ms</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
