<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CO2RR</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/CO2RR.xml</link>
    <description>Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 01:05:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A review of catalytic reduction of carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/63/20241001</link>
      <description>Jiajie Shen, Applied and computational engineering. 63(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396737676

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) generated from the consumption of fossil fuels is one of the main factors contributing to the greenhouse effect. How to mitigate the greenhouse effect and reduce the extraction and consumption of fossil fuels has become an issue worthy of study. In recent years, a technology for the catalytic reduction of CO2 to fossil fuels and chemicals has attracted a great deal of attention by providing a new way to solve this problem. This paper reviews the basic principles of three fundamental catalytic CO2 reduction, photocatalysis, electrocatalysis and thermocatalysis, and two advanced catalytic modes, thermocatalysis and photoelectrocatalysis, derived from these three modes, as well as their advantages and disadvantages. In addition, the challenges that the catalytic reduction of CO2 is currently facing are also discussed. Although this technology has made significant progress over the decades, it is still in its preliminary stage with some shortcomings and there is a long way to go before it can be applied in reality.</description>
      <author>Jiajie Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/63/20241001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism study on dissociation of hydrogen and carbon dioxide towards carbon dioxide methanation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152021</link>
      <description>Baowang Lu, Yuyu Liu, Mitsuhiro Inoue, Eric Rukundo, Takayuki Abe, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396749524

                The study of carbon dioxide (CO2) methanation mechanisms widely argues on the nature and formation of intermediates. How reactants dissociate is still poorly understood. To gain deeper knowledge on its mechanism, we focused on studying reactants dissociation. After H2 dissociation and diffusion, the spillover H atom was observed, as well as the confirmation of H cluster formation on metal through aggregation by simulation and experiment. This H cluster facilitated C-O bond scission to easily form H ligand cobonded to metal, and thus resulted in high CO2 methanation performance. Four driving forces could dissociate CO2, three of them came from supports and metals, and another one was atomic H on metal as the strongest force. This simple and convenient method has wide adaptability and can be developed as an effective standard method for studying CO2 dissociation. The facile dissociation study of reactants would be very helpful in understanding the CO2 hydrogenation mechanism.</description>
      <author>Baowang Lu, Yuyu Liu, Mitsuhiro Inoue, Eric Rukundo, Takayuki Abe</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing the oxidation state of catalysts for effective electrochemical carbon dioxide conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00887h</link>
      <description>Zhitong Wang, Lizhi Xu, Yansong Zhou, Ying Liang, Jinzhu Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Shuyu Zhang, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Xiaodong Shi, Jing Li, Yuliang Yuan, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Chemical Society reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396770106

                In the electrocatalytic CO</description>
      <author>Zhitong Wang, Lizhi Xu, Yansong Zhou, Ying Liang, Jinzhu Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Shuyu Zhang, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Xiaodong Shi, Jing Li, Yuliang Yuan, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00887h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical ring-opening carboxylation of cyclic carbonate with carbon dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01695e</link>
      <description>Li Tao, He Wang, Xiaofei Liu, Wei&#8208;Min Ren, Xiao&#8208;Bing Lu, Wenzhen Zhang, Chemical communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396777302

                Electroreductive ring-opening carboxylation of styrene carbonates with CO2 to achieve dicarboxylic acids and/or &#946;-hydroxy acids has been developed via the selective cleavage of C(sp3)&#8211;O bond in cyclic carbonates. The product...</description>
      <author>Li Tao, He Wang, Xiaofei Liu, Wei&#8208;Min Ren, Xiao&#8208;Bing Lu, Wenzhen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01695e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Production of Ethylene and Hydrogen Peroxide from Paired Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction and Water Oxidation (Adv. Energy Mater. 18/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202470075</link>
      <description>Sotirios Mavrikis, Mich&#233;l K. Nieuwoudt, Maximilian G&#246;ltz, Sophie Ehles, Andreas K&#246;rner, Andreas Hutzler, Emeric Fossy, Andreas Zervas, Oshioriamhe Brai, Moritz Wegener, Florian Doerrfuss, Peter Bouwman, Stefan Rosiwal, Ling Wang, Carlos Ponce de Le&#243;n, Advanced energy materials. 14(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396807071

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sotirios Mavrikis, Mich&#233;l K. Nieuwoudt, Maximilian G&#246;ltz, Sophie Ehles, Andreas K&#246;rner, Andreas Hutzler, Emeric Fossy, Andreas Zervas, Oshioriamhe Brai, Moritz Wegener, Florian Doerrfuss, Peter Bouwman, Stefan Rosiwal, Ling Wang, Carlos Ponce de Le&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202470075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur dioxide- resistant platinum-based intermetallic nanocatalysts encaged by porous nitrogen-doped carbon for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152162</link>
      <description>Manli Wang, Longsheng Cao, Zhiwen Li, Wenbing Yang, Shucheng Sun, Ming Hou, Zhigang Shao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396822671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manli Wang, Longsheng Cao, Zhiwen Li, Wenbing Yang, Shucheng Sun, Ming Hou, Zhigang Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Modulating the Density of Catalytic Sites in Multiple-Component Covalent Organic Frameworks for Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07187</link>
      <description>Minghao Liu, Xinglei Zhao, Shuai Yang, Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Jun He, George Chen, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396872867

                ADVERTISEMENT RETURN TO ARTICLES ASAPPREVAddition/CorrectionNEXTORIGINAL ARTICLEThis notice is a correctionCorrection to "Modulating the Density of Catalytic Sites in Multiple-Component Covalent Organic Frameworks for Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction"Minghao LiuMinghao LiuMore by Minghao Liu, Xingyue ZhaoXingyue ZhaoMore by Xingyue Zhao, Shuai YangShuai YangMore by Shuai Yanghttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-9798-2239, Xiubei YangXiubei YangMore by Xiubei Yang, Xuewen LiXuewen LiMore by Xuewen Li, Jun He*Jun HeMore by Jun Hehttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-8056-0347, George Zheng ChenGeorge Zheng ChenMore by George Zheng Chenhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-5589-5767, Qing Xu*Qing XuMore by Qing Xuhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-9066-9837, and Gaofeng Zeng*Gaofeng ZengMore by Gaofeng Zenghttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-0034-1871Cite this: ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2024, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXPublication Date (Web):May 13, 2024Publication History Received1 May 2024Published online13 May 2024https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsami.4c07187https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07187correctionACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissions This publication is free to access through this site. Learn MoreArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-LEARN ABOUT THESE METRICSArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated. Share Add toView InAdd Full Text with ReferenceAdd Description ExportRISCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore Options Share onFacebookTwitterWechatLinked InRedditEmail PDF (640 KB) Get e-AlertscloseSupporting Info (1)&#187;Supporting Information Supporting Information Get e-Alerts</description>
      <author>Minghao Liu, Xinglei Zhao, Shuai Yang, Xiubei Yang, Xuewen Li, Jun He, George Chen, Qing Xu, Gaofeng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide to C4+ products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101534</link>
      <description>Xiangyun Ma, Boon Siang Yeo, Current opinion in electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396815395

                Long-chain hydrocarbons and oxygenates are used as fuels as well as in many daily applications. The majority of these molecules are derived from fossil fuels, which is a non-renewable commodity. The electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) has been recently found promising in producing C4+ molecules. Herein, we summarize recent works on this topic. The design of C4+ -producing catalysts is compared with those that produce C1-C3 products. Mechanisms for the C&#8211;C coupling step are reviewed.</description>
      <author>Xiangyun Ma, Boon Siang Yeo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101534</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Particulate Matter and Carbon Dioxide Reduction of Four Broad-leaved Evergreen Plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.11628/ksppe.2024.27.2.95</link>
      <description>Huong-Thi Bui, Moonsun Jeong, Sang Yong Kim, Bong-Ju Park, Journal of people, plants, and environment. 27(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396747635

                Background and objective: Since people spend 70-80% of their time indoors, the quality of indoor air has become a crucial factor in overall health. Therefore, poor indoor air quality can have significant adverse effects on our well-being. Common indoor air pollutants are particulate matter (PM) and carbon dioxide (CO2). Plants can remove PM and CO2 through the photosynthesis process and leaf surfaces, and regulate the temperature and humidity of the air. By analyzing the PM and CO2 reduction of four broad-leaved evergreen plants, this study aims to provide data for air purification in indoor spaces.Methods: The four different plant species (Neolitsea sericea (Blume) Koidz., Coffea arabica L., Photinia glabra(Thunb.) Franch. and Sav., and Farfugium japonicum (L.) Kitam.) were selected for this study. Mosquito coils and a CO2 cylinder were the primary sources of PM and CO2. These pollutants were injected into a closed acrylic chamber with plants, and the air quality within the chamber was monitored for a duration of five hours. The plants' effectiveness in reducing carbon dioxide was evaluated through the clean air delivery rate (CADR), while their ability to reduce PM was assessed by analyzing the PM reduction rate. Photosynthetic rates and leaf area were also measured to determine the correlation between air pollution removal and these factors.Results: The ability to remove PM and CO2 varied among plants. Plants with higher rates of photosynthesis were more effective in reducing PM and CO2 than those with lower rates. Among the four plant species, C. arabica and P. glabra were more effective in removing PM and CO2 than the other species. The chamber containing plants exhibited higher humidity and lower temperatures compared to the chamber without plants.Conclusion: These findings suggest that plants can play a significant role in improving indoor air quality. Not only do they effectively reduce levels of PM and CO2, but they also contribute to the regulation of indoor temperature and humidity. The implications of these results highlight the potential of integrating plants into indoor spaces as a natural and multifaceted solution for creating healthier and more comfortable environments.</description>
      <author>Huong-Thi Bui, Moonsun Jeong, Sang Yong Kim, Bong-Ju Park</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.11628/ksppe.2024.27.2.95</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studying the Impact of Renewable Energy Management Systems and Nuclear Energy on Carbon Dioxide Emissions Reductions in G20 Countries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823447</link>
      <description>Amr R. Kamel, Mohamed R. Abonazel, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396816587

                Renewable and nuclear energy are seen as clean and eco-friendly substitutes for energy derived from fossil fuels. Which of the two is better, though, is still up for debate. In order to meet their combined global energy objectives and perhaps become carbon neutral or even carbon negative in the near future, a shift to additional renewable energy sources and nuclear energy will be necessary. One such method of improving energy usage through the implementation of a renewable energy management system (REMS) that will help attain a continuous and reliable source of energy, allowing for the proactive and effective management of renewable assets and dependable supply. This article investigates attitudes and opinions about nuclear and renewable energy production technologies by analyzing the dependence of carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions on non-renewable energy sources, renewable energy sources, and nuclear energy in the group of twenty (G20) countries, over the period from 2000 to 2021. This study employs advanced panel data econometric techniques in the presence of outliers in the G20 dataset, utilizing a random coefficient regression (RCR) model via the robust M-estimation approach to study the impacts of non-renewable, renewable, and nuclear energy use with respect to CO2 emission mitigation in G20 countries. The overall conclusions of the econometric analysis confirm renewable and nuclear energy's importance in reducing CO2 emissions. The findings indicate that energy derived from renewable sources reduces CO2 emissions. Total energy consumption, on the other hand, increases CO2 emissions in the long run. Furthermore, the findings pinpoint that nuclear energy greatly cuts CO2 emissions in all G20 countries. According to these findings, it is pivotal for the G20 countries to increase nuclear energy use and employ REMS to reduce the majority of G20 countries' reliance on fossil fuels in order to minimize CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Amr R. Kamel, Mohamed R. Abonazel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A customized Sn3O4 interface to stabilize *CO2 intermediate for efficient electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152224</link>
      <description>Lei Zhou, Zhenping Qu, Liang Fu, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396853923

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zhou, Zhenping Qu, Liang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post&#8208;synthetic Metalation on the Ionic TiO2 Surface to Enhance Metal&#8208;CO2 Interaction During Photochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400428</link>
      <description>Laxmikanta Mallick, Krishna Samanta, Biswarup Chakraborty, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396740359

                During the photochemical CO2 reduction reaction, CO2 adsorption on the catalyst&#8217;s surface is a crucial step where the binding mode of the [metal&#8208;CO2] adduct directs the product selectivity and efficiency. Herein, an ionic TiO2 nanostructure stabilized by polyoxometalates (POM), ([POM]x@TiO2), is prepared and the sodium counter ions present on the surface to balance the POMs&#8217; charge are replaced with copper(II) ions, (Cux[POM]@TiO2). The microscopic and spectroscopic studies affirm the copper exchange without altering the TiO2 core and weak coordination of copper (II) ions to the POMs&#8217; surface. Band structure analysis suggests the photo&#8208;harvesting efficiency of the TiO2 core with the conduction band edge higher than the reduction potential of CuII/I and multi&#8208;electron CO2 reduction potentials. Photochemical CO2 reduction with Cux[POM]@TiO2 results in 30 &#181;mol gcat.&#8208;1 CO (79%) and 8 &#181;mol gcat&#8208;1 of CH4 (21%). Quasi&#8208;in&#8208;situ Raman study provides evidence in support of CO2 adsorption on the Cux[POM]@TiO2 surface. 13C and D2O labeling studies validates the {Cu&#8208;[CO2]&#8208;} adduct formation. Despite the photo&#8208;harvesting ability of Nax[POM]@TiO2 itself, the poor CO2 adsorption ability of sodium ions highlights the crucial role of copper ion CO2 photo&#8208;reduction. Characterization of the {M&#8208;[&#951;2&#8208;CO2]&#8208;} species via surface tuning validates the CO2 activation and photochemical reduction pathway proposed earlier.</description>
      <author>Laxmikanta Mallick, Krishna Samanta, Biswarup Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite Oxide Catalysts for Enhanced CO2 Reduction: Embroidering Surface Decoration with Ni and Cu Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14050313</link>
      <description>Andrea Osti, Lorenzo Rizzato, Jonathan Cavazzani, Anna Meneghello, Antonella Glisenti, Catalysts. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396805639

                The imperative reduction of carbon dioxide into valuable fuels stands as a crucial step in the transition towards a more sustainable energy system. Perovskite oxides, with their high compositional and property adjustability, emerge as promising catalysts for this purpose, whether employed independently or as a supporting matrix for other active metals. In this study, an A-site-deficient La0.9FeO3 perovskite underwent surface decoration with Ni, Cu or Ni + Cu via a citric acid-templated wet impregnation method. Following extensive characterization through XRD, N2 physisorption, H2-TPR, SEM-EDX, HAADF STEM-EDX mapping, CO2-TPD and XPS, the prepared powders underwent reduction under diluted H2 to yield metallic nanoparticles (NPs). The prepared catalysts were then evaluated for CO2 reduction in a CO2/H2 = 1/4 mixture. The deposition of Ni or Cu NPs on the perovskite support significantly enhanced the conversion of CO2, achieving a 50% conversion rate at 500 &#176;C, albeit resulting in only CO as the final product. Notably, the catalyst featuring Ni-Cu co-deposition outperformed in the intermediate temperature range, exhibiting high selectivity for CH4 production around 350 &#176;C. For this latter catalyst, a synergistic effect of the metal&#8211;support interaction was evidenced by H2-TPR and CO2-TPD experiments as well as a better nanoparticle dispersion. A remarkable stability in a 20 h time-span was also demonstrated for all catalysts, especially the one with Ni-Cu co-deposition.</description>
      <author>Andrea Osti, Lorenzo Rizzato, Jonathan Cavazzani, Anna Meneghello, Antonella Glisenti</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14050313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction mechanism of Cu surface in CO2 reduction process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100328</link>
      <description>Ding Wang, Tianbao Zhang, Zhenxing Li, Jiegou huaxue/Chinese journal of structural chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396750255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ding Wang, Tianbao Zhang, Zhenxing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironment effects from first principles multiscale modeling of electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ff7s8</link>
      <description>Francesca Lorenzutti, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Evan Johnson, Santiago Morandi, Pavle Nikacevic, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Sophia Haussener, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396748070

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction will be a key player in net-zero technologies, yet its industrial implementation is limited. Improvements by fine-tuning the microenvironments, electrolyte environments around the catalytic sites, have been scarce due to the interplay between electrode kinetics and transport. Here, we couple atomistic insights with continuum transport via ab-initio multiscale modeling, explicitly including electrolyte effects at all scales. The model was validated on Ag planar electrodes in several liquid electrolytes and the current dependence with voltage aligns with experimental observations. We show that a balance between CO2 diffusion and cation accumulation needs be achieved to obtain optimal rates. In ionomers, this limitation can be overcome since organic cations-based microenvironments are present at a fixed concentration, but water management becomes critical. Our approach paves the way towards rational microenvironment design in electrochemical CO2 conversion.</description>
      <author>Francesca Lorenzutti, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Evan Johnson, Santiago Morandi, Pavle Nikacevic, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Sophia Haussener</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ff7s8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>meso-Substituent electronic effect of Fe porphyrins on electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01630k</link>
      <description>Hui He, Zi-Yang Qiu, Yin Zhu, Jiafan Kong, Jingshuang Dang, Haitao Lei, Wensheng Zhang, Rui Cao, Chemical communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396782357

                We report Fe porphyrins bearing different meso-substituents for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). By replacing two and four meso-phenyl groups of Fe tetraphneylporphyrin (FeTPP) with strong electron-withdrawing penta&#64258;uorophenyl groups, we...</description>
      <author>Hui He, Zi-Yang Qiu, Yin Zhu, Jiafan Kong, Jingshuang Dang, Haitao Lei, Wensheng Zhang, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01630k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigations on PbS/SiPY-Based Photocathode for Photoelectrochemical Reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524030054</link>
      <description>K. Benfadel, L. Talbi, Sabiha Anas Boussaa, A. Boukezzata, Y. Ouadah, D. S. Allam, Sma&#239;n Hocine, L. Allad, A. Ouerk, C. Torki, S. Bouanik, S. Achacha, A. Manseri, F. Kezzoula, A. Keffous, S. Kaci, Russian journal of electrochemistry. 60(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396731974

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Benfadel, L. Talbi, Sabiha Anas Boussaa, A. Boukezzata, Y. Ouadah, D. S. Allam, Sma&#239;n Hocine, L. Allad, A. Ouerk, C. Torki, S. Bouanik, S. Achacha, A. Manseri, F. Kezzoula, A. Keffous, S. Kaci</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524030054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of an Ilmenite Concentrate by Using a Novel CO2/CH4 Thermal Plasma Torch</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min14050502</link>
      <description>Mohammed El Khalloufi, Gervais Soucy, Jonathan Lapointe, Marcel Paquet, Minerals. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396802815

                Plasma technology has emerged as a very helpful tool in a variety of sectors, notably metallurgy. Innovators and scientists are focused on the problem of finding a more ecologically friendly way of extracting titanium and iron metal from natural ilmenite concentrate for industrial applications. A direct current (DC) plasma torch operating at atmospheric pressure is used in this study to describe a decarbonization process for reducing an ilmenite concentrate. The plasma gases employed in this torch are CO2 and CH4. The molar ratio of the gases may be crucial for achieving a satisfactory reduction of the ilmenite concentrate. As a result, two molar ratios for CO2/CH4 have been chosen: 1:1 and 2:1. During torch operation, a thin layer of graphite is formed on the cathode to establish a protective barrier, prolonging the cathode&#8217;s life. The material was analyzed using X-ray diffraction (XRD) and scanning electron microscopy with energy dispersive spectroscopy (SEM-EDS). The output gases were analyzed using mass spectrometry (MS). In addition, a thermodynamic analysis was performed to predict the development of thermodynamically stable phases. An economic assessment (including capital expenditures (CAPEX) and operating expenditures (OPEX)) and a carbon balance were developed with the feasibility of the piloting in mind.</description>
      <author>Mohammed El Khalloufi, Gervais Soucy, Jonathan Lapointe, Marcel Paquet</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/min14050502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-Doped Cellulose-Based Porous Carbon for Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04696-w</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Zhou, Peking Xia, Yifan Tan, Shuning Xiao, Yuhua Xue, Jing Li, Guangzhi Yang, Catalysis letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396736041

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Zhou, Peking Xia, Yifan Tan, Shuning Xiao, Yuhua Xue, Jing Li, Guangzhi Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04696-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Dynamic Structure and Bond Evolutions in BiOIO3 Photocatalysts during CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407736</link>
      <description>Yujie Lan, Yajun Zhang, Xiaojuan Huang, Yingpu Bi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396868758

                We have established a correlation between photocatalytic activity and dynamic structure/bond evolutions of BiOIO3&#8208;based photocatalysts during CO2 reduction by combining operando X&#8208;ray diffraction with photoelectron spectroscopy. More specifically, the selective photo&#8208;deposition of PtOx species on BiOIO3 (010) facets could effectively promote the electron enrichment on Bi active sites of (100) facets for facilitating the adsorption/activation of CO2 molecules, leading to the formation of Bi sites with high oxidation state and the shrink of crystalline structures. With introducing light irradiation to drive CO2 reduction, the Bi active sites with high oxidation states transformed into normal Bi3+ state, accompanying with the expansion of crystalline structures. Owing to the dynamic structure, bond, and chemical&#8208;state evolutions, a significant improvement of photocatalytic activity for CO evolution has been achieved on PtOx&#8208;BiOIO3 (195.0 &#956;mol g&#8208;1&#8226;h&#8208;1), much higher than the pristine (61.9 &#956;mol g&#8208;1&#8226;h&#8208;1) as well as metal&#8208;Pt decorated BiOIO3 (70.3 &#956;mol g&#8208;1&#8226;h&#8208;1) samples. This work provides new insights to correlate the intrinsically dynamic structure/bond evolutions with CO2 reduction activity, which may help to guide future photocatalyst design.</description>
      <author>Yujie Lan, Yajun Zhang, Xiaojuan Huang, Yingpu Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Dynamic Structure and Bond Evolutions in BiOIO3 Photocatalysts during CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407736</link>
      <description>Yujie Lan, Yajun Zhang, Xiaojuan Huang, Yingpu Bi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396869494

                We have established a correlation between photocatalytic activity and dynamic structure/bond evolutions of BiOIO3&#8208;based photocatalysts during CO2 reduction by combining operando X&#8208;ray diffraction with photoelectron spectroscopy. More specifically, the selective photo&#8208;deposition of PtOx species on BiOIO3 (010) facets could effectively promote the electron enrichment on Bi active sites of (100) facets for facilitating the adsorption/activation of CO2 molecules, leading to the formation of Bi sites with high oxidation state and the shrink of crystalline structures. With introducing light irradiation to drive CO2 reduction, the Bi active sites with high oxidation states transformed into normal Bi3+ state, accompanying with the expansion of crystalline structures. Owing to the dynamic structure, bond, and chemical&#8208;state evolutions, a significant improvement of photocatalytic activity for CO evolution has been achieved on PtOx&#8208;BiOIO3 (195.0 &#956;mol g&#8208;1&#8226;h&#8208;1), much higher than the pristine (61.9 &#956;mol g&#8208;1&#8226;h&#8208;1) as well as metal&#8208;Pt decorated BiOIO3 (70.3 &#956;mol g&#8208;1&#8226;h&#8208;1) samples. This work provides new insights to correlate the intrinsically dynamic structure/bond evolutions with CO2 reduction activity, which may help to guide future photocatalyst design.</description>
      <author>Yujie Lan, Yajun Zhang, Xiaojuan Huang, Yingpu Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice-dislocated bismuth nanowires formed by in-situ chemical etching on copper foam for enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127926</link>
      <description>Shuangchen Ma, Kai Wu, Shuaijun Fan, Pengwei Yang, Liutong Chen, Jing Ma, Lijuan Yang, Hongtao Zhu, Xiaoying Ma, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396829791

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to HCOOH is one of the most feasible and economical methods to achieve carbon neutrality. Bismuth (Bi), as a metal catalyst for CO2RR, is considered to have great potential for application and has been widely studied due to its high formate selectivity, low toxicity, cheapness, and abundance. Unfortunately, low current density and short electrode lifetime have hindered its progress towards practical applications. In this work, we present a method that enables the chemical etching of Bi on Cu, which is capable of spontaneously accomplishing the loading of Bi on Cu foam in the liquid phase at room temperature. Additionally, to provide more abundant catalytically active sites, twisted Bi nanowires (BiNWs) with lattice dislocations were successfully prepared on the surface of Cu foam using a three-step chemical method involving oxidation, reduction, and in-situ etching. The Cu Foam@BiNWs was found to be a highly active electrocatalyst for CO2 reduction to formate at a low applied potential, achieving a faradaic efficiency for formate (FEFormate) of 95 % and a formate partial current density of &#8764; 12 mA cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;0.78 V vs. RHE (reversible hydrogen electrode). Even within such a wide potential window of &#8722;0.68 &#8764; -1.08 V vs. RHE, the FEFormate is consistently above 90 %. Such exceptional CO2 reduction activity can be attributed to the distortions and lattice dislocations present in the surface BiNWs. Furthermore, the Cu Foam@BiNWs electrode demonstrated a total current density close to 100 mA cm&#8722;2 at &#8722;0.98 V in an alkaline flow cell, while maintaining excellent catalytic stability over a prolonged 30-hour period of high current density electrochemical activity, thus showing potential for advancing the industrialisation of formate production. This work emphasizes the crucial role of size-dependent catalysis and crystal defect engineering strategies in the field of electrocatalysis, elucidates the mechanism of the rate-determining step (RDS) in the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction process on the developed catalysts, which can provide valuable insights into the design and development of high performance electrocatalysts not only in CO2RR but also in other fields.</description>
      <author>Shuangchen Ma, Kai Wu, Shuaijun Fan, Pengwei Yang, Liutong Chen, Jing Ma, Lijuan Yang, Hongtao Zhu, Xiaoying Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotional effects of In(PO3)3 on the high catalytic activity of CuOIn(PO3)3/C for CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00645c</link>
      <description>Chao Ruan, Zhongwei Zhao, Hui Wang, Jiaqian Liu, Yifeng Shi, Zeng Ling, Zhongshui Li, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857540

                The construction of Cu-In bi-component catalysts is an effective strategy to enhance the electrocatalytic properties towards CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). However, realizing the co-promotion of In and heteroatom P on...</description>
      <author>Chao Ruan, Zhongwei Zhao, Hui Wang, Jiaqian Liu, Yifeng Shi, Zeng Ling, Zhongshui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00645c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical research on efficient electrocatalysis of CO2 reduction reaction by borophene loaded transition metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104454</link>
      <description>Meiling Liu, Rao Fu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meiling Liu, Rao Fu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation on the promotional role of Ag for reverse water-gas shift reaction on Ni catalysts during CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.088</link>
      <description>Jia Wang, Tiesen Liu, Jinyu Han, Hua Wang, Xinli Zhu, Qingfeng Ge, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830415

                Catalytic reduction of CO2 to CO via reverse water-gas shift reaction on Ni-based catalysts is challenging due to the competing methanation reaction. In this work, the reduction of CO2 toward CO and CH4 has been studied by density functional theory calculation and microkinetic simulations on Ni(211) and Ag@Ni(211) surfaces. On both surfaces, direct CO2 dissociation is more favorable over formate and carboxyl pathways toward CO, and direct CO dissociation is the major pathway toward CH4. The presence of Ag shifts the d-band center of adjacent Ni atoms away from the Fermi level, resulting in reduced affinity to CO2/CO/intermediates and slightly increased barriers for most elementary steps. In particular, the apparent barrier for direct CO2 dissociation is slightly reduced by &#8764;0.1 eV while direct CO dissociation is strongly inhibited by &#8764;0.3 eV along the reaction coordinate, leading to CO as the predominant product on Ag@Ni(211), which agrees well with the experimental results.</description>
      <author>Jia Wang, Tiesen Liu, Jinyu Han, Hua Wang, Xinli Zhu, Qingfeng Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the d-band center of Cu nanoparticles for efficient photo-driven catalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124167</link>
      <description>Libo Wang, Shumin Zhang, Yang Michael Yang, Jiaguo Yu, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396732638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Libo Wang, Shumin Zhang, Yang Michael Yang, Jiaguo Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-utilization of Wastewater Sludge and Heavy Metals for Single-Atom Electrocatalytic Reduction of Gaseous CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2024.109956</link>
      <description>Baiqin Zhou, Zhida Li, Xinyue He, Chunyue Zhang, Shanshan Pi, Min Yang, Shiguo Zhang, Guifeng Li, Ziqi Zhang, Lu Lu, iScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789080

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baiqin Zhou, Zhida Li, Xinyue He, Chunyue Zhang, Shanshan Pi, Min Yang, Shiguo Zhang, Guifeng Li, Ziqi Zhang, Lu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2024.109956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isostructural phase transition-induced piezoelectricity in all-inorganic perovskite CsPbBr3 for catalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124186</link>
      <description>Jie He, Xuandong Wang, Pengju Feng, Yingtang Zhou, Kai Wang, Bo Zou, Mingshan Zhu, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396794026

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie He, Xuandong Wang, Pengju Feng, Yingtang Zhou, Kai Wang, Bo Zou, Mingshan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the Nitrogen/Carbon Ratio in the Organic Ligand of a Nickel Single-Atom Catalyst on its Electrochemical Activity in CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124192</link>
      <description>Hyeonuk Choi, Min Gwan Ha, Jungsoo Suh, Chulwan Lim, Beomil Kim, Shun Wang, Jang Yong Lee, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Jihun Oh, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835243

                Simple, large-scale synthesis of metal single-atom catalysts (SACs) is limited by the aggregation of metal atoms on the support material surface. The N atoms in small organic ligands (SOLs) can anchor single metal atoms, affording abundant surface-active sites. In this study, we investigated the effect of the nitrogen/carbon ratio (N/C) in SOLs on the properties of the resultant Ni single-atom confined nitrogen-doped carbon black (Ni-NCB). The N/C ratio affected the thermal stability of Ni-NCB_N/Cs during carbonization, and the optimal Ni-NCB (Ni-NCB_0.5) was synthesized with the SOL 2-methylimidazole. Ni-NCB_0.5 achieved a CO partial current density of &gt; 500 mA cm&#8211;2 and high CO Faradaic efficiency (96.4%) in the CO2 reduction reaction. The 3- and 4-cell stack systems with Ni-NCB_0.5 (25 cm2 area per unit cell) exhibited an overall current of 10 A, high CO selectivity (&gt; 96.0%), and long-term stability (50 h). This synthetic strategy for SACs can be commercialized and even extended to other industrial electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hyeonuk Choi, Min Gwan Ha, Jungsoo Suh, Chulwan Lim, Beomil Kim, Shun Wang, Jang Yong Lee, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Jihun Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the First Activation Step of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction over Ag and Ni-N-C Active Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109728</link>
      <description>Yujie Wang, Jungho Kim, Hyun Dong Jung, Jun Liu, Ke Yao, Chuan Xia, Seoin Back, Kun Jiang, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396846502

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Wang, Jungho Kim, Hyun Dong Jung, Jun Liu, Ke Yao, Chuan Xia, Seoin Back, Kun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measurement of interfacial charge transfer rate during visible light CO2 reduction under bias voltage conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141330</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Wang, Qiang Chen, Zhu Lei, Jingying Jia, Kun Jia, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396856765

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Wang, Qiang Chen, Zhu Lei, Jingying Jia, Kun Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Linear Correlation of p-Band Center with the Performance of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Revealed by Sn Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124160</link>
      <description>Jiangyi Guo, Fengshou Yu, Yang You, Jiayu Zhan, Luhua Zhang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396732235

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiangyi Guo, Fengshou Yu, Yang You, Jiayu Zhan, Luhua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Oxygen Reduction Reaction Active and CO2 Durable High-entropy Cathode for Solid Oxide Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124175</link>
      <description>Fan He, Feng Zhu, Kang Xu, Yangsen Xu, Dongliang Li, Guangming Yang, Kotaro Sasaki, YongMan Choi, Yu Chen, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396794246

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fan He, Feng Zhu, Kang Xu, Yangsen Xu, Dongliang Li, Guangming Yang, Kotaro Sasaki, YongMan Choi, Yu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-Free, Light Assisted Integrated Co2 Reduction Coupled with Selective Oxidation of Alcohols Under Visible Light Irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821831</link>
      <description>Suman L. Jain, Nitish Saini, Anil Malik, B. Moses Abraham, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396754557

                An integrated CO2 photoreduction to CO by photo-induced electrons coupled with selective oxidation of aromatic alcohols to carbonyl compounds by photo-generated holes using metal-free anthraquinone (AQ) as an organo-photocatalyst under visible illumination is described. The maximum conversion of benzyl alcohol to benzaldehyde was 65.4% with a selectivity of 98%, accompanied with the CO yield in gaseous phase 8.67 &#956;mol h-1 g-1. DFT calculations indicate that initial binding of benzyl alcohol with AQ forms an intermediate IM1 that subsequently interacts with CO2 to give CO2 anion with a free energy change of 0.24 eV. Further, the reduction of CO2 to CO coupled with the oxidation of benzyl alcohol to benzaldehyde and the release of a water molecule. This concerted metal-free photocatalytic system efficiently offers the combined use of electron-hole pairs for integrated organic synthesis coupled with the CO2 conversion in a cost-effective and sustainable manner.</description>
      <author>Suman L. Jain, Nitish Saini, Anil Malik, B. Moses Abraham</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction through constructing chemically homogeneous interfaces via ultrathin carbon encapsulated tin oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109729</link>
      <description>Zongdeng Wu, Di Yao, Peng Zhao, Haiyan Jing, Keren Lu, Boyuan Liu, Xifeng Xia, Wu Lei, Qingli Hao, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396845478

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongdeng Wu, Di Yao, Peng Zhao, Haiyan Jing, Keren Lu, Boyuan Liu, Xifeng Xia, Wu Lei, Qingli Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biological S0 reduction at neutral (pH 6.9) and acidic (pH 3.8) conditions: Performance and microbial community shifts in a H2/CO2-fed bioreactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.11.592705</link>
      <description>Adrian Hidalgo-Ulloa, Charlotte van der Graaf, Jan Weijma, Irene S&#225;nchez&#8208;Andrea, Cees J.N. Buisman, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396868401

                Sulfidogenesis is a promising technology for the selective recovery of chalcophile bulk metals (e.g. Cu, Zn, and Co) from metal-contaminated waters such as acid mine drainage (AMD) and metallurgy waste streams. The use of elemental sulfur (S0) instead of sulfate (SO42-) as electron acceptor reduces electron donor requirements four-fold, lowering process costs, and expands the range of operating conditions to more acidic pH. We previously reported autotrophic S0 reduction using an industrial mesophilic granular sludge as inoculum under thermoacidophilic conditions. Here, we examined the effect of pH on the S0 reduction performance of the same inoculum, in a continuously fed gas-lift reactor run at 30 C under neutral (pH 6.9) and acidic (pH 3.8) conditions. Steady-state volumetric sulfide production rates (VSPR) dropped 2.3-fold upon transition to acidic pH, from 1.79 g L-1 d-1 S2- to 0.71 g L-1 d-1 S2- Microbial community analysis via 16S rRNA gene amplicon sequencing showed that at pH 6.9, the S0-reducing genera Sulfurospirillum, Sulfurovum, Desulfurella, and Desulfovibrio were present at the highest relative abundance, while at pH 3.9 Desulfurella dominated the sequenced reads. The detection of acetic acid and the relative abundance of Acetobacterium at pH 6.9 pointed towards acetogenesis, explaining the dominance of the heterotrophic genus Sulfurospirillum in this H2 and CO2-fed bioreactor.</description>
      <author>Adrian Hidalgo-Ulloa, Charlotte van der Graaf, Jan Weijma, Irene S&#225;nchez&#8208;Andrea, Cees J.N. Buisman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.11.592705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase transfer-assisted indium recovery from spent liquid crystal display panels and its extension in preparing indium-based electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152119</link>
      <description>Yufeng Wu, Zhiyuan Ren, Hui Liu, Feng Guo, Shaonan Tian, Junzhong Yang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396790704

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yufeng Wu, Zhiyuan Ren, Hui Liu, Feng Guo, Shaonan Tian, Junzhong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Electrocatalytic Potential of In-situ Exsolution of Ni Nanoparticles on Lanthanum Calcium Co-doped Strontium Titanate for CO2 Reduction in Solid Oxide Electrolysis Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174831</link>
      <description>Neetu Kumari, Pankaj Tiwari, Suddhasatwa Basu, Neetu Kumari, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396854343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Neetu Kumari, Pankaj Tiwari, Suddhasatwa Basu, Neetu Kumari</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aqueous CO2 Sequestration for Low-Carbon Ready-Mix Concrete</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13164/juniorstav.2024.24136</link>
      <description>Jamie Chong Yujie, Guan Feng Chua, Mingshan Zhao, C.W.Y. Yip, Saradhi Babu Daneti, Fei Jin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396816664

                The cement industry accounts for 8% of global energy- and process-related greenhouse gas emissions. To achieve global net-zero emission targets by 2050, the need for commercially ready low-carbon construction materials is becoming increasingly urgent. The fixation of captured carbon dioxide in concrete through CO&#8322; sequestration is a crucial area of study to reduce concrete embodied carbon. This paper discusses the development of a low-carbon ready-mix concrete (RMC) with aqueous CO2 sequestration, and the synergy between carbon dioxide and other constituent materials. The effectiveness of this approach was evaluated through mineralogical composition analysis using TGA, and the mechanical and rheological properties of various concrete mixes were studied. Aqueous CO2 sequestration using carbonated mixing water can stably fix up to 0.84% of CO2 by weight of cement within the cement matrix as CaCO3. The poor workability and incompatibility with GGBS that results from this approach were addressed by the inclusion of RCA as an external source of alkalinity and lubrication. This mix of low-carbon RMC has similar strength and rheological properties to conventional RMC and achieved an embodied carbon reduction of approximately 47%.</description>
      <author>Jamie Chong Yujie, Guan Feng Chua, Mingshan Zhao, C.W.Y. Yip, Saradhi Babu Daneti, Fei Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.13164/juniorstav.2024.24136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of european trends regarding the reduction of air pollutants in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32347/2411-4049.2024.1.5-16</link>
      <description>Stepan Shapoval, Stepan Mysak, M.Ya. Kuznetsova, Ekolog&#236;&#269;na bezpeka ta prirodokoristuvann&#226;/Ekolog&#236;&#269;na bezpeka &#236; prirodokoristuvann&#226;. 49(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396858683

                The paper analyses European trends in reducing emissions of harmful substances and carbon dioxide. Today, the problem of increasing CO2 is an acute one, and thus the task of decarbonising the planet is an important task for the global community. Along with this, the negative impact of other pollutants, such as NOx and SO2, on the environmental situation in Ukraine and the world as a whole is also important.In order to reduce the amount of polluting gases in the air of Ukraine, it was decided to turn to the experience and practice of the European Union (EU) countries and analyse what has already been done, as well as what is planned to be done in this direction in the coming decades. To this end, we analysed the actual data on the reduction of CO2, NOx, and SO2 emissions by European countries and compared their plans for further emission reductions in the coming years.The theoretical data of the study on the actual reduction of air pollutant and carbon dioxide emissions by European countries, as well as their plans for further reduction of these emissions, are of practical importance, as they show global trends in this problem of global importance and should be applied in all future energy plans both in Ukraine and other countries where this is not taken into account. Therefore, an effective and scientifically based plan for energy saving, clean energy production, and diversification of energy resources is needed to accelerate the transition to clean energy, increase energy independence from unreliable suppliers and unstable supplies of imported fossil fuels (in particular, accelerated phase-out of russian fossil fuels by 2030, which are used by the aggressor as an economic and political weapon), and help solve the climate crisis.</description>
      <author>Stepan Shapoval, Stepan Mysak, M.Ya. Kuznetsova</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32347/2411-4049.2024.1.5-16</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved burnt clay brick masonry: lowering upfront embodied carbon, improving thermal comfort and climate resilience of new housing in the Indo-Gangetic Plains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62744/cate.45273.1190-452-461</link>
      <description>Sameer Maithel, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396796120

                The urban residential building footprint is expected to increase four-fold during 2020-2050 in the Indo-Gangetic Plains region of India. The business-as-usual construction technology of RCC frame with solid burnt clay brick as the walling material use large quantities of steel, concrete and solid brick and is highly resource and carbon intensive. The region produces 110-140 billion solid burnt clay bricks per year. Brick production is associated with large energy consumption, carbon dioxide emission, air pollution and degradation of agricultural land. The study presents an innovative new burnt clay product &#8211; vertically cored interlocking burnt clay block that is being manufactured by a brick manufacturer in the region. The study presents the results of the life cycle analysis (as per EN 15804) and quantifies reductions in carbon and resource consumption for the product and the building element (wall). The analysis is based on the data collected from the industry. The cradle to gate analysis shows a reduction of 31% in the CO2 emissions (kgCO2/m3 of burnt product) and 58% in soil consumption (m3 of soil/m3 of burnt product) for the vertically cored hollow block. A 150 mm thick wall made of vertically cored hollow block results in 55% reduction in the CO2 emissions (kgCO2/m2 of wall) when compared to a 230 mm thick wall of solid brick. In addition, the cement consumption in mortar reduces by 66% and sand consumption by 62% per m2 of wall area. The study further indicates a significant reduction in concrete and steel consumption by extending the analysis to the building level.</description>
      <author>Sameer Maithel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62744/cate.45273.1190-452-461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrided Copper-Iron Composite Oxides Derived from Layered Double Hydroxides for Enhanced Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction to Methane and Formic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59400/esc.v2i2.369</link>
      <description>Dandan Song, Jinqing He, Yiping Wang, Xuhui Zhao, Fazhi Zhang, Xiaodong Lei, Deleted Journal. 2(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396747748

                The reduction of carbon dioxide to valuable chemical products is a promising solution to address carbon balance and energy issues. Herein, amorphous nitrided copper-iron oxides are prepared by gas-phase nitriding of CuFe-layered double hydroxide precursors with urea as nitrogen source. Amorphous materials are more likely to generate defect vacancies during the reaction process, and these vacancies can function as active sites for catalytic reactions. Therefore, the obtained materials show high activity for CO2 electroreduction to methane and formic acid, achieving a total Faraday efficiency of 74.7% at &#8722;0.7 V vs RHE and exhibiting a continuous 10 h durability in the H-cell. The uniformly distributed Cu+ sites act as active sites by losing electrons to activate CO2. During the CO2 electroreduction, CO2 is converted to *COOH via proton-electron coupling, *COOH combines directly with a proton in solution to produce the HCOOH product, and the other part of *COOH undergoes a protonated dehydration process to form the *CHO intermediate which dehydrates again to form CH4. This study provides a new approach for designing CO2 electroreduction catalysts.</description>
      <author>Dandan Song, Jinqing He, Yiping Wang, Xuhui Zhao, Fazhi Zhang, Xiaodong Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59400/esc.v2i2.369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Residual emissions and carbon removal towards Japan&#8217;s net-zero goal: A multi-model analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7620/ad4af2</link>
      <description>Masahiro Sugiyama, Shinichiro Fujimori, Kazumi Wada, Etsushi Kato, Yuhji Matsuo, Osamu Nishiura, Ken Oshiro, Tetsuo Otsuki, Environmental research communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396873247

                Abstract We study Japan&#8217;s net-zero emissions target by 2050 in a multi-model framework, focusing on residual emissions and carbon dioxide removal (CDR). Four energy-economic and integrated assessment models show similar but stronger strategies for the net-zero target, compared to the previous, low-carbon policy target (80% emissions reduction). Results indicate that around 90% (inter-model median) of the current emissions are reduced through abatement, including improved energy efficiency and cleaner electricity and fuels. Models deploy new options such as CDR based on carbon capture and storage (CCS) (bioenergy with CCS and direct air carbon dioxide capture and storage) and hydrogen to achieve net zero. The scale of CCS-based CDR deployment reaches an inter-model median of 132Mt-CO2/yr. The median hydrogen share of final energy in 2050 increases from 0.79% to 6.9% between the low-carbon and net-zero scenarios. The CDR sensitivity analysis reveals that limiting the use of CDR significantly increases the mitigation costs for net zero. Achieving Japan&#8217;s net-zero goal will require exploring methods to reduce residual emissions, including demand-side solutions, and accelerating responsible CDR policies.</description>
      <author>Masahiro Sugiyama, Shinichiro Fujimori, Kazumi Wada, Etsushi Kato, Yuhji Matsuo, Osamu Nishiura, Ken Oshiro, Tetsuo Otsuki</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7620/ad4af2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Approach to Carbon Dioxide Emission Analysis in High
  Human Development Index Countries using Statistical and Machine Learning
  Techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.02340</link>
      <description>Hamed Khosravi, Ahmed Shoyeb Raihan, Farzana Islam, Ashish D. Nimbarte, Imtiaz Ahmed, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396786925

                Reducing Carbon dioxide (CO2) emission is vital at both global and national levels, given their significant role in exacerbating climate change. CO2 emission, stemming from a variety of industrial and economic activities, are major contributors to the greenhouse effect and global warming, posing substantial obstacles in addressing climate issues. It's imperative to forecast CO2 emission trends and classify countries based on their emission patterns to effectively mitigate worldwide carbon emission. This paper presents an in-depth comparative study on the determinants of CO2 emission in twenty countries with high Human Development Index (HDI), exploring factors related to economy, environment, energy use, and renewable resources over a span of 25 years. The study unfolds in two distinct phases: initially, statistical techniques such as Ordinary Least Squares (OLS), fixed effects, and random effects models are applied to pinpoint significant determinants of CO2 emission. Following this, the study leverages supervised and unsupervised machine learning (ML) methods to further scrutinize and understand the factors influencing CO2 emission. Seasonal AutoRegressive Integrated Moving Average with eXogenous variables (SARIMAX), a supervised ML model, is first used to predict emission trends from historical data, offering practical insights for policy formulation. Subsequently, Dynamic Time Warping (DTW), an unsupervised learning approach, is used to group countries by similar emission patterns. The dual-phase approach utilized in this study significantly improves the accuracy of CO2 emission predictions while also providing a deeper insight into global emission trends. By adopting this thorough analytical framework, nations can develop more focused and effective carbon reduction policies, playing a vital role in the global initiative to combat climate change.</description>
      <author>Hamed Khosravi, Ahmed Shoyeb Raihan, Farzana Islam, Ashish D. Nimbarte, Imtiaz Ahmed</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.02340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in tandem electrocatalysis of carbon dioxide: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114516</link>
      <description>Jiateng Chen, Liang Xu, Boxiong Shen, Renewable &amp; sustainable energy reviews. 199(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396785483

                The attainment of carbon neutrality has become a global consensus as a result of the increasing environmental problems caused by the consumption of fossil fuels. To achieve this objective, there has been widespread attention towards the electrocatalytic reduction reaction of carbon dioxide driven by renewable energy sources due to its mild reaction conditions. In recent years, generating high value-added multicarbon products has been the focus of considerable research efforts. However, the process of generating these products has been restricted by the complexity of the reaction path, the limitations of the scaling relationship, and the poor adaptability to the reaction environment, thereby impeding previous studies from achieving efficient conversion at high current densities. As a result, a more suitable catalyst design strategy is required to obtain high value-added products. This study proposes that the design approach of tandem catalysis will be effective in generating multicarbon products by exploring the mechanism of C&#8211;C bond coupling and the configuration of the reaction environment. This research summaries the mechanism and design requirements of tandem catalysis scaled by different intermediates transport distances and review strategies of tandem catalyst configurations, such as nanostructures, phase-mixed, phase-separated, and application of special supports, in facilitating the generation of multicarbon products. The study provides suggestions for the design of CO2 electrocatalytic tandem catalysts and conclude with a discussion of possible future directions.</description>
      <author>Jiateng Chen, Liang Xu, Boxiong Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Analysis of Eight Renewable Energy-Driven Urea-Electricity-Heat-Cooling Multi-Generation Systems: Energy, Exergy, Economic, and Environmental Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823041</link>
      <description>Mou Wu, Rujing Yan, Jing Zhang, Fan Junqiu, Jiangjiang Wang, Zhongke Bai, Lulu Ren, Siyun Zhou, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396783182

                The Haber-Bosch process and chemical looping ammonia generation (CLAG) are the two main pathways for ammonia synthesis in urea production. However, the technical and economic potential of these two methods requires further investigation. This paper establishes and evaluates eight urea-electricity-heat-cooling multi-generation systems driven by renewable energies. This includes two ammonia production processes based on the Haber-Bosch process and the CLAG, two hydrogen production processes based on proton exchange membrane electrolysis and solid oxide electrolysis, and three nitrogen separation processes based on solid oxide fuel cell, pressure swing adsorption, and reduction reactor. For each system, energy, exergy, economic, and environmental evaluation models are developed. Considering the fluctuation in renewable energy resources, an annual evaluation of the different systems is conducted based on a monthly time scale. Also, the effects of purifying excess carbon dioxide for storage on the evaluation indicators are analyzed and assessed. The results showed that the average energy and exergy efficiencies for the Haber-Bosch process are in the ranges of 60-80% and 40-50%, respectively. For the CLAG, the respective efficiencies are 50-70% and 30-40%. Additionally, the multi-generation system combining the Haber-Bosch reaction, reduction reactor, and SOFC yielded the highest energy and exergy efficiency among the eight systems, at 68.2% and 45.78%, respectively. On the other hand, the multi-generation system integrating CLAG, SOFC, and biomass gasification has the shortest discounted payback period of 8 years, with annual revenue and net present value of 32.63 and 6.60 MUSD, respectively. While the operating expenditures of the Haber-Bosch process (12.6-16.6 MUSD) are lower than those of the CLAG process (13.9-17.5 MUSD), its capital expenditures (398.9-433.2 MUSD) are significantly higher than those of the CLAG process (315.9-321.4 MUSD). Also, the conducted environmental assessment highlighted that the multi-generation system integrating the CLAG, reduction reactor, and biomass gasification processes exhibited the lowest overall carbon emissions (0.013 t CO2/t urea) among the investigated systems.</description>
      <author>Mou Wu, Rujing Yan, Jing Zhang, Fan Junqiu, Jiangjiang Wang, Zhongke Bai, Lulu Ren, Siyun Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene Oxide Nanocellulose Composite as a Highly Efficient Substrate-free Room Temperature Gas Sensor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102228</link>
      <description>Manel Azlouk, Mohamed A. Basyooni, Yasin Ramazan Eker, Erhan Zor, Haluk Bing&#246;l, Results in engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396781038

                This study introduces the development of novel, flexible gas sensors operating at room temperature (RT), utilizing a graphene oxide (GO) via the modified Hummers method and bacterial nanocellulose (BNC) composite to enhance gas detection in industrial and environmental settings. The composite materials, denoted as GO@BNC, were synthesized with varying GO concentrations ranging from 2 % to 30 %, aiming to investigate their responsiveness to gases such as carbon dioxide (CO2), oxygen (O2), acetone (Ac), and ethanol (Eth). The prepared nanomaterials were characterized using FT-IR, Raman, TGA, SEM, and AFM techniques. The bandgap of Go ranges from 4.19, 3.47, 3.16, 2.79, and 2.48 eV for 2, 5, 10, 20, and 30 % GO concentrations, respectively. Notably, the sensor containing wt % of 20 % GO concentration exhibited remarkable sensitivity to Ac, achieving a 270 % increase in resistance at a concentration of 250 &#956;L/L. Conversely, the sensor with a wt % of 30% GO composition showed superior sensitivity to Eth, with a 420% signal enhancement under similar conditions. Further modification of GO@BNC through mild reduction resulted in the formation of reduced graphene oxide (rGO@BNC) composites intended to assess the functional groups' impact on sensing performance. Our findings underscore the potential of GO@BNC composites as sustainable and efficient materials for fabricating eco-friendly flexible gas sensors and devices for detecting organic compounds.</description>
      <author>Manel Azlouk, Mohamed A. Basyooni, Yasin Ramazan Eker, Erhan Zor, Haluk Bing&#246;l</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Path to pollution and carbon reduction synergy from the perspective of the digital economy: Fresh evidence from 292 prefecture-level cities in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.119050</link>
      <description>Liang Chenlu, Xiaolong Chen, Di Qin, Environmental research. 252(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721660

                The digital economy is a crucial focus for realizing the transformation of old and new kinetic energy in China. It is widely integrated with various fields of the economy and society, constantly providing a new dynamic mechanism with synergetic control of environmental pollution and carbon emissions (SCEPCE). Based on panel data from 292 prefecture-level cities in China from 2011 to 2021, this study discusses the spatial effects and mechanisms of the digital economy on the coordinated control of pollutants and carbon emissions. The study found that: (1) The digital economy has direct and indirect influences on the coordinated control of pollutants and carbon emissions. The digital economy can drive reductions in pollutants and carbon dioxide emissions by upgrading industrial structures and transforming energy structures. (2) Green innovation plays an active regulatory role in the digital economy and structural optimization, particularly in the context of SCEPCE. This interference helps mitigate the impact of the digital economy on pollution and carbon emissions. (3) The digital economy has a significant spatial spillover effect on the coordinated control of pollutants and carbon emissions. (4) The influence mechanism of the digital economy on pollution reduction and carbon reduction synergy exhibits geographical heterogeneity, resource endowment heterogeneity. To enhance the synergy of pollution reduction and carbon reduction, it is essential to bolster support and optimise the digital economy at various levels. This includes reinforcing regional balance, considering spatial spillover effects, and enhancing the leading role of developed cities in the region.</description>
      <author>Liang Chenlu, Xiaolong Chen, Di Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.119050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of climate change and technological innovation on economic recovery in sub-Saharan Africa: A machine learning perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4245184/v1</link>
      <description>Mwoya Byaro, Anicet Rwezaula, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396867173

                Abstract The COVID-19 pandemic has led to a global economy slowdown. Sub-Saharan Africa&#8217;s (SSA) economy is gradually recovering from the pandemic. This study examines whether climate change variables (such as temperature, carbon dioxide emissions) and technological innovation (measured by total patent applications) can forecast the economic recovery of 19 selected countries in SSA from 2000 to 2022. We applied Kernel-based Regularized Least Squares (KRLS), a machine learning technique, while controlling for financial development, human capital and inflation rates. Our findings indicate that climate change exerts a negative and significant influence on SSA's economic recovery. Specifically, rise in average annual surface temperature change and carbon dioxide emissions decrease in economic recovery. An increase in average technological innovation improves in economic recovery. Inflation rate is associated with reduction in economic recovery. We discuss policy implications and mechanisms through which technological innovation and climate change affect the SSA economy, offering practical policy suggestions.</description>
      <author>Mwoya Byaro, Anicet Rwezaula</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4245184/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water, energy and environment nexus: Quantitative assessment for integrated power plants with renewable energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esr.2024.101410</link>
      <description>Rahim Zahedi, Hossein Yousefi, Alireza Aslani, Rouhollah Ahmadi, Energy strategy reviews. 53(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396812688

                The population increase and the demand for water and energy, accompanied by the implications of environment pollution for natural and human resources, indicate the critical necessity for a coherent movement towards nexus between water, energy, and environment. Due to the fact that power generation industry is responsible for a significant proportion of water and fuel consumption and Carbon dioxide emissions within the world, in this research, the application of the hybrid renewable system in a thermal power plant has been assessed based on the approach of analyzing the link between energy, water and environment. The design of the solar system and the assessment of carbon balance during the power plant lifetime have been conducted in PVsyst application in 2022. Moreover, ReCipe environmental model has been used for assessing the effect of decrease in carbon emission on the ecosystem. The findings of the research indicate that the replacement of at least 2 % of the nominal capacity of the fossil fuel power plant with the renewable one, prevents the emission of 1431.28 tons of carbon dioxide yearly. This amount equals to 380.34 cubic meters of reserve in fossil fuel consumption and 391.73 tons of crude oil. The results also showed that in addition to preserving natural resources, the hybrid cycle design leads to significant water demand reduction which equals to 3842 cubic meters with the capacity to supply underground water sources. Due to the interests of preserving water and energy resources and decreasing carbon emission in power plant industry, within the framework of nexus approach, management of energy supply by replacing resources and using water and heat recovery technologies and application of energy demand management policies based on energy efficiency and environmental implications is recommended.</description>
      <author>Rahim Zahedi, Hossein Yousefi, Alireza Aslani, Rouhollah Ahmadi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esr.2024.101410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Power-Grid-Load-Storage Integration Based on Electricity-Carbon-Gas Cycle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ei259745.2023.10512800</link>
      <description>Chang Liu, Xiangyu Lv, Yongli Wang, Xinyang Cao, Zeliang Yang, Siyan Zhan, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4396783916

                With the rapid development of urban economy and the construction of new towns, the problem of solid waste such as a large number of domestic garbage, sludge and agricultural and forestry waste has become increasingly prominent. In this context, it is particularly urgent to design an integrated scheme of source, grid, load and storage including electricity-carbon-gas cycle. In this paper, a collaborative utilization framework of waste-to-energy system, carbon capture equipment and power-to-gas technology is constructed to form an electricity-carbon-gas cycle. Among them, carbon capture equipment captures carbon dioxide produced by waste power generation, which is used for power-to-gas technology to convert into natural gas, and the power consumption of power-to-gas equipment and flue gas treatment is jointly transferred through storage equipment to achieve peak shaving and valley filling of load and fluctuation of renewable energy output. A multi-strategy fusion honey badger algorithm is proposed to be applied to the research on source-network-load-storage integration, which effectively improves the solution efficiency and the stability of the results. The simulation results show that the scheme has significant advantages in economy, carbon emission and energy efficiency, which provides guidance for the utilization of biomass waste resources and electricity-carbon-gas cycle in the region, and promotes the improvement of regional carbon emission reduction and energy efficiency.</description>
      <author>Chang Liu, Xiangyu Lv, Yongli Wang, Xinyang Cao, Zeliang Yang, Siyan Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1109/ei259745.2023.10512800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The elephant in the conference room: reducing the carbon footprint of aquatic science meetings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/lol2.10402</link>
      <description>Marie&#8208;Elodie Perga, Thorsten Dittmar, Damien Bouffard, Emma S. Kritzberg, Limnology and oceanography letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831364

                The unsustainability of conferences, whose carbon footprint is mostly made of air travel, has remained an academic taboo, even more so that virtual conferences, despite being carbon-efficient, have revealed their limitations. This concern bears an even greater significance for the Association for the Sciences of Limnology and Oceanography (ASLO), considering its emphasis on climate change-related issues. This essay seeks to raise awareness and stimulate action within the ASLO community, building upon well-established scientific approaches. We perform an estimation of the travel-related CO2 emissions of the aquatic science meetings (2004&#8211;2023), further used as a benchmark to explore alternatives to significantly reduce emissions while retaining physical attendance. Taking the leap toward such alternatives would make ASLO a role model of a genuinely sustainable and committed scientific society. The ASLO community is firmly committed to a sustainable future, and themes of the past conferences often infer a link between aquatic systems evolution and climate change. At the latest Aquatic Sciences Meeting (ASM) in 2023, climate change and carbon-centered topics were salient themes, making up to 50% of all contributions (Fig. 1). Many keynotes were remarked on for their willingness to engage toward actions and solutions and go beyond the sole report of dangers and threats posed by climate change and other overpassed planetary limits. Taking part in international scientific conferences such as ASM makes an integrated component of our academic life. Expectations from scientific conferences are to provide an opportunity to stay informed about the latest developments, disseminate one's own research, discuss perspectives and ideas, and get inspired. Scientific conferences also foster a sense of belonging to a community and offer a social context in which to expand research networks. In line with this, academic incentives and travel support are high and on the rise (Bojica et al. 2022). Yet, scientific conferencing also generates significant CO2 emissions at the Worldwide scale. Eighty percent of the carbon footprint of international conferences is made up of air travel, with a lower estimate of roughly 1 tCO2&#8722;e (metric tons of carbon dioxide equivalent, that is, the number of metric tons of CO2 emissions with the same global warming potential as one metric ton of another greenhouse gas) emitted per attendee for transportation (Klower et al. 2020; Tao et al. 2021). If half of the 8 million worldwide academics were to take part annually in an international conference (Sarabipour et al. 2021), transporting academics to international conferences would generate a back-of-the-envelope estimate of 4 MtCO2&#8722;e, rivaling with annual emissions of countries such as Niger, Nicaragua, or Latvia (Crippa et al. 2022). Meeting the Paris Agreement to contain warming to the 1.5&#176;C target requires that the emissions per capita fall down to 2.3 tCO2&#8722;e by 2030 (Gore 2021), while, due to their hypermobile lifestyle, the sole professional travel-related annual emissions for academics can easily reach 6 tCO2&#8722;e per capita (Ciers et al. 2019). The significance of the carbon footprint of scientific conferences has led individual academics and scientific societies to question the current model for conferencing (Malcolm 2008; Achten et al. 2013; Arsenault et al. 2019; Klower et al. 2020; Tao et al. 2021). Despite extending beyond our immediate community, this issue holds particular significance for us within the ASLO community, as we travel the World and generate such greenhouse emissions specifically to meet and devise climate-related matters and the resilience of aquatic systems. It is not the 1st time that the carbon footprint of ASLO conferences has been raised (Harazin 2020). However, we are unaware of any previous attempt to quantify the carbon footprint of ASM, although the exercise has already been undertaken for closely related scientific communities, such as the Ecological Society of America (Alexandra and Jarrett 2011) or the American Geophysical Union (Klower et al. 2020). We believe that this sizing exercise is important for two reasons. First, experience shows that even scholars working in scientific fields closely related to the issues of climate change tend to underestimate their own travel-related emissions (Whitmarsh et al. 2020; Passalacqua 2021). Second, quantifying the C-footprint of ASLO conferences is a required benchmark from which we can explore the efficiency of scenarios aimed at significantly reducing the carbon footprint of ASM while preserving its essence. Many ways are being evoked to engage in a more sustainable conferencing model (moving online or hybrid, optimizing location, setting meatless conditions; Leochico et al. 2021), in which actual efficiency in reducing emissions is rarely quantitatively assessed. Going 100% online appeared, at 1st sight, as the most straightforward way to run conferences for &lt;5% CO2&#8722;e emissions of traditional conferences (Klower et al. 2020; Tao et al. 2021). However, our past 3-yr virtual experience has shown that it largely undermines several of the benefits we expect from conferencing and face-to-face interactions (Brucks and Levav 2022). Is there then a way-out, by which we could significantly reduce the carbon footprint of conferences while escaping the ghost of going fully online? We estimated the travel-related CO2&#8722;e emissions of ASM from 2004 to 2023, from a computational approach similar to Klower et al.'s (2020) study. Based on anonymized attendees' data for each ASM, we computed the distances between the attendees' closest airport and the main airport of the conference venues. For a 1st assessment, we assumed that all attendees flew to the conference location and used a conservative estimate (only direct flights in economy class). Computed emissions (CO2&#8722;e) included greenhouse gases produced by fuel consumption, emissions associated with extracting, refining, and transporting fuels, and changes in radiative forcing due to water vapor emissions at higher altitudes (average emission factor of 163 gCO2&#8722;e km&#8722;1). In a 2nd step, we considered that attendees within 1000 km of the conference venue used landbound-based transportation (i.e., rail, coach, or shared car, considering an average emission factor of 30 gCO2&#8722;e km&#8722;1). All conversion factors were extracted from the greenhouse gas reporting of United Kingdom (Department for Energy Security and Net Zero and Department for Business 2022). We also assessed the CO2&#8722;e emissions saved by the ASM 2023 initiative of meatless catering, considering that a meat-based and a vegetarian meal corresponds respectively to 3.07 and 0.68 kgCO2&#8722;e per capita (Takacs et al. 2022). For methodological details and reproducibility of the essay, we refer to our GitHub (see Data availability statement). Total CO2&#8722;e emissions for a 1-week ASLO conference ranged between 0.5 and 4.5 ktCO2&#8722;e over the past 20 yr, with an average value of 2.1 ktCO2&#8722;e (Fig. 2a). 56% of travel-related emissions were due to long-haul flights (&gt;4000 km one way). The interannual variability of total emissions results from both the conference's location (Fig. 2b) and the attendance (Fig. 2c). Mean emissions per attendee were 1.3 tCO2&#8722;e, a number that is comparable with what had been estimated for international conferences of other scientific societies (Klower et al. 2020), but varied considerably depending on the venue. Islander venues generated a 53% increase of the emissions per attendee, with record emissions from conferences held in Honolulu. Finally, the delocalization of the conferences outside North America since 2006 has fulfilled the goal of ASLO to diversify the origin of attendees and increase attendance (Fig. 2c). ASM held in Europe were, on average, twice more attended than those in Northern America, and attendees from Europe or Asia preferentially attended ASM held on their own continents. As Hawaii meetings stand out in promoting the highest emission both per conference and per attendee, excluding outskirt, islander locations is an essential lever to cut-off travel-related C-emissions for ASM (Harazin 2020). However, mainland, central, well-connected locations still lead to per-capita emissions above 1 tCO2&#8722;e; that is, 46% of what we should emit within a full year by 2030. Rendering ASM sustainable will not be acquired by acting on conference location alone. Seen as an immediate lever to reduce the carbon footprint of academics, more and more universities from the North are encouraging attendees to buy carbon credits. However, we argue that relying on the purchase of carbon offsets to compensate for emissions generated by scientific conferencing cannot be considered an efficient or acceptable alternative. Carbon offset projects backed by airlines fail to remove any carbon dioxide (Greenfield 2021) and rely on overstated promises of true carbon removal (West et al. 2020). On the carbon market, 88% of the sold offsets do not constitute any emission reduction (Probst et al. 2023), and more than 90% of rainforest carbon offsets by the biggest certifier are worthless (West et al. 2023), to the point that the so-called carbon offset projects could even worsen climate change. Besides being counter-effective, carbon credit is a very lucrative trade that favors those who could afford to purchase such offsets while counteracting ASLO's efforts to get more inclusive. Shifting to multi-hub conferences is the structural change that we explore here. The principle of multi-hub conferences implies that meetings take place in several locations at the same time. Attendees go to their closest hub (Klower et al. 2020; Parncutt et al. 2021). Face-to-face interactions are maintained within hubs, while hubs are connected by virtual links (Parncutt et al. 2021). Using the data for ASM 2023, whereby attendance and attendees' diversity were high, we assessed the net reduction of travel-related CO2&#8722;e emissions of shifting from the traditional to a multi-hub model for ASM (Fig. 3). We compared flight paths and CO2&#8722;e emissions between the current traditional ASM model and scenarios of a two-hub model (one central location in Europe and one in North America) and a three-hub model (adding a central hub in Asia). Adding continental hubs significantly reduces the number of intercontinental flights (Fig. 3a&#8211;c). The sum of traveled distances decreases significantly as the number of hubs increases, from 22 million km flown in the traditional one-hub model down to 10 million km in the two-hub and 8 million km in the three-hub scenario, leading to a reduction of total CO2&#8722;e emissions by 52% and 65%, respectively (Fig. 3d). Multi-hubs contribute to reducing per-attendee emissions, with a more balanced share of the C-burden across the attendees' continent of origin (Fig. 3e). Promoting land-bound transportation has a rather minor impact on CO2&#8722;e in a one-hub model (&lt;3% of total CO2&#8722;e). But with the multi-hub model, the potential benefit of promoting land-bound transportation is &gt;10% (Fig. 3d). Serving vegetarian food has only a symbolic impact compared to travel-related emissions in a one-hub scenario. The "meatless day" at the ASM 2023 saved 11 tCO2&#8722;e, that is, 0.3% of the total emissions of the ASM 2023. In a three-hub scenario, shifting to a meatless week (&#8722;58 tCO2&#8722;e) has the potential to decrease emissions by another 5%. The IPCC is clear that limiting warming at manageable levels requires that all sectors do their share, and scientific societies make no exception. In the current academic model, we are stuck within a cognitive conundrum (Whitmarsh et al. 2020): we travel the world to present our studies on the inner causes and consequences of climate change, leading to a demonstrated undermining of our scientific credibility (Attari et al. 2016), while being part of a scientific society committed to raising public awareness on water-related environmental challenges (www.aslo.org). And yet, tackling the question of the C-footprint of conferences, and of academic activities in general, remains an uncomfortable and sensitive topic, if not a complete taboo (Higham and Font 2020; Whitmarsh et al. 2020). The traditional conferencing model is "an outdated luxury the planet cannot afford anymore" (Malcolm 2008). As shown here, low-carbon ASM will require more than a marginal fix, whereby we just avoid outskirt locations or promote carbon offsets. Here, we argue that only structural changes can lead to more sustainable conferencing. Switching to multi-hub ASLO conferences would significantly cut-off on the travel-related CO2&#8722;e emissions while maintaining efficient face-to-face scientific interactions. As multi-hub conferences develop, favoring landbound transport and serving vegetarian food also make an impactful difference, while being symbolic only in a one-hub scenario. While here we aimed only for a 1st-order demonstration of the potential of multi-hubbing, the implementation of such a model shift should come with a revision of what drives the choice of the venues, echoing concerns of Harazin (2020). The choice of the hub locations should be based on criteria oriented toward reducing the C-footprint, and more generally the environmental impact, over touristic attractiveness. For instance, an isochrone map could define optimal cities reachable by train within 10 h, thus incentivizing economic returns for cities and countries actively investing in railway transportation. Some may argue that multi-hub conferences will be challenging to organize, due to time zone differences, and difficulties in managing both online and physical communication. If indeed this would imply to revise our habits, other societies, some of size comparable to the ASLO, have already undertaken the turn (such as the American Meteorological Society in 2022 and the Royal Geographical Society in 2023), and have provided guidelines and feedbacks (Parncutt et al. 2021; Kremser et al. 2024). Those technical requirements should be an integral part of the ASLO's contract specification with conference organizing companies, many of which are currently developing capacities for multi-hubbing. Others may express concerns regarding the financial implications of adopting a multi-hub model because of the escalated demand for audio&#8211;visual equipment across diverse venues. Nonetheless, technological advancements have led to more affordable, compact, and reliable audio-visual gear. Additionally, hosting conferences in smaller hubs could potentially necessitate more modest and cheaper conference venues than those needed for the typical one-hub model. While it remains challenging to precisely gauge the financial impact of multi-hubbing at this stage, it is imperative to couple the multi-hub framework with a financial restructuring to ensure that registration fees do not increase. Engaging in a transformative turn to truly more sustainable conferences through multi-hubs has also the potential to leverage some of the well-known inequalities of traditional conferences, a central mission of the ASLO community. Conference travel opportunities are strongly inequitable (Sarabipour et al. 2021). For economic, family or time-related reasons, academics working in the developing world, and those with care responsibilities have reduced access to the privilege of conference travel, with potential disadvantages to their career development. This also appears in the presented data as scholars outside North America favor ASM within their (sub)continents, when it does not imply traveling too far. Multi-hub ASM will serve ASLO's commitment to diversity, inclusion, and equality, by reducing the cost, time and C-burden associated with ASLO conferencing. The average traveling distance per attendee is cut to less than a 3rd in the three-hub model (1300 km) as compared to the traditional one-hub model (4600 km). Thereby, shall this multi-hub model be successful and lead to a rebound effect of +25% of attendance, most of the additional attendees could travel with landbound transportation, leading to a relatively low increase in CO2 emissions. Finally, our scientific credibility is challenged by our current difficulty to "walk our talk" (Attari et al. 2016) and actively engaging into a transformative model specifically targeted to reduce the C-emissions of conferences is one lever to restore public trust. Some scholars have already chosen not to attend conferences overseas (Higham and Font 2020), even at the risk of being less visible. Yet, a real transformative change implies a collective engagement and a cultural change (Whitmarsh et al. 2020), only possible if led and fostered by scientific societies. Rethinking the conference model provides an opportunity to revise what makes the success of a conference. How often do we need to attend? Is a bigger conference more effective in terms of scientific outcomes and feedbacks? Boosting symbolic capital and enjoying paid trips to nice locations are also reasons that drive frequent conference participation. How much of our perceived incentive to attend is actually a social construction rather than a real scientific benefit? ASLO has already proven its commitment to diversity and equality issues, by putting it into action through its "amplifying Voices" program. For such a strong community of academics at the forefront of climate issues, taking the leap toward committed actions for a sustainable and climate-friendly conference model would place the ASLO at the vanguard of scientific societies. This essay benefited from the suggestions of the associate editor and two reviewers. We thank Patricia Glibert, the ASLO president, and Chris Schneider, from ASLO, for providing access to the ASM data for attendance and abstracts. This study's idea came from a discussion between MEP and EK on the ferry boat on the way back from the ASM 2023.</description>
      <author>Marie&#8208;Elodie Perga, Thorsten Dittmar, Damien Bouffard, Emma S. Kritzberg</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/lol2.10402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing multiple heterogeneous interfaces in one-dimensional carbon fiber materials for superior electromagnetic wave absorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119233</link>
      <description>Qiaoling Zhang, Di Lan, Shuanglin Deng, Junwei Gu, Yiqun Wang, Junwen Ren, Guanglei Wu, Z. Jia, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396836074

                Due to impedance mismatch and a single loss mechanism, carbon fiber fails to meet the requirements for efficient absorbers in terms of lightweight construction and broad absorption band. In this study, we have successfully prepared one-dimensional beaded SiO2@SiC@C nanofiber (SSCF) composites with multiple heterogeneous interfaces by employing the electrospinning-carbothermal reduction method. The beaded SSCF composites effectively address the impedance mismatch issue by controlling silicon dioxide and silicon carbide through carbothermal reduction. This optimization enriches the defects and interfaces of carbon fibers composites, consequently enhancing the electromagnetic wave absorption performance. The SSCF composites demonstrate remarkable performance, with a minimum reflection loss of -59.53 dB at a matched thickness of 2.21 mm and a maximum absorption bandwidth of 6 GHz. This outstanding performance is attributed to the synergistic effects of the multi-phase composition, bead structure, and one-dimensional network structure. These features not only optimize impedance matching but also enhance defect loss, interface polarization loss (SiC/SiO2, C/SiO2, SiC/C, C/Air), conduction loss, and relaxation loss of the SSCF composites. Furthermore, radar cross-section analysis utilizing computer simulation technology confirms the excellent attenuation of microwave energy by the SSCF composites under realistic far-field conditions. This study provides valuable insights for designing efficient one-dimensional carbon-based electromagnetic wave absorbers.</description>
      <author>Qiaoling Zhang, Di Lan, Shuanglin Deng, Junwei Gu, Yiqun Wang, Junwen Ren, Guanglei Wu, Z. Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eco-Friendly Energy Efficient Classrooms and Sustainable Campus Strategies: A Case Study on Energy Management and Carbon Footprint Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.15712</link>
      <description>Ganesh Patil, Satish Suresh Tanavade, International journal of energy economics and policy. 14(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396747782

                This research paper presents a comprehensive study on energy management and carbon footprint reduction in an educational institutional campus. It focuses on implementing energy-efficient technologies and practices to minimize energy consumption and environmental impact. The study encompasses four cases, each addressing different aspects of energy use in a university setting, including the installation of LED lighting, programmable remote switches, and high-efficiency air conditioning systems. The methodology involves a detailed analysis of energy consumption patterns, using smart energy meters and theoretical calculations. Case I establishes a baseline energy consumption, while subsequent cases implement energy-saving measures. Case II involves replacing traditional tube lights with energy-efficient LED lights, resulting in considerable energy savings. Case III extends these savings further by integrating programmable remote switches mapped with student timetables. Finally, Case IV proposes the replacement of older air conditioning units with 25 SEER models, leading to significant reductions in energy use. The results highlight the effectiveness of these interventions. Case II achieves a 66.67% energy saving, while Case III yields up to 77.78% energy saving in lighting and 33.34% in air conditioning. In Case IV, the adoption of high-efficiency air conditioners can result in a 52% energy saving during teaching weeks. The economic benefits of these measures are substantial, with cost savings per classroom ranging from 7.65% in Case II to 53.46% in Case IV. Moreover, the environmental impact of these energy conservation techniques is substantial. The study reports reductions in carbon emissions from 14.71metric tons of carbon dioxide equivalent (MT CO2e) in base Case I to 6.85 MT CO2e in Case IV. The overall carbon emission reductions for Cases II, III, and IV are 7.61%, 36.37%, and 53.43%, respectively. This study demonstrates the profound impact of integrated energy management strategies in reducing the carbon footprint and energy consumption in educational institutions, offering a model for sustainable and economically viable operations.</description>
      <author>Ganesh Patil, Satish Suresh Tanavade</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.15712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigo as a Low&#8208;Cost Redox&#8208;Active Sorbent for Electrochemically Mediated Carbon Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402355</link>
      <description>Krish N. Jayarapu, Anmol Mathur, Xing Li, Andong Liu, Lingyu Zhang, Jaeeun Kim, Hyun-Ah Kim, Su Keun Kuk, Yayuan Liu, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857371

                Abstract Climate change has driven the need for carbon capture to mitigate anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions, yet current thermochemical methods are hampered by high energy intensities. Electrochemically mediated carbon capture (EMCC) utilizing redox&#8208;active carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) carriers is an attractive alternative for carbon capture. Here, an economical vat dye compound, indigo, is presented, which can reversibly capture and release CO 2 upon electrochemical reduction and oxidation, respectively. Electrode and electrolyte engineering strategies are utilized to improve the reversibility and stability of indigo for EMCC. A bench&#8208;scale prototypical fixed&#8208;bed carbon capture device is constructed to demonstrate indigo's EMCC performance under various practically relevant conditions, such as simulated flue gas and extremely dilute sources pertinent to direct air capture. A hybrid sorbent electrode&#8208;gas diffusion layer approach is revealed to alleviate CO 2 mass transport limitations, achieving &#8776;80% CO 2 capacity utilization under a 15% CO 2 feed stream. Furthermore, a reactive&#8208;diffusive mass transport model is developed to illustrate engineering approaches that can be universally applied to optimize fixed&#8208;bed EMCC systems. This work advances the potential for a class of low&#8208;cost sorbents for EMCC while underscoring the importance of molecular, electrolyte, materials, and device engineering strategies to enable high&#8208;performance carbon capture.</description>
      <author>Krish N. Jayarapu, Anmol Mathur, Xing Li, Andong Liu, Lingyu Zhang, Jaeeun Kim, Hyun-Ah Kim, Su Keun Kuk, Yayuan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Polyethylene Terephthalate (PET) Plastic Supply Chain Resource Metabolism Efficiency and Carbon Emissions Co-Reduction Strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16103926</link>
      <description>C. Duan, Zhen Wang, Bingzheng Zhou, Xiaolei Yao, Sustainability. 16(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396747385

                Polyethylene terephthalate (PET) is widely used as a primary plastic packaging material in the global socio-economic system. However, research on the metabolic characteristics of the PET industry across different countries, particularly regarding the entire life cycle supply chain of PET, remains insufficient, significantly hindering progress in addressing plastic pollution worldwide. This study employs the Life Cycle Assessment-Material Flow Analysis (LCA-MFA) method to comprehensively analyze the environmental impacts of PET plastics, with a focus on the processes from production to disposal in 12 regions (covering 41 countries) in 2020. By constructing 13 scenarios and analyzing the development trajectory of PET plastics from 2020 to 2030, this study provides scientific evidence and specific strategies for waste reduction and emission reduction measures in the PET industry. Overall, in 2020, the 12 regions (41 countries) consumed 7297.7 kilotons (kt) of virgin PET resin and 1189.4 kt of recycled PET resin; 23% of plastic waste was manufactured into recycled PET materials, 42% went to landfills, and 35% was incinerated. In 2020, the entire PET plastic supply chain emitted approximately 534.6 million tons (Mt) of carbon dioxide equivalent per year, with production emissions accounting for 46.1%, manufacturing stage emissions accounting for 44.7%, and waste treatment stage emissions accounting for 9.2%. Research indicates that under a scenario of controlled demand, resource efficiency improvement and emission reduction are the most effective, potentially reducing carbon emissions by up to 40%.</description>
      <author>C. Duan, Zhen Wang, Bingzheng Zhou, Xiaolei Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16103926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applicability of carbon nanotube-incorporated cement-based composites as a sensor for measuring the carbonation front: an overview</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3012724</link>
      <description>Jihoon Park, Jisoo Kim, Joonho Seo, Daeik Jang, H.K. Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396781591

                Carbon nanotubes (CNTs) have been widely used in various fields due to their remarkable electrical and mechanical properties. In the construction industry, several studies have been conducted in an attempt to impart conductivity to cement-based composites by incorporating CNTs into the composites. The electrical properties of CNT-incorporated cement-based composites undergo changes due to several factors, allowing one to use these composites as cement-based sensors. Carbonation has been regarded as a significant factor contributing to the deterioration of concrete structures. The reaction between hydrates and dissolved carbon dioxide in concrete leads to the precipitation of calcium carbonate and reduction of pH levels, causing corrosion of reinforcement. Thus, numerous efforts have been dedicated to non-destructively assessing the extent of carbonation of concrete structures. This paper summarizes previous studies on the non-destructive evaluation of the extent of carbonation in concrete. In addition, a preliminary study on the applicability of CNT-incorporated cement-based composites embedded in the concrete structure as sensors for measuring carbonation front will be introduced.</description>
      <author>Jihoon Park, Jisoo Kim, Joonho Seo, Daeik Jang, H.K. Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3012724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduced erosion and its erosion reducing mechanism of gun propellants by octaphenylsilsesquioxane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.05.001</link>
      <description>Taixin Liang, Jiaxin Lu, Fei Xiao, Hongxu Guo, Chunzhi Li, Miao He, Baosheng Liu, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, Nawaa Ali H. Alshammari, Xin Liao, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Zhongliang Xiao, Zhanhu Guo, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830458

                Low erosion high-energy propellant is one of the research directions to extend the weapon's life and improve the weapon's capability. In this study, energetic propellants containing different corrosion inhibitors were designed and prepared. Close bomb tests and semi-confined bomb experiments were used to investigate the burning and erosion properties of the propellants. The mechanism of erosion-reducing of titanium dioxide (TiO2), talc, and octaphenylsilsesquioxane (OPS) on the propellant was comparatively analyzed. The results show that OPS has the lowest burning rate and the longest burning time, and a minimized loss of fire force, with the best effect of explosion heat reduction. The erosion reduction efficiency of OPS is twice that of TiO2 and talc. The mechanism analysis shows that the decomposition and heat absorption of OPS can effectively reduce the thermal erosion effect and carbon erosion, and the gas produced can reduce the loss of chamber pressure and form a uniformly distributed nano-SiO2 protective layer. This solid-state high-efficiency organosilicon erosion inhibitor is an important guide for designing high-energy low-erosion gun propellants.</description>
      <author>Taixin Liang, Jiaxin Lu, Fei Xiao, Hongxu Guo, Chunzhi Li, Miao He, Baosheng Liu, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, Nawaa Ali H. Alshammari, Xin Liao, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Zhongliang Xiao, Zhanhu Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.05.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Gasification on Nitrogen Oxide Emission in Oxy-Fuel Combustion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00835</link>
      <description>Zilong Wang, Anyao Jiao, Feng Liu, Xiaowei Liao, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A/&#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A.. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789589

                Due to the cumulative effect of the recycled flue gas in oxy-fuel combustion, the reduction of NO has become the focus of research in which the role of CO2 gasification has a nonnegligible effect. In this article, the heterogeneous gasification mechanisms of CO2 on coal char during oxy-fuel combustion were studied by density functional theory and transition-state theory. The zigzag char model and char(N) model were selected to investigate the CO2 adsorption and gratification reactions at the molecular level. By comparison, the CO2 gasification reaction is preferred to occur on the zigzag char model with a reduction in the energy barrier and an increase in the reaction rate. When considering char nitrogen conversion, the gasification reaction is more prone to releasing NO first, leading to the contraction of the aromatic ring and the generation of CO at high temperatures. Therefore, the study further highlights the promoting role of CO2 gasification on the homogeneous and heterogeneous reduction of NO, which is mainly reflected in the reduction effect of CO. Moreover, it also accelerates the consumption of coal char and NO formation, which is favorable for the reduction reactions to a certain extent.</description>
      <author>Zilong Wang, Anyao Jiao, Feng Liu, Xiaowei Liao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00835</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting *CO coverage on Cu octahedra enclosed by Cu(1 1 1) for efficient CO2 electroreduction to C2H5OH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160202</link>
      <description>Xin Zhao, Genyan Hao, Qinghong Fang, Xingyou Lang, Dandan Li, Dazhong Zhong, Jinping Li, Qiang Zhao, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835466

                Copper (Cu) electrocatalysts for carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) have attracted much attention due to their ability to produce high value-added C2+ products (e.g., C2H4, C2H5OH, and n-propanol). However, achieving high selectivity of Cu electrocatalysts for C2H5OH in aqueous-based electrolytes remains a significant challenge. In this paper, we report Cu octahedra modified with low-coordinated Cu nanoclusters (Cu oct @Cu_NCs) as an efficient electrocatalyst for CO2RR to C2H5OH. Notably, the defect-site-rich Cu nanoclusters can promote the adsorption of *CO and increase the *CO coverage on Cu octahedra enclosed by Cu(1 1 1), thus promoting CO2RR to C2H5OH. We achieved a high Faradaic efficiency(FE) of 48.16 % for C2H5OH, and that of the C2+ products is 83.31 % at &#8722;1.17 V vs. RHE. This study provides a surface nanostructured route for rationalizing efficient and selective copper electrocatalysts for CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Xin Zhao, Genyan Hao, Qinghong Fang, Xingyou Lang, Dandan Li, Dazhong Zhong, Jinping Li, Qiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical design enables sufficient activated CO2 for efficient electrolysis of bicarbonate to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.04.006</link>
      <description>Mengxin Shen, Lianze Ji, Dongfang Cheng, Ziwei Wang, Qingquan Xue, Shijia Feng, Yanhong Luo, Shuying Chen, Jiahao Wang, Hongzhi Zheng, Xiaojun Wang, Philippe Sautet, Jia Zhu, Joule. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396734056

                Bicarbonate electrolyzers (BCEs) offer a promising approach to reducing the energy cost of CO2 reduction by integrating upstream carbon capture and downstream electrochemical utilization. However, the faradaic efficiency of CO2 electrolysis in BCEs has been limited by insufficient activated CO2 on the catalyst surface. We report a hierarchical design strategy combining molecular and system-level innovations to ensure that there is sufficient activated CO2 on the catalyst in BCEs. At the molecular scale, we introduce a single-atom catalyst CoPc@CNT with strong CO2 adsorption to prevent CO2 desorption from the catalyst surface. Systemically, a cathodic electrolyte cross-flow strategy further enhances CO2 mass transfer. This approach achieves a faradaic efficiency exceeding 96.2% for CO at 50&#8211;300 mA cm&#8722;2, with a 36.0% and 35.3% reduction in overall energy cost compared with conventional BCEs and CO2 gas-fed electrolyzers, respectively. This innovative strategy represents a significant advancement in low-energy-consumption exhaust conversion technologies for carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Mengxin Shen, Lianze Ji, Dongfang Cheng, Ziwei Wang, Qingquan Xue, Shijia Feng, Yanhong Luo, Shuying Chen, Jiahao Wang, Hongzhi Zheng, Xiaojun Wang, Philippe Sautet, Jia Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.04.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extension of Japan&#8217;s Prefectural Emission Accounting and Enrichment of Socioeconomic Data from 1990 to 2020</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-024-03316-x</link>
      <description>Zhiheng Chen, Liqiao Huang, Liusi Yang, Yoshikuni Yoshida, Kenji Tanaka, Yin Long, Scientific data. 11(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835219

                Abstract With the continuous increase in carbon dioxide emissions due to human activities and the resulting severe climate issues, there is global concern about energy conservation and emission reduction. However, detailed data on energy consumption and emissions at a fine-grained scale, particularly regarding spatial dimensions and sector-specific emissions, remains insufficient and in need of refinement and timely updates. In Japan, following the Fukushima nuclear disaster, there has been a significant shift from nuclear power generation to reliance on fossil fuels across various sectors, highlighting disparities in emissions data across different regions and industries. Our work extends the emissions time series for Japan&#8217;s 47 prefectures, incorporating their socioeconomic characteristics over a broader time frame and with a more detailed sectoral classification. The emissions inventory, covering the period from 1990 to 2020, is based on the consumption of the three main fossil fuels across 32 sectors, with emissions carefully allocated for regional power generation. This dataset, presented in a unified format, is expanded to include longer time scales and more detailed socioeconomic data. It is anticipated to offer crucial insights for establishing regional emission reduction targets and identifying sectoral priorities for decarbonization.</description>
      <author>Zhiheng Chen, Liqiao Huang, Liusi Yang, Yoshikuni Yoshida, Kenji Tanaka, Yin Long</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-024-03316-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Chinese &#8220;double carbon strategy&#8221; on soil polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons pollution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2024.108741</link>
      <description>Weiwei Wang, Songchao Chen, Lu Chen, Lingwen Wang, Chao Yang, Zhou Shi, Daohui Lin, Kun Yang, Environment international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835055

                Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) and carbon dioxide primarily originate from the combustion of fossil fuels and biomass. The implementation of the Chinese "double carbon strategy" is expected to impact the distribution of PAH emissions, consequently influencing the spatial distribution trend of PAHs in surface soil. Therefore, it is crucial to quantitatively evaluate the effectiveness of the Chinese "double carbon strategy" on soil PAH pollution for the purpose of "the reduction of pollution and carbon emissions". This study utilized 15,088 individual PAH concentration data from 943 soil samples collected between 2003 and 2020 in China, in conjunction with PAH emissions at a 10 km resolution, for meta-analysis. The calculated PAH emissions in this study are in line with the global PAH emission inventory (PKU-PAH-2007), with a relative standard deviation at the provincial level of less than 25 %. Subsequently, a novel method was developed using emission density and Kow of PAHs to predict PAH concentrations in surface soil based on a least-squares regression model. Compared to other environmental models, the method established in this study significantly reduced the percent sample deviation to less than 70 %. Furthermore, energy consumption data for China were simulated based on the implementation plan of the "double carbon strategy" to project PAH emissions and soil PAH levels for the years 2030 and 2060. The predicted PAH emissions in China were estimated to decrease to 41,300 t in 2030 and 10,406.5 t in 2060 from 78,815 t in 2020. Moreover, the heavily contaminated areas of soil PAHs (i.e., total PAH concentrations in soil exceeding 1000 &#956;g kg&#8722;1) were projected to decrease by 45 % and 82 % in 2030 and 2060, respectively, compared to levels in 2020. These findings suggest that the implementation of the "double carbon strategy" can fundamentally reduce the pollution of PAHs in surface soil of China.</description>
      <author>Weiwei Wang, Songchao Chen, Lu Chen, Lingwen Wang, Chao Yang, Zhou Shi, Daohui Lin, Kun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2024.108741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Cation Stabilization Effects of CO Dimerization for Boosting C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Pathways of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Noble Metal Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400110</link>
      <description>Hon Ho Wong, Ming Sun, Tong Wu, Lu Lu, Qimiao Lu, Baian Chen, Cheuk Hei Chan, Bolong Huang, Advanced energy and sustainability research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396844999

                The carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) is one of the most promising solutions for realizing carbon neutralization via converting the emitted CO 2 into value&#8208;added chemicals. The C&#63743;C coupling step for CO dimerization is the rate&#8208;determining step for C 2 pathways, which have not been thoroughly investigated. Herein, the direct cation stabilization effects on CO dimerization for *OCCO formation on the representative Cu(100) and Pt(100) surfaces are investigated. Density functional theory calculations show that the presence of alkali metal ions plays a vital role in promoting the coupling of *CO monomers on both metal surfaces, where Cu shows a stronger stabilization effect. More importantly, a strong linear correlation ( R 2 &#8776; 0.9) between the dimer stabilization energy and the reaction energy is revealed for the first time, which is a promising indicator for the selectivity of C 2 pathways. Further investigations on electronic structures reveal that the promoting effect on *OCCO formation is strongly related to the negative charges of the molecules, in which the negative charge accumulation is favored by the directional electron transfer due to the chemisorption of *OCCO on Cu(100) surface. This work offers insights into the understanding of C&#63743;C coupling reactions for CO 2 RR mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Hon Ho Wong, Ming Sun, Tong Wu, Lu Lu, Qimiao Lu, Baian Chen, Cheuk Hei Chan, Bolong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Produce low-CO2 silica fume hybrid high-strength concrete using dry ice (solid CO2) as a CO2-utilized admixture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142555</link>
      <description>Mei-Yu Xuan, Run-Sheng Lin, Yi Han, Guiyu Zhang, Guo Cheng, Xiao-Yong Wang, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834176

                Concerns about high-strength concrete (HSC) have increasingly grown in tandem with the building industry's rapid development. However, the high CO2 emissions, high hydration heat, and high autogenous shrinkage of HSCs considered key issues that limit their wide application. In this study, various proportions of dry ice (solid CO2) were added to concrete to optimize HSC. The test results indicated that adding solid CO2 decreased the hydration heat and autogenous shrinkage and increased the mechanical properties and surface electrical resistivity of HSC. This is primarily attributed to the physical and chemical effects of solid CO2 in HSC curing. At 28 d of curing, the sample containing 3 wt.% solid CO2 exhibited the most significant optimization effect. This is attributed to the fact that, at lower solid CO2 content (3%), the production of carbonation products compensates for the loss of strength caused by the reduction of hydration products. In addition, the addition of solid CO2 caused a decrease in the initial temperature, which delayed the hydration reaction and reduced the autogenous shrinkage. Adding solid CO2 led to an increase in acidity and promoted the formation of AFt, further reducing the autogenous shrinkage. And the more solid CO2 added, the greater the reduction in CO2 emissions for the mixture. Therefore, adding solid CO2 can play a role in optimizing the performance and promoting the sustainability of HSC and can contribute to the objectives of low CO2 emissions, low hydration heat, and low autogenous shrinkage of HSC.</description>
      <author>Mei-Yu Xuan, Run-Sheng Lin, Yi Han, Guiyu Zhang, Guo Cheng, Xiao-Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering fast Ti electron channels to single-atom Fe for enhanced CO2 photoreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01972e</link>
      <description>Wuyi Feng, Pan Zhu, Shouyuan Li, Jiantao Fu, Hui-Ying Niu, Rongjun Zhao, Shoujie Liu, Lirong Zheng, Dan Zhao, Jiatao Zhang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396782422

                Owing to the inertness of CO2 molecules, the development of highly active and selective photocatalysts for CO2 reduction reactions (CO2RR) remains a formidable challenge. The interaction between metal sites and...</description>
      <author>Wuyi Feng, Pan Zhu, Shouyuan Li, Jiantao Fu, Hui-Ying Niu, Rongjun Zhao, Shoujie Liu, Lirong Zheng, Dan Zhao, Jiatao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01972e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Co Single Atoms and Ni Clusters on Defect-Rich ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Strong Photothermal Coupling Boosts Photocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01637</link>
      <description>Jinghang Chen, Yifei Ren, Yiwei Fu, Yitao Si, Jie Huang, Jiancheng Zhou, Maochang Liu, Lunbo Duan, Naixu Li, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396814826

                We report a solvothermal method for the synthesis of an oxygen vacancy-enriched ZrO2 photocatalyst with Co single atoms and Ni clusters immobilized on the surface. This catalyst presents superior performance for the reduction of CO2 in H2O vapor, with a CO yield reaching 663.84 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 and a selectivity of 99.52%. The total solar-to-chemical energy conversion efficiency is up to 0.372&#8240;, which is among the highest reported values. The success, on one hand, depends on the Co single atoms and Ni clusters for both extended spectrum absorption and serving as dual-active centers for CO2 reduction and H2O dissociation, respectively; on the other hand, this is attributed to the enhanced photoelectric and thermal effect induced by concentrated solar irradiation. We demonstrate that an intermediate impurity state is formed by the hybridization of the d-orbital of single-atom Co with the molecular orbital of H2O, enabling visible-light-driven excitation over the catalyst. In addition, Ni clusters play a crucial role in altering the adsorption configuration of CO2, with the localized surface plasmon resonance effect enhancing the activation and dissociation of CO2 induced by visible&#8211;near-infrared light. This study provides valuable insights into the synergistic effect of the dual cocatalyst toward both efficient photothermal coupling and surface redox reactions for solar CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Jinghang Chen, Yifei Ren, Yiwei Fu, Yitao Si, Jie Huang, Jiancheng Zhou, Maochang Liu, Lunbo Duan, Naixu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Influencing Factors of Injection Blockage during CO2 Sequestration in One-Dimensional Long Reactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12050960</link>
      <description>Y. Zhang, Houzhen Wei, J Liu, Xiaolong Ma, Processes. 12(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396772556

                Carbon sequestration through CO2 injection into a formation is an effective strategy for reducing greenhouse gas emissions. In this study, a one-dimensional long reactor was constructed to simulate the CO2 injection process under various sediment temperatures, pressures, and flow rates. The formation of CO2 hydrate and the resulting blockages were investigated in detail through a series of indoor experiments. Due to the increasing driving force for CO2 hydrate formation, reducing sediment temperature and increasing sediment pressure can cause hydrate blockage to form near the injection end, leading to an increase in CO2 injection pressure and a reduction in the storage range. Furthermore, CO2 injection rate has a substantial impact on the pattern of hydrate blockage. A lower injection rate facilitates full contact between CO2 gas and pore water, which helps to increase the formation and blockage degree of CO2 hydrates, thereby decreasing the amount of CO2 injection. The experimental investigation presented in this paper examines the laws of CO2 injection and clogging under various sediment conditions and injection processes on a one-dimensional scale, which can provide valuable insights for the design of CO2 sequestration processes.</description>
      <author>Y. Zhang, Houzhen Wei, J Liu, Xiaolong Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12050960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling of a Solar Thermal Plant to Produce Hot Water and Steam for a Brewery Factory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102300</link>
      <description>Kalo G. Traslosheros-Zavala, I. Zavala-Guill&#233;n, A. Acu&#241;a, Manuel Cervantes-Astorga, D. Sauceda, Francisco J. Carranza-Ch&#225;vez, Energies. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396798562

                The environmental impact caused by the intensive exploitation of fossil fuels to generate heat and electricity has already reached a critical level. Also, as the industrial sector is the largest energy consumer, mainly in the form of heat, it has then become compulsive to implement the use of renewable solar heat in industrial processes, such as those found in the food processing and beverages industries, which do not require high temperatures. Consequently, this study examines the viability of supplying heat as hot water at 80 &#176;C and saturated steam at 160 &#176;C to a medium-sized brewery factory through a hybrid solar plant composed of flat plate and parabolic trough collectors and sensible thermal energy storage. The study was conducted numerically using the meteorological conditions of a city different from that where the factory is located because it benefits from higher insolation levels. The mean annual solar fractions achieved were 49.9% for hot water production and 37.3% for steam generation, at a levelized cost of heat of 0.032 USD/kWh, which can be considered competitive if compared against the values reported in other similar solar projects. Also, the decrease in fossil fuel consumption allowed an annual reduction of 252 tons of carbon dioxide emissions.</description>
      <author>Kalo G. Traslosheros-Zavala, I. Zavala-Guill&#233;n, A. Acu&#241;a, Manuel Cervantes-Astorga, D. Sauceda, Francisco J. Carranza-Ch&#225;vez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Electrochemical Conversion of CO2 to Ethanol through the Confinement of Pyridinic N-B layer on Copper Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124168</link>
      <description>Y. Zhao, Qixin Yuan, Ruting Xu, Chenhao Zhang, Kang Sun, Ao Wang, Anqi Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Mengmeng Fan, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396813755

                Developing efficient electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction has gained significant attention in the field of sustainable energy, especially the Cu-based catalysts for CO2 conversion to valuable alcohols. In this study, we developed Cu nanoparticles supported on pyridinic N-B doped graphene nanoribbons/amorphous carbon (Cu/BNC-1) as an electrocatalyst for CO2 reduction, exhibiting substantially improved ethanol (EtOH) conversion rate in terms of activity, selectivity, and stability. The Cu/BNC-1 achieved a remarkable 58.64% Faradaic efficiency (FE) for producing EtOH at -1.0 V vs. RHE with a current density of 20.4 mA cm-2 in 0.5 M KHCO3 electrolyte. In-situ Raman, FT-IR, and density functional theory (DFT) calculations demonstrated that the high C2+ product selectivity of Cu/BNC-1 attributed to the pyridinic N-B modulation, lowering the CO dimerization barrier. Moreover, the synergistic confinement effect of Cu and BNC can stabilize the C-O bond of the &#8270;HOCCH intermediate, thereby increasing the yield of EtOH.</description>
      <author>Y. Zhao, Qixin Yuan, Ruting Xu, Chenhao Zhang, Kang Sun, Ao Wang, Anqi Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Mengmeng Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering CO Selectivity in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction over Silver Microtubular Gas-Diffusion Electrodes via Surface Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01240</link>
      <description>Yizhu Kuang, Guoliang Chen, Hesamoddin Rabiee, Bo Ma, Fatereh Dorosti, Ashok Kumar Nanjundan, Zhonghua Zhu, Hao Wang, Lei Ge, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830183

                An efficient gas diffusion electrode (GDE) is crucial for enhancing mass transport involving gas-phase CO2 conversion in the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Microtubular hollow fiber GDE (HFGDE) with a porous hierarchical wall has garnered significant attention, which can modulate the triple-phase reaction zone and improve the performance of CO2RR. Simultaneously, engineering nano/microstructure surfaces of electrocatalysts have been demonstrated to effectively enhance the selectivity and activity in CO2RR. Here, we developed a porous microparticle Ag-based HFGDE via an in situ electrochemical oxidation&#8211;reduction method. Both the activity and selectivity of CO2 to CO conversion in the porous microparticle Ag-based HFGDE showed significant enhancement over the pristine and thermal reduced Ag HFGDE without surface reconstruction. At &#8722;1.2 V vs RHE, the faradaic efficiency for CO is 94%, with a partial current density of 83.4 mA cm&#8211;2, surpassing that of thermal treatment electrodes, which is only 26% with a partial current density of 12.3 mA cm&#8211;2. The distinctive reconstruction nano/microstructure on the electrocatalyst surface could be attributed to decreasing the activation energy barrier in the rate-limiting step of initial electron/proton transfer. This work represents a facile strategy for surface reconstruction of electrocatalysts in HFGDE as advanced electrode materials to enhance the efficiency of the CO2 conversion.</description>
      <author>Yizhu Kuang, Guoliang Chen, Hesamoddin Rabiee, Bo Ma, Fatereh Dorosti, Ashok Kumar Nanjundan, Zhonghua Zhu, Hao Wang, Lei Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01240</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techno-economic analysis of blue ammonia synthesis using cryogenic CO2 capture Process-A Danish case investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.060</link>
      <description>Hossein Asgharian, Larry Baxter, Florin Iov, Xiaoti Cui, Samuel Simon Araya, Mads Pagh Nielsen, Vincenzo Liso, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396785795

                Ammonia is a vital chemical with numerous applications. Currently, the primary methods for generating the necessary reactants for ammonia production involve steam methane reforming (SMR) and cryogenic air separation unit (CASU), while the Haber-Bosch process converts these reactants into ammonia. However, the SMR process releases substantial amounts of CO2, making it imperative to employ an efficient and cost-effective CO2 capture technology to mitigate emissions. This investigation focuses on evaluating the cryogenic CO2 capture (CCC) process for blue ammonia production and provides a thorough economic analysis, estimating both the initial investment costs and operational expenses involved in producing blue ammonia. The results indicated that the CCC process can capture 90% of the CO2 content in the flue gas emitted by the SMR, incurring an energy penalty of 0.724 MJe/kgCO2 while capturing CO2 in the liquid phase with purities exceeding 99.9%. In this case, the estimated CO2 capture costs would be 18.05, 45.1, and 16.65 USD/ton in 2021, 2022, and 2023, respectively. This represents a 40% reduction compared to the CO2 capture costs associated with conventional amine-based technology. The results of this study indicate that the annual electricity costs for ammonia production increase by 38.5% and 64.2% when employing the CCC and amine-based processes, respectively. This investigation employed an isothermal reactor for ammonia synthesis, using the heat from the exothermic reaction in a water ammonia absorption refrigeration cycle (ARC) to condense and purify ammonia. The results show that the ARC system can effectively condense ammonia at &#8722;6 &#176;C, producing a liquid ammonia stream with 99.3% purity. This leads to a 95% reduction in power consumption compared to a vapor compression refrigeration cycle (VCRC). Consequently, this method has the potential to decrease the annual operational costs for ammonia production by 2.92%, 2.69%, and 3.13% in 2021, 2022, and 2023, respectively. This study indicated that the hydrogen production unit incurs the highest initial investment costs, as well as operating costs, in the blue ammonia production process, followed by CASU and the Haber-Bosch process.</description>
      <author>Hossein Asgharian, Larry Baxter, Florin Iov, Xiaoti Cui, Samuel Simon Araya, Mads Pagh Nielsen, Vincenzo Liso</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated assessment of green hydrogen production in California: Life cycle Greenhouse gas Emissions, Techno-Economic Feasibility, and resource variability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118514</link>
      <description>Loiy Al&#8208;Ghussain, Mohammad Alrbai, Sameer Al&#8208;Dahidi, Zifeng L&#252;, Energy conversion and management. 311(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396785656

                This study explores green hydrogen production, focusing on life cycle assessment (LCA) and techno-economic feasibility; specifically, life cycle greenhouse gas emissions and hydrogen production cost. Existing literature lacks a comprehensive exploration of the impact of solar and wind resource variations, ambient conditions, and proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer sizing on the carbon intensity (CI) and hydrogen production cost. This work explores the relationship between the performance of photovoltaic (PV) and wind systems and the CI of renewable electricity in the U.S. Secondly, this study incorporates the hourly variations in solar and wind resources to assess the variation in hydrogen CI and production costs across California. The study examines how reductions in PEM and Renewable Energy Systems (RES) costs, technological advancements, and the inclusion of co-products' carbon dioxide equivalent (CO2eq) credits and revenues impact hydrogen CI and production costs. Wind-based systems consistently demonstrate lower CI (0.35 &#8722; 1.9 kg CO2eq/kg H2) except for the central regions (CI can reach up to 4.34 kg CO2eq/kg H2), with geographical variations larger than solar-based systems (1.58 &#8722; 2.95 kg CO2eq/kg H2). Similar trends are observed for the hydrogen production cost which varies between 1.5 and 15 USD/kg H2 for wind-based systems and between 3.0 and 5.2 USD/kg H2 for the PV-based systems. This study highlights the importance of optimal sizing of PEM electrolyzer to maximize its utilization for hydrogen production and the use of hourly-based models to assess the CI and production costs of hydrogen. Additionally, the geographical variation in the renewable energy resources and the ambient conditions are important factors that affect the hydrogen cost and the CI of both renewable electricity and green hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Loiy Al&#8208;Ghussain, Mohammad Alrbai, Sameer Al&#8208;Dahidi, Zifeng L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the cost of zero carbon electricity: A techno-economic analysis of combined cycle gas turbines with post-combustion CO2 capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2024.04.067</link>
      <description>Daniel Mullen, Mathieu Lucquiaud, Energy reports. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396820993

                To achieve a sustainable electricity grid, affordable and dispatchable power capacity that supports grid stability and does not increase atmospheric CO2 levels will be required. Combined cycle gas turbines (CCGTs) with post-combustion CO2 capture (PCC) can meet these requirements by capturing and permanently storing all combustion CO2 emissions and, coupled with negative emissions technologies, any remaining life-cycle emissions. For the first time, we present a comprehensive analysis of the technical and financial challenges of producing zero-carbon electricity from CCGTs on a life-cycle basis. We conclude that when the design is optimised, fossil CO2 capture fractions can be increased from 96% to 100% with minimal process modification, commercially available technology and an additional 0.5% decrease in thermal efficiency. This represents a significant 60&#8211;70% reduction in the additional efficiency penalty required to reach zero CO2 emission operation. The Cost of CO2 Avoided of 100% fossil CO2 capture is just 128 &#163;/tCO2, a 3 &#163;/tCO2 increase over the 95% gross CO2 capture fraction required to permit PCC projects in the UK. Indeed, within the bounds of the UK power CCS business model, we show that 100% fossil CO2 capture maximises both variable and capacity payments to the producer, resulting in a 2% decrease in the cost of power produced. For zero-carbon electricity on a life-cycle basis, the recapture and permanent geological storage of all remaining life-cycle CO2e emissions from plant construction &amp; decommissioning, CO2 T&amp;S network operation and the natural gas supply chain (operational CO2e emissions and methane leakage) increases the median Cost of CO2 Avoided to 178 &#163;/tCO2 (130&#8211;371 &#163;/tCO2), leading to the novel conclusion that a market mechanism equating to a CO2 price of over 178&#163;/tCO2 is likely sufficient to incentivise the development of truly CO2-neutral CCGTs.</description>
      <author>Daniel Mullen, Mathieu Lucquiaud</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2024.04.067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Co2 to C1 Conversion Through Long-Lived High-Energy Photoelectrons on Bi/Zno@Znse Array Photocathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821868</link>
      <description>Guanyi Ma, Haiqiang Mu, Zhenli Lv, Jiaxing Guo, Min Zhu, Yonghong Li, Xiaozhong Wang, Jing Li, Feng Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396754565

                The key aspect of the photoelectrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (PEC CO2 RR) lies in designing cathode materials that can generate high-energy photoelectrons, enabling the activation and conversion of CO2 into high-value products. In this study, a coaxially wrapped ZnO@ZnSe array heterostructure was synthesized using a simple anion exchange strategy and metallic Bi nanoparticles (NPs) were subsequently deposited on the surface to construct a Bi/ZnO@ZnSe photocathode with high CO2 conversion capability. This array photocathode possesses a large aspect ratio, which simultaneously satisfies a low charge carrier migration path and a large specific surface area that facilitates mass transfer. Additionally, the barrier formed at the n-n heterojunction interface hinders the transfer of high-energy photoelectrons from ZnSe to lower energy levels, resulting in their rapid capture by Bi while maintaining a relatively long lifetime. These captured electrons act as active sites, efficiently converting CO2 into CO with a Faradaic efficiency above 88.9% at -0.9 V vs. RHE and demonstrating superior stability. This work provides a novel approach for synthesizing high-energy photoelectrode materials with long lifetimes.</description>
      <author>Guanyi Ma, Haiqiang Mu, Zhenli Lv, Jiaxing Guo, Min Zhu, Yonghong Li, Xiaozhong Wang, Jing Li, Feng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polycation-functionalized interface enable in situ capturing of CO2 and filtering of proton for efficient C-N coupling toward highly selective urea electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152161</link>
      <description>Zhichao Wang, Mengfan Wang, Qiyang Cheng, Yanzheng He, Yuzhuo Jiang, Sisi Liu, Tao Qian, Jie Xiong, Chengtao Yang, Chenglin Yan, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396826331

                Electrochemical co-reduction of CO2 and nitrate provides a novel route to convert waste emissions into value-added chemicals such as urea. However, at the actual reaction interface, the insufficient supply of CO2 reactants as well as the excessive coverage of proton and nitrate on the electrocatalyst surface usually lead to complex product distributions from individual hydrogen evolution or nitrate reduction as side reactions, instead of C-N coupling. Here, we rationally optimize this interface by polycation functionalization, forcing highly selective urea electrosynthesis. The abundant polyamine nodes within the functional layer are conductive to in situ capturing of CO2 and filtering of proton, which pertinently control the reagent concentration to promote the selective C-N coupling and inhibit the undesired side reactions. When this tailored interface is coupled with efficient electrocatalyst with neighboring active sites, the proof-of-concept system delivers a maximum urea generation yield rate of 1254.2 &#956;g h&#8722;1 mg&#8722;1 along with a Faradaic efficiency of 83.4 %, as well as outstanding Nurea-selectivity of 91.3 % and Curea-selectivity of nearly 100 %, which is one of the most selective urea generation systems reported so far. This work provides new insights in regulating the catalysis microenvironment for the improvement of overall performance in electrochemical C-N coupling.</description>
      <author>Zhichao Wang, Mengfan Wang, Qiyang Cheng, Yanzheng He, Yuzhuo Jiang, Sisi Liu, Tao Qian, Jie Xiong, Chengtao Yang, Chenglin Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restructuring multi-phase interfaces from Cu-based metal-organic frameworks for selective electroreduction of CO2 to C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc00967c</link>
      <description>Jing Feng, Wenbiao Zhang, Danni Shi, Yingshuai Jia, Yanan Tang, Yuying Meng, Qingsheng Gao, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857077

                Multi-phase interfaces are promising to surmount the energy barriers of electrochemical CO2 reduction involving multiple-electron transfer steps, but challenges still remain in ameliorating interfacial micro-structures and unraveling their dynamic changes...</description>
      <author>Jing Feng, Wenbiao Zhang, Danni Shi, Yingshuai Jia, Yanan Tang, Yuying Meng, Qingsheng Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc00967c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Green Finance, and Eco-Innovation on CO2 Emissions: The Pool Mean Group Evidence from ASEAN Countries in the Context of SDGs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62019/abgmce.v4i1.75</link>
      <description>Zahid Hussain Khokhar, Muhammad Imran, Rashid Rauf, Najaf Naz, Muhammad Waseem, Deleted Journal. 4(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396743140

                This study investigates the influence of green finance, green technology, and eco-innovation on CO2 emissions within ASEAN countries, framed within the context of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), particularly SDG 7 (Affordable and Clean Energy), SDG 9 (Industry, Innovation and Infrastructure), and SDG 13 (Climate Action). Utilizing data from 2002 to 2019 and adopting the Pool Mean Group (PMG) methodology, our analysis sheds light on the critical dynamics between sustainable financial practices, technological advancement in green technologies, and eco-innovative approaches towards achieving significant CO2 emissions reduction. Our findings reveal that green finance significantly empowers the deployment of green technologies and eco-innovations, leading to a notable decrease in CO2 emissions across the studied nations. The study highlights the importance of country-specific policy interventions that cater to the unique economic and technological contexts of ASEAN countries to optimize the contribution of green finance and technology to climate action. These insights offer a valuable guide for policymakers, financial institutions, and other stakeholders in harnessing green finance and technology for environmental sustainability, in alignment with the SDGs. This research contributes to the discourse on sustainable development, emphasizing the pivotal role of finance and innovation in environmental stewardship and carbon reduction efforts across ASEAN countries.</description>
      <author>Zahid Hussain Khokhar, Muhammad Imran, Rashid Rauf, Najaf Naz, Muhammad Waseem</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62019/abgmce.v4i1.75</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT Study on Effect of Metal Type and Coordination Environment on CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; ECR to C&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; Products over M&#8211;N&#8211;C Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00590</link>
      <description>Yu Meng, Linbin Ying, Tao Ye, Ma Liang, Baoning Li, Yan Xing, Xiaoyan Liu, Yanhang Ma, Xiaodong Wen, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396748402

                Electrocatalytic reduction (ECR) of CO2 to chemical products is an important carbon emission reduction method. This work uses DFT to study the stability of N-doped graphene-supported four metal single-atom catalysts (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) and the effects of the coordination environment and metal centers on the selectivity of CO2 ECR to C1 products. The results show that Fe, Co, Ni, and Cu have good stability. The coordination environment has a significant modulating effect on product selectivity, and the change of the number of ligand nitrogen atoms will affect the size of the potential-limiting step of each product. When the number of nitrogen ligands is the same, the different metal centers of the M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst have a significant effect on the selectivity of different products. In addition, the introduction of nitrogen atom ligands can adjust the electronic structure of the graphene-supported metal center, increase the d-band center of most metals, and improve the reaction activity.</description>
      <author>Yu Meng, Linbin Ying, Tao Ye, Ma Liang, Baoning Li, Yan Xing, Xiaoyan Liu, Yanhang Ma, Xiaodong Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the catalytic microenvironment of CuO with hydrophobic CuSA2 for selective CO2 electroreduction to C2+ products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152164</link>
      <description>Chao Wang, Xiangwen Zhang, Qingfa Wang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831521

                Advancing the Faraday efficiency (FE) and current density of Cu catalyzed electrochemical CO2 reduction (ECR) reaction to produce C2+ products is important for its practical applications. Constructing a hydrophobic interface to regulate the local reaction environment is an effective method to improve the selectivity of C2+ products, but it is limited by the low reaction current density. In this work, we fabricated a novel hydrophobic and ECR active copper stearate (CuSA2) decorated CuO nanoparticle catalyst (CuO/CuSA2) for ECR reaction toward C2+ products. As a result, the CuO/CuSA2 catalyst achieved an FE of 61.33 % and a partial current density of 429.33 mA cm&#8722;2 for C2+ products. The CuSA2 and CuO nanoparticle cooperate very well for the formation of C2+ products. The in-situ attenuated total reflectance surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy (ATR-SEIRAS) and electrochemical adsorption experiments indicated that the hydrophobic CuSA2 regulated the local ECR reaction environment. The local &#8727;CO2.- and *CO adsorption were strengthened by hydrophobic CuSA2 modification while the H2O adsorption was inhibited. CuO nanoparticle promotes *CO coupling reaction and enhances C2 intermediates (*OCCOH and *OC2H5) adsorption. Hydrophobic CuSA2 and CuO nanoparticle synergistically promote the generation of C2+ products. This work provides new insights into the design of hydrophobic CO2 reduction electrocatalysts for the preparation of C2+ products.</description>
      <author>Chao Wang, Xiangwen Zhang, Qingfa Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superlative Porous Organic Polymers for Photochemical and Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Applications: From Synthesis to Functionality</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00310</link>
      <description>Syed Asim Ali, Iqra Sadiq, Tokeer Ahmad, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789941

                To mimic the carbon cycle at a kinetically rapid pace, the sustainable conversion of omnipresent CO2 to value-added chemical feedstock and hydrocarbon fuels implies a remarkable prototype for utilizing released CO2. Porous organic polymers (POPs) have been recognized as remarkable catalytic systems for achieving large-scale applicability in energy-driven processes. POPs offer mesoporous characteristics, higher surface area, and superior optoelectronic properties that lead to their relatively advanced activity and selectivity for CO2 conversion. In comparison to the metal organic frameworks, POPs exhibit an enhanced tendency toward membrane formation, which governs their excellent stability with regard to remarkable ultrathinness and tailored pore channels. The structural ascendancy of POPs can be effectively utilized to develop cost-effective catalytic supports for energy conversion processes to leapfrog over conventional noble metal catalysts that have nonlinear techno-economic equilibrium. Herein, we precisely surveyed the functionality of POPs from scratch, classified it, and provided a critical commentary of its current methodological advancements and photo/electrochemical achievements in the CO2 reduction reaction.</description>
      <author>Syed Asim Ali, Iqra Sadiq, Tokeer Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal X-Ray Imaging of Neat and Viscosified CO2 in Displacement of Brine-Saturated Porous Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/214842-pa</link>
      <description>Boxin Ding, Apostolos Kantzas, Abbas Firoozabadi, SPE journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396769923

                Summary CO2 storage in saline aquifers may contribute to a 90% share in preventing emissions to the atmosphere. Due to low CO2 viscosity at the subsurface often found in supercritical (sc) conditions, the injected CO2 may spread quickly at the formation top and increase the probability of leakage. This work relates to improved CO2 storage in saline aquifers by effective viscosification of the sc-CO2 at very low concentrations of engineered oligomers and the effectiveness of slug injection of viscosified CO2 (vis-CO2). We present the results from X-ray computed tomography (CT) imaging to advance the understanding of two-phase CO2-brine flow in porous media and firmly establish the transport mechanisms. X-ray CT imaging of displacement experiments is conducted to quantify the in-situ sc-CO2 saturation spatiotemporally. In neat CO2 injection, gravity override and adverse mobility ratio may result in early breakthrough and low sweep efficiency. We find cumulative brine production from the fraction collector to be lower than X-ray CT imaging at 2 pore volume (PV) injection. The difference between the two is attributed to the solubility of the produced water in the produced CO2 at atmospheric pressure. We show that when the solubility is accounted for, there is a good agreement between direct measurements and in-situ saturation results. There are three reports (two by the same group) that oligomers of 1-decene (O1D) with six repeat units may have marginal CO2 viscosification. The majority of published work by other groups shows that O1D with six repeat units and higher are effective CO2 viscosifiers. In the past, we have demonstrated the effectiveness of an O1D in the displacement of brine by CO2 at a concentration of 1.5 wt%. The effectiveness is examined and identified by three different methods. In this work, we show that the same oligomer is effective at a low concentration of 0.6 wt%. The oligomer slows the breakthrough by 1.6 times and improves the brine production by 34% in the horizontal orientation. X-ray CT imaging results reveal that such a large effect may be from the increase in the interfacial elasticity. We also show that there is no need for continuous injection of the oligomer. A slug of 0.3 PV injection (PVI) of vis-CO2 followed by neat CO2 injection has the same effectiveness as the continuous injection of the vis-CO2. In this work, we also demonstrate the effectiveness of a new engineered molecule at 0.3 wt% that may increase residual trapping by about 35%. The combination of mobility control and residual brine saturation reduction is expected to improve CO2 storage by effective viscosification with low concentrations of oligomers.</description>
      <author>Boxin Ding, Apostolos Kantzas, Abbas Firoozabadi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/214842-pa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of N&#8208;propanol from CO2 Electroreduction on Bicontinuous Cu2O/Cu Nanodomains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405733</link>
      <description>Renjie Zhang, Jianling Zhang, Sha Wang, Zhonghao Tan, Yisen Yang, Yi Song, Meiling Li, Yingzhe Zhao, Hao Wang, Buxing Han, Ran Duan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396776083

                n&#8208;propanol is an important pharmaceutical and pesticide intermediate. To produce n&#8208;propanol by electrochemical reduction of CO2 is a promising way, but is largely restricted by the very low selectivity and activity. How to promote the coupling of *C1 and *C2 intermediates to form the *C3 intermediate for n&#8208;propanol formation is challenging. Here, we propose the construction of bicontinuous structure of Cu2O/Cu electrocatalyst, which consists of ultra&#8208;small Cu2O nanodomains, Cu nanodomains and large amounts of grain boundaries between Cu2O and Cu nanodomains. The n&#8208;propanol current density is as high as 101.6 mA cm&#8722;2 at the applied potential of &#8722;1.1 V vs. reversible hydrogen electrode in flow cell, with the Faradaic efficiency up to 12.1%. Moreover, the catalyst keeps relatively stable during electrochemical CO2 reduction process. Experimental studies and theoretical calculations reveal that the bicontinuous structure of Cu2O/Cu can facilitate the *CO formation, *CO&#8208;*CO coupling and *CO&#8208;*OCCO coupling for the final generation of n&#8208;propanol.</description>
      <author>Renjie Zhang, Jianling Zhang, Sha Wang, Zhonghao Tan, Yisen Yang, Yi Song, Meiling Li, Yingzhe Zhao, Hao Wang, Buxing Han, Ran Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of N&#8208;propanol from CO2 Electroreduction on Bicontinuous Cu2O/Cu Nanodomains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405733</link>
      <description>Renjie Zhang, Jianling Zhang, Sha Wang, Zhonghao Tan, Yisen Yang, Yi Song, Meiling Li, Yingzhe Zhao, Hao Wang, Buxing Han, Ran Duan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396776093

                n&#8208;propanol is an important pharmaceutical and pesticide intermediate. To produce n&#8208;propanol by electrochemical reduction of CO2 is a promising way, but is largely restricted by the very low selectivity and activity. How to promote the coupling of *C1 and *C2 intermediates to form the *C3 intermediate for n&#8208;propanol formation is challenging. Here, we propose the construction of bicontinuous structure of Cu2O/Cu electrocatalyst, which consists of ultra&#8208;small Cu2O nanodomains, Cu nanodomains and large amounts of grain boundaries between Cu2O and Cu nanodomains. The n&#8208;propanol current density is as high as 101.6 mA cm&#8722;2 at the applied potential of &#8722;1.1 V vs. reversible hydrogen electrode in flow cell, with the Faradaic efficiency up to 12.1%. Moreover, the catalyst keeps relatively stable during electrochemical CO2 reduction process. Experimental studies and theoretical calculations reveal that the bicontinuous structure of Cu2O/Cu can facilitate the *CO formation, *CO&#8208;*CO coupling and *CO&#8208;*OCCO coupling for the final generation of n&#8208;propanol.</description>
      <author>Renjie Zhang, Jianling Zhang, Sha Wang, Zhonghao Tan, Yisen Yang, Yi Song, Meiling Li, Yingzhe Zhao, Hao Wang, Buxing Han, Ran Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate Bayesian Optimization of CoO Nanoparticles for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03789</link>
      <description>Lanja R. Karadaghi, Emily M. Williamson, Anh T. To, Allison P. Forsberg, Kyle D. Crans, Craig L. Perkins, Steven C. Hayden, Nicole J. Libretto, Frederick G. Baddour, Daniel A. Ruddy, Noah Malmstadt, Susan E. Habas, Richard L. Brutchey, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396792274

                The hydrogenation of CO2 holds promise for transforming the production of renewable fuels and chemicals. However, the challenge lies in developing robust and selective catalysts for this process. Transition metal oxide catalysts, particularly cobalt oxide, have shown potential for CO2 hydrogenation, with performance heavily reliant on crystal phase and morphology. Achieving precise control over these catalyst attributes through colloidal nanoparticle synthesis could pave the way for catalyst and process advancement. Yet, navigating the complexities of colloidal nanoparticle syntheses, governed by numerous input variables, poses a significant challenge in systematically controlling resultant catalyst features. We present a multivariate Bayesian optimization, coupled with a data-driven classifier, to map the synthetic design space for colloidal CoO nanoparticles and simultaneously optimize them for multiple catalytically relevant features within a target crystalline phase. The optimized experimental conditions yielded small, phase-pure rock salt CoO nanoparticles of uniform size and shape. These optimized nanoparticles were then supported on SiO2 and assessed for thermocatalytic CO2 hydrogenation against larger, polydisperse CoO nanoparticles on SiO2 and a conventionally prepared catalyst. The optimized CoO/SiO2 catalyst consistently exhibited higher activity and CH4 selectivity (ca. 98%) across various pretreatment reduction temperatures as compared to the other catalysts. This remarkable performance was attributed to particle stability and consistent H* surface coverage, even after undergoing the highest temperature reduction, achieving a more stable catalytic species that resists sintering and carbon occlusion.</description>
      <author>Lanja R. Karadaghi, Emily M. Williamson, Anh T. To, Allison P. Forsberg, Kyle D. Crans, Craig L. Perkins, Steven C. Hayden, Nicole J. Libretto, Frederick G. Baddour, Daniel A. Ruddy, Noah Malmstadt, Susan E. Habas, Richard L. Brutchey</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Interfacial ZnO-Cu Nanocomposites in Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Derived Catalysts: Enhancement of Catalytic Activity for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00805</link>
      <description>Jiaxing Chen, XU Wan-yin, Hao Zhang, Junkuo Gao, Wenxin Lin, Qianqian Li, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396805597

                The nanointerfaces of ZnO-Cu and the size of active nanoparticles (NPs) play crucial roles in the development process of CO2 hydrogenation. Herein, Zn-PBC80 with an unsaturated coordination Zn2+ center was constructed from Zn(NO3)2&#183;6H2O and 3,5-bis(4&#8242;-carboxyl-phenyl) pyridine (H2PBC), serving as an anchoring site for supporting Cu2+ and a platform for encapsulating NPs. The different loading concentrations of Cu2+ and pyrolysis of the MOFs-based precursor vary the chemical environments of the catalysts, resulting in different distributed states and average sizes of active sites. Specifically, the pyrolysis of Zn-PBC80-Cu-1 with a concentration ratio of 1:1 facilitates the construction of an interfacial ZnO-Cu nanocomposite and smaller NP size. Among a series of CO2 catalysts, the resultant ZnO-Cu-1-700 exhibits the best catalytic performance with a satisfying CO2 conversion rate (16.5%), outstanding CO selectivity (100%), and promoting catalytic stability over 30 h. The best catalytic performance could be attributed to the more stable electronic structure of metallic Cu NPs and the generation of oxygen vacancies resulting from the unique ZnO-Cu nanointerfaces among the catalysts. This discrepancy in catalytic performance indicates that the active nanointerfaces affects the electronic structure of active centers, providing valuable insight into the design of efficient catalysts for CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Jiaxing Chen, XU Wan-yin, Hao Zhang, Junkuo Gao, Wenxin Lin, Qianqian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decarbonization through Smart Energy Management: Climate Control in Building-Integrated Rooftop Greenhouses for Urban Agriculture Across Various Climate Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142544</link>
      <description>Wei-Han Chen, Fengqi You, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396826394

                This paper investigates the potential benefits of integrating rooftop greenhouses (RTGs) with buildings to reduce energy and CO2 costs, contributing to urban decarbonization efforts. This integration not only advances sustainable urban agriculture but also aligns with the United Nations Sustainable Development Goal 7 (SDG7) - Affordable and Clean Energy, and Sustainable Development Goal 11 (SDG11) - Sustainable Cities and Communities, through its energy-efficient, low-carbon approach. We hypothesize that this integration can significantly lower energy use in integrated RTGs (i-RTGs) and set out to validate this through dynamic models for both building and i-RTG climates, focusing on CO2 concentration, humidity, and temperature. Central to our approach is the implementation of a nonlinear model predictive control (NMPC) framework, which utilizes these dynamic models to make control decisions aimed at minimizing total control costs. This framework operates in a receding horizon procedure, regulating climate factors within the i-RTG and building using various actuators. We validate our approach by simulating an i-RTG atop a building in eleven different cities, demonstrating interactions such as energy, moisture, and CO2 exchange. Significantly, our study reveals that integrating i-RTG with buildings under the NMPC framework leads to a 15.2% reduction in control costs. Additionally, we find that the i-RTG model is adaptable to different climates, with colder regions showing greater cost reduction potential. Our study underscores the viability and advantages of integrating i-RTGs with buildings, offering a sustainable, decarbonizing solution for urban agriculture and building management that contributes to the fulfillment of SDG7 and SDG11.</description>
      <author>Wei-Han Chen, Fengqi You</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142544</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Polysaccharide-based Biodegradable Soft Polymers in the Healthcare Sector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aiepr.2024.05.001</link>
      <description>Zia Ullah Arif, Advanced industrial and engineering polymer research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834781

                Bio-based polymers have garnered significant interest across the manufacturing industry, global economy, and various engineering disciplines such as packaging, tissue engineering, controlled drug delivery, wound dressing, and textiles. In the current era, bio-based polymers, notably polysaccharides, offer a promising platform for constructing intricate and versatile structures in the biomedical sector. These structures encompass applications in tissue engineering and regenerative medicine (TERM), drug delivery devices, coatings for biomedical devices, and wearable sensors, thanks to their distinctive features such as inherent biocompatibility, flexibility, stretchability, mechanical strength, renewability, physiological activity, and favorable biological environment. In this review, we offer a concise overview of diverse types of polysaccharide-based polymers and their composites, properties, and interactions with specific cells and tissues. The review encompasses recent progress in tissue scaffolds designed for cartilage, skin, neural, vascular, cardiac, and bone regeneration, employing both conventional and modern manufacturing techniques. Additionally, it delves into the development of other biodegradable biomedical devices, including drug delivery systems (DDSs), antibacterial coatings on medical devices, wearable sensors, and electronic devices for the healthcare sector. Furthermore, it also elucidates research directions and future perspectives while emphasizing the importance of regulatory approvals and commitment to environmental sustainability. This well-organized and critical review is expected to assist practitioners and researchers in gaining a deeper understanding of current trends, challenges, and potential solutions, thereby harnessing the immense potential of polysaccharide-based biomaterials in the healthcare system. Additionally, the utilization of polysaccharides in the biomedical sector aligns with principles of nature, contributing to the reduction of carbon dioxide emissions and supporting the Sustainable Development Goals of the United Nations.</description>
      <author>Zia Ullah Arif</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aiepr.2024.05.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Chemical Looping Combustion in the Graz Power Cycle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102334</link>
      <description>Carlos Arnaiz del Pozo, Susana S&#225;nchez Orgaz, Alberto Navarro-Calvo, &#193;ngel Jim&#233;nez &#193;lvaro, Schalk Cloete, Energies. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857828

                : Effective decarbonization of the power generation sector requires a multi-pronged approach, including the implementation of CO2 capture and storage (CCS) technologies. The Graz cycle features oxy-combustion CO2 capture in a power production scheme which can result in higher thermal efficiencies than that of a combined cycle. However, the auxiliary consumption required by the air separation unit to provide pure O2 results in a significant energy penalty relative to an unabated plant. In order to mitigate this penalty, the present study explores the possibility of chemical looping combustion (CLC) as an alternative means to supply oxygen for conversion of the fuel. For a midscale power plant, despite reducing the levelized cost of electricity (LCOE) by approximately 12.6% at a CO2 tax of EUR 100/ton and a natural gas price of EUR 6.5/GJ and eliminating the energy penalty of CCS relative to an unabated combined cycle, the cost reductions of CLC in the Graz cycle were not compelling relative to commercially available post-combustion CO2 capture with amines. Although the central assumptions yielded a 3% lower cost for the Graz-CLC cycle, an uncertainty quantification study revealed an 85.3% overlap in the interquartile LCOE range with that of the amine benchmark, indicating that the potential economic benefit is small compared to the uncertainty of the assessment. Thus, this study indicates that the potential of CLC in gas-fired power production is limited, even when considering highly efficient advanced configurations like the Graz cycle.</description>
      <author>Carlos Arnaiz del Pozo, Susana S&#225;nchez Orgaz, Alberto Navarro-Calvo, &#193;ngel Jim&#233;nez &#193;lvaro, Schalk Cloete</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turbulent Rayleigh&#8211;B&#233;nard convection in a supercritical &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si132.svg" display="inline" id="d1e3622"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;CO&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;-based binary mixture with cross-diffusion effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2024.125648</link>
      <description>Xiao Ma, Rin Yun, Jun Yang, Zhan-Chao Hu, International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer/International journal of heat and mass transfer. 228(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396842080

                CO2-based binary mixtures are promising in energy engineering to improve efficiencies of thermodynamic cycles where supercritical CO2 prevails. Indeed, under supercritical pressure and transcritical temperature conditions, special thermophysical properties of binary mixtures make the heat transfer process accompanied by enhanced cross-diffusion effects, i.e., the Soret effect and the Dufour effect. Their influences on heat transfer have not been well understood yet. This paper numerically investigates turbulent Rayleigh&#8211;B&#233;nard convection in CO2-C2H6 binary mixture. Calculations are performed based on a spectral element method solver considering various temperature differences and pressures. Results indicate that the flow field presents a double-vortex structure. The thickness of the boundary layer is negatively correlated with the flow intensity. Under a positive separation ratio, the concentration gradient induced by cross-diffusion effects enhances buoyancy, which in turn reinforces the natural convection and heat transfer. The enhancement becomes stronger as the critical pressure is approached. Turbulent fluctuations are also strengthened by cross-diffusion effects, except for temperature fluctuations. The unusual reduction in temperature fluctuations is attributed to the increased size of the thermal plume caused by the Dufour effect.</description>
      <author>Xiao Ma, Rin Yun, Jun Yang, Zhan-Chao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2024.125648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A medium-entropy engineered double perovskite oxide for efficient and CO2-tolerant cathode of solid oxide fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e00969</link>
      <description>Zhe Wang, Jingwei Li, Mengke Yuan, Juntao Gao, Hongru Hao, Abdalla M. Abdalla, Leilei Xu, Zhe Lv, Bo Wei, Sustainable materials and technologies. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396874054

                Developing highly active and robust cathodes remains challenging for solid oxide fuel cells (SOFCs). Therefore, we report an A-site medium-entropy double perovskite oxide PrBa0.5Sr0.25Ca0.2Ce0.05Co2O5+&#948; (PBSCCC) and its electrocatalytic activity and CO2 tolerance property are systematically probed. The PBSCCC cathode exhibits excellent oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity with a low polarization resistance of 0.027 &#937; cm2 at 700 &#176;C. More importantly, compared to PrBaCo2O5+&#948; (PBC) and PrBa0.8Ca0.2Co2O5+&#948; (PBCC) oxides, its CO2 resistance is prominently enhanced with significantly less BaCO3 and Co3O4 impurities formed. The superior ORR performance and structure stability are mainly attributed to its high electrical conductivity and significantly reduced surface cation segregations. Our results show that the potential of PBSCCC as a cathode material for SOFCs is enormous and also prove the rationality and feasibility of entropy engineering for cathode development.</description>
      <author>Zhe Wang, Jingwei Li, Mengke Yuan, Juntao Gao, Hongru Hao, Abdalla M. Abdalla, Leilei Xu, Zhe Lv, Bo Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e00969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Political Stability in Nine Arab Natural Resource-Abundant Countries (ANRAC) Toward Environmental Sustainability through CO2 Mitigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.15346</link>
      <description>Omed Rafiq Fatah, Hatem Hatef Abdulkadh&#305;m Altaee, International journal of energy economics and policy. 14(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720207

                This study examines the intricate interplay of political stability, natural resource rent, industrialization, globalization, economic growth, and carbon emissions in nine Arab resource-abundant countries (ANRAC) from 1996 to 2019. Applying advanced statistical approaches, such as the Method of Moment Quantiles Regression (MMQREG) as a baseline estimation approach, along with the inclusion of PCSE, FGLS, and FMOLS, to enhance, to enhance the reliability and stability of the obtained results. The study results suggest that globalization, coupled with the interplay between political stability and economic growth, fosters advancements in environmental conditions and the pursuit of sustainable practices. In contrast, political stability, abundant natural resources, sustained economic expansion, and widespread industrialization are associated with increased CO2 emissions, posing detrimental effects on the environment. Notably, there seems to be a correlation between the concurrent improvement of political stability and economic growth and a reduction in CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>Omed Rafiq Fatah, Hatem Hatef Abdulkadh&#305;m Altaee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.15346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the techno-economic feasibility of hydrogen-fuelled reciprocating engines for renewable base-load power generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118515</link>
      <description>Jiayi Li, Zhaoyang Dong, Guanxiong Zhai, Qiyuan Li, Shen Hin Lim, Shiva Abdoli, Sanghoon Kook, Guan Heng Yeoh, Qing Nian Chan, Energy conversion and management. 311(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396842818

                This study investigates the techno-economic feasibility of a photovoltaic power plant integrated with hydrogen energy storage and a dual-fuel reciprocating engine for gas-to-power and power-to-gas operations. The system is optimised for maximising constant grid supply, minimising CO2 emissions, and lowering the levelised cost of electricity (LCOE) to assess its value in future energy landscape. Multi-objective optimisation identified a configuration with a hydrogen-fuelled engine generator offering a constant 10 MW grid supply with minimal CO2 emissions (78 kg/MWh), at a LCOE of $335.52/MWh. This system comprises a 93 MW PEM electrolyser, a 4 MW compressor, and 29 t of compressed hydrogen storage, within the limits of the industry's current or projected capacities. A key highlight of the engine-based approach is its ability to readily enhance grid supply through increased diesel consumption without significantly impacting LCOE, provided CO2 emissions stay within acceptable sector cap. This flexibility surpasses alternative technologies. Further analysis explored potential LCOE reductions using global projected data, bringing optimised LCOE values down to $138.76/MWh, making it competitive to current market prices. Sensitivity analysis revealed the LCOE's highest sensitivity to the discount rate, followed by minimal impact from variations in fuel and electricity prices due to the optimised system configuration. Furthermore, the tightening CO2 emission limits do not affect the optimised system's performance, except for limiting the maximum achievable grid supply in 2050 by increased diesel reliance.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Li, Zhaoyang Dong, Guanxiong Zhai, Qiyuan Li, Shen Hin Lim, Shiva Abdoli, Sanghoon Kook, Guan Heng Yeoh, Qing Nian Chan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Woody Biomass Ash Material in Immobilization of Cadmium, Lead and Zinc in Soil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102206</link>
      <description>El&#380;bieta Rolka, Miros&#322;aw Wyszkowski, Andrzej Cezary &#379;o&#322;nowski, Anna Skorwider-Namiotko, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396733890

                Nowadays, we have observed the dynamic development of bio-heating plants that use wood biomass for heating or energy purposes. The result of this process is a reduction in carbon dioxide emissions as well as in the production of biomass ash (BA). Despite the waste nature of BA, it should be carefully analyzed and assessed for various applications, including environmental ones. Due to the features attributed to BA, including its alkaline reaction, the high capacity of its sorption complex, relatively low salinity, and significant content of macro- and microelements, a hypothesis was put forward in this work undertaken about the positive role of BA as an immobilizing factor for Cd-, Pb-, and Zn-contaminated soils. This research was based on a pot experiment in which four series were considered: (1) BA; (2) BA + Cd; (3) BA + Pb; and (4) BA + Zn. BA was used at doses of 30, 60, and 90 mg pot&#8722;1, and metals at doses of 2 mg Cd, 100 mg Pb, and 300 mg Zn kg&#8722;1 of soil. The test plant was corn grown for green mass. The study took into account the influence of BA on the content of the total forms of heavy metals (Metot) and their available forms (Meav). In the soil without the addition of metals, a significant increase in the content of Cdtot and Cdav, and a decrease in the content of Zntot were observed due to the application of BA. The addition of metals against the background of the BA used resulted in a significant increase in Cdtot, Pbtot, and Zntot, as well as an increase in the available forms of Pbav but a decrease in Znav. However, there was no significant increase in the Cdav content. The obtained results may indicate the potentially immobilizing role of BA only in the case of zinc. They may constitute the basis for further, more detailed research aimed at determining the role of BA in the immobilization of various metals in soil.</description>
      <author>El&#380;bieta Rolka, Miros&#322;aw Wyszkowski, Andrzej Cezary &#379;o&#322;nowski, Anna Skorwider-Namiotko</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valorizing inherent resources from waste streams for in-situ CO2 capture and sequestration in the steel industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142486</link>
      <description>Yuan Meng, Xiaohong Zhu, Yuying Zhang, Yilin Su, Fulin Qu, Chi Sun Poon, Jun Yan, Daniel C.W. Tsang, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830133

                The imperative need for decarbonization within the energy-intensive steel industry, a pivotal sector for meeting global warming mitigation targets, underscores the significance of deploying cost-effective CO2 capture and sequestration (CCS) measures. The substantial external costs and resource consumption associated with traditional CCS methods present practical challenges. Here, we proposed a pragmatic strategy to integrate CCS into the steel industry through recycling inherent resources from steelmaking waste streams for in-situ CCS (ICCS). The composites prepared from blast furnace slag (BFS) and steel slag (SS) demonstrated the capacity to capture a maximum of 2.77 mol/kg of CO2 from the simulated flowing flue gas at 75 &#176;C, and the energy required could be sourced from steelmaking waste heat. Comprehensive characterizations revealed the evolution of phase compositions and pore structures in different BFS/SS-incorporated composites, providing insights into accelerating the carbonation by elevating temperatures and SS dosages. Notably, ICCS strategy was validated to offer significant potential in CO2 emission reduction (up to &#8722;570.0 kg CO2e/t) normalized by compressive strength of the conventional construction materials. Overall, ICCS strategy can minimize the external resource consumption and additional units for implementing collaborative waste recycling in the steel industry with significant environmental benefits.</description>
      <author>Yuan Meng, Xiaohong Zhu, Yuying Zhang, Yilin Su, Fulin Qu, Chi Sun Poon, Jun Yan, Daniel C.W. Tsang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Corn Cob Gasification as a Low-Carbon Technology in the Corn Flour Industry in Mexico</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102256</link>
      <description>Fabio Manzini, Jorge M. Islas-Samperio, Genice K. Grande-Acosta, Energies. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396722025

                In 2021, Mexico produced approximately 24.2 million tons of white corn, generating 3.6 million tons of corn cob residue. The final disposal of corn cob poses an environmental challenge in certain regions. This study examines the technical&#8211;economic feasibility and the greenhouse gas (GHG) mitigation potential of integrating a small-scale cogenerating gasifier fueled by corn cob into a nixtamalized corn flour manufacturing small and medium-sized enterprise (SME). This integration enables the generation of heat and electricity from the produced synthesis gas. Moreover, the process yields residual carbon, which can be used as biochar for soil restoration and removing atmospheric CO2. This option holds significance for the corn flour agroindustry in Mexico, as, in 2021, it consumed approximately 601.9 GWh of electrical energy and 938,279 GJ of thermal energy from LP Gas in its manufacturing processes to produce 2.6 million tons of nixtamalized white corn flour. These processes contributed to a total emission of 410,232 tons of CO2 into the atmosphere. The findings of this study demonstrate a cumulative reduction of 51.7% in CO2 emissions, resulting in economic benefits of USD 85,401 in 2017 for a case study SME that annually produces 1039 tons of corn flour. This study reveals the integration of a gasifier&#8211;cogenerator system fueled by corn cob as an economically viable low-carbon technology in the corn flour manufacturing industry.</description>
      <author>Fabio Manzini, Jorge M. Islas-Samperio, Genice K. Grande-Acosta</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Cu&lt;sup&gt;0&lt;/sup&gt;/Cu&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Interface Promotes Acidic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01516</link>
      <description>Yunling Jiang, Haobo Li, Chaojie Chen, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396873077

                Acidic CO2 electroreduction reaction (CO2RR) shows advantages in high carbon utilization efficiency yet encounters great challenges in suppressing undesired hydrogen evolution competition and increasing C2+ product selectivity. Although it is known that Cu0/Cu+ interfaces are conducive to C&#8211;C coupling processes, the oxidation state of copper cannot be well maintained under the strong reductive condition and large current electrolysis operation. Herein, we propose an I2 addition involved strategy to protect the oxidation state of Cu and promote dynamic Cu0/Cu+ interfaces during acidic CO2RR. With the addition of I2 in the electrolyte, a high C2+ product Faraday efficiency of above 70% can be achieved at 0.4&#8211;0.6 A cm&#8211;2 even under a low K+ concentration of 0.3 M, which is comparable to those reported performances with almost ten times higher K+ concentrations (2&#8211;3 M). This low K+ concentration in electrolytes significantly avoids salt crystallization in the CO2 transport channel to enhance the electrolyzer's stability. As proved by the surface Pourbaix diagram and experimental results, adding excessive I2 into the electrolyte boosts the generation of CuI; also, CuI and metallic Cu coexist under electrochemical reduction conditions, demonstrating that a redox loop of Cu &#8594; CuI &#8594; Cu exists. The loop holds the key to constructing the dynamic Cu0/Cu+ interface, which is tightly bound to the adsorption of the *CO reaction intermediate and further promotes the C&#8211;C coupling process.</description>
      <author>Yunling Jiang, Haobo Li, Chaojie Chen, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of elevation feedbacks and climate mitigation on future Greenland ice sheet melt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1126</link>
      <description>Thirza Nadine Feenstra, Miren Vizca&#237;no, Bert Wouters, Michele Petrini, Raymond Sellevold, Katherine Thayer&#8208;Calder, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396865280

                Abstract. The Greenland Ice Sheet (GrIS) stores freshwater equal to more than seven meters of potential sea level rise and strongly interacts with the Arctic, North Atlantic and global climate. Over the last decades, the GrIS has been losing mass and is projected to lose mass at an increasing rate. Interactions between the GrIS and the climate have the potential to amplify or reduce GrIS mass balance responses to ongoing and projected warming. Here, we investigate the impact of ice sheet-climate interactions on the climate and mass balance of the GrIS using the Community Ice Sheet Model version 2 coupled to the Community Earth System Model version 2 (CESM2-CISM2). To this end, we compare two idealized simulations with a nonevolving and evolving ice sheet topography in which we apply an annual 1 % increase in CO2 concentrations until stabilization at four times pre-industrial (PI) CO2 concentrations (4xCO2). By comparing the 1- and 2-way coupled simulations, we find significant changes in atmospheric blocking, precipitation and cloud formation over Greenland as the GrIS topography evolves, acting as negative feedbacks on mass loss. We also find that a uniform temperature lapse rate represents temperature changes in the ablation area, leading to an overestimation of the positive melt-elevation feedback in the 1-way coupled simulation, resulting in an overestimation of mass loss. Furthermore, we analyze an idealized simulation in which we first apply a 4xPI CO2 forcing and thereafter annually reduce atmospheric CO2 by 5 % until PI concentrations are reached. During the 350 year 4xCO2 forcing period, the ice sheet loses a total mass of 1.1 m sea level equivalent, and part of its margins retreat landward. When the PI CO2 concentration is restored, melt decreases rapidly, leading to a small positive surface mass balance. Combined with the strongly reduced ice discharge resulting from the widespread retreat of the ice sheet margin, this results in the halting of GrIS mass loss, despite a remaining global warming of 2 K. The GrIS, Arctic and North Atlantic ocean strongly interact, causing a complex transitional phase towards a colder climate during the century following the CO2 reduction. Elevated atmospheric temperatures, larger ocean heat transport and a deteriorated state of the snowpack, compared to the initial pre-industrial state, result in limited regrowth of the ice sheet under reintroduced PI CO2 conditions.</description>
      <author>Thirza Nadine Feenstra, Miren Vizca&#237;no, Bert Wouters, Michele Petrini, Raymond Sellevold, Katherine Thayer&#8208;Calder</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New approach to reduce carbon emissions by hydrogen reduction of boron-bearing iron concentrate in a fluidized bed: Reduction kinetics and microstructure analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mineng.2024.108727</link>
      <description>Peiyu Li, Jianwen Yu, Yanjun Li, Peng Gao, Yuexin Han, Minerals engineering. 212(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396757611

                Iron ore reduction using hydrogen instead of coal is a promising technology for minimizing CO2 emissions in the metallurgical industry. In this study, the hydrogen reduction mechanism and kinetics of boron-bearing iron concentrate were investigated in a fluidized bed at 650 &#8764; 850 &#176;C, and the reduction data were quantified with an online gas composition analysis technique. The kinetics parameters were calculated using the model-free method and conventional kinetics model, and the mineral phase composition and micromorphology characteristics of reduced products were analyzed. The results showed that the reduction process of boron-bearing iron concentrate in a fluidized bed can be divided into two periods, with the earlier period was controlled by the spherical shrinking model and the later period was controlled by the three-dimensional diffusion model, and the apparent activation energy was significantly increased from 65.22 kJ/mol to 96.11 kJ/mol. Firstly, the magnetite was rapidly reduced to w&#252;stite and dense metallic iron. With an increase in the thickness of the metallic iron layer, the diffusion of oxygen through the dense iron became the rate-limiting step of the reaction, and the defects within the iron layer played a pivotal role in the following mass transfer process. However, the reduction of ludwigite did not suffer from this restriction since the dense product layer was absent.</description>
      <author>Peiyu Li, Jianwen Yu, Yanjun Li, Peng Gao, Yuexin Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mineng.2024.108727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Floating solar power plant planning based on electricity price fluctuations in Towuti, south Sulawesi</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30574/wjaets.2024.12.1.0159</link>
      <description>Joas Kurnianto, Hery Suliantoro, World Journal of Advanced Engineering Technology and Sciences. 12(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396738288

                A company located in South Sulawesi, intends to mitigate emissions from the Power Plant by constructing an environmentally friendly alternative, namely the Floating Solar Power Plant (FSPP), in Towuti. The development plan involves a feasibility analysis for each configuration of the FSPP, considering technological, economic, and environmental criteria. The selection of the preferred configuration is determined using the Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP) method, based on input from experts. According to this method, the chosen configuration is the on-grid non-battery Floating Solar Power Plant, with a Net Present Value of Rp. 1,431,159,245,752, an Internal Rate of Return of 9.46%, a Payback Period of 8.916 years, a Profitability Ind ex of 1.299, a system efficiency of 21.56%, a carbon footprint of 35,003 kg CO2, and an emission reduction of 9,136,808,273 kg CO2. Decision analysis, involving open and abandonment scenarios based on fluctuations in industrial electricity prices, was conducted using Monte Carlo simulation, yielding a volatility value of 31.2%. The real options analysis recommends abandonment in the twentieth year, with a decision success potential of 38%, based on the results.</description>
      <author>Joas Kurnianto, Hery Suliantoro</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30574/wjaets.2024.12.1.0159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Continuous Plug-Flow Anaerobic-Multistage Anoxic/Aerobic Process Treating Low-C/N Domestic Sewage: Nutrient Removal, Greenhouse Gas Emissions, and Microbial Community Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16103993</link>
      <description>Yunlong Xie, Wenlong Zhang, Jie Jiang, Yi Li, L. Tong, Guang&#8208;Yu Yang, Sustainability. 16(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396798629

                The anaerobic-multistage anoxic/aerobic (A-MAO) process has shown good potential for advanced nitrogen removal in recent years, but its greenhouse gas emissions still need to be fully explored. The effects of the influent distribution and external carbon source sodium acetate on nutrient removal, greenhouse gas emissions, and the microbial community structure in a continuous plug-flow A-MAO reactor fed with real low C/N ratio domestic sewage were investigated. The results showed that altering the allocation of carbon source resulted in average chemical oxygen demand (COD) and total nitrogen (TN) concentration in effluent reduced to 26.10 &#177; 4.86 and 6.65 &#177; 1.73 mg/L, respectively. Both operations reduced the emission rate of greenhouse gas. While the addition of external car-bon sources leaded to lower N2O emission rates and higher CO2 and CH4 emission rates. The addition of sodium acetate facilitated nitrification and denitrification processes, thereby leading to a reduction in N2O production. Meanwhile, it spurred the growth of methanogenic bacteria and heterotrophic microorganisms, thus boosting the production of CO2 and CH4. Influent distribution promoted the increase of Bacteroidota, Chloroflexi and Acidobacteriota of the reactor. The enrichment of typical hydrolytic bacteria and glycogen accumulating organisms (GAOs) increased the utilization efficiency of carbon sources in the system after the addition of sodium acetate. The significant increase of typical denitrifying bacteria (DNBs) Azospira reduced the N2O emission during heterotrophic denitrification process, which was considered to be an important functional genus for increasing nitrogen loss in this system. The rational utilization of carbon source makes the difference in metabolism function. The study provides a valuable strategy for comprehensively evaluating the pollutant removal and greenhouse gas emission reduction from the A-MAO process.</description>
      <author>Yunlong Xie, Wenlong Zhang, Jie Jiang, Yi Li, L. Tong, Guang&#8208;Yu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16103993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascaded *CO&#8208;*COH Intermediates on a Nonmetallic Plasmonic Photocatalyst for CO2&#8208;to&#8208;C2H6 with 90.6% Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202404660</link>
      <description>Liteng Ren, Xiaonan Yang, Xin Sun, Yuling Wang, Huiquan Li, Yupeng Yuan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396730937

                Oxygen vacancies (OV) in nonmetallic plasmonic photocatalysts can decrease the energy barrier for CO2 reduction, boosting C1 intermediate production for potential C2 formation. However, their susceptibility to oxidation weakens C1 intermediate adsorption. Herein we proposed a "photoelectron injection" strategy to safeguard OV in W18O49 by creating a W18O49/ZIS (W/Z) plasmonic photocatalyst. Moreover, photoelectrons contribute to the local multi&#8208;electron environment of W18O49, enhancing the intrinsic excitation of its hot electrons with extended lifetimes, as confirmed by in&#8208;situ XPS and femtosecond transient absorption analysis. Density functional theory calculations revealed that W/Z with Ov enhances CO2 adsorption, activating *CO production, while reducing the energy barrier for *COH production (0.054 eV) and subsequent *CO&#8208;COH coupling (0.574 eV). Successive hydrogenation revealed that the free energy for *CH2CH2 hydrogenation (0.108 eV) was lower than that for *CH2CH2 desorption for C2H4 production (0.277 eV), favouring C2H6 production. Consequently, W/Z achieves an efficient C2H6 activity of 653.6 &#956;mol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1 under visible light, with an exceptionally high selectivity of 90.6%. This work offers a new strategy for the rational design of plasmonic photocatalysts with high selectivity for C2+ products.</description>
      <author>Liteng Ren, Xiaonan Yang, Xin Sun, Yuling Wang, Huiquan Li, Yupeng Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202404660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascaded *CO&#8208;*COH Intermediates on a Nonmetallic Plasmonic Photocatalyst for CO2&#8208;to&#8208;C2H6 with 90.6% Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202404660</link>
      <description>Liteng Ren, Xiaonan Yang, Xin Sun, Yuling Wang, Huiquan Li, Yupeng Yuan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396743018

                Oxygen vacancies (OV) in nonmetallic plasmonic photocatalysts can decrease the energy barrier for CO2 reduction, boosting C1 intermediate production for potential C2 formation. However, their susceptibility to oxidation weakens C1 intermediate adsorption. Herein we proposed a "photoelectron injection" strategy to safeguard OV in W18O49 by creating a W18O49/ZIS (W/Z) plasmonic photocatalyst. Moreover, photoelectrons contribute to the local multi&#8208;electron environment of W18O49, enhancing the intrinsic excitation of its hot electrons with extended lifetimes, as confirmed by in&#8208;situ XPS and femtosecond transient absorption analysis. Density functional theory calculations revealed that W/Z with Ov enhances CO2 adsorption, activating *CO production, while reducing the energy barrier for *COH production (0.054 eV) and subsequent *CO&#8208;COH coupling (0.574 eV). Successive hydrogenation revealed that the free energy for *CH2CH2 hydrogenation (0.108 eV) was lower than that for *CH2CH2 desorption for C2H4 production (0.277 eV), favouring C2H6 production. Consequently, W/Z achieves an efficient C2H6 activity of 653.6 &#956;mol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1 under visible light, with an exceptionally high selectivity of 90.6%. This work offers a new strategy for the rational design of plasmonic photocatalysts with high selectivity for C2+ products.</description>
      <author>Liteng Ren, Xiaonan Yang, Xin Sun, Yuling Wang, Huiquan Li, Yupeng Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202404660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of the Efficiency of a Hybrid Photovoltaic and Photovoltaic Heating System (PV&#8211;Solar) in the Context of a Warehouse for a Housing Community in Poland</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102264</link>
      <description>Andrzej Gawlik, Marcin Nowakowski, Marcin Rabe, Dariusz Rajchel, Yuriy Bilan, Agnieszka &#321;opatka, Jurgita Martinkiene, Serhiy Kozmenko, Energies. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396747011

                In light of global challenges such as the war in Ukraine and the depletion of fossil fuel resources, it is essential to explore sustainable energy solutions. Hybrid energy systems represent a potential solution, offering energy independence to urban housing estates and reducing CO2 emissions. This article aims to explore the feasibility of integrating photovoltaic systems (utilizing vacuum collectors) and combined utilities (system heat and electricity) in a hybrid setup, leveraging existing technical infrastructure with necessary modifications. A key aspect is to perform calculations on the amount of heat and electricity generated from these systems. The study analyzes the demand for heat and electricity among consumers compared to the estimated production from renewable sources. Calculations also include the potential energy savings and CO2 emission reductions achievable through the proposed solutions. The findings indicate that hybrid photovoltaic systems with heat storage could effectively address energy issues in urban housing estates, given adequate support and community involvement. The innovative methodology employed in this study encompasses both analytical and experimental research approaches. The analysis employs advanced statistical techniques and data integration to enhance understanding of the phenomena studied, while the experimental research provides robust results through controlled variable manipulation and precise measurement tools, thereby verifying the study&#8217;s objectives.</description>
      <author>Andrzej Gawlik, Marcin Nowakowski, Marcin Rabe, Dariusz Rajchel, Yuriy Bilan, Agnieszka &#321;opatka, Jurgita Martinkiene, Serhiy Kozmenko</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Reaction Pathways of Ethylene Carbonate and Vinylene Carbonate in Li-Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00927</link>
      <description>Robin Lundstr&#246;m, Neeha Gogoi, Tim Melin, Erik J. Berg, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396779943

                Ethylene carbonate (EC) and vinylene carbonate (VC) are the archetypical electrolyte solvent and additive in Li-ion batteries (LIBs), respectively. However, our understanding of their reaction pathways remains incomplete. Herein, the reaction pathways of EC and VC are explored by using online electrochemical mass spectrometry complemented by nuclear magnetic resonance analysis. For EC, reduction occurs through two distinct pathways &lt;0.8 V vs Li+/Li, one yielding C2H4 and the other yielding CO, depending on the electrode potential and the EC concentration. The CO-releasing pathway does not contribute to the solid electrolyte interphase formation. For VC, reduction commences at &lt;1.9 V, but CO2 gas evolution proceeds through a chemical step via a nucleophilic attack and VC ring opening. Additionally, VC scavenges H2O and reduced protons via hydrolysis and via proton abstraction from the carbon electrode to form EC. Our study uncovers further reaction pathways and underscores the unique properties of EC and VC, both individually and in combination, and elucidates their roles in influencing the formation process in Li-ion batteries.</description>
      <author>Robin Lundstr&#246;m, Neeha Gogoi, Tim Melin, Erik J. Berg</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability analysis for scandium recovery from secondary sources</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12681/ta.36867</link>
      <description>Antonis Peppas, Chrysa Politi, Nikolaos Kountouris, Nafsika Angeliki Zafeiri, Sotiris Kottaridis, Technical Annals. 1(4)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4396754884

                Primary aluminium industry is one of the largest industries associated with high greenhouse gas emissions. It is reported that in 2022, the aluminium production emitted nearly 270 Mt of direct CO2 in the atmosphere. To achieve the European goals of zero emissions by 2050, a reduction of 4% annually is essential. &#932;he industry needs to take a turn towards less impactful production practices, focusing on the valorisation of residues for promoting sustainability. Bauxite residue from alumina production represents a remarkable source of Rare Earth Elements (REEs). This study offers valuable insights into the environmental and economic aspects of processes related to resource Scandium (Sc) extraction and processing in Greece, Romania and Turkey. In this frame, a comparative analysis of the environmental impact of the extraction process of REEs from Bauxite Residues (BR) in the regions mentioned above is presented. The results show that an up to 23% greenhouse gas emissions reduction can be achieved, while the environmental categories of human health risks, aquatic toxicity potential, and terrestrial ecotoxicity potential are improved by applying hydrothermal processes and direct leaching to BR. While the stages of Sc extraction remain consistent, variations in the chemical compositions of BR underscore the influence of local factors. The findings also emphasize the importance of tailoring extraction processes to local conditions and compositions for scandium extraction. These insights can guide industry decisions and contribute to responsible resource management in the future.</description>
      <author>Antonis Peppas, Chrysa Politi, Nikolaos Kountouris, Nafsika Angeliki Zafeiri, Sotiris Kottaridis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12681/ta.36867</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Standardization on the Future of Sustainable Refurbishment of Existing Buildings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-57800-7_56</link>
      <description>Gerald Leindecker, Lecture notes in civil engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396772772

                Abstract There is a vast building stock of existing buildings and the exchange rate is low (up to 0.2% per year). Therefore, there is a very strong need to deal with the existing building stock in respect to circularity. The effect of (new) regulations and standards on this volume for refurbishment and recycling of building materials is therefore crucial to meet the targets of CO2 reduction by increasing aspects of circularity overall to support environmental sustainability. The influence of standards towards the harmonization of technical requirements for refurbishment of existing buildings is therefore essential for wider implementation and acceptance in the market. There is, however, a gap identified between existing relevant standardization efforts and research in the field of refurbishment in the context of circularity. The effect of newly released standards and regulation will be analysed and identified barriers are discussed such as the generation and dissemination process of these standards.</description>
      <author>Gerald Leindecker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-57800-7_56</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terrestrial Ecosystem Model in R (TEMIR) version 1.0: simulating ecophysiological responses of vegetation to atmospheric chemical and meteorological changes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-17-3733-2024</link>
      <description>Amos P. K. Tai, David H. Y. Yung, Timothy Lam, Geoscientific model development. 17(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396759146

                Abstract. The newly developed offline land ecosystem model Terrestrial Ecosystem Model in R (TEMIR) version 1.0 is described here. This version of the model simulates plant ecophysiological (e.g., photosynthetic and stomatal) responses to varying meteorological conditions and concentrations of CO2 and ground-level ozone (O3) based on prescribed meteorological and atmospheric chemical inputs from various sources. Driven by the same meteorological data used in the GEOS-Chem chemical transport model, this allows asynchronously coupled experiments with GEOS-Chem simulations with unique coherency for investigating biosphere&#8211;atmosphere chemical interactions. TEMIR agrees well with FLUXNET site-level gross primary productivity (GPP) in terms of both the diurnal and monthly cycles (correlation coefficients R2&gt;0.85 and R2&gt;0.8, respectively) for most plant functional types (PFTs). Grass and shrub PFTs have larger biases due to generic model representations. The model performs best when driven by local site-level meteorology rather than reanalyzed gridded meteorology. Simulation using gridded meteorology agrees well for annual GPP in seasonality and spatial distribution with a global average of 134 Pg C yr&#8722;1. Application of Monin&#8211;Obukhov similarity theory to infer canopy conditions from gridded meteorology does not improve model performance, predicting an increase of +7 % in global GPP. Present-day O3 concentrations simulated by GEOS-Chem and an O3 damage scheme at high sensitivity show a 2 % reduction in global GPP with prominent reductions of up to 15 % in eastern China and the eastern USA. Regional correlations are generally unchanged when O3 is present and biases are reduced, especially for regions with high O3 damage. An increase in atmospheric CO2 concentration of 20 ppmv from the level in 2000 to the level in 2010 modestly decreases O3 damage due to reduced stomatal uptake, consistent with ecophysiological understanding. Our work showcases the utility of this version of TEMIR for evaluating biogeophysical responses of vegetation to changes in atmospheric composition and meteorological conditions.</description>
      <author>Amos P. K. Tai, David H. Y. Yung, Timothy Lam</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-17-3733-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating geothermal energy in hungary: A case study on sustainable urban heating and emissions mitigation through the district heating infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tust.2024.105804</link>
      <description>David Strasszer, George Xydis, Tunnelling and underground space technology. 149(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396841234

                Hungary boasts exceptional geothermal capabilities, with an Earth's crust thermal gradient nearly double the global average. However, the current utilization of these resources is often one-sided and lacks careful consideration. This comprehensive study offers updated insights into Hungary's geothermal potential and its current energy utilization. By presenting a practical example and employing scenario-based analyses, this study demonstrates how basic calculations can guide investment decisions in geothermal infrastructure. The aim is to address the prevailing issue of cities and towns prioritizing fossil fuel-based energy sources, thereby overshadowing renewable energy alternatives, despite advancing technology. Notably, in the case of Sz&#233;kesfeh&#233;rv&#225;r, it was determined that annual natural gas consumption could be reduced by an impressive 40&#8211;50%, leading to a substantial reduction of 5,000&#8211;9,200 tons of CO2 emissions, depending on the specific scenarios examined.</description>
      <author>David Strasszer, George Xydis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tust.2024.105804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tapping into fungal potential: Biodegradation of plastic and rubber by potent Fungi</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.173188</link>
      <description>S. S. Ibrahim, Danny Ionescu, Hans&#8208;Peter Grossart, Science of the total environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835288

                Plastic polymers are present in most aspects of routine daily life. Their increasing leakage into the environment poses a threat to environmental, animal, and human health. These polymers are often resistant to microbial degradation and are predicted to remain in the environment for tens to hundreds of years. Fungi have been shown to degrade complex polymers and are considered good candidates for bioremediation (biological pollutant reduction) of plastics. Therefore, we screened 18 selected fungal strains for their ability to degrade polyurethane (PU), polyethylene (PE), and tire rubber. As a proxy for plastic polymer mineralization, we quantified O2 consumption and CO2 production in an enclosed biodegradation system providing plastic as the sole carbon source. In contrast to most studies we demonstrated that the tested fungi attach to, and colonize the different plastic polymers without any pretreatment of the plastics and in the absence of sugars, which were suggested essential for priming the degradation process. Functional polymer groups identified by Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), and changes in fungal morphology as seen in light and scanning electron microscopy (SEM) were used as indicators of fungal adaptation to growth on PU as a substrate. Thereby, SEM analysis revealed new morphological structures and deformation of the cell wall of several fungal strains when colonizing PU and utilizing this plastic polymer for cell growth. Strains of Fusarium, Penicillium, Botryotinia cinerea EN41, and Trichoderma demonstrated a high potential to degrade PU, rubber, and PE. Growing on PU, over 90 % of the O2 was consumed in &lt;14 days with 300&#8211;500 ppm of CO2 generated in parallel. Our study highlights a high bioremediation potential of some fungal strains to efficiently degrade plastic polymers, largely dependent on plastic type.</description>
      <author>S. S. Ibrahim, Danny Ionescu, Hans&#8208;Peter Grossart</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.173188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Critical Role of Energy Intensity in Decarbonizing ASEAN: Integrating Growth and Emissions Reductions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.15059</link>
      <description>Setia Damayanti, Eka Sudarmaji, Herlan Masrio, International journal of energy economics and policy. 14(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396730639

                This research analyzes drivers of CO2 emissions across ASEAN countries from 1971-2017 to inform effective policies for sustainable decarbonized development. The goal is to identify critical factors influencing emissions growth and reductions to guide strategic climate mitigation planning. Data includes 3128 emissions, GDP, population, and energy consumption observations from 9 ASEAN nations. Results using the Kaya Index and Logarithmic Mean Divisia Index decomposition reveal GDP growth and population as primary drivers of increasing emissions, while energy efficiency dampens growth. Indonesia saw the highest emissions growth, driven by population and economic expansion. Thailand's phenomenal GDP growth of 3003.7% led to its emission increases. Singapore and the Philippines achieved notable reductions. Findings suggest integrated policies like clean energy, efficiency gains, infrastructure planning, and low-carbon economic reform are needed. Transitioning towards affordable clean energy systems with proactive leadership can enable ASEAN to sustain growth while mitigating climate risks. Further research should identify optimal policy mixes to maximize socio-economic progress and welfare while meeting urgent emission targets tailored to each nation. This study provides vital insights into key factors influencing ASEAN emissions and highlights pathways towards sustainable decarbonized development. The analysis of historical trends aims to inform strategic policymaking for decarbonization.</description>
      <author>Setia Damayanti, Eka Sudarmaji, Herlan Masrio</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32479/ijeep.15059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The regulatory role of cysteine in active phase construction of polyoxometalate-based hydrodesulfurization catalysts: Reduction, chelation, and dispersion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120234</link>
      <description>Cong Zhang, Wenjing Bao, Changle Yue, Fengyue Sun, Yiyuan Xu, Daofeng Sun, Yukun Lu, Chemical engineering science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780816

                Polyoxometalate-based hydrodesulfurization (HDS) catalysts were modified using cysteine to construct efficient CoMoS active phase. Cysteine, characterized by chelating (&#8211;COOH, &#8211;NH2) and reducing (&#8722;SH) groups, assumed a triple role in catalyst synthesis, including reduction, chelation, and dispersion. Cysteine pre-reduced polyoxometalates to heteropoly blue, significantly increasing the catalyst sulfidation. The increased nucleophilicity of heteropoly blue enhanced their attraction to Co2+ ions, intensifying the Co-Mo bimetallic synergy. The formation of Co-chelate species delayed Co sulfidation, allowing for the concurrent sulfidation of both Co and Mo species and promoting the generation of the CoMoS active phase. Carbonaceous deposits from the high-temperature carbonization of cysteine weakened the metal-support interaction, facilitating the dispersion of the active phase. The S-CoPMo12-Cys/Al2O3 catalyst demonstrated high activity in the HDS reaction of dibenzothiophene, showcasing their potential for advanced HDS reaction.</description>
      <author>Cong Zhang, Wenjing Bao, Changle Yue, Fengyue Sun, Yiyuan Xu, Daofeng Sun, Yukun Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Performance of Hemihydrate Phosphogypsum by the Collaborative Effects of Calcium Hydroxide and Carbonation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102204</link>
      <description>J.C. Huang, Zanqun Liu, Wei Xiang-song, Xiangyu Ding, Jiahui Zhu, Yilin Zhao, Babar Iqbal, Shulai Guo, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721811

                Normally, the acidic impurities in hemihydrate phosphogypsum (HPG) must be neutralized when HPG is utilized, and a little amount of calcium hydroxide (CH) is the best choice. In this paper, the effects of excessive CH (5 wt.%, 10 wt.%, 15 wt.% and 20 wt.% of HPG) for carbonation curing on the performance of hardened HPG paste were studied. According to the results of macro tests and microanalyses of XRD, TG, SEM-EDS, MIP and N2 physisorption, it could be verified that CaF2, Ca3(PO4)2 and a large amount of nanoscale CaCO3 crystals were produced as a result of neutralization and carbonation, and the compressive strength and the water resistance of carbonated HPG + CH paste were significantly improved due to the effects of nanoscale CaCO3 crystals on pore refinement and the coverage on the surfaces of gypsum crystals of the hardened paste. Therefore, this study suggests a feasible and green method for recycling HPG/PG, with the collaborative effects of neutralization, performance enhancement and reductions in CO2 emissions.</description>
      <author>J.C. Huang, Zanqun Liu, Wei Xiang-song, Xiangyu Ding, Jiahui Zhu, Yilin Zhao, Babar Iqbal, Shulai Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Energy Conversion using Tri-nuclear M-Ru(II)-M[M= Pt(II), Re(I)] Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-8w0sg</link>
      <description>Shafquat Ullah Khan, Sujoy Biswas, Bishnu Das, Sakira Tabassum Borah, Deep Lahan, Parna Gupta, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396744413

                The tri-nuclear Pt(II)-Ru(II)-Pt(II)(RuPt2) and Re(I)-Ru(II)-Re(II)(RuRe2) complexes, synthesized from mononuclear Ru(II) complex were explored for efficient energy conversion through water splitting and CO2 reduction. The catalysts show excellent activity, serving as promising platforms for sustainable energy applications. The study focuses on designing, stepwise synthesis of the catalysts with insights into the multiple components&#8217; contribution to enhanced catalytic performance. Photophysical and electrochemical analyses highlight the role of the complexes as photocatalysts, where the Ru(II)-polypyridyl unit acts as photosensitizer and the Pt(II)/ Re(I)-polypyridyl units as catalytic sites. Synergistic effects among the components lead to stability, improved performance and emphasizes the significance of multi-nuclear M-Ru(II)-M[M= Pt(II), Re(I)] catalysts in promoting cleaner and more sustainable energy sources.</description>
      <author>Shafquat Ullah Khan, Sujoy Biswas, Bishnu Das, Sakira Tabassum Borah, Deep Lahan, Parna Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-8w0sg</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretical Benchmark of the Geometric and Optical Properties for 3d Transition Metal Nanoclusters via Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00408</link>
      <description>Shana Havenridge, Cong Liu, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A/&#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A.. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835391

                Understanding structure&#8211;property relationships in atomically precise metal nanoclusters is vital in finding selective and tunable catalysts. In this study, density functional theory (DFT) was used to benchmark seven exchange correlation functionals at different basis sets for 17 atomically precise nanoclusters against experimentally determined geometries, band gaps, and optical gaps. The set contains both monometallic and bimetallic clusters that possess at least two types of 3d transition metals (specifically, Cu, Ni, Fe, or Co). The benchmark highlights that PBE0 is a good functional to use regardless of the basis set, and Minnesota functionals do well with respect to specific metals. Further, while long-range corrected functionals overestimate band and optical gaps, they model absorption features better than the other considered functionals. The study additionally looks at the photoinduced hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the CO2 reduction mechanism on nanoclusters reported from the literature.</description>
      <author>Shana Havenridge, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Pursuit of Greenness: Drivers and Consequences of Green Corporate Revenues</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823664</link>
      <description>U&#487;ur Lel, Social Science Research Network. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396878155

                Corporate revenues from environmentally friendly products and services are surging, having reached US$4.69 trillion worldwide in 2023. In this paper, I provide a comprehensive evaluation of these green revenues across countries over the 2008-2023 period. I find that foreign institutional ownership, particularly from countries with stringent environmental norms and regulations, significantly increases green revenue intensity. This correlation is further supported by evidence from index inclusions, indicating a causal relationship. Additionally, firms that tie executive compensation to ESG goals and those with gender-diverse leadership show enhanced green revenue intensity. Leveraging the EU Green Deal as a natural experiment, I demonstrate that increases in green revenues are associated with reductions in CO2 emissions and enhancements in environmental policies and profitability. These effects are mostly concentrated in carbon-intensive industries. Overall, these findings highlight how environmental considerations are integral to shaping corporate strategies and illustrate the pivotal role of institutional investors in fostering the green transition.</description>
      <author>U&#487;ur Lel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of high-performance multiphase heterostructures IT-SOFC cathode materials by Pr-induced in situ assembly</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124174</link>
      <description>Jinghe Bai, Defeng Zhou, Leilei Niu, Xiaofei Zhu, Ning Wang, Qingwen Liang, Youjie Zhang, Ling Hu, Huifang Gong, Wenfu Yan, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396807055

                Here, in situ assembly in La0.6Sr0.4Co0.2Fe0.8O3-&#948; and CoFe2O4 composite (LSCFC) cathode was induced by Pr to form La0.6Sr0.4CoxFeyO3-&#948;/PrCoO3/Co3O4/PrO2 (LSCFC-PI) multiphase heterostructures. The surface of LSCFC-PI forms uniform nanoparticles, and the unique core-shell structure prevents Sr segregation, thereby enhancing CO2 tolerance and increasing oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) active sites. Furthermore, compared with LSCFC, LSCFC-PI increases the oxygen vacancy content of the cathode due to the existence of multiphase heterostructure, improves the ORR kinetics, and the conductivity is also greatly improved. The peak power density (PDD) of LSCFC-PI as a single-cell cathode at 700 &#8451; reached 1.51 W cm-2, which was 2.65 times higher than that of LSCFC's 0.57 W cm-2, and in the long-term stability test at a constant voltage ~0.8 V for 100 hours, showing excellent stability. In situ assembly of multiphase heterostructures is expected to become a new strategy for developing high-performance IT-SOFC cathodes.</description>
      <author>Jinghe Bai, Defeng Zhou, Leilei Niu, Xiaofei Zhu, Ning Wang, Qingwen Liang, Youjie Zhang, Ling Hu, Huifang Gong, Wenfu Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect on combustion performance and emission behavior of diesel engine fueled with hybrid biodiesel produced from a novel ternary oil mixture incorporated with nano additive</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/15567036.2024.2351149</link>
      <description>Brihaspati Singh, A. K. Srivastava, Om Prakash, Energy sources. Part A, Recovery, utilization, and environmental effects. 46(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396847390

                Global energy demand has been above 80% fossil fuels for decades, creating a greater and more complicated energy crisis. Biodiesel is a great alternate energy source for future energy demand. Producing biodiesel from a mixture of waste and non-edible oils may be a practical solution to address the growing global need of biodiesel. In this study, hybrid biodiesel is produced from a ternary oil mixture of Waste cooking oil, Ricinus communis oil, and Melia azedarach oil. The hybrid biodiesel blends are prepared by 10% blending (HB10), 20% blending (HB20) and 30% blending (HB30) and 30ppm multiwall carbon nanotube has been added in the blended fuel through sonicating process. At steady 1500rmp and variable load (0&#8211;100%), the engine behavior has been examined. The results show that the hybrid biodiesel blend (HB10) with 30ppm MWCNT has shown highest cylinder pressure of 70.9 bar, maximum mean gas temperature 1467.56&#176;C. The engine shows 34.08% rise in net heat release and 9.13% rise in exhaust gas temperature as compare to diesel. The maximum rise in break thermal efficiency of 19.74% and minimum reduction in break specific fuel consumption of 13.79% is noticed in comparison to B00. The highest reduction of HC emission is found as 20.83% for HB20MWCNT30 and 19.34% for HB30MWCNT30 as compare to B00. The inclusion of multiwall carbon nanotube in hybrid biodiesel reduces the HC, CO, NOx and smoke emission and increases CO2 emission as compare to respective hybrid biodiesel blend and diesel. The hybrid biodiesel-diesel blend, with multiwall carbon nanotube can be utilized efficiently in diesel engine with improved overall engine behavior.</description>
      <author>Brihaspati Singh, A. K. Srivastava, Om Prakash</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/15567036.2024.2351149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Synergy in Pd-Ni Bimetallics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33540/2361</link>
      <description>Florian Zand, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396873269

                This thesis aims to enhance our understanding of metal segregation in supported bimetallic catalysts, to maximize the synergy between metals. It covers the assessment, effects, and origin of metal segregation as exemplified by supported alloyed Pd-Ni nanoparticles. To assess the degree and type of metal segregation in detail, we introduce a novel analytical technique to study industrial mesoporous catalysts &#8211; atom probe tomography (APT). Due to its nature, measuring mesoporous catalysts was not yet possible with APT, thus we have developed a resin-based sample preparation approach. This enables to unravel sub-nm compositional heterogeneities within/between nanoparticles, which is crucial for the optimization of industrial catalysts. With this upgraded arsenal of analytical techniques, we investigated the origins and effects of metal segregation for bimetallic catalysts prepared via industrially relevant incipient wetness impregnation. It spans most of the catalyst&#8217;s lifetime from precursor decomposition during calcination, alloy formation during reduction, and restructuring under steady and modulating operating conditions. Hereby, we elucidate the pathways for alloy formation for less uniform catalyst materials, describe the origin of reduction promotion, and showcase the catalyst&#8217;s state under operando conditions. However, next to revealing pathways which lead to alloy formation, we shed light on the origins leading to metal segregation. Therefore, we followed the metal precursor decomposition using different gas atmospheres. This allowed to assess the degree of metal segregation and pinpointed which role the decomposition of precursors plays. Finally, we elucidated how metal segregation/alloying between Pd and Ni affects catalysis mechanistically for both CO2 hydrogenation and chitosan depolymerization.</description>
      <author>Florian Zand</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33540/2361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microorganisms in subarctic soils are depleted of ribosomes under short-, medium-, and long-term warming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae081</link>
      <description>Andrea S&#246;llinger, Laureen S Ahlers, Mathilde Borg Dahl, P&#225;ll Sigur&#240;sson, Coline Le Noir de Carlan, Biplabi Bhattarai, Christoph Gall, Victoria Martin, Cornelia Rottensteiner, Liabo L. Motleleng, Eva Marie Breines, Erik Verbruggen, Ivika Ostonen, Bjarni D. Sigur&#240;sson, Andreas Richter, Alexander T&#248;sdal Tveit, &#152;The &#156;ISME journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396779674

                Physiological responses of soil microorganisms to global warming are important for soil ecosystem function and the terrestrial carbon cycle. Here, we investigate the effects of weeks, years, and decades of soil warming across seasons and time on the microbial protein biosynthesis machineries (i.e. ribosomes), the most abundant cellular macromolecular complexes, using RNA:DNA and RNA:MBC (microbial biomass carbon) ratios as proxies for cellular ribosome contents. We compared warmed soils and non-warmed controls of 15 replicated subarctic grassland and forest soil temperature gradients subject to natural geothermal warming. RNA:DNA ratios tended to be lower in the warmed soils during summer and autumn, independent of warming duration (6 weeks, 8-14 years, &gt; 50 years), warming intensity (+3&#176;C, +6&#176;C, +9&#176;C), and ecosystem type. With increasing temperatures RNA:MBC ratios were also decreasing. Additionally, seasonal RNA:DNA ratios of the consecutively sampled forest showed the same temperature-driven pattern. This suggests that subarctic soil microorganisms are depleted of ribosomes under warm conditions and the lack of consistent relationships with other physicochemical parameters besides temperature further suggests temperature as key driver. Furthermore, in incubation experiments, we measured significantly higher CO2 emission rates per unit of RNA from short- and long-term warmed soils compared to non-warmed controls. In conclusion, ribosome reduction may represent a widespread microbial physiological response to warming that offers a selective advantage at higher temperatures, as energy and matter can be reallocated from ribosome synthesis to other processes including substrate uptake and turnover. This way, ribosome reduction could have a substantial effect on soil carbon dynamics.</description>
      <author>Andrea S&#246;llinger, Laureen S Ahlers, Mathilde Borg Dahl, P&#225;ll Sigur&#240;sson, Coline Le Noir de Carlan, Biplabi Bhattarai, Christoph Gall, Victoria Martin, Cornelia Rottensteiner, Liabo L. Motleleng, Eva Marie Breines, Erik Verbruggen, Ivika Ostonen, Bjarni D. Sigur&#240;sson, Andreas Richter, Alexander T&#248;sdal Tveit</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Online Randomised Controlled Trial of Price and Non-Price Interventions to Promote Sustainable Food Choices on Food Delivery Platforms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4818247</link>
      <description>Andreas Kontoleon, Elisabeth Gsottbauer, James Farrington, Sherrie E. Human, Lucia A. Reisch, Social Science Research Network. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396783656

                Food-delivery platforms provide unique opportunities to design user interfaces that encourage healthy, low-carbon meal choices. We conducted an incentivised online randomised controlled trial with 4,008 participants using a simulated food delivery app to test three potential interventions: a sign-posted meat tax, a carbon-footprint label, and a choice-architecture intervention that changed the order of the menu so that the lowest carbon-impact restaurants and dishes were presented first. Results show that only the choice-architecture nudge significantly reduced the average meal carbon footprint&#8212;by 0.3 kg/CO2e per order (12%), driven by a 5.6 percentage point (13%) reduction in high-carbon meal choices. Furthermore, menu repositioning resulted in healthier meal choices, with greater nutritional value and fewer calories, while significantly increasing self-reported satisfaction. Back-of-the-envelope calculations suggest that menu repositioning would be a highly cost-effective policy instrument if implemented at scale, with an expected return on investment in the range of &#163;1.28 to &#163;3.85 per metric ton of avoided CO2 emissions, depending on implementation costs.</description>
      <author>Andreas Kontoleon, Elisabeth Gsottbauer, James Farrington, Sherrie E. Human, Lucia A. Reisch</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4818247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techno-Economic and Environmental Analysis of the Integration of PV Systems into Hybrid Vessels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102303</link>
      <description>Lewis McAllister, Haibin Wang, Energies. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396858255

                Solar energy is one type of clean energy resource, and currently the IMO, EU and UK are targeting net zero carbon emissions by 2050. This paper delves into the integration of photovoltaic (PV) systems into hybrid vessels in order to meet their strategies and targets. The technical challenges that come with designing such systems as well as their economic and environmental impacts are examined. By optimizing the usage of harnessed solar energy, we discover the operational strategy that provides maximal benefits through day-to-day savings as well as over the 25 year lifespan of solar panels. It demonstrates impressive economic viability, with cost savings of up to GBP 4.55 per day and a payoff period as short as 9 years. It also displays a modest emission reduction of up to 8.002 kg of CO2, which serves as proof for a pathway to greener practices in the maritime industry. This report highlights the operational flexibility that a hybrid vessel possesses once paired with a PV system through the ability to withstand regulatory and market changes. Also, when looking ahead, further adoption of PV technology creates opportunities for innovation in adopting renewable energy solutions in maritime transportation.</description>
      <author>Lewis McAllister, Haibin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of a Hybrid Pumice&#8211;Portland Cement Extract on Corrosion Activity of Stainless Steel SS304 and Carbon Mild Steel A36</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102255</link>
      <description>David J. Bonfil, L. V&#233;leva, J.I. Escalante-Garc&#305;&#769;a, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857313

                The change in the corrosion activities of SS304 and the carbon steel A36 were studied during their exposure for 30 days to hybrid pumice-Portland cement extract (CE), to simulate the concrete&#8211;pore environment. The ionic composition and the initial pH (12.99) of the CE were influenced by the reduction of Portland cement (PC) content, volcanic pumice oxides and alkaline activators. Because of the air CO2 dissolution, the pH decreased and maintained a constant value &#8776; 9.10 (established dynamic ionic equilibrium). The CE promoted the passivation of both steels and their free corrosion potential (OCP) reached positive values. On the surfaces, Fe and Cr oxides were formed, according to the nature of the steel. Over the time of exposure, the presence of chloride ions in the pumice caused a localized pitting attack, and for carbon steel, this fact may indicate an intermediate risk of corrosion. The chloride effect was retarded by the accumulation of SO42&#8722; ions at the steel surfaces. Based on electrochemical impedance (EIS), the polarization resistance (Rp) and the thickness of the passive layers were calculated. Their values were compared with those previously reported for the steels exposed to CEs of Portland and supersulfated cements, and the hybrid cement was considered as a PC &#8220;green&#8221; alternative.</description>
      <author>David J. Bonfil, L. V&#233;leva, J.I. Escalante-Garc&#305;&#769;a</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly efficiency H2 production for real coal tar steam reforming over Ni-ca/H-Al catalyst: Effects of oxygen vacancy, CaO doping and synthesis methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.123354</link>
      <description>Jin Deng, Youneng Feng, Chun Li, Zhe Yuan, Ran Shang, Shenfu Yuan, Applied energy. 367(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396841125

                Steam reforming of medium-low temperature coal tar (SRT) to produce H2 is important for addressing the energy crisis and challenges of global climate change. However, current catalysts still suffer from low H2 selectivity, low tar conversion and poor long-term stability due to the complex composition of real coal tar. Herein, a series of Ni-Ca/H-Al catalysts were prepared by different methods. The results showed that the acid pretreatment effectively removed the hydroxyl groups on the surface of &#947;-Al2O3 to form oxygen vacancies (Ov), and the NiO was mainly anchored in the Ov. The cit-Ni-2Ca/H-Al catalyst prepared by citric acid-assisted impregnation exhibited the highest H2 yield (152.74 mmol/g-tar), while CO2 was only 22.11 mmol/g-tar. Characterization showed that the addition of CaO improved the dispersion of NiO and increased the Ov concentration. The increase in Ov weakened the NiO bonds in NiO and facilitated the low-temperature reduction of NiO. The cit-Ni-2Ca/H-Al catalysts prepared by the citric acid-assisted impregnation method had better dispersion and strong basic sites compared with the impregnation and precipitation methods, leading to more active sites for CO2 and H2O adsorption, and improving the carbon build-up resistance and reusability of the catalysts. Py-GC/MS results showed the cit-Ni-2Ca/H-Al had excellent tar deoxidation ability and effectively promoted the breakage of CC bonds in furans, benzene ring branches, and CO bonds in aliphatic hydrocarbons. The cit-Ni-2Ca/H-Al catalyst exhibited high tar conversion (90.96%) and H2 yield (146.27 mmol/g-tar) without any treatment for at least 8 cycles. Interestingly, the H2 yield reached 151.58 mmol/g-tar by the simple regeneration of cit-Ni-2Ca/H-Al. This study provides a theoretical basis for efficient steam reforming of real coal tar for H2 production and catalyst preparation.</description>
      <author>Jin Deng, Youneng Feng, Chun Li, Zhe Yuan, Ran Shang, Shenfu Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.123354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Carbon-Free Automotive Futures: Leveraging AI And ML For Sustainable Transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53555/kuey.v30i5.3474</link>
      <description>Vishwanadham Mandala, Srinivas Naveen Reddy Dolu Surabhi, Phani Durga Nanda Kishore Kommisetty, Bala Maruthi Subba Rao Kuppala, Roopak Ingole, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834406

                This paper delves into the transformative role of artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) in reshaping the automotive industry towards sustainability and environmental consciousness.It begins by examining the integration of intelligent infrastructure, such as sensor-equipped traffic signal lights and cameras, aimed at enhancing road safety and efficiency.Furthermore, the development of autonomous driving and connected vehicle technologies, in conjunction with advancements in V2X communication and 5G technology, presents promising avenues for reducing energy consumption and CO2 emissions in transportation.A critical analysis of the current state of carbon emissions in the automotive industry underscores the pressing need to transition towards carbon-free alternatives, with AI and ML identified as essential tools for predicting emissions, optimizing energy demand, managing electric vehicles, and implementing eco-driving strategies to achieve zero-carbon emissions.Additionally, the paper explores various AI/ML applications for vehicle efficiency improvement, battery optimization, electric vehicle charging, and intelligent traffic management, highlighting their contributions to emissions reduction and improved traffic flow.Nonetheless, the integration of AI/ML into carbon-free automotive futures poses challenges such as regulatory hurdles, infrastructure development, and ethical considerations.Despite these challenges, AI and ML offer promising solutions to mitigate climate change and drive towards a sustainable automotive industry.</description>
      <author>Vishwanadham Mandala, Srinivas Naveen Reddy Dolu Surabhi, Phani Durga Nanda Kishore Kommisetty, Bala Maruthi Subba Rao Kuppala, Roopak Ingole</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53555/kuey.v30i5.3474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Evaluation of the Radioactive Content of Ashes Obtained from the Use of Fuels from Recycled Materials by Co-Processing in the Cement Industry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102287</link>
      <description>J.A. Su&#225;rez-Navarro, Miguel &#193;ngel Sanju&#225;n, Pedro Mora, M.M. Alonso, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857909

                The co-processing of different wastes as fuels in the manufacture of cement clinker not only meets the objectives of a circular economy but also contributes to the reduction in CO2 emissions in the manufacture of Portland cement. However, waste used as alternative fuels, such as sludge or organic-rich residues, may contain naturally occurring radionuclides that can be concentrated during the combustion process. In this study, the presence of natural radionuclides (radioactive series of uranium, thorium, and 40K) and anthropogenic radionuclides (137Cs) in these wastes has been investigated by gamma spectrometry. Possible relationships between the radioactive content and the obtained chemical composition, determined by X-ray fluorescence, have also been studied by applying a principal component analysis (PCA). The results showed that the wastes with the highest radioactive content were sewage sludge with activity concentrations of 238U and 210Pb of 321 &#177; 38 Bq kg&#8722;1 and 110 &#177; 14 Bq kg&#8722;1, respectively. A correlation between radioactive content and Fe2O3 concentration was also observed. The annual effective dose rates to workers for the ashes estimated from the ash content ranged from 0.0033 mSv to 0.092 mSv and therefore do not pose a risk to workers as they are lower than the 1 mSv per year limit for the general public (DIRECTIVE 2013/59/EURATOM).</description>
      <author>J.A. Su&#225;rez-Navarro, Miguel &#193;ngel Sanju&#225;n, Pedro Mora, M.M. Alonso</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102287</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Plastic Waste Gasification by Autothermal Chemical Looping with &amp;gt;90% Syngas Purity for Versatile Feedstock Handling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaecs.2024.100270</link>
      <description>Eric Falascino, Rajesh Joshi, Sonu Kumar, Tanay Jawdekar, Ishani Karki Kudva, Shekhar G. Shinde, Zhuo Cheng, Dikai Xu, Liang&#8208;Shih Fan, Applications in energy and combustion science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396829622

                The chemical looping gasification of plastics (CLGP) is a process that offers an innovative solution for transforming post-consumer waste plastics into high-value products. The process utilizes a co-current moving bed reducer reactor with Iron-titanium-based oxygen carriers to gasify plastic feed and generate syngas autothermally. Its distinguishing feature is its ability to operate over a wide range of feed loadings and co-injection of mixed plastic species without any performance losses. Isothermal bench-scale experiments reveal a syngas purity of &#8764;95%, aligning with the thermodynamic simulations. The moving bed reactor facilitates a deeper reduction of the oxygen carriers to the Fe+FeTiO3 phase, leading to the high syngas purity, which is then verified with additional TGA, XRD, and SEM analysis. For an autothermal operation of CLGP process, an active material content of 20% is found to be sufficient to satisfy the kinetic and thermodynamic constraints. Further integration with downstream production of H2 is presented and compared to a steam gasification process. The process integration simulations show that the CLGP process outperforms the steam gasification system in terms of cold gas efficiency (CGE), effective thermal efficiency (ETE), and H2 yield. CO2 emissions are impressively reduced by &#8764;30% in the CLGP system over that in the steam gasification system due to its ability to autothermally operate the process, unlike the highly endothermic steam gasification process.</description>
      <author>Eric Falascino, Rajesh Joshi, Sonu Kumar, Tanay Jawdekar, Ishani Karki Kudva, Shekhar G. Shinde, Zhuo Cheng, Dikai Xu, Liang&#8208;Shih Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaecs.2024.100270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binary and Ternary Blended Portland Cements Containing Different Types of Rice Husk Ash</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.0589.v1</link>
      <description>Luis Miguel Ordo&#241;ez, M.V. Borrachero, J. Monz&#243;, Lourdes Soriano, J. Pay&#225;, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396761331

                Rice husk ash (RHA) is agricultural waste with high silica content that has had proven technical feasibility as a pozzolanic material since the 1970s. Notwithstanding, its use in mortars and concrete is limited by the standards currently utilized in some countries where RHA production is high and the aforementioned pozzolanic material is not standardized. This is the case of Spain, one of the main rice producers in Europe. Nowadays, the high pressure placed on the Portland cement production sector to reduce energy use and CO2 emissions has given rise to a keen interest shown in mineral admixtures for cement manufacturing. In this research, we intend to establish the contribution of different RHA types to final blended Portland cement properties (symbol &#8220;H&#8221; was used to identify RHA in standardized cements). The experimental results demonstrated that RHA with good pozzolanic properties (large specific surface and high amorphous silica content) had to be limited to 10% cement replacement because of the severe reduction in workability at higher replacement percentages. RHA with lower reactivity, such as crystalline RHA, or fly ash (FA), can be used to prepare binary and ternary blended cements with reactive RHA. It is possible to design the following cements: CEM II/A-H and CEM II/A-(H-V) It would also be possible to design cement (CEM II/B-(H-V) with replacement values up to 30% and the same 28-day mechanical performance observed for the Portland cement without mineral addition.</description>
      <author>Luis Miguel Ordo&#241;ez, M.V. Borrachero, J. Monz&#243;, Lourdes Soriano, J. Pay&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.0589.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Environmental Impact and Benefits of Incorporating Humus Composites in Anaerobic Co-Digestion Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics12050360</link>
      <description>Ke Zhao, Qiang Wang, Meng-Xin Bai, Mengnan Shen, Toxics. 12(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396853666

                This study evaluated the environmental impact and overall benefits of incorporating humus composites in the anaerobic co-digestion of kitchen waste and residual sludge. The life cycle assessment method was used to quantitatively analyze the environmental impact of the entire anaerobic co-digestion treatment process of waste, including garbage collection, transportation, and final product utilization. Moreover, the comprehensive assessment of the environmental impact, energy-saving and emission-reduction abilities, and economic cost of using humus composites in the anaerobic co-digestion treatment process was conducted using a benefit analysis method. The results showed that the anaerobic co-digestion of kitchen waste and residual sludge significantly contributed to the mitigation of global warming potential (GWP), reaching &#8722;19.76 kgCO2-eq, but had the least impact on the mitigation of acidification potential (AP), reaching &#8722;0.10 kgSO2-eq. In addition, the addition of humus composites significantly increased the production of biogas. At a concentration of 5 g/L, the biogas yield of the anaerobic co-digestion process was 70.76 m3, which increased by 50.62% compared with the blank group. This amount of biogas replaces ~50.52 kg of standard coal, reducing CO2 emissions by 13.74 kg compared with burning the same amount of standard coal. Therefore, the anaerobic co-digestion treatment of kitchen waste and residual sludge brings considerable environmental benefits.</description>
      <author>Ke Zhao, Qiang Wang, Meng-Xin Bai, Mengnan Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics12050360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of atmospheric pressure, and of the partial pressures of CO2 and N2, on the growth rates of Anabaena sp. PCC 7938: Assessment and implications for cyanobacterium cultivation on Mars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4348078/v1</link>
      <description>Cyprien Verseux, Tiago P Ramalho, Emma Bohuon, Nils Kunst, Viktoria Lang, Christiane Heinicke, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396868615

                Abstract In situ resource utilization systems based on cyanobacteria could support the sustainability of crewed missions to Mars. However, their resource-efficiency will depend on the extent to which gases from the Martian atmosphere must be processed to support cyanobacterial growth. The main purpose of the present work is to help assess this extent. We therefore start with investigating the impact of changes in atmospheric conditions on the photoautotrophic, diazotrophic growth of the cyanobacterium Anabaena sp. PCC 7938. We show that lowering atmospheric pressure from 1 bar down to 80 hPa, without changing the partial pressures of metabolizable gases, does not reduce growth rates. We also provide equations, analogous to Monod&#8217;s, that describe the dependence of growth rates on the partial pressures of CO2 and N2. We then outline the relationships between atmospheric pressure and composition, the minimal mass of a photobioreactor&#8217;s outer walls (which is dependent on the inner-outer pressure difference), and growth rates. Relying on these relationships, we demonstrate that the structural mass of a photobioreactor can be decreased &#8211; without affecting cyanobacterial productivity &#8211; by reducing the inner gas pressure. We argue, however, that this reduction would be small next to the equivalent system mass of the cultivation system. A greater impact on resource-efficiency could come from the selection of atmospheric conditions which minimize gas processing requirements while adequately supporting cyanobacterial growth. The data and equations we provide can help identify these conditions.</description>
      <author>Cyprien Verseux, Tiago P Ramalho, Emma Bohuon, Nils Kunst, Viktoria Lang, Christiane Heinicke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4348078/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the calculation module for estimating pollutant emission from conventional and hybrid regional aircraft</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15587/1729-4061.2024.302793</link>
      <description>Kateryna Synylo, Vitalii Makarenko, Andrii Krupko, Vadim Tokarev, Eastern-European journal of enterprise technologies. 2(10 (128))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396734426

                For the aviation sector, it is extremely important to devise revolutionary solutions in the field of technology to restrain the potential impact of civil aviation on the environment to the level of the established strategic goals of ACARE (FlightPath2050). The introduction of innovative technologies (improvement of the combustion chamber, the introduction of electric hybrid power plants on airplanes, and the use of alternative aviation fuel) will ensure the sustainable growth of air transportation. To assess the effectiveness of advanced technologies, it is extremely important to have a model for calculating global/local emissions that takes into account the parameters of the flight path of conventional and hybrid aircraft, operational characteristics of the aircraft engine and hybrid powerplant, and the features of sustainable fuel. The improved module for calculating emission indices by combining the module for calculating the parameters of the flight path and the results of calculating the thermogas-dynamic calculation of the aircraft engine makes it possible to detect the influence of fuel consumption (engine thrust) on the values of the emission indices. This feature is representative for evaluating the efficiency of hybrid powerplants because the electrification of the aircraft fleet is primarily aimed at reducing fuel consumption. The analysis of simulation results reveals that the fuel consumption and EINOx are significantly reduced (for the climb stage &#8211; 25 %; for the descent stage &#8211; 30 %) for the hybrid AN26 compared to the conventional AN26. The specified operational measure, in the part of the low-pitch descend, significantly reduces EICO for the hybrid AN26 by an average of 50 % compared to the descend stage for the conventional trajectory. The results of calculations for the entire flight path demonstrate that the use of a hybrid power plant for An26 contributes to an average reduction of fuel consumption by 10 %, NOx emissions by 25 %, water vapor emissions by 10 %, and CO2 by 10 %.</description>
      <author>Kateryna Synylo, Vitalii Makarenko, Andrii Krupko, Vadim Tokarev</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15587/1729-4061.2024.302793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Velocity-selective arterial spin labelling bolus duration measurements: Implications for consensus recommendations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.04.592549</link>
      <description>Ian D. Driver, Harold L. Chandler, Eleonora Patitucci, Elizabeth N. Morgan, Kevin Murphy, Stefano Zappal&#224;, Richard G. Wise, Michael Germuska, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396733781

                Velocity-selective arterial spin labelling (VSASL) MRI is insensitive to arterial transit time. This is an advantage over other perfusion measurements, where long arterial transit times can lead to bias. Therefore, VSASL can be used to study perfusion in the presence of long arterial transit times, such as in the ageing brain, in vascular pathologies, and cancer, or where arterial transit time changes, such as during measurement of cerebrovascular reactivity (CVR). However, when calculating perfusion (cerebral blood flow, CBF, in the brain) from VSASL signal, it is assumed that images are acquired before the trailing edge of the labelled blood has arrived in the imaging slice. The arrival of the trailing edge of the labelled bolus of blood will cause an underestimation of perfusion. Here we measure bolus duration in young, healthy human brains, both at rest and during elevated CBF. Grey matter bolus duration was 1.61 +/- 0.31 s, but there was a large spatial heterogeneity, with bolus duration being lower in anterior brain regions, with some areas having bolus duration &lt; 1.2 s. We place these results in context of recommendations from a recent consensus paper, which recommends imaging 1.4 s after the label, potentially underestimating CBF in anterior regions. Further, we observed a 0.23 +/- 0.12 s reduction in grey matter bolus duration with 5% CO2 inhalation. These results can be used to inform the experimental design of future VSASL studies, to avoid underestimating perfusion by imaging after the arrival of the trailing edge of the labelled bolus.</description>
      <author>Ian D. Driver, Harold L. Chandler, Eleonora Patitucci, Elizabeth N. Morgan, Kevin Murphy, Stefano Zappal&#224;, Richard G. Wise, Michael Germuska</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.04.592549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring equality and sustainability trade-offs of energy transition outcomes in the United States in 2050</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.123376</link>
      <description>Teagan Goforth, Destenie Nock, M. C. Brown, Tapajyoti Ghosh, Patrick Lamers, Applied energy. 367(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396820968

                With increasing focus on equitable and just energy transition, it is critical to understand the trade-offs of different decarbonization outcomes across economic, environmental, and social sustainability criteria. In this analysis, we use a multi-criteria decision analysis to quantify sustainability outcomes across 32 decarbonization outcomes in 2050 in the U.S. The economic sustainability criteria we use are system cost, national average retail rate, and electricity system employment. The environmental sustainability criteria we use are life cycle greenhouse gas emissions, life cycle water depletion, life cycle land transformation, and air pollution fatalities. The social sustainability (distributional impacts) criteria we use are retail rate equality across states, electricity employment equality across low-income households, and air pollution disparities across census tracts. We evaluate performance across these criteria under eleven different stakeholder preference scenarios. We find that decarbonization policies with indefinitely extended tax credits have the highest sustainability score under equal criteria weighting, with greater investments in renewable energy technologies, and result in better environmental, system cost, job, and air pollution disparities compared to mid-case scenarios, that only include current policies and CO2 reduction targets. We also see that our multi-criteria decision analysis identifies decarbonization outcomes that would not have been identified as optimal under a single objective, which highlights the importance of trade-off analyses to understand decarbonization outcomes more holistically.</description>
      <author>Teagan Goforth, Destenie Nock, M. C. Brown, Tapajyoti Ghosh, Patrick Lamers</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.123376</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Efficiency Management in China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-51532-3_4</link>
      <description>Alexey Mikhaylov, Contributions to management science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396876663

                At the current stage of economic development, environmental factors have become crucial in improving the energy efficiency of production. This includes environmental protection, controlling harmful emissions from fuel combustion, energy produced per unit of CO2 released, and managing industrial waste. These indicators, although may seem like restrictions, actually stimulate the implementation of measures to improve energy conservation. Developing an energy strategy for an enterprise is a complex process that requires considering several factors and reviewing them periodically in connection with new technological advancements and competitor initiatives. Without such a strategy, a company cannot create a clear and precise program to improve energy efficiency, which is essential to be a competitive production today. However, it is worth noting that developing an energy efficiency program for a production complex is particularly challenging. It is because optimizing the energy efficiency of individual components alone cannot ensure the overall energy efficiency of the complex as it is a complex socioeconomic system. To maintain competitiveness, the enterprise should reduce its costs, which can be achieved through energy efficiency and energy-saving programs based on a cost leadership strategy. This strategy involves reducing product prices by reducing costs (including energy costs) to attract more consumers, resulting in increased profit volumes. Alternatively, the enterprise can reduce costs (including energy) without reducing product prices while maintaining market share, resulting in increased profit from the sale of each unit of production. A cost reduction strategy to improve energy efficiency and save energy should consider the existence of such costs in almost all parts of the company's value chain, with the scale of production being the most important.</description>
      <author>Alexey Mikhaylov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-51532-3_4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating sulfur migration and transformation in low water-binder ratio cementitious system incorporating phosphogypsum aggregate: environmentally friendly clean materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109586</link>
      <description>X.J. Liu, Chiqiu Wu, Wei Lv, Enlai Dong, Shiyuan Fu, Lingyan Zhang, Yuan Ping Feng, Rui Yu, Journal of building engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789792

                The paper aims to clarify the regulation mechanism of sulfur migration and transformation in a low water-binder ratio system incorporating phosphogypsum aggregate (LWC-PG). Firstly, the combination of S-containing adhesive material and phosphate gypsum aggregate can reduce the migration of sulfate ions (SO42-) in the phosphate gypsum aggregate. The reaction mechanism and macro and micro properties of LWC-PG are characterized by universal testing machine, low field nuclear magnetic field, isothermal calorimeter, XRD diffractometer, scanning electron microscope and nano-indentation. The results show that the calcium sulfoaluminate cementitious system (CSA) is compatible with PG. The results show that CSA is compatible with PG, and the 28d strength of 80% phosphogypsum is 83.4MPa, which can maintain the required strength for high-performance concrete. Secondly, the sulfides in PG react with C4A6S in CSA, resulting in the formation of ettringite that coats the surface of the C-S-H gel, thereby retarding the hydration rate of the slurry. However, due to the presence of phosphate gypsum aggregate, the reaction continues, enhancing the hydration of sulfate cement. Moreover, the interfacial transition zone between the PG and matrix exhibits a strong bond and shows no significant signs of deterioration. Lastly, when using 80% phosphogypsum aggregate instead of natural sand and gravel to produce 100 m3 of concrete, 42 t of phosphogypsum aggregate can be used, which reduces the consumption of natural sand and gravel by 61.4 t, decreases energy consumption by 3070 MJ, reduces CO2 emissions by 178.06 kg, SO2 emissions by 0.37 kg, NOX emissions by 0.25 kg, and dust emissions by 0.087 kg. Life cycle evaluation demonstrates that the production of LWC-PG is associated with low carbon emissions and environmental friendliness, which significantly reduces environmental burden. This is of significant research importance for solid waste management and energy-saving and carbon reduction efforts.</description>
      <author>X.J. Liu, Chiqiu Wu, Wei Lv, Enlai Dong, Shiyuan Fu, Lingyan Zhang, Yuan Ping Feng, Rui Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anoxic photolysis as a Route to Primary Metabolites on Early Earth</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-w7svp</link>
      <description>Olga Taran, Baris Unal, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396759470

                Despite many years of research, results from prebiotic chemistry experiments&#8212;where biologically relevant compounds are formed from simple monomers such as cyanate, CO2, or formaldehyde&#8212; still yield complex mixtures with only trace amounts of the molecules of interest. The prevailing idea that life originated from a sequence of chemical reactions, starting from very simple active molecules and evolving into progressively more complex systems, might be incorrect for two reasons: First, after 70 years of experiments, we still lack robust experimental demonstration of such networks; second, small reactive molecules typically do not exist in high concentrations and readily react to form tars and other complex mixtures. Here I adopt an alternative approach, demonstrating that numerous primary metabolites can be derived from tar-like mixtures through the Advanced Reduction Process (ARP). Tars are formed by polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs), which are widespread in the Universe and likely were the main source of organic carbon on early Earth. Under conditions thought to exist on the prebiotic Earth&#8212;characterized by sunlight, an anoxic sulfur-rich atmosphere, and iron-rich dust - PAH suspensions in water are decomposed to succinic, lactic, malonic, and glycolic acids, all known as primary metabolites in all living systems and main components of ubiquitous citric acid cycle. The sum of reaction yields for these biologically important metabolites reaches up to 40%, with individual product yields ranging from 1-15%. The simplicity of this reaction and the ubiquity of PAHs on prebiotic Earth make this process particularly appealing, suggesting it could have occurred on a vast scale on sunlit planetary surfaces. These findings may reveal an overlooked initial step in the origin of life on Earth, and potentially elsewhere in the Universe.</description>
      <author>Olga Taran, Baris Unal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-w7svp</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Second-Life Electric Vehicle Batteries for Home Photovoltaic Systems: Transforming Energy Storage and Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102345</link>
      <description>Md. Tanjil Sarker, Mohammed Hussein Saleh Mohammed Haram, Siow Jat Shern, Gobbi Ramasamy, Fahmid Al Farid, Energies. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396872441

                Solar-based home PV systems are the most amazing eco-friendly energy innovations in the world, which are not only climate-friendly but also cost-effective solutions. The tropical environment of Malaysia makes it difficult to adopt photovoltaic (PV) systems because of the protracted rainy monsoon season, which makes PV systems useless without backup batteries. Large quantities of lithium-ion battery (LIB) trash are being produced by the electric vehicle (EV) sector. A total of 75% of the highest capacity levels have been discarded. By 2035, it is predicted that the wasted LIBs held as a result of expensive recycling and difficult material separation would carry up to 1200 GWh. An economical and sustainable option is offered by our study, which prototypes a replicated LIB pack that is incorporated into a PV home system. This study investigates the transformational power of second-life electric vehicle batteries (SLEVBs) when incorporated into home photovoltaic (PV) systems. The concept entails reusing existing electric vehicle batteries for stationary applications, offering a unique approach to extending the life of these batteries while meeting the growing need for sustainable domestic energy storage. The study looks at the technological feasibility, economic viability, and environmental effect of introducing SLEVBs into household PV systems, giving vital insight into their role in revolutionizing energy storage techniques and promoting sustainability. In comparison to the Lead&#8211;Acid Battery (LAB) system, the SLEVB system has a cheaper total cost of ownership, with savings of 12.62% compared with new LABs. A CO2 emission reduction of at least 20% is achieved by using the SLEVB system compared with LABs. Electricity can be provided in houses in rural areas where there is no electricity. As a result, the security and superiority of the life of rural residents will improve. It is anticipated that the suggested strategy will lower EV pricing, enabling EV adoption for M40 and B40 groups. Consequently, the Malaysian and worldwide EV business will remain viable.</description>
      <author>Md. Tanjil Sarker, Mohammed Hussein Saleh Mohammed Haram, Siow Jat Shern, Gobbi Ramasamy, Fahmid Al Farid</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17102345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenness of moss biocrusts derived from RGB image is a reliable indicator to estimate biocrust carbon-fixation rates in drylands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2024.112129</link>
      <description>Dexun Qiu, Anita Antoninka, Bo Xiao, Ecological indicators. 163(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396842920

                Biocrusts are common living covers found across drylands worldwide, and their photosynthesis substantially contributes to carbon input in these ecosystems. However, direct monitoring of biocrusts' photosynthetic carbon fixation is challenging due to their scattered distribution, dark pigments, and lower CO2 exchange rate. Current studies have limited monitoring frequency and the results are difficult to extend to a broader spatial scale. Greenness typically functions as an indicator of both vegetation cover and plant photosynthesis. Monitoring biocrust greenness is expected to be able to provide insights into their environmental responses and estimate carbon fixation rates, particularly for moss biocrusts. Here, we monitored greenness, soil moisture and temperature, and gross primary productivity (GPP) of moss biocrusts, as well as climatic factors over two years in the northern China's Loess Plateau. The results indicated that moss biocrust greenness was highly sensitive to changing environmental conditions and exhibited significant temporal variability. Moss biocrust greenness exhibited a notably higher value in wet season (0.384) than in dry season (0.259). According to these greenness values, we proposed moss biocrust activity and classified it into high (&gt;0.403), medium (0.334&#8211;0.403), low (0.271&#8211;0.333), and dormancy (&lt;0.270). Soil moisture, relative humidity, and wind speed were the three main determinates of moss biocrust greenness. Higher soil moisture and relative humidity were linked to increased greenness, whereas elevated wind speed led to a reduction. In dry seasons, soil moisture contributed 23.4 % to the variation in moss biocrust greenness, while in wet seasons relative humidity contributed 16.1 %. A significant and positive correlation between moss biocrust greenness and GPP was found, and annual GPP prediction based on greenness using machine learning performed well. Our study highlights the significance of moss biocrust greenness and their potential as indicators for moss biocrust photosynthetic carbon fixation rates and possibly other ecological functions in drylands.</description>
      <author>Dexun Qiu, Anita Antoninka, Bo Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2024.112129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indicators of Global Climate Change 2023: annual update of key indicators of the state of the climate system and human influence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-2024-149</link>
      <description>Piers M. Forster, Christopher J. Smith, Tristram Walsh, William F. Lamb, Robin Lamboll, B. D. Hall, Mathias Hauser, Aur&#233;lien Ribes, Debbie Rosen, Nathan P. Gillett, Matthew D. Palmer, Joeri Rogelj, Karina von Schuckmann, Blair Trewin, Myles Allen, Robbie M. Andrew, Richard Betts, Tim Boyer, Carlo Buontempo, Samantha Burgess, Chiara Cagnazzo, Lijing Cheng, Pierre Friedlingstein, Andrew Gettelman, Johannes G&#252;tschow, Masayoshi Ishii, Stuart Jenkins, Lan X, Colin Morice, Jens M&#252;hle, Christopher Kadow, John Kennedy, Rachel Killick, P. B. Krummel, Jan C. Minx, Gunnar Myhre, Vaishali Na&#239;k, Glen P. Peters, Anna Pirani, Julia Pongratz, Carl&#8208;Friedrich Schleussner, Sonia I. Seneviratne, Sophie Szopa, Peter Thorne, Mahesh Kovilakam, Elisa Majam&#228;ki, Jukka-Pekka Jalkanen, Margreet van Marle, Rachel Hoesly, R. A. Rohde, Dominik L. Schumacher, Guido R. van der Werf, Russell S. Vose, Kirsten Zickfeld, Xuebin Zhang, Val&#233;rie Masson&#8208;Delmotte, Panmao Zhai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720861

                Abstract. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) assessments are the trusted source of scientific evidence for climate negotiations taking place under the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). Evidence-based decision-making needs to be informed by up-to-date and timely information on key indicators of the state of the climate system and of the human influence on the global climate system. However, successive IPCC reports are published at intervals of 5&#8211;10 years, creating potential for an information gap between report cycles. We follow methods as close as possible to those used in the IPCC Sixth Assessment Report (AR6) Working Group One (WGI) report. We compile monitoring datasets to produce estimates for key climate indicators related to forcing of the climate system: emissions of greenhouse gases and short-lived climate forcers, greenhouse gas concentrations, radiative forcing, the Earth's energy imbalance, surface temperature changes, warming attributed to human activities, the remaining carbon budget, and estimates of global temperature extremes. The purpose of this effort, grounded in an open data, open science approach, is to make annually updated reliable global climate indicators available in the public domain (https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.11064126, Smith et al., 2024a). As they are traceable to IPCC report methods, they can be trusted by all parties involved in UNFCCC negotiations and help convey wider understanding of the latest knowledge of the climate system and its direction of travel. The indicators show that, for the 2014&#8211;2023 decade average, observed warming was 1.19 [1.06 to 1.30] &#176;C, of which 1.19 [1.0 to 1.4] &#176;C was human-induced. For the single year average, human-induced warming reached 1.31 [1.1 to 1.7] &#176;C in 2023 relative to 1850&#8211;1900. This is below the 2023 observed record of 1.43 [1.32 to 1.53] &#176;C, indicating a substantial contribution of internal variability in the 2023 record. Human-induced warming has been increasing at rate that is unprecedented in the instrumental record, reaching 0.26 [0.2&#8211;0.4] &#176;C per decade over 2014&#8211;2023. This high rate of warming is caused by a combination of greenhouse gas emissions being at an all-time high of 54 &#177; 5.4 GtCO2e per year over the last decade, as well as reductions in the strength of aerosol cooling. Despite this, there is evidence that the rate of increase in CO2 emissions over the last decade has slowed compared to the 2000s, and depending on societal choices, a continued series of these annual updates over the critical 2020s decade could track a change of direction for some of the indicators presented here.</description>
      <author>Piers M. Forster, Christopher J. Smith, Tristram Walsh, William F. Lamb, Robin Lamboll, B. D. Hall, Mathias Hauser, Aur&#233;lien Ribes, Debbie Rosen, Nathan P. Gillett, Matthew D. Palmer, Joeri Rogelj, Karina von Schuckmann, Blair Trewin, Myles Allen, Robbie M. Andrew, Richard Betts, Tim Boyer, Carlo Buontempo, Samantha Burgess, Chiara Cagnazzo, Lijing Cheng, Pierre Friedlingstein, Andrew Gettelman, Johannes G&#252;tschow, Masayoshi Ishii, Stuart Jenkins, Lan X, Colin Morice, Jens M&#252;hle, Christopher Kadow, John Kennedy, Rachel Killick, P. B. Krummel, Jan C. Minx, Gunnar Myhre, Vaishali Na&#239;k, Glen P. Peters, Anna Pirani, Julia Pongratz, Carl&#8208;Friedrich Schleussner, Sonia I. Seneviratne, Sophie Szopa, Peter Thorne, Mahesh Kovilakam, Elisa Majam&#228;ki, Jukka-Pekka Jalkanen, Margreet van Marle, Rachel Hoesly, R. A. Rohde, Dominik L. Schumacher, Guido R. van der Werf, Russell S. Vose, Kirsten Zickfeld, Xuebin Zhang, Val&#233;rie Masson&#8208;Delmotte, Panmao Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-2024-149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Characteristics and Product Distribution of Tar-Rich Coal In-Situ Underground Pyrolysis: Influence of Heterogeneous Seam</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4825036</link>
      <description>Zunyi Yu, Wei Guo, Panxi Yang, Fu Yang, Li Ma, Jing Wang, Hongqiang Li, Bolun Yang, Zhiqiang Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396838912

                Tar-rich coal contains more hydrogen-rich structures such as aliphatic side chains and bridge bonds, which is a good raw material for coal to oil. In-situ underground pyrolysis of tar-rich coal has significant advantages such as environmental friendliness and high safety factor; it is an efficient coal utilization technology. Due to the influence of geological structure and other factors in the formation process, underground coal seam was often heterogeneous, generally accompanied by coal gangue interlayers. Due to the coal gangue being relatively dense and has poor thermal conductivity, it is also rich in metal oxides, it would inevitably affect the pyrolysis characteristics and product distribution during pyrolysis process of heterogeneous tar-rich coal seam. The pyrolysis characteristics of heterogeneous tar-rich coal seam with different positions and layers of coal gangue interlayer were investigated by the thermogravimetric analyzer, and related kinetic parameters were obtained by the distributed activation energy model (DAEM). Based on the fixed bed tube furnace reactor, the pyrolysis experiments of heterogeneous tar-rich coal seam with different positions and layers of coal gangue interlayer were also carried out, and the pyrolysis products were characterized and analyzed. The thermogravimetric results showed that in the pyrolysis process of heterogeneous tar-rich coal seam, the initial pyrolysis temperature and the temperature corresponding to maximum weight loss rate shifted to the higher temperature range, and the pyrolysis characteristic index decreased significantly. Under the same conditions, the corresponding pyrolysis characteristic indexes of the upper coal gangue interlayer and 4 layers of coal gangue interlayer were lower, which were 11.69 (10-8&#8901;%&#8901;min-1&#8901;&#176;C-3) and 11.65 (10-8&#8901;%&#8901;min-1&#8901;&#176;C-3), respectively. Compared with homogeneous tar-rich coal seam, pyrolysis activation energies of heterogeneous coal seam generally showed the decreasing trend. Under the conditions of the upper part containing coal gangue interlayer and the upper-and-lower parts containing coal gangue interlayer, the pyrolysis activation energies were higher due to the hindrance of the cover layer of coal gangue to the volatile release, which were 555.88 kJ&#183;mol-1 and 546.66 kJ&#183;mol-1 respectively. The results of fixed bed pyrolysis experiments showed that compared with homogeneous tar-rich coal seam, the tar yield obtained was reduced, the degree of tar lightening was significantly improved, and the proportion of lighter tar was up to 70.00 wt.%. The contents of aromatic hydrocarbons and phenolic compounds in tar increased, the contents of aliphatic hydrocarbons and oxygenated compounds decreased significantly, and the maximum reductions were nearly 4.50 wt.% and 6.50 wt.%, respectively. The gas yield increased, the proportions of H2 and CO2 in the gas increased, and the proportions of CO and CH4 decreased to varying degrees. The tar yields were lower under the conditions of upper gangue and 4 layers gangue, which were 6.53 wt.% and 5.81 wt.%, respectively, and the degrees of tar lightening were also more significant. From the relationship between pyrolysis characteristic parameters and tar properties of heterogeneous tar-rich coal seam pyrolysis, it was found that the existence of coal gangue interlayer was not conducive to the tar production, but it could promote the lightening of tar and improve the tar quality.</description>
      <author>Zunyi Yu, Wei Guo, Panxi Yang, Fu Yang, Li Ma, Jing Wang, Hongqiang Li, Bolun Yang, Zhiqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4825036</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
