<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:21:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A Hitchhiker's Guide to Deep Chemical Language Processing for Bioactivity Prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00311j</link>
      <description>R&#305;za &#214;z&#231;elik, Francesca Grisoni, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405454695

                Deep learning has significantly accelerated drug discovery, with 'chemical language' processing (CLP) emerging as a prominent approach. CLP learns from molecular string representations (e.g., Simplified Molecular Input Line Entry Systems...</description>
      <author>R&#305;za &#214;z&#231;elik, Francesca Grisoni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00311j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calibration-Free Quantification and Automated Data Analysis for High-Throughput Reaction Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00347k</link>
      <description>Felix Katzenburg, Florian Boser, Felix Sch&#228;fer, Philipp Pflueger, Frank Glorius, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405473080

                The accelerated generation of reaction data through high-throughput experimentation and automation has the potential to boost organic synthesis. However, efforts to generate diverse reaction datasets or identify generally applicable reaction...</description>
      <author>Felix Katzenburg, Florian Boser, Felix Sch&#228;fer, Philipp Pflueger, Frank Glorius</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00347k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schedule Optimization for Chemical Library Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00327f</link>
      <description>Qianxiang Ai, Fanwang Meng, Runzhong Wang, Joachim Klein, Alexander G. Godfrey, Connor W. Coley, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405502589

                Automated chemistry platforms hold the potential to enable large-scale organic synthesis campaigns, such as producing a library of compounds for biological evaluation. The efficiency of such platforms will depend on...</description>
      <author>Qianxiang Ai, Fanwang Meng, Runzhong Wang, Joachim Klein, Alexander G. Godfrey, Connor W. Coley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00327f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid-LLM-GNN: Integrating Large Language Models and Graph Neural Networks for Enhanced Materials Property Prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00199k</link>
      <description>Youjia Li, Vishu Gupta, Muhammed Nur Talha Kilic, Kamal Choudhary, Daniel Wines, Wei&#8208;keng Liao, Alok Choudhary, Ankit Agrawal, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405535846

                Graph-centric learning has attracted significant interest in materials informatics. Accordingly, a family of graph-based machine learning models, primarily utilizing Graph Neural Networks (GNN), has been developed to provide accurate prediction...</description>
      <author>Youjia Li, Vishu Gupta, Muhammed Nur Talha Kilic, Kamal Choudhary, Daniel Wines, Wei&#8208;keng Liao, Alok Choudhary, Ankit Agrawal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00199k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Discovery from Porous Organic Cages Literature Using a Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00337c</link>
      <description>Yong&#8208;Liang Su, Siyuan Yang, Ming Liu, Aiting Kai, Linjiang Chen, Ming Liu, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405591138

                Porous organic cages (POCs) are an emerging subclass of porous materials, drawing increasing attention due to their structural tunability, modularity and processibility, with the research in this area rapidly expanding....</description>
      <author>Yong&#8208;Liang Su, Siyuan Yang, Ming Liu, Aiting Kai, Linjiang Chen, Ming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00337c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity Recognition in Scientific Experimentation using Multimodal Visual Encoding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00287c</link>
      <description>Gianmarco Gabrieli, I. Morales, Dimitrios Christofidellis, Mara Graziani, Andrea Giovannini, Federico Zipoli, Amol Thakkar, Antonio Foncubierta, Matteo Manica, Patrick Ruch, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405599463

                Capturing actions during scientific experimentation is a cornerstone of reproducibility and collaborative research. While large multimodal models hold promise for automatic action (or activity) recognition, their ability to provide real-time...</description>
      <author>Gianmarco Gabrieli, I. Morales, Dimitrios Christofidellis, Mara Graziani, Andrea Giovannini, Federico Zipoli, Amol Thakkar, Antonio Foncubierta, Matteo Manica, Patrick Ruch</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00287c</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
