<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 01:24:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven analysis of text-mined seed-mediated syntheses of gold nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00158c</link>
      <description>Sanghoon Lee, Kevin Cruse, Samuel P. Gleason, A. Paul Alivisatos, Gerbrand Ceder, Anubhav Jain, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404639435

                Gold nanoparticle synthesis recipes were extracted from the literature to obtain data-driven hypotheses for synthesis outcome morphology and size. Used images from https://Flaticon.com.</description>
      <author>Sanghoon Lee, Kevin Cruse, Samuel P. Gleason, A. Paul Alivisatos, Gerbrand Ceder, Anubhav Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00158c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Framework for Reviewing the Results of Automated Conversion of Structured Organic Synthesis Procedures from the Literature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00335g</link>
      <description>Kojiro Machi, Seiji Akiyama, Yuuya Nagata, Masaharu Yoshioka, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404733186

                Organic synthesis procedures in the scientific literature are typically shared in prose (i.e., as unstructured data), which is not suitable for data-driven research applications. To represent such procedures, there is...</description>
      <author>Kojiro Machi, Seiji Akiyama, Yuuya Nagata, Masaharu Yoshioka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00335g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for accelerated prediction of lattice thermal conductivity at arbitrary temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00286e</link>
      <description>Zihe Li, Mengke Li, Yufeng Luo, Haibin Cao, Huijun Liu, Ying Fang, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404759490

                Efficient evaluation of lattice thermal conductivity (&#954; L ) is critical for applications ranging from thermal management to energy conversion. In this work, we propose a neural network (NN) model that allows...</description>
      <author>Zihe Li, Mengke Li, Yufeng Luo, Haibin Cao, Huijun Liu, Ying Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00286e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Prediction of Conformationally-Dependent DFT-Level Descriptors using Graph Neural Networks for Carboxylic Acids and Alkyl Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00284a</link>
      <description>Brittany C. Haas, Melissa A. Hardy, S. V. Shree Sowndarya, Keir Adams, Connor W. Coley, Robert S. Paton, Matthew S. Sigman, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404811330

                Data-driven reaction discovery and development is a growing field that relies on the use of molecular descriptors to capture key information about substrates, ligands, and targets. Broad adaptation of this...</description>
      <author>Brittany C. Haas, Melissa A. Hardy, S. V. Shree Sowndarya, Keir Adams, Connor W. Coley, Robert S. Paton, Matthew S. Sigman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00284a</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
