<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:21:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Features of Chemical Elements Extracted from Local Geometries in Crystal Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00346b</link>
      <description>Andrij Vasylenko, Dmytro Antypov, Sven Schewe, Luke M. Daniels, John B. Claridge, Matthew S. Dyer, Matthew J. Rosseinsky, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406037181

                Computational modelling of materials using machine learning (ML) and historical data has become integral to materials research across physical sciences. The accuracy of predictions for material properties using computational modelling...</description>
      <author>Andrij Vasylenko, Dmytro Antypov, Sven Schewe, Luke M. Daniels, John B. Claridge, Matthew S. Dyer, Matthew J. Rosseinsky</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00346b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Predictive Toxicology: Overcoming Hurdles and Shaping the Future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00257a</link>
      <description>Sara Masarone, Katie V Victoria Beckwith, Matthew Wilkinson, Shreshth Tuli, Amy Lane, S Windsor, Jordan Lane, Layla Hosseini-Gerami, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406085336

                Modern drug discovery projects are plagued with high failure rate many of which have safety as the underlying cause. The drug discovery process involves selecting the right compounds from a...</description>
      <author>Sara Masarone, Katie V Victoria Beckwith, Matthew Wilkinson, Shreshth Tuli, Amy Lane, S Windsor, Jordan Lane, Layla Hosseini-Gerami</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00257a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-objective Bayesian Optimization: A Case Study in Material Extrusion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00281d</link>
      <description>Jay I. Myung, James R. Deneault, Jorge Chang, Inhan Kang, Benji Maruyama, Mark A. Pitt, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406087434

                Autonomous experimentation is a rapidly growing approach to materials science research. Machine learning can assist in improving the efficiency and capability of experimentation with algorithms that adaptively identify optimal design...</description>
      <author>Jay I. Myung, James R. Deneault, Jorge Chang, Inhan Kang, Benji Maruyama, Mark A. Pitt</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00281d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Approach to Protein Chemical Shifts Prediction from Sequence Using Protein Language Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00367e</link>
      <description>He Zhu, Lidan Hu, Yang Yu, Z Chen, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406117605

                Chemical shifts are crucial parameters in protein Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) experiments. Specifically, Chemical shifts of backbone atoms are essential for determining the constraints in protein structure analysis. Despite their...</description>
      <author>He Zhu, Lidan Hu, Yang Yu, Z Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00367e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active learning driven prioritisation of compounds from on-demand libraries targeting the SARS-CoV-2 main protease</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00343h</link>
      <description>Ben Cree, M. Bieniek, Siddique Amin, Akane Kawamura, D. J. A. Cole, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406183574

                FEgrow is an open-source software package for building congeneric series of compounds in protein binding pockets. For a given ligand core and receptor structure, it employs hybrid machine learning /...</description>
      <author>Ben Cree, M. Bieniek, Siddique Amin, Akane Kawamura, D. J. A. Cole</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00343h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ULaMDyn: Enhancing Excited-State Dynamics Analysis Through Streamlined Unsupervised Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00374h</link>
      <description>Max Pinheiro, Matheus de Oliveira Bispo, Rafael S. Mattos, Mariana T. do Casal, Bidhan Chandra Garain, Josene M. Toldo, Saikat Mukherjee, Mario Barbatti, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406185387

                The analysis of nonadiabatic molecular dynamics (NAMD) data presents significant challenges due to its high dimensionality and complexity. To address these issues, we introduce ULaMDyn, a Pythonbased, open-source package designed...</description>
      <author>Max Pinheiro, Matheus de Oliveira Bispo, Rafael S. Mattos, Mariana T. do Casal, Bidhan Chandra Garain, Josene M. Toldo, Saikat Mukherjee, Mario Barbatti</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00374h</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
