<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 01:36:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive sampling of coverage effects in catalysis by leveraging generalization in neural network models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00328d</link>
      <description>Daniel Schwalbe&#8208;Koda, Nitish Govindarajan, Joel B. Varley, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405193217

                A combination of generalization in neural networks and fast data pipelines enables comprehensive sampling coverage and co-adsorption effects in heterogeneous catalyst models.</description>
      <author>Daniel Schwalbe&#8208;Koda, Nitish Govindarajan, Joel B. Varley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00328d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;Al NMR chemical shifts in zeolite MFI via machine learning acceleration of structure sampling and shift prediction.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00306c</link>
      <description>Daniel Willimetz, Andreas Erlebach, Christopher J. Heard, Luk&#225;&#353; Grajciar, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405200804

                Zeolites, such as MFI, are versatile microporous aluminosilicate materials that are widely used in catalysis and adsorption processes. The location of the aluminium within the zeolite framework is one of...</description>
      <author>Daniel Willimetz, Andreas Erlebach, Christopher J. Heard, Luk&#225;&#353; Grajciar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00306c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MatFold: systematic insights into materials discovery models&#8217; performance through standardized cross-validation protocols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00250d</link>
      <description>Matthew Witman, Peter Schindler, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405203246

                Machine learning (ML) models in the materials sciences that are validated by overly simplistic cross-validation (CV) protocols can yield biased performance estimates for downstream modeling or materials screening tasks. This...</description>
      <author>Matthew Witman, Peter Schindler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00250d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Mechanical Properties of Non-Equimolar High-Entropy Carbides using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00243a</link>
      <description>Xi Zhao, Shu-guang Cheng, S. F. Yu, Jiming Zheng, Ruizhi Zhang, Meng Guo, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405265950

                High-entropy carbides (HECs) have garnered significant attention due to their unique mechanic properties. However, the design of novel HECs has been limited by extensive trial-and-error strategies, along with insufficient knowledge...</description>
      <author>Xi Zhao, Shu-guang Cheng, S. F. Yu, Jiming Zheng, Ruizhi Zhang, Meng Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00243a</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
