<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 01:21:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Acquisition of absorption and fluorescence spectral data using chatbots</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00255e</link>
      <description>Masahiko Taniguchi, Jonathan S. Lindsey, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405421036

                Spectra &#8211; the lifeblood of photochemistry &#8211; have been very difficult to find in the literature. Chatbots, remarkably, may enable their more efficient acquisition and prove to be generally powerful tools for searching the scientific literature.</description>
      <author>Masahiko Taniguchi, Jonathan S. Lindsey</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00255e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hitchhiker's Guide to Deep Chemical Language Processing for Bioactivity Prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00311j</link>
      <description>R&#305;za &#214;z&#231;elik, Francesca Grisoni, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405454695

                Deep learning has significantly accelerated drug discovery, with 'chemical language' processing (CLP) emerging as a prominent approach. CLP learns from molecular string representations (e.g., Simplified Molecular Input Line Entry Systems...</description>
      <author>R&#305;za &#214;z&#231;elik, Francesca Grisoni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00311j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calibration-Free Quantification and Automated Data Analysis for High-Throughput Reaction Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00347k</link>
      <description>Felix Katzenburg, Florian Boser, Felix Sch&#228;fer, Philipp Pflueger, Frank Glorius, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405473080

                The accelerated generation of reaction data through high-throughput experimentation and automation has the potential to boost organic synthesis. However, efforts to generate diverse reaction datasets or identify generally applicable reaction...</description>
      <author>Felix Katzenburg, Florian Boser, Felix Sch&#228;fer, Philipp Pflueger, Frank Glorius</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00347k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schedule Optimization for Chemical Library Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00327f</link>
      <description>Qianxiang Ai, Fanwang Meng, Runzhong Wang, Joachim Klein, Alexander G. Godfrey, Connor W. Coley, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405502589

                Automated chemistry platforms hold the potential to enable large-scale organic synthesis campaigns, such as producing a library of compounds for biological evaluation. The efficiency of such platforms will depend on...</description>
      <author>Qianxiang Ai, Fanwang Meng, Runzhong Wang, Joachim Klein, Alexander G. Godfrey, Connor W. Coley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00327f</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
