<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 01:26:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of Molecular Conformations using Generative Adversarial Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00179f</link>
      <description>Congsheng Xu, Xiaomei Deng, Yi Lu, Peiyuan Yu, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404496394

                The accurate determination of a molecule&#8217;s accessible conformations is key to the success of studying its properties. Traditional computational methods for exploring the conformational space of molecules such as molecular...</description>
      <author>Congsheng Xu, Xiaomei Deng, Yi Lu, Peiyuan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00179f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Analysis of Miniature Synaptic Calcium Transients Using Positive Unlabeled Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00197d</link>
      <description>Frederic Beaupr&#233;, Anthony Bilodeau, Theresa Wiesner, G. LECLERC, Mado Lemieux, Gabriel Nadeau, Katrine Castonguay, Bi Fan, Simon Labrecque, Ren&#233;e Hlo&#382;ek, Paul De Koninck, Christian Gagn&#233;, Flavie Lavoie&#8208;Cardinal, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404534236

                Ca 2+ imaging methods are widely used for studying cellular activity in the brain, allowing detailed analysis of dynamic processes across various scales. Enhanced by high-contrast optical microscopy and fluorescent Ca 2+ ...</description>
      <author>Frederic Beaupr&#233;, Anthony Bilodeau, Theresa Wiesner, G. LECLERC, Mado Lemieux, Gabriel Nadeau, Katrine Castonguay, Bi Fan, Simon Labrecque, Ren&#233;e Hlo&#382;ek, Paul De Koninck, Christian Gagn&#233;, Flavie Lavoie&#8208;Cardinal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00197d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated High-throughput Organic Crystal Structure Prediction via Population-based Sampling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00264d</link>
      <description>Qiang Zhu, Shinnosuke Hattori, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404536367

                With advancements in computational molecular modeling and powerful structure search methods, it is now possible to systematically screen crystal structures for small organic molecules. In this context, we introduce the...</description>
      <author>Qiang Zhu, Shinnosuke Hattori</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00264d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven analysis of text-mined seed-mediated syntheses of gold nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00158c</link>
      <description>Sanghoon Lee, Kevin Cruse, Samuel P. Gleason, A. Paul Alivisatos, Gerbrand Ceder, Anubhav Jain, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404639435

                Gold nanoparticle synthesis recipes were extracted from the literature to obtain data-driven hypotheses for synthesis outcome morphology and size. Used images from https://Flaticon.com.</description>
      <author>Sanghoon Lee, Kevin Cruse, Samuel P. Gleason, A. Paul Alivisatos, Gerbrand Ceder, Anubhav Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00158c</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
