<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:18:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Does one need to polish electrodes in an eight pattern? Automation provides the answer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00323c</link>
      <description>Naruki Yoshikawa, Gun Deniz Akkoc, Sergio Pablo&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Yang Cao, Han Hao, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406246894

                Automation of electrochemical measurements can accelerate the discovery of new electroactive materials.</description>
      <author>Naruki Yoshikawa, Gun Deniz Akkoc, Sergio Pablo&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Yang Cao, Han Hao, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00323c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Agents in Chemical Research: GVIM - An Intelligent Research Assistant System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00398e</link>
      <description>Kangyong Ma, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406236141

                This work utilizes collected and organized instructional data from the field of chemical science to fine-tune mainstream open-source large language models. To objectively evaluate the performance of the fine-tuned models,...</description>
      <author>Kangyong Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00398e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated computational workflows for muon spin spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00314d</link>
      <description>Ifeanyi John Onuorah, Miki Bonacci, Muhammad Maikudi Isah, Marcello Mazzani, R. De Renzi, Giovanni Pizzi, Pietro Bonf&#224;, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406242505

                Positive muon spin rotation and relaxation spectroscopy is a well established experimental technique for studying materials. It provides a local probe that generally complements scattering techniques in the study of...</description>
      <author>Ifeanyi John Onuorah, Miki Bonacci, Muhammad Maikudi Isah, Marcello Mazzani, R. De Renzi, Giovanni Pizzi, Pietro Bonf&#224;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00314d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Data Management Workflow to Process Tabular Data in Automated and High-throughput Heterogeneous Catalysis Research</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00350k</link>
      <description>Erwin Lam, Tanguy Maury, Stefan Preiss, Yuhui Hou, Hannes Frey, Caterina Barillari, Paco Laveille, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406248117

                Data management and processing are crucial steps to implement streamlined and standardized data workflows for automated and high-throughput laboratories. Electronic laboratory notebooks (ELNs) have proven to be effective to manage...</description>
      <author>Erwin Lam, Tanguy Maury, Stefan Preiss, Yuhui Hou, Hannes Frey, Caterina Barillari, Paco Laveille</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00350k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting hydrogen atom transfer energy barriers using Gaussian process regression</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00174e</link>
      <description>E. A. Ulanov, Ghul&#257;m Q&#257;dir, Kai Riedmiller, Pascal Friederich, Frauke Gr&#228;ter, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406276896

                Predicting reaction barriers for arbitrary configurations based on only a limited set of density functional theory (DFT) calculations would render the design of catalysts or the simulation of reactions within...</description>
      <author>E. A. Ulanov, Ghul&#257;m Q&#257;dir, Kai Riedmiller, Pascal Friederich, Frauke Gr&#228;ter</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00174e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimising Digital Twin Laboratories with Conversational AIs: Enhancing Immersive Training and Simulation through Virtual Reality</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00330f</link>
      <description>Mae Taylor, Zaid Muwaffak, Matthew R. Penny, Blanka R. Szulc, Steven R. Brown, Andy Merritt, Stephen T. Hilton, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406335943

                Digital twin laboratories, accessible through low-cost, portable virtual reality (VR) headsets, have become a powerful tool in chemical education and research collaboration. These immersive digital environments replicate physical laboratories, offering...</description>
      <author>Mae Taylor, Zaid Muwaffak, Matthew R. Penny, Blanka R. Szulc, Steven R. Brown, Andy Merritt, Stephen T. Hilton</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00330f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A multi-robot-multi-task scheduling system for autonomous chemistry laboratories</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00313f</link>
      <description>Junyi Zhou, Man Luo, Linjiang Chen, Qing Zhu, Shan Jiang, Fei Zhang, Weiwei Shang, Jun Jiang, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406371854

                We present a multi-robot-multi-task scheduling system designed for autonomous chemistry laboratories to enhance the efficiency of executing complex chemical experiments. Building on the herein formulated and developed scheduling algorithms and...</description>
      <author>Junyi Zhou, Man Luo, Linjiang Chen, Qing Zhu, Shan Jiang, Fei Zhang, Weiwei Shang, Jun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00313f</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
