<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 01:27:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Resonance Theory: Forecasting the Flow of Programmable Catalytic Loops</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00216d</link>
      <description>Madeline A. Murphy, Kyle Noordhoek, Sallye R. Gathmann, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Christopher J. Bartel, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405892021

                Chemical transformations on catalyst surfaces occur through series and parallel reaction pathways. These complex networks and their behavior can be most simply evaluated through a three-species surface reaction loop (A*...</description>
      <author>Madeline A. Murphy, Kyle Noordhoek, Sallye R. Gathmann, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Christopher J. Bartel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00216d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SMARTpy: A Python Package for the Generation of Cavity Steric Molecular Descriptors and Applications to Diverse Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00329b</link>
      <description>Beck R. Miller, Ryan C. Cammarota, Matthew S. Sigman, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406003754

                Steric molecular descriptors designed for machine learning (ML) applications are critical for connecting structure-function relationships to mechanistic insight. However, many of these descriptors are not suitable for application to complex...</description>
      <author>Beck R. Miller, Ryan C. Cammarota, Matthew S. Sigman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00329b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Features of Chemical Elements Extracted from Local Geometries in Crystal Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00346b</link>
      <description>Andrij Vasylenko, Dmytro Antypov, Sven Schewe, Luke M. Daniels, John B. Claridge, Matthew S. Dyer, Matthew J. Rosseinsky, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406037181

                Computational modelling of materials using machine learning (ML) and historical data has become integral to materials research across physical sciences. The accuracy of predictions for material properties using computational modelling...</description>
      <author>Andrij Vasylenko, Dmytro Antypov, Sven Schewe, Luke M. Daniels, John B. Claridge, Matthew S. Dyer, Matthew J. Rosseinsky</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00346b</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
