<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 01:37:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A Framework for Reviewing the Results of Automated Conversion of Structured Organic Synthesis Procedures from the Literature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00335g</link>
      <description>Kojiro Machi, Seiji Akiyama, Yuuya Nagata, Masaharu Yoshioka, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404733186

                Organic synthesis procedures in the scientific literature are typically shared in prose (i.e., as unstructured data), which is not suitable for data-driven research applications. To represent such procedures, there is...</description>
      <author>Kojiro Machi, Seiji Akiyama, Yuuya Nagata, Masaharu Yoshioka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00335g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for accelerated prediction of lattice thermal conductivity at arbitrary temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00286e</link>
      <description>Zihe Li, Mengke Li, Yufeng Luo, Haibin Cao, Huijun Liu, Ying Fang, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404759490

                Efficient evaluation of lattice thermal conductivity (&#954; L ) is critical for applications ranging from thermal management to energy conversion. In this work, we propose a neural network (NN) model that allows...</description>
      <author>Zihe Li, Mengke Li, Yufeng Luo, Haibin Cao, Huijun Liu, Ying Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00286e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Prediction of Conformationally-Dependent DFT-Level Descriptors using Graph Neural Networks for Carboxylic Acids and Alkyl Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00284a</link>
      <description>Brittany C. Haas, Melissa A. Hardy, S. V. Shree Sowndarya, Keir Adams, Connor W. Coley, Robert S. Paton, Matthew S. Sigman, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404811330

                Data-driven reaction discovery and development is a growing field that relies on the use of molecular descriptors to capture key information about substrates, ligands, and targets. Broad adaptation of this...</description>
      <author>Brittany C. Haas, Melissa A. Hardy, S. V. Shree Sowndarya, Keir Adams, Connor W. Coley, Robert S. Paton, Matthew S. Sigman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00284a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph Neural Network-State Predictive Information Bottleneck (GNN-SPIB) approach for learning molecular thermodynamics and kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00315b</link>
      <description>Ziyue Zou, Dedi Wang, Pratyush Tiwary, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404818721

                Molecular dynamics simulations offer detailed insights into atomic motions but face timescale limitations. Enhanced sampling methods have addressed these challenges but even with machine learning, they often rely on pre-selected...</description>
      <author>Ziyue Zou, Dedi Wang, Pratyush Tiwary</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00315b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CopDDB: a descriptor database for copolymers and its applications to machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00266k</link>
      <description>Takayoshi Yoshimura, Hiromoto Kato, Shunto Oikawa, T. Inagaki, Shigehito Asano, Tetsunori Sugawara, Tomoyuki Miyao, Takamitsu Matsubara, Hiroharu Ajiro, Mikiya Fujii, Yu&#8208;ya Ohnishi, Miho Hatanaka, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404823970

                Polymer informatics, which involves applying data-driven science to polymers, has attracted considerable research interest. However, developing adequate descriptors for polymers, particularly copolymers, to facilitate machine learning (ML) models with limited...</description>
      <author>Takayoshi Yoshimura, Hiromoto Kato, Shunto Oikawa, T. Inagaki, Shigehito Asano, Tetsunori Sugawara, Tomoyuki Miyao, Takamitsu Matsubara, Hiroharu Ajiro, Mikiya Fujii, Yu&#8208;ya Ohnishi, Miho Hatanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00266k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PolyCL: Contrastive Learning for Polymer Representation Learning via Explicit and Implicit Augmentations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00236a</link>
      <description>Jiajun Zhou, Yijie Yang, Austin M. Mroz, Kim E. Jelfs, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404830438

                Polymers play a crucial role in a wide array of applications due to their diverse and tunable properties. Establishing the relationship between polymer representations and their properties is crucial to...</description>
      <author>Jiajun Zhou, Yijie Yang, Austin M. Mroz, Kim E. Jelfs</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00236a</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
