<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 01:27:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Prediction of Conformationally-Dependent DFT-Level Descriptors using Graph Neural Networks for Carboxylic Acids and Alkyl Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00284a</link>
      <description>Brittany C. Haas, Melissa A. Hardy, S. V. Shree Sowndarya, Keir Adams, Connor W. Coley, Robert S. Paton, Matthew S. Sigman, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404811330

                Data-driven reaction discovery and development is a growing field that relies on the use of molecular descriptors to capture key information about substrates, ligands, and targets. Broad adaptation of this...</description>
      <author>Brittany C. Haas, Melissa A. Hardy, S. V. Shree Sowndarya, Keir Adams, Connor W. Coley, Robert S. Paton, Matthew S. Sigman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00284a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph Neural Network-State Predictive Information Bottleneck (GNN-SPIB) approach for learning molecular thermodynamics and kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00315b</link>
      <description>Ziyue Zou, Dedi Wang, Pratyush Tiwary, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404818721

                Molecular dynamics simulations offer detailed insights into atomic motions but face timescale limitations. Enhanced sampling methods have addressed these challenges but even with machine learning, they often rely on pre-selected...</description>
      <author>Ziyue Zou, Dedi Wang, Pratyush Tiwary</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00315b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CopDDB: a descriptor database for copolymers and its applications to machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00266k</link>
      <description>Takayoshi Yoshimura, Hiromoto Kato, Shunto Oikawa, T. Inagaki, Shigehito Asano, Tetsunori Sugawara, Tomoyuki Miyao, Takamitsu Matsubara, Hiroharu Ajiro, Mikiya Fujii, Yu&#8208;ya Ohnishi, Miho Hatanaka, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404823970

                Polymer informatics, which involves applying data-driven science to polymers, has attracted considerable research interest. However, developing adequate descriptors for polymers, particularly copolymers, to facilitate machine learning (ML) models with limited...</description>
      <author>Takayoshi Yoshimura, Hiromoto Kato, Shunto Oikawa, T. Inagaki, Shigehito Asano, Tetsunori Sugawara, Tomoyuki Miyao, Takamitsu Matsubara, Hiroharu Ajiro, Mikiya Fujii, Yu&#8208;ya Ohnishi, Miho Hatanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00266k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PolyCL: Contrastive Learning for Polymer Representation Learning via Explicit and Implicit Augmentations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00236a</link>
      <description>Jiajun Zhou, Yijie Yang, Austin M. Mroz, Kim E. Jelfs, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404830438

                Polymers play a crucial role in a wide array of applications due to their diverse and tunable properties. Establishing the relationship between polymer representations and their properties is crucial to...</description>
      <author>Jiajun Zhou, Yijie Yang, Austin M. Mroz, Kim E. Jelfs</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00236a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data efficiency of classification strategies for chemical and materials design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00298a</link>
      <description>Quinn Gallagher, Michael Webb, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404961437

                We benchmark the performance of space-filling and active learning algorithms on classification problems in materials science, revealing trends in optimally data-efficient algorithms.</description>
      <author>Quinn Gallagher, Michael Webb</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00298a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Materials Discovery Framework Based on Conditional Generative Models Applied to the Design of Polymer Electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00293h</link>
      <description>Arash Khajeh, X. L. Lei, Weike Ye, Zhenze Yang, Linda Hung, Daniel Schweigert, Ha-Kyung Kwon, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404984467

                In this work, we introduce a computational polymer discovery framework that efficiently designs polymers with tailored properties. The framework comprises three core components&#8212;--a conditioned generative model, a computational evaluation module,...</description>
      <author>Arash Khajeh, X. L. Lei, Weike Ye, Zhenze Yang, Linda Hung, Daniel Schweigert, Ha-Kyung Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00293h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back cover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90052a</link>
      <description>, Digital Discovery. 3(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405000977

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90052a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Front cover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90049a</link>
      <description>, Digital Discovery. 3(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405001196

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90049a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contents list</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90051k</link>
      <description>, Digital Discovery. 3(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405001228

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90051k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside front cover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90050b</link>
      <description>, Digital Discovery. 3(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405001263

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90050b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Exploration with Expert Knowledge (SEEK) in Autonomous Scanning Probe Microscopy with Active Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00277f</link>
      <description>Utkarsh Pratiush, Hiroshi Funakubo, Rama K. Vasudevan, Sergei V. Kalinin, Yongtao Liu, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405002930

                Microscopy techniques have played vital roles in materials science, biology, and nanotechnology, offering high-resolution imaging and detailed insights into properties at nanoscale and atomic level. The automation of microscopy experiments,...</description>
      <author>Utkarsh Pratiush, Hiroshi Funakubo, Rama K. Vasudevan, Sergei V. Kalinin, Yongtao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00277f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing High Entropy Alloy Spaces: Methods and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00262h</link>
      <description>Brent Vela, Trevor Hastings, Marshall Allen, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405016183

                Multi-Principal Element Alloys (MPEAs) have emerged as an exciting area of research in materials science in the 2020s, owing to the vast potential for discovering alloys with unique and tailored...</description>
      <author>Brent Vela, Trevor Hastings, Marshall Allen, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00262h</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
