<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 01:21:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence-assisted electrochemical sensors for qualitative and semi-quantitative multiplexed analyses</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00318g</link>
      <description>Rocco Cancelliere, Mario Molinara, Antonio Licheri, Antonio Maffucci, Laura Micheli, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406624736

                AI-integrated electrochemical sensors boost peak resolution and sensitivity, enabling precise detection of electroactive species in complex matrices. This method enhances analytical capabilities, providing an analytically robust solution.</description>
      <author>Rocco Cancelliere, Mario Molinara, Antonio Licheri, Antonio Maffucci, Laura Micheli</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00318g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commit: Mini article for dynamic reporting of incremental improvements to previous scholarly work</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90053g</link>
      <description>Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8211;Guzik, Jason E. Hein, Joshua Schrier, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406633347

                Introducing Commit, a new article type at Digital Discovery intended for reporting incremental improvements on work previously published in the journal.</description>
      <author>Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8211;Guzik, Jason E. Hein, Joshua Schrier</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90053g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the expertise of large language models in materials science and metallurgical engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00319e</link>
      <description>Christophe Bajan, G. Lambard, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406736930

                This study establishes a performance baseline for 15 LLMs on materials science tasks using the MaScQA benchmark, paving the way for AI-driven advancements in materials discovery and analysis.</description>
      <author>Christophe Bajan, G. Lambard</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00319e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cartesian Encoding Graph Neural Network for Crystal Structures Property Prediction: Application to Thermal Ellipsoid Estimation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00352g</link>
      <description>Andr&#233;s Sol&#233;, Albert Mosella-Montoro, Joan Cardona, Silvia G&#243;mez&#8208;Coca, Daniel Aravena, Eliseo Ru&#237;z, Javier Ruiz&#8208;Hidalgo, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406780971

                In the diffraction resolution of crystal structures, the thermal ellipsoids are a critical parameter that is usually more difficult to determine than atomic positions. These ellipsoids are quantified through the...</description>
      <author>Andr&#233;s Sol&#233;, Albert Mosella-Montoro, Joan Cardona, Silvia G&#243;mez&#8208;Coca, Daniel Aravena, Eliseo Ru&#237;z, Javier Ruiz&#8208;Hidalgo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00352g</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
