<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 01:19:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence-assisted electrochemical sensors for qualitative and semi-quantitative multiplexed analyses</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00318g</link>
      <description>Rocco Cancelliere, Mario Molinara, Antonio Licheri, Antonio Maffucci, Laura Micheli, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406624736

                AI-integrated electrochemical sensors boost peak resolution and sensitivity, enabling precise detection of electroactive species in complex matrices. This method enhances analytical capabilities, providing an analytically robust solution.</description>
      <author>Rocco Cancelliere, Mario Molinara, Antonio Licheri, Antonio Maffucci, Laura Micheli</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00318g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commit: Mini article for dynamic reporting of incremental improvements to previous scholarly work</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90053g</link>
      <description>Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8211;Guzik, Jason E. Hein, Joshua Schrier, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406633347

                Introducing Commit, a new article type at Digital Discovery intended for reporting incremental improvements on work previously published in the journal.</description>
      <author>Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8211;Guzik, Jason E. Hein, Joshua Schrier</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd90053g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition and structure analyzer/featurizer for explainable machine-learning models to predict solid state structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00332b</link>
      <description>Emil I. Jaffal, Sangjoon Lee, Danila Shiryaev, Alex Vtorov, Nikhil K. Barua, Holger Kleinke, Anton O. Oliynyk, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406525604

                Traditional and non-classical machine learning models for solid-state structure prediction have predominantly relied on compositional features (derived from properties of constituent elements) to predict the existence of structure and its...</description>
      <author>Emil I. Jaffal, Sangjoon Lee, Danila Shiryaev, Alex Vtorov, Nikhil K. Barua, Holger Kleinke, Anton O. Oliynyk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00332b</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
