<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Discovery</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Digital-Discovery.xml</link>
    <description>Articles in Digital Discovery</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 01:20:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid-LLM-GNN: Integrating Large Language Models and Graph Neural Networks for Enhanced Materials Property Prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00199k</link>
      <description>Youjia Li, Vishu Gupta, Muhammed Nur Talha Kilic, Kamal Choudhary, Daniel Wines, Wei&#8208;keng Liao, Alok Choudhary, Ankit Agrawal, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405535846

                Graph-centric learning has attracted significant interest in materials informatics. Accordingly, a family of graph-based machine learning models, primarily utilizing Graph Neural Networks (GNN), has been developed to provide accurate prediction...</description>
      <author>Youjia Li, Vishu Gupta, Muhammed Nur Talha Kilic, Kamal Choudhary, Daniel Wines, Wei&#8208;keng Liao, Alok Choudhary, Ankit Agrawal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00199k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Discovery from Porous Organic Cages Literature Using a Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00337c</link>
      <description>Yong&#8208;Liang Su, Siyuan Yang, Ming Liu, Aiting Kai, Linjiang Chen, Ming Liu, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405591138

                Porous organic cages (POCs) are an emerging subclass of porous materials, drawing increasing attention due to their structural tunability, modularity and processibility, with the research in this area rapidly expanding....</description>
      <author>Yong&#8208;Liang Su, Siyuan Yang, Ming Liu, Aiting Kai, Linjiang Chen, Ming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00337c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity Recognition in Scientific Experimentation using Multimodal Visual Encoding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00287c</link>
      <description>Gianmarco Gabrieli, I. Morales, Dimitrios Christofidellis, Mara Graziani, Andrea Giovannini, Federico Zipoli, Amol Thakkar, Antonio Foncubierta, Matteo Manica, Patrick Ruch, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405599463

                Capturing actions during scientific experimentation is a cornerstone of reproducibility and collaborative research. While large multimodal models hold promise for automatic action (or activity) recognition, their ability to provide real-time...</description>
      <author>Gianmarco Gabrieli, I. Morales, Dimitrios Christofidellis, Mara Graziani, Andrea Giovannini, Federico Zipoli, Amol Thakkar, Antonio Foncubierta, Matteo Manica, Patrick Ruch</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00287c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting homopolymer and copolymer solubility through machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00290c</link>
      <description>Christopher D. Stubbs, Yeonjoon Kim, Ethan C. Quinn, Ra&#250;l P&#233;rez&#8208;Soto, Eugene Y.&#8208;X. Chen, Seonah Kim, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405714714

                Polymer solubility has applications in many important and diverse fields, including microprocessor fabrication, environmental conservation, paint formulation, and drug delivery, but it remains under-explored compared to its relative importance. This...</description>
      <author>Christopher D. Stubbs, Yeonjoon Kim, Ethan C. Quinn, Ra&#250;l P&#233;rez&#8208;Soto, Eugene Y.&#8208;X. Chen, Seonah Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00290c</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
