<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Dynamic catalysis - citing and related</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Dynamic-catalysis---citing-and-related.xml</link>
    <description>papers related to dynamic catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 01:19:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Impedance Spectroscopy: Concept and Application on CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Methanation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02442</link>
      <description>Andreas Borgschulte, Marco Achermann, Marin Nikoli&#263;, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403336465

                Complex modeling of periodic excitation combined with time-resolved product detection is used to describe the complex response function of a catalytic system. We describe this concept of catalytic impedance spectroscopy (CIS) and the underlying general experimental approach and a concrete setup. The feasibility of CIS is experimentally demonstrated along the catalytic CO</description>
      <author>Andreas Borgschulte, Marco Achermann, Marin Nikoli&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exsolved Cu&#8211;ZnO interfaces for methanol production from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; at atmospheric pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05812g</link>
      <description>Sanaz Soodi, Eleonora Cal&#236;, Shailza Saini, William S. J. Skinner, Alex Martinez Martin, Gwilherm Kerherve, Marco Pietro Mezzapesa, Samir Bensaid, David J. Payne, Melis S. Duyar, Kalliopi Kousi, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403491297

                An exsolved intimate Cu&#8211;ZnO interface allows for the conversion of CO 2 to methanol at atmospheric pressures.</description>
      <author>Sanaz Soodi, Eleonora Cal&#236;, Shailza Saini, William S. J. Skinner, Alex Martinez Martin, Gwilherm Kerherve, Marco Pietro Mezzapesa, Samir Bensaid, David J. Payne, Melis S. Duyar, Kalliopi Kousi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05812g</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
