<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>high-entropy-oxides</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/high-entropy-oxides.xml</link>
    <description>high entropy oxides in catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 01:26:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>One-Pot Synthesis of (CrMnFeCoNi)O&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; High-Entropy Oxides for Efficient Catalytic Oxidation of Propane: A Promising Substitute for Noble Metal Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14292</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Bowen Han, Feng Bi, Zhongbiao Wu, Xiaole Weng, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404582402

                The efficient catalytic oxidation of propane, as a short-chain alkane, remains challenging in environmental catalysis. High-entropy oxides (HEOs) exhibit advantages in abundant and well-dispersed elemental composition, exceptional thermal stability, and enriched lattice defects. Herein, (CrMnFeCoNi)Ox HEO catalysts are successfully synthesized by using a continuous hydrothermal flow synthesis (CHFS) route, without any subsequent calcination processes. This route yields HEOs with fine particle sizes, high specific surface areas, and abundant near-surface lattice oxygen compared to the traditional coprecipitation method. Notably, the propane conversion over the CHFS-made (CrMnFeCoNi)Ox HEO reaches 90% at 255 &#176;C, with an apparent activation energy of 53.2 kJ/mol, mainly attributed to its enriched lattice oxygen and enhanced oxygen mobility that prevent the accumulation of acetates and the consequent occupation of active sites. In comparison to commercial Pt/Al2O3 and Pd/Al2O3, (CrMnFeCoNi)Ox HEO demonstrates exceptional activity and can maintain long-term stability under high-temperature (upon 650 &#176;C) and moisture-rich conditions (at 2&#8211;10 vol %). These attributes highlight its potential as a promising substitute for noble metal catalysts in industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Yang Li, Bowen Han, Feng Bi, Zhongbiao Wu, Xiaole Weng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14292</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
