<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>high-entropy-oxides</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/high-entropy-oxides.xml</link>
    <description>high entropy oxides in catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:43:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Robust high-entropy spinel oxides for peroxymonosulfate activation: Stabilization effect and enhancement mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150826</link>
      <description>Leijiang Zhang, Na Wang, Fengyuan Wang, Ping Xu, Xijiang Han, Yunchen Du, Chemical engineering journal (1996. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393346101

                High-entropy alloys/oxides (HEAs/HEOs) combining multiple metal cations into single-phase structures are becoming attractive for catalysis and energy conversion. However, few relevant researches are available in the fields of peroxymonosulfate (PMS)-based advanced oxidation technologies. Herein, an entropy-stabilized spinel oxide, HESO [(Cr0.2Mn0.2Fe0.2Co0.2Ni0.2)3O4] has been successfully prepared for PMS activation taking bisphenol A (BPA) as a model pollutant. A stable HESO-600 with a well-defined spinel structure is harvested by regulating calcination temperature. HESO-600 exhibits specific structural and chemical stability, achieves complete degradation of BPA within 60 min, and gives minimal ion leaching (82 &#956;g/L). Furthermore, even after 5 cycles, it maintains an efficiency of over 90 %. Combined results of characterizations and theoretical calculations, it is indicated that multiple active sites and synergistic effects of different elements in HESO-600 contribute to the strong adsorption of PMS and the efficient electron transport during the oxidation reaction. The random occupancy of multiple cations promotes the generation of oxygen vacancies, which are conducive to promoting the production of reactive oxygen species and strengthening the catalytic performance of catalyst. This work provides a new family of metal oxide catalysts to motivate PMS for water decontamination.</description>
      <author>Leijiang Zhang, Na Wang, Fengyuan Wang, Ping Xu, Xijiang Han, Yunchen Du</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of High Entropy Alloy Nanoparticles by Pulsed Laser Ablation in Liquids: Influence of Target Preparation on Stoichiometry and Productivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400064</link>
      <description>Shabbir Tahir, &#1053;. &#1060;. &#1064;&#1082;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1095;, Benedikt Eggert, Johanna Lill, Oleksandr Gatsa, Miroslava Flimelov&#225;, Esmaeil Adabifiroozjaei, Nadezhda M. Bulgakova, Leopoldo Molina&#8208;Luna, Heiko Wende, Michael Farle, Alexander V. Bulgakov, Carlos Do&#241;ate&#8208;Buend&#237;a, Bilal G&#246;kce, ChemNanoMat (Weinheim). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393191692

                Abstract High entropy alloys (HEAs) have a wide range of applications across various fields, including structural engineering, biomedical science, catalysis, magnetism, and nuclear technology. Nanoscale HEA particles show promising catalytic properties. Nevertheless, attaining versatile composition control in nanoparticles poses a persistent challenge. This study proposes the use of pulsed laser ablation in liquids (PLAL) for synthesizing nanoparticles using equiatomic CoCrFeMnNi targets with varied preparation methods. We evaluate the impact of target preparation method on nanoparticle yield and composition as well as the magnetic properties of the nanoparticles. The elemental powder&#8208;pressed heat&#8208;treated target (HEA&#8208;PP), identified as the most time&#8208;efficient and cost&#8208;effective, exhibits noticeable segregation and non&#8208;uniform elemental distribution compared to ball milled hot&#8208;pressed powder (HEA&#8208;BP) and face&#8208;centered cubic (FCC) single crystal (HEA&#8208;SX) alloy targets. From all targets, nanoparticles (sizes from 2 to 120 nm) can be produced in ethanol with a nearly equiatomic CoCrFeMnNi composition and a FCC structure, showing oxidation of up to 20 at.%. Nanoparticles from HEA&#8208;PP exist in a solid solution state, while those from HEA&#8208;BP and HEA&#8208;SX form core&#8208;shell structures with a Mn shell due to inhomogeneous material expulsion, confirmed by mass spectrometry. HEA&#8208;PP PLAL synthesis demonstrates 6.8 % and 15.1 % higher productivity compared to HEA&#8208;BP and HEA&#8208;SX, establishing PLAL of elemental powder&#8208;pressed targets as a reliable, time&#8208;efficient, and cost&#8208;effective method for generating solid solution HEA nanoparticles.</description>
      <author>Shabbir Tahir, &#1053;. &#1060;. &#1064;&#1082;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1095;, Benedikt Eggert, Johanna Lill, Oleksandr Gatsa, Miroslava Flimelov&#225;, Esmaeil Adabifiroozjaei, Nadezhda M. Bulgakova, Leopoldo Molina&#8208;Luna, Heiko Wende, Michael Farle, Alexander V. Bulgakov, Carlos Do&#241;ate&#8208;Buend&#237;a, Bilal G&#246;kce</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400064</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
