<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>high-entropy-oxides</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/high-entropy-oxides.xml</link>
    <description>high entropy oxides in catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 01:20:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Energy Solutions and Environmental Remediation: Piezocatalysis in Ferroelectric High-Entropy Oxides and 2D Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2024-02392595mtgabs</link>
      <description>Jyh-Ming Wu, Meeting abstracts/Meeting abstracts (Electrochemical Society. CD-ROM). MA2024-02(39)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405590608

                Hydrogen is the most abundant element on Earth, and it is a safe and efficient source of energy. Through electrocatalysis and photocatalysis water molecules can be split into O and H 2 , which can then be used for fuel. This has been widely studied as a promising approach to reduce CO 2 emissions and reliance on fossil fuels. A solar-assisted electrochemical process that generates H 2 without toxic byproducts is being investigated. Solutions involving the remediation of water pollutants, water splitting, and clean energy alternatives have been widely investigated. However, most semiconducting photocatalysts are not very efficient when used in water-based solutions, because they have a low quantum yield. This talk will report how the piezocatalyts and flexocatalysts can proceed with electrochemical reactions for highly efficient wastewater treatment and hydrogen production. Considering the piezophototronic effect in the visible range, we combined a ferroelectric component with a high entropy oxide (HEO) compound, which can significantly enhance the charge transfer of the HEO's surface, enhancing the catalytic activity (Figure 1). Theoretical calculations revealed that a ferroelectric component could create an inner electric field at interfacial phase boundaries and effectively moderate free carriers, strengthening the charge separation in the ferroelectric HEO catalyst. When an external mechanical force was coupled with photoirradiation, the photoinduced charge separation coupled with piezoelectric polarization enhanced the charge transport in trapping sites. In this talk, I will provide an overview of High Entropy Oxide (HEO) ferroelectric catalysts, along with advancements in piezocatalysts within 2D materials and ferroelectric domains. The concepts presented will pave the way for designing next-generation piezo-photocatalysts. References Y. T. Lin, S. N. Lai, J. M. Wu*, Advanced Materials 32 (34), 2002875, 2020. SC Chang, HY Chen, PH Chen, JT Lee, JM Wu*, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental 324, 122204, 2023. Figure 1</description>
      <author>Jyh-Ming Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2024-02392595mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
