<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>high-entropy-oxides</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/high-entropy-oxides.xml</link>
    <description>high entropy oxides in catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:44:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Cobalt Catalysts Encapsulating Cobalt Nanoparticles with Built-In Electric Field for Ultrafast and Lasting Peroxymonosulfate Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestwater.3c00774</link>
      <description>Haiyan Zou, Haitao Wang, Hongqi Sun, Wenshuang Sun, Shuangjiang Luo, Tielong Li, Xiaoguang Duan, Sihui Zhan, ACS ES&amp;T Water. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392193592

                Cobalt single-atom catalysts (Co-SAs) are rising stars in persulfate chemistry for their well-defined coordination, reduced metal usage, and exceptional activity. However, the simultaneous formation of cobalt nanoparticles (Co-NPs) with Co-SAs raises questions about their complex interplay and synergy in catalysis. In this study, we synthesized Co-SAs-encapsulated Co-NPs (CoNP@NC/Co-SA) using the laser-induced carbonization strategy of high entropy synthesis technology. The results show that 93.23% of phenol can be removed in 15 min and 91.60% in 3 min in the CoNP@NC/Co-SA/PMS system. Simulation results showed that Co-NPs fine-tune the electronic structure of Co-SA sites, optimizing PMS adsorption and activation to generate confined reactive species. The surface-activated PMS-catalyst complex directly attacked adsorbed pollutants on the catalyst surface via an electron-transfer regime. CoNP@NC/Co-SA catalyzes PMS oxidation through a nonradical pathway with high selectivity toward target organics. The findings emphasize the synergistic effect of Co-SAs and Co-NPs in promoting Fenton-like catalysis, enlightening the rational design of advanced composite materials via synergistic molecular and interfacial engineering for fast and long-lasting catalytic oxidation. At the same time, this work provides insights into the electronic structure regulation of metal centers at the atomic level.</description>
      <author>Haiyan Zou, Haitao Wang, Hongqi Sun, Wenshuang Sun, Shuangjiang Luo, Tielong Li, Xiaoguang Duan, Sihui Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestwater.3c00774</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
