<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>high-entropy-oxides</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/high-entropy-oxides.xml</link>
    <description>high entropy oxides in catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 01:05:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing sulfur resistance of oxides in carbon monoxide oxidation by a high&#8208;entropy&#8208;stabilized strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18470</link>
      <description>Shengyu Du, Pengfei Zhang, AIChE journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396706305

                Abstract Industrial chemical processes require sulfur&#8208;resistant catalysts, which reduce catalyst replacement costs and simplify process operations. Herein, a high&#8208;entropy&#8208;stabilized strategy was put forward for sulfur&#8208;resistant catalysis. A spinel high entropy (Zn 0.2 Mg 0.2 Cu 0.2 Mn 0.2 Co 0.2 Al 2 O 4 ) was introduced by ball milling process with aluminum isopropoxide as the main precursor. Zn 0.2 Mg 0.2 Cu 0.2 Mn 0.2 Co 0.2 Al 2 O 4 possessed a high surface area of 171.2 m 2 g &#8722;1 , higher than typical high&#8208;entropy oxides (HEOs). The high&#8208;entropy spinel catalyst exhibited better SO 2 &#8208;resistance performance in the oxidation of carbon monoxide, better than the simple oxides. The SO 2 &#8208;resistance of Zn 0.2 Mg 0.2 Cu 0.2 Mn 0.2 Co 0.2 Al 2 O 4 was primarily improved by reinforcing the stability of the oxide using a high&#8208;entropy structure to decrease the absorption of SO 2 on its surface. Any adsorbed SO 2 on the surface of the HEO was then selectively trapped by sacrificial metal ions with stronger electron&#8208;withdrawing ability, protecting the active center (Cu 2+ , Co 2+ ) from poisoning. This work reveals the significance of high&#8208;entropy structures in sulfur resistance.</description>
      <author>Shengyu Du, Pengfei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18470</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
