<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>high-entropy-oxides</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/high-entropy-oxides.xml</link>
    <description>high entropy oxides in catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 01:03:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Synthesis Methods for High&#8208;Entropy Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202300297</link>
      <description>Timothy G. Ritter, Samhita Pappu, Reza Shahbazian&#8208;Yassar, Advanced energy and sustainability research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395683868

                High&#8208;entropy materials (HEMs) represent a revolutionary class of materials that have garnered significant attention in the field of materials science due to their extraordinary properties in diverse fields of applications such as catalysis and electrochemistry. The past decade has witnessed a substantial increase in the study of these materials, exploring new synthesis routes and compositions. What began as the synthesis of high&#8208;entropy alloys has expanded to encompass several classes of HEMs such as oxides, hydroxides, sulfides, nitrides, and carbides, among others. Several synthesis methods have been developed to produce these materials. This review therefore highlights the fundamental concepts of HEMs, including their core effects, with a major emphasis on their scalable synthesis routes. The advantages and drawbacks of these methods are also discussed. As HEMs transition from the lab to large&#8208;scale production, there is a growing need for cost&#8208;effective and scalable synthesis methods with high material yield suitable for a variety of applications like hydrogen storage, catalysis, batteries, supercapacitors, and fuel cells. Hence, this review serves as an introduction to scalable synthesis routes based on crystal structure, desired elements, synthesis times, and equipment costs.</description>
      <author>Timothy G. Ritter, Samhita Pappu, Reza Shahbazian&#8208;Yassar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202300297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin&#8208;Regulated Fenton&#8208;Like Catalysis for Nonradical Oxidation over Metal Oxide@Carbon Composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401397</link>
      <description>Bofeng Li, Liu Ya, Kunsheng Hu, Qing Dai, Chunmao Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Shaobin Wang, Yuxian Wang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395082091

                Abstract The spin state of the transition metal species (TMs) has been recognized as a critical descriptor in Fenton&#8208;like catalysis. The raised spin state of dispersed TMs in carbon will enhance the redox processes with adsorbed peroxides and improve the oxidation performance. Nevertheless, establishing the spin&#8208;activity correlations for the encapsulated TM nanoparticles remains challenging because of the difficulties in fine&#8208;tuning the spin state of TM species and the insufficient understanding of orbital hybridization states upon interaction with peroxides. Here, the advantage of the fast&#8208;temperature heating/quenching of microwave thermal shock is taken to engineer the structure and spin state of encapsulated TMs within the N&#8208;doped graphitic carbons. The reduced TMs particle size and enhanced TMs&#8208;carbon coupling increase surface entropy and regulate e g electron filling of the high&#8208;spin TM&#8208;N coordination, endowing electrons with high mobility and facilitating peroxymonosulfate (PMS) adsorption. The strong interactions further uplift the PMS O 2p band position toward the Fermi level and thus elevate the oxidation potential of surface&#8208;activated PMS (PMS * ) as the dominant nonradical species for pollutant degradation. The deciphered orbital hybridizations of engineered high&#8208;spin TM and PMS enlighten the smart design of spin&#8208;regulated nanocomposites for advanced water purification.</description>
      <author>Bofeng Li, Liu Ya, Kunsheng Hu, Qing Dai, Chunmao Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Shaobin Wang, Yuxian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401397</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
