<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>high-entropy-oxides</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/high-entropy-oxides.xml</link>
    <description>high entropy oxides in catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 01:12:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional single-crystalline mesoporous high-entropy oxide nanoplates for efficient electrochemical biomass upgrading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50721-2</link>
      <description>Yanzhi Wang, Hangjuan He, LV Hao, Fengrui Jia, Ben Liu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401419486

                Abstract Mesoporous single crystals have received more attention than ever in catalysis-related applications due to their unique structural functions. Despite great efforts, their progress in engineering crystallinity and composition has been remarkably slower than expected. In this manuscript, a template-free strategy is developed to prepare two-dimensional high-entropy oxide (HEO) nanoplates with single-crystallinity and penetrated mesoporosity, which further ensures precise control over high-entropy compositions and crystalline phases. Single-crystalline mesoporous HEOs (SC-MHEOs) disclose high electrocatalytic performance in 5-hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation reaction (HMFOR) for efficient biomass upgrading, with remarkable HMF conversion of 99.3% and superior 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) selectivity of 97.7%. Moreover, with nitrate reduction as coupling cathode reaction, SC-MHEO realizes concurrent electrosynthesis of value-added FDCA and ammonia in the two-electrode cell. Our study provides a powerful paradigm for producing a library of novel mesoporous single crystals for important catalysis-related applications, especially in the two-electrode cell.</description>
      <author>Yanzhi Wang, Hangjuan He, LV Hao, Fengrui Jia, Ben Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50721-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study of Porous High&#8208;entropy Oxides as Low&#8208;temperature Catalysts for CO2 Methanation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400476</link>
      <description>Amy J. Knorpp, Monika Mielniczuk, Marin Nikoli&#263;, Alexander Vogel, Renato Figi, Claudia Schreiner, Andreas Borgschulte, Michael Stuer, European Journal of Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333650

                High&#8208;entropy oxides (HEOs) are an emerging class of materials whose compositional complexity has garnered attention because of their tailorable chemistries and unique properties arising from extreme configurational entropy. Solid&#8208;state methods are often employed to synthesize HEOs, but such methods result in poor material properties for catalytic processes, leaving HEOs less studied for catalysis. Here we utilize different wet&#8208;synthesis strategies to produce porous HEOs and investigate their performance in heterogeneous CO2 hydrogenation to methane. Specifically, HEOs were synthesized using hydrothermal, co&#8208;precipitation, and solvothermal methods, resulting in different morphologies like platelets or spheres. Of the tested materials, HEOs with 2&#8208;D platelets derived from hydrothermally&#8208;synthesized high&#8208;entropy layered double hydroxides had superior catalytic performance, especially in low&#8208;temperature regimes (&lt;300&#176;C). K&#8208;edge XANES indicated that metallic sites (Ni0&#8208;Co0) were formed during the reaction, and these metallic sites are dispersed into the HEO matrix which is confirmed by STEM/elemental mapping. This facile synthesis approach allows for realized synergy between the metallic sites and the HEO support, leading to superior performance for CO2 methanation compared to low&#8208;entropy counterparts. Finally, this study illustrates how HEOs offer new avenues of tailorability in terms of the interplay between support, active site and reaction temperatures for heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Amy J. Knorpp, Monika Mielniczuk, Marin Nikoli&#263;, Alexander Vogel, Renato Figi, Claudia Schreiner, Andreas Borgschulte, Michael Stuer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400476</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
