<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>high-entropy-oxides</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/high-entropy-oxides.xml</link>
    <description>high entropy oxides in catalysis</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 01:08:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Spin&#8208;Regulated Fenton&#8208;Like Catalysis for Nonradical Oxidation over Metal Oxide@Carbon Composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401397</link>
      <description>Bofeng Li, Liu Ya, Kunsheng Hu, Qing Dai, Chunmao Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Shaobin Wang, Yuxian Wang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395082091

                Abstract The spin state of the transition metal species (TMs) has been recognized as a critical descriptor in Fenton&#8208;like catalysis. The raised spin state of dispersed TMs in carbon will enhance the redox processes with adsorbed peroxides and improve the oxidation performance. Nevertheless, establishing the spin&#8208;activity correlations for the encapsulated TM nanoparticles remains challenging because of the difficulties in fine&#8208;tuning the spin state of TM species and the insufficient understanding of orbital hybridization states upon interaction with peroxides. Here, the advantage of the fast&#8208;temperature heating/quenching of microwave thermal shock is taken to engineer the structure and spin state of encapsulated TMs within the N&#8208;doped graphitic carbons. The reduced TMs particle size and enhanced TMs&#8208;carbon coupling increase surface entropy and regulate e g electron filling of the high&#8208;spin TM&#8208;N coordination, endowing electrons with high mobility and facilitating peroxymonosulfate (PMS) adsorption. The strong interactions further uplift the PMS O 2p band position toward the Fermi level and thus elevate the oxidation potential of surface&#8208;activated PMS (PMS * ) as the dominant nonradical species for pollutant degradation. The deciphered orbital hybridizations of engineered high&#8208;spin TM and PMS enlighten the smart design of spin&#8208;regulated nanocomposites for advanced water purification.</description>
      <author>Bofeng Li, Liu Ya, Kunsheng Hu, Qing Dai, Chunmao Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Shaobin Wang, Yuxian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401397</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
