<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>liquid-metal</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/liquid-metal.xml</link>
    <description>low temperature liquid metals</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 01:13:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Low-temperature dechlorination of polyvinyl chloride (PVC) for production of H &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and carbon materials using liquid metal catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adm9963</link>
      <description>Felipe Polo&#8208;Garzon, Zili Wu, Yuanyuan Li, Jin Zhang, Xinbin Yu, Elena Toups, Eddie L&#243;pez&#8208;Honorato, Joshua T. Damron, Jeffrey C. Foster, Yongqiang Cheng, Luke L. Daemen, Anibal J. Ramirez&#8208;Cuesta, Harry M. Meyer, Science Advances. 10(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400945077

                Polyvinyl chloride (PVC) is ubiquitous in everyday life; however, it is not recycled because it degrades uncontrollably into toxic products above 250&#176;C. Therefore, it is of interest to controllably dechlorinate PVC at mild temperatures to generate narrowly distributed carbon materials. We present a catalytic route to dechlorinate PVC (~90% reduction of Cl content) at mild temperature (200&#176;C) to produce gas H</description>
      <author>Felipe Polo&#8208;Garzon, Zili Wu, Yuanyuan Li, Jin Zhang, Xinbin Yu, Elena Toups, Eddie L&#243;pez&#8208;Honorato, Joshua T. Damron, Jeffrey C. Foster, Yongqiang Cheng, Luke L. Daemen, Anibal J. Ramirez&#8208;Cuesta, Harry M. Meyer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adm9963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Throughput Ammonia Production from Nitrate Using Liquid Metal Synthesized Bismuth Nano&#8208;Catalyst (Adv. Energy Mater. 28/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202470116</link>
      <description>Sahar Nazari, Jing Sun, Mahroo Baharfar, Philippe Poulin, Kourosh Kalantar&#8208;zadeh, Rouhollah Jalili, Dorna Esrafilzadeh, Advanced Energy Materials. 14(28)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401036189

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sahar Nazari, Jing Sun, Mahroo Baharfar, Philippe Poulin, Kourosh Kalantar&#8208;zadeh, Rouhollah Jalili, Dorna Esrafilzadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202470116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liquid Metal Alloys Enable Efficient Formate Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408966</link>
      <description>Hui Huang, Xue Ding, Xinnan Mao, Yuchen Yan, Fang Lv, Binbin Pan, Wei Huang, Lu Wang, Na Han, Yanguang Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400887504

                Abstract Liquid metals are an interesting class of materials with the unique combination of metallic nature and liquid fluidity, and have recently been explored in many emerging fields. Their potential applications in catalysis, unfortunately, remain largely untapped. Herein, Ga&#8208;mediated liquid metal alloying as an effective strategy is demonstrated to prepare functional alloys for catalysis. The alloying is carried out by dissolving indium or tin pellets in liquid gallium at room temperature or assisted by gentle heating, giving rise to binary Ga 1&#8722; x In x and Ga 1&#8722; x Sn x liquid metal alloys with tunable chemical compositions. When further subjected to ultrasonication in water, they are ruptured into nanosized particles with liquid metal cores and thin surface oxide shells. Electrochemical measurements reveal that the liquid metal alloying significantly promotes electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction to formate. Taking Ga 0.75 In 0.25 as an example, its formate Faradaic efficiency is enhanced by 10%&#8211;20% compared to those of Ga and In, and its formate partial current density is 4&#8211;6 times larger than those of Ga and In. This enhancement is rationalized via computational simulations showing that the surrounding of In active sites with Ga atoms deactivates the undesirable reaction pathways to CO or H 2 , and facilitates selective formate electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Hui Huang, Xue Ding, Xinnan Mao, Yuchen Yan, Fang Lv, Binbin Pan, Wei Huang, Lu Wang, Na Han, Yanguang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408966</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
