<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>liquid-metal</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/liquid-metal.xml</link>
    <description>low temperature liquid metals</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 01:02:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Supported Catalytically Active Liquid Metal Solutions: Liquid Metal Catalysis with Ternary Alloys, Enhancing Activity in Propane Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01282</link>
      <description>Michael J. Moritz, Sven Maisel, Narayanan Raman, Haiko Wittk&#228;mper, Christoph Wichmann, Mathias Grabau, Deniz Kahraman, Julien Steffen, Nicola Taccardi, Andreas G&#246;rling, Marco Haumann, Peter Wasserscheid, Hans&#8208;Peter Steinr&#252;ck, Christian Papp, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394728272

                The research and optimization of catalysts are instrumental in revolutionizing chemical processes and making them viable in terms of energy and resources. Supported catalytically active liquid metal solutions (SCALMS) are highly active and stable in the harsh environment of the dehydrogenation reaction of alkanes. This is attributed to their liquid and dynamic nature and their isolated catalytically active single-atom sites. SCALMS consists of a liquid metal matrix (gallium) in which a catalytically active transition metal (platinum, rhodium, palladium, or nickel) is dissolved. Binary SCALMS systems are the subject of extensive research, aiming at a better understanding for achieving optimal performance. This work uses a combined multidisciplinary approach to examine ternary systems of the active transition metal platinum with mixtures of gallium with either tin or indium. Reaction engineering and surface chemical analysis by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy are combined with density functional theory (DFT) and machine learning force field (ML-FF) simulations. Introducing a third metal into the mixture alters the reactivity, surface composition, and concentration gradient in the liquid metal catalyst. We demonstrate that changes in catalytic reactivity correlate with changes in the surface concentration of the active transition metal platinum and of the position of the d-band center. These findings hold great promise for future research directions as they offer potential starting points for developing SCALMS systems.</description>
      <author>Michael J. Moritz, Sven Maisel, Narayanan Raman, Haiko Wittk&#228;mper, Christoph Wichmann, Mathias Grabau, Deniz Kahraman, Julien Steffen, Nicola Taccardi, Andreas G&#246;rling, Marco Haumann, Peter Wasserscheid, Hans&#8208;Peter Steinr&#252;ck, Christian Papp</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galvanic Replacement Synthesis of VO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;@EGaIn&#8211;PEG Core&#8211;Shell Nanohybrids for Peroxidase Mimics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02213</link>
      <description>Xiaojian Xu, Yanchun Shen, Rui Xing, Jie Kong, Rongxin Su, Renliang Huang, Wei Qi, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394856785

                The development of high-performance biosensors is a key focus in the nanozyme field, but the current limitations in biocompatibility and recyclability hinder their broader applications. Herein, we address these challenges by constructing core&#8211;shell nanohybrids with biocompatible poly(ethylene glycol) (PEG) modification using a galvanic replacement reaction between orthovanadate ions and liquid metal (LM) (VOx@EGaIn-PEG). By leveraging the excellent charge transfer properties and the low band gap of the LM surface oxide, the VOx@EGaIn-PEG heterojunction can effectively convert hydrogen peroxide into hydroxyl radicals, demonstrating excellent peroxidase-like activity and stability (Km = 490 &#956;M, vmax = 1.206 &#956;M/s). The unique self-healing characteristics of LM further enable the recovery and regeneration of VOx@EGaIn-PEG nanozymes, thereby significantly reducing the cost of biological detection. Building upon this, we developed a nanozyme colorimetric sensor suitable for biological systems and integrated it with a smartphone to create an efficient quantitative detection platform. This platform allows for the convenient and sensitive detection of glucose in serum samples, exhibiting a good linear relationship in the range of 10&#8211;500 &#956;M and a detection limit of 2.35 &#956;M. The remarkable catalytic potential of LM, combined with its biocompatibility and regenerative properties, offers valuable insights for applications in catalysis and biomedical fields.</description>
      <author>Xiaojian Xu, Yanchun Shen, Rui Xing, Jie Kong, Rongxin Su, Renliang Huang, Wei Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02213</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
