<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>liquid-metal</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/liquid-metal.xml</link>
    <description>low temperature liquid metals</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 01:19:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Triboelectric Sensor based on Catalyst&#8208;Diffusion Self&#8208;Encapsulated Conductive Liquid&#8208;Metal&#8208;Silicone Ink for Somatosensory Soft Robotic System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202412293</link>
      <description>Shuai Xian, Yong Xu, Yixin Li, Zhenfeng Wu, Xing Xie, Zhigang Wu, Xiya Yang, Yong Zhong, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403214305

                Abstract The combination of fluidity and metallic conductivity has attracted considerable attention to liquid metal (LM), but its development remains challenging due to enormous surface tension. Here, vinyl&#8208;terminated silicone oil and platinum catalyst are added to LM to reduce its surface tension, which develops a special type of liquid&#8208;metal&#8208;silicone (LMS) ink with a catalyst diffusion effect. Combined with an embedded three&#8208;dimentional (3D) printing method, the LMS ink is printed on the support matrix, and the catalyst diffuses outward along the print path to cure the silicone around it, directly constructing self&#8208;encapsulated conductive composites with excellent conductivity and self&#8208;encapsulated flexible tactile sensors based on triboelectric nanogenerator (TENG). The sensor exhibits excellent sensitivity (0.308 V kPa &#8722;1 ), high linearity (&#8776;0.99), and good durability (over 10 000 cycles). Furthermore, when used in flexible wearable electronics, the sensor demonstrates a good performance with an accuracy of &#8776;96% in classifying different human postures using a convolutional neural network. Finally, through embedded 3D printing with LMS ink and silicone ink, a somatosensory soft robotic gripper with complex cavity structures is designed and manufactured in one step, achieving the all&#8208;in&#8208;one integration of sensors and actuators. This study shows great application potential in flexible electronics and soft robotic systems.</description>
      <author>Shuai Xian, Yong Xu, Yixin Li, Zhenfeng Wu, Xing Xie, Zhigang Wu, Xiya Yang, Yong Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202412293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liquid Metal Electrocatalyst with Ultralow Pt Loading for Ethanol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400370</link>
      <description>Muhammad Hamza Nazir, Tu C. Le, Imtisal Zahid, Karma Zuraiqi, Mew P. Aukarasereenont, Caiden J. Parker, Pierre H. A. Vaillant, Fahad Jabbar, Chung Kim Nguyen, Mehmood Irfan, Mariam Ameen, Michelle J. S. Spencer, Andrew J. Christofferson, Salvy P. Russo, Ken Chiang, Nastaran Meftahi, Torben Daeneke, Dan Yang, Small Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403202030

                Developing efficient and durable electrocatalysts for ethanol electro&#8208;oxidation is crucial for enabling the application of direct ethanol fuel cell technology. Herein, it is demonstrated that Pt&#8211;Ga liquid metal&#8208;based nanodroplets can serve as an efficient electrocatalyst to drive ethanol oxidation. The mass activity of Pt is significantly improved by alloying with liquid gallium. Guided by machine learning neural networks, a low&#8208;concentration alkaline electrolyte is specifically formulated to allow electrodes with ultralow Pt loading to demonstrate remarkable activity toward ethanol oxidation with a mass activity as high as 13.47 A mg &#8722;1 Pt , which is more than 14 times higher than that of commercial Pt/C electrocatalysts (i.e., 0.76 A mg &#8722;1 Pt ). Computational studies reveal that the superior activity is associated with the presence of Ga oxides adjacent to Pt on the catalyst surface which leads to energetically favorable pathways for the oxidation process. The findings reveal untapped opportunities in the realm of liquid metal catalysis and hold great promise for the future development of high&#8208;performance alcohol fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Hamza Nazir, Tu C. Le, Imtisal Zahid, Karma Zuraiqi, Mew P. Aukarasereenont, Caiden J. Parker, Pierre H. A. Vaillant, Fahad Jabbar, Chung Kim Nguyen, Mehmood Irfan, Mariam Ameen, Michelle J. S. Spencer, Andrew J. Christofferson, Salvy P. Russo, Ken Chiang, Nastaran Meftahi, Torben Daeneke, Dan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400370</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
