<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>liquid-metal</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/liquid-metal.xml</link>
    <description>low temperature liquid metals</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 01:21:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Molten Sn solvent expands liquid metal catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56222-0</link>
      <description>Junma Tang, Nastaran Meftahi, Andrew J. Christofferson, Jing Sun, Ruohan Yu, Md. Arifur Rahim, Jianbo Tang, Guangzhao Mao, Torben Daeneke, Richard B. Kaner, Salvy P. Russo, Kourosh Kalantar&#8208;zadeh, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406657236

                Abstract Regulating favorable assemblies of metallic atoms in the liquid state provides promise for catalyzing various chemical reactions. Expanding the selection of metallic solvents, especially those with unique properties and low cost, enables access to distinctive fluidic atomic structures on the surface of liquid alloys and offers economic feasibility. Here, Sn solvent, as a low-cost commodity, supports unique atomic assemblies at the interface of molten SnIn 0.1034 Cu 0.0094 , which are highly selective for H 2 synthesis from hydrocarbons. Atomistic simulations reveal that distinctive adsorption patterns with hexadecane can be established with Cu transiently reaching the interfacial layer, ensuring an energy-favorable route for H 2 generation. Experiments with a natural oil as feedstock underscore this approach&#8217;s performance, producing 1.2 &#215; 10 &#8722; 4 mol/min of H 2 with 5.0 g of catalyst at ~93.0% selectivity while offering reliable scalability and durability at 260 &#176;C. This work presents an alternative avenue of tuning fluidic atomic structures, broadening the applications of liquid metals.</description>
      <author>Junma Tang, Nastaran Meftahi, Andrew J. Christofferson, Jing Sun, Ruohan Yu, Md. Arifur Rahim, Jianbo Tang, Guangzhao Mao, Torben Daeneke, Richard B. Kaner, Salvy P. Russo, Kourosh Kalantar&#8208;zadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56222-0</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
