<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>liquid-metal</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/liquid-metal.xml</link>
    <description>low temperature liquid metals</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 01:02:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Supported Catalytically Active Liquid Metal Solutions: Liquid Metal Catalysis with Ternary Alloys, Enhancing Activity in Propane Dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01282</link>
      <description>Michael J. Moritz, Sven Maisel, Narayanan Raman, Haiko Wittk&#228;mper, Christoph Wichmann, Mathias Grabau, Deniz Kahraman, Julien Steffen, Nicola Taccardi, Andreas G&#246;rling, Marco Haumann, Peter Wasserscheid, Hans&#8208;Peter Steinr&#252;ck, Christian Papp, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394728272

                The research and optimization of catalysts are instrumental in revolutionizing chemical processes and making them viable in terms of energy and resources. Supported catalytically active liquid metal solutions (SCALMS) are highly active and stable in the harsh environment of the dehydrogenation reaction of alkanes. This is attributed to their liquid and dynamic nature and their isolated catalytically active single-atom sites. SCALMS consists of a liquid metal matrix (gallium) in which a catalytically active transition metal (platinum, rhodium, palladium, or nickel) is dissolved. Binary SCALMS systems are the subject of extensive research, aiming at a better understanding for achieving optimal performance. This work uses a combined multidisciplinary approach to examine ternary systems of the active transition metal platinum with mixtures of gallium with either tin or indium. Reaction engineering and surface chemical analysis by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy are combined with density functional theory (DFT) and machine learning force field (ML-FF) simulations. Introducing a third metal into the mixture alters the reactivity, surface composition, and concentration gradient in the liquid metal catalyst. We demonstrate that changes in catalytic reactivity correlate with changes in the surface concentration of the active transition metal platinum and of the position of the d-band center. These findings hold great promise for future research directions as they offer potential starting points for developing SCALMS systems.</description>
      <author>Michael J. Moritz, Sven Maisel, Narayanan Raman, Haiko Wittk&#228;mper, Christoph Wichmann, Mathias Grabau, Deniz Kahraman, Julien Steffen, Nicola Taccardi, Andreas G&#246;rling, Marco Haumann, Peter Wasserscheid, Hans&#8208;Peter Steinr&#252;ck, Christian Papp</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A diffusion model for liquid metal dealloying. Application to NiCu precursors dealloyed in liquid Ag</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.119908</link>
      <description>London Lesage, Takumi Suga, Takeshi Wada, Hidemi Kato, Christophe Le Bourlot, &#201;ric Maire, Nicolas Mary, Pierre-Antoine Geslin, Acta materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394600929

                Liquid metal dealloying is a promising technique to elaborate porous metallic materials with potential applications for catalysis and energy storage. It consists in the selective dissolution of an element out of a precursor alloy by immersing it in a liquid bath. To model this process, we introduce a one-dimensional diffusion model that relies on the thermodynamic properties of the ternary system, and on a maximum velocity criterion of the reaction front. The model is compared to experimental measurements conducted on NiCu samples dealloyed in liquid Ag. Regarding the kinetics, the model enable to reach experimental time-scales, replicate experimental trends, and reveal the influence of the ligament structure on the dealloying rate. Also, by assuming thermodynamic equilibria between solid and liquid phases in the dealloyed region, the microstructure gradient obtained numerically is in satisfactory agreement with experimental measurements. These numerical results are obtained without adjustable parameters, which opens the possibility to predict dealloyed microstructures as function of the process parameters (precursor and bath composition, dealloying time and temperature, etc.).</description>
      <author>London Lesage, Takumi Suga, Takeshi Wada, Hidemi Kato, Christophe Le Bourlot, &#201;ric Maire, Nicolas Mary, Pierre-Antoine Geslin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.119908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Catalysis-Relevant Oxidation and Annealing Treatments on Nanostructured GaRh Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02286</link>
      <description>Tzung-En Hsieh, Johannes Frisch, Regan G. Wilks, Christian Papp, Marcus B&#228;r, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394621642

                In this study, we examine the surface-derived electronic and chemical structures of nanostructured GaRh alloys as a model system for supported catalytically active liquid metal solutions (SCALMS), a novel catalyst candidate for dehydrogenation reactions that are important for the petrochemical and hydrogen energy industry. It is reported that under ambient conditions, SCALMS tends to form a gallium oxide shell, which can be removed by an activation treatment at elevated temperatures and hydrogen flow to enhance the catalytic reactivity. We prepared a 7 at. % Rh containing the GaRh sample and interrogated the evolution of the surface chemical and electronic structure by photoelectron spectroscopy (complemented by scanning electron microscopy) upon performing surface oxidation and (activation treatment mimicking) annealing treatments in ultrahigh vacuum conditions. The initially pronounced Rh 4d and Fermi level-derived states in the valence band spectra disappear upon oxidation (due to formation of a GaOx shell) but reemerge upon annealing, especially for temperatures of 600 &#176;C and above, i.e., when the GaOx shell is efficiently being removed and the Ga matrix is expected to be liquid. At the same temperature, new spectroscopic features at both the high and low binding energy sides of the Rh 3d5/2 spectra are observed, which we attribute to new GaRh species with depleted and enriched Rh contents, respectively. A liquefied and GaOx-free surface is also expected for GaRh SCALMS at reaction conditions, and thus the revealed high-temperature properties of the GaRh alloy provide insights about respective catalysts at work.</description>
      <author>Tzung-En Hsieh, Johannes Frisch, Regan G. Wilks, Christian Papp, Marcus B&#228;r</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02286</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
