<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:39:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A Study on the Role of Electric Field in Low-Temperature Plasma Catalytic Ammonia Synthesis via Integrated Density Functional Theory and Microkinetic Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.3c00654</link>
      <description>Ketong Shao, Ali Mesbah, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390901408

                Low-temperature plasma catalysis has shown promise for various chemical processes such as light hydrocarbon conversion, volatile organic compounds removal, and ammonia synthesis. Plasma-catalytic ammonia synthesis has the potential advantages of leveraging renewable energy and distributed manufacturing principles to mitigate the pressing environmental challenges of the energy-intensive Haber-Bosh process, towards sustainable ammonia production. However, lack of foundational understanding of plasma-catalyst interactions poses a key challenge to optimizing plasma-catalytic processes. Recent studies suggest electro- and photoeffects, such as electric field and charge, can play an important role in enhancing surface reactions. These studies mostly rely on using density functional theory (DFT) to investigate surface reactions under these effects. However, integration of DFT with microkinetic modeling in plasma catalysis, which is crucial for establishing a comprehensive understanding of the interplay between the gas-phase chemistry and surface reactions, remains largely unexplored. This paper presents a first-principles framework coupling DFT calculations and microkinetic modeling to investigate the role of electric field on plasma-catalytic ammonia synthesis. The DFT-microkinetic model shows more consistent predictions with experimental observations, as compared to the case wherein the variable effects of plasma process parameters on surface reactions are neglected. In particular, predictions of the DFT-microkinetic model indicate electric field can have a notable effect on surface reactions relative to other process parameters. A global sensitivity analysis is performed to investigate how ammonia synthesis pathways will change in relation to different plasma process parameters. The DFT-microkinetic model is then used in conjunction with active learning to systematically explore the complex parameter space of the plasma-catalytic ammonia synthesis to maximize the amount of produced ammonia while inhibiting reactions dissipating energy, such as the recombination of H2 through gas-phase H radicals and surface-adsorbed H. This paper demonstrates the importance of accounting for the effects of electric field on surface reactions when investigating and optimizing the performance of plasma-catalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Ketong Shao, Ali Mesbah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.3c00654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-specific metal-support interaction to switch the activity of Ir single atoms for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-44815-0</link>
      <description>Jie Wei, Hengjing Tang, Li Sheng, Ruyang Wang, Minghui Fan, Jin Wan, Yaoguo Wu, Z. D. Zhang, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390904335

                Abstract The metal-support interactions (MSI) could greatly determine the electronic properties of single-atom catalysts, thus affecting the catalytic performance. However, the typical approach to regulating MSI usually suffers from interference of the variation of supports or sacrificing the stability of catalysts. Here, we effectively regulate the site-specific MSI of Ir single atoms anchored on Ni layered double hydroxide through an electrochemical deposition strategy. Cathodic deposition drives Ir atoms to locate at three-fold facial center cubic hollow sites with strong MSI, while anodic deposition drives Ir atoms to deposit onto oxygen vacancy sites with weak MSI. The mass activity and intrinsic activity of Ir single-atom catalysts with strong MSI towards oxygen evolution reaction are 19.5 and 5.2 times that with weak MSI, respectively. Mechanism study reveals that the strong MSI between Ir atoms and the support stimulates the activity of Ir sites by inducing the switch of active sites from Ni sites to Ir sites and optimizes the adsorption strength of intermediates, thereby enhancing the activity.</description>
      <author>Jie Wei, Hengjing Tang, Li Sheng, Ruyang Wang, Minghui Fan, Jin Wan, Yaoguo Wu, Z. D. Zhang, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-44815-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electroreduction on two-dimensional transition metal 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12-perthiolated coronene frameworks: a theoretical investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00268976.2024.2303394</link>
      <description>Xuelian She, Lin Cheng, Ying Wang, Kai Li, Zhijian Wu, Molecular Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390909288

                Developing highly efficient catalysts for carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) is significant in producing useful chemicals and alleviating environmental pollution. Herein, a series of two-dimensional TM-PTC (TM = Sc-Zn, PTC = 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12-perthiolated coronene) frameworks as CO2RR electrocatalysts are investigated based on the density functional method. The calculated results showed that the main product is CH4 for TM-PTC (TM = Sc-Mn). However, these catalysts can be poisoned by water molecules due to its strong adsorption on the catalyst surface. To solve the problem, we modified these catalysts by adding axial oxygen (TM-O-PTC). Our study showed that TM-O-PTC (TM = V, Cr) are good catalysts for CO2RR to produce CH4. We expected that this work could provide a useful strategy for developing high-performance CO2RR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xuelian She, Lin Cheng, Ying Wang, Kai Li, Zhijian Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00268976.2024.2303394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D printed electrically conductive amine based sorbent for CO2 capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104064</link>
      <description>Marijke Jacobs, Yoran De Vos, Marleen Rombouts, International Journal of Greenhouse Gas Control. 132(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390916550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marijke Jacobs, Yoran De Vos, Marleen Rombouts</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material Dynamics of Manganese-Based Oxychlorides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02362</link>
      <description>Ruihan Li, Dennis Nordlund, Linsey C. Seitz, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390918522

                Earth-abundant manganese-based oxides have emerged as promising alternatives to noble-metal-based catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic conditions; however, their inferior activity and stability present critical challenges for the sustainable production of hydrogen via water electrolysis. Moving beyond oxides, heteroanionic materials, which incorporate anions with lower electronegativity than oxygen, have shown potential for improving the OER performance, but a detailed understanding of the underlying mechanisms is lacking. Here, we investigate manganese-based oxychlorides (Mn8O10Cl3 and FeMn7O10Cl3) that exhibit excellent activity and stability for acidic OER to elucidate material property dynamics and correlate them with OER behaviors. Our rigorous electrochemical stability testing reveals that the high operating potential mitigates Mn dissolution over prolonged exposure to the OER conditions. Through a combination of ex situ and in situ surface and bulk-sensitive X-ray spectroscopy analyses, we observe a trade-off between increasing Mn valence and maintaining structural integrity, which results in dynamic bond length changes within the [MnCl6] octahedra during the activation and degradation processes of these oxychloride catalysts. This study provides insights into the fundamental relationships between the chemical, electronic, and geometric properties of the catalysts and their electrocatalytic outcomes.</description>
      <author>Ruihan Li, Dennis Nordlund, Linsey C. Seitz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning boosted &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;b&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; study of the thermal conductivity of Janus PtSTe van der Waals heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.035417</link>
      <description>Lijun Pan, Jes&#250;s Carrete, Zhao Wang, Georg K. H. Madsen, Physical Review B. 109(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390919215

                Calculating the thermal conductivity of heterostructures with multiple layers presents a significant challenge for state-of-the-art ab initio methods. In this study we introduce an efficient neural-network force field (NNFF) to explore the thermal transport characteristics of van der Waals heterostructures based on PtSTe, using both the phonon Boltzmann transport equation and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations. Besides demonstrating a remarkable level of agreement with both theoretical and experimental data, our predictions reveal that heterogeneous combinations like $\mathrm{PtSTe}\text{\ensuremath{-}}{\mathrm{PtTe}}_{2}$ display a notable reduction in thermal conductivity at room temperature, primarily due to broken out-of-plane symmetries and the presence of weak van der Waals interactions. Furthermore, our study highlights the superiority of MD simulations with NNFFs in capturing higher-order anharmonic phonon properties. This is demonstrated through the analysis of the temperature-dependent thermal conductivity curves of PtSTe-based van der Waals heterostructures and advances our understanding of phonon transport in those materials.</description>
      <author>Lijun Pan, Jes&#250;s Carrete, Zhao Wang, Georg K. H. Madsen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.035417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Metalloborophene Nanoribbons on Cu(110)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314576</link>
      <description>Xiao&#8208;Ji Weng, Yi Zhu, Ying Xu, Jie Bai, Zhuhua Zhang, Bin Xu, Xiang&#8208;Feng Zhou, Yongjun Tian, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390919368

                Abstract Metalloborophene, characterized by the presence of metal&#8208;centered boron wheels denoted as M&#169;B n , has garnered considerable attention in recent years due to its versatile properties and potential applications in fields such as electronics, spintronics, and catalysis. However, the experimental verification of metalloborophene is challenging, mainly due to the unconventional 2D boron networks. In this study, scanning tunneling microscopy, X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy, low energy electron diffraction, and first&#8208;principles calculations are employed to unveil Cu&#169;B 8 metalloborophene nanoribbons formed via spontaneous alloying after the deposition of boron on a heated Cu(110) substrate under ultrahigh vacuum condition. The thermodynamically preferred precursor, the anchoring of boron network to metal atoms, and anisotropic lattice mismatch are identified as pivotal factors in the formation of these metalloborophene nanoribbons. This discovery expands the repertoire of 2D materials and offers a potential pathway for the synthesis of other metalloborophenes.</description>
      <author>Xiao&#8208;Ji Weng, Yi Zhu, Ying Xu, Jie Bai, Zhuhua Zhang, Bin Xu, Xiang&#8208;Feng Zhou, Yongjun Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data driven computational design of stable oxygen evolution catalysts by DFT and machine learning: Promising electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2023.12.048</link>
      <description>Hwanyeol Park, Yunseok Kim, Sang&#8208;Hoon Choi, Ho Jun Kim, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390937419

                The revolutionary development of machine learning (ML), data science, and analytics, coupled with its application in material science, stands as a significant milestone of the scientific community over the last decade. Investigating active, stable, and cost-efficient catalysts is crucial for oxygen evolution reaction owing to the significance in a range of electrochemical energy conversion processes. In this work, we have demonstrated an efficient approach of high-throughput screening to find stable transition metal oxides under acid condition for high-performance oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts through density functional theory (DFT) calculation and a machine learning algorithm. A methodology utilizing both the Materials Project database and DFT calculations was introduced to assess the acid stability under specific reaction conditions. Building upon this, OER catalytic activity of acid-stable materials was examined, highlighting potential OER catalysts that meet the required properties. We identified IrO2, Fe(SbO3)2, Co(SbO3)2, Ni(SbO3)2, FeSbO4, Fe(SbO3)4, MoWO6, TiSnO4, CoSbO4, and Ti(WO4)2 as promising catalysts, several of which have already been experimentally discovered for their robust OER performance, while others are novel for experimental exploration, thereby broadening the chemical scope for efficient OER electrocatalysts. Descriptors of the bond length of TM&#8211;O and the first ionization energy were used to unveil the OER activity origin. From the calculated results, guidance has been derived to effectively execute advanced high-throughput screenings for the discovery of catalysts with favorable properties. Furthermore, the intrinsic correlation between catalytic performance and various atomic and structural factors was elucidated using the ML algorithm. Through these approaches, we not only streamline the choice of the promising electrocatalysts but also offer insights for the design of varied catalyst models and the discovery of superior catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hwanyeol Park, Yunseok Kim, Sang&#8208;Hoon Choi, Ho Jun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2023.12.048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Mechanism of Nitrobenzene Reduction to Aniline by Phosphomolybdic Acid Supported TM&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c03106</link>
      <description>Congcong Zhao, Shuang Wang, Likai Yan, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390938484

                Catalytic hydrogenation of nitrobenzene (Ph-NO2) to aniline (Ph-NH2) is a model reaction in the field of catalysis, in which the development of efficient catalysts remains a great challenge due to the lack of strategies to solve activity and selectivity problems. In this work, the mechanism of Ph-NO2 hydrogenation over Pt1 supported on phosphomolybdic acid (&#945;-PMA) was proposed by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The results show that the dissociation of the first and second N-O bonds is triggered by single H-induced and double H-induced mechanisms, respectively. The limiting potential of the reaction process is -0.19 V, which is the smallest potential in the field of Ph-NO2 reduction reaction to date. In the whole reaction process, the catalytic active site is the Pt atom, and polyoxometalate plays the role of an electronic sponge in the reaction. Additionally, based on experimentally confirmed Pt1/Na3PMA, the reduction capacity of Pd1/Na3PMA toward Ph-NO2 was predicted by DFT calculation. The distinctive adsorption patterns of Ph-NO2 on Pt1/Na3PMA and Pd1/Na3PMA were elucidated using the DOS diagram and fragment molecular orbital analysis. We anticipate that our theoretical calculations can provide novel perspectives for experimental researchers.</description>
      <author>Congcong Zhao, Shuang Wang, Likai Yan, Zhong&#8208;Min Su</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c03106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Dielectric Relaxation of Liquid Water Using Neural Network Potential and Classical Pairwise Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.124054</link>
      <description>Jae Hyun Ryu, Ji Woong Yu, Tae Jun Yoon, Won Bo Lee, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390941665

                Understanding the role of hydrogen bond networks in determining the relaxation dynamics is essential for understanding natural phenomena in liquid water. Classical pairwise additive models have been widely utilized for elaborating the underlying mechanism behind the relaxation phenomena. However, they have shown their limits due to either the absence or inaccurate descriptions of many-body and medium-to-long-range interactions. This work demonstrates that the Deep Potential Molecular Dynamics (DPMD) model trained with SCAN functional help calculate the dielectric constant at the accuracy of the first-principles simulations. The DPMD model outperforms the classical force fields (SPC/Fw and TIP4P/&#949;) in predicting dielectric spectra especially in replicating high-frequency excesses, attributed to its adeptness in simulating intricate hydrogen bond networks. Through a comprehensive analysis of the simulation results, it becomes evident that only the DPMD model effectively accommodates a wide range of hydrogen bond coordination scenarios thereby characterizing the intricate nature of the hydrogen bond network. This adaptability stems from the intricate interplay of many-body interactions and intramolecular dynamics. In addition, orientation defects within the DPMD model play a significant role in shaping the potential energy barrier due to the adaptability.</description>
      <author>Jae Hyun Ryu, Ji Woong Yu, Tae Jun Yoon, Won Bo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.124054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd 4d Orbital Overlapping Modulation on Au@Pd Nanowires for Efficient H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13259</link>
      <description>Zhongmin Deng, Amir Hassan Bagherzadeh Mostaghimi, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Samira Siahrostami, Xiaolei Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390943237

                Isolating Pd atoms has been shown to be crucial for the design of a Pd-based electrocatalyst toward 2e&#8211; oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). However, there are limited studies focusing on the systematic compositional design that leads to an optimal balance between activity and selectivity. Herein, we design a series of Au@Pd core@shell structures to investigate the influence of the Pd 4d orbital overlapping degree on 2e&#8211; ORR performance. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that enhanced H2O2 selectivity and activity are achieved at Pdn clusters with n &#8804; 3, and Pd clusters larger than Pd3 should be active for 4e&#8211; ORR. However, experimental results show that Au@Pd nanowires (NWs) with Pd4 as the primary structure exhibit the optimal H2O2 performance in an acidic electrolyte with a high mass activity (7.05 A mg&#8211;1 at 0.4 V) and H2O2 selectivity (nearly 95%). Thus, we report that Pd4, instead of Pd3, is the upper threshold of Pd cluster size for an ideal 2e&#8211; ORR. It results from the oxygen coverage on the catalyst surface during the ORR process, and such an oxygen coverage phenomenon causes electron redistribution and weakened *OOH binding strength on active sites, leading to enhanced activity of Pd4 with only 0.06 V overpotential in acidic media.</description>
      <author>Zhongmin Deng, Amir Hassan Bagherzadeh Mostaghimi, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Samira Siahrostami, Xiaolei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of metal&#8208;free 2D electrocatalysts toward the oxygen electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20220174</link>
      <description>Joyjit Kundu, Taehyun Kwon, Kwangyeol Lee, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Exploration. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390944231

                Abstract The advancement of economical and readily available electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) holds paramount importance in the advancement of fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries. Recently, 2D non&#8208;metallic materials have obtained substantial attention as viable alternatives for ORR catalysts due to their manifold advantages, encompassing low cost, ample availability, substantial surface&#8208;to&#8208;volume ratio, high conductivity, exceptional durability, and competitive activity. The augmented ORR performances observed in metal&#8208;free 2D materials typically arise from heteroatom doping, defects, or the formation of heterostructures. Here, the authors delve into the realm of electrocatalysts for the ORR, pivoting around metal&#8208;free 2D materials. Initially, the merits of metal&#8208;free 2D materials are explored and the reaction mechanism of the ORR is dissected. Subsequently, a comprehensive survey of diverse metal&#8208;free 2D materials is presented, tracing their evolutionary journey from fundamental concepts to pragmatic applications in the context of ORR. Substantial importance is given on the exploration of various strategies for enhancing metal&#8208;free 2D materials and assessing their impact on inherent material performance, including electronic properties. Finally, the challenges and future prospects that lie ahead for metal&#8208;free 2D materials are underscored, as they aspire to serve as efficient ORR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Joyjit Kundu, Taehyun Kwon, Kwangyeol Lee, Sang&#8208;Il Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20220174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvation Enthalpy Determination for Aqueous-Phase Reaction Adsorbates Using Ab Initio Molecular Dynamics-Based Structure Sampling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06870</link>
      <description>Hyonho Chun, Ankita Morankar, Zhenhua Zeng, Jeffrey Greeley, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390964436

                The interplay between covalent and noncovalent interactions at the solid&#8211;liquid interface strongly influences electrocatalytic reactions. Although methods to determine the former interactions have been rigorously developed, the latter are often described with static bilayer models or similarly approximate methods. In this study, we account for the disorder and dynamics at complex electrochemical interfaces by proposing a simple theory to estimate the enthalpy of solvation for adsorbed intermediates. In a strategy reminiscent of Born&#8211;Haber cycles, the enthalpy of solvation is expressed in terms of two subprocesses: vacancy creation by water reorganization and adsorbate interaction with solvent molecules. The magnitude of the solvation enthalpy is then determined as a mean valueof hydrated adsorbate-catalyst configurations obtained from simulated annealing with ab initio molecular dynamic (AIMD) simulations. This theory can be generalized for many combinations of surfaces and adsorbates. Its application improves treatment of energetics at electrified solid&#8211;liquid interfaces as well as corresponding structure&#8211;activity&#8211;stability predictions, as demonstrated for electrochemical oxygen reduction on Pt(111) and on Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts and for ethanol electrooxidation on Pt(111).</description>
      <author>Hyonho Chun, Ankita Morankar, Zhenhua Zeng, Jeffrey Greeley</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Wyckoff Sites to Construct Machine-Learning-Driven Interatomic Potentials for Crystalline Materials: A Case Study on &#945;-Alumina</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c05908</link>
      <description>Christian Rodr&#237;guez-Mart&#237;nez, Tony Schwedek, Evelyn Salazar, Xim Bokhimi, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390964539

                We present a methodology leveraging machine learning models to generate interatomic potentials for crystalline materials. This approach is rooted in the material&#8217;s crystallography in question. Specifically, we tap into the occupied Wyckoff sites, extracting the defining features that encapsulate the atomic local order in the material. Our choice for the target variable is the formation energy per atom, derived from the total energy of the structure&#8217;s representative cell. Our machine learning model&#8217;s architecture depends on the occupied Wyckoff sites. The diversity of these occupied sites conditions the layering scheme within the model. Atoms occupying a particular Wyckoff site were modeled with the architecture and learning parameters linked to the respective layer. To illustrate our method, we developed an interatomic potential for atomic interactions in &#945;-alumina. For training purposes, we generated the samples through quantum mechanical computations. The evaluation of the learned interatomic potential involved conducting molecular dynamics calculations on a 2 &#215; 2 &#215; 2 supercell, yielding formation energies per atom deviating by less than 1.0 meV from the quantum mechanics results. The methodology described here paves the way for further innovations, potentially ushering in the creation of interatomic potentials that can be utilized for more than one material. Moreover, this approach provides valuable insights into the feasibility of substituting atoms within a compound by focusing exclusively on the specific Wyckoff sites that they occupy.</description>
      <author>Christian Rodr&#237;guez-Mart&#237;nez, Tony Schwedek, Evelyn Salazar, Xim Bokhimi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c05908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of acidic titanium-based oxygen evolution anode catalyst design: mechanistic, compositional design, and research status</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173576</link>
      <description>Chuanbin Li, Tao Lin, Xiaotian Yuan, Hongzhou Jiang, Zhifang Hu, Yanxi Yin, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390967206

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key half-reaction in fields including water electrolysis, organic synthesis, and water treatment. With the development of the industry, research into highly active and stable oxygen evolution anodes in an acidic environment is essential. DSA is the dimensionally stable anode. Widespread attention has been paid to titanium-based DSAs in the field of acidic oxygen precipitation due to their low overpotential and high acid resistance. The titanium-based anode mainly consists of two parts: catalyst and titanium substrate, where the design of the catalyst is the key to the anode design. The factors affecting the catalytic activity and durability of the titanium-based DSA were heterogeneous and rarely reported. In this paper, the influence of catalytic mechanism and composition design on the catalytic activity and service life of anode is reviewed from the perspective of the catalyst. Then, the current situation related to anode preparation is summarized, and an improvement strategy to enhance the activity and stability of anode is proposed based on the failure mode of titanium-based DSA.</description>
      <author>Chuanbin Li, Tao Lin, Xiaotian Yuan, Hongzhou Jiang, Zhifang Hu, Yanxi Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Zn/Co&#8211;N&#8211;C as ORR Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11355</link>
      <description>Weixuan Xu, Rui Zeng, Michael Rebarchik, Alvaro Posada-Borb&#243;n, Huiqi Li, Christopher J. Pollock, Manos Mavrikakis, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390976238

                Hydrogen fuel cells have drawn increasing attention as one of the most promising next-generation power sources for future automotive transportation. Developing efficient, durable, and low-cost electrocatalysts, to accelerate the sluggish oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) kinetics, is urgently needed to advance fuel cell technologies. Herein, we report on metal&#8211;organic frameworks-derived nonprecious dual metal single-atom catalysts (SACs) (Zn/Co&#8211;N&#8211;C), consisting of Co&#8211;N4 and Zn&#8211;N4 local structures. These catalysts exhibited superior ORR activity with a half-wave potential (E1/2) of 0.938 V versus RHE (reversible hydrogen electrode) and robust stability (&#916;E1/2 = &#8722;8.5 mV) after 50k electrochemical cycles. Moreover, this remarkable performance was validated under realistic fuel cell working conditions, achieving a record-high peak power density of &#8764;1 W cm&#8211;2 among the reported SACs for alkaline fuel cells. Operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy was conducted to identify the active sites and reveal catalytic mechanistic insights. The results indicated that the Co atom in the Co&#8211;N4 structure was the main catalytically active center, where one axial oxygenated species binds to form an Oads&#8211;Co&#8211;N4 moiety during the ORR. In addition, theoretical studies, based on a potential-dependent microkinetic model and core-level shift calculations, showed good agreement with the experimental results and provided insights into the bonding of oxygen species on Co&#8211;N4 centers during the ORR. This work provides a comprehensive mechanistic understanding of the active sites in the Zn/Co&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts and will pave the way for the future design and advancement of high-performance single-site electrocatalysts for fuel cells and other energy applications.</description>
      <author>Weixuan Xu, Rui Zeng, Michael Rebarchik, Alvaro Posada-Borb&#243;n, Huiqi Li, Christopher J. Pollock, Manos Mavrikakis, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Pt&#8211;N4 Active Sites Anchored on Porous C3N4 Nanosheet for Boosting the Photocatalytic CO2 Reduction with Nearly 100% CO Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123737</link>
      <description>Song Hu, Panzhe Qiao, Longzhou Xiao, Guiming Ba, Xiaolong Zu, Huilin Hu, Jinhua Ye, Defa Wang, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390987109

                Photoreduction of CO2 and H2O into fuels and value-added chemicals is a promising green technology for solar-to-chemical conversion. However, improving the conversion efficiency with regulated product selectivity is a big challenge due to the sluggish dynamic transfer and insufficient active sites. Herein, we report on Pt single atoms anchored porous C3N4 nanosheet photocatalyst (Pt1@CN) with Pt&#8211;N4 coordination for stable and efficient CO2 photoreduction using H2O as reductant. The Pt1@CN exhibits an evolution rate of 84.8 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 with nearly 100% CO selectivity, outperforming most previous C3N4-based single-atom photocatalysts. Experimental and DFT calculation results reveal that the Pt&#8211;N4 coordinated active sites promote the photogenerated electron transfer, CO2 adsorption/activation, *COOH generation, and *CO desorption, thus accounting for the significantly improved CO2 photoreduction activity with &#8764;100% CO selectivity. This study provides a deep insight into the significant roles of single-atom active sites in enhancing the CO2 photoreduction activity and regulating the product selectivity.</description>
      <author>Song Hu, Panzhe Qiao, Longzhou Xiao, Guiming Ba, Xiaolong Zu, Huilin Hu, Jinhua Ye, Defa Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the impact of oxygen functional groups on the catalytic activity of M-N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-C catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction: A density functional theory and machine learning approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3mh02115g</link>
      <description>Liang Xie, Wei Zhou, Yuming Huang, Zhibin Qu, Longhao Li, Chaowei Yang, Yani Ding, Junfeng Li, Xiaoxiao Meng, Fei Sun, Jihui Gao, Guangbo Zhao, Yukun Qin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390987145

                While current experimental and computational studies often concentrate on introducing external structures or idealized MN 4 models, we emphasize the often-overlooked impact of inherent OGs within the carbon structure of MN 4 materials, presenting a new perspective on their catalytic activity origin.</description>
      <author>Liang Xie, Wei Zhou, Yuming Huang, Zhibin Qu, Longhao Li, Chaowei Yang, Yani Ding, Junfeng Li, Xiaoxiao Meng, Fei Sun, Jihui Gao, Guangbo Zhao, Yukun Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3mh02115g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid synthesis of active Pt single atoms and Ru clusters on carbon black &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; a highly efficient microwave strategy for the hydrogen evolution reaction in acidic and alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta05396b</link>
      <description>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Bozhi Yang, Manjun Zhan, Shaorou Ke, Yang Fan, Xiaowen Wu, Yicen Liu, Zhaohui Huang, Xin Min, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390988147

                Using a highly efficient microwave reduction strategy, we successfully designed a novel synergistic electrocatalyst, Pt 1 Ru x @C, which was synthesized in an impressively short time of only 50 seconds.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Bozhi Yang, Manjun Zhan, Shaorou Ke, Yang Fan, Xiaowen Wu, Yicen Liu, Zhaohui Huang, Xin Min</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta05396b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOFs coupled transition metals, graphene, and MXenes: Emerging electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148776</link>
      <description>Abdul Hanan, Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Faiza Bibi, Amjad Ali Khan, Irfan Ali Soomro, Altaf Hussain, Umair Aftab, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390990449

                Development of effective transition metal catalyst to alternate precious metal platinum (Pt) based catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) has attracted wide interest recently. HER through electrochemical water splitting (EWS) is a green pathway to generate hydrogen (H2) fuel without any carbon dioxide (CO2) emission. However, this technology has been restricted dependency on platinum (Pt)-based catalyst to achieve optimum performance. At present, Pt based catalyst serves as a benchmark material in electrochemical H2 production. Extensive studies have been conducted on new type of porous materials metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) due to the Pt-based catalysts scarcity and cost. In this review, we have discussed the latest advancements of MOFs, which encompass transition metals (TMs), graphene, and MXenes. MOF-based electrocatalysts synthesis methods and electrochemical characteristics are also briefly summarized. Scientists can embark on further exploration of the capabilities offered by MOF-based catalysts by expanding the progress achieved and acknowledging the hurdles that remain. Consequently, their efforts can significantly contribute to the advancement of next-generation technologies for energy storage and conversion.</description>
      <author>Abdul Hanan, Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Faiza Bibi, Amjad Ali Khan, Irfan Ali Soomro, Altaf Hussain, Umair Aftab</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoxPy monolayers as ideal materials for electrochemical applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159412</link>
      <description>Li Xue, Baolei Li, Chaozheng He, Haizhong Guo, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391004056

                Exploring high-performance and cost-effective materials for electrochemical applications to meet eco-friendly and sustainable energy demands remain as an urgent need all the time. Large specific surface area and robust chemical activity endow two-dimensional (2D) materials with the potential as excellent candidates for electrochemical applications. Herein, we systematically study the 2D morphology for the Co-P system via advanced structural search and identify a series of stable monolayers, such as CoP, Co2P, and Co3P2. Detailed first-principle calculations reveal that these monolayers showcase inherent metallicity which benefits boosting the electrochemical process. For hydrogen evolution reactions (HER), the activity of CoP could reach 54 meV, which is comparable to that of Pt. As anode material potassium-ion batteries, CoP exhibits a suitable open circuit voltage and high capacity to store metal ion. This work disclosed the possible multifunctional applications for CoxPy monolayers and provided some theoretical guidance in designing electrocatalysts and anode materials from 2D transition-metal materials used in electrochemical processes.</description>
      <author>Li Xue, Baolei Li, Chaozheng He, Haizhong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single Atoms Supported on Defect Ceria as an Active and Stable Dual-Site Catalyst for Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.3c04237</link>
      <description>Dung Van Dao, Giovanni Di Liberto, Sunny Yadav, Periyayya Uthirakumar, Kai Chen, Gianfranco Pacchioni, In&#8722;Hwan Lee, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391014224

                This work evaluates the feasibility of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) using Pt single-atoms (1.0 wt %) on defect-rich ceria (Pt1/CeOx) as an active and stable dual-site catalyst. The catalyst displayed a low overpotential and a small Tafel slope in an alkaline medium. Moreover, Pt1/CeOx presented a high mass activity and excellent durability, competing with those of the commercial Pt/C (20 wt %). In this picture, the defective CeOx is active for water adsorption and dissociation to create H* intermediates, providing the first site where the reaction occurs. The H* intermediate species then migrate to adsorb and react on the Pt2+ isolated atoms, the site where H2 is formed and released. DFT calculations were also performed to obtain mechanistic insight on the Pt1/CeOx catalyst for the HER. The results indicate a new possibility to improve the state-of-the-art alkaline HER catalysts via a combined effect of the O vacancies on the ceria support and Pt2+ single atoms.</description>
      <author>Dung Van Dao, Giovanni Di Liberto, Sunny Yadav, Periyayya Uthirakumar, Kai Chen, Gianfranco Pacchioni, In&#8722;Hwan Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.3c04237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climbing the Hydrogen Evolution Volcano with a NiTi Shape Memory Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03216</link>
      <description>Sreetama Ghosh, Denver Haycock, N. C. Mehra, Susanta Bera, Hannah Johnson, Lucian Roiban, M. Aouine, P. Vernoux, Peter C. Th&#252;ne, William F. Schneider, Mihalis N. Tsampas, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391014304

                Alkaline water electrolysis is a sustainable way to produce green hydrogen using renewable electricity. Even though the rates of the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are 2-3 orders of magnitude less under alkaline conditions than under acidic conditions, the possibility of using non-precious metal catalysts makes alkaline HER appealing. We identify a novel and facile route for substantially improving HER performance via the use of commercially available NiTi shape memory alloys, which upon heating undergo a phase transformation from the monoclinic martensite to the cubic austenite structure. While the room-temperature performance is modest, austenitic NiTi outperforms Pt (which is the state-of-the-art HER electrocatalyst) in terms of current density by &#8804;50% at 80 &#176;C. Surface ensembles presented by the austenite phase are computed with density functional theory to bind hydrogen more weakly than either metallic Ni or Ti and to have binding energies ideally suited for HER.</description>
      <author>Sreetama Ghosh, Denver Haycock, N. C. Mehra, Susanta Bera, Hannah Johnson, Lucian Roiban, M. Aouine, P. Vernoux, Peter C. Th&#252;ne, William F. Schneider, Mihalis N. Tsampas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal electronic descriptors for optimizing hydrogen evolution in transition metal-doped MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159329</link>
      <description>Jisong Hu, Jiaying Mo, Chengpeng Yu, Dongsheng Li, Rui Zhang, Ling Miao, Xiao Ji, Jianjun Jiang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391018225

                The integration of transition metal (TM) atoms into two-dimensional (2D) transition metal carbides and nitrides (MXenes) has been identified as a promising strategy for enhancing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance. However, the vast combinatorial space presents challenges for rapid catalyst screening. In response, high-throughput calculations were conducted on Ti2CO2 and Zr2CO2 doped with a wide array of TM single atoms. The local structural and corresponding electronic structural changes were analyzed, with an emphasis on their implications for HER performance. Furthermore, universal electronic descriptors were developed using the Sure Independence Screening and Sparsifying Operator (SISSO) method, harmonizing the Gibbs free energy of hydrogen adsorption (&#916;GH*) trends across different MXenes substrates doped with TM atoms. These descriptors enabled the prediction of Cr, Fe, Ru, Pd, Os, and Ir as effective dopants for optimizing the &#916;GH* of Hf2CO2, resulting in a reduction of &#916;GH* from 1.082 eV to within &#177; 0.2 eV. Our work not only highlights the potential of these TM dopants in significantly enhancing the catalytic activity of MXenes but also underscores the value of universal electronic structure descriptors in rapidly identifying and developing high-performance HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jisong Hu, Jiaying Mo, Chengpeng Yu, Dongsheng Li, Rui Zhang, Ling Miao, Xiao Ji, Jianjun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated anode with 3D electron/ion conductive network for stable lithium metal batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103201</link>
      <description>Ziqiang Liu, Xiao Fu, Zhendong Li, Dingcheng Guo, Zh&#233; Peng, Ruijuan Xiao, Xiayin Yao, Energy Storage Materials. 66(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391018604

                Lithium metal anode has attracted increasing attention due to its ultra-high theoretical specific capacity and low redox potential. However, the severe interface problems caused by the parasitic reactions at the anode/separator interface greatly hinder its applications. Herein we design a 3D lithium&#8722;boron (LiB) fiber integrated lithium anode with polypropylene separator through the interfacial adhesive strategy with poly(vinylidene fluoride-co-hexafluoropropylene)-based polymer electrolyte. The 3D Li/LiB anode after chemical etching can increase the exchange current density to 36.8 mA cm&#8722;2, which is about 14 times the value of the pristine anode with 2.6 mA cm&#8722;2. Meanwhile, the poly(vinylidene fluoride-co-hexafluoropropylene)-based polymer electrolyte ensures high ionic conductivity and interfacial stability. Thus, the integrated anode with 3D electron/ion conductive network can guide Li deposition away from the unsafe anode/separator interface, and directly suppress the growth of lithium dendrites. As a result, the integrated anode with LiNi0.83Mn0.06Co0.11O2 cathode exhibits an excellent discharge capacity of 168.3 mAh g &#8722;1 at a high current density of 5 C. Besides, the rigid LiB skeleton coupling with flexible PVDF-HFP-based polymer electrolyte can effectively prevent the pulverization of lithium anode during long-term cycling, showing superior cycling stability of 1000 cycles at 1 C with a capacity retention of 76 %. This work provides a promising integrated anode for stable lithium metal batteries without lithium dendrite growth.</description>
      <author>Ziqiang Liu, Xiao Fu, Zhendong Li, Dingcheng Guo, Zh&#233; Peng, Ruijuan Xiao, Xiayin Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance prediction of gas turbine blade with multi-source random factors using active learning-based neural network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.122481</link>
      <description>Zicheng Qiu, Yuqi Wang, Jinxing Li, Yonghui Xie, Di Zhang, Applied Thermal Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390948931

                Rapid and accurate performance acquisition of high-temperature gas turbine blades is fundamental to energy system design, analysis, and evaluation. Data-driven surrogate models are a popular alternative to complex and expensive numerical methods, but they require numerous labeled data and are often inaccurate when influenced by multi-source random factors. In this paper, a data-driven framework is proposed based on neural networks and active learning. Gas turbine blade performance with multi-source random factors can be quickly and accurately predicted. Two active learning-based sampling strategies, the Bayesian Sampling strategy (BS) and the Combined Sampling strategy (CS), are proposed to improve the efficiency of dataset building. The established prediction model is called active learning-based neural network (ALNN), which significantly improves the prediction accuracy with small samples. Compared with the artificial neural network using traditional Latin hypercube sampling, the prediction accuracy for the maximum stress of the blade is improved by 31.9%, and the prediction accuracy for the maximum deformation is improved by 47.6%. In addition, based on the ALNN, the low cycle fatigue probabilistic life of the gas turbine blade with multi-source random factors is evaluated. When the material and processing parameters and operating condition parameters are varied randomly, the minimum value of the low cycle fatigue life is 7000 cycles.</description>
      <author>Zicheng Qiu, Yuqi Wang, Jinxing Li, Yonghui Xie, Di Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.122481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NH3 decomposition in autothermal microchannel reactors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-88503-4.00003-x</link>
      <description>Ali Behrad Vakylabad, Mohammad Amin Makarem, Zohre Moravvej, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391064792

                The focus of this chapter is on the breakdown of ammonia intending to produce hydrogen as the cleanest source of energy. A review of microreactors and related technical literature is first collected. Then, the chemical mechanism of two coupled reactions (combustion and decomposition) are discussed. These two reactions are essentially underway in the same coupled microchannels. An autothermal plug-flow reactor for NH3 decomposition is a type of chemical reactor that utilizes a catalytic process to convert ammonia (NH3) into nitrogen (N2) and hydrogen (H2). This reaction is important in the production of hydrogen for fuel cells, as well as in the removal of ammonia from industrial waste streams. The autothermal plug-flow reactor is particularly useful for this reaction because it allows for both exothermic and endothermic reactions to occur simultaneously, without the need for external heating or cooling. The reactor design includes an annular region on the outside of a microchannel containing the catalyst, which allows for efficient heat transfer and mass transfer. The main effective parameters for this type of reactor include temperature, pressure, flow rate, catalyst type and loading, reactant concentration, reactor geometry, and inlet temperature and composition. By optimizing these parameters, the efficiency, selectivity, and yield of the NH3 decomposition reaction can be improved.</description>
      <author>Ali Behrad Vakylabad, Mohammad Amin Makarem, Zohre Moravvej, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-88503-4.00003-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Performance Evaluation of Absorbents for the Electrowinning-Coupled Competitive Separation CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07594</link>
      <description>Xiaomei Wang, Huifeng Fan, Yuanhao Mao, Teng Zhang, Sayd Sultan, Yunsong Yu, Zaoxiao Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391157027

                Electrowinning-coupled competitive separation (ECCS) CO2 capture technology, utilizing renewable electricity as the energy input, is regarded as a promising electrochemically mediated CO2 capture approach to substitute for the traditional solvent-based CO2 scrubbing method. However, this technology is still distant from practical application due to its energy-intensive property, sensitivity to oxygen, amine degradation, and system complexity. The selection of a suitable solvent plays a crucial role in enhancing the overall performance and scalability of the ECCS system. To address an efficient solvent screening method, this paper proposed a systematic comparison of solvents in terms of thermodynamics, electrochemistry, absorption, and desorption performance. The proposed solvent screening method undergoes a critical evaluation through the development of a thermodynamic model and experimentation. Using MEA, EDA, and NH3 as examples (solvents extensively discussed in the ECCS system), the paper provides a comprehensive discussion of the solvent screening method. Results indicate that EDA exhibits superior CO2 absorption and thermodynamic performance. NH3 solvent demonstrates better CO2 desorption and electrochemical performance. However, there is an antithetical relationship between the thermodynamic and electrochemical performance. This phenomenon arises because the Cu2+&#8211;solvent complex, characterized by a stronger coupling performance, is more stable, necessitating a higher potential to reduce the Cu2+&#8211;solvent complex. This leads to increased energy consumption during the solvent regeneration process. Therefore, when solvent screening is conducted, it is essential to categorize and thoroughly consider thermodynamics, electrochemistry, and absorption and desorption performance.</description>
      <author>Xiaomei Wang, Huifeng Fan, Yuanhao Mao, Teng Zhang, Sayd Sultan, Yunsong Yu, Zaoxiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Assembled FeIII-TAML-Based Magnetic Nanostructures for Rapid and Sustainable Destruction of Bisphenol A</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00128-023-03834-1</link>
      <description>Ruochen Dong, Lihua Bai, Sijia Liang, Shuo Xu, Song Gao, Hongjian Li, Ran Hong, Chao Wang, Cheng Gu, Bulletin of Environmental Contamination and Toxicology. 112(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391294140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruochen Dong, Lihua Bai, Sijia Liang, Shuo Xu, Song Gao, Hongjian Li, Ran Hong, Chao Wang, Cheng Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00128-023-03834-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxial Stabilization and Persistent Nucleation of the 3C Polymorph of Ba&lt;sub&gt;0.6&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;0.4&lt;/sub&gt;MnO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c11934</link>
      <description>Catherine Zhou, Charles L. Evans, Elizabeth C. Dickey, Gregory S. Rohrer, Paul A. Salvador, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390939574

                Ba-rich compositions in the BaxSr1-xMnO3 (BSMO) cubic perovskite (3C) system are magnetic ferroelectrics and are of interest for their strong magnetoelectric coupling. Beyond x = 0.5, they only form in hexagonal polymorphs. Here, the 3C phase boundary is pushed to Ba0.6Sr0.4MnO3 for the thin films. Using regular pulsed laser deposition (rPLD), 3C Ba0.6Sr0.4MnO3 could be epitaxially stabilized on DyScO3 (101)o substrates by using a 0.1% O2/99.9% N2 gas mixture. However, the 3C phase was mixed with the 4H polymorph for films 24 nm thick and above, and the films were relatively rough. To improve flatness and phase purity, changes in growth kinetics were investigated and interval PLD (iPLD) was especially effective. In iPLD, deposition is interrupted after completion of approximately one monolayer, and the deposit is annealed for a specific period of time before repeating. Both film flatness and, more importantly, the volume of the 3C polymorph improved with iPLD, resulting in 40 nm single-phase films. The results imply that iPLD improves the persistent nucleation of highly metastable phases and offers a new approach to epitaxial stabilization of novel materials, including more Ba-rich BSMO compositions in the 3C structure.</description>
      <author>Catherine Zhou, Charles L. Evans, Elizabeth C. Dickey, Gregory S. Rohrer, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c11934</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence in catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-99135-3.00002-6</link>
      <description>Srinivas Rangarajan, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391223759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Srinivas Rangarajan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-99135-3.00002-6</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
