<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:42:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>The Advancement of Catalysts for Proton&#8208;Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527831005.ch9</link>
      <description>Yi Cheng, Shuangyin Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392092382

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Cheng, Shuangyin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527831005.ch9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic mechanism of sulfur-nitrogen doping metal single-atom graphene-based catalysts for the conversion of CO2 to CH4: a computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108470</link>
      <description>Xiangying Lv, Jingyuan Guo, Jiewei Zhan, Guo&#8208;Jun Kang, Xiaoxing Liu, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392093379

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangying Lv, Jingyuan Guo, Jiewei Zhan, Guo&#8208;Jun Kang, Xiaoxing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dipole Effect on Oxygen Evolution Reaction of 2D Janus Single-Atom Catalysts: A Case of Rh Anchored on the &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;6&lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt;2-NP Configurations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03148</link>
      <description>Tao Huang, Yaping Zhong, Lei Li, Wan Hui, Can Leng, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392093761

                Catalytic performance of single-atom catalysts (SACs) relies fundamentally on the electronic nature and local coordination environment of the active site. Here, based on a machine-learning (ML)-aided density functional theory (DFT) method, we reveal that the intrinsic dipole in Janus materials has a significant impact on the catalytic activity of SACs, using 2D &#947;-phosphorus carbide (&#947;-PC) as a model system. Specifically, a local dipole around the active site is a key degree to tune the catalytic activity and can be used as an important descriptor with a high feature importance of 17.1% in predicting the difference of adsorption free energy (&#916;GO* &#8211; &#916;GOH*) to assess the activity of the oxygen evolution reaction. As a result, the catalytic performance of SACs can be tuned by an intrinsic dipole, in stark contrast to those external stimuli strategies previously used. These results suggest that dipole engineering and the revolutionary DFT-ML hybrid scheme are novel approaches for designing high-performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Huang, Yaping Zhong, Lei Li, Wan Hui, Can Leng, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protective effects of Pt-N-C single-atom nanozymes against myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45927-3</link>
      <description>Tianbao Ye, Cheng Chen, Di Wang, Chengjie Huang, Zhe Yan, Yu Chen, Xian Jin, Xiuyuan Wang, Yiyang Li, Chengxing Shen, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392094779

                Abstract Effective therapeutic strategies for myocardial ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury remain elusive. Targeting reactive oxygen species (ROS) provides a practical approach to mitigate myocardial damage following reperfusion. In this study, we synthesize an antioxidant nanozyme, equipped with a single-Platinum (Pt)-atom (PtsaN-C), for protecting against I/R injury. PtsaN-C exhibits multiple enzyme-mimicking activities for ROS scavenging with high efficiency and stability. Mechanistic studies demonstrate that the excellent ROS-elimination performance of the single Pt atom center precedes that of the Pt cluster center, owing to its better synergistic effect and metallic electronic property. Systematic in vitro and in vivo studies confirm that PtsaN-C efficiently counteracts ROS, restores cellular homeostasis and prevents apoptotic progression after I/R injury. PtsaN-C also demonstrates good biocompatibility, making it a promising candidate for clinical applications. Our study expands the scope of single-atom nanozyme in combating ROS-induced damage and offers a promising therapeutic avenue for the treatment of I/R injury.</description>
      <author>Tianbao Ye, Cheng Chen, Di Wang, Chengjie Huang, Zhe Yan, Yu Chen, Xian Jin, Xiuyuan Wang, Yiyang Li, Chengxing Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45927-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerium doped graphene-based materials towards oxygen reduction reaction catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108461</link>
      <description>Lanna E.B. Lucchetti, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto, Mauro C. Santos, J. Almeida, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392103933

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lanna E.B. Lucchetti, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto, Mauro C. Santos, J. Almeida</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect engineering in transition&#8208;metal (Fe, Co, and Ni)&#8208;based electrocatalysts for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.485</link>
      <description>Kaili Wu, Chaojie Lyu, Jiarun Cheng, Wenqiang Ding, Jiwen Wu, Qian Wang, Woon&#8208;Ming Lau, Jinlong Zheng, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392104756

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting seems to be an efficient strategy to deal with increasingly serious environmental problems and energy crises but still suffers from the lack of stable and efficient electrocatalysts. Designing practical electrocatalysts by introducing defect engineering, such as hybrid structure, surface vacancies, functional modification, and structural distortions, is proven to be a dependable solution for fabricating electrocatalysts with high catalytic activities, robust stability, and good practicability. This review is an overview of some relevant reports about the effects of defect engineering on the electrocatalytic water splitting performance of electrocatalysts. In detail, the types of defects, the preparation and characterization methods, and catalytic performances of electrocatalysts are presented, emphasizing the effects of the introduced defects on the electronic structures of electrocatalysts and the optimization of the intermediates' adsorption energy throughout the review. Finally, the existing challenges and personal perspectives of possible strategies for enhancing the catalytic performances of electrocatalysts are proposed. An in&#8208;depth understanding of the effects of defect engineering on the catalytic performance of electrocatalysts will light the way to design high&#8208;efficiency electrocatalysts for water splitting and other possible applications.</description>
      <author>Kaili Wu, Chaojie Lyu, Jiarun Cheng, Wenqiang Ding, Jiwen Wu, Qian Wang, Woon&#8208;Ming Lau, Jinlong Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Composition of the Metal Dimer Site in Chabazite for Direct Methane-to-Methanol Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06635</link>
      <description>Unni Engedahl, Astrid Boje, Henrik Str&#246;m, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck, Anders Hellman, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392105713

                Methanol is a liquid energy carrier that has the potential to reduce the use of fossil fuels. Industrial production of methanol is currently a multistep high-temperature/high-pressure synthesis route. Direct conversion of methane to methanol under low-temperature and low-pressure conditions is an interesting but challenging alternative, which presently lacks suitable catalysts. Here, the complete reaction cycle for direct methane-to-methanol conversion over transition-metal dimers in the chabazite zeolite is studied by using density functional theory calculations and microkinetic modeling. In particular, a reaction mechanism previously identified for the Cu2 dimer is explored under dry and wet conditions for dimers composed of Ag, Au, Pd, Ni, Co, Fe, and Zn and the bimetallic dimers AuCu, PdCu, and AuPd. The density-functional-theory-based microkinetic modeling shows that Cu2, AuPd, and PdCu dimers have reasonable turnover frequencies under technologically relevant conditions. The adsorption energy of atomic oxygen is identified as a descriptor for the reaction landscape as it correlates with the adsorption and transition-state energies of the other reaction intermediates. Using the established scaling relations, a volcano plot of the rate is generated with its apex close to the Cu2, AuPd, and PdCu dimers.</description>
      <author>Unni Engedahl, Astrid Boje, Henrik Str&#246;m, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck, Anders Hellman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06635</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Oxygen Electrode Bifunctionality with Platinum and Nickel Nanoparticle-Decorated Nitrogen-Doped Binary Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12030453</link>
      <description>Du&#353;an Mladenovi&#263;, Yasemin Aykut, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan, G&#252;lin Selda Pozan Soylu, Diogo M.F. Santos, &#352;&#263;epan S. Miljani&#263;, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, Processes. 12(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392111040

                Developing bifunctional oxygen electrode materials with superior activity for oxygen reduction (ORR) and oxygen evolution (OER) reactions is essential for advancing regenerative fuel cell and rechargeable metal&#8211;air battery technologies. This present work deals with the synthesis and characterization of electrocatalysts containing Pt and Ni nanoparticles supported on nitrogen-doped mixed metal oxides (Mn2O3-NiO) and the systematic evaluation of their bifunctional ORR/OER performance in an alkaline medium. These electrocatalysts have been successfully synthesized by a simple and fast microwave method. PtNi/Mn2O3-NiO-N with a binary metal oxide-to-N ratio of 1:2 demonstrated the best performance among the studied materials regarding bifunctional electrocatalytic activity (&#8710;E = 0.96 V) and robust stability.</description>
      <author>Du&#353;an Mladenovi&#263;, Yasemin Aykut, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan, G&#252;lin Selda Pozan Soylu, Diogo M.F. Santos, &#352;&#263;epan S. Miljani&#263;, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12030453</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mo&#8211;salicylaldehyde-linker (Mo&#8211;Tp) based 2D MOF as a single-atom catalyst for the nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta06666e</link>
      <description>Hassan A. Alhadidi Almheiri, Nirpendra Singh, Dinesh Shetty, Kyriaki Polychronopoulou, Ali A. AlHammadi, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392113686

                This work investigates a Mo&#8211;Tp 2D MOF screened from a number of different transition-metal-based 2D MOFs. After exfoliation, the Mo&#8211;Tp 2D MOF produces ammonia via the distal pathway at a very low limiting potential of &#8722;0.38 V.</description>
      <author>Hassan A. Alhadidi Almheiri, Nirpendra Singh, Dinesh Shetty, Kyriaki Polychronopoulou, Ali A. AlHammadi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta06666e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical synthesis of ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-88516-4.00006-8</link>
      <description>Sarra Knani, Yaovi Holade, Angelo Basile, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392113698

                The electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) is a highly intended strategy of producing ammonia. However, several drawbacks, such as the weak adsorption energy of the N2 molecules on catalyst surfaces, the competing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and the low catalytic activity and selectivity of the used electrocatalysts, make it challenging to increase the NH3 production yield and the Faradaic efficiency (FE). The single-atom electrocatalyst (SAC) is a new category of 0 D nanoparticles that received great attention in the electrocatalysis field and showed satisfactory performance for the NRR. This chapter provides a brief insight into the recent progress of the experimental and theoretical investigations of NRR on SACs, FE, mechanism pathways, and HER suppression. Besides, the origin of the activity, stability, and selectivity of the SACs toward NRR are discussed. Finally, the challenges for the fabrication of new efficient materials are provided.</description>
      <author>Sarra Knani, Yaovi Holade, Angelo Basile</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-88516-4.00006-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of strain in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.007</link>
      <description>Zhixuan Feng, Chia-Tsen Dai, Zhe Zhang, Xuefei Lei, Wenning Mu, Rui Guo, Xuanwen Liu, Jinyuan You, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392122210

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhixuan Feng, Chia-Tsen Dai, Zhe Zhang, Xuefei Lei, Wenning Mu, Rui Guo, Xuanwen Liu, Jinyuan You</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ag&#8211;Ru interface for highly efficient hydrazine assisted water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ee02981f</link>
      <description>Xiaoyang Fu, Dongfang Cheng, Ao Zhang, Jingxuan Zhou, Sibo Wang, Xun Zhao, Jun Chen, Philippe Sautet, Yu Huang, Xiangfeng Duan, Energy and Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392125252

                Ru decorated Ag nanoparticles are designed as highly effective bifunctional electrocatalysts for hydrazine oxidation and hydrogen evolution reactions, enabling a hydrazine assisted water electrolyser with greatly increased current density.</description>
      <author>Xiaoyang Fu, Dongfang Cheng, Ao Zhang, Jingxuan Zhou, Sibo Wang, Xun Zhao, Jun Chen, Philippe Sautet, Yu Huang, Xiangfeng Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ee02981f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking accelerated oxygen evolution reaction enabled by explosive reconstruction of active species based on Co&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;N@NC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00196f</link>
      <description>Hyung Wook Choi, Jiwon Kim, Hyeon&#8208;Seok Bang, Khaled Badawy, Ui Young Lee, Dong In Jeong, Yeseul Kim, Kotiba Hamad, Bong Kyun Kang, Byung Mook Weon, Hyung Suk Oh, Nirpendra Singh, Dae Ho Yoon, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392135567

                The development of a hierarchical structure of Co/Co 4 N@NC has been successfully achieved. The robust oxygen evolution reaction activity of Co/Co 4 N@NC is attributed to the modulation of the d-band center, which reconstruct Co 2+ into Co 3+ .</description>
      <author>Hyung Wook Choi, Jiwon Kim, Hyeon&#8208;Seok Bang, Khaled Badawy, Ui Young Lee, Dong In Jeong, Yeseul Kim, Kotiba Hamad, Bong Kyun Kang, Byung Mook Weon, Hyung Suk Oh, Nirpendra Singh, Dae Ho Yoon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00196f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing and understanding Leaching-Resistant cobalt nanoparticles via N/P incorporation for liquid phase hydroformylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115374</link>
      <description>Carmen Galdeano-Ruano, Silvia Guti&#233;rrez&#8208;Tarri&#241;o, Christian Wittee Lopes, Jaime Mazar&#237;o, Lidia E. Chinchilla, Giovanni Agostini, Jos&#233; J. Calvino, Juan P. Holgado, Enrique Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Castell&#243;n, Alberto Rold&#225;n, Pascual O&#241;a&#8208;Burgos, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392135876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Carmen Galdeano-Ruano, Silvia Guti&#233;rrez&#8208;Tarri&#241;o, Christian Wittee Lopes, Jaime Mazar&#237;o, Lidia E. Chinchilla, Giovanni Agostini, Jos&#233; J. Calvino, Juan P. Holgado, Enrique Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Castell&#243;n, Alberto Rold&#225;n, Pascual O&#241;a&#8208;Burgos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115374</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How transformative are transformative agreements? Evidence from Germany across disciplines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11192-024-04955-y</link>
      <description>W. Benedikt Schmal, Scientometrics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392136948

                Abstract Research institutions across the globe attempt to change the academic publishing system as digitization opens up new opportunities, and subscriptions to the large journal bundles of the leading publishers put library budgets under pressure. One approach is the negotiation of so-called transformative agreements. I study the &#8216;DEAL&#8217; contracts between nearly all German research institutions and Springer Nature and Wiley. I investigate 6.1 million publications in 5,862 journals covering eight fields in the years 2016&#8211;2022 and apply a causal difference-in-differences design to identify whether the likelihood of a paper appearing in an eligible journal increases. The effect strongly depends on the discipline. While material science, chemistry, and economics s tend to hift towards these journals, all other disciplines in my sample do not react. Suggestive evidence hints at the market position of the encompassed publishers before the &#8216;DEAL&#8217; was established: Springer Nature and Wiley appear to benefit more from the contracts in disciplines in which they possessed a higher market share ex ante. The transformative vigor of these agreements in terms of publication behavior seems to be limited. It and highlights that the developments in this intertwined market require further examination.</description>
      <author>W. Benedikt Schmal</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11192-024-04955-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic interactions between adsorbates and catalyst surfaces over long-term OER stability testing in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115387</link>
      <description>Ruihan Li, Bingzhang Lu, Jane Edgington, Linsey Seit, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392137363

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruihan Li, Bingzhang Lu, Jane Edgington, Linsey Seit</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical performance of symmetric solid oxide cells employing a Sc-doped SrFeO3-&#948;-based electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149970</link>
      <description>Caichen Yang, Yuhao Wang, Yunfeng Tian, Ziling Wang, Jian Pu, Francesco Ciucci, Bo Chi, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392138498

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Caichen Yang, Yuhao Wang, Yunfeng Tian, Ziling Wang, Jian Pu, Francesco Ciucci, Bo Chi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density functional theory study of dissociative adsorption of O2 on Pd-skin Pd3Cu(1 1 1) surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112876</link>
      <description>Yanlin Yu, Huaizhang Gu, Guangxin Wu, Xuexia Liu, Computational Materials Science. 237(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392139576

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanlin Yu, Huaizhang Gu, Guangxin Wu, Xuexia Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealloyed nanoporous platinum alloy electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.286</link>
      <description>Viswanathan S. Saji, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392140006

                Dealloyed nanoporous platinum (np-Pt) alloy electrocatalysts are advantageous owing to the lower Pt content in the alloy composition, nanoporous architecture with high electrochemically active surface area, and excellent electrocatalytic activity and durability. Chemical, electrochemical or other dealloying methods help to develop commercially relevant np-Pt alloys. Selection of the appropriate precursor alloy composition, dealloying solution concentration and time, and the number and nature of dealloying steps are essential to optimize the desirable properties. We comprehensively review the available information on dealloyed Pt and its binary, ternary, quaternary and high-entropy alloys, nanoparticles and composites. The review presents various Pt alloy types and their dealloying conditions and the current understanding of the mechanism of electrocatalysis at the nanoporous confined spaces. The origin and the factors contributing to the electrocatalytic activity of dealloyed nanoporous electrocatalysts are discussed. The collective information could assist researchers in deriving more efficient and durable dealloyed electrocatalysts in various electrochemical energy applications.</description>
      <author>Viswanathan S. Saji</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-precision colorimetric-fluorescent dual-mode biosensor for detecting acetylcholinesterase based on a trimetallic nanozyme for efficient peroxidase-mimicking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.013</link>
      <description>Meie Zheng, Mingxing Liu, Zichen Song, Fuqiu Ma, Hao Zhu, Huiling Guo, Hongjian Sun, Journal of Materials Science &amp; Technology. 191(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392145906

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meie Zheng, Mingxing Liu, Zichen Song, Fuqiu Ma, Hao Zhu, Huiling Guo, Hongjian Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Lignocellulosic Molecule Adsorption Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01292</link>
      <description>Joakim S. Jestil&#228;, Nian Fen Wu, Fabio Priante, Adam S. Foster, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392150988

                Here, we present a study combining Bayesian optimization structural inference with the machine learning interatomic potential Neural Equivariant Interatomic Potential (NequIP) to accelerate and enable the study of the adsorption of the conformationally flexible lignocellulosic molecules &#946;-d-xylose and 1,4-&#946;-d-xylotetraose on a copper surface. The number of structure evaluations needed to map out the relevant potential energy surfaces are reduced by Bayesian optimization, while NequIP minimizes the time spent on each evaluation, ultimately resulting in cost-efficient and reliable sampling of large systems and configurational spaces. Although the applicability of Bayesian optimization for the conformational analysis of the more flexible xylotetraose molecule is restricted by the sample complexity bottleneck, the latter can be effectively bypassed with external conformer search tools, such as the Conformer-Rotamer Ensemble Sampling Tool, facilitating the subsequent lower-dimensional global minimum adsorption structure determination. Finally, we demonstrate the applicability of the described approach to find adsorption structures practically equivalent to the density functional theory counterparts at a fraction of the computational cost.</description>
      <author>Joakim S. Jestil&#228;, Nian Fen Wu, Fabio Priante, Adam S. Foster</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Defect Limitations in Photocatalysis: Boron&#8208;Incorporation Engineered Crystalline Red Phosphorus for Enhanced Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400542</link>
      <description>Xinya Pei, Junwei Bian, Wei Zhang, Zhuofeng Hu, Yun Hau Ng, Dong Ye, Xiaofeng Zhai, Zhen Wei, Yuxi Liu, Jiguang Deng, Hongxing Dai, Lin Jing, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392153574

                Abstract Photocatalytic hydrogen evolution (PHE) from water splitting is a promising technology for clean and renewable energy production. Elemental crystalline red phosphorus (CRP) is purposefully designed and developed for PHE reaction. However, the photocatalytic activity of CRP is limited by its intrinsic P vacancy (V P ) defects, which lead to detrimental charge trapping at deep states and hence its severe recombination. To address this issue, a boron (B) incorporated CRP (B&#8208;CRP) photocatalyst is tailored, synthesized via a simple and mild boric acid&#8208;assisted hydrothermal strategy. The incorporation of B effectively fills the V P defects, reducing deep trap states (DTS) and introducing beneficial shallow trap states (STS) within the band structure of CRP. This defect engineering approach leads to enhanced photocatalytic activity, with B&#8208;CRP achieving a PHE rate of 1392 &#181;mol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 , significantly outperforming most reported elemental photocatalysts in the literature. Density functional theory (DFT) simulations and ultrafast spectroscopy support the constructive role of B&#8208;dopant&#8208;induced STS in prolonging active charge carrier lifetimes, promoting more efficient photocatalytic reactions. The findings not only demonstrate the effectiveness of B&#8208;CRP as a photocatalyst but also highlight the usefulness of dopant&#8208;induced STS in advancing PHE technologies.</description>
      <author>Xinya Pei, Junwei Bian, Wei Zhang, Zhuofeng Hu, Yun Hau Ng, Dong Ye, Xiaofeng Zhai, Zhen Wei, Yuxi Liu, Jiguang Deng, Hongxing Dai, Lin Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A universal and scalable transformation of bulk metals into single-atom catalysts in ionic liquids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2319136121</link>
      <description>Shujuan Wang, Ming&#8208;Hui Lu, Xuewen Xia, Fei Wang, Xiaolu Xiong, Kai Ding, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Qian Xu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Hujun Shen, Ji Li, Yufeng Zhao, Jing Wang, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392157760

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) with maximized metal atom utilization and intriguing properties are of utmost importance for energy conversion and catalysis science. However, the lack of a straightforward and scalable synthesis strategy of SACs on diverse support materials remains the bottleneck for their large-scale industrial applications. Herein, we report a general approach to directly transform bulk metals into single atoms through the precise control of the electrodissolution&#8211;electrodeposition kinetics in ionic liquids and demonstrate the successful applicability of up to twenty different monometallic SACs and one multimetallic SAC with five distinct elements. As a case study, the atomically dispersed Pt was electrodeposited onto Ni 3 N/Ni-Co-graphene oxide heterostructures in varied scales (up to 5 cm &#215; 5 cm) as bifunctional catalysts with the electronic metal&#8211;support interaction, which exhibits low overpotentials at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER, 30 mV) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER, 263 mV) with a relatively low Pt loading (0.98 wt%). This work provides a simple and practical route for large-scale synthesis of various SACs with favorable catalytic properties on diversified supports using alternative ionic liquids and inspires the methodology on precise synthesis of multimetallic single-atom materials with tunable compositions.</description>
      <author>Shujuan Wang, Ming&#8208;Hui Lu, Xuewen Xia, Fei Wang, Xiaolu Xiong, Kai Ding, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Qian Xu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Hujun Shen, Ji Li, Yufeng Zhao, Jing Wang, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2319136121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-site segmentally synergistic catalysis mechanism: boosting CoFeSx nanocluster for sustainable water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45700-6</link>
      <description>Siran Xu, Sihua Feng, Yue Yu, Dongping Xue, Mengli Liu, Chao Wang, Kaiyue Zhao, Bingjun Xu, Jianan Zhang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392165142

                Abstract Efficient oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts are essential for sustainable clean energy conversion. However, catalytic materials followed the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) with the inherent scaling relationship between key oxygen intermediates *OOH and *OH, or the lattice-oxygen-mediated mechanism (LOM) with the possible lattice oxygen migration and structural reconstruction, which are not favorable to the balance between high activity and stability. Herein, we propose an unconventional Co-Fe dual-site segmentally synergistic mechanism (DSSM) for single-domain ferromagnetic catalyst CoFeS x nanoclusters on carbon nanotubes (CNT) (CFS-ACs/CNT), which can effectively break the scaling relationship without sacrificing stability. Co 3+ (L.S, t 2g 6 e g 0 ) supplies the strongest OH* adsorption energy, while Fe 3+ (M.S, t 2g 4 e g 1 ) exposes strong O* adsorption. These dual-sites synergistically produce of Co-O-O-Fe intermediates, thereby accelerating the release of triplet-state oxygen ( &#8593; O = O &#8593; ). As predicted, the prepared CFS-ACs/CNT catalyst exhibits less overpotential than that of commercial IrO 2 , as well as approximately 633 h of stability without significant potential loss.</description>
      <author>Siran Xu, Sihua Feng, Yue Yu, Dongping Xue, Mengli Liu, Chao Wang, Kaiyue Zhao, Bingjun Xu, Jianan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45700-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes as Effective Sulfur Hosts and Electrocatalysts to Suppress Lithium Polysulfide Shuttling: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07776</link>
      <description>Thilini Boteju, Sathish Ponnurangam, Venkataraman Thangadurai, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392166721

                Exploring electrocatalysts for the sulfur reduction reaction (SRR) has emerged as a promising strategy to suppress the shuttle effect and enhance the kinetics in lithium&#8211;sulfur (Li&#8211;S) batteries. A comprehensive understanding of the electrocatalytic mechanism within Li&#8211;S batteries remains elusive, which hinders the rational design of advanced electrocatalysts for these systems. In this study, two-dimensional (2D) transition metal carbides and nitrides (MXenes) have been investigated for the catalytic conversion of lithium polysulfides (LiPSs) using density functional theory (DFT). Our findings reveal that MXenes show a moderate binding affinity for LiPSs, suggesting favorable thermodynamics for their role as electrocatalysts for the SRR. This thermodynamic favorability promotes the suppression of the LiPSs&#8217; shuttle effect and the enhancement of the SRR kinetics. The SRR process in Li&#8211;S batteries consists of multiple steps with varying activation energies. Our analysis by constructing the energy diagram for the multistep SRR indicates that the initial reduction of S8 to Li2S8 is facile with a lower activation energy, while the last step where Li2S2 converts to Li2S appears to be a rate-limiting step. To predict the catalytic abilities of MXene structures, we built a volcano-shaped relationship between the adsorption of LiPSs and catalytic activity. We show three MXenes&#9472;Ta2CO2, Zr2NO2, and Mo2NO2 as potential electrocatalysts that exhibit lower thermodynamic overpotentials for the SRR. These findings represent a significant step toward developing advanced electrocatalysts that may unlock the full potential of Li&#8211;S batteries, paving the way for improved energy storage systems with enhanced efficiency and performance.</description>
      <author>Thilini Boteju, Sathish Ponnurangam, Venkataraman Thangadurai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Informative Training Data for Efficient Property Prediction in Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks by Active Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13687</link>
      <description>Antonio San Jos&#233;, &#201;milie Devijver, N. Jakse, Roberta Poloni, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392167663

                In recent data-driven approaches to material discovery, scenarios where target quantities are expensive to compute and measure are often overlooked. In such cases, it becomes imperative to construct a training set that includes the most diverse, representative, and informative samples. Here, a novel regression tree-based active learning algorithm is employed for such a purpose. It is applied to predict the band gap and adsorption properties of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), a novel class of materials that results from the virtually infinite combinations of their building units. Simpler and low dimensional descriptors, such as those based on stoichiometric and geometric properties, are used to compute the feature space for this model owing to their ability to better represent MOFs in the low data regime. The partitions given by a regression tree constructed on the labeled part of the data set are used to select new samples to be added to the training set, thereby limiting its size while maximizing the prediction quality. Tests on the QMOF, hMOF, and dMOF data sets reveal that our method constructs small training data sets to learn regression models that predict the target properties more efficiently than existing active learning approaches, and with lower variance. Specifically, our active learning approach is highly beneficial when labels are unevenly distributed in the descriptor space and when the label distribution is imbalanced, which is often the case for real world data. The regions defined by the tree help in revealing patterns in the data, thereby offering a unique tool to efficiently analyze complex structure&#8211;property relationships in materials and accelerate materials discovery.</description>
      <author>Antonio San Jos&#233;, &#201;milie Devijver, N. Jakse, Roberta Poloni</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13687</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
