<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 18:29:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single Atoms Supported on Defect Ceria as an Active and Stable Dual-Site Catalyst for Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.3c04237</link>
      <description>Dung Van Dao, Giovanni Di Liberto, Sunny Yadav, Periyayya Uthirakumar, Kai Chen, Gianfranco Pacchioni, In&#8722;Hwan Lee, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391014224

                This work evaluates the feasibility of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) using Pt single-atoms (1.0 wt %) on defect-rich ceria (Pt1/CeOx) as an active and stable dual-site catalyst. The catalyst displayed a low overpotential and a small Tafel slope in an alkaline medium. Moreover, Pt1/CeOx presented a high mass activity and excellent durability, competing with those of the commercial Pt/C (20 wt %). In this picture, the defective CeOx is active for water adsorption and dissociation to create H* intermediates, providing the first site where the reaction occurs. The H* intermediate species then migrate to adsorb and react on the Pt2+ isolated atoms, the site where H2 is formed and released. DFT calculations were also performed to obtain mechanistic insight on the Pt1/CeOx catalyst for the HER. The results indicate a new possibility to improve the state-of-the-art alkaline HER catalysts via a combined effect of the O vacancies on the ceria support and Pt2+ single atoms.</description>
      <author>Dung Van Dao, Giovanni Di Liberto, Sunny Yadav, Periyayya Uthirakumar, Kai Chen, Gianfranco Pacchioni, In&#8722;Hwan Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.3c04237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical water oxidation for hydrogen peroxide production: Focus on catalyst and reaction medium design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111960</link>
      <description>Zhimin Gao, Ye Cao, Qiuzi Zhu, Cunshi Wang, Wangjun Bai, Jianzhong Zhu, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. 12(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391018661

                Hydrogen peroxide (H2O2), as a valuable oxidant, has been extensively used in environmental applications. In the past decade, the electrochemical two-electron water oxidation reactions (2e&#8722; WOR) process have attracted considerable interest as a promising route to realize the decentralized production of H2O2. Nonetheless, a systematic review regarding the rational design strategies for electrochemical H2O2 synthesis systems through the 2e&#8722; WOR is still scarce, which is essential for advancing this burgeoning field. Hence, the basic knowledge of WOR, including the reaction mechanism, theoretical calculation prediction, and catalytic performance evaluation indicators, is introduced at the beginning of this review. Next, the different design strategies of catalysts and reaction medium modulation for H2O2 production by the 2e&#8722; WOR route are critically discussed and reviewed. Ultimately, some significant perspectives are proposed on the challenges and opportunities of 2e&#8722; WOR for H2O2 generation based on recent advances.</description>
      <author>Zhimin Gao, Ye Cao, Qiuzi Zhu, Cunshi Wang, Wangjun Bai, Jianzhong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-based/derived catalysts for electrochemical overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.106</link>
      <description>Yan He, Wei Liu, Jingquan Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391020576

                Water-splitting electrocatalysis has gained increasing attention as a promising strategy for developing renewable energy in recent years, but its high overpotential caused by the unfavorable thermodynamics has limited its widespread implementation. Therefore, there is an urgent need to design catalytic materials with outstanding activity and stability that can overcome the high overpotential and thus improve the electrocatalytic efficiency. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) based and/or derived materials are widely used as water-splitting catalysts because of their easily controlled structures, abundant heterointerfaces and increased specific surface area. Herein, some recent research findings on MOFs-based/derived materials are summarized and presented. First, the mechanism and evaluation parameters of electrochemical water splitting are described. Subsequently, advanced modulation strategies for designing MOFs-based/derived catalysts and their catalytic performance toward water splitting are summarized. In particular, the correlation between chemical composition/structural functionalization and catalytic performance is highlighted. Finally, the future outlook and challenges for MOFs materials are also addressed.</description>
      <author>Yan He, Wei Liu, Jingquan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lotus root-like RuIr alloys with close-packed (0001) branches: strain-driven performance for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.016</link>
      <description>Mingyue Xiao, Xu Wang, Rongchao Li, Yanhui Sun, Jingjun Liu, Feng Li, Jianying Gan, Shixin Gao, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391023139

                Achieving composition tunability and structure editability of nanoalloys with high level strain may be an efficient strategy to remarkably boost catalytic performance toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic water oxidation. Herein, lotus root-like RuIr alloys with native micro-strain were constructed by an epitaxial growth of Ru-richened hcp-(0001) branches on Ir-richened fcc-(111) seeds using a polyol thermal synthesis strategy. The resultant Ru60Ir40 alloy shows an OER overpotential of 197 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 46.59 mV dec&#8722;1, showing no obvious activity decay for 80 h continuous chronopotentiometry test in 0.5 M H2SO4. The related characterizations including X-ray absorption fine structure (XAFS) spectroscopy and density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that that the remarkably improved activity of the lotus root-like alloy can be attributed to the (0001) facet-triggered strain, which can efficiently optimize the electronic band structure of the active metal and the weakening of the chemisorption of oxygen-containing substances to boost OER electrocatalysis. Therefore, this work provides a new strategy to designing a class of advanced electrocatalysts with high strain using diverse nanostructures as building materials for carbon-free clean energy conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Mingyue Xiao, Xu Wang, Rongchao Li, Yanhui Sun, Jingjun Liu, Feng Li, Jianying Gan, Shixin Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bibliometric Mining of Research Trends in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ai5010012</link>
      <description>Lars Lundberg, Martin Boldt, Anton Borg, H&#229;kan Grahn, AI. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391034571

                We present a method, including tool support, for bibliometric mining of trends in large and dynamic research areas. The method is applied to the machine learning research area for the years 2013 to 2022. A total number of 398,782 documents from Scopus were analyzed. A taxonomy containing 26 research directions within machine learning was defined by four experts with the help of a Python program and existing taxonomies. The trends in terms of productivity, growth rate, and citations were analyzed for the research directions in the taxonomy. Our results show that the two directions, Applications and Algorithms, are the largest, and that the direction Convolutional Neural Networks is the one that grows the fastest and has the highest average number of citations per document. It also turns out that there is a clear correlation between the growth rate and the average number of citations per document, i.e., documents in fast-growing research directions have more citations. The trends for machine learning research in four geographic regions (North America, Europe, the BRICS countries, and The Rest of the World) were also analyzed. The number of documents during the time period considered is approximately the same for all regions. BRICS has the highest growth rate, and, on average, North America has the highest number of citations per document. Using our tool and method, we expect that one could perform a similar study in some other large and dynamic research area in a relatively short time.</description>
      <author>Lars Lundberg, Martin Boldt, Anton Borg, H&#229;kan Grahn</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ai5010012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering the Nickel Iron Oxyhydroxide through a Heterostructure Cocatalyst for Superior Alkaline and Saline Water Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02406</link>
      <description>T. Susikumar, G. John, M. Navaneethan, Madhusmita Sahoo, A. K. Ray, Nirpendra Singh, P. Justin Jesuraj, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391035646

                Hydrogen production using an electrochemical cell might be an alternative to conventional fuel systems (i.e., fossil fuels). The NiFe-layered hydroxide (NiFeOxHy) is one of the most popular electrocatalysts for water-splitting applications. However, its electrochemical activity is limited in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) because of its minimal active sites and modest charge transfer rates. To overcome the limitations in NiFeOxHy, silver sulfide (Ag2S) and graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) were added as heterostructure cocatalysts. The heterostructure cocatalyst (Ag2S/g-C3N4) addition in NiFeOxHy is found to improve the electrochemical double layer capacitance (EDLC) seven times greater than that of pristine NiFeOxHy. The addition of the heterostructure cocatalyst in the NiFeOxHy sample enables hydrogen production with a minimum overpotential of &#951;10 = 43 mV and Tafel slope of 131 mV/dec in saline water conditions. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy reveals that the heterostructure cocatalyst effectively donates electrons to NiFeOxHy, which enhance the resultant charge transfer ability of the electrocatalyst. In addition, the density functional theoretical (DFT) analysis suggests that the exposed sulfur (S) sites within the Ag2S/g-C3N4 heterostructure cocatalyst serve as the prominent catalytic center for H* interactions. This study highlights the alteration of charge transfer dynamics in NiFeOxHy via heterostructure cocatalyst addition as an effective way to facilitate enhanced alkaline and saline water reduction.</description>
      <author>T. Susikumar, G. John, M. Navaneethan, Madhusmita Sahoo, A. K. Ray, Nirpendra Singh, P. Justin Jesuraj</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of a protic dimeric ionic liquid on PEM fuel cell performance and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.163</link>
      <description>Liang Wang, Oscar Morales&#8208;Collazo, Joan F. Brennecke, Hongfei Jia, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 58(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391041589

                Protic dimeric ionic liquid (IL) 9&#8242;9&#8217;-(butane-1, 4-diyl)bis (3,4,6,7,8,9-hexahydro-2H-pyrimido [1,2-a]pyrimidin-1-ium) 1,1,2,2,3,3,4,4,4-nonafluorobutane-1-sulfonate (D-HTBD) has been developed as a surface modifier to a PtCo/C oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalyst for polymer electrolyte membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). Thermal properties, intrinsic conductivity, and viscosity were studied to understand the ionic liquid's protonation effect. The protic IL was incorporated into the PtCo/C catalyst and its effect on MEA performance at various humidities were evaluated and compared with pristine PtCo/C catalyst. Electrochemically active surface area, AC impedance and gas diffusion resistance of the MEAs with IL were compared with the PtCo/C catalyst without modification by IL. Besides promoting the oxygen reduction reaction activity of the PtCo/C catalyst, the protic dimeric IL enhances dry condition MEA performance significantly, attributed to the hydrogen bonds between the Br&#248;nsted acids and Br&#248;nsted bases. A durability study of the PtCo/C catalyst with and without IL shows the reduction of catalyst degradation after incorporating IL. This work suggests that the protic dimeric IL could be a promising modifier to enhance ORR catalyst activity, fuel cell performance and durability.</description>
      <author>Liang Wang, Oscar Morales&#8208;Collazo, Joan F. Brennecke, Hongfei Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benzotrithiophene-based covalent organic frameworks as efficient catalysts for artificial photosynthesis of H2O2 in pure water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148922</link>
      <description>Mingjie Liu, Peipei He, Hantao Gong, Zhenghua Zhao, Yueming Li, Kai Zhou, Yuemin Lin, Jing Li, Zongbi Bao, Qiwei Yang, Yiwen Yang, Qilong Ren, Zhiguo Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. 482(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391042414

                Direct synthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) using oxygen and water through the photocatalytic route is a prospective approach for the on-site production of H2O2. However, the limited varieties of photocatalytic sites and ambiguous structure-active relationship impede the development of environmentally friendly technology. Herein, we report a active compound (benzotrithiophene, BTT) for the photosynthesis of H2O2 using oxygen and water, and design four benzotrithiophene-based 2D covalent organic frameworks (BTT-COFs) linked with aromatic amines linkers. Significant enhancement in photocatalytic activity has been observed via the introduction of BTT struct into 2D COFs. The high crystallinity of COFs increases the visible light absorption ability and photostability of BTT. The suitable distance of BTT struct in COFs and the construction of donor&#8211;acceptor (D-A) structure further promote the carrier generation and transfer. The COF-BTT-TAPT exhibited the highest H2O2 production rate of 620 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1. Mechanism investigation experiments have given the validation that BTT-COFs efficiently reduce oxygen in pure water to form H2O2 under visible-light irradiation. This work paves a revolutionary way for designing and fabricating high-performance metal-free photocatalysts for visible-light-driven H2O2 production.</description>
      <author>Mingjie Liu, Peipei He, Hantao Gong, Zhenghua Zhao, Yueming Li, Kai Zhou, Yuemin Lin, Jing Li, Zongbi Bao, Qiwei Yang, Yiwen Yang, Qilong Ren, Zhiguo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory-Based Kinetic Modeling of Reactions of Hydrogen Isotopes (H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, D&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, T&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) and Carbonaceous Gases (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, CO, CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;) on the ZrCo(110) Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08169</link>
      <description>Jinfan Chen, Tao Tang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391044401

                ZrCo and its alloys have attracted extensive attention as promising hydrogen isotope storage materials for nuclear fusion reactors. However, ZrCo can be readily poisoned by carbonaceous impurity gases like CO2 and CO introduced by input hydrogen isotopes or produced during the fusion reactor operation procedure. In this work, with density functional theory calculations and microkinetic modeling, the poisoning effects of CO2 and CO are identified by predominantly occupying active sites on the metal surface when reaching equilibrium. Surface reaction events related to CO2 are mostly molecular adsorption&#8211;desorption steps due to its strong binding strength. Dissociation of CO occurs readily even at room temperature, and the resident time length for the coverage of hydrogen being higher than other species is longer than CO2, indicating that the ZrCo alloy is more resistant to CO-poisoning compared to CO2. Interaction between CH4 and ZrCo is not active with the coexistence of hydrogen, making this impurity inert in deteriorating hydrogen storage performance. Hydrogen isotope effects are characterized by comparing reactions among H2 + CO2(CO), D2 + CO2(CO), and T2 + CO2(CO) mixing gases, with hydrogen resident time lengths decreasing from H2 to T2.</description>
      <author>Jinfan Chen, Tao Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Together Theoretical and Experimental Perspectives in Single&#8208;Atom Alloys for Electrochemical Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308084</link>
      <description>Mohammad Bashir Ahmed, Cheng Wang, Yongxiang Zhao, Clastin I. Sathish, Zhihao Lei, Liang Qiao, Chenghua Sun, Shaobin Wang, J. Kennedy, Ajayan Vinu, Jiabao Yi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391051284

                Abstract Ammonia is an essential commodity in the food and chemical industry. Despite the energy&#8208;intensive nature, the Haber&#8211;Bosch process is the only player in ammonia production at large scales. Developing other strategies is highly desirable, as sustainable and decentralized ammonia production is crucial. Electrochemical ammonia production by directly reducing nitrogen and nitrogen&#8208;based moieties powered by renewable energy sources holds great potential. However, low ammonia production and selectivity rates hamper its utilization as a large&#8208;scale ammonia production process. Creating effective and selective catalysts for the electrochemical generation of ammonia is critical for long&#8208;term nitrogen fixation. Single&#8208;atom alloys (SAAs) have become a new class of materials with distinctive features that may be able to solve some of the problems with conventional heterogeneous catalysts. The design and optimization of SAAs for electrochemical ammonia generation have recently been significantly advanced. This comprehensive review discusses these advancements from theoretical and experimental research perspectives, offering a fundamental understanding of the development of SAAs for ammonia production.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Bashir Ahmed, Cheng Wang, Yongxiang Zhao, Clastin I. Sathish, Zhihao Lei, Liang Qiao, Chenghua Sun, Shaobin Wang, J. Kennedy, Ajayan Vinu, Jiabao Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcing oxygen electrocatalytic activity via selective dual-phase heterointerface engineering for rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02531-6</link>
      <description>Chao Cheng, Chunyi Zhi, Zhongti Sun, Yongqiang Ming, T. Xiang, Qian Zhu, Zirui Wu, Bing Li, Yang Li, Cheng Jin, Yong Cao, Juan Yang, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391053486

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Cheng, Chunyi Zhi, Zhongti Sun, Yongqiang Ming, T. Xiang, Qian Zhu, Zirui Wu, Bing Li, Yang Li, Cheng Jin, Yong Cao, Juan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02531-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled doping of ultralow amounts Ru on Ni cathode for PEMWE: Experimental and theoretical elucidation of enhanced performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123738</link>
      <description>Kyeong-Rim Yeo, Ho-Young Kim, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Seongbeen Kim, Jinwoo Lee, Haesun Park, Soo&#8208;Kil Kim, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental. 346(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391055438

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) is an environmentally benign technology for large-scale hydrogen production. Despite many catalysts being developed to replace Pt, successful development of low-cost catalysts that meet the balance of performance and durability is limited. In this work, atomically dispersed Ru on Ni catalyst-integrated porous transport electrodes were fabricated by a simple electrodeposition. With a trace amount of Ru (&lt; 0.05 mgRu&#183;cm&#8722;2), the Ni98.1Ru1.9 cathode catalyst exhibited an overpotential of 35 mV at &#8211;10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 with excellent stability. Density functional theory calculation revealed that the high performance was driven by optimized adsorption strength and improved mobility of hydrogen on the catalyst surface. The Ni98.1Ru1.9 electrode was further verified in a PEMWE cell and resulting performance (6.0 A&#183;cm&#8722;2 at 2.25 Vcell) and stability (0.13 mV&#183;h&#8722;1 decay rate at 1 A&#183;cm&#8722;2) surpassed previously reported non-Pt and even Pt electrodes, demonstrating its readiness as an advanced cathode to replace Pt.</description>
      <author>Kyeong-Rim Yeo, Ho-Young Kim, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Seongbeen Kim, Jinwoo Lee, Haesun Park, Soo&#8208;Kil Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing highly efficient bifunctional catalysts for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution by modifying MXene with transition metal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.089</link>
      <description>Dai Yu, Xiuyun Zhao, Desheng Zheng, Qingrui Zhao, Jing Feng, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 660(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391063505

                Exploring highly active electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has become a growing interest in recent years. Herein, an efficient pathway for designing MXene-based ORR/OER catalysts is proposed. It involves introducing non-noble metals into Vo (vacancy site), H1 and H2 (the hollow sites on top of C and the metal atom, respectively) sites on M2CO2 surfaces, named TM-VO/H1/H2-M2CO2 (TM = Fe, Co, Ni, M = V, Nb, Ta). Among these recombination catalysts, Co-H1-V2CO2 and Ni-H1-V2CO2 exhibit the most promising ORR catalytic activities, with low overpotential values of 0.35 and 0.37 V, respectively. Similarly, Fe-H1-V2CO2, Co-VO-Nb2CO2, and Ni-H2-Nb2CO2 possess low OER overpotential values of 0.29, 0.39, and 0.44 V, respectively, suggesting they have enormous potential as effective catalysts for OER. Notably, Co-H2-Ta2CO2 possesses the lowest potential gap value of 0.53 V, demonstrating it has an extraordinary bifunctional catalytic activity. The excellent catalytic performance of these recombination catalysts can be elucidated through an electronic structure analysis, which primarily relies on the electron-donating capacity and synergistic effects between transition metals and sub-metals. These results provide theoretical guidance for designing new ORR and OER catalysts using 2D MXene materials.</description>
      <author>Dai Yu, Xiuyun Zhao, Desheng Zheng, Qingrui Zhao, Jing Feng, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The enhanced electro/photocatalytic activity for nitric oxide reduction to ammonia by B@g-C9N10 monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.128914</link>
      <description>Min Wang, Yuhong Huang, Haiping Lin, Haili Zhao, Fang Ma, Jianmin Zhang, Xiumei Wei, Materials Chemistry and Physics. 315(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391063548

                Selective electro/photocatalytic reduction of nitride oxide (NO) to ammonia (NH3) provides a promising way to remove the pollutant under ambient conditions. The key to NO reduction reaction (NORR) is to develop more economical and efficient electrocatalysts compared to the industrialized Pt-based catalysts. In this work, the boron atom doping g-C9N10 monolayer (B@g-C9N10) is designed and the electro/photocatalytic NORR performance is systematically investigated by means of density functional theory (DFT). Among the N-end, O-end and side-on structures, the N-end NO adsorption is found to be the most stable one, which greatly favors the NO activation by the &#8220;&#963;-donation and &#960;* back-donation&#8221; mechanism. Among the N-distal, N-alternating, O-distal, O-alternating, Mixed 1&#8211;3 hydrogenation pathways in the electrocatalytic process, the O-alternating and Mixed-2 pathways are the most efficient NORR routes, which have the same limiting potential (UL) of &#8722;0.386 V in the step of *NH2&#8594;*NH3. However, the NO molecule is more easily activated in *N&#8211;OH along O-alternating pathway than Mixed-2 pathway. The energy barrier can be further decreased by considering the implicit and explicit solvation model and the NH3 selectivity of B@g-C9N10 is higher than N2O, N2 and H2. The irradiating energy of 1.094 eV can decrease the reaction energy, resulting in the spontaneous NORR process along Mixed-2 pathway. Our findings uncover a promising approach to design a bifunctional NORR electro/photocatalyst with high NH3 selectivity and activity NO&#8594;NH3 conversion.</description>
      <author>Min Wang, Yuhong Huang, Haiping Lin, Haili Zhao, Fang Ma, Jianmin Zhang, Xiumei Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.128914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representative longevity testing of direct air capture materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148901</link>
      <description>Russell A. Hunt, Jeremy Gillbanks, Jason P. Czapla, Zhijian Wan, Caleb Karmelich, Cameron White, Colin D. Wood, Chemical Engineering Journal. 481(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391064300

                Direct-air CO2 capture (DAC) is a rapidly expanding field of research driven by a growing need for net-negative technologies. One leading class of materials for DAC is amine-based adsorbents, however these may have limited lifetime due to oxidative degradation. Material longevity is a critical parameter; however, most studies test the stability of these materials under inert atmospheres, removing the oxidation pathway. Consequently, more realistic longevity testing is needed. This work presents a method using ambient air and partial vacuum conditions to assess the stability of DAC materials realistically. A custom-built, automated system was developed whereby CO2 adsorption was conducted in ambient air and desorption under vacuum. In this study, the novel method presented here is compared to a TGA method for analysis of the commercial ion exchange resin Lewatit VP OC 1065. A novel crosslinked polyamine designated here as CA-1 is also examined using the system under various conditions. The method involves the measurement and re-measurement of adsorption capacity between adsorption/desorption cycles. The Lewatit resin was cycled 180 times with desorption at 80 &#176;C and 100 mbar absolute. In this test, it lost 31.20 % of original capacity, contrasted with a 5.47 % loss from the inert TGA method. The CA-1 crosslinked polyamine was then cycled 500 times at three sets of desorption conditions: 80 &#176;C and atmospheric pressure, 80 &#176;C and 500 mbar absolute, and 75 &#176;C and 200 mbar absolute. The sample at 200 mbar lost only 2.79 % original uptake, compared to 28.74 % in atmospheric pressure.</description>
      <author>Russell A. Hunt, Jeremy Gillbanks, Jason P. Czapla, Zhijian Wan, Caleb Karmelich, Cameron White, Colin D. Wood</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the potential of ZIF-based electrocatalysts for electrochemical reduction of CO2: Recent advances, current trends, and machine learnings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215669</link>
      <description>Omer Ahmed Taialla, Muhammad Umar, A. Abdullahi, Esraa Kotob, Mohammed Awad, Ahmad Bala Alhassan, I. Hussain, Khalid M. Omer, Saheed A. Ganiyu, Khalid Alhooshani, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 504(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391068346

                The socio-economic advancements have led to the emergence of anthropogenic carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions, which have had a profound influence on ecosystems and climate change. This review focuses on CO2 Electrochemical Reduction (CO2-ECR), a new technology with significant potential for reducing CO2 emissions through the optimal use of renewable resources. In recent years, there has been a concerted effort to develop catalysts that are both effective and efficient in order to improve the efficiency of CO2-ECR for the production of desired products. Zeolitic imidazolidine frameworks (ZIFs) have gained significant attention in the field of CO2-ECR due to their significant surface area and presence of active sites. ZIFs, which consist of imidazole organic linkers and a variety of metals, are tunable with respect to their electrochemical activity and properties, thereby affecting the selectivity of CO2-ECR. This review elucidates ZIFs as CO2-ECR electrocatalysts, encompassing ligand modifications, metal variations, and different reaction conditions, contributing to the quest for efficient solutions in mitigating CO2 concentration and achieving carbon neutrality. Researchers have extensively studied operational conditions impacting these materials. Technology utilization further aids in explaining experimental observations. This review has significant potential for application in studying and fabrication of electrocatalytic ZIFs-based materials that are effective for academic and industrial research and development.</description>
      <author>Omer Ahmed Taialla, Muhammad Umar, A. Abdullahi, Esraa Kotob, Mohammed Awad, Ahmad Bala Alhassan, I. Hussain, Khalid M. Omer, Saheed A. Ganiyu, Khalid Alhooshani</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A unique adsorption-diffusion-decomposition mechanism for hydrogen evolution reaction towards high-efficiency Cr, Fe-modified CoP nanorod catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123749</link>
      <description>Hui Li, Li Du, Ying Zhang, Liang Xu, Shuang Li, Chun Cheng Yang, Q. Jiang, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391070297

                The rational construction of high-efficiency transition metal phosphides catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is crucial since their sluggish kinetics of water dissociation remain severe barriers for HER performance. The theoretical calculations indicate a unique adsorption-diffusion-decomposition mechanism for H2O molecules on CoP (111) surface. Herein, Fe could decrease H2O decomposition barrier energies and increase the amount of active sites, along with Cr could accelerate H2O adsorption, diffusion and increase the conductivity of the reaction surface. Aided by this mechanism, a self-supported electrode of Cr and Fe dual-doped CoP nanorod arrays grown on nickel foam was prepared. The electrode only requires an overpotential of 27 mV at 10 mA cm-2 for alkaline HER with excellent durability for 400 h. Moreover, the catalyst presents only 1.505 V at 10 mA cm-2 for alkaline water electrolysis. This work provides an in-depth understanding on catalytic mechanism of CoP-based materials.</description>
      <author>Hui Li, Li Du, Ying Zhang, Liang Xu, Shuang Li, Chun Cheng Yang, Q. Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First principle investigation of nitric oxide reduction reaction for efficient ammonia synthesis over a Fe&#8211;Mo dual-atom electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101535</link>
      <description>Xiuxia Zhang, Lianxin Xia, Bofan Lang, Jiali Yu, Xinming Liu, Rui&#8208;Biao Lin, Xinwei Wang, Journal of the Energy Institute. 113(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391070689

                Electrocatalytic conversion of NO-to-NH3 holds immense potential for removing contaminants and producing zero-carbon fuel. To facilitate widespread commercial adoption of this technology, electrocatalysts with exceptional stability, high activity, and selective performance are urgently desired. We developed a novel dual-atom electrocatalyst, Fe&#8211;Mo@NG, in which Fe&#8211;Mo dimer is anchored to N-doped graphite. Through the first principle calculations, it is discovered that Fe&#8211;Mo@NG provided exceptional performance in NO-to-NH3 conversion. The parallel adsorption type was found can maximize the activation of NO. And the most favorable adsorption structure exhibits a limiting potential of &#8722;0.26 eV, surpassing that of most conventional electrocatalysts. The remarkable NORR activity of Fe&#8211;Mo@NG is traced back the synergistic effect between the dual-atom active site and the electronic interactions between the active site and NO. At high coverages, the interaction between intermediates and free NO molecules may lead to the formation of N2 or N2O. Overall, our research introduces a promising dual-atom electrocatalyst with broad applicability in NO reduction reactions, providing novel insights into the dual-atom catalysts design.</description>
      <author>Xiuxia Zhang, Lianxin Xia, Bofan Lang, Jiali Yu, Xinming Liu, Rui&#8208;Biao Lin, Xinwei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuO2 Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution in Acidic Media: Mechanism, Activity Promotion Strategy and Research Progress</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29020537</link>
      <description>Jirong Bai, Wei Zhou, Jingliang Xu, Quanfa Zhou, Yaoyao Deng, Mei Xiang, Dongsheng Xiang, Yaqiong Su, Molecules. 29(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391089701

                Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis (PEMWE) under acidic conditions outperforms alkaline water electrolysis in terms of less resistance loss, higher current density, and higher produced hydrogen purity, which make it more economical in long-term applications. However, the efficiency of PEMWE is severely limited by the slow kinetics of anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), poor catalyst stability, and high cost. Therefore, researchers in the past decade have made great efforts to explore cheap, efficient, and stable electrode materials. Among them, the RuO2 electrocatalyst has been proved to be a major promising alternative to Ir-based catalysts and the most promising OER catalyst owing to its excellent electrocatalytic activity and high pH adaptability. In this review, we elaborate two reaction mechanisms of OER (lattice oxygen mechanism and adsorbate evolution mechanism), comprehensively summarize and discuss the recently reported RuO2-based OER electrocatalysts under acidic conditions, and propose many advanced modification strategies to further improve the activity and stability of RuO2-based electrocatalytic OER. Finally, we provide suggestions for overcoming the challenges faced by RuO2 electrocatalysts in practical applications and make prospects for future research. This review provides perspectives and guidance for the rational design of highly active and stable acidic OER electrocatalysts based on PEMWE.</description>
      <author>Jirong Bai, Wei Zhou, Jingliang Xu, Quanfa Zhou, Yaoyao Deng, Mei Xiang, Dongsheng Xiang, Yaqiong Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29020537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Hydrogenation Selectivity of an Unsaturated Aldehyde via Single-Atom Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10994</link>
      <description>Hio Tong Ngan, Philippe Sautet, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391091852

                Selective hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes to produce unsaturated alcohols remains a challenge in catalysis. Here, we explore, on the basis of first-principles simulations, single-atom alloy (SAA) catalysts on copper as a class of catalytic materials to enhance the selectivity for C&#9552;O bond hydrogenation in unsaturated aldehydes by controlling the binding strength of the C&#9552;C and C&#9552;O bonds. We show that on SAA of early transition metals such as Ti, Zr, and Hf, the C&#9552;O binding mode of acrolein is favored but the strong binding renders subsequent hydrogenation and desorption impossible. On SAA of late-transition metals, on the other hand, the C&#9552;C binding mode is favored and C&#9552;C bond hydrogenation follows, resulting in the production of undesired saturated aldehydes. Mid-transition metals (Cr and Mn) in Cu(111) appear as the optimal systems, since they favor acrolein adsorption via the C&#9552;O bond but with a moderate binding strength, compatible with catalysis. Additionally, acrolein migration from the C&#9552;O to the C&#9552;C binding mode, which would open the low energy path for C&#9552;C bond hydrogenation, is prevented by a large barrier for this process. SAA of Cr in Cu appears as an optimal candidate, and kinetic simulations show that the selectivity for propenol formation is controlled by preventing the acrolein migration from the more stable C&#9552;O to the less stable C&#9552;C binding mode and subsequent H-migration and by the formation of the O-H bond from the monohydrogenated intermediate. Dilute alloy catalysts therefore enable tuning the binding strength of intermediates and transition states, opening control of catalytic activity and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Hio Tong Ngan, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10994</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Single-Layer Ir Clusters Enabling 100% Selective Chlorine Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05738</link>
      <description>Shuang Li, Xu Guo, Xiaofang Liu, Jianglan Shui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391096719

                The exclusive selectivity of the chlorine evolution reaction (CER) is crucial for the chlor-alkali industry to obtain pure chlorine gas and avoid the cost of separating the byproduct oxygen. However, 100% CER selectivity remains a challenge for the currently known CER catalysts. Here, we report a catalyst of atomic single-layer Ir clusters on CeO2 nanorods (IrSL/CeO2). Under the strong metal/support interaction, IrSL has a strong adsorption to oxygen, thereby suppressing the oxygen evolution reaction. Coupled with the uniform active sites of the single-layer Ir clusters, IrSL/CeO2 achieves almost 100% CER selectivity in acidic NaCl solution ranging from open circuit potential to practical current density levels. In addition, IrSL/CeO2 exhibits 1.7 times higher catalytic activity than its single-atom counterparts, and its noble metal efficiency is 84 times higher than that of commercial anodes (DSAs). Our finding provides a solution to the selective catalysis of chlor-alkali electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Shuang Li, Xu Guo, Xiaofang Liu, Jianglan Shui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Agreement of Binuclear 2D Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Sites for Superior Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07547</link>
      <description>Naomi Helsel, Pabitra Pal Choudhury, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391101616

                This work analyzes the bifunctional activity of a binuclear two-dimensional metal&#8211;organic framework fragment (2D-SA) utilizing ab initio spin-polarized density functional theory calculations. Cobalt, iron, and a combination of the two metals were simulated due to their history with promising oxygen reduction/oxygen evolution reactions (ORR/OER) activity. The favorable reaction pathways of both the ORR and OER have been realized including the addition of pristine/doped graphene substrate. The Co-2D-SAs had the best performance toward OER only, while the Fe-2D-SAs were favorable toward ORR. The results show that when the bimetallic Co/Fe-2D-SA was supported by graphene, both the ORR overpotential of the Fe site and the OER overpotential of the Co site were found to be the best for the bifunctional activity. This superior bifunctional activity is attributed to both the substrate effect and cooperative agreement between iron and cobalt in the bimetallic 2D-SA by adjusting their spin states due to the antiferromagnetic coupling of the binuclear sites.</description>
      <author>Naomi Helsel, Pabitra Pal Choudhury</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the hydrogen evolution reaction on NiTe monolayers &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; defect engineering: a computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3qi02444j</link>
      <description>Yangcun Xiang, Yuting Sun, Yuejie Liu, Qinghai Cai, Jingxiang Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391106507

                Herein, we explored the feasibility to boost the HER catalytic performance of two-dimensional (2D) NiTe by defect engineering.</description>
      <author>Yangcun Xiang, Yuting Sun, Yuejie Liu, Qinghai Cai, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3qi02444j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Cation Disorder Triggered-Electronic Reshuffling for Sustainable Conventional Layered Oxide Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02219</link>
      <description>Weixin Chen, Dilxat Muhtar, Kaili Li, Gao-Fei Xiao, Jian Cao, Tang Yiping, Guoyu Qian, Xueyi Lu, Yang Sun, Xia Lu, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391106660

                Unraveling the underlying thermodynamic principles governing the sustainable conventional layered cathodes at the electron-scale remains a critical challenge, yet it is essential for advancing Li-ion batteries toward a high energy density future. In this context, the layered LixNi1/3Co1/3Mn1/3O2 is taken as an example to disclose the intricate connection among the structural disorders, electronic transfer, redox chemistry, and performance degradation using ab initio calculations. During cation disordering, the dramatic picture of electronic reshuffling is sculpted by the appearance of electron trapping centers/parasitic holes in the local TM-rich domain, as well as the O:2p lone-pairs in the local Li-rich domain. Distinct redox processes emerge wherein the parasitic holes can effectively couple with the adjacent transition metal (TM:d electron) and/or the oxygen ions (O:2p lone-pairs) depending on the states of charge. Regarding the structural stability, the electronic reshuffling induces a reciprocal relationship between cation disorder and oxygen stability, posing a concealed threat of reversibility. A new self-sustaining process is conceived as the primary pathway for severe layered damages and degradation. Notably, the cation disorder triggered-electronic reshuffling exhibits strict regularity that depends on the relative energies of the TM:d and O:2p states, holding promise for the reasonable design of sustainable layered cathodes. The theoretical framework provides a novel and self-consistent description of the thermodynamic conditions toward the reversible electrochemical process for conventional layered cathodes.</description>
      <author>Weixin Chen, Dilxat Muhtar, Kaili Li, Gao-Fei Xiao, Jian Cao, Tang Yiping, Guoyu Qian, Xueyi Lu, Yang Sun, Xia Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P&#8208;Incorporation Induced Enhancement of Lattice Oxygen Participation in Double Perovskite Oxides to Boost Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309091</link>
      <description>Gaoliang Fu, Leilei Zhang, Ruixue Wei, Huili Liu, Ruipeng Hou, Yue Zhang, Kun Yang, Shouren Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391108255

                Abstract Activating the lattice oxygen in the catalysts to participate in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which can break the scaling relation&#8211;induced overpotential limitation (&gt; 0.37 V) of the adsorbate evolution mechanism, has emerged as a new and highly effective guide to accelerate the OER. However, how to increase the lattice oxygen participation of catalysts during OER remains a major challenge. Herein, P&#8208;incorporation induced enhancement of lattice oxygen participation in double perovskite LaNi 0.58 Fe 0.38 P 0.07 O 3&#8208;&#963; (PLNFO) is studied. P&#8208;incorporation is found to be crucial for enhancing the OER activity. The current density reaches 1.35 mA cm ECSA &#8722;2 at 1.63 V (vs RHE), achieving a sixfold increase in intrinsic activity. Experimental evidences confirm the dominant lattice oxygen participation mechanism (LOM) for OER pathway on PLNFO. Further electronic structures reveal that P&#8208;incorporation shifts the O p &#8208;band center by 0.7 eV toward the Fermi level, making the states near the Fermi level more O p character, thus facilitating LOM and fast OER kinetics. This work offers a possible method to develop high&#8208;performance double perovskite OER catalysts for electrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Gaoliang Fu, Leilei Zhang, Ruixue Wei, Huili Liu, Ruipeng Hou, Yue Zhang, Kun Yang, Shouren Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NH3 decomposition in autothermal microchannel reactors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-88503-4.00003-x</link>
      <description>Ali Behrad Vakylabad, Mohammad Amin Makarem, Zohre Moravvej, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391064792

                The focus of this chapter is on the breakdown of ammonia intending to produce hydrogen as the cleanest source of energy. A review of microreactors and related technical literature is first collected. Then, the chemical mechanism of two coupled reactions (combustion and decomposition) are discussed. These two reactions are essentially underway in the same coupled microchannels. An autothermal plug-flow reactor for NH3 decomposition is a type of chemical reactor that utilizes a catalytic process to convert ammonia (NH3) into nitrogen (N2) and hydrogen (H2). This reaction is important in the production of hydrogen for fuel cells, as well as in the removal of ammonia from industrial waste streams. The autothermal plug-flow reactor is particularly useful for this reaction because it allows for both exothermic and endothermic reactions to occur simultaneously, without the need for external heating or cooling. The reactor design includes an annular region on the outside of a microchannel containing the catalyst, which allows for efficient heat transfer and mass transfer. The main effective parameters for this type of reactor include temperature, pressure, flow rate, catalyst type and loading, reactant concentration, reactor geometry, and inlet temperature and composition. By optimizing these parameters, the efficiency, selectivity, and yield of the NH3 decomposition reaction can be improved.</description>
      <author>Ali Behrad Vakylabad, Mohammad Amin Makarem, Zohre Moravvej, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-88503-4.00003-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Assembled FeIII-TAML-Based Magnetic Nanostructures for Rapid and Sustainable Destruction of Bisphenol A</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00128-023-03834-1</link>
      <description>Ruochen Dong, Lihua Bai, Sijia Liang, Shuo Xu, Song Gao, Hongjian Li, Ran Hong, Chao Wang, Cheng Gu, Bulletin of Environmental Contamination and Toxicology. 112(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391294140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruochen Dong, Lihua Bai, Sijia Liang, Shuo Xu, Song Gao, Hongjian Li, Ran Hong, Chao Wang, Cheng Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00128-023-03834-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Performance Evaluation of Absorbents for the Electrowinning-Coupled Competitive Separation CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07594</link>
      <description>Xiaomei Wang, Huifeng Fan, Yuanhao Mao, Teng Zhang, Sayd Sultan, Yunsong Yu, Zaoxiao Zhang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391157027

                Electrowinning-coupled competitive separation (ECCS) CO2 capture technology, utilizing renewable electricity as the energy input, is regarded as a promising electrochemically mediated CO2 capture approach to substitute for the traditional solvent-based CO2 scrubbing method. However, this technology is still distant from practical application due to its energy-intensive property, sensitivity to oxygen, amine degradation, and system complexity. The selection of a suitable solvent plays a crucial role in enhancing the overall performance and scalability of the ECCS system. To address an efficient solvent screening method, this paper proposed a systematic comparison of solvents in terms of thermodynamics, electrochemistry, absorption, and desorption performance. The proposed solvent screening method undergoes a critical evaluation through the development of a thermodynamic model and experimentation. Using MEA, EDA, and NH3 as examples (solvents extensively discussed in the ECCS system), the paper provides a comprehensive discussion of the solvent screening method. Results indicate that EDA exhibits superior CO2 absorption and thermodynamic performance. NH3 solvent demonstrates better CO2 desorption and electrochemical performance. However, there is an antithetical relationship between the thermodynamic and electrochemical performance. This phenomenon arises because the Cu2+&#8211;solvent complex, characterized by a stronger coupling performance, is more stable, necessitating a higher potential to reduce the Cu2+&#8211;solvent complex. This leads to increased energy consumption during the solvent regeneration process. Therefore, when solvent screening is conducted, it is essential to categorize and thoroughly consider thermodynamics, electrochemistry, and absorption and desorption performance.</description>
      <author>Xiaomei Wang, Huifeng Fan, Yuanhao Mao, Teng Zhang, Sayd Sultan, Yunsong Yu, Zaoxiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic screening of transition-metal-doped hydroxyapatite for efficient photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102692</link>
      <description>Yuting Li, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Josep Albero, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Lourdes F. Vega, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391448738

                We present the first comprehensive investigation of transition metal-substituted Hydroxyapatite (TM-HAP) materials for photocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2RR). Density functional theory (DFT) was used to study in a systematic manner the stability of 3d, 4d, 5d transition metal dopants on the HAP (000&#773;1) surface, analyzing their stability, activity, and selectivity for photocatalytic CO2RR. DFT results allowed to narrow down the selection to three transition metal elements (Co, Ni, Mo) based on their structural stability, band structure and performance. A selective analysis of product formation for carbon monoxide and formate was made, showing that TM dopants facilitate the initial protonation step in the CO2 reduction by adsorbing H2 molecule on TM atoms and then dissociating it into two hydrogen atoms. The performance of Ni- and Co-HAP towards the reaction activity is consistent with experimental results. Mo-HAP stands as a new and attractive photocatalyst for further investigation, given its excellent predicted performance.</description>
      <author>Yuting Li, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Josep Albero, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Lourdes F. Vega</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of chemicals and energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-14005-1.00009-x</link>
      <description>Adewale Giwa, Ahmed Yusuf, Hammed Abiodun Balogun, B. Anand, Setareh Heidari, David M. Warsinger, Hanifa Taher, Sulaiman Al&#8208;Zuhair, Bismah Shaikh, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391490678

                Electrochemical membrane technology has been identified as a promising technology for sustainable chemical and energy production due to its potential to address several challenges in the production of chemicals and energy, including energy consumption, greenhouse gas emissions, and waste generation. Electrochemical membrane processes can be applied to produce a wide range of feedstocks, including gases, liquids, and solids. This versatility can enable the coproduction of multiple chemicals and energy products from various feedstocks. In this chapter, the production of chemicals and energy, including bioelectricity, biomethane, biohydrogen, bioethanol, hydrogen peroxide, biodegradable electronics and biosensors, dry air from humid air, air separation into nitrogen and oxygen gases, organic solvent extraction, CO2 and H2 separation from gas mixtures, plasma generation, dewatered microalgae biomass, and purified microalgae-based products, are discussed. Electrochemical membrane processes can offer environmental benefits, such as CO2 reduction, leading to more sustainable and socially responsible production practices. The electrochemical conversion of CO2 can lead to the production of valuable chemicals, such as ethanol. With continued research and development, electrochemical membrane technology is expected to play an increasingly important role in chemical and energy production.</description>
      <author>Adewale Giwa, Ahmed Yusuf, Hammed Abiodun Balogun, B. Anand, Setareh Heidari, David M. Warsinger, Hanifa Taher, Sulaiman Al&#8208;Zuhair, Bismah Shaikh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-14005-1.00009-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climbing the Hydrogen Evolution Volcano with a NiTi Shape Memory Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03216</link>
      <description>Sreetama Ghosh, Denver Haycock, N. C. Mehra, Susanta Bera, Hannah Johnson, Lucian Roiban, M. Aouine, P. Vernoux, Peter C. Th&#252;ne, William F. Schneider, Mihalis N. Tsampas, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391014304

                Alkaline water electrolysis is a sustainable way to produce green hydrogen using renewable electricity. Even though the rates of the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are 2-3 orders of magnitude less under alkaline conditions than under acidic conditions, the possibility of using non-precious metal catalysts makes alkaline HER appealing. We identify a novel and facile route for substantially improving HER performance via the use of commercially available NiTi shape memory alloys, which upon heating undergo a phase transformation from the monoclinic martensite to the cubic austenite structure. While the room-temperature performance is modest, austenitic NiTi outperforms Pt (which is the state-of-the-art HER electrocatalyst) in terms of current density by &#8804;50% at 80 &#176;C. Surface ensembles presented by the austenite phase are computed with density functional theory to bind hydrogen more weakly than either metallic Ni or Ti and to have binding energies ideally suited for HER.</description>
      <author>Sreetama Ghosh, Denver Haycock, N. C. Mehra, Susanta Bera, Hannah Johnson, Lucian Roiban, M. Aouine, P. Vernoux, Peter C. Th&#252;ne, William F. Schneider, Mihalis N. Tsampas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence in catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-99135-3.00002-6</link>
      <description>Srinivas Rangarajan, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391223759

                Artificial intelligence (AI) is playing an increasingly large role in catalysis, similar to other aspects of manufacturing. In particular, modern data science and machine learning (ML) methods coupled with informatics, optimization, and statistics are fast becoming a mainstay in both the modeling and design of catalysts and associated processes. This chapter provides an overview of AI and ML in (1) improving mechanistic modeling by speeding up bottleneck steps, (2) developing models to compute adsorbate and transition state energies quickly, (3) screen vast spaces of catalysts efficiently, and (4) learn from experimental data and guide further experimentation, including high throughput and autonomous experiments, to discover new catalytic formulations. Underlying all of these topics are cross-cutting concepts such as model interpretability, uncertainty quantification, incorporating domain knowledge, and community-wide sharing/access to databases and software. Significant advances have been made in a short span, there is tremendous untapped potential for AI and ML in catalysis.</description>
      <author>Srinivas Rangarajan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-99135-3.00002-6</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
