<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:40:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Data driven computational design of stable oxygen evolution catalysts by DFT and machine learning: Promising electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2023.12.048</link>
      <description>Hwanyeol Park, Yunseok Kim, Sang&#8208;Hoon Choi, Ho Jun Kim, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390937419

                The revolutionary development of machine learning (ML), data science, and analytics, coupled with its application in material science, stands as a significant milestone of the scientific community over the last decade. Investigating active, stable, and cost-efficient catalysts is crucial for oxygen evolution reaction owing to the significance in a range of electrochemical energy conversion processes. In this work, we have demonstrated an efficient approach of high-throughput screening to find stable transition metal oxides under acid condition for high-performance oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts through density functional theory (DFT) calculation and a machine learning algorithm. A methodology utilizing both the Materials Project database and DFT calculations was introduced to assess the acid stability under specific reaction conditions. Building upon this, OER catalytic activity of acid-stable materials was examined, highlighting potential OER catalysts that meet the required properties. We identified IrO2, Fe(SbO3)2, Co(SbO3)2, Ni(SbO3)2, FeSbO4, Fe(SbO3)4, MoWO6, TiSnO4, CoSbO4, and Ti(WO4)2 as promising catalysts, several of which have already been experimentally discovered for their robust OER performance, while others are novel for experimental exploration, thereby broadening the chemical scope for efficient OER electrocatalysts. Descriptors of the bond length of TM&#8211;O and the first ionization energy were used to unveil the OER activity origin. From the calculated results, guidance has been derived to effectively execute advanced high-throughput screenings for the discovery of catalysts with favorable properties. Furthermore, the intrinsic correlation between catalytic performance and various atomic and structural factors was elucidated using the ML algorithm. Through these approaches, we not only streamline the choice of the promising electrocatalysts but also offer insights for the design of varied catalyst models and the discovery of superior catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hwanyeol Park, Yunseok Kim, Sang&#8208;Hoon Choi, Ho Jun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2023.12.048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvation Enthalpy Determination for Aqueous-Phase Reaction Adsorbates Using Ab Initio Molecular Dynamics-Based Structure Sampling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06870</link>
      <description>Hyonho Chun, Ankita Morankar, Zhenhua Zeng, Jeffrey Greeley, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390964436

                The interplay between covalent and noncovalent interactions at the solid&#8211;liquid interface strongly influences electrocatalytic reactions. Although methods to determine the former interactions have been rigorously developed, the latter are often described with static bilayer models or similarly approximate methods. In this study, we account for the disorder and dynamics at complex electrochemical interfaces by proposing a simple theory to estimate the enthalpy of solvation for adsorbed intermediates. In a strategy reminiscent of Born&#8211;Haber cycles, the enthalpy of solvation is expressed in terms of two subprocesses: vacancy creation by water reorganization and adsorbate interaction with solvent molecules. The magnitude of the solvation enthalpy is then determined as a mean valueof hydrated adsorbate-catalyst configurations obtained from simulated annealing with ab initio molecular dynamic (AIMD) simulations. This theory can be generalized for many combinations of surfaces and adsorbates. Its application improves treatment of energetics at electrified solid&#8211;liquid interfaces as well as corresponding structure&#8211;activity&#8211;stability predictions, as demonstrated for electrochemical oxygen reduction on Pt(111) and on Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts and for ethanol electrooxidation on Pt(111).</description>
      <author>Hyonho Chun, Ankita Morankar, Zhenhua Zeng, Jeffrey Greeley</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Wyckoff Sites to Construct Machine-Learning-Driven Interatomic Potentials for Crystalline Materials: A Case Study on &#945;-Alumina</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c05908</link>
      <description>Christian Rodr&#237;guez-Mart&#237;nez, Tony Schwedek, Evelyn Salazar, Xim Bokhimi, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390964539

                We present a methodology leveraging machine learning models to generate interatomic potentials for crystalline materials. This approach is rooted in the material&#8217;s crystallography in question. Specifically, we tap into the occupied Wyckoff sites, extracting the defining features that encapsulate the atomic local order in the material. Our choice for the target variable is the formation energy per atom, derived from the total energy of the structure&#8217;s representative cell. Our machine learning model&#8217;s architecture depends on the occupied Wyckoff sites. The diversity of these occupied sites conditions the layering scheme within the model. Atoms occupying a particular Wyckoff site were modeled with the architecture and learning parameters linked to the respective layer. To illustrate our method, we developed an interatomic potential for atomic interactions in &#945;-alumina. For training purposes, we generated the samples through quantum mechanical computations. The evaluation of the learned interatomic potential involved conducting molecular dynamics calculations on a 2 &#215; 2 &#215; 2 supercell, yielding formation energies per atom deviating by less than 1.0 meV from the quantum mechanics results. The methodology described here paves the way for further innovations, potentially ushering in the creation of interatomic potentials that can be utilized for more than one material. Moreover, this approach provides valuable insights into the feasibility of substituting atoms within a compound by focusing exclusively on the specific Wyckoff sites that they occupy.</description>
      <author>Christian Rodr&#237;guez-Mart&#237;nez, Tony Schwedek, Evelyn Salazar, Xim Bokhimi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c05908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of acidic titanium-based oxygen evolution anode catalyst design: mechanistic, compositional design, and research status</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173576</link>
      <description>Chuanbin Li, Tao Lin, Xiaotian Yuan, Hongzhou Jiang, Zhifang Hu, Yanxi Yin, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390967206

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key half-reaction in fields including water electrolysis, organic synthesis, and water treatment. With the development of the industry, research into highly active and stable oxygen evolution anodes in an acidic environment is essential. DSA is the dimensionally stable anode. Widespread attention has been paid to titanium-based DSAs in the field of acidic oxygen precipitation due to their low overpotential and high acid resistance. The titanium-based anode mainly consists of two parts: catalyst and titanium substrate, where the design of the catalyst is the key to the anode design. The factors affecting the catalytic activity and durability of the titanium-based DSA were heterogeneous and rarely reported. In this paper, the influence of catalytic mechanism and composition design on the catalytic activity and service life of anode is reviewed from the perspective of the catalyst. Then, the current situation related to anode preparation is summarized, and an improvement strategy to enhance the activity and stability of anode is proposed based on the failure mode of titanium-based DSA.</description>
      <author>Chuanbin Li, Tao Lin, Xiaotian Yuan, Hongzhou Jiang, Zhifang Hu, Yanxi Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Zn/Co&#8211;N&#8211;C as ORR Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11355</link>
      <description>Weixuan Xu, Rui Zeng, Michael Rebarchik, Alvaro Posada-Borb&#243;n, Huiqi Li, Christopher J. Pollock, Manos Mavrikakis, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390976238

                Hydrogen fuel cells have drawn increasing attention as one of the most promising next-generation power sources for future automotive transportation. Developing efficient, durable, and low-cost electrocatalysts, to accelerate the sluggish oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) kinetics, is urgently needed to advance fuel cell technologies. Herein, we report on metal&#8211;organic frameworks-derived nonprecious dual metal single-atom catalysts (SACs) (Zn/Co&#8211;N&#8211;C), consisting of Co&#8211;N4 and Zn&#8211;N4 local structures. These catalysts exhibited superior ORR activity with a half-wave potential (E1/2) of 0.938 V versus RHE (reversible hydrogen electrode) and robust stability (&#916;E1/2 = &#8722;8.5 mV) after 50k electrochemical cycles. Moreover, this remarkable performance was validated under realistic fuel cell working conditions, achieving a record-high peak power density of &#8764;1 W cm&#8211;2 among the reported SACs for alkaline fuel cells. Operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy was conducted to identify the active sites and reveal catalytic mechanistic insights. The results indicated that the Co atom in the Co&#8211;N4 structure was the main catalytically active center, where one axial oxygenated species binds to form an Oads&#8211;Co&#8211;N4 moiety during the ORR. In addition, theoretical studies, based on a potential-dependent microkinetic model and core-level shift calculations, showed good agreement with the experimental results and provided insights into the bonding of oxygen species on Co&#8211;N4 centers during the ORR. This work provides a comprehensive mechanistic understanding of the active sites in the Zn/Co&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts and will pave the way for the future design and advancement of high-performance single-site electrocatalysts for fuel cells and other energy applications.</description>
      <author>Weixuan Xu, Rui Zeng, Michael Rebarchik, Alvaro Posada-Borb&#243;n, Huiqi Li, Christopher J. Pollock, Manos Mavrikakis, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Pt&#8211;N4 Active Sites Anchored on Porous C3N4 Nanosheet for Boosting the Photocatalytic CO2 Reduction with Nearly 100% CO Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123737</link>
      <description>Song Hu, Panzhe Qiao, Longzhou Xiao, Guiming Ba, Xiaolong Zu, Huilin Hu, Jinhua Ye, Defa Wang, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390987109

                Photoreduction of CO2 and H2O into fuels and value-added chemicals is a promising green technology for solar-to-chemical conversion. However, improving the conversion efficiency with regulated product selectivity is a big challenge due to the sluggish dynamic transfer and insufficient active sites. Herein, we report on Pt single atoms anchored porous C3N4 nanosheet photocatalyst (Pt1@CN) with Pt&#8211;N4 coordination for stable and efficient CO2 photoreduction using H2O as reductant. The Pt1@CN exhibits an evolution rate of 84.8 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 with nearly 100% CO selectivity, outperforming most previous C3N4-based single-atom photocatalysts. Experimental and DFT calculation results reveal that the Pt&#8211;N4 coordinated active sites promote the photogenerated electron transfer, CO2 adsorption/activation, *COOH generation, and *CO desorption, thus accounting for the significantly improved CO2 photoreduction activity with &#8764;100% CO selectivity. This study provides a deep insight into the significant roles of single-atom active sites in enhancing the CO2 photoreduction activity and regulating the product selectivity.</description>
      <author>Song Hu, Panzhe Qiao, Longzhou Xiao, Guiming Ba, Xiaolong Zu, Huilin Hu, Jinhua Ye, Defa Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid synthesis of active Pt single atoms and Ru clusters on carbon black &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; a highly efficient microwave strategy for the hydrogen evolution reaction in acidic and alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta05396b</link>
      <description>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Bozhi Yang, Manjun Zhan, Shaorou Ke, Yang Fan, Xiaowen Wu, Yicen Liu, Zhaohui Huang, Xin Min, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390988147

                Using a highly efficient microwave reduction strategy, we successfully designed a novel synergistic electrocatalyst, Pt 1 Ru x @C, which was synthesized in an impressively short time of only 50 seconds.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Bozhi Yang, Manjun Zhan, Shaorou Ke, Yang Fan, Xiaowen Wu, Yicen Liu, Zhaohui Huang, Xin Min</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta05396b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOFs coupled transition metals, graphene, and MXenes: Emerging electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148776</link>
      <description>Abdul Hanan, Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Faiza Bibi, Amjad Ali Khan, Irfan Ali Soomro, Altaf Hussain, Umair Aftab, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390990449

                Development of effective transition metal catalyst to alternate precious metal platinum (Pt) based catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) has attracted wide interest recently. HER through electrochemical water splitting (EWS) is a green pathway to generate hydrogen (H2) fuel without any carbon dioxide (CO2) emission. However, this technology has been restricted dependency on platinum (Pt)-based catalyst to achieve optimum performance. At present, Pt based catalyst serves as a benchmark material in electrochemical H2 production. Extensive studies have been conducted on new type of porous materials metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) due to the Pt-based catalysts scarcity and cost. In this review, we have discussed the latest advancements of MOFs, which encompass transition metals (TMs), graphene, and MXenes. MOF-based electrocatalysts synthesis methods and electrochemical characteristics are also briefly summarized. Scientists can embark on further exploration of the capabilities offered by MOF-based catalysts by expanding the progress achieved and acknowledging the hurdles that remain. Consequently, their efforts can significantly contribute to the advancement of next-generation technologies for energy storage and conversion.</description>
      <author>Abdul Hanan, Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Faiza Bibi, Amjad Ali Khan, Irfan Ali Soomro, Altaf Hussain, Umair Aftab</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoxPy monolayers as ideal materials for electrochemical applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159412</link>
      <description>Li Xue, Baolei Li, Chaozheng He, Haizhong Guo, Applied Surface Science. 653(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391004056

                Exploring high-performance and cost-effective materials for electrochemical applications to meet eco-friendly and sustainable energy demands remain as an urgent need all the time. Large specific surface area and robust chemical activity endow two-dimensional (2D) materials with the potential as excellent candidates for electrochemical applications. Herein, we systematically study the 2D morphology for the Co-P system via advanced structural search and identify a series of stable monolayers, such as CoP, Co2P, and Co3P2. Detailed first-principle calculations reveal that these monolayers showcase inherent metallicity which benefits boosting the electrochemical process. For hydrogen evolution reactions (HER), the activity of CoP could reach 54 meV, which is comparable to that of Pt. As anode material potassium-ion batteries, CoP exhibits a suitable open circuit voltage and high capacity to store metal ion. This work disclosed the possible multifunctional applications for CoxPy monolayers and provided some theoretical guidance in designing electrocatalysts and anode materials from 2D transition-metal materials used in electrochemical processes.</description>
      <author>Li Xue, Baolei Li, Chaozheng He, Haizhong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single Atoms Supported on Defect Ceria as an Active and Stable Dual-Site Catalyst for Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.3c04237</link>
      <description>Dung Van Dao, Giovanni Di Liberto, Sunny Yadav, Periyayya Uthirakumar, Kai Chen, Gianfranco Pacchioni, In&#8722;Hwan Lee, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391014224

                This work evaluates the feasibility of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) using Pt single-atoms (1.0 wt %) on defect-rich ceria (Pt1/CeOx) as an active and stable dual-site catalyst. The catalyst displayed a low overpotential and a small Tafel slope in an alkaline medium. Moreover, Pt1/CeOx presented a high mass activity and excellent durability, competing with those of the commercial Pt/C (20 wt %). In this picture, the defective CeOx is active for water adsorption and dissociation to create H* intermediates, providing the first site where the reaction occurs. The H* intermediate species then migrate to adsorb and react on the Pt2+ isolated atoms, the site where H2 is formed and released. DFT calculations were also performed to obtain mechanistic insight on the Pt1/CeOx catalyst for the HER. The results indicate a new possibility to improve the state-of-the-art alkaline HER catalysts via a combined effect of the O vacancies on the ceria support and Pt2+ single atoms.</description>
      <author>Dung Van Dao, Giovanni Di Liberto, Sunny Yadav, Periyayya Uthirakumar, Kai Chen, Gianfranco Pacchioni, In&#8722;Hwan Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.3c04237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climbing the Hydrogen Evolution Volcano with a NiTi Shape Memory Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03216</link>
      <description>Sreetama Ghosh, Denver Haycock, N. C. Mehra, Susanta Bera, Hannah Johnson, Lucian Roiban, M. Aouine, P. Vernoux, Peter C. Th&#252;ne, William F. Schneider, Mihalis N. Tsampas, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391014304

                Alkaline water electrolysis is a sustainable way to produce green hydrogen using renewable electricity. Even though the rates of the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are 2-3 orders of magnitude less under alkaline conditions than under acidic conditions, the possibility of using non-precious metal catalysts makes alkaline HER appealing. We identify a novel and facile route for substantially improving HER performance via the use of commercially available NiTi shape memory alloys, which upon heating undergo a phase transformation from the monoclinic martensite to the cubic austenite structure. While the room-temperature performance is modest, austenitic NiTi outperforms Pt (which is the state-of-the-art HER electrocatalyst) in terms of current density by &#8804;50% at 80 &#176;C. Surface ensembles presented by the austenite phase are computed with density functional theory to bind hydrogen more weakly than either metallic Ni or Ti and to have binding energies ideally suited for HER.</description>
      <author>Sreetama Ghosh, Denver Haycock, N. C. Mehra, Susanta Bera, Hannah Johnson, Lucian Roiban, M. Aouine, P. Vernoux, Peter C. Th&#252;ne, William F. Schneider, Mihalis N. Tsampas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal electronic descriptors for optimizing hydrogen evolution in transition metal-doped MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159329</link>
      <description>Jisong Hu, Jiaying Mo, Chengpeng Yu, Dongsheng Li, Rui Zhang, Ling Miao, Xiao Ji, Jianjun Jiang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391018225

                The integration of transition metal (TM) atoms into two-dimensional (2D) transition metal carbides and nitrides (MXenes) has been identified as a promising strategy for enhancing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance. However, the vast combinatorial space presents challenges for rapid catalyst screening. In response, high-throughput calculations were conducted on Ti2CO2 and Zr2CO2 doped with a wide array of TM single atoms. The local structural and corresponding electronic structural changes were analyzed, with an emphasis on their implications for HER performance. Furthermore, universal electronic descriptors were developed using the Sure Independence Screening and Sparsifying Operator (SISSO) method, harmonizing the Gibbs free energy of hydrogen adsorption (&#916;GH*) trends across different MXenes substrates doped with TM atoms. These descriptors enabled the prediction of Cr, Fe, Ru, Pd, Os, and Ir as effective dopants for optimizing the &#916;GH* of Hf2CO2, resulting in a reduction of &#916;GH* from 1.082 eV to within &#177; 0.2 eV. Our work not only highlights the potential of these TM dopants in significantly enhancing the catalytic activity of MXenes but also underscores the value of universal electronic structure descriptors in rapidly identifying and developing high-performance HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jisong Hu, Jiaying Mo, Chengpeng Yu, Dongsheng Li, Rui Zhang, Ling Miao, Xiao Ji, Jianjun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated anode with 3D electron/ion conductive network for stable lithium metal batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103201</link>
      <description>Ziqiang Liu, Xiao Fu, Zhendong Li, Dingcheng Guo, Zh&#233; Peng, Ruijuan Xiao, Xiayin Yao, Energy Storage Materials. 66(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391018604

                Lithium metal anode has attracted increasing attention due to its ultra-high theoretical specific capacity and low redox potential. However, the severe interface problems caused by the parasitic reactions at the anode/separator interface greatly hinder its applications. Herein we design a 3D lithium&#8722;boron (LiB) fiber integrated lithium anode with polypropylene separator through the interfacial adhesive strategy with poly(vinylidene fluoride-co-hexafluoropropylene)-based polymer electrolyte. The 3D Li/LiB anode after chemical etching can increase the exchange current density to 36.8 mA cm&#8722;2, which is about 14 times the value of the pristine anode with 2.6 mA cm&#8722;2. Meanwhile, the poly(vinylidene fluoride-co-hexafluoropropylene)-based polymer electrolyte ensures high ionic conductivity and interfacial stability. Thus, the integrated anode with 3D electron/ion conductive network can guide Li deposition away from the unsafe anode/separator interface, and directly suppress the growth of lithium dendrites. As a result, the integrated anode with LiNi0.83Mn0.06Co0.11O2 cathode exhibits an excellent discharge capacity of 168.3 mAh g &#8722;1 at a high current density of 5 C. Besides, the rigid LiB skeleton coupling with flexible PVDF-HFP-based polymer electrolyte can effectively prevent the pulverization of lithium anode during long-term cycling, showing superior cycling stability of 1000 cycles at 1 C with a capacity retention of 76 %. This work provides a promising integrated anode for stable lithium metal batteries without lithium dendrite growth.</description>
      <author>Ziqiang Liu, Xiao Fu, Zhendong Li, Dingcheng Guo, Zh&#233; Peng, Ruijuan Xiao, Xiayin Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical water oxidation for hydrogen peroxide production: Focus on catalyst and reaction medium design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111960</link>
      <description>Zhimin Gao, Ye Cao, Qiuzi Zhu, Cunshi Wang, Wangjun Bai, Jianzhong Zhu, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. 12(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391018661

                Hydrogen peroxide (H2O2), as a valuable oxidant, has been extensively used in environmental applications. In the past decade, the electrochemical two-electron water oxidation reactions (2e&#8722; WOR) process have attracted considerable interest as a promising route to realize the decentralized production of H2O2. Nonetheless, a systematic review regarding the rational design strategies for electrochemical H2O2 synthesis systems through the 2e&#8722; WOR is still scarce, which is essential for advancing this burgeoning field. Hence, the basic knowledge of WOR, including the reaction mechanism, theoretical calculation prediction, and catalytic performance evaluation indicators, is introduced at the beginning of this review. Next, the different design strategies of catalysts and reaction medium modulation for H2O2 production by the 2e&#8722; WOR route are critically discussed and reviewed. Ultimately, some significant perspectives are proposed on the challenges and opportunities of 2e&#8722; WOR for H2O2 generation based on recent advances.</description>
      <author>Zhimin Gao, Ye Cao, Qiuzi Zhu, Cunshi Wang, Wangjun Bai, Jianzhong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au-Pt heterostructure cocatalysts on g-C3N4 for enhanced H2 evolution from photocatalytic glucose reforming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2024.112678</link>
      <description>Fangjie Ding, Hongbo Yu, Wei Liu, Xiao Cheng Zeng, Sha Li, Lin Chen, Bing Li, Jian-Zhong Guo, Chunzheng Wu, No host. 238(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391019394

                Glucose from plants or food industry wastes is a cost-effective hole scavenger for photocatalytic water splitting, but the related H2 evolution rate is always restricted by the fast recombination of photo electron-hole pairs and the poor intrinsic activity of traditional Pt cocatalysts. Herein, we fabricated Au-Pt heterostructure cocatalyst that consist of one &#8764;3 nm Au core and several &#8764;1 nm Pt islands on ultrathin g-C3N4 through one-pot photo-deposition. The heterostructure exhibited superior H2 evolution activity to monometallic Au or Pt nanoparticles. Our experiments and theoretical calculations demonstrated that the enhanced activity was caused by the synergistic effect between Au and Pt, rather than the well-known plasmonic effect of Au. The heterostructure not only favored the trapping of photo electrons from g-C3N4, but also had suitable adsorption strength of H*, exhibiting high intrinsic activity towards H2 evolution. Our research provides a strategy to boost photocatalytic H2 evolution by regulating the synergy of bimetallic cocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Fangjie Ding, Hongbo Yu, Wei Liu, Xiao Cheng Zeng, Sha Li, Lin Chen, Bing Li, Jian-Zhong Guo, Chunzheng Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2024.112678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-based/derived catalysts for electrochemical overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.106</link>
      <description>Yan He, Wei Liu, Jingquan Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391020576

                Water-splitting electrocatalysis has gained increasing attention as a promising strategy for developing renewable energy in recent years, but its high overpotential caused by the unfavorable thermodynamics has limited its widespread implementation. Therefore, there is an urgent need to design catalytic materials with outstanding activity and stability that can overcome the high overpotential and thus improve the electrocatalytic efficiency. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) based and/or derived materials are widely used as water-splitting catalysts because of their easily controlled structures, abundant heterointerfaces and increased specific surface area. Herein, some recent research findings on MOFs-based/derived materials are summarized and presented. First, the mechanism and evaluation parameters of electrochemical water splitting are described. Subsequently, advanced modulation strategies for designing MOFs-based/derived catalysts and their catalytic performance toward water splitting are summarized. In particular, the correlation between chemical composition/structural functionalization and catalytic performance is highlighted. Finally, the future outlook and challenges for MOFs materials are also addressed.</description>
      <author>Yan He, Wei Liu, Jingquan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lotus root-like RuIr alloys with close-packed (0001) branches: strain-driven performance for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.016</link>
      <description>Mingyue Xiao, Xu Wang, Rongchao Li, Yanhui Sun, Jingjun Liu, Feng Li, Jianying Gan, Shixin Gao, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391023139

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyue Xiao, Xu Wang, Rongchao Li, Yanhui Sun, Jingjun Liu, Feng Li, Jianying Gan, Shixin Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bibliometric Mining of Research Trends in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ai5010012</link>
      <description>Lars Lundberg, Martin Boldt, Anton Borg, H&#229;kan Grahn, AI. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391034571

                We present a method, including tool support, for bibliometric mining of trends in large and dynamic research areas. The method is applied to the machine learning research area for the years 2013 to 2022. A total number of 398,782 documents from Scopus were analyzed. A taxonomy containing 26 research directions within machine learning was defined by four experts with the help of a Python program and existing taxonomies. The trends in terms of productivity, growth rate, and citations were analyzed for the research directions in the taxonomy. Our results show that the two directions, Applications and Algorithms, are the largest, and that the direction Convolutional Neural Networks is the one that grows the fastest and has the highest average number of citations per document. It also turns out that there is a clear correlation between the growth rate and the average number of citations per document, i.e., documents in fast-growing research directions have more citations. The trends for machine learning research in four geographic regions (North America, Europe, the BRICS countries, and The Rest of the World) were also analyzed. The number of documents during the time period considered is approximately the same for all regions. BRICS has the highest growth rate, and, on average, North America has the highest number of citations per document. Using our tool and method, we expect that one could perform a similar study in some other large and dynamic research area in a relatively short time.</description>
      <author>Lars Lundberg, Martin Boldt, Anton Borg, H&#229;kan Grahn</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ai5010012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering the Nickel Iron Oxyhydroxide through a Heterostructure Cocatalyst for Superior Alkaline and Saline Water Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02406</link>
      <description>T. Susikumar, G. John, M. Navaneethan, Madhusmita Sahoo, A. K. Ray, Nirpendra Singh, P. Justin Jesuraj, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391035646

                Hydrogen production using an electrochemical cell might be an alternative to conventional fuel systems (i.e., fossil fuels). The NiFe-layered hydroxide (NiFeOxHy) is one of the most popular electrocatalysts for water-splitting applications. However, its electrochemical activity is limited in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) because of its minimal active sites and modest charge transfer rates. To overcome the limitations in NiFeOxHy, silver sulfide (Ag2S) and graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) were added as heterostructure cocatalysts. The heterostructure cocatalyst (Ag2S/g-C3N4) addition in NiFeOxHy is found to improve the electrochemical double layer capacitance (EDLC) seven times greater than that of pristine NiFeOxHy. The addition of the heterostructure cocatalyst in the NiFeOxHy sample enables hydrogen production with a minimum overpotential of &#951;10 = 43 mV and Tafel slope of 131 mV/dec in saline water conditions. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy reveals that the heterostructure cocatalyst effectively donates electrons to NiFeOxHy, which enhance the resultant charge transfer ability of the electrocatalyst. In addition, the density functional theoretical (DFT) analysis suggests that the exposed sulfur (S) sites within the Ag2S/g-C3N4 heterostructure cocatalyst serve as the prominent catalytic center for H* interactions. This study highlights the alteration of charge transfer dynamics in NiFeOxHy via heterostructure cocatalyst addition as an effective way to facilitate enhanced alkaline and saline water reduction.</description>
      <author>T. Susikumar, G. John, M. Navaneethan, Madhusmita Sahoo, A. K. Ray, Nirpendra Singh, P. Justin Jesuraj</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of a protic dimeric ionic liquid on PEM fuel cell performance and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.163</link>
      <description>Liang Wang, Oscar Morales&#8208;Collazo, Joan F. Brennecke, Hongfei Jia, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 58(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391041589

                Protic dimeric ionic liquid (IL) 9&#8242;9&#8217;-(butane-1, 4-diyl)bis (3,4,6,7,8,9-hexahydro-2H-pyrimido [1,2-a]pyrimidin-1-ium) 1,1,2,2,3,3,4,4,4-nonafluorobutane-1-sulfonate (D-HTBD) has been developed as a surface modifier to a PtCo/C oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalyst for polymer electrolyte membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). Thermal properties, intrinsic conductivity, and viscosity were studied to understand the ionic liquid's protonation effect. The protic IL was incorporated into the PtCo/C catalyst and its effect on MEA performance at various humidities were evaluated and compared with pristine PtCo/C catalyst. Electrochemically active surface area, AC impedance and gas diffusion resistance of the MEAs with IL were compared with the PtCo/C catalyst without modification by IL. Besides promoting the oxygen reduction reaction activity of the PtCo/C catalyst, the protic dimeric IL enhances dry condition MEA performance significantly, attributed to the hydrogen bonds between the Br&#248;nsted acids and Br&#248;nsted bases. A durability study of the PtCo/C catalyst with and without IL shows the reduction of catalyst degradation after incorporating IL. This work suggests that the protic dimeric IL could be a promising modifier to enhance ORR catalyst activity, fuel cell performance and durability.</description>
      <author>Liang Wang, Oscar Morales&#8208;Collazo, Joan F. Brennecke, Hongfei Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benzotrithiophene-based covalent organic frameworks as efficient catalysts for artificial photosynthesis of H2O2 in pure water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148922</link>
      <description>Mingjie Liu, Peipei He, Hantao Gong, Zhenghua Zhao, Yueming Li, Kai Zhou, Yuemin Lin, Jing Li, Zongbi Bao, Qiwei Yang, Yiwen Yang, Qilong Ren, Zhiguo Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. 482(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391042414

                Direct synthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) using oxygen and water through the photocatalytic route is a prospective approach for the on-site production of H2O2. However, the limited varieties of photocatalytic sites and ambiguous structure-active relationship impede the development of environmentally friendly technology. Herein, we report a active compound (benzotrithiophene, BTT) for the photosynthesis of H2O2 using oxygen and water, and design four benzotrithiophene-based 2D covalent organic frameworks (BTT-COFs) linked with aromatic amines linkers. Significant enhancement in photocatalytic activity has been observed via the introduction of BTT struct into 2D COFs. The high crystallinity of COFs increases the visible light absorption ability and photostability of BTT. The suitable distance of BTT struct in COFs and the construction of donor&#8211;acceptor (D-A) structure further promote the carrier generation and transfer. The COF-BTT-TAPT exhibited the highest H2O2 production rate of 620 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1. Mechanism investigation experiments have given the validation that BTT-COFs efficiently reduce oxygen in pure water to form H2O2 under visible-light irradiation. This work paves a revolutionary way for designing and fabricating high-performance metal-free photocatalysts for visible-light-driven H2O2 production.</description>
      <author>Mingjie Liu, Peipei He, Hantao Gong, Zhenghua Zhao, Yueming Li, Kai Zhou, Yuemin Lin, Jing Li, Zongbi Bao, Qiwei Yang, Yiwen Yang, Qilong Ren, Zhiguo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory-Based Kinetic Modeling of Reactions of Hydrogen Isotopes (H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, D&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, T&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) and Carbonaceous Gases (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, CO, CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;) on the ZrCo(110) Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08169</link>
      <description>Jinfan Chen, Tao Tang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391044401

                ZrCo and its alloys have attracted extensive attention as promising hydrogen isotope storage materials for nuclear fusion reactors. However, ZrCo can be readily poisoned by carbonaceous impurity gases like CO2 and CO introduced by input hydrogen isotopes or produced during the fusion reactor operation procedure. In this work, with density functional theory calculations and microkinetic modeling, the poisoning effects of CO2 and CO are identified by predominantly occupying active sites on the metal surface when reaching equilibrium. Surface reaction events related to CO2 are mostly molecular adsorption&#8211;desorption steps due to its strong binding strength. Dissociation of CO occurs readily even at room temperature, and the resident time length for the coverage of hydrogen being higher than other species is longer than CO2, indicating that the ZrCo alloy is more resistant to CO-poisoning compared to CO2. Interaction between CH4 and ZrCo is not active with the coexistence of hydrogen, making this impurity inert in deteriorating hydrogen storage performance. Hydrogen isotope effects are characterized by comparing reactions among H2 + CO2(CO), D2 + CO2(CO), and T2 + CO2(CO) mixing gases, with hydrogen resident time lengths decreasing from H2 to T2.</description>
      <author>Jinfan Chen, Tao Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Together Theoretical and Experimental Perspectives in Single&#8208;Atom Alloys for Electrochemical Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308084</link>
      <description>Mohammad Bashir Ahmed, Cheng Wang, Yongxiang Zhao, Clastin I. Sathish, Zhihao Lei, Liang Qiao, Chenghua Sun, Shaobin Wang, J. Kennedy, Ajayan Vinu, Jiabao Yi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391051284

                Abstract Ammonia is an essential commodity in the food and chemical industry. Despite the energy&#8208;intensive nature, the Haber&#8211;Bosch process is the only player in ammonia production at large scales. Developing other strategies is highly desirable, as sustainable and decentralized ammonia production is crucial. Electrochemical ammonia production by directly reducing nitrogen and nitrogen&#8208;based moieties powered by renewable energy sources holds great potential. However, low ammonia production and selectivity rates hamper its utilization as a large&#8208;scale ammonia production process. Creating effective and selective catalysts for the electrochemical generation of ammonia is critical for long&#8208;term nitrogen fixation. Single&#8208;atom alloys (SAAs) have become a new class of materials with distinctive features that may be able to solve some of the problems with conventional heterogeneous catalysts. The design and optimization of SAAs for electrochemical ammonia generation have recently been significantly advanced. This comprehensive review discusses these advancements from theoretical and experimental research perspectives, offering a fundamental understanding of the development of SAAs for ammonia production.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Bashir Ahmed, Cheng Wang, Yongxiang Zhao, Clastin I. Sathish, Zhihao Lei, Liang Qiao, Chenghua Sun, Shaobin Wang, J. Kennedy, Ajayan Vinu, Jiabao Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon capture technologies: A review on technology readiness level</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.130898</link>
      <description>Hesamedin Hekmatmehr, Ali Esmaeili, Maryam Pourmahdi, Saeid Atashrouz, Ali Abedi, Meftah Ali Abuswer, Dragutin Nedeljkovi&#263;, Mohammad Latifi, Sherif Farag, Ahmad Mohaddespour, Fuel. 363(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391053153

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hesamedin Hekmatmehr, Ali Esmaeili, Maryam Pourmahdi, Saeid Atashrouz, Ali Abedi, Meftah Ali Abuswer, Dragutin Nedeljkovi&#263;, Mohammad Latifi, Sherif Farag, Ahmad Mohaddespour</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.130898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcing oxygen electrocatalytic activity via selective dual-phase heterointerface engineering for rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02531-6</link>
      <description>Chao Cheng, Chunyi Zhi, Zhongti Sun, Yongqiang Ming, T. Xiang, Qian Zhu, Zirui Wu, Bing Li, Yang Li, Cheng Jin, Yong Cao, Juan Yang, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391053486

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Cheng, Chunyi Zhi, Zhongti Sun, Yongqiang Ming, T. Xiang, Qian Zhu, Zirui Wu, Bing Li, Yang Li, Cheng Jin, Yong Cao, Juan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02531-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NH3 decomposition in autothermal microchannel reactors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-88503-4.00003-x</link>
      <description>Ali Behrad Vakylabad, Mohammad Amin Makarem, Zohre Moravvej, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391064792

                The focus of this chapter is on the breakdown of ammonia intending to produce hydrogen as the cleanest source of energy. A review of microreactors and related technical literature is first collected. Then, the chemical mechanism of two coupled reactions (combustion and decomposition) are discussed. These two reactions are essentially underway in the same coupled microchannels. An autothermal plug-flow reactor for NH3 decomposition is a type of chemical reactor that utilizes a catalytic process to convert ammonia (NH3) into nitrogen (N2) and hydrogen (H2). This reaction is important in the production of hydrogen for fuel cells, as well as in the removal of ammonia from industrial waste streams. The autothermal plug-flow reactor is particularly useful for this reaction because it allows for both exothermic and endothermic reactions to occur simultaneously, without the need for external heating or cooling. The reactor design includes an annular region on the outside of a microchannel containing the catalyst, which allows for efficient heat transfer and mass transfer. The main effective parameters for this type of reactor include temperature, pressure, flow rate, catalyst type and loading, reactant concentration, reactor geometry, and inlet temperature and composition. By optimizing these parameters, the efficiency, selectivity, and yield of the NH3 decomposition reaction can be improved.</description>
      <author>Ali Behrad Vakylabad, Mohammad Amin Makarem, Zohre Moravvej, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-88503-4.00003-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance prediction of gas turbine blade with multi-source random factors using active learning-based neural network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.122481</link>
      <description>Zicheng Qiu, Yuqi Wang, Jinxing Li, Yonghui Xie, Di Zhang, Applied Thermal Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390948931

                Rapid and accurate performance acquisition of high-temperature gas turbine blades is fundamental to energy system design, analysis, and evaluation. Data-driven surrogate models are a popular alternative to complex and expensive numerical methods, but they require numerous labeled data and are often inaccurate when influenced by multi-source random factors. In this paper, a data-driven framework is proposed based on neural networks and active learning. Gas turbine blade performance with multi-source random factors can be quickly and accurately predicted. Two active learning-based sampling strategies, the Bayesian Sampling strategy (BS) and the Combined Sampling strategy (CS), are proposed to improve the efficiency of dataset building. The established prediction model is called active learning-based neural network (ALNN), which significantly improves the prediction accuracy with small samples. Compared with the artificial neural network using traditional Latin hypercube sampling, the prediction accuracy for the maximum stress of the blade is improved by 31.9%, and the prediction accuracy for the maximum deformation is improved by 47.6%. In addition, based on the ALNN, the low cycle fatigue probabilistic life of the gas turbine blade with multi-source random factors is evaluated. When the material and processing parameters and operating condition parameters are varied randomly, the minimum value of the low cycle fatigue life is 7000 cycles.</description>
      <author>Zicheng Qiu, Yuqi Wang, Jinxing Li, Yonghui Xie, Di Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.122481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Performance Evaluation of Absorbents for the Electrowinning-Coupled Competitive Separation CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07594</link>
      <description>Xiaomei Wang, Huifeng Fan, Yuanhao Mao, Teng Zhang, Sayd Sultan, Yunsong Yu, Zaoxiao Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391157027

                Electrowinning-coupled competitive separation (ECCS) CO2 capture technology, utilizing renewable electricity as the energy input, is regarded as a promising electrochemically mediated CO2 capture approach to substitute for the traditional solvent-based CO2 scrubbing method. However, this technology is still distant from practical application due to its energy-intensive property, sensitivity to oxygen, amine degradation, and system complexity. The selection of a suitable solvent plays a crucial role in enhancing the overall performance and scalability of the ECCS system. To address an efficient solvent screening method, this paper proposed a systematic comparison of solvents in terms of thermodynamics, electrochemistry, absorption, and desorption performance. The proposed solvent screening method undergoes a critical evaluation through the development of a thermodynamic model and experimentation. Using MEA, EDA, and NH3 as examples (solvents extensively discussed in the ECCS system), the paper provides a comprehensive discussion of the solvent screening method. Results indicate that EDA exhibits superior CO2 absorption and thermodynamic performance. NH3 solvent demonstrates better CO2 desorption and electrochemical performance. However, there is an antithetical relationship between the thermodynamic and electrochemical performance. This phenomenon arises because the Cu2+&#8211;solvent complex, characterized by a stronger coupling performance, is more stable, necessitating a higher potential to reduce the Cu2+&#8211;solvent complex. This leads to increased energy consumption during the solvent regeneration process. Therefore, when solvent screening is conducted, it is essential to categorize and thoroughly consider thermodynamics, electrochemistry, and absorption and desorption performance.</description>
      <author>Xiaomei Wang, Huifeng Fan, Yuanhao Mao, Teng Zhang, Sayd Sultan, Yunsong Yu, Zaoxiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Assembled FeIII-TAML-Based Magnetic Nanostructures for Rapid and Sustainable Destruction of Bisphenol A</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00128-023-03834-1</link>
      <description>Ruochen Dong, Lihua Bai, Sijia Liang, Shuo Xu, Song Gao, Hongjian Li, Ran Hong, Chao Wang, Cheng Gu, Bulletin of Environmental Contamination and Toxicology. 112(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391294140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruochen Dong, Lihua Bai, Sijia Liang, Shuo Xu, Song Gao, Hongjian Li, Ran Hong, Chao Wang, Cheng Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00128-023-03834-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxial Stabilization and Persistent Nucleation of the 3C Polymorph of Ba&lt;sub&gt;0.6&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;0.4&lt;/sub&gt;MnO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c11934</link>
      <description>Catherine Zhou, Charles L. Evans, Elizabeth C. Dickey, Gregory S. Rohrer, Paul A. Salvador, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390939574

                Ba-rich compositions in the BaxSr1-xMnO3 (BSMO) cubic perovskite (3C) system are magnetic ferroelectrics and are of interest for their strong magnetoelectric coupling. Beyond x = 0.5, they only form in hexagonal polymorphs. Here, the 3C phase boundary is pushed to Ba0.6Sr0.4MnO3 for the thin films. Using regular pulsed laser deposition (rPLD), 3C Ba0.6Sr0.4MnO3 could be epitaxially stabilized on DyScO3 (101)o substrates by using a 0.1% O2/99.9% N2 gas mixture. However, the 3C phase was mixed with the 4H polymorph for films 24 nm thick and above, and the films were relatively rough. To improve flatness and phase purity, changes in growth kinetics were investigated and interval PLD (iPLD) was especially effective. In iPLD, deposition is interrupted after completion of approximately one monolayer, and the deposit is annealed for a specific period of time before repeating. Both film flatness and, more importantly, the volume of the 3C polymorph improved with iPLD, resulting in 40 nm single-phase films. The results imply that iPLD improves the persistent nucleation of highly metastable phases and offers a new approach to epitaxial stabilization of novel materials, including more Ba-rich BSMO compositions in the 3C structure.</description>
      <author>Catherine Zhou, Charles L. Evans, Elizabeth C. Dickey, Gregory S. Rohrer, Paul A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c11934</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence in catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-99135-3.00002-6</link>
      <description>Srinivas Rangarajan, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391223759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Srinivas Rangarajan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-99135-3.00002-6</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
