<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:43:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Study on ORR reaction of B-doped graphene supported Co atoms with different defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114506</link>
      <description>Zhihua Ju, Xuyun Zhang, Yong Wang, Yan Liang, Fapeng Yu, Yong Liu, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391642348

                The performance of single atom catalyst (SAC) is strongly affected by its carrier. Five configurations with single vacancy, double vacancy, and defect site were calculated using density functional theory (DFT), and it was found that the electronic structure and state density were effectively regulated after introducing the B atom. The ORR activity was studied by doping different coordination layers. The results show that when doped with the second coordination layer of Co-DVG-N4 configuration, B can improve the adsorption strength of the central Co atom to the oxygen intermediate and show excellent ORR activity. Co-DVG-N4-B4(12.9 %) and Co-DVG-N4-B5(16.1 %) have relatively low overpotentials of 0.49 V and 0.47 V, providing an effective theoretical basis for rationalizing efficient electrocatalysts based on Co carbon materials.</description>
      <author>Zhihua Ju, Xuyun Zhang, Yong Wang, Yan Liang, Fapeng Yu, Yong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An efficient approach to compartmentalize double layer effects on kinetics of interfacial proton-electron transfer reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115360</link>
      <description>Naveen Agrawal, Andrew Jark-Wah Wong, Sharad Maheshwari, Michael J. Janik, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391643101

                Activation barriers for elementary electrochemical reactions can show strong dependence on the composition and structure of the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface, the electrochemical double layer (EDL), due to the highly polar nature of ion/electron transfer transition states. A compartmentalized analytical framework, built upon DFT calculations, is developed to consider complex interactions between reaction intermediates and the EDL. The approach analytically captures how altering interfacial properties, such as the dielectric constant or distribution of electrolyte charges, impact electrocatalytic activation barriers. Dipole moment change along the reaction path plays the largest role in dictating the extent to which interfacial properties impact elementary electrochemical kinetics. The compartmentalization and uncertainty quantification capability of the developed framework is illustrated employing a Helmholtz model with two parameters, dielectric constant and double layer thickness. The framework translates routine DFT analysis of (water-assisted) hydrogenation activation barriers to proton-coupled electron transfer barriers that depend analytically on electrode potential and EDL properties.</description>
      <author>Naveen Agrawal, Andrew Jark-Wah Wong, Sharad Maheshwari, Michael J. Janik</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APA-graphene: A multifunctional material for lithium-ion batteries and electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100699</link>
      <description>Wei Liu, Yunhao Xie, Liang Chen, Mingming Guo, Jing Xu, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391648745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Liu, Yunhao Xie, Liang Chen, Mingming Guo, Jing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100699</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia via Cu2O/Cu(OH)2 heterostructures promoting electron transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6480-1</link>
      <description>Jing Geng, Shengjun Ji, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391649902

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Geng, Shengjun Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6480-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Study of Bimetallic Pairs Embedded on Graphene Co-Doped with N and O for N2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29040779</link>
      <description>Haotian Dong, Hao Sun, Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Xue-Mei Duan, Jingyao Liu, Molecules. 29(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391650891

                The electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) is considered a viable alternative to the Haber&#8211;Bosch process for ammonia synthesis, and the design of highly active and selective catalysts is crucial for the industrialization of the NRR. Dual-atom catalysts (DACs) with dual active sites offer flexible active sites and synergistic effects between atoms, providing more possibilities for the tuning of catalytic performance. In this study, we designed 48 graphene-based DACs with N4O2 coordination (MM&#8242;@N4O2-G) using density functional theory. Through a series of screening strategies, we explored the reaction mechanisms of the NRR for eight catalysts in depth and revealed the &#8220;acceptance&#8211;donation&#8221; mechanism between the active sites and the N2 molecules through electronic structure analysis. The study found that the limiting potential of the catalysts exhibited a volcano-shaped relationship with the d-band center of the active sites, indicating that the synergistic effect between the bimetallic components can regulate the d-band center position of the active metal M, thereby controlling the reaction activity. Furthermore, we investigated the selectivity of the eight DACs and identified five potential NRR catalysts. Among them, MoCo@N4O2-G showed the best NRR performance, with a limiting potential of &#8722;0.20 V. This study provides theoretical insights for the design and development of efficient NRR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Haotian Dong, Hao Sun, Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Xue-Mei Duan, Jingyao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29040779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e638" altimg="si89.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;-&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e643" altimg="si90.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;z&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; hybridization promotes the high-efficiency hydrogen evolution &#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159642</link>
      <description>Jiajia Zhou, Yu-Hao Wei, Nan Gao, Anlong Kuang, Shao-Yi Wu, Min-Quan Kuang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391655850

                Heusler alloys with tunable electronic properties have promising catalytic applications. In this work, the hydrogen evolution reaction and the underlying catalytic mechanism of the full Heusler alloys Co2TiAl and Co2TiGa are investigated. The first-principles calculations indicate the Gibbs free energy difference (&#916;GH&#8727;) of the active Co-site on the (001) surface is &#8722;0.06 and &#8722;0.07 eV for Co2TiAl and Co2TiGa, respectively, which is comparable to the benchmark Pt (&#8722;0.09 eV). The high-efficiency HER activity can ascribe to the appropriate hybridization between the H-s and Co-dz2 orbital. Noticeably, the HER activity is robust against to the electron (hole) doping until the hybridization between the H-s and Co-dx2&#8722;y2 orbital emerges, in which the hole doping is equal or greater than 0.2 holes per a formula unit. In addition, the activation energy of the Tafel reaction at the Co-site is evaluated to be 0.37 and 0.41 eV for Co2TiAl and Co2TiGa, respectively, which is nearly half of the value of Pt (111) surface (0.85 eV). This work unveils the excellent and robust HER activity of Co2TiAl and Co2TiGa and reveals the s-dz2 bonding is an important factor for designing the HER catalysts based on the L21-type Heusler alloys.</description>
      <author>Jiajia Zhou, Yu-Hao Wei, Nan Gao, Anlong Kuang, Shao-Yi Wu, Min-Quan Kuang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159642</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review on techno-economics of hydrogen production using current and emerging processes: Status and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.101890</link>
      <description>Medhat A. Nemitallah, Abdulrahman A. Alnazha, Usama Ahmed, Mohammed El-Adawy, Mohamed A. Habib, Results in Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391656376

                This review presents a broad exploration of the techno economic evaluation of different technologies utilized in the production of hydrogen from both renewable and non-renewable sources. These encompass methods ranging from extracting hydrogen from fossil fuels or biomass to employing microbial processes, electrolysis of water, and various thermochemical cycles. A rigorous techno-economic evaluation of hydrogen production technologies can provide a critical cost comparison for future resource allocation, priorities, and trajectory. This evaluation will have a great impact on future hydrogen production projects and the development of new approaches to reduce overall production costs and make it a cheaper fuel. Different methods of hydrogen production exhibit varying efficiencies and costs: fast pyrolysis can yield up to 45% hydrogen at a cost range of $1.25 to $2.20 per kilogram, while gasification, operating at temperatures exceeding 750 &#176;C, faces challenges such as limited small-scale coal production and issues with tar formation in biomass. Steam methane reforming, which constitutes 48% of hydrogen output, experiences cost fluctuations depending on scale, whereas auto-thermal reforming offers higher efficiency albeit at increased costs. Chemical looping shows promise in emissions reduction but encounters economic hurdles, and sorption-enhanced reforming achieves over 90% hydrogen but requires CO2 storage. Renewable liquid reforming proves effective and economically viable. Additionally, electrolysis methods like PEM aim for costs below $2.30 per kilogram, while dark fermentation, though cost-effective, grapples with efficiency challenges. Overcoming technical, economic barriers, and managing electricity costs remains crucial for optimizing hydrogen production in a low-carbon future, necessitating ongoing research and development efforts.</description>
      <author>Medhat A. Nemitallah, Abdulrahman A. Alnazha, Usama Ahmed, Mohammed El-Adawy, Mohamed A. Habib</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.101890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening of a Single-Atom Catalyst Supported by Monolayer Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03188</link>
      <description>Keat Hoe Yeoh, Yee Hui Robin Chang, Khian&#8722;Hooi Chew, Junke Jiang, Tiem Leong Yoon, Duu Sheng Ong, Boon Tong Goh, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391657118

                The search for high-performance catalysts to improve the catalytic activity for an oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is crucial for developing a proton exchange membrane fuel cell. Using the first-principles method, we have performed computational screening on a series of transition metal (TM) atoms embedded in monolayer Nb2S2C to enhance the ORR activity. Through the scaling relationship and volcano plot, our results reveal that the introduction of a single Ni or Rh atom through substitutional doping into monolayer Nb2S2C yields promising ORR catalysts with low overpotentials of 0.52 and 0.42 V, respectively. These doped atoms remain intact on the monolayer Nb2S2C even at elevated temperatures. Importantly, the catalytic activity of the Nb2S2C doped with a TM atom can be effectively correlated with an intrinsic descriptor, which can be computed based on the number of d orbital electrons and the electronegativity of TM and O atoms.</description>
      <author>Keat Hoe Yeoh, Yee Hui Robin Chang, Khian&#8722;Hooi Chew, Junke Jiang, Tiem Leong Yoon, Duu Sheng Ong, Boon Tong Goh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical boroncarbonitride nanosheets as metal-free catalysts for enhanced oxidative dehydrogenation of propane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119848</link>
      <description>Guangming Wang, Anming Hu, Qiwei Duan, Longji Cui, Ziyi Chen, Zelong Huang, Xuefei Zhang, Shuping Huang, Zailai Xie, Chemical Engineering Science. 288(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391667305

                Boroncarbonitrides (BCNs) are recently developed new catalytic system for efficient oxidative dehydrogenation (ODH) of alkanes to alkenes. Herein, a series of novel hierarchical BCN materials are synthesized using asymmetric hydrogen bonds self-assembly between methylguanidine and boric acid, along with ammonia deposition. The XRD, S(T)EM, and XPS characterizations confirm the presence of ternary BCN solid solution covered by small serrated-like BCN nanosheets materials in the 2D plates. The unique hierarchical structure and developed mesoporosity of the BCN material contribute to its outstanding catalytic performance. The optimal catalyst delivers robust catalytic performance and long-term stability in the ODH of propane reaction with propylene and total olefin selectivity of 74.7% and 89.7% at a stable 20.4% propane conversion, much better than BCN sheets and h-BN catalyst. Results show that the in-situ formation of suitable amounts of amorphous BOX species within the BCN structure, along with the maintenance of the 2D skeleton at elevated temperatures, is a significant contribution in the enhanced ODH reactivity. Moreover, density functional theory calculation also demonstrates that the presence appropriate carbon content in BCN catalysts can significantly promote the ODH of propane reaction.</description>
      <author>Guangming Wang, Anming Hu, Qiwei Duan, Longji Cui, Ziyi Chen, Zelong Huang, Xuefei Zhang, Shuping Huang, Zailai Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrastable electrocatalytic seawater splitting at ampere-level current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-023-01263-w</link>
      <description>Rong-Chang Fan, Changhao Liu, Zhonghua Li, Huiting Huang, Jianyong Feng, Zhaosheng Li, Zhigang Zou, Nature Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391680871

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rong-Chang Fan, Changhao Liu, Zhonghua Li, Huiting Huang, Jianyong Feng, Zhaosheng Li, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-023-01263-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Ru&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Active Sites via Coordination Engineering for Tuning Hydrogen Evolution across the Full pH Value</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02367</link>
      <description>Zhaoyang Han, Sang&#8208;Hee Son, Kyungsaeng Kim, Shasha Gao, Gonglei Shao, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391683027

                The asymmetric coordination engineering of single metal atom is a challenging task for single-atom catalysts (SACs) to further amplify the catalytic potential. Hence, a unique asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;N2 active site is meticulously engineered through the pyrolysis of an organic complex with 1,10-phenanthroline-2,9-dicarboxylic acid and Ru metal ions. The coordination evolution of the Ru atom is examined as a function of annealing temperature, evolving from the asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;N2 configuration to the asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;Ru and finally to the Ru&#8211;Ru structure. The electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution performance makes it clear that the SACs with asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;N2 active sites outperform intermediate O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;Ru, Ru nanosheets, and even commercial Pt/C catalysts across the full pH value. The optimal HER performance is attributed to the formation of asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;N2 active sites, which exhibit the lowest &#916;GH* owing to the unique structure of Ru coordinated with double heterononmetallic atoms, which is confirmed by X-ray absorption spectroscopy. This work underscores the pivotal role of coordination engineering in SACs, with particular emphasis on the significance of asymmetric single-atom catalytic centers and their potential in diverse catalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Zhaoyang Han, Sang&#8208;Hee Son, Kyungsaeng Kim, Shasha Gao, Gonglei Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acidic media enables oxygen-tolerant electrosynthesis of multicarbon products from simulated flue gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45527-1</link>
      <description>Meng Wang, B.X. Wang, Ji&#8208;Guang Zhang, Shibo Xi, Lixin Ning, Zhiyong Mi, Qin Yang, Mingsheng Zhang, Wan Ru Leow, Jia Zhang, Yanwei Lum, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391687274

                Abstract Renewable electricity powered electrochemical CO 2 reduction (CO 2 R) offers a valuable method to close the carbon cycle and reduce our overreliance on fossil fuels. However, high purity CO 2 is usually required as feedstock, which potentially decreases the feasibility and economic viability of the process. Direct conversion of flue gas is an attractive option but is challenging due to the low CO 2 concentration and the presence of O 2 impurities. As a result, up to 99% of the applied current can be lost towards the undesired oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Here, we show that acidic electrolyte can significantly suppress ORR on Cu, enabling generation of multicarbon products from simulated flue gas. Using a composite Cu and carbon supported single-atom Ni tandem electrocatalyst, we achieved a multicarbon Faradaic efficiency of 46.5% at 200 mA cm -2 , which is ~20 times higher than bare Cu under alkaline conditions. We also demonstrate stable performance for 24 h with a multicarbon product full-cell energy efficiency of 14.6%. Strikingly, this result is comparable to previously reported acidic CO 2 R systems using pure CO 2 . Our findings demonstrate a potential pathway towards designing efficient electrolyzers for direct conversion of flue gas to value-added chemicals and fuels.</description>
      <author>Meng Wang, B.X. Wang, Ji&#8208;Guang Zhang, Shibo Xi, Lixin Ning, Zhiyong Mi, Qin Yang, Mingsheng Zhang, Wan Ru Leow, Jia Zhang, Yanwei Lum</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45527-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Modulation in Cu Doped NiCo LDH/NiCo Heterostructure for Highly Efficient Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311182</link>
      <description>Xuewen Xia, Shujuan Wang, Dan Li&#250;, Fei Wang, Xueqiang Zhang, Hao Zhang, Xiaojiang Yu, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Chaoyi Chen, Yufeng Zhao, Ji Li, Qian Xu, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391690247

                Abstract Layered double hydroxides (LDHs), promising bifunctional electrocatalysts for overall water splitting, are hindered by their poor conductivity and sluggish electrochemical reaction kinetics. Herein, a hierarchical Cu&#8208;doped NiCo LDH/NiCo alloy heterostructure with rich oxygen vacancies by electronic modulation is tactfully designed. It extraordinarily effectively drives both the oxygen evolution reaction (151 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (73 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) in an alkaline medium. As bifunctional electrodes for overall water splitting, a low cell voltage of 1.51 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and remarkable long&#8208;term stability for 100 h are achieved. The experimental and theoretical results reveal that Cu doping and NiCo alloy recombination can improve the conductivity and reaction kinetics of NiCo LDH with surface charge redistribution and reduced Gibbs free energy barriers. This work provides a new inspiration for further design and construction of nonprecious metal&#8208;based bifunctional electrocatalysts based on electronic structure modulation strategies.</description>
      <author>Xuewen Xia, Shujuan Wang, Dan Li&#250;, Fei Wang, Xueqiang Zhang, Hao Zhang, Xiaojiang Yu, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Chaoyi Chen, Yufeng Zhao, Ji Li, Qian Xu, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311182</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate construction of cobalt vacancies in Co3O4 to promote oxyhydroxide formation for water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2766-y</link>
      <description>Zhijuan Liu, Guangjin Wang, Jinyu Guo, Yanyong Wang, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391690577

                The introduction of defect sites has been widely reported to enhance electrocatalysts&#8217; abilities by increasing their affinity for reaction intermediates. Many different defect types, such as cation and anion vacancies, can exist in nano-materials. The different defect sites can make different contributions to the electrochemical ability. Therefore, a constructed defect should be accurate and specific, which makes it easy to identify the optimal defect type to facilitate electrochemical reactions. In this work, we used cobalt vacancies in Co3O4 as an example and synthesized Co3O4 with bivalent cobalt vacancies (Co3O4-VCo(II)) and trivalent cobalt vacancies (Co3O4-VCo(III)). Electrochemical results demonstrate that introducing cobalt vacancies considerably enhances the electrocatalytic activity of Co3O4. Furthermore, Co3O4-VCo(II) exhibits the most outstanding oxygen evolution ability with the fastest reaction kinetic rate. Quasi-operando X-ray photoelectron microscopy spectrum analysis results indicate that the presence of VCo(II) can accelerate CoOOH active site formation during the oxygen evolution reaction process. Density functional theory calculations reveal that introducing cobalt vacancies can endow Co3O4 with metal-like conductivity. The O p-band center can be moved near the Fermi level, and the free energy barrier can be the lowest with the presence of VCo(II), resulting in a fast kinetics rate of oxygen exchange at the electrocatalyst surface and optimal adsorption energy to reaction intermediates to display excellent electrochemical ability. This work provides substantial guidance for designing efficient defect-rich electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhijuan Liu, Guangjin Wang, Jinyu Guo, Yanyong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2766-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Element-dependent effects of alkali cations on nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.02.011</link>
      <description>Yida Zhang, Zhentao Ma, Shuo Yang, Qingyu Wang, Limin Liu, Yu Bai, Dewei Rao, Gongming Wang, Hongliang Li, Xusheng Zheng, Science Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391691052

                Catalytic conversion of nitrate (NO3&#8722;) pollutants into ammonia (NH3) offers a sustainable and promising route for both wastewater treatment and NH3 synthesis. Alkali cations are prevalent in nitrate solutions, but their roles beyond charge balance in catalytic NO3&#8722; conversion have been generally ignored. Herein, we report the promotion effect of K+ cations in KNO3 solution for NO3&#8722; reduction over a TiO2-supported Ni single-atom catalyst (Ni1/TiO2). For photocatalytic NO3&#8722; reduction reaction, Ni1/TiO2 exhibited a 1.9-fold NH3 yield rate with nearly 100% selectivity in KNO3 solution relative to that in NaNO3 solution. Mechanistic studies reveal that the K+ cations from KNO3 gradually bonded with the surface of Ni1/TiO2, in situ forming a K-O-Ni moiety during reaction, whereas the Na+ ions were unable to interact with the catalyst in NaNO3 solution. The charge accumulation on the Ni sites induced by the incorporation of K atom promoted the adsorption and activation of NO3&#8722;. Furthermore, the K-O-Ni moiety facilitated the multiple proton-electron coupling of NO3&#8722; into NH3 by stabilizing the intermediates.</description>
      <author>Yida Zhang, Zhentao Ma, Shuo Yang, Qingyu Wang, Limin Liu, Yu Bai, Dewei Rao, Gongming Wang, Hongliang Li, Xusheng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.02.011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of H2O2 via two-electron oxygen reduction over carbon-based catalysts: From microenvironment control to electrode/reactor design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enrev.2024.100069</link>
      <description>Jingjing Jia, Zhenxin Li, Yunrui Tian, Xia Li, Rui Chen, Jiachen Liu, Ji Liang, Energy reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391691194

                The electrochemical production of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) by the two-electron oxygen reduction (2e&#8722;-ORR) process has the advantages of high safety, low energy consumption, and environmental friendliness. For 2e&#8722;-ORR, the catalyst/electrode is the key component as it strongly affects catalytic performance and cost. Carbon materials have the advantages of high electronic conductivity, good structural stability, easy control of nanostructures, and low cost. Therefore, it has been regarded as a promising catalyst/electrode material for the electrosynthesis of H2O2 via 2e&#8722;-ORR. In addition, studies have also considered the optimization of the liquid/gas interface by tuning the electrode surface, electrolyte pH, and reactor configurations for further improving the activity and selectivity of catalysts. In this review, we provide an in-depth discussion of the recent research on the carbon-based electrocatalysts for 2e&#8722;-ORR, especially in terms of microenvironment tuning, catalyst/electrode interface engineering, and reactor design for achieving stable and efficient production of H2O2. The challenges that we are still facing and the future development prospects will then be concluded, which we believe should help the future development in this field.</description>
      <author>Jingjing Jia, Zhenxin Li, Yunrui Tian, Xia Li, Rui Chen, Jiachen Liu, Ji Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enrev.2024.100069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing heterojunctions of CoAl2O4 and Ni3S2 anchored on carbon cloth to acquire multiple active sites for efficient overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118109</link>
      <description>Ting Cheng, Mingyue Wen, Chen Chen, Junfa Zhu, Yongnian Dai, Xiao Zhang, Baoxuan Hou, Lei Wang, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391692471

                Constructing heterojunction interface is an efficient strategy to accelerate the catalytic activity for electrochemical reaction. In this work, a novel composite heterojunction electrocatalyst (CAO/NiS400/CC), deriving from the combination of CoAl2O4 (CAO) and Ni3S2 anchored on carbon cloth (CC) was prepared, through hydrothermal process followed by electrodeposition. After successful synthesis, CoAl2O4 particles were intricately embedded in Ni3S2 and formed an active heterostructure, exhibited outstanding catalytic capacity for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and improved the efficiencies of overall water splitting. As expected, the composite heterojunction electrocatalyst demonstrated excellent catalytic performances with lower overpotential of 163.2 mV at 100 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 and Tafel slope of 20.4 mV&#183;dec-1for HER and 400 mV at 100 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 and Tafel slope of 51.1 mV&#183;dec-1 for OER, respectively, accompanied by long-term structural stability after 40 h and 3000 Cyclic Voltammetry (CV) cycles. Moreover, Density functional theory (DFT) calculation illustrated that the robust electrocatalytic performance was attributed to the simultaneous presence of multiple catalytic active sites surrounding the heterojunction interface. Furthermore, CAO/NiS400/CC electrocatalyst facilitated the overall water splitting reaction under a cell voltage of only 1.48 V with dual catalytic capabilities for HER and OER. The combined action of active catalytic sites within both CAO and Ni3S2 around the interface contributed the optimal electrocatalytic performance, making the CAO/NiS400/CC as a promising alternative to electrocatalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Ting Cheng, Mingyue Wen, Chen Chen, Junfa Zhu, Yongnian Dai, Xiao Zhang, Baoxuan Hou, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkaline Water Electrolysis for Green Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.3c00709</link>
      <description>Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z, Accounts of Chemical Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391693949

                ConspectusThe global energy landscape is undergoing significant change. Hydrogen is seen as the energy carrier of the future and will be a key element in the development of more sustainable industry and society. However, hydrogen is currently produced mainly from fossil fuels, and this needs to change. Alkaline water electrolysis with advanced technology has the most significant potential for this transition to produce large-scale green hydrogen by utilizing renewable energy. The assembly of industrial electrolyzer plants is more complex on a larger scale, but it follows a basic working principle, which involves two half-cells of anode and cathode sites where the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) occur. Out of the two reactions, the OER is more challenging both thermodynamically and kinetically. Besides having access to renewable electricity, developing durable and abundant electrocatalysts for the OER remains a challenge in large-scale alkaline water electrolysis. Among different physicochemical properties, the electrocatalyst surface and its interaction with water and reaction intermediates, as well as formed molecular hydrogen and oxygen, play an essential role in the catalytic performance and the reaction mechanism. In particular, the binding strengths between the catalyst surface and intermediates determine the rate-limiting step and electrocatalytic performance.This Account gives some insights into the status of the hydrogen economy and basic principles of alkaline water electrolysis by covering its fundamentals as well as industrial developments. Further, the HER and OER reaction mechanisms of alkaline water electrolysis and selected electrocatalyst progress for both half-reactions are briefly discussed. The Adsorbate Evolution Mechanism and the Lattice Oxygen Mechanism for the OER are explained with specific references. This Account also deliberates on the author&#8217;s selected contributions to the development of transition metal-based electrocatalysts for alkaline water electrolysis with an emphasis on OER. The focus is particularly given to the enhancement of intrinsic activity, the role of eg-filling, phase segregation, and defect structure of cobalt-based electrocatalysts for OER. Structural modification and phase transformation of the cobalt oxide electrocatalyst under working conditions are further deliberated. In addition, the creation of new active surface species and the activation of cobalt- and nickel-based electrocatalysts through iron uptake from the alkaline electrolyte are discussed. In the end, this Account provides a brief overview of challenges related to large-scale production and utilization of green hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.3c00709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential synergy between Pt2Ni4 Atomic-Clusters, oxygen vacancies and adjacent Pd nanoparticles outperforms commercial Pt nanocatalyst in alkaline fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149421</link>
      <description>Dinesh Bhalothia, Amisha Beniwal, Che Yan, Kai-Chin Wang, Chenhao Wang, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen, Chemical Engineering Journal. 483(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391706540

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is a key &#8220;showstopper&#8221; for the commercial viability of alkaline fuel cells (AFCs). In this study, we developed a ternary nanocatalyst (NC) coloaded with Pt2Ni4 atomic clusters and palladium (Pd) nanoparticles (NPs) on oxygen vacancies (OVs) enriched nickel hydroxide-support (henceforth denoted as NiPP). This material outperforms the commercial J.M.-Pt/C (20 wt%) catalyst by &#8764;75 and &#8764;38 times with exceptionally high mass activities (MA)s of 5050.3 mAmgPt-1 and 952.3 mAmgPt-1 at 0.85 V and 0.90 V vs RHE, respectively, in alkaline ORR (0.1 M KOH). The high structural reliability of the Pt2Ni4 endows the NiPP NC with outstanding durability, where it achieves an optimum MA of 5755.9 mAmgPt-1 after 10 K cycles in an accelerated durability test (ADT) and retains the original performance up to 15 K cycles. Moreover, NiPP delivers an outstanding power density (339.1.4 mW cm&#8722;2) and short circuit current density (910.8 mA cm&#8722;2), which exceeds the commercial J.M.-Pt/C (174.9 mW cm&#8722;2 and 720.4 mA cm&#8722;2) when serving as the cathodic catalyst in an AFC. The results of physical characterizations, electrochemical analysis and in-situ XAS analysis suggest that the exceptional performance is originated from the potential synergism between the neighbouring reaction sites of Pt2Ni4 (OV in Ni(OH)x and Pd NPs). During ORR, the Pt2Ni4 atomic clusters and OVs boost the O2 splitting, while the adjacent Pd NPs promote the subsequent relocation of OH&#8211; ions. The obtained results provide the potential design strategies for the atomic-scale surface engineering of advanced ORR NCs in alkaline fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Dinesh Bhalothia, Amisha Beniwal, Che Yan, Kai-Chin Wang, Chenhao Wang, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable conversion of alkaline nitrate to ammonia at activities greater than 2 A cm&#8722;2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45534-2</link>
      <description>Wanru Liao, J. Wang, Ganghai Ni, Kang Liu, Changxu Liu, Shanyong Chen, Qiyou Wang, Yingkang Chen, Ting Luo, Xiqing Wang, Yanqiu Wang, Wenzhang Li, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chao Ma, Hongmei Li, Ying Liang, Weizhen Liu, Junwei Fu, B. Xi, Min Liu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391716671

                Abstract Nitrate (NO 3 &#8210; ) pollution poses significant threats to water quality and global nitrogen cycles. Alkaline electrocatalytic NO 3 &#8210; reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) emerges as an attractive route for enabling NO 3 &#8210; removal and sustainable ammonia (NH 3 ) synthesis. However, it suffers from insufficient proton (H + ) supply in high pH conditions, restricting NO 3 &#8210; -to-NH 3 activity. Herein, we propose a halogen-mediated H + feeding strategy to enhance the alkaline NO 3 RR performance. Our platform achieves near-100% NH 3 Faradaic efficiency (pH = 14) with a current density of 2 A cm &#8211;2 and enables an over 99% NO 3 &#8211; -to-NH 3 conversion efficiency. We also convert NO 3 &#8210; to high-purity NH 4 Cl with near-unity efficiency, suggesting a practical approach to valorizing pollutants into valuable ammonia products. Theoretical simulations and in situ experiments reveal that Cl-coordination endows a shifted d -band center of Pd atoms to construct local H + -abundant environments, through arousing dangling O-H water dissociation and fast *H desorption, for *NO intermediate hydrogenation and finally effective NO 3 &#8210; -to-NH 3 conversion.</description>
      <author>Wanru Liao, J. Wang, Ganghai Ni, Kang Liu, Changxu Liu, Shanyong Chen, Qiyou Wang, Yingkang Chen, Ting Luo, Xiqing Wang, Yanqiu Wang, Wenzhang Li, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chao Ma, Hongmei Li, Ying Liang, Weizhen Liu, Junwei Fu, B. Xi, Min Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45534-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced alkaline hydrogen evolution performance through Ru-Incorporated electronic structure Modification: Transitioning from Mo3P to Mo2RuP</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149486</link>
      <description>Peng Zhang, Shiyu Xu, Zhengyang Li, Zongfu An, Ho Seok Park, Ji Man Kim, Pil J. Yoo, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391718332

                In accordance with the Sabatier principle, Mo-based catalysts typically exhibit lower catalytic activity in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to strong interactions between Mo and hydrogen within their structures. To overcome this limitation, here, we introduce a novel approach by incorporating Ru into Mo3P to modify its electronic structure, resulting in a novel water splitting cathode material of I&#773;42m structured Mo2RuP. Notably, Mo2RuP demonstrates as an efficient catalyst for alkaline HER, exhibiting outstanding performance with extremely low overpotentials of 29 mV and 62 mV at current densities of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. It also displays a small Tafel slope (30 mV dec-1) and long-term durability in hydrogen production even at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in a 1 mol/L KOH solution. First-principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations elucidate that Ru-substitution significantly reduces the hydrogen adsorption Gibbs free energy on various crystal facets of Mo2RuP. This alteration facilitates the transformation of the material to the kinetically favorable Volmer-Heyrovsky pathway during the HER. Furthermore, a comprehensive characterization and investigation into the electronic structure of this innovative material validate the efficacy of Ru modulation within the Mo3P structure. The strategy of Ru-substitution to adjust the electronic structure of Mo-based catalysts offers a viable approach for the development of novel, stable, and high-performance catalysts for the HER.</description>
      <author>Peng Zhang, Shiyu Xu, Zhengyang Li, Zongfu An, Ho Seok Park, Ji Man Kim, Pil J. Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium And Silver Synergetic Regulation NiFe LDH Boosting Long&#8208;Duration Industrial Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315674</link>
      <description>Hengyi Chen, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Haojie Chen, Yang Yang, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391719280

                Abstract The chloride ions in seawater result in corrosion, low catalytic efficiency, and poor stability of the electrocatalysts in direct seawater electrolysis, which limits the use of large&#8208;scale seawater electrolysis technology. Herein, a corrosion&#8208;resistant Ag/NiFeRu layered double hydroxide (LDH) electrocatalyst for seawater electrolysis at industrial current density, in which Ru and Ag species in the catalyst can have a corrosion&#8208;resistance of chloride ions from the anode surface and enhance its robustness in seawater is designed. The catalyst requires the overpotentials of 256 and 287 mV to obtain a current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH and 1 m KOH + seawater, respectively. More importantly, it works stably for over 1000 h at 1 A cm &#8722;2 in alkaline seawater. Further quasi&#8208;industrial conditions measurement (6 m KOH + seawater, 60 &#176;C) shows a markedly low overpotential of 174 mV at 1 A cm &#8722;2 on Ag/NiFeRu LDH, obtaining over 140 h under harsh industrial conditions. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that the Ru species can effectively regulate the local electronic structure of NiFe LDH, and enhance the intrinsic activity of NiFe LDH. The transformation of Ag 2 O from Ag during OER stabilizes the Fe site in NiFe LDH, which improves the overall stability of the electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Hengyi Chen, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Haojie Chen, Yang Yang, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315674</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Solid&#8208;State Gas Sensing Realized via Fast K&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Transport Kinetics in Earth Abundant Rock&#8208;Silicates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202302231</link>
      <description>Mohamad Khoshkalam, Yousef Alizad Farzin, Benjamin Heckscher Sj&#248;lin, Chiara Spezzati, Peter Holtappels, Ivano E. Castelli, Bhaskar Reddy Sudireddy, Advanced Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391729579

                Here we report on the discovery of a novel fast potassium super stoichiometric silicate, with fully earth&#8208;abundant nominal chemical composition of K 2+ x Mg 1&#8722; x /2 SiO 4 , which exhibits near superionic K + conductivity, up to 5 &#215; 10 &#8722;5 S cm &#8722;1 at room temperature. Fast K + conduction is attributed to a high Continuous Symmetry Measure value in K&#8208;polyhedrons, coupled with a low packing ratio of Corner&#8208;Sharing&#8208;framework. This is the first time that such a high conductivity is measured by a rock&#8208;silicate formed only by abundant metal ions. K 2+ x Mg 1&#8722; x /2 SiO 4 displays excellent stability under air and humidity, which renders it a very promising candidate for economical fabrication of electrochemical devices such as potentiometric gas sensors. We demonstrated this by fabricating a gas sensor for SO 2 detection, as the first demonstration of type III potentiometric gas sensors using K + conductors. At 500 &#176;C and SO 2 concentrations in the range of 0&#8211;10 ppm, the sensor exhibited high sensitivities (69&#8211;72 mV dec &#8722;1 ), robust signal output (220 mV for 2 ppm of SO 2 ), fast response times (1&#8211;6 min), and excellent stability in ambient condition.</description>
      <author>Mohamad Khoshkalam, Yousef Alizad Farzin, Benjamin Heckscher Sj&#248;lin, Chiara Spezzati, Peter Holtappels, Ivano E. Castelli, Bhaskar Reddy Sudireddy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202302231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the intrinsic activity of various transition metal sulfides for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr06456e</link>
      <description>Xie Hu, Yang Gao, Xinying Luo, Junjie Xiong, Ping Chen, Bin Wang, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391729643

                The electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is an efficient approach to convert sustainable energy sources into clean energy carriers, H 2 .</description>
      <author>Xie Hu, Yang Gao, Xinying Luo, Junjie Xiong, Ping Chen, Bin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr06456e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances and prospects of iron-based noble metal-free catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction in acidic environment: A mini review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.027</link>
      <description>Hongyan Xu, Zhanhong Ma, Zhongmin Wan, Zhongfu An, Xiaoguang Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391731405

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) occurred in acidic media, as the cathode reaction of proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs) with great commercialization potential, has attracted much attention. However, the slow kinetics of ORR and the high cost of cathode catalysts (mainly platinum (Pt)-based materials in current) have become the main obstacle to the rapid development of PEMFCs. Therefore, the exploration of efficient and inexpensive non-precious metal-based ORR catalysts has emerged as an urgent issue. Non-noble transition metal-based materials have been widely investigated as ORR catalysts in acidic media. This review focused on the investigation of iron (Fe) based catalysts in acidic ORR processes. In this review, the ORR mechanism was first introduced. Subsequently, the fabrication method of Fe-based catalysts by co-pyrolysis of mixtures containing Fe, non-metal, and organic precursors was discussed. Finally, the recent advances of Fe-based materials (carbides, nitrides, oxides, phosphides, chalcogenides, hybrids, alloys and single atom catalysts) as acidic ORR catalysts were summarized, and mainly focused on catalytic performance, stability and catalytic mechanism studies with Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculation. Finally, the challenges and future perspectives of Fe-based catalysts were also proposed.</description>
      <author>Hongyan Xu, Zhanhong Ma, Zhongmin Wan, Zhongfu An, Xiaoguang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.027</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
