<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:45:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyzing Sustainable Water Splitting with Single Atom Catalysts: Recent Advances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202300330</link>
      <description>Niharul Alam, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Naseem Iqbal, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391926985

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting for sustainable hydrogen and oxygen production have shown enormous potentials. However, this method needs low&#8208;cost and highly active catalysts. Traditional nano catalysts, while effective, have limits since their active sites are mostly restricted to the surface and edges, leaving interior surfaces unexposed in redox reactions. Single atom catalysts (SACs), which take advantage of high atom utilization and quantum size effects, have recently become appealing electrocatalysts. Strong interaction between active sites and support in SACs have considerably improved the catalytic efficiency and long&#8208;term stability, outperforming their nano&#8208;counterparts. This review&#8216;s first section examines the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) and the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER). In the next section, SACs are categorized as noble metal, non&#8208;noble metal, and bimetallic synergistic SACs. In addition, this review emphasizes developing methodologies for effective SAC design, such as mass loading optimization, electrical structure modulation, and the critical role of support materials. Finally, Carbon&#8208;based materials and metal oxides are being explored as possible supports for SACs. Importantly, for the first time, this review opens a discussion on waste&#8208;derived supports for single atom catalysts used in electrochemical reactions, providing a cost&#8208;effective dimension to this vibrant research field. The well&#8208;known design techniques discussed here may help in development of electrocatalysts for effective water splitting.</description>
      <author>Niharul Alam, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Naseem Iqbal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202300330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density&#8208;Functional Theory Studies on Photocatalysis and Photoelectrocatalysis: Challenges and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/solr.202300948</link>
      <description>Chi&#8208;Hui Lin, Jyoti Rohilla, Hsuan&#8208;Hung Kuo, Chun-yi Chen, Tso&#8208;Fu Mark Chang, Masato Sone, Pravin P. Ingole, Yu&#8208;Chieh Lo, Yung&#8208;Jung Hsu, Solar RRL. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391929686

                Density&#8208;functional theory (DFT) is pivotal in the advancement of photocatalysis and photoelectrocatalysis. Its capability to explore electronic structures of materials contributes significantly to clarifying the mechanisms of photocatalytic (PC) and photoelectrocatalytic (PEC) processes. DFT calculations enable a deeper understanding of how these processes work at a molecular level, which is essential for designing versatile photocatalysts and photoelectrodes and optimizing reaction pathways. In this perspective, key PC and PEC applications, such as H 2 production, CO 2 reduction, dye degradation, and N 2 reduction, where DFT is instrumental in optimizing materials designs and reaction pathways, are highlighted. Exploration on the synergy between experimental research and DFT calculations is highlighted, which is crucial for the development of efficient and environmentally friendly energy solutions. The discussion further extends to challenges and future directions, emphasizing the need for incorporating factors, including discrepancy in scale, light illumination, electrolyte presence, and applied bias, into DFT calculations, to achieve a more comprehensive understanding of PC and PEC systems. In this perspective, it is aimed to provide a holistic view of the current state and potential advancements in photocatalyst and photoelectrode modeling, thereby guiding future research toward more effective and sustainable energy and chemical production processes in PC and PEC systems.</description>
      <author>Chi&#8208;Hui Lin, Jyoti Rohilla, Hsuan&#8208;Hung Kuo, Chun-yi Chen, Tso&#8208;Fu Mark Chang, Masato Sone, Pravin P. Ingole, Yu&#8208;Chieh Lo, Yung&#8208;Jung Hsu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/solr.202300948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrocatalytic activation of sulfate for sulfamethoxazole degradation and simultaneous H2 production by bifunctional N,P co-doped black-blue TiO2 nanotube array electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149828</link>
      <description>Shan Li, Guoquan Zhang, Dong Meng, Fenglin Yang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391931133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shan Li, Guoquan Zhang, Dong Meng, Fenglin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The NOMAD mini-apps: A suite of kernels from ab initio electronic structure codes enabling co-design in high-performance computing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.1</link>
      <description>Isidre Mas Magre, Ricardo Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a Cela Esp&#237;n, Julio Gutierrez Moreno, Open research Europe. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933077

                This article introduces a suite of mini-applications (mini-apps) designed to optimise computational kernels in ab initio electronic structure codes. The suite is developed from flagship applications participating in the NOMAD Center of Excellence, such as the ELPA eigensolver library and the GW implementations of the exciting, Abinit, and FHI-aims codes. The mini-apps were identified by targeting functions that significantly contribute to the total execution time in the parent applications. This strategic selection allows for concentrated optimisation efforts. The suite is designed for easy deployment on various High-Performance Computing (HPC) systems, supported by an integrated CMake build system for straightforward compilation and execution. The aim is to harness the capabilities of emerging (post)exascale systems, which necessitate concurrent hardware and software development &#8212; a concept known as co-design. The mini-app suite serves as a tool for profiling and benchmarking, providing insights that can guide both software optimisation and hardware design. Ultimately, these developments will enable more accurate and efficient simulations of novel materials, leveraging the full potential of exascale computing in material science research.</description>
      <author>Isidre Mas Magre, Ricardo Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a Cela Esp&#237;n, Julio Gutierrez Moreno</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kinisi: Bayesian analysis of mass transport from molecular dynamics simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.05984</link>
      <description>Andrew R. McCluskey, Alexander G. Squires, Josh W. Dunn, Samuel W. Coles, Benjamin J. Morgan, Journal of open source software. 9(94)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933289

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrew R. McCluskey, Alexander G. Squires, Josh W. Dunn, Samuel W. Coles, Benjamin J. Morgan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.05984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of single-atom alloy catalysts in electrochemical conversion of carbon dioxide: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119910</link>
      <description>Jingnan Wang, Kunpeng Zhao, Yi Ding, Yongan Yang, Xi Wu, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933654

                Atomic-scale understanding of C-C coupling in the electrocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable C2 chemicals remains elusive. Herein, we selected Group VIII and IB transition metals as active sites incorporated into the Cu(1 0 0) surface to construct single-atom alloy catalysts. The stability, selectivity, and activity of a series of catalysts were calculated using density functional theory. Fe, Co, Ni, Ru/Cu(1 0 0) exhibit the potential as candidates to generate C2 products and suppress the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The reaction proceeds through the reduction of CO2 to key intermediates *CO and *CHO, which undergoes C-C coupling to generate *CO-CHO, subsequently undergoing different protonation processes to yield diverse C2 products. The rate-determining step for Fe, Co, Ni, and Ru/Cu(1 0 0), is the hydrogenation of *CO, with a comparable energy barrier of 0.8 eV. Moreover, Fe and Co/Cu(1 0 0) favor the formation of C2H4 as the primary product, while Ni and Ru/Cu(1 0 0) predominantly produce CH3COOH.</description>
      <author>Jingnan Wang, Kunpeng Zhao, Yi Ding, Yongan Yang, Xi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methane sulfonic acid-assisted synthesis of g-C3N4/Ni2P/Ni foam: Efficient, stable and recyclable for photocatalytic nitrogen fixation under visible light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112276</link>
      <description>Xianqiang Gao, Bowen Zhang, Lulu Cao, Fei Liu, Hai Fan, Chuanjun Wang, Junjie Xu, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391940943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianqiang Gao, Bowen Zhang, Lulu Cao, Fei Liu, Hai Fan, Chuanjun Wang, Junjie Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Special Activity of Stone&#8211;Wales Defect Graphene for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction: A Comparison Study between the Charge-Neutral Model and the Constant Potential Model Calculated by Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08035</link>
      <description>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391942912

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Oxidation of the Intermetallic Compound PtAl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from Ab Initio Thermodynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06290</link>
      <description>Wei Xie, Chunhua Cai, Guangwen Zhou, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391945161

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Xie, Chunhua Cai, Guangwen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali Containing Layered Metal Oxides as Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300761</link>
      <description>Mario Falsaperna, Rosa Arrigo, Frank Marken, Simon J. Freakley, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391948002

                Abstract Improving the efficiency of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential to realise energy systems based on water electrolysis. Many catalysts have been developed for the OER to date, with iridium&#8208;based oxides being the most promising due to their relative stability towards corrosion in acidic electrolytes under oxidising potentials. In recent years, examples of catalysts adopting layered structures have been shown to have promising characteristics such as higher conductivity and higher electrochemically active surface area compared to highly crystalline metal oxides. Furthermore, such materials possess additional tuneable properties such as interlayer spacing, identity and concentration of the interlayer species, edge and interlayer active sites, and higher active surface area. Recent attention has focused on mono&#8208; and polymetallic lithium&#8208;containing layered materials, where the presence of interlayer lithium cations, in situ delithiation processes and combinations of transition metal oxides result in enhanced catalytic properties towards OER. This review aims to provide a summary of the recent developments of such layered materials, in which lithium or other alkali metal ions occupy interlayer sites in oxides.</description>
      <author>Mario Falsaperna, Rosa Arrigo, Frank Marken, Simon J. Freakley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst Selection over an Electrochemical Reductive Coupling Reaction toward Direct Electrosynthesis of Oxime from NO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; and Aldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14687</link>
      <description>Wei Chen, Yandong Wu, Yimin Jiang, Guangxing Yang, Yingying Li, Lei Xu, Ming Yang, Binbin Wu, Yuping Pan, Yanzhi Xu, Qinghua Liu, Chen Chen, Feng Peng, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391952084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Chen, Yandong Wu, Yimin Jiang, Guangxing Yang, Yingying Li, Lei Xu, Ming Yang, Binbin Wu, Yuping Pan, Yanzhi Xu, Qinghua Liu, Chen Chen, Feng Peng, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14687</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering &lt;scp&gt;Pt&#8208;Cu&lt;/scp&gt; diatomics electrocatalysts enables highly efficient urea synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18403</link>
      <description>Fei Lu, Jingnan Wang, Yuhang Gao, Yan Wang, Xi Wu, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391954090

                Abstract The rational design of novel heterogeneous urea&#8208;synthesis electrocatalysts (HUECs) poses an immense challenge due to their inherent complexity. Moreover, the ideal HUECs must also possess the ability to suppress two major competitive reactions: hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and N 2 reduction reaction (NRR). However, this daunting task can be made feasible with the use of heterogeneous diatomic catalysts that have been supported by unambiguous theoretical models. Herein, we report a design for an efficient platinum&#8208;copper diatomic electrocatalyst (Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 ) for urea production based on theoretical predictions. Through rational screening of 8 Pt&#8208;diatomics HUECs, we discovered that Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 can effectively suppress HER and NRR while promoting the adsorption of CO 2 and N 2 . Subsequently, we experimentally fabricated Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 which exhibited optimal urea electrosynthesis activity of 51.71 mol urea mol Pt+Cu &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 . Pt 1 &#8208;Cu 1 diatomics in Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 could synergistically encourage the activation of *CO 2 /*N 2 and crucial C&#8208;N coupling with an optimal energy barrier (0.25 eV).</description>
      <author>Fei Lu, Jingnan Wang, Yuhang Gao, Yan Wang, Xi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optoelectronic and transport properties of vacancy-ordered double-perovskite halides: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.024036</link>
      <description>Supriti Ghorui, Jiban Kangsabanik, M. Aslam, Aftab Alam, Physical review applied. 21(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391954370

                In the search for stable lead-free perovskites, vacancy-ordered double perovskites (VODPs), ${\mathrm{A}}_{2}{\mathrm{BX}}_{6}$, have emerged as a promising class of materials for solar harvesting owing to their nontoxicity, better stability, and unique optoelectronic properties. Recently, this class has been explored for a wide range of applications, such as photovoltaics, photodetectors, photocatalysis, and light-emitting diodes. Here, we present the stability and the key physical attributes of a few selected compounds in a systematic manner using state-of-the-art first-principles calculations. A careful structural and stability analysis via simulation of convex hulls and compositional phase diagrams for different structural prototypes discloses 14 stable compounds and one metastable compound in this class. Electronic structure calculations using hybrid functionals reveals that six compounds possess band gaps in the ideal visible region. These six compounds, namely ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Sn}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Pd}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Te}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Ti}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Pt}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, and ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Pd}\mathrm{Br}}_{6}$, show high optical absorption ($\ensuremath{\approx}{10}^{5}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{cm}}^{\ensuremath{-}1}$), giving rise to high spectroscopic limited maximum efficiency (15--23%) in the thin-film thickness range. Close inspection of the transport properties reveals polar optical phonon scattering to be the dominant mechanism limiting overall mobility. Further analysis of the polaron excitations discloses the possibility of large polaron formation at low to moderate defect concentrations. At high defect concentrations, ionized impurity scattering takes over. Such analysis can be extremely useful for choosing the optimal growth conditions for a given material intended to be used for a desired application. Additionally, a few selected compounds show moderate to high electron mobility values ($\ensuremath{\sim}13--63\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{cm}}^{2}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{V}}^{\ensuremath{-}1}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{s}}^{\ensuremath{-}1}$) at room temperature. Overall, the present study paves an important path to help design VODPs as lead-free potential candidates for future optoelectronic applications.</description>
      <author>Supriti Ghorui, Jiban Kangsabanik, M. Aslam, Aftab Alam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.024036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into the Selective Electrocatalytic Reduction of NO to NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; on a Two-Dimensional Cu-Benzylthiol Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Nanostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05958</link>
      <description>Hao Yin, Minghao Gong, Pengbo Lyu, Ran Wang, Lizhong Sun, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391956639

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Yin, Minghao Gong, Pengbo Lyu, Ran Wang, Lizhong Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Fe and Co binary single atoms based air cathodes for high performance and ultra-stable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103286</link>
      <description>Yu-Chieh Ting, Chih&#8208;Chieh Cheng, Shin&#8208;Hong Lin, Ting Lin, Po&#8208;Wei Chen, F.Y. Yen, Shuwen Chang, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu, Energy Storage Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391957760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Chieh Ting, Chih&#8208;Chieh Cheng, Shin&#8208;Hong Lin, Ting Lin, Po&#8208;Wei Chen, F.Y. Yen, Shuwen Chang, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Positivity preserving density matrix minimization at finite temperatures via square root</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0189864</link>
      <description>Jacob M. Leamer, William Dawson, Denys I. Bondar, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391960448

                We present a Wave Operator Minimization (WOM) method for calculating the Fermi&#8211;Dirac density matrix for electronic structure problems at finite temperature while preserving physicality by construction using the wave operator, i.e., the square root of the density matrix. WOM models cooling a state initially at infinite temperature down to the desired finite temperature. We consider both the grand canonical (constant chemical potential) and canonical (constant number of electrons) ensembles. Additionally, we show that the number of steps required for convergence is independent of the number of atoms in the system. We hope that the discussion and results presented in this article reinvigorate interest in density matrix minimization methods.</description>
      <author>Jacob M. Leamer, William Dawson, Denys I. Bondar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0189864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Performance Iridium&#8211;Molybdenum Oxide Electrocatalysts for Water Oxidation in Acid: Bayesian Optimization Discovery and Experimental Testing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13491</link>
      <description>Jacques A. Esterhuizen, Aarti Mathur, Bryan R. Goldsmith, Suljo Linic, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391963993

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jacques A. Esterhuizen, Aarti Mathur, Bryan R. Goldsmith, Suljo Linic</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed Stochastic-Deterministic Approach for Many-Body Perturbation Theory Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.132.086401</link>
      <description>Aaron R. Altman, Smriti K. Kundu, Felipe H. da Jornada, Physical Review Letters. 132(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391972280

                We present an approach for $GW$ calculations of quasiparticle energies with quasiquadratic scaling by approximating high-energy contributions to the Green's function in its Lehmann representation with effective stochastic vectors. The method is easy to implement without altering the $GW$ code, converges rapidly with stochastic parameters, and treats systems of various dimensionality and screening response. Our calculations on a 5.75\ifmmode^\circ\else\textdegree\fi{} twisted ${\mathrm{MoS}}_{2}$ bilayer show how large-scale $GW$ methods include geometry relaxations and electronic correlations on an equal basis in structurally nontrivial materials.</description>
      <author>Aaron R. Altman, Smriti K. Kundu, Felipe H. da Jornada</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.132.086401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni-doping effects on formation and migration of oxygen vacancies in SrFe&lt;sub&gt;1&#8722;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&lt;i&gt;&#948;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; oxygen carriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ra08321g</link>
      <description>Tian Tian Jia, Yifei Hao, Hua Hao, Zhi Zhang, RSC Advances. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391974220

                Ni is a promising B-site doping element capable of improving the oxygen carrier performance of SrFeO 3 perovskite.</description>
      <author>Tian Tian Jia, Yifei Hao, Hua Hao, Zhi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ra08321g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated analysis of surface facets: the example of cesium telluride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01224-7</link>
      <description>Holger-Dietrich Sa&#223;nick, Caterina Cocchi, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391982702

                Abstract High-throughput screening combined with ab initio calculations is a powerful tool to explore technologically relevant materials characterized by complex configurational spaces. Despite the impressive developments achieved in this field in the last few years, most studies still focus on bulk materials, although the relevant processes for energy conversion, production, and storage occur on surfaces. Herein, we present an automatized computational scheme that is capable of calculating surface properties in inorganic crystals from first principles in a high-throughput fashion. After introducing the method and its implementation, we showcase its applicability, focusing on four polymorphs of Cs 2 Te, an established photocathode material for particle accelerators, considering slabs with low Miller indices and different terminations. This analysis gives insight into how the surface composition, accessible through the proposed high-throughput screening method, impacts the electronic properties and, ultimately, the photoemission performance. The developed scheme offers new opportunities for automated computational studies beyond bulk materials.</description>
      <author>Holger-Dietrich Sa&#223;nick, Caterina Cocchi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01224-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data&#8208;Driven Screening of Pivotal Subunits in Edge&#8208;Anchored Single Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400107</link>
      <description>Qitong Ye, Xiao Su Yi, Cai&#8208;Zhuang Wang, Tao Zhang, Yipu Liu, Shiwei Lin, Hong Jin Fan, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391984271

                Abstract Oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are key reactions in diverse energy conversion devices, highlighting the importance of efficient catalysts. Edge&#8208;anchored single atom catalysts (E&#8208;SACs) emerge as a special class of atomic structure, but the detailed configuration and its correlation with catalytic activity remain little explored. Herein, a total of 78 E&#8208;SACs (E&#8208;TM&#8208;N x &#8208;C) have been constructed based on 26 transition metal (TM) species with three coordination patterns. Using structural stability and ORR/OER catalytic activity as the evaluation criteria, a few catalytic structures comparable to Pt (111) for ORR and IrO 2 (110) for OER are screened based on high&#8208;throughput calculations. The screening results unveil that the E&#8208;Rh&#8208;N 4 &#8208;C configuration exhibits most efficient bifunctional activity for both ORR and OER with an overpotential of 0.38 and 0.61 V, respectively. Electronic structure analysis confirms the distinctive edge effects on the electronic properties of TM and N species, and the feature importance derived from machine learning illustrates the efficacy of E&#8208;TM&#8208;N x subunit configuration in determining the catalytic activity of E&#8208;SACs. Finally, the trained Gradient Boosting Regression (GBR) model exhibits acceptable accuracy in predicting the OH intermediates adsorption strength for E&#8208;SACs, thereby paving the way for expanding catalytic structures based on E&#8208;SACs.</description>
      <author>Qitong Ye, Xiao Su Yi, Cai&#8208;Zhuang Wang, Tao Zhang, Yipu Liu, Shiwei Lin, Hong Jin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning guides the discovery of high-performance HEA catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.1004118</link>
      <description>J. Wang, Min Wei, Junyu Zhang, IntechOpen eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391995369

                High performance catalysts are crucial to generating clean fuels, reducing the impact of global warming, and providing solutions to environmental pollution. Improved processes for catalyst design and a better understanding of catalytic processes are key for improving the effectiveness and activities. HEAs typically have at least four principal elements, this atomic structure gives them unique properties that have applications and excellent performance in a variety of fields including catalysis. The complexity of HEAs makes challenge for computational researchers, providing promising opportunities for the application of machine learning. Recent advances in data science have great potential to accelerate catalyst research, particularly the rapid exploration of large materials chemistry spaces through machine learning. Here a comprehensive and critical review of machine learning techniques used in HEA catalysis research is provided. Sources of HEA catalyst data and current approaches to represent these materials by mathematical features are described, the most commonly used machine learning methods summarized, and the quality and utility of catalyst models evaluated. Illustrations of how machine learning models are applied to novel HEA catalysts discovery and used to reveal catalytic reaction mechanisms are provided.</description>
      <author>J. Wang, Min Wei, Junyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.1004118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probe the Dynamic Adsorption and Phase Transition of Underpotential Deposition Processes at Electrode&#8211;Electrolyte Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03899</link>
      <description>Kuo-Hao Chen, Fatemeh Fathi, Tristan Maxson, Mezbah Hossain, Emil F. Khisamutdinov, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, Xiangqun Zeng, Zhihai Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392044078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kuo-Hao Chen, Fatemeh Fathi, Tristan Maxson, Mezbah Hossain, Emil F. Khisamutdinov, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, Xiangqun Zeng, Zhihai Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supervised AI and Deep Neural Networks to Evaluate High-Entropy Alloys as Reduction Catalysts in Aqueous Environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05017</link>
      <description>Rafael B. Araujo, Tomas Edvinsson, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392044082

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rafael B. Araujo, Tomas Edvinsson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complementary probes for the electrochemical interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41570-024-00575-5</link>
      <description>Ernest Pastor, Zan Lian, Lu Xia, David &#201;cija, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, Sara Barja, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jordi Arbiol, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer, Nature Reviews Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392044291

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ernest Pastor, Zan Lian, Lu Xia, David &#201;cija, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, Sara Barja, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jordi Arbiol, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41570-024-00575-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local-environment-guided selection of atomic structures for the development of machine-learning potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0187892</link>
      <description>Renzhe Li, Chuan Zhou, Amankumar Singh, Yong Pei, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392014929

                Machine learning potentials (MLPs) have attracted significant attention in computational chemistry and materials science due to their high accuracy and computational efficiency. The proper selection of atomic structures is crucial for developing reliable MLPs. Insufficient or redundant atomic structures can impede the training process and potentially result in a poor quality MLP. Here, we propose a local-environment-guided screening algorithm for efficient dataset selection in MLP development. The algorithm utilizes a local environment bank to store unique local environments of atoms. The dissimilarity between a particular local environment and those stored in the bank is evaluated using the Euclidean distance. A new structure is selected only if its local environment is significantly different from those already present in the bank. Consequently, the bank is then updated with all the new local environments found in the selected structure. To demonstrate the effectiveness of our algorithm, we applied it to select structures for a Ge system and a Pd13H2 particle system. The algorithm reduced the training data size by around 80% for both without compromising the performance of the MLP models. We verified that the results were independent of the selection and ordering of the initial structures. We also compared the performance of our method with the farthest point sampling algorithm, and the results show that our algorithm is superior in both robustness and computational efficiency. Furthermore, the generated local environment bank can be continuously updated and can potentially serve as a growing database of feature local environments, aiding in efficient dataset maintenance for constructing accurate MLPs.</description>
      <author>Renzhe Li, Chuan Zhou, Amankumar Singh, Yong Pei, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0187892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Effects of Varying the Ti Concentration on the Mechanical Properties of Cu&#8211;Ti Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c07561</link>
      <description>Vasileios Fotopoulos, Corey S. O&#8217;Hern, Mark D. Shattuck, Alexander L. Shluger, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933315

                The mechanical properties of CuTi alloys have been characterized extensively through experimental studies. However, a detailed understanding of why the strength of Cu increases after a small fraction of Ti atoms are added to the alloy is still missing. In this work, we address this question using density functional theory (DFT) and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations with the modified embedded atom method (MEAM) interatomic potentials. First, we performed calculations of the uniaxial tension deformations of small bicrystalline Cu cells using DFT static simulations. We then carried out uniaxial tension deformations on much larger bicrystalline and polycrystalline Cu cells by using MEAM MD simulations. In bicrystalline Cu, the inclusion of Ti increases the grain boundary separation energy and the maximum tensile stress. The DFT calculations demonstrate that the increase in the tensile stress can be attributed to an increase in the local charge density arising from Ti. MEAM simulations in larger bicrystalline systems have shown that increasing the Ti concentration decreases the density of the stacking faults. This observation is enhanced in polycrystalline Cu, where the addition of Ti atoms, even at concentrations as low as 1.5 atomic (at.) %, increases the yield strength and elastic modulus of the material compared to pure Cu. Under uniaxial tensile loading, the addition of small amounts of Ti hinders the formation of partial Shockley dislocations in the grain boundaries of Cu, leading to a reduced level of local deformation. These results shed light on the role of Ti in determining the mechanical properties of polycrystalline Cu and enable the engineering of grain boundaries and the inclusion of Ti to improve degradation resistance.</description>
      <author>Vasileios Fotopoulos, Corey S. O&#8217;Hern, Mark D. Shattuck, Alexander L. Shluger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c07561</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
