<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:42:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Advantages of Bimetallic Electrocatalysts for Cathodes in a Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-52239-0_3</link>
      <description>Angelina Pavlets, Ekaterina Kozhokar, Yana Astravukh, Ilya Pankov, Alexey S. Nikulin, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Springer Proceedings in Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391425240

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Angelina Pavlets, Ekaterina Kozhokar, Yana Astravukh, Ilya Pankov, Alexey S. Nikulin, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-52239-0_3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study of Various Approaches to the Synthesis of PtCo/C Electrocatalysts for Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-52239-0_2</link>
      <description>E. R. Beskopylny, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1044;. &#1050;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1091;&#1101;&#1088;, V. S. Menshchikov, Springer Proceedings in Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391425411

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. R. Beskopylny, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1044;. &#1050;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1091;&#1101;&#1088;, V. S. Menshchikov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-52239-0_2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative dual-active sites in interfacially engineered interfaces for high-performance S-scheme solar-driven CO2 photoreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.168</link>
      <description>Baoji Miao, Yange Cao, Imran Khan, Qiuling Chen, Salman Ali Khan, Amir Zada, Muhammad Shahyan, Sharafat Ali, Rizwan Ullah, Jinbo Bai, Muhammad Rizwan, Abdullah M. S. Alhuthali, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391427700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baoji Miao, Yange Cao, Imran Khan, Qiuling Chen, Salman Ali Khan, Amir Zada, Muhammad Shahyan, Sharafat Ali, Rizwan Ullah, Jinbo Bai, Muhammad Rizwan, Abdullah M. S. Alhuthali</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated energy storage and CO2 conversion using an aqueous battery with tamed asymmetric reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44283-y</link>
      <description>Yumei Liu, Yun An, Jiexin Zhu, Lujun Zhu, Xiaomei Li, Peng Gao, Guanjie He, Quanquan Pang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391428670

                Abstract Developing a CO 2 -utilization and energy-storage integrated system possesses great advantages for carbon- and energy-intensive industries. Efforts have been made to developing the Zn-CO 2 batteries, but access to long cycling life and low charging voltage remains a grand challenge. Here we unambiguously show such inefficiencies originate from the high-barrier oxygen evolution reaction on charge, and by recharging the battery via oxidation of reducing molecules, Faradaic efficiency-enhanced CO 2 reduction and low-overpotential battery regeneration can be simultaneously achieved. Showcased by using hydrazine oxidation, our battery demonstrates a long life over 1000 hours with a charging voltage as low as 1.2 V. The low charging voltage and formation of gaseous product upon hydrazine oxidation are the key to stabilize the catalyst over cycling. Our findings suggest that by fundamentally taming the asymmetric reactions, aqueous batteries are viable tools to achieve integrated energy storage and CO 2 conversion that is economical, highly energy efficient, and scalable.</description>
      <author>Yumei Liu, Yun An, Jiexin Zhu, Lujun Zhu, Xiaomei Li, Peng Gao, Guanjie He, Quanquan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44283-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable synthesis of Au-rich core/PtNi rich shell nanoparticles with strain effect for enhanced hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133353</link>
      <description>Chunling Qin, Chao Wang, Peng Fei Li, Chuanjin Huang, Hassanien Gomaa, Cuihua An, Qibo Deng, Ning Hu, Colloids and Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391430357

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunling Qin, Chao Wang, Peng Fei Li, Chuanjin Huang, Hassanien Gomaa, Cuihua An, Qibo Deng, Ning Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous nitrogen-doped carbon nanocages decorated with bimetallic iron/cobalt sites as superior oxygen catalysts for liquid and all-solid-state Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.110660</link>
      <description>Xiaobing Ren, Pengfei Zhang, Xinxin Tang, He&#8208;Gen Zheng, Zhongmin Wan, Journal of Energy Storage. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391434426

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaobing Ren, Pengfei Zhang, Xinxin Tang, He&#8208;Gen Zheng, Zhongmin Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.110660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Development and Future Frontiers of Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Neutral Media and Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314282</link>
      <description>Truong&#8208;Giang Vo, Jiajian Gao, Yan Liu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391437432

                Abstract The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in neutral media is of great importance due to its potential to optimize energy generation and storage application. With the increasing urgency for sustainable and efficient energy solutions, comprehensively understanding and enhancing ORR performance in such media have become crucial. This review aims to shed light on this critical yet challenging area. This review encapsulates the fundamental principle of ORR and the latest breakthrough in the field of electrocatalysts, with a distinct focus on innovative synthesis strategies for creating novel, efficient, and robust electrocatalysts. A succinct evaluation of the strengths, limitations, performance, and reaction mechanism is presented. The essential findings are analyzed and their implications for future research directions. Finally, an outlook on current advances, challenges, and future research recommendations is provided. This review serves as a stepping&#8208;stone toward harnessing the underutilizing energy potential within the extensive aquatic environment.</description>
      <author>Truong&#8208;Giang Vo, Jiajian Gao, Yan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chestnut-like Molybdenum-Doped Nickel Cobaltite Spinel Oxide Nanoparticles Grown on Ni Foam as the Electrocatalyst for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05156</link>
      <description>Refah Saad Alkhaldi, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Mohamed Jaffer Sadiq Mohamed, M.A. Almessiere, A. Baykal, S. &#199;al&#305;&#351;kan, Y. Slimani, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391447078

                The 3D NiMoxCo2&#8211;xO4 (x &#8804; 0.06) chestnut-like spinel oxide nanoparticles (CNSPs) grown on Ni foam were effectively prepared hydrothermally. The formation of Ni&#8211;Co CNSPs was confirmed by the XRD powder pattern, which exhibited a pure cubic spinel oxide structure without undesired phases. All ratios revealed a broadened peak representing a small crystal size (12.8&#8211;17.5 nm) range. The chestnut-like CNSPs were presented by FE-SEM, SEM, TEM, and HR-TEM analysis. The chemical composition of the products was confirmed by EDX. The 3D NiMoxCo2&#8211;xO4 (x = 0.04) CNSP electrocatalyst exhibited hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity as evidenced by 0.224 V overpotential, Tafel slope 61.9 mV/dec, and high stability for 36 h of chronopotentiometry techniques. The surface and electrochemical characterization revealed that 4.0% Mo-doped exhibits improved HER activity due to significantly higher electrochemical surface area and accelerated charge-transfer kinetics at the semiconductor electrolyte interface. Density functional theory is employed to investigate the impact of Mo dopants on the HER performance. This study shows how both hydrogen and water molecules adhere to the surface of Mo-doped NiCo2O4 slab structures. The findings indicate that introducing Mo dopants leads to an augmentation of chemical activity through water adsorption, resulting in an enhanced electrocatalytic process and improved HER activity up to a specific Mo concentration, and their impact on spin-dependent electronic structure characteristics is revealed by the density of states spectra. This work not only gives insights into low-metal-cost materials for efficient and durable HER electrocatalysts, but it also provides a successful showcase model catalyst for in-depth mechanistic insights into electrochemical HER processes and their industrial applications in the future.</description>
      <author>Refah Saad Alkhaldi, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Mohamed Jaffer Sadiq Mohamed, M.A. Almessiere, A. Baykal, S. &#199;al&#305;&#351;kan, Y. Slimani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Potentials with the Iterative Boltzmann Inversion: Training to Experiment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01051</link>
      <description>Sakib Matin, Alice Allen, Justin S. Smith, Nicholas Lubbers, Ryan B. Jadrich, Richard A. Messerly, Benjamin Nebgen, Ying Wai Li, Sergei Tretiak, Kipton Barros, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391464120

                Methodologies for training machine learning potentials (MLPs) with quantum-mechanical simulation data have recently seen tremendous progress. Experimental data have a very different character than simulated data, and most MLP training procedures cannot be easily adapted to incorporate both types of data into the training process. We investigate a training procedure based on iterative Boltzmann inversion that produces a pair potential correction to an existing MLP using equilibrium radial distribution function data. By applying these corrections to an MLP for pure aluminum based on density functional theory, we observe that the resulting model largely addresses previous overstructuring in the melt phase. Interestingly, the corrected MLP also exhibits improved performance in predicting experimental diffusion constants, which are not included in the training procedure. The presented method does not require autodifferentiating through a molecular dynamics solver and does not make assumptions about the MLP architecture. Our results suggest a practical framework for incorporating experimental data into machine learning models to improve the accuracy of molecular dynamics simulations.</description>
      <author>Sakib Matin, Alice Allen, Justin S. Smith, Nicholas Lubbers, Ryan B. Jadrich, Richard A. Messerly, Benjamin Nebgen, Ying Wai Li, Sergei Tretiak, Kipton Barros</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Interplay of the Br&#248;nsted Acidity of Catalyst Ancillary Groups and the Solution Components in Iron-porphyrin-Mediated Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10127</link>
      <description>Ana Sonea, Nicholas R. Crudo, Jeffrey J. Warren, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391464343

                The rapid and efficient conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) to carbon monoxide (CO) is an ongoing challenge. Catalysts based on iron-porphyrin cores have emerged as excellent electrochemical mediators of the two proton + two electron reduction of CO2 to CO, and many of the design features that promote function are known. Of those design features, the incorporation of Br&#248;nsted acids in the second coordination sphere of the iron ion has a significant impact on catalyst turnover kinetics. The Br&#248;nsted acids are often in the form of hydroxyphenyl groups. Herein, we explore how the acidity of an ancillary 2-hydroxyphenyl group affects the performance of CO2 reduction electrocatalysts. A series of meso-5,10,15,20-tetraaryl porphyrins were prepared where only the functional group at the 5-meso position has an ionizable proton. A series of cyclic voltammetry (CV) experiments reveal that the complex with &#8722;OMe positioned para to the ionizable &#8722;OH shows the largest CO2 reduction rate constants in acetonitrile solvent. This is the least acidic &#8722;OH of the compounds surveyed. The turnover frequency of the &#8722;OMe derivative can be further improved with the addition of 4-trifluoromethylphenol to the solution. In contrast, the iron-porphyrin complex with &#8722;CF3 positioned opposite the ionizable &#8722;OH shows the smallest CO2 reduction rate constants, and its turnover frequency is less enhanced with the addition of phenols to the reaction solutions. The origin of this effect is rationalized based on kinetic isotope effect experiments and density functional calculations. We conclude that catalysts with weaker internal acids coupled with stronger external acid additives provide superior CO2 reduction kinetics.</description>
      <author>Ana Sonea, Nicholas R. Crudo, Jeffrey J. Warren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening of Suitable Adatom to Enhance CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction on Noble-Metal Based Dual-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c05794</link>
      <description>Sourav Ghoshal, Pranab Sarkar, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391469208

                In this work, we have employed first-principles density functional theory (DFT) to account for the comparative efficiency of TiO2 and g-CN supported Ru2 and Rh2 dual-atom catalysts (DACs) for electrochemical CO2 reduction reactions (CO2RRs). Based on DFT calculations, g-CN supported DACs were found to have superior stability and CO2 reduction activity than that of TiO2 supported DACs. However, Ru2@g-CN and Rh2@g-CN double atom catalysts suffer from poor selectivity, as the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is likely to occur more favorably than that of CO2RR. Here, we have revealed that the replacement of one noble metal by an earth-abundant transition metal can boost the selectivity of CO2RRs, while inhibiting the HER. In search of a highly selective and low-cost noble-metal based CO2 reduction catalyst, we have designed a series of g-CN supported heteronuclear MRu (M = Sc&#8211;Zn) dimers and performed a systematic computational screening to identify a suitable adatom (M), which drastically improves the selectivity. Based on the evaluation of stability, activity, and selectivity, VRu@g-CN is finally identified as the best candidate, with the lowest limiting potential of &#8722;0.11 V and a high theoretical Faradaic efficiency of 99.57%.</description>
      <author>Sourav Ghoshal, Pranab Sarkar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c05794</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double&#8208;Walled Tubular Heusler&#8208;Type Platinum&#8211;Ruthenium Phosphide as All&#8208;pH Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Catalyst Outperforming Platinum and Ruthenium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304269</link>
      <description>Yong-Ju Hong, Seong Chan Cho, S.H. Kim, Haneul Jin, Jae Hun Seol, Tae Kyung Lee, Jungho Ryu, Gracita M. Tomboc, Taekyung Kim, Hionsuck Baik, Changhyeok Choi, Jinhyoung Jo, Sangyeon Jeong, Eunsoo Lee, Yousung Jung, Docheon Ahn, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Sung Jong Yoo, Sang Uck Lee, Kwangyeol Lee, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391476925

                Abstract Nanostructured ionic compounds have driven major technological advancements in displays, photovoltaics, and catalysis. Current research focuses on refining the chemical composition of such compounds. In this study, a strategy for creating stoichiometrically well&#8208;defined nanoscale multiple&#8208;cation systems, where the atomically precise structure maximizes the synergistic cooperation between cations at the atomic scale is reported. The unprecedented construction of Heusler&#8208;type PtRuP 2 double&#8208;walled nanotubes through sequential anion/cation exchange reactions is demonstrated. The PtRuP 2 catalyst exhibits record&#8208;high catalytic performance and durability for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in alkaline electrolytes and anion&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolyzers. The investigations highlight the crucial role of Pt/Ru dual centers, providing multiple active sites that accelerate the HER kinetics within a single phosphide material, in the sequential operation of H 2 O activation/dissociation at Ru and H 2 production at adjacent Pt sites. These findings open new avenues for optimizing ionic compound&#8208;based HER electrocatalysts, offering platinum&#8208;metal alternatives in acidic and alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Yong-Ju Hong, Seong Chan Cho, S.H. Kim, Haneul Jin, Jae Hun Seol, Tae Kyung Lee, Jungho Ryu, Gracita M. Tomboc, Taekyung Kim, Hionsuck Baik, Changhyeok Choi, Jinhyoung Jo, Sangyeon Jeong, Eunsoo Lee, Yousung Jung, Docheon Ahn, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Sung Jong Yoo, Sang Uck Lee, Kwangyeol Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into Selectivity Differences of Glycerol Electro-Oxidation on Pt(111) and Ag(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05551</link>
      <description>Zhongjie Meng, David Tran, Johan Hjelm, Henrik H. Kristoffersen, Jan Rossmeisl, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391484173

                Electro-oxidation is a way to utilize glycerol, a byproduct of biodiesel production, to produce fuels and feedstock chemicals for the chemical industry. A significant challenge is to get products with high selectivity, so it is desirable to understand the glycerol oxidation mechanisms in further detail. Using density functional theory calculations, we investigated possible glycerol oxidation intermediates on Pt(111) and Ag(111). We find that the different adsorption preferences of the intermediates on Pt (adsorption via carbon atoms) and Ag (adsorption via oxygen atoms) lead to different preferred reaction pathways, resulting in different products. The reaction pathways on both surfaces involve glyceraldehyde as a key intermediate; however, upon further oxidation, Pt(111) preferentially produces glyceric acid (CH2OH&#8211;CHOH&#8211;COOH), while on Ag(111) C&#8211;C bonds are broken, which leads to the production of glycolaldehyde and formic acid (CH2OH&#8211;CHO and HCOOH). These predictions agree well with the experimental outcome of the electro-oxidation of glycerol on Pt and Ag surfaces. Our study therefore provides useful insights for optimizing the selectivity of glycerol oxidation and improving the utilization of glycerol.</description>
      <author>Zhongjie Meng, David Tran, Johan Hjelm, Henrik H. Kristoffersen, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-Edge Decoration and Clustering of Pt Atoms on a Cu(211) Stepped Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c04776</link>
      <description>Amin Mohammadpour, Sarp Kaya, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391484211

                The atomic manipulation of the low-coordination sites of metal catalysts can give rise to activity enhancement; however, it is rather challenging to locally probe the dynamic changes and activities of these sites. Herein, step-edge/terrace site decoration and site exchange of Pt atoms with a stepped Cu(211) surface were investigated by a combination of infrared reflection absorption spectroscopy (IRRAS) and temperature-programmed desorption (TPD) of carbon monoxide (CO). For a low coverage of Pt, step decoration and site exchange with Cu were found to be two pathways to isolate Pt as single atoms. CO preferentially adsorbs near the Cu step sites on the lower terrace, and the binding energies of CO show strong Pt coverage dependence. The presence of Pt on terrace and step sites modifies the binding energy of CO absorbed on Cu in the proximity. Increased Pt&#8211;Pt lateral coordination changes the site preference; however, the reduced binding energy of CO to Pt is attributed to heteroatom bond formation rather than the strain induced by the lattice mismatch.</description>
      <author>Amin Mohammadpour, Sarp Kaya</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c04776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8211;Support Interaction between Titanium Oxynitride and Pt Nanoparticles Enables Efficient Low-Pt-Loaded High-Performance Electrodes at Relevant Oxygen Reduction Reaction Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03883</link>
      <description>Armin Hrnji&#263;, Ana Rebeka Kam&#353;ek, Lazar Bijeli&#263;, Anja Lon&#269;ar, Nik Maselj, Milutin Smiljani&#263;, Jan Trputec, Nikolay Vovk, Luka Pavko, Francisco Ruiz-Zepeda, Marjan Bele, Primo&#382; Jovanovi&#269;, Nejc Hodnik, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391484257

                In the present work, we report on a synergistic relationship between platinum nanoparticles and a titanium oxynitride support (TiOxNy/C) in the context of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysis. As demonstrated herein, this composite configuration results in significantly improved electrocatalytic activity toward the ORR relative to platinum dispersed on carbon support (Pt/C) at high overpotentials. Specifically, the ORR performance was assessed under an elevated mass transport regime using the modified floating electrode configuration, which enabled us to pursue the reaction closer to PEMFC-relevant current densities. A comprehensive investigation attributes the ORR performance increase to a strong interaction between platinum and the TiOxNy/C support. In particular, according to the generated strain maps obtained via scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM), the Pt-TiOxNy/C analogue exhibits a more localized strain in Pt nanoparticles in comparison to that in the Pt/C sample. The altered Pt structure could explain the measured ORR activity trend via the d-band theory, which lowers the platinum surface coverage with ORR intermediates. In terms of the Pt particle size effect, our observation presents an anomaly as the Pt-TiOxNy/C analogue, despite having almost two times smaller nanoparticles (2.9 nm) compared to the Pt/C benchmark (4.8 nm), manifests higher specific activity. This provides a promising strategy to further lower the Pt loading and increase the ECSA without sacrificing the catalytic activity under fuel cell-relevant potentials. Apart from the ORR, the platinum-TiOxNy/C interaction is of a sufficient magnitude not to follow the typical particle size effect also in the context of other reactions such as CO stripping, hydrogen oxidation reaction, and water discharge. The trend for the latter is ascribed to the lower oxophilicity of Pt-based on electrochemical surface coverage analysis. Namely, a lower surface coverage with oxygenated species is found for the Pt-TiOxNy/C analogue. Further insights were provided by performing a detailed STEM characterization via the identical location mode (IL-STEM) in particular, via 4DSTEM acquisition. This disclosed that Pt particles are partially encapsulated within a thin layer of TiOxNy origin.</description>
      <author>Armin Hrnji&#263;, Ana Rebeka Kam&#353;ek, Lazar Bijeli&#263;, Anja Lon&#269;ar, Nik Maselj, Milutin Smiljani&#263;, Jan Trputec, Nikolay Vovk, Luka Pavko, Francisco Ruiz-Zepeda, Marjan Bele, Primo&#382; Jovanovi&#269;, Nejc Hodnik</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c03883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Metal-Ion-Doped Carbon Nitrides for Photocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05961</link>
      <description>Shanping Liu, Valentin Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Dong Fan, Peixiang Lu, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Guillaume Maurin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391486029

                Poly(heptazine imides) (PHIs) have emerged as prominent layered carbon nitride-based materials with potential oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalytic activity owing to their strong VIS light absorption, long excited-state lifetimes, high surface-to-volume ratios, and the possibility of tuning their properties via hosting different metal ions in their pores. A series of metal-ion-doped PHI-M (M = K+, Rb+, Mg2+, Zn2+, Mn2+, and Co2+) were first systematically explored using density functional theory calculations. These simulations led an in-depth understanding of the microscopic OER mechanism in these systems and identified PHI-Co2+ as the best OER catalyst of this family of PHIs, whereas PHI-Mn2+ can be an alternative promising OER catalyst. This level of performance was attributed to a thermodynamically favorable formation of the reaction intermediates as well as its red-shifted absorption in the VIS region involving the population of long-lived states, as revealed by time-dependent density functional theory calculations. We further demonstrated that the electronic properties of the *OH intermediates (Bader population, crystal orbital Hamilton population analysis, and adsorption energies) are reliable descriptors to anticipate the OER activity of this family of PHIs. This rational analysis paved the way toward the prediction of the OER performance of another PHI-M derivative, i.e., PHI-Fe2+. The computationally explored PHI-Fe2+, PHI-Mn2+, and PHI-Co2+ systems were then synthesized alongside PHI-K+, and their photocatalytic OER activities were assessed. These experimental findings confirmed the best photocatalytic OER performance for PHI-Co2+ with an oxygen production of 31.2 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1 that is 60 times higher than the pristine g-C3N4 (0.5 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1), whereas PHI-Fe2+ and PHI-Mn2+ are seen as alternative OER catalysts with attractive oxygen production of 11.20 and 4.69 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1, respectively. Decisively, this joint experimental&#8211;computational study reveals PHI-Co2+ to be among the best of the OER catalysts so far reported in the literature including some perovskites.</description>
      <author>Shanping Liu, Valentin Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Dong Fan, Peixiang Lu, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Guillaume Maurin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Approach for Hydrogen Technology: Fundamental Concepts and Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-49108-5_10</link>
      <description>Victor M&#225;rquez, Eric Chin Hong Ng, Daniel Torres, Carlos Borr&#225;s, B.R. Scharifker, Franco M. Cabrerizo, Lorean Madriz, Ronald Vargas, Advances in material research and technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488222

                This chapter presents aspects related to the electrochemical approach to hydrogenHydrogen technologies, considering key concepts that drive both the thermodynamicThermodynamic and kineticKinetic phenomena of the redoxRedox processes involved. Strategies to improve surface processes on various electrode materialsElectrode material are considered. The fundamental approach to the development of applied technologies illustrates the impact on the environmentEnvironment and energyEnergy, as well as the role of related physicochemicalPhysicochemical processes.</description>
      <author>Victor M&#225;rquez, Eric Chin Hong Ng, Daniel Torres, Carlos Borr&#225;s, B.R. Scharifker, Franco M. Cabrerizo, Lorean Madriz, Ronald Vargas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-49108-5_10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noble-Metal-Free Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Overall Water Splitting in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-49108-5_9</link>
      <description>Subhasis Shit, Tapas Kuila, Suneel Kumar Srivastava, Advances in material research and technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488228

                The ever-growing energy crisisEnergy crisis and environmental pollutionEnvironmental pollution motivated scientific researchers to develop a green energyEnergy economy. Hydrogen generationHydrogen generation through electrochemical water splittingWater splitting has shown immense potentiality to be an important energy conversionEnergy conversion technology towards the said goal. The electrochemical water splittingWater splitting consists of two half-cell reactionsHalf-cell reactions: hydrogen evolutionHydrogen evolution reactionReaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER)Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER). The overall water splittingWater splitting is sluggish as both of these half-cell reactionsHalf-cell reactions involve multiple protonProton and electron transferElectron transfer steps. Theoretical as well as experimental results have revealed that the noble-metal-based electrocatalystsNoble-metal-based electrocatalysts (such as Pt and RuO2RuO) possess superior electrocatalytic activityElectrocatalytic activity toward water splittingWater splitting. However, these materials lack commercial-scale applicability due to their high price and lower abundanceAbundance. Recently, numerous investigations have been conducted to develop cheap and efficient noble-metal-freeNoble-metal-free electrocatalystsElectrocatalyst. Pure waterWater is a poor conductor of electricityElectricity and thus an electrolyteElectrolyte is added to facilitate the overall water-splittingWater splitting process. The efficiencyEfficiency and costCost-effectiveness of water electrolysisWater electrolysis are higher in an alkaline mediumAlkaline medium if all the technical aspects related to it are considered together. An electrocatalyst with sufficient bifunctional activityBifunctional activity towards both HERHydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) and OEROxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) in the same operational condition simplifies the electrolyzerElectrolyzer optimization process and consequently, higher efficiencyEfficiency in full water splittingWater splitting is achieved. So, a cheap and efficient bifunctional noble-metal-freeNoble-metal-free electrocatalystElectrocatalyst for water splittingWater splitting in an alkaline mediumAlkaline medium is highly desirable. BoridesBoride, carbidesCarbide, pnictidesPnictides, and chalcogenidesChalcogenide of transition metalsTransition metal like Fe, Co, Ni, etc. show significant promise in that context. Few transition metalTransition metal-based heterostructuresHeterostructure and engineered electrocatalysts also exhibit desirable bifunctional activityBifunctional activity towards overall water splittingWater splitting. This chapter provides a brief idea about electrocatalytic water splittingWater splitting and also summarizes some recent advancements in noble-metal-freeNoble-metal-free bifunctional electrocatalystBifunctional electrocatalyst development. Finally, the future prospects in the development of efficient and cheap bifunctional electrocatalystsElectrocatalyst for water splittingWater splitting have been discussed.</description>
      <author>Subhasis Shit, Tapas Kuila, Suneel Kumar Srivastava</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-49108-5_9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Technologies in Catalyst Research</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-49108-5_1</link>
      <description>Ammara Khalid, Maria Batool, Maryam Saghir, Tahoor Khalid, Muhammad Faizan Nazar, Advances in material research and technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488241

                The discovery of new technologies to potentially improve catalystCatalyst efficiencyEfficiency is seen as an emerging approach. The currentCurrent chapter deals with the barriers that are being faced during advancing of different catalystsCatalyst. Various strategies have been developed over the past few decades to overcome shortcomings such as costCost inefficacy, instability due to moistureMoisture, salty environmentEnvironment and reduced work efficiencyEfficiency in heterogeneousHeterogeneous condition. Extensive research is being carried out to find cheap and environmentally friendlyEnvironmentally friendly renewableRenewable resources for the development of catalystsCatalyst for different reactionsReaction. This chapter focuses on photocatalysisPhotocatalysis, electrocatalysisElectrocatalysis, and recent advances in biocatalysis. These techniques are employed due to their cost effectivenessCost effectiveness and efficiencyEfficiency. So, we have detailed here working condition and mechanismMechanism of these techniques. Biocatalysis is described here in detail due to its green nature as emerging science is stressing upon green synthesisSynthesis and catalystsCatalyst.</description>
      <author>Ammara Khalid, Maria Batool, Maryam Saghir, Tahoor Khalid, Muhammad Faizan Nazar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-49108-5_1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts for electrocatalytic oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00004-5</link>
      <description>Yuan Ha, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488602

                The electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is the key process for fuel cells and metal-air batteries at the cathode electrode. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have emerged as one of the most promising candidates to replace Pt-based catalysts for highly efficient ORR owing to their maximal atom utilization and excellent catalytic efficiency. This chapter aims to provide fundamentals and the current standing of noble and nonnoble metal-based SACs for O2 reduction in the cathodic reaction of fuel cells and metal-air batteries. The discussion starts with an introduction to the catalytic mechanisms of ORR, followed by an overview of examples of SACs for ORR in fuel cells and metal-air batteries. The influences of chemical composition, active sites, and electronic structure of SACs on the ORR property and catalytic mechanisms have been summarized by the results of experiments that have been reported. A perspective is deliberated at the end about the application prospects and challenges for the development of SACs in fuel cells and metal-air batteries are generalized.</description>
      <author>Yuan Ha</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00004-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Regulation of the Fe-Based Single-Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109268</link>
      <description>Xiaochen Wang, Zhiwen Kang, Dan Wang, Yafei Zhao, Xu Xiang, Huishan Shang, Bing Zhang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391490718

                The excessive consumption of fossil energy causes serious environmental problems, which has driven the exploration of clean and sustainable energy. Oxygen electrocatalysis as the core reaction of emerging energy conversion has attracted significant attention. Fe-based single-atom catalysts (SACs) are efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen electrocatalysis on account of high intrinsic reaction activity, maximized metal atom utilization, well-defined active sites, customizable coordination environment, and regulable electronic structure. Although considerable performance improvements for Fe-based SACs in the oxygen electrocatalysis process have been made, the principle of modifying the electronic structure to promote the catalytic performance of Fe-based SACs is still ambiguous. In this review, the authors systematically summarize the regulation tactics for optimizing the catalytic activity and durability of Fe-based SACs toward oxygen electrocatalysis through different electronic structure adjustment methods, including the modulation of coordination atoms, metallic regulation, and the substrate effect. Ultimately, the challenges and future perspectives in the further development of Fe-based SACs are proposed.</description>
      <author>Xiaochen Wang, Zhiwen Kang, Dan Wang, Yafei Zhao, Xu Xiang, Huishan Shang, Bing Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109268</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single rhodium atom embedded two dimensional MoSi2N4: A promising electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159361</link>
      <description>Yazhao Yuan, Chunyu Zhang, Baonan Jia, Feng Wei, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Long Li, Feng Chen, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu, Applied Surface Science. 653(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391493522

                It is essential to develop electrocatalysts that exhibit excellent performance in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) for electrochemical energy applications. Recently, MoSi2N4 monolayer has been synthesized and attracted widespread interest. Herein, we constructed a series of structures by embedding transition metal (TM = Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ir, Pt and Au) atom into MoSi2N4 with N vacancy (VN-MSN), denoted as TM@VN-MSN, and investigated their ORR activity systematically by first-principles calculations. It is found that TM@VN-MSN systems are stable and there is charge transfer between TM atom and MoSi2N4. After screening, Rh@VN-MSN has the best ORR catalytic activity with an overpotential of 0.35 V, even lower than that of classical Pt (1 1 1). Furthermore, an implicit solvation model is used to evaluate the solvent effect. The volcano plots and scaling relations are established based on free energies of intermediates, and verified &#916;G*OH can use as a descriptor to explore the ORR activity on TM@VN-MSN. Moreover, d-band center theory and crystal orbital Hamilton populations (COHP) are used to reveal the ORR activity origin. This work not only provide a promising method for designing a new type of MoSi2N4-based ORR catalysts, but also expands its application in the field of electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Yazhao Yuan, Chunyu Zhang, Baonan Jia, Feng Wei, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Long Li, Feng Chen, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Investigation on the Strain Engineering Control of Tic as Tunable High-Efficiency Bifunctional Cathode Materials for Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4689216</link>
      <description>Mingyang Wang, Jianjun Mao, Yudong Pang, Xilin Zhang, Zongxian Yang, Zhansheng Lu, Shuting Yang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391493830

                Developing efficient cathode materials and strategies to suppress the shuttle effect and promote the reaction kinetics were the key scientific issues for the development of high performance lithium&#8211;sulfur (Li&#8211;S) batteries. Modify the properties of a material through strain engineering is an effective strategy to enhance the performance of adsorption and catalysis ability for special species. In this paper, first-principles calculations were carried out to investigate the anchoring effect and electrochemical performance of TiC(001) subjected to biaxial symmetric mechanical (compressive and tensile) strains. The results demonstrate that the adsorption energies of the lithium polysulfides (LiPSs) were enhanced monotonically and the metallic properties were also remain along with the compressive strain to tensile strain. In addition, an appropriate strain could reduce the migration barrier of Li ions, the dissociation barrier of Li2S and the Gibbs free energy of the sulfur reduction reaction (SRR) to realize the rapid charge/discharge processes. Especially, the p-band center of carbon atoms in TiC was proposed as an effective descriptor to identify the adsorption and catalysis ability of the anchoring materials under biaxial strain. Our results indicate that strain engineering is a promising strategy to improve the comprehensive performance of anchoring materials in Li&#8722;S batteries.</description>
      <author>Mingyang Wang, Jianjun Mao, Yudong Pang, Xilin Zhang, Zongxian Yang, Zhansheng Lu, Shuting Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4689216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon dioxide hydrogenation for sustainable energy storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.199</link>
      <description>Alberto Boretti, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 58(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391502943

                This paper explores green hydrogen-based carbon dioxide (CO2) hydrogenation for the production of oxygenates, presenting it as a pivotal strategy for mitigating carbon emissions and advancing sustainable energy solutions. The conversion of CO2 into oxygenates through hydrogenation emerges as a promising avenue, particularly in the context of transportation applications where the storage of hydrogen poses challenges. The substitution of fossil diesel and gasoline fuels with green hydrogen-derived dimethyl ether, or methanol/ethanol, is advantageous from a life cycle analysis (LCA) CO2 emission perspective even without the capture of the CO2. However, the greatest sustainability appeal is contingent on the crucial aspect of capturing CO2 when utilizing these fuels, which is an aspect currently absent in the literature. This narrative review comprehensively explores catalytic processes, mechanisms, sustainability perspectives, and the current state of research in this evolving area. It encompasses both the production of oxygenates through CO2 hydrogenation and the subsequent utilization of these oxygenates in fuel cells or combustion systems, emphasizing the integration of CO2 capture technologies. The paper contributes to the discourse surrounding the environmental and technological dimensions of energy storage ecosystems, providing a holistic view of their potential to foster sustainable energy solutions.</description>
      <author>Alberto Boretti</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrastable and Phosphoric Acid-Resistant PtRhCu@Pt Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalyst for High-Temperature Polymer Electrolyte Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04488</link>
      <description>An Zhao, Huanqiao Li, Xiaoming Zhang, Zhangxun Xia, Hong Zhang, Wenling Chu, Shansheng Yu, Suli Wang, Gongquan Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391509433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>An Zhao, Huanqiao Li, Xiaoming Zhang, Zhangxun Xia, Hong Zhang, Wenling Chu, Shansheng Yu, Suli Wang, Gongquan Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic screening of transition-metal-doped hydroxyapatite for efficient photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102692</link>
      <description>Yuting Li, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Josep Albero, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Lourdes F. Vega, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391448738

                We present the first comprehensive investigation of transition metal-substituted Hydroxyapatite (TM-HAP) materials for photocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2RR). Density functional theory (DFT) was used to study in a systematic manner the stability of 3d, 4d, 5d transition metal dopants on the HAP (000&#773;1) surface, analyzing their stability, activity, and selectivity for photocatalytic CO2RR. DFT results allowed to narrow down the selection to three transition metal elements (Co, Ni, Mo) based on their structural stability, band structure and performance. A selective analysis of product formation for carbon monoxide and formate was made, showing that TM dopants facilitate the initial protonation step in the CO2 reduction by adsorbing H2 molecule on TM atoms and then dissociating it into two hydrogen atoms. The performance of Ni- and Co-HAP towards the reaction activity is consistent with experimental results. Mo-HAP stands as a new and attractive photocatalyst for further investigation, given its excellent predicted performance.</description>
      <author>Yuting Li, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Josep Albero, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Lourdes F. Vega</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of chemicals and energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-14005-1.00009-x</link>
      <description>Adewale Giwa, Ahmed Yusuf, Hammed Abiodun Balogun, B. Anand, Setareh Heidari, David M. Warsinger, Hanifa Taher, Sulaiman Al&#8208;Zuhair, Bismah Shaikh, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391490678

                Electrochemical membrane technology has been identified as a promising technology for sustainable chemical and energy production due to its potential to address several challenges in the production of chemicals and energy, including energy consumption, greenhouse gas emissions, and waste generation. Electrochemical membrane processes can be applied to produce a wide range of feedstocks, including gases, liquids, and solids. This versatility can enable the coproduction of multiple chemicals and energy products from various feedstocks. In this chapter, the production of chemicals and energy, including bioelectricity, biomethane, biohydrogen, bioethanol, hydrogen peroxide, biodegradable electronics and biosensors, dry air from humid air, air separation into nitrogen and oxygen gases, organic solvent extraction, CO2 and H2 separation from gas mixtures, plasma generation, dewatered microalgae biomass, and purified microalgae-based products, are discussed. Electrochemical membrane processes can offer environmental benefits, such as CO2 reduction, leading to more sustainable and socially responsible production practices. The electrochemical conversion of CO2 can lead to the production of valuable chemicals, such as ethanol. With continued research and development, electrochemical membrane technology is expected to play an increasingly important role in chemical and energy production.</description>
      <author>Adewale Giwa, Ahmed Yusuf, Hammed Abiodun Balogun, B. Anand, Setareh Heidari, David M. Warsinger, Hanifa Taher, Sulaiman Al&#8208;Zuhair, Bismah Shaikh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-14005-1.00009-x</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
