<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:43:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Lignocellulosic Molecule Adsorption Structure Determination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01292</link>
      <description>Joakim S. Jestil&#228;, Nian Fen Wu, Fabio Priante, Adam S. Foster, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392150988

                Here, we present a study combining Bayesian optimization structural inference with the machine learning interatomic potential Neural Equivariant Interatomic Potential (NequIP) to accelerate and enable the study of the adsorption of the conformationally flexible lignocellulosic molecules &#946;-d-xylose and 1,4-&#946;-d-xylotetraose on a copper surface. The number of structure evaluations needed to map out the relevant potential energy surfaces are reduced by Bayesian optimization, while NequIP minimizes the time spent on each evaluation, ultimately resulting in cost-efficient and reliable sampling of large systems and configurational spaces. Although the applicability of Bayesian optimization for the conformational analysis of the more flexible xylotetraose molecule is restricted by the sample complexity bottleneck, the latter can be effectively bypassed with external conformer search tools, such as the Conformer-Rotamer Ensemble Sampling Tool, facilitating the subsequent lower-dimensional global minimum adsorption structure determination. Finally, we demonstrate the applicability of the described approach to find adsorption structures practically equivalent to the density functional theory counterparts at a fraction of the computational cost.</description>
      <author>Joakim S. Jestil&#228;, Nian Fen Wu, Fabio Priante, Adam S. Foster</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Defect Limitations in Photocatalysis: Boron&#8208;Incorporation Engineered Crystalline Red Phosphorus for Enhanced Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400542</link>
      <description>Xinya Pei, Junwei Bian, Wei Zhang, Zhuofeng Hu, Yun Hau Ng, Dong Ye, Xiaofeng Zhai, Zhen Wei, Yuxi Liu, Jiguang Deng, Hongxing Dai, Lin Jing, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392153574

                Abstract Photocatalytic hydrogen evolution (PHE) from water splitting is a promising technology for clean and renewable energy production. Elemental crystalline red phosphorus (CRP) is purposefully designed and developed for PHE reaction. However, the photocatalytic activity of CRP is limited by its intrinsic P vacancy (V P ) defects, which lead to detrimental charge trapping at deep states and hence its severe recombination. To address this issue, a boron (B) incorporated CRP (B&#8208;CRP) photocatalyst is tailored, synthesized via a simple and mild boric acid&#8208;assisted hydrothermal strategy. The incorporation of B effectively fills the V P defects, reducing deep trap states (DTS) and introducing beneficial shallow trap states (STS) within the band structure of CRP. This defect engineering approach leads to enhanced photocatalytic activity, with B&#8208;CRP achieving a PHE rate of 1392 &#181;mol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 , significantly outperforming most reported elemental photocatalysts in the literature. Density functional theory (DFT) simulations and ultrafast spectroscopy support the constructive role of B&#8208;dopant&#8208;induced STS in prolonging active charge carrier lifetimes, promoting more efficient photocatalytic reactions. The findings not only demonstrate the effectiveness of B&#8208;CRP as a photocatalyst but also highlight the usefulness of dopant&#8208;induced STS in advancing PHE technologies.</description>
      <author>Xinya Pei, Junwei Bian, Wei Zhang, Zhuofeng Hu, Yun Hau Ng, Dong Ye, Xiaofeng Zhai, Zhen Wei, Yuxi Liu, Jiguang Deng, Hongxing Dai, Lin Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A universal and scalable transformation of bulk metals into single-atom catalysts in ionic liquids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2319136121</link>
      <description>Shujuan Wang, Ming&#8208;Hui Lu, Xuewen Xia, Fei Wang, Xiaolu Xiong, Kai Ding, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Qian Xu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Hujun Shen, Ji Li, Yufeng Zhao, Jing Wang, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392157760

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) with maximized metal atom utilization and intriguing properties are of utmost importance for energy conversion and catalysis science. However, the lack of a straightforward and scalable synthesis strategy of SACs on diverse support materials remains the bottleneck for their large-scale industrial applications. Herein, we report a general approach to directly transform bulk metals into single atoms through the precise control of the electrodissolution&#8211;electrodeposition kinetics in ionic liquids and demonstrate the successful applicability of up to twenty different monometallic SACs and one multimetallic SAC with five distinct elements. As a case study, the atomically dispersed Pt was electrodeposited onto Ni 3 N/Ni-Co-graphene oxide heterostructures in varied scales (up to 5 cm &#215; 5 cm) as bifunctional catalysts with the electronic metal&#8211;support interaction, which exhibits low overpotentials at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER, 30 mV) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER, 263 mV) with a relatively low Pt loading (0.98 wt%). This work provides a simple and practical route for large-scale synthesis of various SACs with favorable catalytic properties on diversified supports using alternative ionic liquids and inspires the methodology on precise synthesis of multimetallic single-atom materials with tunable compositions.</description>
      <author>Shujuan Wang, Ming&#8208;Hui Lu, Xuewen Xia, Fei Wang, Xiaolu Xiong, Kai Ding, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Qian Xu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Hujun Shen, Ji Li, Yufeng Zhao, Jing Wang, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2319136121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-site segmentally synergistic catalysis mechanism: boosting CoFeSx nanocluster for sustainable water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45700-6</link>
      <description>Siran Xu, Sihua Feng, Yue Yu, Dongping Xue, Mengli Liu, Chao Wang, Kaiyue Zhao, Bingjun Xu, Jianan Zhang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392165142

                Abstract Efficient oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts are essential for sustainable clean energy conversion. However, catalytic materials followed the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) with the inherent scaling relationship between key oxygen intermediates *OOH and *OH, or the lattice-oxygen-mediated mechanism (LOM) with the possible lattice oxygen migration and structural reconstruction, which are not favorable to the balance between high activity and stability. Herein, we propose an unconventional Co-Fe dual-site segmentally synergistic mechanism (DSSM) for single-domain ferromagnetic catalyst CoFeS x nanoclusters on carbon nanotubes (CNT) (CFS-ACs/CNT), which can effectively break the scaling relationship without sacrificing stability. Co 3+ (L.S, t 2g 6 e g 0 ) supplies the strongest OH* adsorption energy, while Fe 3+ (M.S, t 2g 4 e g 1 ) exposes strong O* adsorption. These dual-sites synergistically produce of Co-O-O-Fe intermediates, thereby accelerating the release of triplet-state oxygen ( &#8593; O = O &#8593; ). As predicted, the prepared CFS-ACs/CNT catalyst exhibits less overpotential than that of commercial IrO 2 , as well as approximately 633 h of stability without significant potential loss.</description>
      <author>Siran Xu, Sihua Feng, Yue Yu, Dongping Xue, Mengli Liu, Chao Wang, Kaiyue Zhao, Bingjun Xu, Jianan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45700-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes as Effective Sulfur Hosts and Electrocatalysts to Suppress Lithium Polysulfide Shuttling: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07776</link>
      <description>Thilini Boteju, Sathish Ponnurangam, Venkataraman Thangadurai, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392166721

                Exploring electrocatalysts for the sulfur reduction reaction (SRR) has emerged as a promising strategy to suppress the shuttle effect and enhance the kinetics in lithium&#8211;sulfur (Li&#8211;S) batteries. A comprehensive understanding of the electrocatalytic mechanism within Li&#8211;S batteries remains elusive, which hinders the rational design of advanced electrocatalysts for these systems. In this study, two-dimensional (2D) transition metal carbides and nitrides (MXenes) have been investigated for the catalytic conversion of lithium polysulfides (LiPSs) using density functional theory (DFT). Our findings reveal that MXenes show a moderate binding affinity for LiPSs, suggesting favorable thermodynamics for their role as electrocatalysts for the SRR. This thermodynamic favorability promotes the suppression of the LiPSs&#8217; shuttle effect and the enhancement of the SRR kinetics. The SRR process in Li&#8211;S batteries consists of multiple steps with varying activation energies. Our analysis by constructing the energy diagram for the multistep SRR indicates that the initial reduction of S8 to Li2S8 is facile with a lower activation energy, while the last step where Li2S2 converts to Li2S appears to be a rate-limiting step. To predict the catalytic abilities of MXene structures, we built a volcano-shaped relationship between the adsorption of LiPSs and catalytic activity. We show three MXenes&#9472;Ta2CO2, Zr2NO2, and Mo2NO2 as potential electrocatalysts that exhibit lower thermodynamic overpotentials for the SRR. These findings represent a significant step toward developing advanced electrocatalysts that may unlock the full potential of Li&#8211;S batteries, paving the way for improved energy storage systems with enhanced efficiency and performance.</description>
      <author>Thilini Boteju, Sathish Ponnurangam, Venkataraman Thangadurai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting photocatalytic hydrogen evolution rates in layered graphitic carbon nitride through integrated non-noble CoB co-catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.261</link>
      <description>Suraj Gupta, Chayathorn Prapaitrakool, B.R. Bhagat, C. S. Yeh, Alpa Dashora, Akawat Sirisuk, N. Patel, Nina Daneu, Andra&#382; Kocjan, Matja&#382; Spreitzer, Jeffrey C.S. Wu, Marjeta Ma&#269;ek Kr&#382;manc, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392180686

                Despite being one of the most widely studied metal-free semiconductors, graphitic carbon-nitride (gC3N4) shows meaningful photocatalytic activities only when loaded with noble-metal co-catalysts. The present work reports an alternative to noble metals in the form of cobalt boride (CoB) co-catalyst that can be easily integrated within the gC3N4 framework with facile fabrication strategies. The optimized CoB-gC3N4 composite showed &#8764;60 times higher hydrogen generation rate compared to bare gC3N4 nanosheets, with good stability. Detailed morphological, structural, chemical, electrochemical and spectroscopic investigations revealed the key aspects of CoB-gC3N4 composite that unanimously led to higher photocatalytic activity. Computational investigations not only corroborated the experimental results but also established that the surface Co and B sites in CoB provided the most energetically favoured sites for hydrogen evolution reaction. Based on the experimental and computational investigations, a generic reaction mechanism was formulated that will prove as a guiding light for future studies on similar photocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Suraj Gupta, Chayathorn Prapaitrakool, B.R. Bhagat, C. S. Yeh, Alpa Dashora, Akawat Sirisuk, N. Patel, Nina Daneu, Andra&#382; Kocjan, Matja&#382; Spreitzer, Jeffrey C.S. Wu, Marjeta Ma&#269;ek Kr&#382;manc</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An NiFeSn Oxyhydroxide Electrocatalyst Wet Gel for Highly Efficient Water Electrolysis in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109428</link>
      <description>Taehee Kim, Hwapyung Jung, Hee Young Choi, Donghyeon Kang, Wonjun Lee, Vinayak G. Parale, Umakant M. Patil, Younghun Kim, J. S. Kim, Sang-Hyun Kim, Sang Woo Kim, Kazuyoshi Kanamori, Hyung Ho Park, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392184869

                Since the kinetic barrier posed by the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a significant obstacle in water-splitting systems, the creation of effective and inexpensive OER electrocatalysts has received considerable research interest. We report the facile synthesis of an amorphized NiFeSn oxyhydroxide wet gel on Ni foam via a gelation-induced embedding method. Its intrinsic pore structure provided a sufficiently large surface area without the need for a binder. The NiFeSn oxyhydroxide wet-gel electrocatalyst only needed overpotentials of 253, 301, and 346 mV to produce 100, 200, and 300 mA&#183;cm-2, respectively, for the OER and an overpotential value of 198 mV at 50 mA&#183;cm-2 for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Moreover, an exceptionally low voltage of 1.55 V was required for overall water splitting under alkaline conditions. Enhancement of the catalytic properties of the oxyhydroxide by adding Sn was confirmed by using density functional theory calculations. The nanoporous multi-metallic wet gel can be used to create effective low-cost stable self-supporting electrocatalysts with a high current density for enhanced water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Taehee Kim, Hwapyung Jung, Hee Young Choi, Donghyeon Kang, Wonjun Lee, Vinayak G. Parale, Umakant M. Patil, Younghun Kim, J. S. Kim, Sang-Hyun Kim, Sang Woo Kim, Kazuyoshi Kanamori, Hyung Ho Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Design of an Electro-Organocatalyst for Conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; into Formaldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.3c07806</link>
      <description>Foroogh Khezeli, Craig Plaisance, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392185690

                Density functional theory calculations employing a hybrid implicit/explicit solvation method were used to explore a new strategy for electrochemical conversion of CO2 using an electro-organocatalyst. A particular structural motif is identified that consists of an electron-rich vicinal enediamine (&gt;N&#8211;C&#9552;C&#8211;N&lt;) backbone, which is capable of activating CO2 by the formation of a C&#8211;C bond while subsequently facilitating the transfer of electrons from a chemically inert cathode to ultimately produce formaldehyde. Unlike transition metal-based electrocatalysts, the electro-organocatalyst is not constrained by scaling relations between the formation energies of activated CO2 and adsorbed CO, nor is it expected to be active for the competing hydrogen evolution reaction. The rate-limiting steps are found to occur during two proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) sequences and are associated with the transfer of a proton from a proton transfer mediator to a carbon atom on the electro-organocatalyst. The difficulty of this step in the second PCET sequence necessitates an electrode potential of &#8722;0.85 V vs RHE to achieve the maximum turnover frequency. In addition, it is postulated that the electro-organocatalyst should also be capable of forming long-chain aldehydes by successively carrying out reductive aldol condensation to grow the alkyl chain one carbon at a time.</description>
      <author>Foroogh Khezeli, Craig Plaisance</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.3c07806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Potential and Active-Site Environment on Single-Iron-Atom-Catalyzed Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction from Accurate Quantum Many-Body Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05999</link>
      <description>Jincheng Lei, Tianyu Zhu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392185788

                Single iron atoms supported on nitrogen-doped graphene (Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C) have shown promise in catalyzing electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO with low overpotential and high selectivity. However, the nature of its rate-limiting step and the effect of active-site environment on catalytic activity are still under debate. Previous theoretical studies exclusively rely on density functional theory (DFT), but their predictions are limited by inherent errors in DFT functionals, leading to diverging conclusions on catalytic mechanisms. Herein, we employ an efficient quantum embedding strategy to enable high-level coupled-cluster (CCSD(T)) simulations of the thermodynamics of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C-catalyzed CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) and its competing hydrogen evolution reaction. Our calculations accurately predict experimental CO binding energy, onset potential, and potential of maximal Faradaic efficiency (FE) with FeN4 as the catalytic active site. We find that the thermodynamic-limiting step is the formation of a *COOH intermediate at low overpotential, which becomes CO2 adsorption and CO desorption at higher overpotential. Our simulation reveals that the potential-dependent high selectivity of FeN4 originates from the higher charge capacity of *COOH compared to *H. Furthermore, our calculations elucidate distinct roles of active-site environments, including vacancy defect and nitrogen doping. Particularly, graphitic nitrogen doping simultaneously lowers the CO2RR onset potential and allows a wider potential range for high CO FE. This work highlights the importance of robust many-body quantum chemical simulations in achieving quantitative understanding of multistep electrocatalytic reaction mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Jincheng Lei, Tianyu Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically Induced Ru/CoOOH Synergistic Catalyst as Bifunctional Electrode Materials for Alkaline Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311884</link>
      <description>Yan Ma, Yuan Ha, Liangqiang Chen, Ziqi An, Xing Liu, Zhenni Wang, Zhimin Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392186966

                Abstract Efficient and affordable price bifunctional electrocatalysts based on transition metal oxides for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions have a balanced efficiency, but it remains a significant challenge to control their activity and durability. Herein, a trace Ru (0.74 wt.%) decorated ultrathin CoOOH nanosheets (&#8776;4 nm) supported on the surface of nickel foam (Ru/CoOOH@NF) is rationally designed via an electrochemically induced strategy to effectively drive the electrolysis of alkaline overall water splitting. The as&#8208;synthesized Ru/CoOOH@NF electrocatalysts integrate the advantages of a large number of different HER (Ru nanoclusters) and OER (CoOOH nanosheets) active sites as well as strong in&#8208;suit structure stability, thereby exhibiting exceptional catalytic activity. In particular, the ultra&#8208;low overpotential of the HER (36 mV) and the OER (264 mV) are implemented to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Experimental and theoretical calculations also reveal that Ru/CoOOH@NF possesses high intrinsic conductivity, which facilitates electron release from H 2 O and H&#8208;OH bond breakage and accelerates electron/mass transfer by regulating the charge distribution. This work provides a new avenue for the rational design of low&#8208;cost and high&#8208;activity bifunctional electrocatalysts for large&#8208;scale water&#8208;splitting technology and expects to help contribute to the creation of various hybrid electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yan Ma, Yuan Ha, Liangqiang Chen, Ziqi An, Xing Liu, Zhenni Wang, Zhimin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311884</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The graphene-supported transition metal cluster as efficient electrocatalyst for nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00214-024-03101-4</link>
      <description>Jinqiang Li, Jiale Liu, Hui Li, Chaozheng He, Yuming Wei, Huijun Kong, Wei Song, Theoretical Chemistry Accounts. 143(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392186982

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinqiang Li, Jiale Liu, Hui Li, Chaozheng He, Yuming Wei, Huijun Kong, Wei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00214-024-03101-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetochiral tunneling in paramagnetic Co &lt;sub&gt;1/3&lt;/sub&gt; NbS &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2318443121</link>
      <description>Seong Joon Lim, Sobhit Singh, Fei&#8208;Ting Huang, Shangke Pan, Kefeng Wang, Jae Wook Kim, Jinwoong Kim, David Vanderbilt, Sang&#8208;Wook Cheong, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392189707

                Electric currents have the intriguing ability to induce magnetization in nonmagnetic crystals with sufficiently low crystallographic symmetry. Some associated phenomena include the non-linear anomalous Hall effect in polar crystals and the nonreciprocal directional dichroism in chiral crystals when magnetic fields are applied. In this work, we demonstrate that the same underlying physics is also manifested in the electronic tunneling process between the surface of a nonmagnetic chiral material and a magnetized scanning probe. In the paramagnetic but chiral metallic compound Co 1/3 NbS 2 , the magnetization induced by the tunneling current is shown to become detectable by its coupling to the magnetization of the tip itself. This results in a contrast across different chiral domains, achieving atomic-scale spatial resolution of structural chirality. To support the proposed mechanism, we used first-principles theory to compute the chirality-dependent current-induced magnetization and Berry curvature in the bulk of the material. Our demonstration of this magnetochiral tunneling effect opens up an avenue for investigating atomic-scale variations in the local crystallographic symmetry and electronic structure across the structural domain boundaries of low-symmetry nonmagnetic crystals.</description>
      <author>Seong Joon Lim, Sobhit Singh, Fei&#8208;Ting Huang, Shangke Pan, Kefeng Wang, Jae Wook Kim, Jinwoong Kim, David Vanderbilt, Sang&#8208;Wook Cheong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2318443121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An interesting synergistic effect of heteronuclear dual-atom catalysts for hydrogen production: Offsetting or promoting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6436-5</link>
      <description>Zhonghao Wang, Tingcha Wei, Jialin Liu, Gang Zhou, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392194106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhonghao Wang, Tingcha Wei, Jialin Liu, Gang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6436-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co(O)&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;(N)&#8208;type single&#8208;atom&#8208;based catalysts and ligand&#8208;driven modulation of electrocatalytic properties for reducing oxygen molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.27</link>
      <description>Yunseok Shin, Yeunhee Lee, Changbum Jo, Yong&#8208;Hyun Kim, Sunghee Park, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392195656

                Abstract Single&#8208;atom&#8208;based catalysts are intriguing electrocatalytic platforms that combine the advantages of molecular catalysts and conductive carbon&#8208;based materials. In this work, hybrids (Co&#8208;NrGO&#8208;1 and Co&#8208;NrGO&#8208;2) were generated by wet&#8208;reactions between organometallic complexes (Co(CH 3 COO) 2 and Co[CH 3 (CH 2 ) 3 CH(C 2 H 5 )COO] 2 , respectively) and N&#8208;doped reduced graphene oxide at 25&#176;C. Various characterizations revealed the formation of atomically dispersed Co(O) 4 (N) species in Co&#8208;NrGO&#8208;2. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations explained the effect of the aliphatic C7 group in Co2 on the formation processes. The Co&#8208;NrGO&#8208;2 hybrid showed excellent catalytic performance, such as onset (0.94 V) and half&#8208;wave (0.83 V) potentials, for electrochemical oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Co&#8208;NrGO&#8208;2 outperformed Co&#8208;NrGO&#8208;1, which was explained by more back donation to the antibonding orbitals of O 2 from electron&#8208;rich aliphatic groups. DFT calculations support this feature, with mechanistic investigations showing favored ORR reactions and facile breakage of double bonds in O 2 .</description>
      <author>Yunseok Shin, Yeunhee Lee, Changbum Jo, Yong&#8208;Hyun Kim, Sunghee Park</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.27</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability challenges and opportunities of NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.110</link>
      <description>Yujun Han, Jingyi Wang, Yuhang Liu, Tianqi Li, Tongzhou Wang, Xinyue Li, X. J. Ye, Guodong Li, Jihong Li, Wenbin Hu, Yida Deng, Carbon Neutralization. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392196226

                Abstract Water splitting is a critical process for the production of green hydrogen, contributing to the advancement of a circular economy. However, the application of water splitting devices on a large scale is primarily impeded by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode. Thus, developing and designing efficient OER catalysts is a significant target. NiFe&#8208;based catalysts are extensively researched as excellent OER electrocatalysts due to their affordability, abundant reserves, and intrinsic activities. However, they still suffer from long&#8208;term stability challenges. To date, few systematic strategies for improving OER durability have been reported. In this review, various advanced NiFe&#8208;based catalysts are introduced. Moreover, the OER stability challenges of NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts in alkaline media, including iron segregation, structural degradation, and peeling from the substrate are summarized. More importantly, strategies to enhance OER stability are highlighted and opportunities are discussed to facilitate future stability studies for alkaline water electrolysis. This review presents a design strategy for NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts and anion exchange membrane (AEM) electrolyzers to overcome stability challenges in OER, which also emphasizes the importance of long&#8208;term stability in alkaline media and its significance for achieving large&#8208;scale commercialization.</description>
      <author>Yujun Han, Jingyi Wang, Yuhang Liu, Tianqi Li, Tongzhou Wang, Xinyue Li, X. J. Ye, Guodong Li, Jihong Li, Wenbin Hu, Yida Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of iron(III) in aqueous and alkaline environments with &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; and ReaxFF potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0182460</link>
      <description>A. Riefer, Matthias Hackert-Osch&#228;tzchen, Philipp Pl&#228;nitz, Gunnar Meichsner, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392198190

                The iron(III) complexes [Fe(H2O)n(OH)m]3&#8722;m (n + m = 5, 6, m &#8804; 3) and corresponding proton transfer reactions are studied with total energy calculations, the nudged elastic band (NEB) method, and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations using ab initio and a modification of reactive force field potentials, the ReaxFF-AQ potentials, based on the implementation according to B&#246;hm et al. [J. Phys. Chem. C 120, 10849&#8211;10856 (2016)]. Applying ab initio potentials, the energies for the reactions [Fe(H2O)n(OH)m]3&#8722;m + H2O &#8594; [Fe(H2O)n&#8722;1(OH)m+1]2&#8722;m + H3O+ in a gaseous environment are in good agreement with comparable theoretical results. In an aqueous (aq) or alkaline environment, with the aid of NEB computations, respective minimum energy paths with energy barriers of up to 14.6 kcal/mol and a collective transfer of protons are modeled. Within MD simulations at room temperature, a permanent transfer of protons around the iron(III) ion is observed. The information gained concerning the geometrical and energetic properties of water and the [Fe(H2O)n(OH)m]3&#8722;m complexes from the ab initio computations has been used as reference data to optimize parameters for the O&#8211;H&#8211;Fe interaction within the ReaxFF-AQ approach. For the optimized ReaxFF-AQ parameter set, the statistical properties of the basic water model, such as the radial distribution functions and the proton hopping functions, are evaluated. For the [Fe(H2O)n(OH)m]3&#8722;m complexes, it was found that while geometrical and energetic properties are in good agreement with the ab initio data for gaseous environment, the statistical properties as obtained from the MD simulations are only partly in accordance with the ab initio results for the iron(III) complexes in aqueous or alkaline environments.</description>
      <author>A. Riefer, Matthias Hackert-Osch&#228;tzchen, Philipp Pl&#228;nitz, Gunnar Meichsner</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0182460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts for Electrocatalysis Revitalization: Exploring the Structure&#8208;Performance Correlation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303281</link>
      <description>Ming Wah Wong, Joel Jie Foo, Jian Yiing Loh, Wee&#8208;Jun Ong, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392199444

                Abstract In light of the profound shift toward renewable fuels, dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) are impressively prospected as auspicious catalysts for electrocatalysis revitalization, toward accomplishing environmental remediation and sustainable global energy security. Leveraging appealing attributes such as inspiring synergistic effect, additional adjacent adsorption sites, and ultrahigh atom utilization, DACs are endowed with unprecedented stability, activity, and selectivity in multifarious energy&#8208;related applications. By virtue of addressing time and technological prominence to review this ground&#8208;breaking atomic electrocatalyst, this review first encompasses a correlation elucidation between the substrate, dual&#8208;atoms, and facile synthetic approaches with intriguing modification strategies. Furthermore, the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art characterization techniques specially employed for DACs are spotlighted, alongside rigorously unveiling the novel mechanistic insights&#8217; milestone gained from both theoretical modeling and experimental research in multitudes of environmentally benign electrocatalytic applications, including O 2 reduction, CO 2 reduction, H 2 evolution, O 2 evolution, N 2 reduction, and other fundamental reactions. As a final note, this review presents a brief conclusion highlighting current challenges and outlining prospects for this frontier. Importantly, this review deciphers the structure&#8208;performance correlation while excavating the advancement gained in DACs, thus is anticipated to shed light for the catalysis community on bolstering an intense evolution of DACs while triggering sapient inspiration for more robust next&#8208;generation catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ming Wah Wong, Joel Jie Foo, Jian Yiing Loh, Wee&#8208;Jun Ong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the universal principle for the rational design of single-atom electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-023-01106-z</link>
      <description>Haoxiang Xu, Daojian Cheng, Dapeng Cao, Xiao Cheng Zeng, Nature Catalysis. 7(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392201277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoxiang Xu, Daojian Cheng, Dapeng Cao, Xiao Cheng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-023-01106-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Informative Training Data for Efficient Property Prediction in Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks by Active Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13687</link>
      <description>Antonio San Jos&#233;, &#201;milie Devijver, N. Jakse, Roberta Poloni, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392167663

                In recent data-driven approaches to material discovery, scenarios where target quantities are expensive to compute and measure are often overlooked. In such cases, it becomes imperative to construct a training set that includes the most diverse, representative, and informative samples. Here, a novel regression tree-based active learning algorithm is employed for such a purpose. It is applied to predict the band gap and adsorption properties of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), a novel class of materials that results from the virtually infinite combinations of their building units. Simpler and low dimensional descriptors, such as those based on stoichiometric and geometric properties, are used to compute the feature space for this model owing to their ability to better represent MOFs in the low data regime. The partitions given by a regression tree constructed on the labeled part of the data set are used to select new samples to be added to the training set, thereby limiting its size while maximizing the prediction quality. Tests on the QMOF, hMOF, and dMOF data sets reveal that our method constructs small training data sets to learn regression models that predict the target properties more efficiently than existing active learning approaches, and with lower variance. Specifically, our active learning approach is highly beneficial when labels are unevenly distributed in the descriptor space and when the label distribution is imbalanced, which is often the case for real world data. The regions defined by the tree help in revealing patterns in the data, thereby offering a unique tool to efficiently analyze complex structure&#8211;property relationships in materials and accelerate materials discovery.</description>
      <author>Antonio San Jos&#233;, &#201;milie Devijver, N. Jakse, Roberta Poloni</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13687</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
