<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:43:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of mixing time on a reversal tolerant anode measured ex situ for a PEMFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.236</link>
      <description>S.J.T. Homan, Kerem Aylar, Adrian Jurjevi&#263;, M. Scolari, Atsushi Urakawa, Peyman Taheri, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391804977

                When no hydrogen can reach the Pt catalyst in the anode for the hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) of an operating proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC), the anode potential increases and causes the cell potential to be reversed compared to normal operation conditions. During this reversal, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and carbon oxidation reaction (COR) will occur at the anode, where the COR has devastating consequences for the electrode. Introducing an OER catalyst limits the COR to occur, which makes a reversal tolerant anode (RTA). In this research, RTAs are differentiated by applying different ball milling times during catalyst layer processing, forming big and small OER (IrOx/TiOx) and HOR (Pt/C) catalyst particles. The two different particle sizes were electrochemically tested using a rotating disc electrode (RDE). Both catalyst sizes show a decrease in OER activity (mA cm&#8722;2) accompanied by loss of the ionomer in a self-developed accelerated stress test (AST). The small particle RTAs show higher OER activity as a result of increased surface area. However, during a chronopotentiometry measurement, which mimics a fuel cell reversal, the small particle coatings show a worse reversal tolerance. This phenomenon can be attributed to the increased difficulty in removing oxygen bubbles.</description>
      <author>S.J.T. Homan, Kerem Aylar, Adrian Jurjevi&#263;, M. Scolari, Atsushi Urakawa, Peyman Taheri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of Nitrogen Coordination Modulation of Fe_N&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;@BP System Catalysts on the Activity of Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07527</link>
      <description>Ching T. Hou, Sen Ming, Keyuan Chen, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Lian Yu, Hongying Hou, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391806634

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ching T. Hou, Sen Ming, Keyuan Chen, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Lian Yu, Hongying Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Study of Nitrogen Fixation Electrocatalysts Based on Two-Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05754</link>
      <description>Zhengqin Xiong, Ying Xu, An Yu Bao, Sheng Wei, Jie Zhan, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391811694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhengqin Xiong, Ying Xu, An Yu Bao, Sheng Wei, Jie Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Nitric Oxide Reduction Reaction through Surface Doping on Superstructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109396</link>
      <description>Baokun Zhang, Ying Dai, Baibiao Huang, Zhao Qian, Rajeev Ahuja, Wei Wei, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391812169

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baokun Zhang, Ying Dai, Baibiao Huang, Zhao Qian, Rajeev Ahuja, Wei Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-N-C core-shell catalysts with single low-spin Fe(&#8545;)-N4 species for oxygen reduction reaction and high-performance proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.074</link>
      <description>Wei Yan, Linhui Yu, Binghua Yang, Caihong Li, Fang Chen, Wenlong Guo, Fang&#8208;Xing Xiao, Yangming Lin, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391817857

                Fe-N-doped carbon materials (Fe-N-C) are promising candidates for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) relative to Pt-based catalysts in proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). However, the intrinsic contributions of Fe-N4 moiety with different chemical/spin states (e.g. D1, D2, D3, etc.) to ORR are unclear since various states coexist inevitably. In the present work, Fe-N-C core-shell nanocatalyst with single low-spin Fe(&#8545;)-N4 species (D1) is synthesized and identified with ex-situ ultralow temperature M&#246;ssbauer spectroscopy (T=1.6 K) that could essentially differentiate various Fe-N4 states and invisible Fe-O species. By quantifying with CO-pulse chemisorption, site density and turnover frequency of Fe-N-C catalysts reach 2.4&#215;1019 site g&#8722;1 and 23 e site&#8722;1 s&#8722;1 during the ORR, respectively. Half-wave potential (0.915 VRHE) of the Fe-N-C catalyst is more positive (approximately 54 mV) than that of Pt/C. Moreover, we observe that the performance of PEMFCs on Fe-N-C almost achieves the 2025 target of the US Department of Energy by demonstrating a current density of 1.037 A cm&#8722;2 combined with the peak power density of 0.685 W cm&#8722;2, suggesting the critical role of Fe(&#8545;)-N4 site (D1). After 500 h of running, PEMFCs still deliver a power density of 1.26 W cm&#8722;2 at 1.0 bar H2-O2. An unexpected rate-determining step is figured out by isotopic labelling experiment and theoretical calculation. This work not only offers valuable insights regarding the intrinsic contribution of Fe-N4 with a single spin state to alkaline/acidic ORR, but also provides great opportunities for developing high-performance stable PEMFCs.</description>
      <author>Wei Yan, Linhui Yu, Binghua Yang, Caihong Li, Fang Chen, Wenlong Guo, Fang&#8208;Xing Xiao, Yangming Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.074</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Polaritonic Chemistry: Accessing Chemical Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c12829</link>
      <description>Christian Sch&#228;fer, Jakub Fojt, Eric Lindgren, Paul Erhart, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391824217

                Altering chemical reactivity and material structure in confined optical environments is on the rise, and yet, a conclusive understanding of the microscopic mechanisms remains elusive. This originates mostly from the fact that accurately predicting vibrational and reactive dynamics for soluted ensembles of realistic molecules is no small endeavor, and adding (collective) strong light&#8211;matter interaction does not simplify matters. Here, we establish a framework based on a combination of machine learning (ML) models, trained using density-functional theory calculations and molecular dynamics to accelerate such simulations. We then apply this approach to evaluate strong coupling, changes in reaction rate constant, and their influence on enthalpy and entropy for the deprotection reaction of 1-phenyl-2-trimethylsilylacetylene, which has been studied previously both experimentally and using ab initio simulations. While we find qualitative agreement with critical experimental observations, especially with regard to the changes in kinetics, we also find differences in comparison with previous theoretical predictions. The features for which the ML-accelerated and ab initio simulations agree show the experimentally estimated kinetic behavior. Conflicting features indicate that a contribution of dynamic electronic polarization to the reaction process is more relevant than currently believed. Our work demonstrates the practical use of ML for polaritonic chemistry, discusses limitations of common approximations, and paves the way for a more holistic description of polaritonic chemistry.</description>
      <author>Christian Sch&#228;fer, Jakub Fojt, Eric Lindgren, Paul Erhart</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c12829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size tuning of Pt nanoparticles on ZrO2: Optimizing catalytic performance for hydrogen evolution and water-splitting reactions - A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.142</link>
      <description>Ayyaz Mahmood, Tehmina Akram, Shenggui Chen, Huafu Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391825258

                In heterogeneous catalysis, determining the optimal metal particle size is challenging due to the intricate relationship between particle size, electronic structure, and activity. Here, we investigate the size-dependent activity of Pt nanoparticle (PtNP)-based ZrO2 catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and water-splitting reaction (WSR) using density functional theory (DFT) and ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations. By analyzing different Pt nanoparticle sizes (Pt4, Pt7, Pt11, P15, Pt19, and Pt25) supported on ZrO2, we determined their optimized geometries, and electronic structures, and calculated the hydrogen adsorption energies (&#916;GH) for HER and activation energies barrier (&#916;&#8225;G) for WSR. The calculated results demonstrate that Pt11 is the optimal size for HER, exhibiting the lowest &#916;GH (&#8722;0.066 eV), while Pt15 shows the lowest &#916;&#8225;G (0.24 eV) for WSR. The density of states (DOS) shows that the occupied Pt states fill the gap of ZrO2 (3.72 eV), significantly reducing the band gap (Eg) of the PtNP/ZrO2 composites. The most favorable configuration of the PtNP on ZrO2 for HER and WSR is determined to be a three-Pt-layer structure with rooflike edges which corresponds to a nanoparticle size of &#8764;0.70&#8211;1.55 nm for experiments. These findings can be regarded as an effort toward the design and optimization of metal-based oxide catalysts for renewable energy applications.</description>
      <author>Ayyaz Mahmood, Tehmina Akram, Shenggui Chen, Huafu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Calorific Biohydrogen Production Under High Pressure: Ca2+ Addition, Theoretical Prediction, and Continuous Operation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4725685</link>
      <description>Om Prakash, Masoud Makian, Young-Chae Song, Seoktae Kang, Dong Hoon Kim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391826431

                The removal of CO2 (called &#8220;upgrading&#8221;) is essential in bio-H2 production processes including dark fermentation (DF), which is energy-intensive and adds economic burden. Here, it was attempted to generate high-calorific bio-H2 (high H2-content) directly from the fermenter under high pressure in the presence of Ca2+. High pressure was automatically generated by holding the produced gas at a certain limit.Batch test results showed that Ca2+ addition was helpful to keep the pH by precipitating with dissolved CO2, resulting in the gradual increase of H2 content to 93% at 17.5 bar (vs. 77% at 11.2 bar in the control). Then, the theoretical approaches, based on balance and equilibrium equations, were made to investigate the effects of Ca2+ addition at different dosages (0-1 g CaCl2/L) under different pressures during continuous operation. It was found that the H2 content around 90% at the permissible pressure (&#8804;10 bar) can be only achieved at 1 g CaCl2/L addition. Lastly, continuous operation of DF was conducted in an up-flow anaerobic sludge blanket reactor fed with glucose (10 g COD/L) with 1 g CaCl2/L addition. The H2 content in bio-H2 gradually increased with the pressure increase, from 49.5% at 1 bar to 84.9% at 9 bar. No distinct changes in morphological and physico-chemical properties were observed in the granules exposed at different pressures. Although there was a drop in the amount of H2 produced due to the increase in dissolved H2 and metabolic shift as pressure increased, the decrease in upgrading cost made high-pressure DF economically feasible.</description>
      <author>Om Prakash, Masoud Makian, Young-Chae Song, Seoktae Kang, Dong Hoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4725685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MatNexus: A comprehensive text mining and analysis suite for materials discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.softx.2024.101654</link>
      <description>Lei Zhang, Markus Stricker, SoftwareX. 26(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391836100

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zhang, Markus Stricker</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.softx.2024.101654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superionic lithium transport via multiple coordination environments defined by two-anion packing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adh5115</link>
      <description>Guopeng Han, Andrij Vasylenko, Luke M. Daniels, Christopher M. Collins, Lucia Corti, Ruiyong Chen, Hongjun Niu, Troy D. Manning, Dmytro Antypov, Matthew S. Dyer, Jungwoo Lim, Marco Zanella, Manel Sonni, Mounib Bahri, Hongil Jo, Yun Dang, Craig M. Robertson, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Blanc, Laurence J. Hardwick, Nigel D. Browning, John B. Claridge, Matthew J. Rosseinsky, Science. 383(6684)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391836522

                Fast cation transport in solids underpins energy storage. Materials design has focused on structures that can define transport pathways with minimal cation coordination change, restricting attention to a small part of chemical space. Motivated by the greater structural diversity of binary intermetallics than that of the metallic elements, we used two anions to build a pathway for three-dimensional superionic lithium ion conductivity that exploits multiple cation coordination environments. Li 7 Si 2 S 7 I is a pure lithium ion conductor created by an ordering of sulphide and iodide that combines elements of hexagonal and cubic close-packing analogously to the structure of NiZr. The resulting diverse network of lithium positions with distinct geometries and anion coordination chemistries affords low barriers to transport, opening a large structural space for high cation conductivity.</description>
      <author>Guopeng Han, Andrij Vasylenko, Luke M. Daniels, Christopher M. Collins, Lucia Corti, Ruiyong Chen, Hongjun Niu, Troy D. Manning, Dmytro Antypov, Matthew S. Dyer, Jungwoo Lim, Marco Zanella, Manel Sonni, Mounib Bahri, Hongil Jo, Yun Dang, Craig M. Robertson, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Blanc, Laurence J. Hardwick, Nigel D. Browning, John B. Claridge, Matthew J. Rosseinsky</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adh5115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptor for C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N-Supported Single-Cluster Catalysts in Bifunctional Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03573</link>
      <description>Jing Pan, Min Li, Ivo A. W. Filot, Hui Wang, Emiel J. M. Hensen, Long Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391840068

                Developing highly active cluster catalysts for the bifunctional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is significant for future renewable energy technology. Here, we employ first-principles calculations combined with a genetic algorithm to explore the activity trends of transition metal clusters supported on C2N. Our results indicate that the supported clusters, as bifunctional catalysts for the OER and the ORR, may outperform single-atom catalysts. In particular, the C2N-supported Ag6 cluster exhibits outstanding bifunctional activity with low overpotentials. Mechanistic analysis indicates that the activity of the cluster is related to the number of atoms in the active site as well as the interaction between the intermediate and the cluster. Accordingly, we identify a descriptor that links the intrinsic properties of the clusters with the activity of both the OER and the ORR. This work provides guidelines and strategies for the rational design of highly efficient bifunctional cluster catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jing Pan, Min Li, Ivo A. W. Filot, Hui Wang, Emiel J. M. Hensen, Long Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field&#8208;Assisted Water Splitting: Mechanism, Optimization Strategies, and Future Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202316544</link>
      <description>Shengyu Ma, Qiang Fu, Jiecai Han, Yu&#8208;Chong Tai, Xianjie Wang, Zhihua Zhang, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391840669

                Abstract Rationally designing of highly efficient electrocatalysts is critical to improving hydrogen production by water electrolysis. However, bottlenecks still require consideration when optimizing the intrinsic performance of electrocatalysts. Applying appropriate external fields to catalytic systems may effectively overcome such bottlenecks and enhance the performance of catalysts. Among various external fields, the magnetic field has received extensive attention owing to its multifunctionality, non&#8208;contact nature, and non&#8208;invasiveness, thereby requiring more research and development. In this review, recent advances in magnetic field&#8208;assisted water electrolysis are systematically outlined. Firstly, the diverse methods used for pre&#8208;regulating catalysts under magnetic fields, including optimized nucleation, induction heating, and directed growth, are discussed. It then explores the effects of magnetic fields on electrochemical processes, including magnetothermal, magnetohydrodynamic, and induced electric impact. Then, the influences of magnetic fields on the intrinsic properties of catalysts, such as spin polarization and spin reconstruction effects, are addressed. Finally, a discussion of the potential perspectives of magnetic field&#8208;enhanced water splitting, including catalyst design, experimental precision, and in situ characterization, are then provided to guide further research.</description>
      <author>Shengyu Ma, Qiang Fu, Jiecai Han, Yu&#8208;Chong Tai, Xianjie Wang, Zhihua Zhang, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202316544</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Structural Optimization for the Supported Metal System Based on Hybrid Approach Combining Bayesian Optimization with Local Search</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01265</link>
      <description>Shinyoung Bae, Dongjae Shin, H. Jin Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Jong Min Lee, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391847110

                Numerous systematic methods have been developed to search for the global minimum of the potential energy surface, which corresponds to the optimal atomic structure. However, the majority of them still demand a substantial computing load due to the relaxation process that is embedded as an inner step inside the algorithm. Here, we propose a hybrid approach that combines Bayesian optimization (BO) and a local search that circumvents the relaxation step and efficiently finds the optimum structure, particularly in supported metal systems. The hybridization strategy combining the capabilities of BO&#8217;s effective exploration and the local search&#8217;s fast convergence expedites structural search. In addition, the formulation of physical constraints regarding the materials system and the feature of screening structure similarity enhance the computational efficiency of the proposed method. The proposed algorithm is demonstrated in two supported metal systems, showing the potential of the proposed method in the field of structural optimization.</description>
      <author>Shinyoung Bae, Dongjae Shin, H. Jin Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Jong Min Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron transport kinetics via ZnO with ultralow Fe dopant for stable oxygen reduction to H2O2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149527</link>
      <description>Xingchen Chai, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Lei Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391847886

                The two-electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e&#8722; ORR) is a promising approach to obtain hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) from oxygen in a friend manner. However, the 4e&#8722; ORR being the thermodynamically preferred route to H2O is always competes with the 2e&#8722; route. Herein, the ultralow iron was doped into ZnO through a solution combustion synthesis to construct an active and stable catalyst for 2e&#8722; ORR. In alkaline conditions, the catalyst exhibits a H2O2 production rate of 3.8 mol gcat&#8722;1h&#8722;1 and selectivity of more than 95 % with a Faraday efficiency of 88.6 % &#177; 2.2 %. More importantly, it shows a negligible activity decay with a durability of 500 h, representing the best stability performance among all the metal oxide catalysts. Furthermore, the catalyst exhibits an efficient electrochemical degradation ability of model organic pollutants in alkaline conditions. Experiments and theoretical calculations have demonstrated that the substitution defects generated by trace Fe doping promote the interfacial 2e&#8722; ORR transfer rate, leading to a high H2O2 selectivity. This work provides a facile but efficient strategy for the construction of carbon-free metal oxide electrocatalysts for H2O2 production.</description>
      <author>Xingchen Chai, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Evolution Mediated by Sulphur Vacancies and Substitutional Mn in Few-Layered Molybdenum Disulphide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101524</link>
      <description>Mouna Rafei, Alexis Pi&#241;eiro-Garc&#237;a, Xiuyu Wu, Dimitrios K. Perivoliotis, Thomas W&#229;gberg, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391848003

                MoS2 is widely praised as a promising replacement for Pt as electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), but even today, it still suffers from low performance. This issue is tackled by using Mn3+ as surface modifier to trigger sulphur vacancy formation and enhance electron transport in few-layered 2H MoS2. Only 10 at% of Mn is sufficient to transform the semiconductive MoS2 into an active HER electrocatalyst. The insertion of Mn reduces both HER onset potential and Tafel slope which allows to reach -100 mA cm-2 at an overpotential of 206 mV, ten times larger of what undoped MoS2 can achieve. The enhanced activity arises because Mn3+ introduces electronic states near the conduction band, promote sulphur vacancies, and increases the hydrogen adsorption. In addition to its facile production and extended shelf-life, Mn-MoS2 exhibit an efficiency of 73% at 800 mA cm-2@2.0 V when used in proton exchange membrane water electrolysers.</description>
      <author>Mouna Rafei, Alexis Pi&#241;eiro-Garc&#237;a, Xiuyu Wu, Dimitrios K. Perivoliotis, Thomas W&#229;gberg, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation on the strain engineering control of TiC as tunable high-efficiency bifunctional cathode materials for Lithium&#8211;Sulfur batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159714</link>
      <description>Mingyang Wang, Jianjun Mao, Yudong Pang, Xilin Zhang, Zongxian Yang, Zhansheng Lu, Shuting Yang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391848483

                Developing efficient cathode materials and strategies to suppress the shuttle effect and promote the reaction kinetics were the key scientific issues for the development of high performance lithium&#8211;sulfur (Li&#8211;S) batteries. Modify the properties of a material through strain engineering is an effective strategy to enhance the performance of adsorption and catalysis ability for special species. In this paper, first-principles calculations were carried out to investigate the anchoring effect and electrochemical performance of TiC(0 0 1) subjected to biaxial symmetric mechanical (compressive and tensile) strains. The results demonstrate that the adsorption energies of the lithium polysulfides (LiPSs) were enhanced monotonically and the metallic properties were also remaining along with the compressive strain to tensile strain. In addition, an appropriate strain could reduce the migration barrier of Li ions, the dissociation barrier of Li2S and the Gibbs free energy of the sulfur reduction reaction (SRR) to realize the rapid charge/discharge processes. Especially, the p-band center of carbon atoms in TiC was proposed as an effective descriptor to identify the adsorption and catalysis ability of the anchoring materials under biaxial strain. Our results indicate that strain engineering is a promising strategy to improve the comprehensive performance of anchoring materials in Li &#8722; S batteries.</description>
      <author>Mingyang Wang, Jianjun Mao, Yudong Pang, Xilin Zhang, Zongxian Yang, Zhansheng Lu, Shuting Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel nanotubes based on methylene-bridged cycloparaphenyleneas as highly efficient catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114502</link>
      <description>Hazem Abdelsalam, Omar H. Abd&#8208;Elkader, Mohamed A. Saad, Mahmoud A. S. Sakr, Qinfang Zhang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391849061

                Nanotubes constructed from methylene-bridged cycloparaphenyleneas (MCPPs) are investigated using density functional theory. The dynamical stability is indicated by the real vibrational frequencies of the infrared spectra. MCPPs are semiconductors with an energy gap of &#8764; 2.9 eV that significantly decreases in the finite nanotubes. This decrease is a result of the interactive molecular orbitals that are localized at the pentagonal rings linking MCPPs. The UV-vis spectra show that transitions from the highest occupied and neighbor orbitals to the lowest unoccupied orbital dominate the primary absorption peaks. Oxygen evolution reaction shows that all the reaction intermediates, HO, O, and HOO are adsorbed by the pentagonal active sites. The considered nanotubes show good catalytic performance but the best performance is observed in the wider nanotubes with an overpotential of 0.10 V. This remarkably low overpotential in addition to the abundant active sites makes finite nanotubes from MCPPs exceptional catalysts for oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Hazem Abdelsalam, Omar H. Abd&#8208;Elkader, Mohamed A. Saad, Mahmoud A. S. Sakr, Qinfang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the bifunctional oxygen reduction/evolution reaction activity of atomically dispersed zirconium on graphene using boron and nitrogen co-dopants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104070</link>
      <description>Jessie Manopo, Pangeran Niti Kusumo, Yolanda Rati, Yudi Darma, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391849111

                We study the impact of surface engineering using boron and nitrogen co-dopant on the activity of atomically dispersed zirconium on graphene for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR/OER). We discover that the presence of boron and nitrogen co-dopants enhances the activity of the reactions. The O-Zr-N4-B active site displays excellent bifunctionality for the reactions with ORR overpotential (&#951;ORR) of 0.33 V and OER overpotential (&#951;OER) of 0.23 V. However, the formation of another active site, O-Zr-N4-BN, may dominate in certain synthesis conditions, but it exhibits poorer ORR/OER bifunctionality. To understand the origin of the bifunctionality, we identify the Gibbs free energy (&#916;G) that strongly correlates with the overpotential of the reactions. We discover that the regulation of -OH binding energy is the origin of ORR/OER bifunctionality. Boron doping weakens the interaction between Zr and the -OH adsorbate, which can be attributed to reduced charge density. Further addition of nitrogen doping strengthens the interaction between Zr and the oxygen-containing intermediate. These findings have the potential to aid in the development of improved catalyst materials for effective bifunctional oxygen reduction and evolution reactions.</description>
      <author>Jessie Manopo, Pangeran Niti Kusumo, Yolanda Rati, Yudi Darma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen peroxide electrogeneration from O2 electroreduction: A review focusing on carbon electrocatalysts and environmental applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.141456</link>
      <description>Aline B. Trench, Caio Machado Fernandes, Jo&#227;o Paulo Moura, Lanna E.B. Lucchetti, Thays de Souza Lima, Vanessa S. Antonin, J. Almeida, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto, Irma Robles, Artur J. Motheo, Marcos R.V. Lanza, Mauro C. Santos, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391849884

                Hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) stands as one of the foremost utilized oxidizing agents in modern times. The established method for its production involves the intricate and costly anthraquinone process. However, a promising alternative pathway is the electrochemical hydrogen peroxide production, accomplished through the oxygen reduction reaction via a 2-electron pathway. This method not only simplifies the production process but also upholds environmental sustainability, especially when compared to the conventional anthraquinone method. In this review paper, recent works from the literature focusing on the 2-electron oxygen reduction reaction promoted by carbon electrocatalysts are summarized. The practical applications of these materials in the treatment of effluents contaminated with different pollutants (drugs, dyes, pesticides, and herbicides) are presented. Water treatment aiming to address these issues can be achieved through advanced oxidation electrochemical processes such as electro-Fenton, solar-electro-Fenton, and photo-electro-Fenton. These processes are discussed in detail in this work and the possible radicals that degrade the pollutants in each case are highlighted. The review broadens its scope to encompass contemporary computational simulations focused on the 2-electron oxygen reduction reaction, employing different models to describe carbon-based electrocatalysts. Finally, perspectives and future challenges in the area of carbon-based electrocatalysts for H2O2 electrogeneration are discussed. This review paper presents a forward-oriented viewpoint of present innovations and pragmatic implementations, delineating forthcoming challenges and prospects of this ever-evolving field.</description>
      <author>Aline B. Trench, Caio Machado Fernandes, Jo&#227;o Paulo Moura, Lanna E.B. Lucchetti, Thays de Souza Lima, Vanessa S. Antonin, J. Almeida, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto, Irma Robles, Artur J. Motheo, Marcos R.V. Lanza, Mauro C. Santos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.141456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the confinement effect by a sandwiched subnanoreactor on the electrocatalytic performance for the nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159715</link>
      <description>B. Wang, Jianjun Diao, Qiang Fu, Yuchen Ma, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391850356

                Nanoconfinement effect allows precise tuning of catalyst performance by providing a spatially confined (sub)nanoscale environment for reaction systems. For the confined catalysts constructed from two-dimensional materials and transition metals, it can be achieved experimentally by wrapping metal nanoparticles in layers of carbon or other similar materials. Here, we propose a new type of confined catalyst composed of iron clusters sandwiched between graphitic carbon nitride and black phosphorus monolayers, and investigate its performance in the nitrogen reduction reaction by first-principles simulations. It is found that the overpotential at the Fe active site exhibits a significant decrease from 0.82 V to 0.49 V after the formation of the confined interfacial microenvironment, which is attributed to the spatial confinement by the two-dimensional monolayers and the change in binding patterns between the adsorbed species and the iron cluster. The corresponding selectivity in competition with the hydrogen evolution reaction is also improved to a certain extent. Moreover, the appearance of electronic states of the black phosphorus overlayer at the Fermi level further promotes the carrier transport in the electrochemical processes. Our work demonstrates the role of the nanoconfinement effect in enhancing the electrocatalytic performance and may shed new light on the rational design of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>B. Wang, Jianjun Diao, Qiang Fu, Yuchen Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Transition&#8208;Metal Atom Anchored on a Rhenium Disulfide Monolayer: An Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution and Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308416</link>
      <description>Meiling Pan, X. Cui, Qun Jing, Haiming Duan, Fangping Ouyang, Rong Wu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391880793

                Abstract Developing efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) bifunctional electrocatalysts is attractive for rechargeable metal&#8211;air batteries. Meanwhile, single metal atoms embedded in 2D layered transition metal chalcogenides (TMDs) have become a very promising catalyst. Recently, many attentions have been paid to the 2D ReS 2 electrocatalyst due to its unique distorted octahedral 1T&#8217; crystal structure and thickness&#8208;independent electronic properties. Here, the catalytic activity of different transition metal (TM) atoms embedded in ReS 2 using the density functional theory is investigated. The results indicate that TM@ReS 2 exhibits outstanding thermal stability, good electrical conductivity, and electron transfer for electrochemical reactions. And the Ir@ReS 2 and Pd@ReS 2 can be used as OER/ORR bifunctional electrocatalysts with a lower overpotential for OER (&#951; OER ) of 0.44 V and overpotentials for ORR (&#951; ORR ) of 0.26 V and 0.27 V, respectively. The excellent catalytic activity is attributed to the optimal adsorption strength for oxygen intermediates coming from the effective modulation of the electronic structure of ReS 2 after Ir/Pd doping. The results can help to deeply understand the catalytic activity of TM@ReS 2 and develop novel and highly efficient OER/ORR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Meiling Pan, X. Cui, Qun Jing, Haiming Duan, Fangping Ouyang, Rong Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Hierarchical MOF-Derived Defect-Rich NiFe Spinel Ferrite as a Highly Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Redox Reactions in Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17789</link>
      <description>Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Wathanyu Kao-ian, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Piyasan Praserthdam, Wanwisa Limphirat, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Tetsu Yonezawa, Soorathep Kheawhom, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391881989

                The strategy of defect engineering is increasingly recognized for its pivotal role in modulating the electronic structure, thereby significantly improving the electrocatalytic performance of materials. In this study, we present defect-enriched nickel and iron oxides as highly active and cost-effective electrocatalysts, denoted as Ni0.6Fe2.4O4@NC, derived from NiFe-based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) for oxygen reduction reactions (ORR) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER). XANES and EXAFS confirm that the crystals have a distorted structure and metal vacancies. The cation defect-rich Ni0.6Fe2.4O4@NC electrocatalyst exhibits exceptional ORR and OER activities (&#916;E = 0.68 V). Mechanistic pathways of electrochemical reactions are studied by DFT calculations. Furthermore, a rechargeable zinc&#8211;air battery (RZAB) using the Ni0.6Fe2.4O4@NC catalyst demonstrates a peak power density of 187 mW cm&#8211;2 and remarkable long-term cycling stability. The flexible solid-state ZAB using the Ni0.6Fe2.4O4@NC catalyst exhibits a power density of 66 mW cm&#8211;2. The proposed structural design strategy allows for the rational design of electronic delocalization of cation defect-rich NiFe spinel ferrite attached to ultrathin N-doped graphitic carbon sheets in order to enhance active site availability and facilitate mass and electron transport.</description>
      <author>Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Wathanyu Kao-ian, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Piyasan Praserthdam, Wanwisa Limphirat, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Tetsu Yonezawa, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress of Transition Metal Selenides for Electrochemical Oxygen Reduction to Hydrogen Peroxide: From Catalyst Design to Electrolyzers Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309448</link>
      <description>Yingnan Wang, Caidi Han, Li Ma, Tigang Duan, Yue Du, Jian Wu, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Jian Gao, Xiaodong Zhu, Y. Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391882047

                Abstract Hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) is a highly value&#8208;added and environmental&#8208;friendly chemical with various applications. The production of H 2 O 2 by electrocatalytic 2e &#8722; oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) has emerged as a promising alternative to the energy&#8208;intensive anthraquinone process. High selectivity Catalysts combining with superior activity are critical for the efficient electrosynthesis of H 2 O 2 . Earth&#8208;abundant transition metal selenides (TMSs) being discovered as a classic of stable, low&#8208;cost, highly active and selective catalysts for electrochemical 2e &#8722; ORR. These features come from the relatively large atomic radius of selenium element, the metal&#8208;like properties and the abundant reserves. Moreover, compared with the advanced noble metal or single&#8208;atom catalysts, the kinetic current density of TMSs for H 2 O 2 generation is higher in acidic solution, which enable them to become suitable catalyst candidates. Herein, the recent progress of TMSs for ORR to H 2 O 2 is systematically reviewed. The effects of TMSs electrocatalysts on the activity, selectivity and stability of ORR to H 2 O 2 are summarized. It is intended to provide an insight from catalyst design and corresponding reaction mechanisms to the device setup, and to discuss the relationship between structure and activity.</description>
      <author>Yingnan Wang, Caidi Han, Li Ma, Tigang Duan, Yue Du, Jian Wu, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Jian Gao, Xiaodong Zhu, Y. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Methanesulfonates with Mixed Anionic Groups with Large Band Gaps and Enhanced Birefringence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c03278</link>
      <description>Mingli Liang, Yujie Zhang, Eugene Izvarin, Michael J. Waters, James M. Rondinelli, P. Shiv Halasyamani, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391882486

                Four new metal methanesulfonates with mixed anionic groups, Bi(SeO3)(CH3SO3) (1), Bi(TeO3)(CH3SO3) (2), Ba(BF4)(CH3SO3) (3), and Ba2(BF4)(CH3SO3)3(H2O)3 (4), have been successfully synthesized. Compounds 1 and 2 are isomorphic and exhibit a two-dimensional (2D) layered structure. Stereoactive lone pairs are observed with Se4+, Te4+, and Bi3+. Compound 3 features a three-dimensional (3D) structure formed by connecting [Ba(CH3SO3)]+ layers via BF4 tetrahedra, whereas compound 4 features a 2D layered structure, where the BF4 tetrahedra are positioned on both sides of the [Ba2(CH3SO3)3]+ layers. The ultraviolet&#8211;visible&#8211;near-infrared (UV&#8211;vis-NIR) spectra indicate that compounds 1 and 2 have absorption edges at 270 and 274 nm, whereas compounds 3 and 4, with absorption edges below 200 nm, are characterized as deep-UV crystals. Calculations were performed to determine the absorption edges, and comparative analysis indicates a significant enhancement in the calculated birefringence values compared to analogous compounds.</description>
      <author>Mingli Liang, Yujie Zhang, Eugene Izvarin, Michael J. Waters, James M. Rondinelli, P. Shiv Halasyamani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c03278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Hot-Carrier Distributions of Plasmonic Nanostructures through Surface Alloying</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c11418</link>
      <description>Jakub Fojt, Tuomas P. Rossi, Priyank V. Kumar, Paul Erhart, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391884518

                Alloyed metal nanoparticles are a promising platform for plasmonically enabled hot-carrier generation, which can be used to drive photochemical reactions. Although the non-plasmonic component in these systems has been investigated for its potential to enhance catalytic activity, its capacity to affect the photochemical process favorably has been underexplored by comparison. Here, we study the impact of surface alloy species and concentration on hot-carrier generation in Ag nanoparticles. By first-principles simulations, we photoexcite the localized surface plasmon, allow it to dephase, and calculate spatially and energetically resolved hot-carrier distributions. We show that the presence of non-noble species in the topmost surface layer drastically enhances hot-hole generation at the surface at the expense of hot-hole generation in the bulk, due to the additional d-type states that are introduced to the surface. The energy of the generated holes can be tuned by choice of the alloyant, with systematic trends across the d-band block. Already low surface alloy concentrations have a large impact, with a saturation of the enhancement effect typically close to 75% of a monolayer. Hot-electron generation at the surface is hindered slightly by alloying, but here a judicious choice of the alloy composition allows one to strike a balance between hot electrons and holes. Our work underscores the promise of utilizing multicomponent nanoparticles to achieve enhanced control over plasmonic catalysis and provides guidelines for how hot-carrier distributions can be tailored by designing the electronic structure of the surface through alloying.</description>
      <author>Jakub Fojt, Tuomas P. Rossi, Priyank V. Kumar, Paul Erhart</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c11418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Effects of Varying the Ti Concentration on the Mechanical Properties of Cu&#8211;Ti Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c07561</link>
      <description>Vasileios Fotopoulos, Corey S. O&#8217;Hern, Mark D. Shattuck, Alexander L. Shluger, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933315

                The mechanical properties of CuTi alloys have been characterized extensively through experimental studies. However, a detailed understanding of why the strength of Cu increases after a small fraction of Ti atoms are added to the alloy is still missing. In this work, we address this question using density functional theory (DFT) and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations with the modified embedded atom method (MEAM) interatomic potentials. First, we performed calculations of the uniaxial tension deformations of small bicrystalline Cu cells using DFT static simulations. We then carried out uniaxial tension deformations on much larger bicrystalline and polycrystalline Cu cells by using MEAM MD simulations. In bicrystalline Cu, the inclusion of Ti increases the grain boundary separation energy and the maximum tensile stress. The DFT calculations demonstrate that the increase in the tensile stress can be attributed to an increase in the local charge density arising from Ti. MEAM simulations in larger bicrystalline systems have shown that increasing the Ti concentration decreases the density of the stacking faults. This observation is enhanced in polycrystalline Cu, where the addition of Ti atoms, even at concentrations as low as 1.5 atomic (at.) %, increases the yield strength and elastic modulus of the material compared to pure Cu. Under uniaxial tensile loading, the addition of small amounts of Ti hinders the formation of partial Shockley dislocations in the grain boundaries of Cu, leading to a reduced level of local deformation. These results shed light on the role of Ti in determining the mechanical properties of polycrystalline Cu and enable the engineering of grain boundaries and the inclusion of Ti to improve degradation resistance.</description>
      <author>Vasileios Fotopoulos, Corey S. O&#8217;Hern, Mark D. Shattuck, Alexander L. Shluger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c07561</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
