<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:43:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst Selection over an Electrochemical Reductive Coupling Reaction toward Direct Electrosynthesis of Oxime from NO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; and Aldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14687</link>
      <description>Wei Chen, Yandong Wu, Yimin Jiang, Guangxing Yang, Yingying Li, Lei Xu, Ming Yang, Binbin Wu, Yuping Pan, Yanzhi Xu, Qinghua Liu, Chen Chen, Feng Peng, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391952084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Chen, Yandong Wu, Yimin Jiang, Guangxing Yang, Yingying Li, Lei Xu, Ming Yang, Binbin Wu, Yuping Pan, Yanzhi Xu, Qinghua Liu, Chen Chen, Feng Peng, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14687</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering &lt;scp&gt;Pt&#8208;Cu&lt;/scp&gt; diatomics electrocatalysts enables highly efficient urea synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18403</link>
      <description>Fei Lu, Jingnan Wang, Yuhang Gao, Yan Wang, Xi Wu, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391954090

                Abstract The rational design of novel heterogeneous urea&#8208;synthesis electrocatalysts (HUECs) poses an immense challenge due to their inherent complexity. Moreover, the ideal HUECs must also possess the ability to suppress two major competitive reactions: hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and N 2 reduction reaction (NRR). However, this daunting task can be made feasible with the use of heterogeneous diatomic catalysts that have been supported by unambiguous theoretical models. Herein, we report a design for an efficient platinum&#8208;copper diatomic electrocatalyst (Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 ) for urea production based on theoretical predictions. Through rational screening of 8 Pt&#8208;diatomics HUECs, we discovered that Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 can effectively suppress HER and NRR while promoting the adsorption of CO 2 and N 2 . Subsequently, we experimentally fabricated Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 which exhibited optimal urea electrosynthesis activity of 51.71 mol urea mol Pt+Cu &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 . Pt 1 &#8208;Cu 1 diatomics in Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 could synergistically encourage the activation of *CO 2 /*N 2 and crucial C&#8208;N coupling with an optimal energy barrier (0.25 eV).</description>
      <author>Fei Lu, Jingnan Wang, Yuhang Gao, Yan Wang, Xi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optoelectronic and transport properties of vacancy-ordered double-perovskite halides: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.024036</link>
      <description>Supriti Ghorui, Jiban Kangsabanik, M. Aslam, Aftab Alam, Physical review applied. 21(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391954370

                In the search for stable lead-free perovskites, vacancy-ordered double perovskites (VODPs), ${\mathrm{A}}_{2}{\mathrm{BX}}_{6}$, have emerged as a promising class of materials for solar harvesting owing to their nontoxicity, better stability, and unique optoelectronic properties. Recently, this class has been explored for a wide range of applications, such as photovoltaics, photodetectors, photocatalysis, and light-emitting diodes. Here, we present the stability and the key physical attributes of a few selected compounds in a systematic manner using state-of-the-art first-principles calculations. A careful structural and stability analysis via simulation of convex hulls and compositional phase diagrams for different structural prototypes discloses 14 stable compounds and one metastable compound in this class. Electronic structure calculations using hybrid functionals reveals that six compounds possess band gaps in the ideal visible region. These six compounds, namely ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Sn}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Pd}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Te}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Ti}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Pt}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, and ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Pd}\mathrm{Br}}_{6}$, show high optical absorption ($\ensuremath{\approx}{10}^{5}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{cm}}^{\ensuremath{-}1}$), giving rise to high spectroscopic limited maximum efficiency (15--23%) in the thin-film thickness range. Close inspection of the transport properties reveals polar optical phonon scattering to be the dominant mechanism limiting overall mobility. Further analysis of the polaron excitations discloses the possibility of large polaron formation at low to moderate defect concentrations. At high defect concentrations, ionized impurity scattering takes over. Such analysis can be extremely useful for choosing the optimal growth conditions for a given material intended to be used for a desired application. Additionally, a few selected compounds show moderate to high electron mobility values ($\ensuremath{\sim}13--63\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{cm}}^{2}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{V}}^{\ensuremath{-}1}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{s}}^{\ensuremath{-}1}$) at room temperature. Overall, the present study paves an important path to help design VODPs as lead-free potential candidates for future optoelectronic applications.</description>
      <author>Supriti Ghorui, Jiban Kangsabanik, M. Aslam, Aftab Alam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.024036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into the Selective Electrocatalytic Reduction of NO to NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; on a Two-Dimensional Cu-Benzylthiol Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Nanostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05958</link>
      <description>Hao Yin, Minghao Gong, Pengbo Lyu, Ran Wang, Lizhong Sun, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391956639

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Yin, Minghao Gong, Pengbo Lyu, Ran Wang, Lizhong Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Fe and Co binary single atoms based air cathodes for high performance and ultra-stable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103286</link>
      <description>Yu-Chieh Ting, Chih&#8208;Chieh Cheng, Shin&#8208;Hong Lin, Ting Lin, Po&#8208;Wei Chen, F.Y. Yen, Shuwen Chang, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu, Energy Storage Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391957760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Chieh Ting, Chih&#8208;Chieh Cheng, Shin&#8208;Hong Lin, Ting Lin, Po&#8208;Wei Chen, F.Y. Yen, Shuwen Chang, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Positivity preserving density matrix minimization at finite temperatures via square root</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0189864</link>
      <description>Jacob M. Leamer, William Dawson, Denys I. Bondar, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391960448

                We present a Wave Operator Minimization (WOM) method for calculating the Fermi&#8211;Dirac density matrix for electronic structure problems at finite temperature while preserving physicality by construction using the wave operator, i.e., the square root of the density matrix. WOM models cooling a state initially at infinite temperature down to the desired finite temperature. We consider both the grand canonical (constant chemical potential) and canonical (constant number of electrons) ensembles. Additionally, we show that the number of steps required for convergence is independent of the number of atoms in the system. We hope that the discussion and results presented in this article reinvigorate interest in density matrix minimization methods.</description>
      <author>Jacob M. Leamer, William Dawson, Denys I. Bondar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0189864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Performance Iridium&#8211;Molybdenum Oxide Electrocatalysts for Water Oxidation in Acid: Bayesian Optimization Discovery and Experimental Testing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13491</link>
      <description>Jacques A. Esterhuizen, Aarti Mathur, Bryan R. Goldsmith, Suljo Linic, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391963993

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jacques A. Esterhuizen, Aarti Mathur, Bryan R. Goldsmith, Suljo Linic</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed Stochastic-Deterministic Approach for Many-Body Perturbation Theory Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.132.086401</link>
      <description>Aaron R. Altman, Smriti K. Kundu, Felipe H. da Jornada, Physical Review Letters. 132(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391972280

                We present an approach for $GW$ calculations of quasiparticle energies with quasiquadratic scaling by approximating high-energy contributions to the Green's function in its Lehmann representation with effective stochastic vectors. The method is easy to implement without altering the $GW$ code, converges rapidly with stochastic parameters, and treats systems of various dimensionality and screening response. Our calculations on a 5.75\ifmmode^\circ\else\textdegree\fi{} twisted ${\mathrm{MoS}}_{2}$ bilayer show how large-scale $GW$ methods include geometry relaxations and electronic correlations on an equal basis in structurally nontrivial materials.</description>
      <author>Aaron R. Altman, Smriti K. Kundu, Felipe H. da Jornada</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.132.086401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni-doping effects on formation and migration of oxygen vacancies in SrFe&lt;sub&gt;1&#8722;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&lt;i&gt;&#948;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; oxygen carriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ra08321g</link>
      <description>Tian Tian Jia, Yifei Hao, Hua Hao, Zhi Zhang, RSC Advances. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391974220

                Ni is a promising B-site doping element capable of improving the oxygen carrier performance of SrFeO 3 perovskite.</description>
      <author>Tian Tian Jia, Yifei Hao, Hua Hao, Zhi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ra08321g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated analysis of surface facets: the example of cesium telluride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01224-7</link>
      <description>Holger-Dietrich Sa&#223;nick, Caterina Cocchi, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391982702

                Abstract High-throughput screening combined with ab initio calculations is a powerful tool to explore technologically relevant materials characterized by complex configurational spaces. Despite the impressive developments achieved in this field in the last few years, most studies still focus on bulk materials, although the relevant processes for energy conversion, production, and storage occur on surfaces. Herein, we present an automatized computational scheme that is capable of calculating surface properties in inorganic crystals from first principles in a high-throughput fashion. After introducing the method and its implementation, we showcase its applicability, focusing on four polymorphs of Cs 2 Te, an established photocathode material for particle accelerators, considering slabs with low Miller indices and different terminations. This analysis gives insight into how the surface composition, accessible through the proposed high-throughput screening method, impacts the electronic properties and, ultimately, the photoemission performance. The developed scheme offers new opportunities for automated computational studies beyond bulk materials.</description>
      <author>Holger-Dietrich Sa&#223;nick, Caterina Cocchi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01224-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data&#8208;Driven Screening of Pivotal Subunits in Edge&#8208;Anchored Single Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400107</link>
      <description>Qitong Ye, Xiao Su Yi, Cai&#8208;Zhuang Wang, Tao Zhang, Yipu Liu, Shiwei Lin, Hong Jin Fan, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391984271

                Abstract Oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are key reactions in diverse energy conversion devices, highlighting the importance of efficient catalysts. Edge&#8208;anchored single atom catalysts (E&#8208;SACs) emerge as a special class of atomic structure, but the detailed configuration and its correlation with catalytic activity remain little explored. Herein, a total of 78 E&#8208;SACs (E&#8208;TM&#8208;N x &#8208;C) have been constructed based on 26 transition metal (TM) species with three coordination patterns. Using structural stability and ORR/OER catalytic activity as the evaluation criteria, a few catalytic structures comparable to Pt (111) for ORR and IrO 2 (110) for OER are screened based on high&#8208;throughput calculations. The screening results unveil that the E&#8208;Rh&#8208;N 4 &#8208;C configuration exhibits most efficient bifunctional activity for both ORR and OER with an overpotential of 0.38 and 0.61 V, respectively. Electronic structure analysis confirms the distinctive edge effects on the electronic properties of TM and N species, and the feature importance derived from machine learning illustrates the efficacy of E&#8208;TM&#8208;N x subunit configuration in determining the catalytic activity of E&#8208;SACs. Finally, the trained Gradient Boosting Regression (GBR) model exhibits acceptable accuracy in predicting the OH intermediates adsorption strength for E&#8208;SACs, thereby paving the way for expanding catalytic structures based on E&#8208;SACs.</description>
      <author>Qitong Ye, Xiao Su Yi, Cai&#8208;Zhuang Wang, Tao Zhang, Yipu Liu, Shiwei Lin, Hong Jin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning guides the discovery of high-performance HEA catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.1004118</link>
      <description>J. Wang, Min Wei, Junyu Zhang, IntechOpen eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391995369

                High performance catalysts are crucial to generating clean fuels, reducing the impact of global warming, and providing solutions to environmental pollution. Improved processes for catalyst design and a better understanding of catalytic processes are key for improving the effectiveness and activities. HEAs typically have at least four principal elements, this atomic structure gives them unique properties that have applications and excellent performance in a variety of fields including catalysis. The complexity of HEAs makes challenge for computational researchers, providing promising opportunities for the application of machine learning. Recent advances in data science have great potential to accelerate catalyst research, particularly the rapid exploration of large materials chemistry spaces through machine learning. Here a comprehensive and critical review of machine learning techniques used in HEA catalysis research is provided. Sources of HEA catalyst data and current approaches to represent these materials by mathematical features are described, the most commonly used machine learning methods summarized, and the quality and utility of catalyst models evaluated. Illustrations of how machine learning models are applied to novel HEA catalysts discovery and used to reveal catalytic reaction mechanisms are provided.</description>
      <author>J. Wang, Min Wei, Junyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.1004118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probe the Dynamic Adsorption and Phase Transition of Underpotential Deposition Processes at Electrode&#8211;Electrolyte Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03899</link>
      <description>Kuo-Hao Chen, Fatemeh Fathi, Tristan Maxson, Mezbah Hossain, Emil F. Khisamutdinov, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, Xiangqun Zeng, Zhihai Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392044078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kuo-Hao Chen, Fatemeh Fathi, Tristan Maxson, Mezbah Hossain, Emil F. Khisamutdinov, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, Xiangqun Zeng, Zhihai Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supervised AI and Deep Neural Networks to Evaluate High-Entropy Alloys as Reduction Catalysts in Aqueous Environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05017</link>
      <description>Rafael B. Araujo, Tomas Edvinsson, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392044082

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rafael B. Araujo, Tomas Edvinsson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complementary probes for the electrochemical interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41570-024-00575-5</link>
      <description>Ernest Pastor, Zan Lian, Lu Xia, David &#201;cija, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, Sara Barja, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jordi Arbiol, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer, Nature Reviews Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392044291

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ernest Pastor, Zan Lian, Lu Xia, David &#201;cija, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, Sara Barja, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jordi Arbiol, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41570-024-00575-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learned atomic cluster expansion potentials for fast and quantum-accurate thermal simulations of wurtzite AlN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0188905</link>
      <description>Yang Guang, Y. Liu, Lei Yang, Bing&#8208;Yang Cao, Journal of Applied Physics. 135(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392048091

                Thermal transport in wurtzite aluminum nitride (w-AlN) significantly affects the performance and reliability of corresponding electronic devices, particularly when lattice strains inevitably impact the thermal properties of w-AlN in practical applications. To accurately model the thermal properties of w-AlN with high efficiency, we develop a machine learning interatomic potential based on the atomic cluster expansion (ACE) framework. The predictive power of the ACE potential against density functional theory (DFT) is demonstrated across a broad range of properties of w-AlN, including ground-state lattice parameters, specific heat capacity, coefficients of thermal expansion, bulk modulus, and harmonic phonon dispersions. Validation of lattice thermal conductivity is further carried out by comparing the ACE-predicted values to the DFT calculations and experiments, exhibiting the overall capability of our ACE potential in sufficiently describing anharmonic phonon interactions. As a practical application, we perform a lattice dynamics analysis using the potential to unravel the effects of biaxial strains on thermal conductivity and phonon properties of w-AlN, which is identified as a significant tuning factor for near-junction thermal design of w-AlN-based electronics.</description>
      <author>Yang Guang, Y. Liu, Lei Yang, Bing&#8208;Yang Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0188905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scholar Metrics Scraper (SMS): automated retrieval of citation and author data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/frma.2024.1335454</link>
      <description>Y. S. Cao, Nicole A. Cheung, Dean Giustini, Jeffrey LeDue, Timothy H. Murphy, Frontiers in Research Metrics and Analytics. 9(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392057301

                Academic departments, research clusters and evaluators analyze author and citation data to measure research impact and to support strategic planning. We created Scholar Metrics Scraper (SMS) to automate the retrieval of bibliometric data for a group of researchers. The project contains Jupyter notebooks that take a list of researchers as an input and exports a CSV file of citation metrics from Google Scholar (GS) to visualize the group's impact and collaboration. A series of graph outputs are also available. SMS is an open solution for automating the retrieval and visualization of citation data.</description>
      <author>Y. S. Cao, Nicole A. Cheung, Dean Giustini, Jeffrey LeDue, Timothy H. Murphy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/frma.2024.1335454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triple Play of Band Gap, Interband, and Plasmonic Excitations for Enhanced Catalytic Activity in Pd/H&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;MoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles in the Visible Region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17101</link>
      <description>Leticia S. Bezerra, Samir A. Belhout, Shiqi Wang, Jhon Quiroz, P. M. S. Oliveira, Shwetha Shetty, George J. M. Rocha, Hugo Leandro Sousa dos Santos, Sana Frindy, Freddy E. Oropeza, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Antti&#8208;Jussi Kallio, Simo Huotari, Wenyi Huo, Pedro H. C. Camargo, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392058068

                Plasmonic photocatalysis has been limited by the high cost and scalability of plasmonic materials, such as Ag and Au. By focusing on earth-abundant photocatalyst/plasmonic materials (HxMoO3) and Pd as a catalyst, we addressed these challenges by developing a solventless mechanochemical synthesis of Pd/HxMoO3 and optimizing photocatalytic activities in the visible range. We investigated the effect of HxMoO3 band gap excitation (at 427 nm), Pd interband transitions (at 427 nm), and HxMoO3 localized surface plasmon resonance (LSPR) excitation (at 640 nm) over photocatalytic activities toward the hydrogen evolution and phenylacetylene hydrogenation as model reactions. Although both excitation wavelengths led to comparable photoenhancements, a 110% increase was achieved under dual excitation conditions (427 + 640 nm). This was assigned to a synergistic effect of optical excitations that optimized the generation of energetic electrons at the catalytic sites. These results are important for the development of visible-light photocatalysts based on earth-abundant components.</description>
      <author>Leticia S. Bezerra, Samir A. Belhout, Shiqi Wang, Jhon Quiroz, P. M. S. Oliveira, Shwetha Shetty, George J. M. Rocha, Hugo Leandro Sousa dos Santos, Sana Frindy, Freddy E. Oropeza, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Antti&#8208;Jussi Kallio, Simo Huotari, Wenyi Huo, Pedro H. C. Camargo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional SiH/g-C3N4 van der Waals Type-II Heterojunction Photocatalyst: A New Effective and Promising Photocatalytic Material</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14030263</link>
      <description>Qi Wang, Qian Zhu, Lei Cao, Liangdong Fan, Feng Gu, Ying Zhang, Cao Zheng, Shixian Xiong, Liang Xu, Coatings. 14(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392081661

                The two-dimensional layered heterostructure have been demonstrated as an effective method for achieving efficient photocatalytic hydrogen production. In this work, we propose, for the first time, the creation of van der Waals heterostructures from monolayers of SiH and g-C3N4 using first-principle calculations. We also systematically investigated additional properties for the first time, such as the electronic structure and optical behavior of van der Waals heterostructures composed of SiH and g-C3N4 monolayers. The results of this study show that the SiH/g-C3N4 heterostructure is categorized as a type-II heterostructure, which has a bandgap of 2.268 eV. Furthermore, the SiH/g-C3N4 heterostructure interface was observed to efficiently separate and transfer photogenerated charges, resulting in an enhanced photocatalytic redox performance. Moreover, the calculation of HOMO (Highest occupied molecular orbital) and LUMO (Least unoccupied molecular orbital) and charge density difference can further confirm that the SiH/g-C3N4 heterojunction is a type-II heterojunction, which has excellent photocatalytic hydrogen production and water decomposition performance. In addition, the SiH/g-C3N4 heterostructure exhibited excellent HER (Hydrogen evolution reaction) efficiency. This is essential for the process of photocatalytic water splitting. In SiH/g-C3N4 heterojunctions, the redox potential required for water splitting is spanned by the band edge potential. Calculating the absorption spectra, it was discovered that the SiH/g-C3N4 heterostructure possesses outstanding optical properties within the visible-light range, implying its high efficiency in photocatalytic hydrogen production. This research provides a broader research direction for the investigation of novel efficient photocatalysts and offers effective theoretical guidance for future efficient photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Qi Wang, Qian Zhu, Lei Cao, Liangdong Fan, Feng Gu, Ying Zhang, Cao Zheng, Shixian Xiong, Liang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14030263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Advancement of Catalysts for Proton&#8208;Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527831005.ch9</link>
      <description>Yi Cheng, Shuangyin Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392092382

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Cheng, Shuangyin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527831005.ch9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic mechanism of sulfur-nitrogen doping metal single-atom graphene-based catalysts for the conversion of CO2 to CH4: a computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108470</link>
      <description>Xiangying Lv, Jingyuan Guo, Jiewei Zhan, Guo&#8208;Jun Kang, Xiaoxing Liu, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392093379

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangying Lv, Jingyuan Guo, Jiewei Zhan, Guo&#8208;Jun Kang, Xiaoxing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dipole Effect on Oxygen Evolution Reaction of 2D Janus Single-Atom Catalysts: A Case of Rh Anchored on the &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;6&lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt;2-NP Configurations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03148</link>
      <description>Tao Huang, Yaping Zhong, Lei Li, Wan Hui, Can Leng, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392093761

                Catalytic performance of single-atom catalysts (SACs) relies fundamentally on the electronic nature and local coordination environment of the active site. Here, based on a machine-learning (ML)-aided density functional theory (DFT) method, we reveal that the intrinsic dipole in Janus materials has a significant impact on the catalytic activity of SACs, using 2D &#947;-phosphorus carbide (&#947;-PC) as a model system. Specifically, a local dipole around the active site is a key degree to tune the catalytic activity and can be used as an important descriptor with a high feature importance of 17.1% in predicting the difference of adsorption free energy (&#916;GO* &#8211; &#916;GOH*) to assess the activity of the oxygen evolution reaction. As a result, the catalytic performance of SACs can be tuned by an intrinsic dipole, in stark contrast to those external stimuli strategies previously used. These results suggest that dipole engineering and the revolutionary DFT-ML hybrid scheme are novel approaches for designing high-performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Huang, Yaping Zhong, Lei Li, Wan Hui, Can Leng, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protective effects of Pt-N-C single-atom nanozymes against myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45927-3</link>
      <description>Tianbao Ye, Cheng Chen, Di Wang, Chengjie Huang, Zhe Yan, Yu Chen, Xian Jin, Xiuyuan Wang, Yiyang Li, Chengxing Shen, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392094779

                Abstract Effective therapeutic strategies for myocardial ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury remain elusive. Targeting reactive oxygen species (ROS) provides a practical approach to mitigate myocardial damage following reperfusion. In this study, we synthesize an antioxidant nanozyme, equipped with a single-Platinum (Pt)-atom (PtsaN-C), for protecting against I/R injury. PtsaN-C exhibits multiple enzyme-mimicking activities for ROS scavenging with high efficiency and stability. Mechanistic studies demonstrate that the excellent ROS-elimination performance of the single Pt atom center precedes that of the Pt cluster center, owing to its better synergistic effect and metallic electronic property. Systematic in vitro and in vivo studies confirm that PtsaN-C efficiently counteracts ROS, restores cellular homeostasis and prevents apoptotic progression after I/R injury. PtsaN-C also demonstrates good biocompatibility, making it a promising candidate for clinical applications. Our study expands the scope of single-atom nanozyme in combating ROS-induced damage and offers a promising therapeutic avenue for the treatment of I/R injury.</description>
      <author>Tianbao Ye, Cheng Chen, Di Wang, Chengjie Huang, Zhe Yan, Yu Chen, Xian Jin, Xiuyuan Wang, Yiyang Li, Chengxing Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45927-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerium doped graphene-based materials towards oxygen reduction reaction catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108461</link>
      <description>Lanna E.B. Lucchetti, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto, Mauro C. Santos, J. Almeida, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392103933

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lanna E.B. Lucchetti, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto, Mauro C. Santos, J. Almeida</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect engineering in transition&#8208;metal (Fe, Co, and Ni)&#8208;based electrocatalysts for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.485</link>
      <description>Kaili Wu, Chaojie Lyu, Jiarun Cheng, Wenqiang Ding, Jiwen Wu, Qian Wang, Woon&#8208;Ming Lau, Jinlong Zheng, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392104756

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting seems to be an efficient strategy to deal with increasingly serious environmental problems and energy crises but still suffers from the lack of stable and efficient electrocatalysts. Designing practical electrocatalysts by introducing defect engineering, such as hybrid structure, surface vacancies, functional modification, and structural distortions, is proven to be a dependable solution for fabricating electrocatalysts with high catalytic activities, robust stability, and good practicability. This review is an overview of some relevant reports about the effects of defect engineering on the electrocatalytic water splitting performance of electrocatalysts. In detail, the types of defects, the preparation and characterization methods, and catalytic performances of electrocatalysts are presented, emphasizing the effects of the introduced defects on the electronic structures of electrocatalysts and the optimization of the intermediates' adsorption energy throughout the review. Finally, the existing challenges and personal perspectives of possible strategies for enhancing the catalytic performances of electrocatalysts are proposed. An in&#8208;depth understanding of the effects of defect engineering on the catalytic performance of electrocatalysts will light the way to design high&#8208;efficiency electrocatalysts for water splitting and other possible applications.</description>
      <author>Kaili Wu, Chaojie Lyu, Jiarun Cheng, Wenqiang Ding, Jiwen Wu, Qian Wang, Woon&#8208;Ming Lau, Jinlong Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local-environment-guided selection of atomic structures for the development of machine-learning potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0187892</link>
      <description>Renzhe Li, Chuan Zhou, Amankumar Singh, Yong Pei, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392014929

                Machine learning potentials (MLPs) have attracted significant attention in computational chemistry and materials science due to their high accuracy and computational efficiency. The proper selection of atomic structures is crucial for developing reliable MLPs. Insufficient or redundant atomic structures can impede the training process and potentially result in a poor quality MLP. Here, we propose a local-environment-guided screening algorithm for efficient dataset selection in MLP development. The algorithm utilizes a local environment bank to store unique local environments of atoms. The dissimilarity between a particular local environment and those stored in the bank is evaluated using the Euclidean distance. A new structure is selected only if its local environment is significantly different from those already present in the bank. Consequently, the bank is then updated with all the new local environments found in the selected structure. To demonstrate the effectiveness of our algorithm, we applied it to select structures for a Ge system and a Pd13H2 particle system. The algorithm reduced the training data size by around 80% for both without compromising the performance of the MLP models. We verified that the results were independent of the selection and ordering of the initial structures. We also compared the performance of our method with the farthest point sampling algorithm, and the results show that our algorithm is superior in both robustness and computational efficiency. Furthermore, the generated local environment bank can be continuously updated and can potentially serve as a growing database of feature local environments, aiding in efficient dataset maintenance for constructing accurate MLPs.</description>
      <author>Renzhe Li, Chuan Zhou, Amankumar Singh, Yong Pei, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0187892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density functional theory study of dissociative adsorption of O2 on Pd-skin Pd3Cu(1 1 1) surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112876</link>
      <description>Yanlin Yu, Huaizhang Gu, Guangxin Wu, Xuexia Liu, Computational Materials Science. 237(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392139576

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanlin Yu, Huaizhang Gu, Guangxin Wu, Xuexia Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112876</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
