<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:41:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Single Transition&#8208;Metal Atom Anchored on a Rhenium Disulfide Monolayer: An Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution and Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308416</link>
      <description>Meiling Pan, X. Cui, Qun Jing, Haiming Duan, Fangping Ouyang, Rong Wu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391880793

                Abstract Developing efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) bifunctional electrocatalysts is attractive for rechargeable metal&#8211;air batteries. Meanwhile, single metal atoms embedded in 2D layered transition metal chalcogenides (TMDs) have become a very promising catalyst. Recently, many attentions have been paid to the 2D ReS 2 electrocatalyst due to its unique distorted octahedral 1T&#8217; crystal structure and thickness&#8208;independent electronic properties. Here, the catalytic activity of different transition metal (TM) atoms embedded in ReS 2 using the density functional theory is investigated. The results indicate that TM@ReS 2 exhibits outstanding thermal stability, good electrical conductivity, and electron transfer for electrochemical reactions. And the Ir@ReS 2 and Pd@ReS 2 can be used as OER/ORR bifunctional electrocatalysts with a lower overpotential for OER (&#951; OER ) of 0.44 V and overpotentials for ORR (&#951; ORR ) of 0.26 V and 0.27 V, respectively. The excellent catalytic activity is attributed to the optimal adsorption strength for oxygen intermediates coming from the effective modulation of the electronic structure of ReS 2 after Ir/Pd doping. The results can help to deeply understand the catalytic activity of TM@ReS 2 and develop novel and highly efficient OER/ORR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Meiling Pan, X. Cui, Qun Jing, Haiming Duan, Fangping Ouyang, Rong Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Hierarchical MOF-Derived Defect-Rich NiFe Spinel Ferrite as a Highly Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Redox Reactions in Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17789</link>
      <description>Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Wathanyu Kao-ian, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Piyasan Praserthdam, Wanwisa Limphirat, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Tetsu Yonezawa, Soorathep Kheawhom, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391881989

                The strategy of defect engineering is increasingly recognized for its pivotal role in modulating the electronic structure, thereby significantly improving the electrocatalytic performance of materials. In this study, we present defect-enriched nickel and iron oxides as highly active and cost-effective electrocatalysts, denoted as Ni0.6Fe2.4O4@NC, derived from NiFe-based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) for oxygen reduction reactions (ORR) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER). XANES and EXAFS confirm that the crystals have a distorted structure and metal vacancies. The cation defect-rich Ni0.6Fe2.4O4@NC electrocatalyst exhibits exceptional ORR and OER activities (&#916;E = 0.68 V). Mechanistic pathways of electrochemical reactions are studied by DFT calculations. Furthermore, a rechargeable zinc&#8211;air battery (RZAB) using the Ni0.6Fe2.4O4@NC catalyst demonstrates a peak power density of 187 mW cm&#8211;2 and remarkable long-term cycling stability. The flexible solid-state ZAB using the Ni0.6Fe2.4O4@NC catalyst exhibits a power density of 66 mW cm&#8211;2. The proposed structural design strategy allows for the rational design of electronic delocalization of cation defect-rich NiFe spinel ferrite attached to ultrathin N-doped graphitic carbon sheets in order to enhance active site availability and facilitate mass and electron transport.</description>
      <author>Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Wathanyu Kao-ian, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Piyasan Praserthdam, Wanwisa Limphirat, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Tetsu Yonezawa, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress of Transition Metal Selenides for Electrochemical Oxygen Reduction to Hydrogen Peroxide: From Catalyst Design to Electrolyzers Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309448</link>
      <description>Yingnan Wang, Caidi Han, Li Ma, Tigang Duan, Yue Du, Jian Wu, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Jian Gao, Xiaodong Zhu, Y. Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391882047

                Abstract Hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) is a highly value&#8208;added and environmental&#8208;friendly chemical with various applications. The production of H 2 O 2 by electrocatalytic 2e &#8722; oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) has emerged as a promising alternative to the energy&#8208;intensive anthraquinone process. High selectivity Catalysts combining with superior activity are critical for the efficient electrosynthesis of H 2 O 2 . Earth&#8208;abundant transition metal selenides (TMSs) being discovered as a classic of stable, low&#8208;cost, highly active and selective catalysts for electrochemical 2e &#8722; ORR. These features come from the relatively large atomic radius of selenium element, the metal&#8208;like properties and the abundant reserves. Moreover, compared with the advanced noble metal or single&#8208;atom catalysts, the kinetic current density of TMSs for H 2 O 2 generation is higher in acidic solution, which enable them to become suitable catalyst candidates. Herein, the recent progress of TMSs for ORR to H 2 O 2 is systematically reviewed. The effects of TMSs electrocatalysts on the activity, selectivity and stability of ORR to H 2 O 2 are summarized. It is intended to provide an insight from catalyst design and corresponding reaction mechanisms to the device setup, and to discuss the relationship between structure and activity.</description>
      <author>Yingnan Wang, Caidi Han, Li Ma, Tigang Duan, Yue Du, Jian Wu, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Jian Gao, Xiaodong Zhu, Y. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Methanesulfonates with Mixed Anionic Groups with Large Band Gaps and Enhanced Birefringence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c03278</link>
      <description>Mingli Liang, Yujie Zhang, Eugene Izvarin, Michael J. Waters, James M. Rondinelli, P. Shiv Halasyamani, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391882486

                Four new metal methanesulfonates with mixed anionic groups, Bi(SeO3)(CH3SO3) (1), Bi(TeO3)(CH3SO3) (2), Ba(BF4)(CH3SO3) (3), and Ba2(BF4)(CH3SO3)3(H2O)3 (4), have been successfully synthesized. Compounds 1 and 2 are isomorphic and exhibit a two-dimensional (2D) layered structure. Stereoactive lone pairs are observed with Se4+, Te4+, and Bi3+. Compound 3 features a three-dimensional (3D) structure formed by connecting [Ba(CH3SO3)]+ layers via BF4 tetrahedra, whereas compound 4 features a 2D layered structure, where the BF4 tetrahedra are positioned on both sides of the [Ba2(CH3SO3)3]+ layers. The ultraviolet&#8211;visible&#8211;near-infrared (UV&#8211;vis-NIR) spectra indicate that compounds 1 and 2 have absorption edges at 270 and 274 nm, whereas compounds 3 and 4, with absorption edges below 200 nm, are characterized as deep-UV crystals. Calculations were performed to determine the absorption edges, and comparative analysis indicates a significant enhancement in the calculated birefringence values compared to analogous compounds.</description>
      <author>Mingli Liang, Yujie Zhang, Eugene Izvarin, Michael J. Waters, James M. Rondinelli, P. Shiv Halasyamani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c03278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Hot-Carrier Distributions of Plasmonic Nanostructures through Surface Alloying</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c11418</link>
      <description>Jakub Fojt, Tuomas P. Rossi, Priyank V. Kumar, Paul Erhart, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391884518

                Alloyed metal nanoparticles are a promising platform for plasmonically enabled hot-carrier generation, which can be used to drive photochemical reactions. Although the non-plasmonic component in these systems has been investigated for its potential to enhance catalytic activity, its capacity to affect the photochemical process favorably has been underexplored by comparison. Here, we study the impact of surface alloy species and concentration on hot-carrier generation in Ag nanoparticles. By first-principles simulations, we photoexcite the localized surface plasmon, allow it to dephase, and calculate spatially and energetically resolved hot-carrier distributions. We show that the presence of non-noble species in the topmost surface layer drastically enhances hot-hole generation at the surface at the expense of hot-hole generation in the bulk, due to the additional d-type states that are introduced to the surface. The energy of the generated holes can be tuned by choice of the alloyant, with systematic trends across the d-band block. Already low surface alloy concentrations have a large impact, with a saturation of the enhancement effect typically close to 75% of a monolayer. Hot-electron generation at the surface is hindered slightly by alloying, but here a judicious choice of the alloy composition allows one to strike a balance between hot electrons and holes. Our work underscores the promise of utilizing multicomponent nanoparticles to achieve enhanced control over plasmonic catalysis and provides guidelines for how hot-carrier distributions can be tailored by designing the electronic structure of the surface through alloying.</description>
      <author>Jakub Fojt, Tuomas P. Rossi, Priyank V. Kumar, Paul Erhart</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c11418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral Induced Spin Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00661</link>
      <description>Brian P. Bloom, Yossi Paltiel, Ron Naaman, David H. Waldeck, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391885773

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brian P. Bloom, Yossi Paltiel, Ron Naaman, David H. Waldeck</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00661</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational investigation of the oxygen reduction reaction on the edges of differently-sized, shaped and terminated graphene nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.118942</link>
      <description>Drago&#351; Lucian Isac, Raluca Jalba, &#350;tefan-Gabriel &#350;origa, Yuheng Zhao, Frederik Tielens, Ionu&#355; Tranca, Man Isabela-Costinela, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391887971

                Graphene nanoclusters (GNCs), part of the graphene family of nanomaterials, are attracting interest as promising Pt free catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction (ORR) at the cathode of the fuel cells. This investigation focuses on the theoretical prediction of their possible edge activity towards ORR determined by their shape, size and termination type. In this framework, using density functional theory (DFT) we examined the zigzag (zz) and armchair terminated (ac) triangular (T), rhombohedral (R) and hexagonal (H) GNCs of various sizes, ranging from C13 to C114. The theoretical onset overpotential (&#951;th,onset) indicate that several GNC edges could be active for ORR. The model indicates that the zigzag edges of all triangular GNCs (C13&#8211;C46) as well as of the largest investigated rhombohedral shapes (C48, C70) are active for ORR. A correlation between the band gaps, spin densities and p-band centers of the edge carbon atoms and the adsorption energies of the ORR intermediate moieties (HOO*/O*/HO*) are discussed and which are directly related to their activity. One trend is related to the decrease of the adsorption energies with the decrease of the band gap and accordingly an increase of their ORR activities. The case studies, show that the explicit water model developed by using machine learning potentials and combined with DFT, stabilizes the ORR intermediates stronger than the implicit one, thus increasing slightly the onset overpotential. Overall, this computational study enhances our fundamental understanding of the edges of GNC for their potential application in electrocatalysis without doping.</description>
      <author>Drago&#351; Lucian Isac, Raluca Jalba, &#350;tefan-Gabriel &#350;origa, Yuheng Zhao, Frederik Tielens, Ionu&#355; Tranca, Man Isabela-Costinela</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.118942</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction Reaction of TiO2 Nanotubes by Combining Surface Oxygen Vacancy Engineering and Zr Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14040366</link>
      <description>Maged N. Shaddad, Prabhakarn Arunachalam, Mahmoud Hezam, Saba A. Aladeemy, Mamduh J. Aljaafreh, Sharif Abu Alrub, Abdullah M. Al&#8208;Mayouf, Nanomaterials. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391893370

                This work examines the cooperative effect between Zr doping and oxygen vacancy engineering in anodized TiO2 nanotubes (TNTs) for enhanced oxygen reduction reactions (ORRs). Zr dopant and annealing conditions significantly affected the electrocatalytic characteristics of grown TNTs. Zr doping results in Zr4+ substituted for Ti4+ species, which indirectly creates oxygen vacancy donors that enhance charge transfer kinetics and reduce carrier recombination in TNT bulk. Moreover, oxygen vacancies promote the creation of unsaturated Ti3+(Zr3+) sites at the surface, which also boosts the ORR interfacial process. Annealing at reductive atmospheres (e.g., H2, vacuum) resulted in a larger increase in oxygen vacancies, which greatly enhanced the ORR activity. In comparison to bare TNTs, Zr doping and vacuum treatment (Zr:TNT&#8211;Vac) significantly improved the conductivity and activity of ORRs in alkaline media. The finding also provides selective hydrogen peroxide production by the electrochemical reduction of oxygen.</description>
      <author>Maged N. Shaddad, Prabhakarn Arunachalam, Mahmoud Hezam, Saba A. Aladeemy, Mamduh J. Aljaafreh, Sharif Abu Alrub, Abdullah M. Al&#8208;Mayouf</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14040366</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-level insights into bioinspired Fe/Ni bimetallic active sites on carbon nitrides for electrocatalytic O2 evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149799</link>
      <description>Yunseok Shin, Seong Chan Cho, Kilsu Park, Jae Hun Seol, Dongwook Lim, Subin Choi, Changbum Jo, Sung Hyeon Baeck, Jongwoo Lim, Sang Uck Lee, Sunghee Park, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391896201

                Atomically dispersed active speices on nanomaterials have shown greate promise for various catalytic reactions. In this work, bioinspired bimetallic materials (FeNi-CN) are produced through the mixing of melamine with FeCl2&#183;4H2O and NiCl2&#183;6H2O followed by heat treatment. FeNi-CN exhibits exceptional electrocatalytic activity with an overpotential of 250 mV for oxygen evolution reactions (OERs), which surpasses the well-known IrO2. Additionally, it shows excellent cyclic durability up to 10,000th cycle. The various characterizations reveal the atomically dispersed Fe and Ni atoms across C3N4 networks through coordination to N atoms. Comparative experiments with monometallic samples show that bimetallic FeNi-CN outperforms them. Density functional theory calculations support these findings, indicating that Ni has a higher OER activity than Fe, and the combination of bimetallic Ni and Fe and structural corrugation in FeNi-CN enhances catalytic performance. Ex-situ study supports the electrochemical stability. This work suggests the potential of bimetallic catalysts for electrocatalytic application.</description>
      <author>Yunseok Shin, Seong Chan Cho, Kilsu Park, Jae Hun Seol, Dongwook Lim, Subin Choi, Changbum Jo, Sung Hyeon Baeck, Jongwoo Lim, Sang Uck Lee, Sunghee Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149799</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cutting-edge advancements in MXene-derived materials: Revolutionary electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution and high-performance energy storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215722</link>
      <description>Muhammad Saleem Khan, Amjad Hussain, Muhammad Tahir Saleh, Mohammad Ibrahim, Faisal Attique, Xiaohui Sun, H&#252;sn&#252; Emrah &#220;nalan, Muhammad Shafi, Yaqoob Khan, Idrees Khan, Ahmed H. Ragab, Abeer A. Hassan, Rawaid Ali, Zafar Ali, Abdul Jabbar Khan, Amir Zada, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 506(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391907192

                MXenes belong to a set of 2-dimensional (2D) materials composed of transition metals, carbides, nitrides, and carbonitrides demonstrated unique properties in several fields including catalysis and energy storage. This review provides a comprehensive overview of the recent trends in MXene-based catalysts for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) and their potential applications in energy storage devices. MXenes are widely sought-after as HER catalysts because of their distinctive properties including large surface area, variable surface chemistry, and high electrical conductivity. Extensive research in their synthesis, characterization, and performance reveals their superior catalytic activity, stability, and affordability compared to conventional catalysts. They have also shown great promise for use in energy storage devices notably supercapacitors and batteries. This review paper examines various synthesis techniques and emphasizes how various factors affect catalysis with MXenes for HER. The 2D structure of MXenes enables effective charge storage and transfer, with excellent conductivity and numerous active sites for species adsorption. In the MXenes domain, a crucial gap exists lack of a thorough review on recent advancements, specifically focusing on electrocatalysts for HER and energy storage in batteries. This concise narrative systematically addresses current progress, challenges, proposing solutions, briefly exploring synthesis methods, and delving into applications including prospective HER catalysts and strategies for enhanced activity and energy storage, especially in sodium, lithium, and zinc ion batteries.)</description>
      <author>Muhammad Saleem Khan, Amjad Hussain, Muhammad Tahir Saleh, Mohammad Ibrahim, Faisal Attique, Xiaohui Sun, H&#252;sn&#252; Emrah &#220;nalan, Muhammad Shafi, Yaqoob Khan, Idrees Khan, Ahmed H. Ragab, Abeer A. Hassan, Rawaid Ali, Zafar Ali, Abdul Jabbar Khan, Amir Zada</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Pyrolysis for High-Loading Transition Metal Single Atoms on 2D-Nitro-Oxygeneous Carbon as Efficient ORR Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c18548</link>
      <description>Teera Butburee, Jitprabhat Ponchai, Pongtanawat Khemthong, Poobodin Mano, Pongkarn Chakthranont, Saran Youngjan, Jakkapop Phanthasri, Supawadee Namuangruk, Kajornsak Faungnawakij, Xingya Wang, Yu Chen, Lijuan Zhang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391909267

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Teera Butburee, Jitprabhat Ponchai, Pongtanawat Khemthong, Poobodin Mano, Pongkarn Chakthranont, Saran Youngjan, Jakkapop Phanthasri, Supawadee Namuangruk, Kajornsak Faungnawakij, Xingya Wang, Yu Chen, Lijuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c18548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyzing Sustainable Water Splitting with Single Atom Catalysts: Recent Advances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202300330</link>
      <description>Niharul Alam, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Naseem Iqbal, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391926985

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting for sustainable hydrogen and oxygen production have shown enormous potentials. However, this method needs low&#8208;cost and highly active catalysts. Traditional nano catalysts, while effective, have limits since their active sites are mostly restricted to the surface and edges, leaving interior surfaces unexposed in redox reactions. Single atom catalysts (SACs), which take advantage of high atom utilization and quantum size effects, have recently become appealing electrocatalysts. Strong interaction between active sites and support in SACs have considerably improved the catalytic efficiency and long&#8208;term stability, outperforming their nano&#8208;counterparts. This review&#8216;s first section examines the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) and the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER). In the next section, SACs are categorized as noble metal, non&#8208;noble metal, and bimetallic synergistic SACs. In addition, this review emphasizes developing methodologies for effective SAC design, such as mass loading optimization, electrical structure modulation, and the critical role of support materials. Finally, Carbon&#8208;based materials and metal oxides are being explored as possible supports for SACs. Importantly, for the first time, this review opens a discussion on waste&#8208;derived supports for single atom catalysts used in electrochemical reactions, providing a cost&#8208;effective dimension to this vibrant research field. The well&#8208;known design techniques discussed here may help in development of electrocatalysts for effective water splitting.</description>
      <author>Niharul Alam, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Naseem Iqbal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202300330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density&#8208;Functional Theory Studies on Photocatalysis and Photoelectrocatalysis: Challenges and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/solr.202300948</link>
      <description>Chi&#8208;Hui Lin, Jyoti Rohilla, Hsuan&#8208;Hung Kuo, Chun-yi Chen, Tso&#8208;Fu Mark Chang, Masato Sone, Pravin P. Ingole, Yu&#8208;Chieh Lo, Yung&#8208;Jung Hsu, Solar RRL. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391929686

                Density&#8208;functional theory (DFT) is pivotal in the advancement of photocatalysis and photoelectrocatalysis. Its capability to explore electronic structures of materials contributes significantly to clarifying the mechanisms of photocatalytic (PC) and photoelectrocatalytic (PEC) processes. DFT calculations enable a deeper understanding of how these processes work at a molecular level, which is essential for designing versatile photocatalysts and photoelectrodes and optimizing reaction pathways. In this perspective, key PC and PEC applications, such as H 2 production, CO 2 reduction, dye degradation, and N 2 reduction, where DFT is instrumental in optimizing materials designs and reaction pathways, are highlighted. Exploration on the synergy between experimental research and DFT calculations is highlighted, which is crucial for the development of efficient and environmentally friendly energy solutions. The discussion further extends to challenges and future directions, emphasizing the need for incorporating factors, including discrepancy in scale, light illumination, electrolyte presence, and applied bias, into DFT calculations, to achieve a more comprehensive understanding of PC and PEC systems. In this perspective, it is aimed to provide a holistic view of the current state and potential advancements in photocatalyst and photoelectrode modeling, thereby guiding future research toward more effective and sustainable energy and chemical production processes in PC and PEC systems.</description>
      <author>Chi&#8208;Hui Lin, Jyoti Rohilla, Hsuan&#8208;Hung Kuo, Chun-yi Chen, Tso&#8208;Fu Mark Chang, Masato Sone, Pravin P. Ingole, Yu&#8208;Chieh Lo, Yung&#8208;Jung Hsu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/solr.202300948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrocatalytic activation of sulfate for sulfamethoxazole degradation and simultaneous H2 production by bifunctional N,P co-doped black-blue TiO2 nanotube array electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149828</link>
      <description>Shan Li, Guoquan Zhang, Dong Meng, Fenglin Yang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391931133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shan Li, Guoquan Zhang, Dong Meng, Fenglin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The NOMAD mini-apps: A suite of kernels from ab initio electronic structure codes enabling co-design in high-performance computing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.1</link>
      <description>Isidre Mas Magre, Ricardo Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a Cela Esp&#237;n, Julio Gutierrez Moreno, Open research Europe. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933077

                This article introduces a suite of mini-applications (mini-apps) designed to optimise computational kernels in ab initio electronic structure codes. The suite is developed from flagship applications participating in the NOMAD Center of Excellence, such as the ELPA eigensolver library and the GW implementations of the exciting, Abinit, and FHI-aims codes. The mini-apps were identified by targeting functions that significantly contribute to the total execution time in the parent applications. This strategic selection allows for concentrated optimisation efforts. The suite is designed for easy deployment on various High-Performance Computing (HPC) systems, supported by an integrated CMake build system for straightforward compilation and execution. The aim is to harness the capabilities of emerging (post)exascale systems, which necessitate concurrent hardware and software development &#8212; a concept known as co-design. The mini-app suite serves as a tool for profiling and benchmarking, providing insights that can guide both software optimisation and hardware design. Ultimately, these developments will enable more accurate and efficient simulations of novel materials, leveraging the full potential of exascale computing in material science research.</description>
      <author>Isidre Mas Magre, Ricardo Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a Cela Esp&#237;n, Julio Gutierrez Moreno</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kinisi: Bayesian analysis of mass transport from molecular dynamics simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.05984</link>
      <description>Andrew R. McCluskey, Alexander G. Squires, Josh W. Dunn, Samuel W. Coles, Benjamin J. Morgan, Journal of open source software. 9(94)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933289

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrew R. McCluskey, Alexander G. Squires, Josh W. Dunn, Samuel W. Coles, Benjamin J. Morgan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.05984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of single-atom alloy catalysts in electrochemical conversion of carbon dioxide: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119910</link>
      <description>Jingnan Wang, Keli Zhao, Yi Ding, Yongan Yang, Xi Wu, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933654

                Atomic-scale understanding of C-C coupling in the electrocatalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into valuable C2 chemicals remains elusive. Herein, we selected Group VIII and IB transition metals as active sites incorporated into the Cu(1 0 0) surface to construct single-atom alloy catalysts. The stability, selectivity, and activity of a series of catalysts were calculated using density functional theory. Fe, Co, Ni, Ru/Cu(1 0 0) exhibit the potential as candidates to generate C2 products and suppress the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The reaction proceeds through the reduction of CO2 to key intermediates *CO and *CHO, which undergoes C-C coupling to generate *CO-CHO, subsequently undergoing different protonation processes to yield diverse C2 products. The rate-determining step for Fe, Co, Ni, and Ru/Cu(1 0 0), is the hydrogenation of *CO, with a comparable energy barrier of 0.8 eV. Moreover, Fe and Co/Cu(1 0 0) favor the formation of C2H4 as the primary product, while Ni and Ru/Cu(1 0 0) predominantly produce CH3COOH.</description>
      <author>Jingnan Wang, Keli Zhao, Yi Ding, Yongan Yang, Xi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methane sulfonic acid-assisted synthesis of g-C3N4/Ni2P/Ni foam: Efficient, stable and recyclable for photocatalytic nitrogen fixation under visible light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112276</link>
      <description>Xianqiang Gao, Bowen Zhang, Lulu Cao, Fei Liu, Hai Fan, Chuanjun Wang, Junjie Xu, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391940943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianqiang Gao, Bowen Zhang, Lulu Cao, Fei Liu, Hai Fan, Chuanjun Wang, Junjie Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Special Activity of Stone&#8211;Wales Defect Graphene for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction: A Comparison Study between the Charge-Neutral Model and the Constant Potential Model Calculated by Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08035</link>
      <description>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391942912

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Oxidation of the Intermetallic Compound PtAl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from Ab Initio Thermodynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06290</link>
      <description>Wei Xie, Chunhua Cai, Guangwen Zhou, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391945161

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Xie, Chunhua Cai, Guangwen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali Containing Layered Metal Oxides as Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300761</link>
      <description>Mario Falsaperna, Rosa Arrigo, Frank Marken, Simon J. Freakley, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391948002

                Abstract Improving the efficiency of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential to realise energy systems based on water electrolysis. Many catalysts have been developed for the OER to date, with iridium&#8208;based oxides being the most promising due to their relative stability towards corrosion in acidic electrolytes under oxidising potentials. In recent years, examples of catalysts adopting layered structures have been shown to have promising characteristics such as higher conductivity and higher electrochemically active surface area compared to highly crystalline metal oxides. Furthermore, such materials possess additional tuneable properties such as interlayer spacing, identity and concentration of the interlayer species, edge and interlayer active sites, and higher active surface area. Recent attention has focused on mono&#8208; and polymetallic lithium&#8208;containing layered materials, where the presence of interlayer lithium cations, in situ delithiation processes and combinations of transition metal oxides result in enhanced catalytic properties towards OER. This review aims to provide a summary of the recent developments of such layered materials, in which lithium or other alkali metal ions occupy interlayer sites in oxides.</description>
      <author>Mario Falsaperna, Rosa Arrigo, Frank Marken, Simon J. Freakley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst Selection over an Electrochemical Reductive Coupling Reaction toward Direct Electrosynthesis of Oxime from NO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; and Aldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14687</link>
      <description>Wei Chen, Yandong Wu, Yimin Jiang, Guangxing Yang, Yingying Li, Lei Xu, Ming Yang, Binbin Wu, Yuping Pan, Yanzhi Xu, Qinghua Liu, Chen Chen, Feng Peng, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391952084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Chen, Yandong Wu, Yimin Jiang, Guangxing Yang, Yingying Li, Lei Xu, Ming Yang, Binbin Wu, Yuping Pan, Yanzhi Xu, Qinghua Liu, Chen Chen, Feng Peng, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14687</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering &lt;scp&gt;Pt&#8208;Cu&lt;/scp&gt; diatomics electrocatalysts enables highly efficient urea synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18403</link>
      <description>Fei Lu, Jingnan Wang, Yuhang Gao, Yan Wang, Xi Wu, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391954090

                Abstract The rational design of novel heterogeneous urea&#8208;synthesis electrocatalysts (HUECs) poses an immense challenge due to their inherent complexity. Moreover, the ideal HUECs must also possess the ability to suppress two major competitive reactions: hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and N 2 reduction reaction (NRR). However, this daunting task can be made feasible with the use of heterogeneous diatomic catalysts that have been supported by unambiguous theoretical models. Herein, we report a design for an efficient platinum&#8208;copper diatomic electrocatalyst (Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 ) for urea production based on theoretical predictions. Through rational screening of 8 Pt&#8208;diatomics HUECs, we discovered that Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 can effectively suppress HER and NRR while promoting the adsorption of CO 2 and N 2 . Subsequently, we experimentally fabricated Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 which exhibited optimal urea electrosynthesis activity of 51.71 mol urea mol Pt+Cu &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 . Pt 1 &#8208;Cu 1 diatomics in Pt 1 Cu 1 &#8208;TiO 2 could synergistically encourage the activation of *CO 2 /*N 2 and crucial C&#8208;N coupling with an optimal energy barrier (0.25 eV).</description>
      <author>Fei Lu, Jingnan Wang, Yuhang Gao, Yan Wang, Xi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optoelectronic and transport properties of vacancy-ordered double-perovskite halides: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.024036</link>
      <description>Supriti Ghorui, Jiban Kangsabanik, M. Aslam, Aftab Alam, Physical review applied. 21(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391954370

                In the search for stable lead-free perovskites, vacancy-ordered double perovskites (VODPs), ${\mathrm{A}}_{2}{\mathrm{BX}}_{6}$, have emerged as a promising class of materials for solar harvesting owing to their nontoxicity, better stability, and unique optoelectronic properties. Recently, this class has been explored for a wide range of applications, such as photovoltaics, photodetectors, photocatalysis, and light-emitting diodes. Here, we present the stability and the key physical attributes of a few selected compounds in a systematic manner using state-of-the-art first-principles calculations. A careful structural and stability analysis via simulation of convex hulls and compositional phase diagrams for different structural prototypes discloses 14 stable compounds and one metastable compound in this class. Electronic structure calculations using hybrid functionals reveals that six compounds possess band gaps in the ideal visible region. These six compounds, namely ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Sn}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Pd}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Te}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Ti}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Pt}\mathrm{I}}_{6}$, and ${\mathrm{Cs}}_{2}{\mathrm{Pd}\mathrm{Br}}_{6}$, show high optical absorption ($\ensuremath{\approx}{10}^{5}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{cm}}^{\ensuremath{-}1}$), giving rise to high spectroscopic limited maximum efficiency (15--23%) in the thin-film thickness range. Close inspection of the transport properties reveals polar optical phonon scattering to be the dominant mechanism limiting overall mobility. Further analysis of the polaron excitations discloses the possibility of large polaron formation at low to moderate defect concentrations. At high defect concentrations, ionized impurity scattering takes over. Such analysis can be extremely useful for choosing the optimal growth conditions for a given material intended to be used for a desired application. Additionally, a few selected compounds show moderate to high electron mobility values ($\ensuremath{\sim}13--63\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{cm}}^{2}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{V}}^{\ensuremath{-}1}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{s}}^{\ensuremath{-}1}$) at room temperature. Overall, the present study paves an important path to help design VODPs as lead-free potential candidates for future optoelectronic applications.</description>
      <author>Supriti Ghorui, Jiban Kangsabanik, M. Aslam, Aftab Alam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.024036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into the Selective Electrocatalytic Reduction of NO to NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; on a Two-Dimensional Cu-Benzylthiol Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Nanostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05958</link>
      <description>Hao Yin, Minghao Gong, Pengbo Lyu, Ran Wang, Lizhong Sun, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391956639

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Yin, Minghao Gong, Pengbo Lyu, Ran Wang, Lizhong Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local-environment-guided selection of atomic structures for the development of machine-learning potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0187892</link>
      <description>Renzhe Li, Chuan Zhou, Amankumar Singh, Yong Pei, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392014929

                Machine learning potentials (MLPs) have attracted significant attention in computational chemistry and materials science due to their high accuracy and computational efficiency. The proper selection of atomic structures is crucial for developing reliable MLPs. Insufficient or redundant atomic structures can impede the training process and potentially result in a poor quality MLP. Here, we propose a local-environment-guided screening algorithm for efficient dataset selection in MLP development. The algorithm utilizes a local environment bank to store unique local environments of atoms. The dissimilarity between a particular local environment and those stored in the bank is evaluated using the Euclidean distance. A new structure is selected only if its local environment is significantly different from those already present in the bank. Consequently, the bank is then updated with all the new local environments found in the selected structure. To demonstrate the effectiveness of our algorithm, we applied it to select structures for a Ge system and a Pd13H2 particle system. The algorithm reduced the training data size by around 80% for both without compromising the performance of the MLP models. We verified that the results were independent of the selection and ordering of the initial structures. We also compared the performance of our method with the farthest point sampling algorithm, and the results show that our algorithm is superior in both robustness and computational efficiency. Furthermore, the generated local environment bank can be continuously updated and can potentially serve as a growing database of feature local environments, aiding in efficient dataset maintenance for constructing accurate MLPs.</description>
      <author>Renzhe Li, Chuan Zhou, Amankumar Singh, Yong Pei, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0187892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Effects of Varying the Ti Concentration on the Mechanical Properties of Cu&#8211;Ti Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c07561</link>
      <description>Vasileios Fotopoulos, Corey S. O&#8217;Hern, Mark D. Shattuck, Alexander L. Shluger, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391933315

                The mechanical properties of CuTi alloys have been characterized extensively through experimental studies. However, a detailed understanding of why the strength of Cu increases after a small fraction of Ti atoms are added to the alloy is still missing. In this work, we address this question using density functional theory (DFT) and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations with the modified embedded atom method (MEAM) interatomic potentials. First, we performed calculations of the uniaxial tension deformations of small bicrystalline Cu cells using DFT static simulations. We then carried out uniaxial tension deformations on much larger bicrystalline and polycrystalline Cu cells by using MEAM MD simulations. In bicrystalline Cu, the inclusion of Ti increases the grain boundary separation energy and the maximum tensile stress. The DFT calculations demonstrate that the increase in the tensile stress can be attributed to an increase in the local charge density arising from Ti. MEAM simulations in larger bicrystalline systems have shown that increasing the Ti concentration decreases the density of the stacking faults. This observation is enhanced in polycrystalline Cu, where the addition of Ti atoms, even at concentrations as low as 1.5 atomic (at.) %, increases the yield strength and elastic modulus of the material compared to pure Cu. Under uniaxial tensile loading, the addition of small amounts of Ti hinders the formation of partial Shockley dislocations in the grain boundaries of Cu, leading to a reduced level of local deformation. These results shed light on the role of Ti in determining the mechanical properties of polycrystalline Cu and enable the engineering of grain boundaries and the inclusion of Ti to improve degradation resistance.</description>
      <author>Vasileios Fotopoulos, Corey S. O&#8217;Hern, Mark D. Shattuck, Alexander L. Shluger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c07561</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
