<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:44:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the apparent hydrogen binding energy to achieve high-performance Ni-based hydrogen oxidation reaction catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45370-4</link>
      <description>Xingdong Wang, Xuerui Liu, Jinjie Fang, Houpeng Wang, Xianwei Liu, Haiyong Wang, Chengjin Chen, Yongsheng Wang, Xuejiang Zhang, Wei Zhu, Zhongbin Zhuang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391607919

                Abstract High-performance platinum-group-metal-free alkaline hydrogen oxidation reaction catalysts are essential for the hydroxide exchange membrane fuel cells, which generally require high Pt loadings on the anode. Herein, we report a highly active hydrogen oxidation reaction catalyst, NiCuCr, indicated by the hydroxide exchange membrane fuel cell with a high peak power density of 577 mW cm &#8722;2 (18 times as high as the Ni/C anode) and a stability of more than 150 h (a degradation rate slower by 7 times than the Ni/C anode). The spectroscopies demonstrate that the alloy effect from Cu weakens the hydrogen binding, and the surface Cr 2 O 3 species enhance the interfacial water binding. Both effects bring an optimized apparent hydrogen binding energy and thus lead to the high hydrogen oxidation reaction performance of NiCuCr. These results suggest that the apparent hydrogen binding energy determines the hydrogen oxidation reaction performance and that its tuning is beneficial toward high electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Xingdong Wang, Xuerui Liu, Jinjie Fang, Houpeng Wang, Xianwei Liu, Haiyong Wang, Chengjin Chen, Yongsheng Wang, Xuejiang Zhang, Wei Zhu, Zhongbin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45370-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Spin Dynamics in Diatomic Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts on Graphyne for Enhanced Co Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202301016</link>
      <description>Shuang&#8208;Te Zhao, Wei Zhang, Xuelong Zhang, Cun&#8208;biao Lin, Wenxian Chen, Guilin Zhuang, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391608697

                Abstract Investigating spin dynamics in electrocatalysis is crucial for the rational design of magnetically heterogeneous catalysts. Utilizing spin&#8208;polarized density functional theory calculation, herein, the spin dynamic of diatomic Co&#8322;&#8208;supported &#947;&#8208;graphyne (Co 2 &#8208;GY) catalysts during the process of CO electroreduction (eCORR) is identified, focusing on the effect of the applied potential and acidity on spin dynamic and catalytic performance. In particular, the obtained Co 2 &#8208;GY shows a new efficient C 2 pathway of CH 2 * + CHO* coupling mechanism, resulting in the optimal CH 3 CH 2 OH product with &#8710;G of 0.50 eV and the selectivity of 99.99% under alkaline conditions. Under acidic media, Co 2 &#8208;GY exhibits the optimal C 1 product (CH 3 OH) with &#8710;G of 0.27 eV and a selectivity of 99.99%. During CO electroreduction, the reaction environment (pH and applied potential) influences spin dynamics in catalyst&#8208;reactant systems, affecting the spin transition of diatomic Co 2 active sites among four magnetic states: ferromagnetic, antiferromagnetic, paramagnetic, and diamagnetic. These findings will be helpful for the rational design of transition&#8208;metal heterogeneous catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shuang&#8208;Te Zhao, Wei Zhang, Xuelong Zhang, Cun&#8208;biao Lin, Wenxian Chen, Guilin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202301016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru&#8208;supported Cu nanowire catalyst enabling to suppress C&#8211;C coupling for high&#8208;selectivity ethylamine electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18377</link>
      <description>Xiaoli Dong, Dong Liu, Yanbin Qi, Wangxin Ge, Xiaoli Jiang, Yuan Zhao, Wenfei Zhang, Pengfei Tian, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391611303

                Abstract Electrochemical acetonitrile hydrogenation compared with thermocatalytic hydrogenation provides a potential route to produce ethylamine in mild conditions. It is challenging to suppress the C&#8211;C coupling for improving ethylamine selectivity. Here, Ru&#8208;supported Cu nanowire catalysts (Ru&#8208;Cu NWs) are designed to achieve nearly 100% specific selectivity of ethylamine without coupling byproducts. In situ vibrational spectroscopy and electron spin resonance results reveal that the Ru&#8208;Cu NWs provide a high active adsorption hydrogen (H*) coverage at the electrified interface so that the imine intermediates are more readily hydrogenated to generate ethylamine, thus suppressing the C&#8211;C coupling. Density functional theory calculations disclose that the formation of H* occurs more readily over Ru&#8208;Cu NWs than Cu NWs. Moreover, the presence of Ru changes the potential&#8208;determining step and facilitates the entire hydrogenation process. The strategy and understanding established here can be extended to other electrocatalytic hydrogenation reactions.</description>
      <author>Xiaoli Dong, Dong Liu, Yanbin Qi, Wangxin Ge, Xiaoli Jiang, Yuan Zhao, Wenfei Zhang, Pengfei Tian, Hongliang Jiang, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decreasing the O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;to&#8208;H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Kinetic Energy Barrier on Dilute Binary Alloy Surfaces with Controlled Configurations of Isolated Active Atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314281</link>
      <description>Shieh-Shing Lin, Cheng-Chun Chang, Meng&#8208;Hsuan Tsai, Chih&#8208;Hao Chen, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Chia&#8208;Ying Wu, I&#8208;Ting Kao, Wen&#8208;Yang Jao, Chia&#8208;Hsin Wang, Wen&#8208;Yueh Yu, Chi&#8208;Chang Hu, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Tung&#8208;Han Yang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391613003

                Abstract Shifting from the typical 4e &#8211; pathway to H 2 O in electrochemical oxygen reduction to the 2e &#8211; pathway to H 2 O 2 is increasingly recognized as an environmentally friendly approach for producing H 2 O 2 . However, the competitive 4e &#8722; pathway is a significant obstacle to the production of H 2 O 2 since H 2 O is the thermodynamically favored product. Here, a series of Pt, Pd, and Rh active atoms diluted within inert&#8208;Au matrices with precisely controlled atomic arrangements and coordination environments are synthesized via facet engineering for O 2 &#8208;to&#8208;H 2 O 2 production. Surprisingly, individually dispersed Pt atoms within the Au surface enclosed by the square atomic arrangements exhibit superior H 2 O 2 selectivity and achieve a maximum selectivity of 90% at 0.36 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode. Operando synchrotron ambient pressure X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy identifies the presence of *OOH key intermediates on these isolated Pt active sites. Grand canonical density&#8208;functional theory also reveals that the kinetic energy barrier for the 2e &#8722; pathway (0.08 eV; OOH* + H + + e &#8722; &#8594; H 2 O 2 ) on the isolated Pt sites is significantly lower than the 4e &#8722; pathway (0.29 eV; OOH* + H + + e &#8722; &#8594; O* + H 2 O). This work enables atomic&#8208;scale control in dilute binary alloy surfaces with specific configurations of isolated active atoms and provides essential guidance for catalyst design to boost O 2 &#8208;to&#8208;H 2 O 2 production.</description>
      <author>Shieh-Shing Lin, Cheng-Chun Chang, Meng&#8208;Hsuan Tsai, Chih&#8208;Hao Chen, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Chia&#8208;Ying Wu, I&#8208;Ting Kao, Wen&#8208;Yang Jao, Chia&#8208;Hsin Wang, Wen&#8208;Yueh Yu, Chi&#8208;Chang Hu, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Tung&#8208;Han Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe,Co co-implanted dendritic CeO2/CeF3 heterostructure@MXene nanocomposites as structurally stable electrocatalysts with ultralow overpotential for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.012</link>
      <description>Yachun Mao, Xiaotong Yang, Kaiyu Dong, Tian Sheng, Qiang Yuan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391615735

                Exploring low-cost, high-activity, and structurally stable nonprecious metal electrocatalysts for sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is paramount for water electrolysis. Herein, we successfully prepare a novel Fe,Co-CeO2/CeF3@MXene heterostructure with Fe&#8211;Co dual active sites and oxygen vacancies for alkaline OER using an energy-free consumption co-deposition method. Impressively, Fe,Co-CeO2/CeF3@MXene achieves an ultralow overpotential of 192 mV and a long-term stability of 110 h at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 without structural changes, thereby outperforming the commercial IrO2 (345 mV). In addition, Fe,Co-CeO2/CeF3@MXene exhibits much superior activity (271 mV) and durability to IrO2 (385 mV) in the real seawater OER. Wind- and solar energy-assisted water electrolysis devices show their promising prospects for sustainable green hydrogen production. Characterization techniques and theoretical calculations reveal that the Fe,Co co-implanted CeO2/CeF3 heterostructure effectively degrades the energy barrier of the OER and optimizes the adsorption strength of *OH, *O, and *OOH intermediates. It exhibits the dual coupling mechanism of the adsorbed evolution and lattice oxygen mechanisms, which synergistically improves the OER performance. This work provides a facile and efficacious strategy for synthesizing a new class of heterostructures to achieve significant enhancement in the activity and stability of OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yachun Mao, Xiaotong Yang, Kaiyu Dong, Tian Sheng, Qiang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring 2D metal-organic frameworks for enhanced CO2 reduction efficiency through modulating conjugated ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuproc.2024.108049</link>
      <description>Sajjad Ali, Pir Muhammad Ismail, Muhammad Humayun, M. Bououdina, Liang Qiao, Fuel Processing Technology. 255(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391625704

                The technology of electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to produce hydrocarbon fuels not only alleviates energy shortages but also suppresses the greenhouse effect, demonstrating enormous potential applications. In this context, we aim to explore new reliable materials for reducing CO2 (CO2RR) through electrocatalysis. Hence, we investigated the performance of Cu3(C12X)2, where X signifies organic-ligands (N&#8321;&#8322;H&#8326;, N&#8329;H&#8323;O&#8323;, N&#8329;H&#8323;S&#8323;, N&#8326;O&#8326;, N&#8326;S&#8326;) for the CO2RR using density functional theory (DFT). The 2D Cu3(C12X)2 monolayers show metallic characteristics because of the presence of adequate &#960; electron conjugation network as-well-as a constructive interaction between the metal atom, organic-ligands, and benzene-rings, with the exception of Cu3(C12N9H3O3)2, which displayed semiconducting characteristic. The catalytic activity of Cu3(C12X)2 can be tuned by adjusting the organic-ligands' ability to facilitate interaction between the CO2RR intermediates and the metal complex (Cu-X4). Among all MOFs, Cu3(C12N6S6)2 have excellent CO2RR activity towards CO and formic acid. All other Cu3(C12X)2 monolayers demonstrated dynamic CO2RR catalytic activity as well as superior selectivity over hydrogen evolution (HER) suggesting that these materials have the potential to be useful as CO2RR electrocatalysts. This study introduces the concept of building MOFs with favorable features to meet the specific needs of a number of research domains including catalysis, energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Sajjad Ali, Pir Muhammad Ismail, Muhammad Humayun, M. Bououdina, Liang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuproc.2024.108049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Z-scheme overall water splitting for hydrogen generation with Sc2CCl2/ML (ML = MoTe2, Hf2CO2) heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.287</link>
      <description>X.D. Li, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, Wenkai Zhao, Yu&#8208;Liang Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391629187

                Direct Z-schemes for photocatalytic overall water splitting for hydrogen generation are constructed for Sc2CCl2/MoTe2 and Sc2CCl2/Hf2CO2 heterostructures on the basis of the calculated band alignment and built-in electric field. Solar-to-hydrogen efficiency (&#951;STH&#8242;), which is evaluated using the overpotentials of the band edges and band gaps, can reach 22.09 % for Sc2CCl2/MoTe2 and 19.07 % for Sc2CCl2/Hf2CO2. Tensile strains have little effect on &#951;STH&#8242;. Compressive strains substantially increase the &#951;STH&#8242; of Sc2CCl2/MoTe2 and boost that of the Sc2CCl2/Hf2CO2 heterostructure only slightly. Nonadiabatic dynamics simulations reveal that the lifetime of the photogenerated electron in one of the stacking patterns of Sc2CCl2/MoTe2 is much larger than that of the other configurations, indicating that the reduction ability of the electron is well protected. However, the interlayer electron&#8211;hole recombination in Sc2CCl2/MoTe2 is faster than that in Sc2CCl2/Hf2CO2, implying that the Z-schemes with the former are more efficient than the Z-schemes with the latter. The hydrogen and oxidation evolution reactions with the two heterostructures are thermodynamically feasible but the reactions cannot proceed spontaneously. These findings provide a helpful guide for the development of photocatalytic materials for photocatalytic hydrogen generation from overall water splitting based on the title heterostructures.</description>
      <author>X.D. Li, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, Wenkai Zhao, Yu&#8208;Liang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.287</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The atomic structural descriptor based on cluster expansion method and superior performance of oxygen reduction on PtTi surface alloys from theoretical perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.341</link>
      <description>Jia-Qi Tan, Guang-Qiang Yu, Bo-Ying Huang, Yin Wang, Xibo Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391629564

                Although alloying Pt with Ti is a feasible routine to improve oxygen reduction activity and stability, the atomic configuration of surface alloys on PtTi is still lacking deep understanding. Herein, the effect of Ti concentrations (x) in sublayer on ORR activity of PtTi surface alloys (Pt@Pt1-xTix@) with FCC or HCP Ti substrate, are systematically studied by first-principles calculations. The accurate atomic structural descriptor based on cluster expansion method is proposed to describe local atomic environment effect on intermediate (OH/OOH) adsorption ability. Different from b = 3.20 eV in traditional linear scaling relationship &#916;GOOH = &#916;GOH + b, the b values vary from 3.15 to 3.53 eV on PtTi surface alloys. Among surfaces alloys with different Ti concentrations, FCC- and HCP-Pt@Pt1-xTix(Pt)@ displayed the highest stability and catalytic activity at x = 3/9, and possessed a threefold and fivefold times of catalytic activity with a benchmark Pt(111) according to the calculated exchange current rate constants. Importantly, the FCC-Pt@Pt1-xTix(Pt)@ could be promising ORR catalyst as its high ORR activity at larger range of Ti concentration (x = 1/9&#8211;3/9), strong stability, and low Pt usage.</description>
      <author>Jia-Qi Tan, Guang-Qiang Yu, Bo-Ying Huang, Yin Wang, Xibo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of defective MnCo-LDH nanoflowers with high activity for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.130961</link>
      <description>Bolin Li, Liping Dai, Gouq-Jen Su, Zhaoming Xia, Yu&#8208;Xin Ye, Ze-Sheng Li, Fuel. 364(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391629728

                Manganese-cobalt layered double hydroxide (MnCo-LDH) is a kind of layered bimetallic hydroxide with good catalytic performance and stability for water decomposition. In this paper, a series of defective MnCo-LDH materials with different Mn/Co molar ratio was prepared by hydrothermal method. The results show that the MnCo-nanoflowers containing Mn and Co elements are successfully prepared, and all of them contain N, O, Mn and Co elements. The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalytic performance of Co vacancy (VCo)-MnCo-LDH is better than that of commercial electrode Pt/C, and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalytic performance of Mn vacancy (VMn)-MnCo-LDH is better than that of commercial electrode RuO2. Two-electrode overall water splitting (OWS) test showed that the overpotential required by VMn-MnCo-LDH/NF||VCo-MnCo-LDH/NF and Pt/C/NF||RuO2/NF were 1.56 V and 1.72 V respectively at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and the catalytic activity of the prepared defective MnCo-LDH is excellent bifunctional electrocatalysts for both HER and OER.</description>
      <author>Bolin Li, Liping Dai, Gouq-Jen Su, Zhaoming Xia, Yu&#8208;Xin Ye, Ze-Sheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.130961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on ORR reaction of B-doped graphene supported Co atoms with different defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114506</link>
      <description>Zhihua Ju, Xuyun Zhang, Yong Wang, Yan Liang, Fapeng Yu, Yong Liu, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391642348

                The performance of single atom catalyst (SAC) is strongly affected by its carrier. Five configurations with single vacancy, double vacancy, and defect site were calculated using density functional theory (DFT), and it was found that the electronic structure and state density were effectively regulated after introducing the B atom. The ORR activity was studied by doping different coordination layers. The results show that when doped with the second coordination layer of Co-DVG-N4 configuration, B can improve the adsorption strength of the central Co atom to the oxygen intermediate and show excellent ORR activity. Co-DVG-N4-B4(12.9 %) and Co-DVG-N4-B5(16.1 %) have relatively low overpotentials of 0.49 V and 0.47 V, providing an effective theoretical basis for rationalizing efficient electrocatalysts based on Co carbon materials.</description>
      <author>Zhihua Ju, Xuyun Zhang, Yong Wang, Yan Liang, Fapeng Yu, Yong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An efficient approach to compartmentalize double layer effects on kinetics of interfacial proton-electron transfer reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115360</link>
      <description>Naveen Agrawal, Andrew Jark-Wah Wong, Sharad Maheshwari, Michael J. Janik, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391643101

                Activation barriers for elementary electrochemical reactions can show strong dependence on the composition and structure of the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface, the electrochemical double layer (EDL), due to the highly polar nature of ion/electron transfer transition states. A compartmentalized analytical framework, built upon DFT calculations, is developed to consider complex interactions between reaction intermediates and the EDL. The approach analytically captures how altering interfacial properties, such as the dielectric constant or distribution of electrolyte charges, impact electrocatalytic activation barriers. Dipole moment change along the reaction path plays the largest role in dictating the extent to which interfacial properties impact elementary electrochemical kinetics. The compartmentalization and uncertainty quantification capability of the developed framework is illustrated employing a Helmholtz model with two parameters, dielectric constant and double layer thickness. The framework translates routine DFT analysis of (water-assisted) hydrogenation activation barriers to proton-coupled electron transfer barriers that depend analytically on electrode potential and EDL properties.</description>
      <author>Naveen Agrawal, Andrew Jark-Wah Wong, Sharad Maheshwari, Michael J. Janik</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APA-graphene: A multifunctional material for lithium-ion batteries and electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100699</link>
      <description>Wei Liu, Yunhao Xie, Liang Chen, Mingming Guo, Jing Xu, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391648745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Liu, Yunhao Xie, Liang Chen, Mingming Guo, Jing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100699</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia via Cu2O/Cu(OH)2 heterostructures promoting electron transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6480-1</link>
      <description>Jing Geng, Shengjun Ji, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391649902

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Geng, Shengjun Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6480-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Study of Bimetallic Pairs Embedded on Graphene Co-Doped with N and O for N2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29040779</link>
      <description>Haotian Dong, Hao Sun, Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Xue-Mei Duan, Jingyao Liu, Molecules. 29(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391650891

                The electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) is considered a viable alternative to the Haber&#8211;Bosch process for ammonia synthesis, and the design of highly active and selective catalysts is crucial for the industrialization of the NRR. Dual-atom catalysts (DACs) with dual active sites offer flexible active sites and synergistic effects between atoms, providing more possibilities for the tuning of catalytic performance. In this study, we designed 48 graphene-based DACs with N4O2 coordination (MM&#8242;@N4O2-G) using density functional theory. Through a series of screening strategies, we explored the reaction mechanisms of the NRR for eight catalysts in depth and revealed the &#8220;acceptance&#8211;donation&#8221; mechanism between the active sites and the N2 molecules through electronic structure analysis. The study found that the limiting potential of the catalysts exhibited a volcano-shaped relationship with the d-band center of the active sites, indicating that the synergistic effect between the bimetallic components can regulate the d-band center position of the active metal M, thereby controlling the reaction activity. Furthermore, we investigated the selectivity of the eight DACs and identified five potential NRR catalysts. Among them, MoCo@N4O2-G showed the best NRR performance, with a limiting potential of &#8722;0.20 V. This study provides theoretical insights for the design and development of efficient NRR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Haotian Dong, Hao Sun, Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Xue-Mei Duan, Jingyao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29040779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e638" altimg="si89.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;-&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e643" altimg="si90.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;z&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; hybridization promotes the high-efficiency hydrogen evolution &#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159642</link>
      <description>Jiajia Zhou, Yu-Hao Wei, Nan Gao, Anlong Kuang, Shao-Yi Wu, Min-Quan Kuang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391655850

                Heusler alloys with tunable electronic properties have promising catalytic applications. In this work, the hydrogen evolution reaction and the underlying catalytic mechanism of the full Heusler alloys Co2TiAl and Co2TiGa are investigated. The first-principles calculations indicate the Gibbs free energy difference (&#916;GH&#8727;) of the active Co-site on the (001) surface is &#8722;0.06 and &#8722;0.07 eV for Co2TiAl and Co2TiGa, respectively, which is comparable to the benchmark Pt (&#8722;0.09 eV). The high-efficiency HER activity can ascribe to the appropriate hybridization between the H-s and Co-dz2 orbital. Noticeably, the HER activity is robust against to the electron (hole) doping until the hybridization between the H-s and Co-dx2&#8722;y2 orbital emerges, in which the hole doping is equal or greater than 0.2 holes per a formula unit. In addition, the activation energy of the Tafel reaction at the Co-site is evaluated to be 0.37 and 0.41 eV for Co2TiAl and Co2TiGa, respectively, which is nearly half of the value of Pt (111) surface (0.85 eV). This work unveils the excellent and robust HER activity of Co2TiAl and Co2TiGa and reveals the s-dz2 bonding is an important factor for designing the HER catalysts based on the L21-type Heusler alloys.</description>
      <author>Jiajia Zhou, Yu-Hao Wei, Nan Gao, Anlong Kuang, Shao-Yi Wu, Min-Quan Kuang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159642</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review on techno-economics of hydrogen production using current and emerging processes: Status and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.101890</link>
      <description>Medhat A. Nemitallah, Abdulrahman A. Alnazha, Usama Ahmed, Mohammed El-Adawy, Mohamed A. Habib, Results in Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391656376

                This review presents a broad exploration of the techno economic evaluation of different technologies utilized in the production of hydrogen from both renewable and non-renewable sources. These encompass methods ranging from extracting hydrogen from fossil fuels or biomass to employing microbial processes, electrolysis of water, and various thermochemical cycles. A rigorous techno-economic evaluation of hydrogen production technologies can provide a critical cost comparison for future resource allocation, priorities, and trajectory. This evaluation will have a great impact on future hydrogen production projects and the development of new approaches to reduce overall production costs and make it a cheaper fuel. Different methods of hydrogen production exhibit varying efficiencies and costs: fast pyrolysis can yield up to 45% hydrogen at a cost range of $1.25 to $2.20 per kilogram, while gasification, operating at temperatures exceeding 750 &#176;C, faces challenges such as limited small-scale coal production and issues with tar formation in biomass. Steam methane reforming, which constitutes 48% of hydrogen output, experiences cost fluctuations depending on scale, whereas auto-thermal reforming offers higher efficiency albeit at increased costs. Chemical looping shows promise in emissions reduction but encounters economic hurdles, and sorption-enhanced reforming achieves over 90% hydrogen but requires CO2 storage. Renewable liquid reforming proves effective and economically viable. Additionally, electrolysis methods like PEM aim for costs below $2.30 per kilogram, while dark fermentation, though cost-effective, grapples with efficiency challenges. Overcoming technical, economic barriers, and managing electricity costs remains crucial for optimizing hydrogen production in a low-carbon future, necessitating ongoing research and development efforts.</description>
      <author>Medhat A. Nemitallah, Abdulrahman A. Alnazha, Usama Ahmed, Mohammed El-Adawy, Mohamed A. Habib</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.101890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening of a Single-Atom Catalyst Supported by Monolayer Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03188</link>
      <description>Keat Hoe Yeoh, Yee Hui Robin Chang, Khian&#8208;Hooi Chew, Junke Jiang, Tiem Leong Yoon, Duu Sheng Ong, Boon Tong Goh, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391657118

                The search for high-performance catalysts to improve the catalytic activity for an oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is crucial for developing a proton exchange membrane fuel cell. Using the first-principles method, we have performed computational screening on a series of transition metal (TM) atoms embedded in monolayer Nb2S2C to enhance the ORR activity. Through the scaling relationship and volcano plot, our results reveal that the introduction of a single Ni or Rh atom through substitutional doping into monolayer Nb2S2C yields promising ORR catalysts with low overpotentials of 0.52 and 0.42 V, respectively. These doped atoms remain intact on the monolayer Nb2S2C even at elevated temperatures. Importantly, the catalytic activity of the Nb2S2C doped with a TM atom can be effectively correlated with an intrinsic descriptor, which can be computed based on the number of d orbital electrons and the electronegativity of TM and O atoms.</description>
      <author>Keat Hoe Yeoh, Yee Hui Robin Chang, Khian&#8208;Hooi Chew, Junke Jiang, Tiem Leong Yoon, Duu Sheng Ong, Boon Tong Goh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical boroncarbonitride nanosheets as metal-free catalysts for enhanced oxidative dehydrogenation of propane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119848</link>
      <description>Guangming Wang, Anming Hu, Qiwei Duan, Longji Cui, Ziyi Chen, Zelong Huang, Xuefei Zhang, Shuping Huang, Zailai Xie, Chemical Engineering Science. 288(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391667305

                Boroncarbonitrides (BCNs) are recently developed new catalytic system for efficient oxidative dehydrogenation (ODH) of alkanes to alkenes. Herein, a series of novel hierarchical BCN materials are synthesized using asymmetric hydrogen bonds self-assembly between methylguanidine and boric acid, along with ammonia deposition. The XRD, S(T)EM, and XPS characterizations confirm the presence of ternary BCN solid solution covered by small serrated-like BCN nanosheets materials in the 2D plates. The unique hierarchical structure and developed mesoporosity of the BCN material contribute to its outstanding catalytic performance. The optimal catalyst delivers robust catalytic performance and long-term stability in the ODH of propane reaction with propylene and total olefin selectivity of 74.7% and 89.7% at a stable 20.4% propane conversion, much better than BCN sheets and h-BN catalyst. Results show that the in-situ formation of suitable amounts of amorphous BOX species within the BCN structure, along with the maintenance of the 2D skeleton at elevated temperatures, is a significant contribution in the enhanced ODH reactivity. Moreover, density functional theory calculation also demonstrates that the presence appropriate carbon content in BCN catalysts can significantly promote the ODH of propane reaction.</description>
      <author>Guangming Wang, Anming Hu, Qiwei Duan, Longji Cui, Ziyi Chen, Zelong Huang, Xuefei Zhang, Shuping Huang, Zailai Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.119848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrastable electrocatalytic seawater splitting at ampere-level current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-023-01263-w</link>
      <description>Rong-Chang Fan, Changhao Liu, Zhonghua Li, Huiting Huang, Jianyong Feng, Zhaosheng Li, Zhigang Zou, Nature Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391680871

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rong-Chang Fan, Changhao Liu, Zhonghua Li, Huiting Huang, Jianyong Feng, Zhaosheng Li, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-023-01263-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Ru&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Active Sites via Coordination Engineering for Tuning Hydrogen Evolution across the Full pH Value</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02367</link>
      <description>Zhaoyang Han, Sang&#8208;Hee Son, Kyungsaeng Kim, Shasha Gao, Gonglei Shao, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391683027

                The asymmetric coordination engineering of single metal atom is a challenging task for single-atom catalysts (SACs) to further amplify the catalytic potential. Hence, a unique asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;N2 active site is meticulously engineered through the pyrolysis of an organic complex with 1,10-phenanthroline-2,9-dicarboxylic acid and Ru metal ions. The coordination evolution of the Ru atom is examined as a function of annealing temperature, evolving from the asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;N2 configuration to the asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;Ru and finally to the Ru&#8211;Ru structure. The electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution performance makes it clear that the SACs with asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;N2 active sites outperform intermediate O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;Ru, Ru nanosheets, and even commercial Pt/C catalysts across the full pH value. The optimal HER performance is attributed to the formation of asymmetric O2&#8211;Ru&#8211;N2 active sites, which exhibit the lowest &#916;GH* owing to the unique structure of Ru coordinated with double heterononmetallic atoms, which is confirmed by X-ray absorption spectroscopy. This work underscores the pivotal role of coordination engineering in SACs, with particular emphasis on the significance of asymmetric single-atom catalytic centers and their potential in diverse catalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Zhaoyang Han, Sang&#8208;Hee Son, Kyungsaeng Kim, Shasha Gao, Gonglei Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acidic media enables oxygen-tolerant electrosynthesis of multicarbon products from simulated flue gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45527-1</link>
      <description>Meng Wang, B.X. Wang, Ji&#8208;Guang Zhang, Shibo Xi, Lixin Ning, Zhiyong Mi, Qin Yang, Mingsheng Zhang, Wan Ru Leow, Jia Zhang, Yanwei Lum, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391687274

                Abstract Renewable electricity powered electrochemical CO 2 reduction (CO 2 R) offers a valuable method to close the carbon cycle and reduce our overreliance on fossil fuels. However, high purity CO 2 is usually required as feedstock, which potentially decreases the feasibility and economic viability of the process. Direct conversion of flue gas is an attractive option but is challenging due to the low CO 2 concentration and the presence of O 2 impurities. As a result, up to 99% of the applied current can be lost towards the undesired oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Here, we show that acidic electrolyte can significantly suppress ORR on Cu, enabling generation of multicarbon products from simulated flue gas. Using a composite Cu and carbon supported single-atom Ni tandem electrocatalyst, we achieved a multicarbon Faradaic efficiency of 46.5% at 200 mA cm -2 , which is ~20 times higher than bare Cu under alkaline conditions. We also demonstrate stable performance for 24 h with a multicarbon product full-cell energy efficiency of 14.6%. Strikingly, this result is comparable to previously reported acidic CO 2 R systems using pure CO 2 . Our findings demonstrate a potential pathway towards designing efficient electrolyzers for direct conversion of flue gas to value-added chemicals and fuels.</description>
      <author>Meng Wang, B.X. Wang, Ji&#8208;Guang Zhang, Shibo Xi, Lixin Ning, Zhiyong Mi, Qin Yang, Mingsheng Zhang, Wan Ru Leow, Jia Zhang, Yanwei Lum</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45527-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Modulation in Cu Doped NiCo LDH/NiCo Heterostructure for Highly Efficient Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311182</link>
      <description>Xuewen Xia, Shujuan Wang, Dan Li&#250;, Fei Wang, Xueqiang Zhang, Hao Zhang, Xiaojiang Yu, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Chaoyi Chen, Yufeng Zhao, Ji Li, Qian Xu, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391690247

                Abstract Layered double hydroxides (LDHs), promising bifunctional electrocatalysts for overall water splitting, are hindered by their poor conductivity and sluggish electrochemical reaction kinetics. Herein, a hierarchical Cu&#8208;doped NiCo LDH/NiCo alloy heterostructure with rich oxygen vacancies by electronic modulation is tactfully designed. It extraordinarily effectively drives both the oxygen evolution reaction (151 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (73 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) in an alkaline medium. As bifunctional electrodes for overall water splitting, a low cell voltage of 1.51 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and remarkable long&#8208;term stability for 100 h are achieved. The experimental and theoretical results reveal that Cu doping and NiCo alloy recombination can improve the conductivity and reaction kinetics of NiCo LDH with surface charge redistribution and reduced Gibbs free energy barriers. This work provides a new inspiration for further design and construction of nonprecious metal&#8208;based bifunctional electrocatalysts based on electronic structure modulation strategies.</description>
      <author>Xuewen Xia, Shujuan Wang, Dan Li&#250;, Fei Wang, Xueqiang Zhang, Hao Zhang, Xiaojiang Yu, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Chaoyi Chen, Yufeng Zhao, Ji Li, Qian Xu, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311182</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate construction of cobalt vacancies in Co3O4 to promote oxyhydroxide formation for water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2766-y</link>
      <description>Zhijuan Liu, Guangjin Wang, Jinyu Guo, Yanyong Wang, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391690577

                The introduction of defect sites has been widely reported to enhance electrocatalysts&#8217; abilities by increasing their affinity for reaction intermediates. Many different defect types, such as cation and anion vacancies, can exist in nano-materials. The different defect sites can make different contributions to the electrochemical ability. Therefore, a constructed defect should be accurate and specific, which makes it easy to identify the optimal defect type to facilitate electrochemical reactions. In this work, we used cobalt vacancies in Co3O4 as an example and synthesized Co3O4 with bivalent cobalt vacancies (Co3O4-VCo(II)) and trivalent cobalt vacancies (Co3O4-VCo(III)). Electrochemical results demonstrate that introducing cobalt vacancies considerably enhances the electrocatalytic activity of Co3O4. Furthermore, Co3O4-VCo(II) exhibits the most outstanding oxygen evolution ability with the fastest reaction kinetic rate. Quasi-operando X-ray photoelectron microscopy spectrum analysis results indicate that the presence of VCo(II) can accelerate CoOOH active site formation during the oxygen evolution reaction process. Density functional theory calculations reveal that introducing cobalt vacancies can endow Co3O4 with metal-like conductivity. The O p-band center can be moved near the Fermi level, and the free energy barrier can be the lowest with the presence of VCo(II), resulting in a fast kinetics rate of oxygen exchange at the electrocatalyst surface and optimal adsorption energy to reaction intermediates to display excellent electrochemical ability. This work provides substantial guidance for designing efficient defect-rich electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhijuan Liu, Guangjin Wang, Jinyu Guo, Yanyong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2766-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Element-dependent effects of alkali cations on nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.02.011</link>
      <description>Yida Zhang, Zhentao Ma, Shuo Yang, Qingyu Wang, Limin Liu, Yu Bai, Dewei Rao, Gongming Wang, Hongliang Li, Xusheng Zheng, Science Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391691052

                Catalytic conversion of nitrate (NO3&#8722;) pollutants into ammonia (NH3) offers a sustainable and promising route for both wastewater treatment and NH3 synthesis. Alkali cations are prevalent in nitrate solutions, but their roles beyond charge balance in catalytic NO3&#8722; conversion have been generally ignored. Herein, we report the promotion effect of K+ cations in KNO3 solution for NO3&#8722; reduction over a TiO2-supported Ni single-atom catalyst (Ni1/TiO2). For photocatalytic NO3&#8722; reduction reaction, Ni1/TiO2 exhibited a 1.9-fold NH3 yield rate with nearly 100% selectivity in KNO3 solution relative to that in NaNO3 solution. Mechanistic studies reveal that the K+ cations from KNO3 gradually bonded with the surface of Ni1/TiO2, in situ forming a K-O-Ni moiety during reaction, whereas the Na+ ions were unable to interact with the catalyst in NaNO3 solution. The charge accumulation on the Ni sites induced by the incorporation of K atom promoted the adsorption and activation of NO3&#8722;. Furthermore, the K-O-Ni moiety facilitated the multiple proton-electron coupling of NO3&#8722; into NH3 by stabilizing the intermediates.</description>
      <author>Yida Zhang, Zhentao Ma, Shuo Yang, Qingyu Wang, Limin Liu, Yu Bai, Dewei Rao, Gongming Wang, Hongliang Li, Xusheng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.02.011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of H2O2 via two-electron oxygen reduction over carbon-based catalysts: From microenvironment control to electrode/reactor design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enrev.2024.100069</link>
      <description>Jingjing Jia, Zhenxin Li, Yunrui Tian, Xia Li, Rui Chen, Jiachen Liu, Ji Liang, Energy reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391691194

                The electrochemical production of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) by the two-electron oxygen reduction (2e&#8722;-ORR) process has the advantages of high safety, low energy consumption, and environmental friendliness. For 2e&#8722;-ORR, the catalyst/electrode is the key component as it strongly affects catalytic performance and cost. Carbon materials have the advantages of high electronic conductivity, good structural stability, easy control of nanostructures, and low cost. Therefore, it has been regarded as a promising catalyst/electrode material for the electrosynthesis of H2O2 via 2e&#8722;-ORR. In addition, studies have also considered the optimization of the liquid/gas interface by tuning the electrode surface, electrolyte pH, and reactor configurations for further improving the activity and selectivity of catalysts. In this review, we provide an in-depth discussion of the recent research on the carbon-based electrocatalysts for 2e&#8722;-ORR, especially in terms of microenvironment tuning, catalyst/electrode interface engineering, and reactor design for achieving stable and efficient production of H2O2. The challenges that we are still facing and the future development prospects will then be concluded, which we believe should help the future development in this field.</description>
      <author>Jingjing Jia, Zhenxin Li, Yunrui Tian, Xia Li, Rui Chen, Jiachen Liu, Ji Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enrev.2024.100069</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
