<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:45:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Highly efficient Ru-based Heusler alloys for nitrogen reduction reaction: Breaking scaling relations and regulating potential determining steps</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159686</link>
      <description>Xiayong Chen, Jing Zhou, Wangyu Hu, Bowen Huang, Dingwang Yuan, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391733718

                In this study, we investigated the catalytic activity of Ru-based Heusler alloys towards the nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) using first-principles calculations. Compared to pure Ru metal, these alloys exhibit a significant reduction in the overpotential, showcasing enhanced catalytic performance. The most promising candidate, the Ru2ScP alloy, demonstrates an impressively low overpotential of only &#8722;0.40 V for the NRR, and it also exhibits higher selectivity towards NRR over the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Furthermore, we found that several key adsorbates on the surface of the candidate alloys simultaneously exhibit non-linear scaling relationships of adsorption free energies. This allows for individual control over the barrier of potential determining steps (PDS) in the NRR process by overcoming the limitation of the scaling relations in pure metals. This study offers valuable guidance for the design of Ru-based Heusler alloys to obtain improved catalytic performance for the NRR.</description>
      <author>Xiayong Chen, Jing Zhou, Wangyu Hu, Bowen Huang, Dingwang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Strain Effect on Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction of Pt-Based Intermetallics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06291</link>
      <description>Z.Y. Zhong, Yuanhua Tu, Longhai Zhang, Ke Jiang, Chengzhi Zhong, Wei Tan, Lingyu Wang, Jiaxi Zhang, Hui&#8208;Hua Song, Li Du, Zhiming Cui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391738668

                Elucidating the relationship between electrocatalytic activity and surface strain is pivotal for designing highly efficient electrocatalysts for the acidic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, a general correlation is currently absent due to the lack of ideal catalytic materials platforms with well-defined structures and components. Herein, we select L10 and L12 Pt-based intermetallic compounds as model materials to construct a series of core&#8211;shell catalysts with strained Pt skins (IMC@Pt) and establish the correlation between surface strain and HER performance. Density functional theory calculations were performed to determine the surface strain degree, d-band center, and key descriptor &#916;GH* of the catalysts for HER. By combining theoretical and experimental data, we propose a volcano-type trend between surface strain and the HER activity of IMC@Pt with an apex at 4% compressive strain. In addition, we demonstrate a class of highly active and durable IMC@Pt catalysts for acidic HER. Among them, the Pt3V@Pt catalyst exhibits the highest intrinsic HER activity with a specific activity of 4.24 mA cmPt&#8211;2 at an overpotential of 20 mV, which is 4 times higher than that of Pt. This work provides a solid understanding of the essential nature of PtM alloy catalysts and can guide the design of high-performance HER catalysts for water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Z.Y. Zhong, Yuanhua Tu, Longhai Zhang, Ke Jiang, Chengzhi Zhong, Wei Tan, Lingyu Wang, Jiaxi Zhang, Hui&#8208;Hua Song, Li Du, Zhiming Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Electronic Properties-Driven Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction on Metal-Conjugated Porphyrin 2D-MOFs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c16406</link>
      <description>Ashakiran Maibam, Ibrahim Orhan, Sa&#239;laja Krishnamurty, Salvy P. Russo, Ravichandar Babarao, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391742646

                Two-dimensional (2D) metal organic framework (MOF) or metalloporphyrin nanosheets with a stable metal-N4 complex unit present the metal as a single-atom catalyst dispersed in the 2D porphyrin framework. First-principles calculations on the 3d-transition metals in M-TCPP are investigated in this study for their surface-dependent electronic properties including work function and d-band center. Crystal orbital Hamiltonian population (-pCOHP) analysis highlights a higher contribution of the bonding state in the M&#8211;N bond and antibonding state in the N&#8211;N bond to be essential for N&#8211;N bond activation. A linear relationship between &#916;Gmax and surface electronic properties, N&#8211;N bond strength, and Bader charge has been found to influence the rate-determining potential for nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) in M-TCPP MOFs. 2D Ti-TCPP MOF, with a kinetic energy barrier of 1.43 eV in the final protonation step of enzymatic NRR, shows exclusive NRR selectivity over competing hydrogen reduction (HER) and nitrogenous compounds (NO and NO2). Thus, Ti-TCPP MOF with an NRR limiting potential of &#8722;0.35 V in water solvent is proposed as an attractive candidate for electrocatalytic NRR.</description>
      <author>Ashakiran Maibam, Ibrahim Orhan, Sa&#239;laja Krishnamurty, Salvy P. Russo, Ravichandar Babarao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c16406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of theory prediction and experimental electrooxidation of glycerol on NiCo2O4 nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64585-1</link>
      <description>Yan Duan, Mifeng Xue, Yizhi Liu, Man Zhang, Yuchen Wang, Baojun Wang, Riguang Zhang, Kai Yan, Chinese Journal of Catalysis. 57(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391743253

                Electrocatalytic refinery of low-value biomass-based glycerol into value-added chemicals formic acid (FA) is an attractive alternative to traditional thermochemical refineries. However, constructing non-precious catalysts with abundant active hydroxyl (OH*) is the main obstacle to the electrocatalytic glycerol oxidation reaction (EGOR). Herein, we combine density functional theory (DFT) and experiments to investigate EGOR over the finely constructed NiCo2O4 nanosheets. DFT results firstly indicate that the NiCo2O4 nanosheets exhibit the highly hydroxylated (311)-OH* surface with the lowest Gibbs free energy, which significantly improves the electrochemical reaction kinetics and can achieve desirable FA yield by adjusting the adsorption energy of the adsorption intermediate. Following the theoretical prediction, ultrathin NiCo2O4 nanosheets (~1.70 nm) are fabricated by a facile electrodeposition method with sufficient OH* on the surface. The charge-transfer resistance of NiCo2O4 nanosheets in EGOR is only 0.94 &#937; and the anode power consumption can be reduced by up to 320 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, keeping the high glycerol conversion (89%) and FA selectivity (70%) during the 120-h stability test. DFT calculations and experimental tools (e.g., multi-potential step experiments, operational electrochemical impedance spectroscopy) confirm that OH* in-situ generated on the thin nanosheets structure is essential in facilitating charge transfer between catalysts and adsorbed molecules to enhance C&#8211;C bond cleavage. This work offers a guideline for the rational design of robust catalysts for the selective upgrading of biomass-derived chemicals.</description>
      <author>Yan Duan, Mifeng Xue, Yizhi Liu, Man Zhang, Yuchen Wang, Baojun Wang, Riguang Zhang, Kai Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64585-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Role of Cations in Stabilizing Hydrogen Radicals for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-CO Conversion via a Reverse Water-Gas Shift Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00005</link>
      <description>Ruijuan Zhao, Lei Li, Qianbao Wu, Qing Li, Chunhua Cui, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391755712

                Electrochemically converting CO2 into valuable chemicals and fuels in acidic media is argued as a promising energy- and carbon-efficient route. Although several key roles of alkali cations have been unveiled, the alkali cation trends for CO2 reduction remain largely elusive. With decreasing cation size from Cs+ to Li+, here we show that the apparent proton diffusion coefficient in 3.0 M Li+ is tens-fold lower than in 3.0 M K+ and 3.0 M Cs+ acidic electrolytes. Although Li+ has the strongest inhibition ability for proton transport, it acts the worst for both the CO2-to-CO conversion and partial current density on Au catalysts. Unexpectedly, K+ with a higher proton transport performs the best for CO2-to-CO conversion. We thus revisit the roles of alkali cations and find that hydrated K+ can stabilize hydrogen radicals benefiting CO2 conversion at the electrode interface while for Li+ this is not the case. This study proposes that cation-stabilized atomic hydrogen assists in activating CO2 via a reverse water-gas shift route under electrochemical conditions.</description>
      <author>Ruijuan Zhao, Lei Li, Qianbao Wu, Qing Li, Chunhua Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Assisted Analysis and Prediction of Rubber Formulation Using Existing Databases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aichem.2024.100054</link>
      <description>Wei Deng, Yuhui Zhao, Yinggan Zheng, Yilong Yin, Hongwei Yan, Lijun Liu, Dapeng Wang, Artificial Intelligence Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391755935

                Designing rubber formulations can greatly benefit from using a database that stores the formulations and corresponding property data of rubber composites. Such a database can expedite the decision-making process by swiftly identifying the most suitable formulations for specific applications. However, the management of a rubber formulation database encounters various issues, including missing formulation and property data, as well as data entry errors. These issues can impede the decision-making processes and even result in incorrect decisions being made. In this study, machine learning (ML) algorithms were applied to analyze rubber formulation databases. Our findings highlight the success of the ML algorithm in effectively filling in missing data and identifying erroneous data. Furthermore, it demonstrates the accurate prediction of properties for untested formulations within the pre-determined database space. The results underline the outstanding performance of ML algorithms in expediting the rubber formulation design process and emphasize their immense potential to play a prominent role in the advancement of rubber composites.</description>
      <author>Wei Deng, Yuhui Zhao, Yinggan Zheng, Yilong Yin, Hongwei Yan, Lijun Liu, Dapeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aichem.2024.100054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the modulation mechanism of B-site doping on the thermochemical properties of CaMnO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&lt;i&gt;&#948;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;: an experimental and computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta04632j</link>
      <description>Zeyu Ning, S. L. Gan, Haoran Xu, C.D. Gu, Peixi Zhu, Jinsong Zhou, Gang Xiao, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391758420

                Cr and Fe doping disrupts the electronegativity and bond energy balance of CaMnO 3 , creating different active sites and enhancing the reactivity. Bond energy calculations allow the prediction of reaction temperature and reaction enthalpy.</description>
      <author>Zeyu Ning, S. L. Gan, Haoran Xu, C.D. Gu, Peixi Zhu, Jinsong Zhou, Gang Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta04632j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational chemistry for water-splitting electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d2cs01068b</link>
      <description>Licheng Miao, Wenzhao Jia, Xuejie Cao, Lifang Jiao, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391758505

                This review presents the basics of electrochemical water electrolysis, discusses the progress in computational methods, models, and descriptors, and evaluates the remaining challenges in this field.</description>
      <author>Licheng Miao, Wenzhao Jia, Xuejie Cao, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d2cs01068b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal single-atom anchored on MoSi2N4 monolayer as highly efficient electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.113926</link>
      <description>Wei Xun, Xin Liu, Qingsong Jiang, Yin&#8208;Zhong Wu, Xiao Yang, Molecular Catalysis. 556(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391764443

                Single-atom catalysts are considered as a promising method for efficient energy conversion, owing to their advantages of high atom utilization and low catalyst cost. However, finding a stable two-dimensional structure and high hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance is a current research hotspot. Herein, based on the first-principles calculations, we identify the HER properties of six catalysts (TM@MoSi2N4, TM = Sc, Ti, V, Fe, Co, and Ni) comprising transition metal atoms anchored on MoSi2N4 monolayer. The results show that the spin-polarized states appear around the Fermi level after anchoring TM atoms. Therefore, the energy level of the first available unoccupied state for accommodating hydrogen drops, regulating the bonding strength of hydrogen. Thus, the single transition metal atom activates the active site of the MoSi2N4 inert base plane, becoming a quite suitable site for the HER. Based on &#916;GH*, the exchange current density and volcano diagram of the corresponding catalytic system were also calculated. Among them, V@MoSi2N4 (&#916;GH* = -0.07 eV) and Ni@MoSi2N4 (&#916;GH* = 0.06 eV) systems show efficient the HER property. Our study confirms that the transition metal atom anchoring is an effective means to improve the performance of electrocatalysis, and TM@MoSi2N4 has practical application potential as a high efficiency HER electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Wei Xun, Xin Liu, Qingsong Jiang, Yin&#8208;Zhong Wu, Xiao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.113926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental evidences of the direct influence of external magnetic fields on the mechanism of the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0179761</link>
      <description>Camilo A. Mesa, Felipe A. Garc&#233;s&#8208;Pineda, Miguel Garc&#237;a&#8208;Tecedor, Jiahao Yu, Bahareh Khezri, Sergi Plana-Ruiz, Bruno L&#243;pez, R. Iturbe, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, APL Energy. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391766798

                The use of magnetic fields as external stimuli to improve the kinetics of electrochemical reactions is attracting substantial attention, given their potential to reduce energy losses. Despite recent reports showing a positive effect on catalytic performance upon applying a magnetic field to a working electrode, there are still many uncertainties and a lack of experimental evidence correlating the presence of the magnetic field to the electrocatalytic performance. Here, we present a combination of electrochemical and spectroscopic tools that demonstrate how the presence of an external magnetic field alters the reaction mechanism of the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), accelerating the overall performance of a Ni4FeOx electrode. Complementary experimental evidence has been gathered supporting the participation of this microscopic magnetic field effect. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) points to a speed-up of the intrinsic reaction kinetics, independent of other indirect effects. In the same direction, the spectro-electrochemical fingerprint of the intermediate species that appear during the electrocatalytic cycle, as detected under operando conditions, indicates a change in the order of the reaction as a function of hole accumulation. All these experimental data confirm the direct influence of an external magnetic field on the reaction mechanism at the origin of the magnetically enhanced electrocatalytic OER.</description>
      <author>Camilo A. Mesa, Felipe A. Garc&#233;s&#8208;Pineda, Miguel Garc&#237;a&#8208;Tecedor, Jiahao Yu, Bahareh Khezri, Sergi Plana-Ruiz, Bruno L&#243;pez, R. Iturbe, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0179761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of N/Fe/S-Codoped Cathode Catalysts on Gasification Residue Carbon for Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04344</link>
      <description>Simin Wang, Liang Ren, Guoyu Zhang, Yan Gong, Qinghua Guo, Guangsuo Yu, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391772163

                The gasification fine slag (GFS) contains a large amount of residual carbon (RC). The RC has a large specific surface area, a well-developed pore structure, and a wide pore size distribution. Therefore, oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts can be prepared using the RC and can be applied in zinc&#8211;air batteries. In this work, ORR catalysts were prepared by using the RC as precursors with N/Fe/S codoping. The codoping effect between different heteroatoms was investigated by combining physicochemical and electrochemical characterization. The results demonstrate that the N/Fe/S-codoped catalyst CKN6FeS has a high onset potential and average electron transfer number. In alkaline conditions, CKN6FeS exhibits catalytic activity comparable to that of commercial Pt/C and shows better methanol tolerance than that of Pt/C. It shows good catalytic ability in zinc&#8211;air batteries with good cycling stability and durability, achieving high power density and specific capacity.</description>
      <author>Simin Wang, Liang Ren, Guoyu Zhang, Yan Gong, Qinghua Guo, Guangsuo Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironment reconstitution of highly active Ni single atoms on oxygen-incorporated Mo2C for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45533-3</link>
      <description>Mengyun Hou, Lirong Zheng, D.L. Zhao, Xin Tan, Wuyi Feng, Jiantao Fu, Tianxin Wei, Minhua Cao, Jiatao Zhang, Chen Chen, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391772549

                Abstract The rational design of efficient bifunctional single-atom electrocatalysts for industrial water splitting and the comprehensive understanding of its complex catalytic mechanisms remain challenging. Here, we report a Ni single atoms supported on oxygen-incorporated Mo 2 C via Ni-O-Mo bridge bonds, that gives high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) bifunctional activity. By ex situ synchrotron X-ray absorption spectroscopy and electron microscopy, we found that after HER, the coordination number and bond lengths of Ni-O and Ni-Mo (Ni-O-Mo) were all altered, yet the Ni species still remain atomically dispersed. In contrast, after OER, the atomically dispersed Ni were agglomerated into very small clusters with new Ni-Ni (Ni-O-Ni) bonds appeared. Combining experimental results and DFT calculations, we infer the oxidation degree of Mo 2 C and the configuration of single-atom Ni are both vital for HER or OER. This study provides both a feasible strategy and model to rational design highly efficient electrocatalysts for water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Mengyun Hou, Lirong Zheng, D.L. Zhao, Xin Tan, Wuyi Feng, Jiantao Fu, Tianxin Wei, Minhua Cao, Jiatao Zhang, Chen Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45533-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting hydrogen evolution kinetics of self-supported MoC-Mo2C heterojunction electrode by platinum decoration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143922</link>
      <description>Wenting Li, Yibin Yao, Xianglin Liu, Yu Zhang, Wei Liu, Ze Liu, Huayi Yin, Dihua Wang, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391772744

                Molybdenum carbide-based hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) electrocatalysts have attracted widespread attention with their low cost and relatively high catalytic activity. Despite the significant progress made in tuning the morphology and structure, the intrinsic catalytic activity of molybdenum carbide awaits further improvement. Herein, a Pt-decorated self-supported MoC-Mo2C electrode with super-intrinsic HER catalytic activity is prepared by a simple adsorption-electroreduction method. The HER performance is improved with increasing the loading of Pt. The optimal MoC-Mo2C-Pt heterojunction electrode has a low overpotential of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 (58 mV in H2SO4, 82 mV in KOH) and small Tafel slope (24 mV dec&#8722;1 in H2SO4, 29 mV dec&#8722;1 in KOH), which is reduced to 0.45-0.5, 0.7-0.8, and 0.4-0.7 times of pristine MoC-Mo2C, Pt foil, and commercial Pt/C (2 mg cm&#8722;2), respectively. The improved HER catalysis is attributed to the rapid dissociation of water on MoC-Mo2C and efficient desorption of hydrogen on Pt. Therefore, decorating carbides with Pt is an effective way to design HER catalysts with enhanced catalytic activities in a wide pH range.</description>
      <author>Wenting Li, Yibin Yao, Xianglin Liu, Yu Zhang, Wei Liu, Ze Liu, Huayi Yin, Dihua Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free-Standing Single-Atom Catalyst-Based Electrodes for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41918-023-00193-7</link>
      <description>M. Nur Hossain, Lei Zhang, Roberto Neagu, Enoch Rassachack, Electrochemical Energy Reviews. 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391775270

                Abstract Electrochemical CO 2 reduction technology could solve the CO 2 -induced climate warming by electrochemically converting atmospheric CO 2 back into fuel, essentially recycling it and building a low carbon emission economy. However, the electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) poses a significant challenge due to the highly stable and linear CO 2 molecules, in addition to a proton-coupled multi-electron transfer process. Thus, highly active catalysts, placed on activity bolstering materials, and permeable electrodes are crucial for CO 2 RR. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have recently garnered increasing interest in the electrocatalysis community due to their potentially high mass efficiency and cost benefits (every atom is an active center, resulting in nearly 100% utilization) and adjustable selectivity (higher uniformity of the active sites compared to nanoparticles). However, preserving the accessibility and activity of the SACs inside the electrode poses major materials development and electrode design challenges. A conventional layered structure SAC electrode typically consists of a gas diffusion layer (GDL), a microporous layer (MPL) and a SAC catalyst layer (SACCL), fabricated by using a powder bonding process. However, this process usually encounters issues such as delamination and instability of SACs due to the weak binder-catalyst-support interface. Conversely, the free-standing SAC electrode design has the potential to overcome these issues by eliminating the GDL, MPL, and need of a binder, in contrast to the powder bonding process. This work first reviews the latest developments in experimental and modeling studies of powdered SAC electrode by the traditional powder bonding process. Next, it examines the development towards the free-standing SAC electrode for high-performance electrochemical reduction of CO 2 . The synthesis-structure-fabrication-performance relationships of SAC-based materials and associated electrodes are analyzed. Furthermore, the article presents future challenges and perspectives for high-performance SAC electrodes for CO 2 RR. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>M. Nur Hossain, Lei Zhang, Roberto Neagu, Enoch Rassachack</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41918-023-00193-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metals Based Dual Single&#8208;atom Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis: Stunning Advances and Future Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301392</link>
      <description>Saira Ajmal, Yang Zhao, Ghulam Yasin, Felix Ofori Boakye, Mohammad Tabish, Mohammed Mujahid Alam, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Wei Zhao, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391778585

                Abstract During the past few years, single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted considerable attention in electrolysis due to their outstanding catalytic performance and efficient atomic utilization. SACs exhibit a simple structure, high catalytic activity, consistent scaling relationships for single sites, and low metal content but their practical applications are still limited. Dual single&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs), which feature excellent selectivity, high atomic utilization efficiency, and remarkable stability, are emerging as new frontiers in heterogeneous electrocatalysis. They increase catalytic activity by promoting synergistic effects between metal&#8208;active sites. In this paper, we present a comprehensive overview of the latest developments in dual&#8208;atom catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In addition, we explore the differences between homonuclear and heteronuclear configurations, the emergence of single/dual&#8208;site metal catalysts, and the methods currently used for their synthesis. Lastly, this review discusses several perspectives for advancing the development of dual&#8208;atom catalysts for OER and ORR electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Saira Ajmal, Yang Zhao, Ghulam Yasin, Felix Ofori Boakye, Mohammad Tabish, Mohammed Mujahid Alam, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Wei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkage-engineered donor&#8211;acceptor covalent organic frameworks for optimal photosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide from water and air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-023-01102-3</link>
      <description>Ruoyang Liu, Yongzhi Chen, Hongde Yu, Miroslav Polo&#382;ij, Yuanyuan Guo, Tze Chien Sum, Thomas Heine, Donglin Jiang, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391779736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruoyang Liu, Yongzhi Chen, Hongde Yu, Miroslav Polo&#382;ij, Yuanyuan Guo, Tze Chien Sum, Thomas Heine, Donglin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-023-01102-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Adsorption, Structure and Dynamics of Co2 &#8211; Ch4 Mixture in Mg-Mof-74 and the Influence of Intercrystalline Orientational Disorder</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4724684</link>
      <description>Indu Dhiman, Siddharth Gautam, David R. Cole, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391791247

                Mg-MOF-74 is a highly efficient adsorbent for CO2 and is known to exhibit good performance in the separation of a CO2-CH4 mixture via selective adsorption. In this work we use molecular simulations to study the effects of disorder in Mg-MOF-74 on the selective adsorption, structure, and dynamics of a CO2-CH4 mixture. Positional disorder is introduced in the adsorbent by separating individual Mg-MOF-74 crystallites via inserting intercrystalline space between them. Rotating a crystallite with respect to others by different extents provides the orientational disorder (OD). Positional disorder is observed to enhance the adsorption selectivity of CO2 over CH4. The additional adsorption sites made available by exposing crystallite surfaces may provide added selectively for CO2. Mechanistically, solid-fluid interaction and associated dynamics at the additional sites is produced by predominantly an electrostatic affect. While OD in Mg-MOF-74 is found to have a rather weak effect on the rotation of CO2, its effects on the translational motion of CO2 are significant. This behavior follows a systematic pattern dictated by the interplay of the pore geometry of Mg-MOF-74 and Mg2+ - CO2 interactions. Our results provide a guide on how to tailor Mg-MOF-74 adsorption behavior with desired properties by purposeful introduction of OD.</description>
      <author>Indu Dhiman, Siddharth Gautam, David R. Cole</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4724684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing hydrogen evolution reaction using iridium atomic monolayer on conventional electrodes: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.156</link>
      <description>Abdul Ahad Mamun, Asif Billah, Muhammad Anisuzzaman Talukder, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391798117

                In a water-electrolysis system for hydrogen production, the kinetics of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) critically depend on the exchange current density (J0) of the electrode. Noble metals, e.g., Pt, Ir, Rh, and Au, offer a significant J0 when used as electrodes, assisting faster HER. However, instead of using expensive noble metals as electrodes, a thin layer on conventional electrodes, e.g., Ni, Cu, Ag, and Mo, also increases J0. An electrode&#8217;s J0 during HER is calculated from the free energy of hydrogen adsorption (&#916;GH), which is determined from hydrogen adsorption energy (Ead) on the electrode surface. This work considered an Ir atomic monolayer as an electrocatalyst on the (111) plane of conventional Ni, Cu, Ag, and Mo electrodes, producing modified Ir/Ni(111), Ir/Cu(111), Ir/Ag(111), and Ir/Mo(111) electrodes. This work calculated Ead of the modified electrodes using the density functional theory (DFT). In addition, this work develops an advanced kinetic model for the exchange current density considering the concentration of hydrogen ions (CH+) and partial pressure of hydrogen gas (PH2). The dependence of activation overpotential (&#951;a) vs. J0 relationship on CH+ and PH2 in HER is investigated. For the modified electrodes, J0 increases by 102&#8211;103 times compared to the conventional electrodes, resulting in efficient H2 production with low losses.</description>
      <author>Abdul Ahad Mamun, Asif Billah, Muhammad Anisuzzaman Talukder</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of mixing time on a reversal tolerant anode measured ex situ for a PEMFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.236</link>
      <description>S.J.T. Homan, Kerem Aylar, Adrian Jurjevi&#263;, M. Scolari, Atsushi Urakawa, Peyman Taheri, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391804977

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S.J.T. Homan, Kerem Aylar, Adrian Jurjevi&#263;, M. Scolari, Atsushi Urakawa, Peyman Taheri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of Nitrogen Coordination Modulation of Fe_N&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;@BP System Catalysts on the Activity of Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07527</link>
      <description>Ching T. Hou, Sen Ming, Keyuan Chen, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Lian Yu, Hongying Hou, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391806634

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ching T. Hou, Sen Ming, Keyuan Chen, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Lian Yu, Hongying Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Study of Nitrogen Fixation Electrocatalysts Based on Two-Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05754</link>
      <description>Zhengqin Xiong, Ying Xu, An Yu Bao, Sheng Wei, Jie Zhan, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391811694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhengqin Xiong, Ying Xu, An Yu Bao, Sheng Wei, Jie Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Nitric Oxide Reduction Reaction through Surface Doping on Superstructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109396</link>
      <description>Baokun Zhang, Ying Dai, Baibiao Huang, Zhao Qian, Rajeev Ahuja, Wei Wei, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391812169

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baokun Zhang, Ying Dai, Baibiao Huang, Zhao Qian, Rajeev Ahuja, Wei Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-N-C core-shell catalysts with single low-spin Fe(&#8545;)-N4 species for oxygen reduction reaction and high-performance proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.074</link>
      <description>Wei Yan, Linhui Yu, Binghua Yang, Caihong Li, Fang Chen, Wenlong Guo, Fang&#8208;Xing Xiao, Yangming Lin, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391817857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Yan, Linhui Yu, Binghua Yang, Caihong Li, Fang Chen, Wenlong Guo, Fang&#8208;Xing Xiao, Yangming Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.074</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Polaritonic Chemistry: Accessing Chemical Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c12829</link>
      <description>Christian Sch&#228;fer, Jakub Fojt, Eric Lindgren, Paul Erhart, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391824217

                Altering chemical reactivity and material structure in confined optical environments is on the rise, and yet, a conclusive understanding of the microscopic mechanisms remains elusive. This originates mostly from the fact that accurately predicting vibrational and reactive dynamics for soluted ensembles of realistic molecules is no small endeavor, and adding (collective) strong light&#8211;matter interaction does not simplify matters. Here, we establish a framework based on a combination of machine learning (ML) models, trained using density-functional theory calculations and molecular dynamics to accelerate such simulations. We then apply this approach to evaluate strong coupling, changes in reaction rate constant, and their influence on enthalpy and entropy for the deprotection reaction of 1-phenyl-2-trimethylsilylacetylene, which has been studied previously both experimentally and using ab initio simulations. While we find qualitative agreement with critical experimental observations, especially with regard to the changes in kinetics, we also find differences in comparison with previous theoretical predictions. The features for which the ML-accelerated and ab initio simulations agree show the experimentally estimated kinetic behavior. Conflicting features indicate that a contribution of dynamic electronic polarization to the reaction process is more relevant than currently believed. Our work demonstrates the practical use of ML for polaritonic chemistry, discusses limitations of common approximations, and paves the way for a more holistic description of polaritonic chemistry.</description>
      <author>Christian Sch&#228;fer, Jakub Fojt, Eric Lindgren, Paul Erhart</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c12829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size tuning of Pt nanoparticles on ZrO2: Optimizing catalytic performance for hydrogen evolution and water-splitting reactions - A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.142</link>
      <description>Ayyaz Mahmood, Tehmina Akram, Shenggui Chen, Huafu Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391825258

                In heterogeneous catalysis, determining the optimal metal particle size is challenging due to the intricate relationship between particle size, electronic structure, and activity. Here, we investigate the size-dependent activity of Pt nanoparticle (PtNP)-based ZrO2 catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and water-splitting reaction (WSR) using density functional theory (DFT) and ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations. By analyzing different Pt nanoparticle sizes (Pt4, Pt7, Pt11, P15, Pt19, and Pt25) supported on ZrO2, we determined their optimized geometries, and electronic structures, and calculated the hydrogen adsorption energies (&#916;GH) for HER and activation energies barrier (&#916;&#8225;G) for WSR. The calculated results demonstrate that Pt11 is the optimal size for HER, exhibiting the lowest &#916;GH (&#8722;0.066 eV), while Pt15 shows the lowest &#916;&#8225;G (0.24 eV) for WSR. The density of states (DOS) shows that the occupied Pt states fill the gap of ZrO2 (3.72 eV), significantly reducing the band gap (Eg) of the PtNP/ZrO2 composites. The most favorable configuration of the PtNP on ZrO2 for HER and WSR is determined to be a three-Pt-layer structure with rooflike edges which corresponds to a nanoparticle size of &#8764;0.70&#8211;1.55 nm for experiments. These findings can be regarded as an effort toward the design and optimization of metal-based oxide catalysts for renewable energy applications.</description>
      <author>Ayyaz Mahmood, Tehmina Akram, Shenggui Chen, Huafu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Structural Optimization for the Supported Metal System Based on Hybrid Approach Combining Bayesian Optimization with Local Search</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01265</link>
      <description>Shinyoung Bae, Dongjae Shin, H. Jin Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Jong Min Lee, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391847110

                Numerous systematic methods have been developed to search for the global minimum of the potential energy surface, which corresponds to the optimal atomic structure. However, the majority of them still demand a substantial computing load due to the relaxation process that is embedded as an inner step inside the algorithm. Here, we propose a hybrid approach that combines Bayesian optimization (BO) and a local search that circumvents the relaxation step and efficiently finds the optimum structure, particularly in supported metal systems. The hybridization strategy combining the capabilities of BO&#8217;s effective exploration and the local search&#8217;s fast convergence expedites structural search. In addition, the formulation of physical constraints regarding the materials system and the feature of screening structure similarity enhance the computational efficiency of the proposed method. The proposed algorithm is demonstrated in two supported metal systems, showing the potential of the proposed method in the field of structural optimization.</description>
      <author>Shinyoung Bae, Dongjae Shin, H. Jin Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Jong Min Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01265</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
