<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New citations for John Kitchin</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/New-citations-for-John-Kitchin.xml</link>
    <description>New citations for my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 12:35:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing geometric representations for molecules with equivariant vector-scalar interactive message passing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-43720-2</link>
      <description>Yusong Wang, Tong Wang, Shaoning Li, Xinheng He, Mingyu Li, Zun Wang, Nanning Zheng, Borong Shao, Tie-Yan Liu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390617556

                Abstract Geometric deep learning has been revolutionizing the molecular modeling field. Despite the state-of-the-art neural network models are approaching ab initio accuracy for molecular property prediction, their applications, such as drug discovery and molecular dynamics (MD) simulation, have been hindered by insufficient utilization of geometric information and high computational costs. Here we propose an equivariant geometry-enhanced graph neural network called ViSNet, which elegantly extracts geometric features and efficiently models molecular structures with low computational costs. Our proposed ViSNet outperforms state-of-the-art approaches on multiple MD benchmarks, including MD17, revised MD17 and MD22, and achieves excellent chemical property prediction on QM9 and Molecule3D datasets. Furthermore, through a series of simulations and case studies, ViSNet can efficiently explore the conformational space and provide reasonable interpretability to map geometric representations to molecular structures.</description>
      <author>Yusong Wang, Tong Wang, Shaoning Li, Xinheng He, Mingyu Li, Zun Wang, Nanning Zheng, Borong Shao, Tie-Yan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-43720-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCS3: A cocatalyst surpassing Pt for photocatalytic hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2023.12.183</link>
      <description>Hongbo Shi, Bo Yan, Hao Xu, Haiyuan Li, Yan He, Dingxin Liu, Gongzheng Yang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390533552

                Cocatalysts play a key role in improving photocatalytic performance by enhancing conductivity and providing an enormous number of active sites simultaneously. However, cocatalysts are usually made of noble metals such as Pt, which are expensive and rare. Therefore, cocatalysts derived from cheap and abundant elements are highly desirable. Here, for the first time, we demonstrate that NiCS3, which is made from nickel that is abundant and costs less than 0.04 % of Pt, is an effective substitute for Pt cocatalysts for the photocatalytic activity of CdS nanorods in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Under visible light, the NiCS3/CdS composite with NiCS3 as the cocatalyst achieved an astonishing H2 production of 61.9 mmol&#183;g-1&#183;h-1 while maintaining high stability, which is 14 times higher than that observed when using CdS alone and nearly 2 times higher than that of Pt/CdS. We also established that the metallicity of NiCS3 results in good carrier conductivity, which promotes the electron transfer and the separation of photo-induced carriers. Due to the appropriate adsorption energy &#916;GH*, NiCS3 more readily adsorbs hydrogen protons and desorbs molecular hydrogen during the photocatalytic process compared with Pt. Additionally, NiCS3 can effectively inhibit the photo-corrosion effect of CdS itself, ensuring a good stability of HER. These results suggest that NiCS3 is a promising substitute for Pt cocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongbo Shi, Bo Yan, Hao Xu, Haiyuan Li, Yan He, Dingxin Liu, Gongzheng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2023.12.183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly efficient electrocatalysts for seawater electrolysis under high current density: A critical review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/metm.11</link>
      <description>Nutthaphak Kitiphatpiboon, Meng Chen, Changrui Feng, Shasha Li, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan, MetalMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390659500

                Abstract According to the International Energy Agency (IEA) strategy, water electrolysis will be a second priority for hydrogen production by 2030, which can support sustainable development goals (SDGs). However, for the large&#8208;scale application, especially seawater electrolysis at a high current density, cost and durability of the electrocatalytic system need to be taken into account. Herein, fundamental mechanisms of seawater electrolysis in a wide range of pH values, potential electrocatalysts for overall water splitting, recent progress on synthesis electrocatalysts and basic principles for the evaluation of electrocatalysts are reviewed. Subsequently, critical parameters and issues for scaling&#8208;up of seawater electrolyzers are critically discussed. Finally, future prospects for completing sustainable hydrogen production from seawater for sustainable development are outlooked. It is anticipated to offer guidelines for the design and production of innovative electrocatalysts with high electrocatalytic activity and durability for the industrial scale application.</description>
      <author>Nutthaphak Kitiphatpiboon, Meng Chen, Changrui Feng, Shasha Li, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/metm.11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single&#8208;Atoms on Structurally&#8208;Integrated 3D N&#8208;Doped Carbon Tubes Grid for Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309067</link>
      <description>Qijun Pan, Yuguang Wang, Bin Chen, Xiang Zhang, Dou Lin, Sisi Yan, Fangming Han, Huijun Zhao, Guowen Meng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390662432

                Abstract To date, the excellent mass&#8208;catalytic activities of Pt single&#8208;atoms catalysts (Pt&#8208;SACs) toward hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are categorically confirmed; however, their high current density performance remains a challenge for practical applications. Here, a binder&#8208;free approach is exemplified to fabricate self&#8208;standing superhydrophilic&#8208;superaerphobic Pt&#8208;SACs cathodes by directly anchoring Pt&#8208;SAs via Pt&#8208;N x C 4&#8208;x coordination bonds to the structurally&#8208;integrated 3D nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon tubes (N&#8208;CTs) array grid (denoted as Pt@N&#8208;CTs). The 3D Pt@N&#8208;CTs cathode with optimal Pt&#8208;SACs loading is capable of operating at a high current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 with an ultralow overpotential of 157.9 mV with remarkable long&#8208;term stability over 11 days at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . The 3D super&#8208;wettable free&#8208;standing Pt@N&#8208;CTs possess interconnected vertical and lateral N&#8208;CTs with hierarchical&#8208;sized open channels, which facilitates the mass transfer. The binder&#8208;free immobilization adding to the large surface area and 3D&#8208;interconnected open channels endow Pt@N&#8208;CTs cathodes with high accessible active sites, electrical conductivity, and structural stability that maximize the utilization efficiency of Pt&#8208;SAs to achieve ampere&#8208;level current density HER at low overpotentials.</description>
      <author>Qijun Pan, Yuguang Wang, Bin Chen, Xiang Zhang, Dou Lin, Sisi Yan, Fangming Han, Huijun Zhao, Guowen Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification of a Durability Descriptor for Molecular Oxygen Reduction Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03209</link>
      <description>Nagaprasad Reddy Samala, Ariel Friedman, Lior Elbaz, Ilya Grinberg, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390674849

                The development of durable platinum-group-metal-free oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts is a key research direction for enabling the wide use of fuel cells. Here, we use a combination of experimental measurements and density functional theory calculations to study the activity and durability of seven iron-based metallophthalocyanine (MPc) ORR catalysts that differ only in the identity of the substituent groups on the MPcs. While the MPcs show similar ORR activity, their durabilities as measured by the current decay half-life differ greatly. We find that the energy difference between the hydrogenated intermediate structure and the final demetalated structure (&#916;Edemetalation) of the MPcs is linearly related to the degradation reaction barrier energy. Comparison to the degradation data for the previously studied metallocorrole systems suggested that &#916;Edemetalation also serves as a descriptor for the corrole systems and that the high availability of protons at the active site due to the COOH group of the o-corrole decreases the durability.</description>
      <author>Nagaprasad Reddy Samala, Ariel Friedman, Lior Elbaz, Ilya Grinberg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03209</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated de Novo Design of Olefin Metathesis Catalysts: Computational and Experimental Analysis of a Simple Thermodynamic Design Criterion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01649</link>
      <description>Marco Foscato, Giovanni Occhipinti, Sondre H. Hopen Eliasson, Vidar R. Jensen, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390690975

                Methods for computational de novo design of inorganic molecules have paved the way for automated design of homogeneous catalysts. Such studies have so far relied on correlation-based prediction models as fitness functions (figures of merit), but the soundness of these approaches has yet to be tested by experimental verification of de novo-designed catalysts. Here, a previously developed criterion for the optimization of dative ligands L in ruthenium-based olefin metathesis catalysts RuCl2(L)(L&#8242;)(&#9552;CHAr), where Ar is an aryl group and L&#8242; is a phosphine ligand dissociating to activate the catalyst, was used in de novo design experiments. These experiments predicted catalysts bearing an N-heterocyclic carbene (L = 9) substituted by two N-bound mesityls and two tert-butyl groups at the imidazolidin-2-ylidene backbone to be promising. Whereas the phosphine-stabilized precursor assumed by the prediction model could not be made, a pyridine-stabilized ruthenium alkylidene complex (17) bearing carbene 9 was less active than a known leading pyridine-stabilized Grubbs-type catalyst (18, L = H2IMes). A density functional theory-based analysis showed that the unsubstituted metallacyclobutane (MCB) intermediate generated in the presence of ethylene is the likely resting state of both 17 and 18. Whereas the design criterion via its correlation between the stability of the MCB and the rate-determining barrier indeed seeks to stabilize the MCB, it relies on RuCl2(L)(L&#8242;)(&#9552;CH2) adducts as resting states. The change in resting state explains the discrepancy between the prediction and the actual performance of catalyst 17. To avoid such discrepancies and better address the multifaceted challenges of predicting catalytic performance, future de novo catalyst design studies should explore and test design criteria incorporating information from more than a single relative energy or intermediate.</description>
      <author>Marco Foscato, Giovanni Occhipinti, Sondre H. Hopen Eliasson, Vidar R. Jensen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of Interaction of Water above the Methylammonium Lead Iodide Perovskite Nanocluster: Size Effect and Water-Induced Defective States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c02807</link>
      <description>Jie Huang, Bowen Wang, Hejin Yan, Yongqing Cai, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390691552

                Water is often viewed as detrimental to organic halide perovskite stability. However, evidence highlights its efficacy as a solvent during organic perovskite liquid synthesis. This paradox prompts an investigation into water's influence on perovskite nanoclusters. Employing first principle calculations and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations, surprisingly, we discover some subsurface layers of methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI3) nanoclusters exhibit stronger relaxation than surface layers. Moreover, a strong quantum confinement effect enhances the band gap of MAPbI3 as the nanocluster size decreases. Notably, the water molecules above MAPbI3 nanoclusters induce rich localized defect states, generating low-lying shallow states above the valence band for the small amounts of surface water molecules and band-like deep states across the whole gap for large nanoclusters. This work provides insights into water's role in the electronic structure and structural evolution of perovskite nanoclusters, aiding the design of water-resistant layers to protect perovskite quantum dots from ambient humidity.</description>
      <author>Jie Huang, Bowen Wang, Hejin Yan, Yongqing Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c02807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing ReaxFF for molecular dynamics simulations of lithium-ion batteries: an interactive reparameterization protocol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-50978-5</link>
      <description>Paolo de Angelis, Roberta Cappabianca, Matteo Fasano, Pietro Asinari, Eliodoro Chiavazzo, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390696847

                Abstract Lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) have become an essential technology for the green economy transition, as they are widely used in portable electronics, electric vehicles, and renewable energy systems. The solid-electrolyte interphase (SEI) is a key component for the correct operation, performance, and safety of LIBs. The SEI arises from the initial thermal metastability of the anode-electrolyte interface, and the resulting electrolyte reduction products stabilize the interface by forming an electrochemical buffer window. This article aims to make a first&#8212;but important&#8212;step towards enhancing the parametrization of a widely-used reactive force field (ReaxFF) for accurate molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of SEI components in LIBs. To this end, we focus on Lithium Fluoride (LiF), an inorganic salt of great interest due to its beneficial properties in the passivation layer. The protocol relies heavily on various Python libraries designed to work with atomistic simulations allowing robust automation of all the reparameterization steps. The proposed set of configurations, and the resulting dataset, allow the new ReaxFF to recover the solid nature of the inorganic salt and improve the mass transport properties prediction from MD simulation. The optimized ReaxFF surpasses the previously available force field by accurately adjusting the diffusivity of lithium in the solid lattice, resulting in a two-order-of-magnitude improvement in its prediction at room temperature. However, our comprehensive investigation of the simulation shows the strong sensitivity of the ReaxFF to the training set, making its ability to interpolate the potential energy surface challenging. Consequently, the current formulation of ReaxFF can be effectively employed to model specific and well-defined phenomena by utilizing the proposed interactive reparameterization protocol to construct the dataset. Overall, this work represents a significant initial step towards refining ReaxFF for precise reactive MD simulations, shedding light on the challenges and limitations of ReaxFF force field parametrization. The demonstrated limitations emphasize the potential for developing more versatile and advanced force fields to upscale ab initio simulation through our interactive reparameterization protocol, enabling more accurate and comprehensive MD simulations in the future.</description>
      <author>Paolo de Angelis, Roberta Cappabianca, Matteo Fasano, Pietro Asinari, Eliodoro Chiavazzo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-50978-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learning-accelerated design of high-performance platinum intermetallic nanoparticle fuel cell catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44674-1</link>
      <description>Pengfei Yin, Xiangfu Niu, S.T. Li, Kai Chen, Xi Zhang, Ming J. Zuo, Liang Zhang, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390699021

                Abstract Carbon supported PtCo intermetallic alloys are known to be one of the most promising candidates as low-platinum oxygen reduction reaction electrocatalysts for proton-exchange-membrane fuel cells. Nevertheless, the intrinsic trade-off between particle size and ordering degree of PtCo makes it challenging to simultaneously achieve a high specific activity and a large active surface area. Here, by machine-learning-accelerated screenings from the immense configuration space, we are able to statistically quantify the impact of chemical ordering on thermodynamic stability. We find that introducing of Cu/Ni into PtCo can provide additional stabilization energy by inducing Co-Cu/Ni disorder, thus facilitating the ordering process and achieveing an improved tradeoff between specific activity and active surface area. Guided by the theoretical prediction, the small sized and highly ordered ternary Pt 2 CoCu and Pt 2 CoNi catalysts are experimentally prepared, showing a large electrochemically active surface area of ~90 m 2 g Pt &#8210;1 and a high specific activity of ~3.5 mA cm &#8210;2 .</description>
      <author>Pengfei Yin, Xiangfu Niu, S.T. Li, Kai Chen, Xi Zhang, Ming J. Zuo, Liang Zhang, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44674-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A replacement strategy for regulating local environment of single-atom Co-SxN4&#8722;x catalysts to facilitate CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44652-7</link>
      <description>Jiajing Pei, Huishan Shang, Junjie Mao, Zhe Chen, Rui Sui, Xuejiang Zhang, Danni Zhou, Yu Wang, Fang Zhang, Wei Zhu, Tao Wang, Wenxing Chen, Zhongbin Zhuang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390699058

                Abstract The performances of single-atom catalysts are governed by their local coordination environments. Here, a thermal replacement strategy is developed for the synthesis of single-atom catalysts with precisely controlled and adjustable local coordination environments. A series of Co-S x N 4&#8722;x ( x = 0, 1, 2, 3) single-atom catalysts are successfully synthesized by thermally replacing coordinated N with S at elevated temperature, and a volcano relationship between coordinations and catalytic performances toward electrochemical CO 2 reduction is observed. The Co-S 1 N 3 catalyst has the balanced COOH*and CO* bindings, and thus locates at the apex of the volcano with the highest performance toward electrochemical CO 2 reduction to CO, with the maximum CO Faradaic efficiency of 98 &#177; 1.8% and high turnover frequency of 4564 h &#8722;1 at an overpotential of 410 mV tested in H-cell with CO 2 -saturated 0.5 M KHCO 3 , surpassing most of the reported single-atom catalysts. This work provides a rational approach to control the local coordination environment of the single-atom catalysts, which is important for further fine-tuning the catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Jiajing Pei, Huishan Shang, Junjie Mao, Zhe Chen, Rui Sui, Xuejiang Zhang, Danni Zhou, Yu Wang, Fang Zhang, Wei Zhu, Tao Wang, Wenxing Chen, Zhongbin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44652-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Alloy Catalysts for Alkyne Semihydrogenation via Descriptor-Based High-Throughput Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</link>
      <description>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701504

                Although alloying is a common approach to developing catalysts for alkyne selective hydrogenation, the geometric and electronic effects of active sites on the kinetics of alkyne selective hydrogenation are still ambiguous, hindering rational design of alloy catalysts. Herein, we construct structural descriptors to categorize and reorganize the roles of electronic and geometric factors in the kinetics of acetylene semihydrogenation. The prediction model based on our proposed structural descriptors successfully elucidates the activity and selectivity trends among Pd-based alloys and can also be extended to rationalize the kinetics trend among single-atom alloys and Ni-based alloys for semihydrogenation of acetylene and even other alkynes, in good agreement with available experimental references. Aided by thermodynamic stability analysis and structural descriptors, 489 Pd-based bimetallic alloys via a high-throughput screening protocol were evaluated, and finally, Pd1Nb3 and Pd1Hf3 were identified with a high yield of ethylene and inexpensive cost and validated by our experimental studies.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold Nanoparticles for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction: An Optimum Defined by Size and Shape</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10610</link>
      <description>Esperanza Sedano Varo, Rikke Plougmann, Joakim Kryger-Baggesen, Joerg R. Jinschek, Stig Helveg, Ib Chorkendorff, Christian Danvad Damsgaard, Jakob Kibsgaard, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701643

                Understanding the size-dependent behavior of nanoparticles is crucial for optimizing catalytic performance. We investigate the differences in selectivity of size-selected gold nanoparticles for CO2 electroreduction with sizes ranging from 1.5 to 6.5 nm. Our findings reveal an optimal size of approximately 3 nm that maximizes selectivity toward CO, exhibiting up to 60% Faradaic efficiency at low potentials. High-resolution transmission electron microscopy reveals different shapes for the particles and suggests that multiply twinned nanoparticles are favorable for CO2 reduction to CO. Our analysis shows that twin boundaries pin 8-fold coordinated surface sites and in turn suggests that a variation of size and shape to optimize the abundance of 8-fold coordinated sites is a viable path for optimizing the CO2 electrocatalytic reduction to CO. This work contributes to the advancement of nanocatalyst design for achieving tunable selectivity for CO2 conversion into valuable products.</description>
      <author>Esperanza Sedano Varo, Rikke Plougmann, Joakim Kryger-Baggesen, Joerg R. Jinschek, Stig Helveg, Ib Chorkendorff, Christian Danvad Damsgaard, Jakob Kibsgaard</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Prediction of Oer Activity for Pnma Perovskite Via Minimal Structure Relaxation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4690003</link>
      <description>Chanseok Kim, Mina Yoon, Jun Hee Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701865

                This study focuses on exploring alternative catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in renewable fuel production, emphasizing the potential of multi-metal oxides derived from Earth-abundant metals and perovskites. The research integrates traditional experiments with machine learning and theoretical investigations, utilizing descriptors like oxygen p-band center (Op) and metal d-band center (Md). Through high-throughput calculations and crystal graph convolutional neural networks (CGCNN), the study screens a large compositional space of perovskites and predicts Op/Md for 149,952 perovskites, highlighting elemental ratios around Op/Md=0.48 as promising for OER active materials. Notably, an analysis of the elemental ratios around Op/Md=0.48 revealed higher proportions of Ca, Sr, and Ba on the A-site, and Mo, Ni, and Fe on the B-site. This descriptor-based machine learning approach demonstrates its power for predicting promising perovskite OER candidates.</description>
      <author>Chanseok Kim, Mina Yoon, Jun Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4690003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linking CO to Urea Production from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;/NO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; Co-Electrolysis on Transition Metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06279</link>
      <description>Hsien-Chin Li, Yeu-Shiuan Ho, Guo-Lin Yang, Ren-Han Li, Tung-Chun Kuo, Chi-Tien Hsieh, Young-Hyuk Kwon, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390704331

                Electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2ER) has the potential to advance carbon neutrality and renewable energy storage. Advanced CO2ER catalysts can selectively produce a wide array of products. Their importance is amplified when coreducing CO2 with nitrate/nitrite ions (NO3&#8211;/NO2&#8211;) to generate organic compounds containing C&#8211;N bonds, enhancing product diversity and value. Some transition metals effectively catalyze the coreduction of CO2 and NO3&#8211;/NO2&#8211; to yield urea. However, a disparity exists between the experimental observations that underscore the significance of CO production in urea synthesis and the theoretical perspectives that dismiss the role of CO in C&#8211;N bond creation. To reconcile this disparity, we utilized density functional theory combined with a constant electrode potential model to investigate four facile CO2 + *N1 (the intermediates from NO3&#8211;/NO2&#8211; reduction to NH3) couplings&#9472;representing the primary C&#8211;N formation pathways on a range of transition metal surfaces. Our comprehensive study elucidates the relationships among C&#8211;N coupling barriers, *N1, and CO adsorption energies. Notably, we found that while CO is not involved in C&#8211;N formation, a catalyst&#8217;s proficiency in generating CO from CO2ER is indicative of its reduced adsorption strength. This result indicates a heightened reactivity in forming C&#8211;N bonds via the CO2 + *N1 couplings. Our theoretical exploration adeptly bridges the discrepancies observed between earlier experimental and theoretical studies.</description>
      <author>Hsien-Chin Li, Yeu-Shiuan Ho, Guo-Lin Yang, Ren-Han Li, Tung-Chun Kuo, Chi-Tien Hsieh, Young-Hyuk Kwon, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Platinum Group Metal-Free and Durable Catalysts for Direct Borohydride Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02578</link>
      <description>Youngdon Ko, Junkil Park, Xiong Zhang, Liqun Kang, Thi Ha My Pham, Victor Boureau, Cuong Pham&#8208;Huu, Jihan Kim, Liping Zhong, Andreas Z&#252;ttel, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390722093

                Platinum group metal-free catalysts (e.g., Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C and Co&#8211;N&#8211;C) are used as hydrogen peroxide reduction reaction (PRR) catalysts in direct borohydride fuel cells (DBFCs). Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C is more active in the PRR and demonstrates high performance at the beginning of the DBFC test, whereas Co&#8211;N&#8211;C exhibits more stability in long-term operation. In the DBFC-accelerated durability test, Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C displays an activity decline of 18.6%, whereas Co&#8211;N&#8211;C exhibits a more stable performance, with an activity decrease of only 6.7%. In addition, the active site of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C degrades more rapidly than that of Co&#8211;N&#8211;C in terms of demetalation of the central atom, as revealed by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. Furthermore, density functional theory simulations indicate that Co&#8211;N&#8211;C is more stable than Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C in both O2 and H2O2 environments. Overall, this study demonstrates that non-noble transition metal catalysts can fully replace platinum group metal catalysts at the cathode and anode in liquid-fuel-powered DBFC systems.</description>
      <author>Youngdon Ko, Junkil Park, Xiong Zhang, Liqun Kang, Thi Ha My Pham, Victor Boureau, Cuong Pham&#8208;Huu, Jihan Kim, Liping Zhong, Andreas Z&#252;ttel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd-Catalysed asymmetric allylic alkylation of heterocycles: a user's guide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00856h</link>
      <description>Fran&#231;ois Richard, Paul G. Clark, Al Hannam, Thomas Keenan, Alexandre Jean, Stellios Arseniyadis, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390739365

                This review analyses recent advances and strategies employed in the Pd-AAA of nucleophilic prochiral heterocycles. Each section is focused on a specific heterocycle, where optimisation data and reaction scope have been carefully analysed.</description>
      <author>Fran&#231;ois Richard, Paul G. Clark, Al Hannam, Thomas Keenan, Alexandre Jean, Stellios Arseniyadis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00856h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local reaction environment in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00669g</link>
      <description>Chaojie Chen, Huanyu Jin, Pengtang Wang, Xiaohua Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi&#8208;Zhang Qiao, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390744198

                Beyond conventional electrocatalyst engineering, recent studies have unveiled the effectiveness of manipulating the local reaction environment in enhancing the performance of electrocatalytic reactions. The general principles and strategies of local environmental engineering for different electrocatalytic processes have been extensively investigated. This review provides a critical appraisal of the recent advancements in local reaction environment engineering, aiming to comprehensively assess this emerging field. It presents the interactions among surface structure, ions distribution and local electric field in relation to the local reaction environment. Useful protocols such as the interfacial reactant concentration, mass transport rate, adsorption/desorption behaviors, and binding energy are in-depth discussed toward modifying the local reaction environment. Meanwhile, electrode physical structures and reaction cell configurations are viable optimization methods in engineering local reaction environments. In combination with operando investigation techniques, we conclude that rational modifications of the local reaction environment can significantly enhance various electrocatalytic processes by optimizing the thermodynamic and kinetic properties of the reaction interface. We also outline future research directions to attain a comprehensive understanding and effective modulation of the local reaction environment.</description>
      <author>Chaojie Chen, Huanyu Jin, Pengtang Wang, Xiaohua Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi&#8208;Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00669g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction by borophene supported bimetallic catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.051</link>
      <description>Meiling Liu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390766525

                Bimetal atom catalysts (BACs) hold significant potential for various applications as a result of the synergistic interaction between adjacent metal atoms. This interaction leads to improved catalytic performance, while simultaneously maintaining high atomic efficiency and exceptional selectivity, similar to single atom catalysts (SACs). Bimetallic site catalysts (M2&#946;12) supported by &#946;12-borophene were developed as catalysts for electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). The research on density functional theory (DFT) demonstrates that M2&#946;12 exhibits exceptional stability, conductivity, and catalytic activity. Investigating the most efficient reaction pathway for CO2RR by analyzing the Gibbs free energy (&#916;G) during potential determining steps (PDS) and choosing a catalyst with outstanding catalytic performance for CO2RR. The overpotential required for Fe2&#946;12 and Ag2&#946;12 to generate CO is merely 0.05 V. This implies that the conversion of CO2 to CO can be accomplished with minimal additional voltage. The overpotential values for Cu2&#946;12 and Ag2&#946;12 during the formation of HCOOH were merely 0.001 and 0.07 V, respectively. Furthermore, the Rh2&#946;12 catalyst exhibits a relatively low overpotential of 0.51 V for CH3OH and 0.65 V for CH4. The Fe2&#946;12 produces C2H4 through the *CO-*CO pathway, while Ag2&#946;12 generates CH3CH2OH via the *CO-*CHO coupling pathway, with remarkably low overpotentials of 0.84 and 0.60 V, respectively. The study provides valuable insights for the systematic design and screening of electrocatalysts for CO2RR that exhibit exceptional catalytic performance and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Meiling Liu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small difference in the work function induced superior catalytic performance of MoS2/M2CO2 heterostructures for hydrogen evolution reaction: A computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.027</link>
      <description>Siyao Wang, Yu Liu, Fengyu Li, Jingxiang Zhao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 57(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390767960

                Motivated by the unique structures and diverse properties of two-dimensional (2D) heterostructures, herein, we designed a series of heterojunction-based catalysts composed of MoS2 and M2CO2 monolayers (M = Ti, V, Cr, Zr, Nb, Mo, Hf, and Ta) monolayers, and investigated their activities towards HER by means of density functional theory (DFT) computations. The results showed that these van der Waals heterostructures exhibit favorable stability, high stiffness, and versatile electronic properties. Interestingly, MoS2/Nb2CO2 and MoS2/Ta2CO2 candidates were expected to exhibit high HER catalytic activity at low H coverage due to their optimal H* adsorption strength, and the low barrier for H2 release via the Heyrovsky mechanism. More importantly, we for the first time proposed that the difference in the work functions between MoS2 and M2CO2 can be utilized as an ideal descriptor to rationalize the remarkably different HER catalytic activity of these MoS2/M2CO2 hybrid materials. This work not only suggested efficient catalysts for advancing sustainable H2 production, but also opened a new door to further explore the potential of 2D heterostructures in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Siyao Wang, Yu Liu, Fengyu Li, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Oxygen Reduction Reaction Performance of Pt by a N-Doping Strategy and Inducing Tensile Strain of Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03950</link>
      <description>Shujie Xue, Rei&#8208;Cheng Yang, Cong Liu, Jianan Zhao, Shanshan Sun, Qinghong Huang, Qinghong Huang, Yuping Wu, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390776481

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shujie Xue, Rei&#8208;Cheng Yang, Cong Liu, Jianan Zhao, Shanshan Sun, Qinghong Huang, Qinghong Huang, Yuping Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Strategies for Improving the Catalytic Activity of Ultrathin Transition Metal Sulfide Nanosheets Toward the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101492</link>
      <description>Wenda Ma, Dong Yan, Jihong Li, Wang Yang, Tongzhou Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390790097

                Hydrogen is considered as one of the clean secondary energy sources required in industry and daily life. Electrocatalytic hydrogen production is believed to be the most reliable method for converting renewable energy into chemical energy. Two-dimensional (2D) transition metal disulfides (TMDs), as an emerging electrocatalysts, have been widely investigated for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water splitting. Herein, this review summarizes the recent progress and the strategies of ultrathin TMDs for improving the OER electrocatalytic activities. The basic catalytic mechanism of OER is first introduced, and then the catalytic characteristics of 2D TMDs are presented. Importantly, this review specifically concentrates on strategies to improve catalytic activity such as phase engineering, defect/vacancy engineering, heterostructure, doping effect, and catalyst support material. It can be concluded that these regulatory strategies can largely enhance the electrocatalytic performance by increasing the active site exposure and improving the electrocatalytic kinetics. In addition, the challenges and perspectives of 2D TMDs catalysts are presented, which offers valuable guidance in designing efficient and low-cost OER electrocatalysts for future energy applications. We hope that this review will inspire future studies and bridge the gap between strategy design and practical application.</description>
      <author>Wenda Ma, Dong Yan, Jihong Li, Wang Yang, Tongzhou Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A machine-learning-assisted study of propylene adsorption behaviors on transition metals and alloys: Beyond the Dewar-Chatt-Duncanson model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100875</link>
      <description>Yuexin Wang, Min-Hui Li, Ran Cao, Ming Lei, Zhi&#8208;Jun Sui, Xinggui Zhou, De Chen, Yi&#8208;An Zhu, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390796258

                The interactions between propylene and heterogeneous catalysts play a crucial role in determining the catalytic performance in various propylene-related reactions. In this work, density functional theory (DFT) calculations and machine-learning techniques have been used to examine the adsorption behaviors of propylene on elemental transition metals and alloys. To predict propylene adsorption energies without DFT calculations, a set of intrinsic features and the random forest algorithm are employed to train a surrogate model. The analysis of frontier orbitals and density of states is then used to provide a physical interpretation of the observations by machine learning. Our results suggest the transition metal-propylene interactions are not only due to the electron transfer between the d states and the &#960; bonding and &#960;&#8727; antibonding orbitals in the C=C double bond, but they also are influenced by the filling and energy levels of the metal valence s and p orbitals, which is well beyond the Dewar-Chatt-Duncanson model.</description>
      <author>Yuexin Wang, Min-Hui Li, Ran Cao, Ming Lei, Zhi&#8208;Jun Sui, Xinggui Zhou, De Chen, Yi&#8208;An Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes as Electrocatalysts for the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction: Recent Advances and Future Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300598</link>
      <description>Ling Peng Meng, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390829428

                Abstract Electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction (CO 2 RR) is gaining momentum as an effective process to capture and convert CO 2 into valuable chemicals and fuels, as well as to contribute reducing greenhouse gas emissions. Two&#8208;dimensional transition metal carbides and/or nitrides (MXenes) are increasingly attracting attention as CO 2 RR electrocatalysts due to their enhanced chemical activity and selectivity, overcoming limitations of traditional metal CO 2 RR electrocatalysts, and likely breaking the scaling relations of reaction intermediates toward the desired product. The present concept reviews the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art in the computational description of CO 2 RR on MXenes, going from CO 2 activation on pristine models to different surface terminations, and discuss possible ways to tune the catalytic activity and selectivity, including doping, defects, supported single metal atoms, solvent effects, and electric field effects, while putting in the spotlight prospects by including kinetic aspects.</description>
      <author>Ling Peng Meng, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying the distinct roles of dual dopants in stabilizing the platinum-nickel nanowire catalyst for durable fuel cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-44788-0</link>
      <description>Lei Gao, Tulai Sun, Xuli Chen, Zhilong Yang, Mengfan Li, Wenchuan Lai, Wenhua Zhang, Quan Yuan, Hongwen Huang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390841334

                Stabilizing active PtNi alloy catalyst toward oxygen reduction reaction is essential for fuel cell. Doping of specific metals is an empirical strategy, however, the atomistic insight into how dopant boosts the stability of PtNi catalyst still remains elusive. Here, with typical examples of Mo and Au dopants, we identify the distinct roles of Mo and Au in stabilizing PtNi nanowires catalysts. Specifically, due to the stronger interaction between atomic orbital for Ni-Mo and Pt-Au, the Mo dopant mainly suppresses the outward diffusion of Ni atoms while the Au dopant contributes to the stabilization of surface Pt overlayer. Inspired by this atomistic understanding, we rationally construct the PtNiMoAu nanowires by integrating the different functions of Mo and Au into one entity. Such catalyst assembled in fuel cell cathode thus presents both remarkable activity and durability, even surpassing the United States Department of Energy technical targets for 2025.</description>
      <author>Lei Gao, Tulai Sun, Xuli Chen, Zhilong Yang, Mengfan Li, Wenchuan Lai, Wenhua Zhang, Quan Yuan, Hongwen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-44788-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the effects of Vo on the magnetic and photocatalytic properties of bilayer anatase TiO2(001): C/N/S</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.112986</link>
      <description>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390863853

                In this study, we investigated the effect of Vo on the magnetic and photocatalytic properties of bilayer anatase TiO2 (001): C/N/S using first principles within the density functional theory framework. Through research, it has been discovered that the stability and electronic structure of oxygen vacancies can vary depending on their positions, ultimately resulting in diverse photocatalytic performances. When the distance between N and Vo is relatively close, bilayer TiO2(001) system exhibited a relatively low formation energy under Ti-rich conditions, a high cohesive energy, and no virtual frequency formed in the phonon spectrum. Thus, it has good stability. The bilayer Ti24O46N (001) system displayed the most evident red shift in the absorption spectrum, the largest electric dipole moment, the smallest work function, relatively high carrier activity, a notable difference in mobility between electrons and holes, reduced recombination of electrons and holes, an extended carrier lifetime, and superior oxidation reaction capability. Consequently, the bilayer Ti24O46N (001) surface system emerged as the most suitable catalyst for the photo-degradation of water to produce oxygen.</description>
      <author>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.112986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing geometric representations for molecules with equivariant vector-scalar interactive message passing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-43720-2</link>
      <description>Yusong Wang, Tong Wang, Shaoning Li, Xinheng He, Mingyu Li, Zun Wang, Nanning Zheng, Borong Shao, Tie-Yan Liu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390617556

                Abstract Geometric deep learning has been revolutionizing the molecular modeling field. Despite the state-of-the-art neural network models are approaching ab initio accuracy for molecular property prediction, their applications, such as drug discovery and molecular dynamics (MD) simulation, have been hindered by insufficient utilization of geometric information and high computational costs. Here we propose an equivariant geometry-enhanced graph neural network called ViSNet, which elegantly extracts geometric features and efficiently models molecular structures with low computational costs. Our proposed ViSNet outperforms state-of-the-art approaches on multiple MD benchmarks, including MD17, revised MD17 and MD22, and achieves excellent chemical property prediction on QM9 and Molecule3D datasets. Furthermore, through a series of simulations and case studies, ViSNet can efficiently explore the conformational space and provide reasonable interpretability to map geometric representations to molecular structures.</description>
      <author>Yusong Wang, Tong Wang, Shaoning Li, Xinheng He, Mingyu Li, Zun Wang, Nanning Zheng, Borong Shao, Tie-Yan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-43720-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCS3: A cocatalyst surpassing Pt for photocatalytic hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2023.12.183</link>
      <description>Hongbo Shi, Bo Yan, Hao Xu, Haiyuan Li, Yan He, Dingxin Liu, Gongzheng Yang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390533552

                Cocatalysts play a key role in improving photocatalytic performance by enhancing conductivity and providing an enormous number of active sites simultaneously. However, cocatalysts are usually made of noble metals such as Pt, which are expensive and rare. Therefore, cocatalysts derived from cheap and abundant elements are highly desirable. Here, for the first time, we demonstrate that NiCS3, which is made from nickel that is abundant and costs less than 0.04 % of Pt, is an effective substitute for Pt cocatalysts for the photocatalytic activity of CdS nanorods in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Under visible light, the NiCS3/CdS composite with NiCS3 as the cocatalyst achieved an astonishing H2 production of 61.9 mmol&#183;g-1&#183;h-1 while maintaining high stability, which is 14 times higher than that observed when using CdS alone and nearly 2 times higher than that of Pt/CdS. We also established that the metallicity of NiCS3 results in good carrier conductivity, which promotes the electron transfer and the separation of photo-induced carriers. Due to the appropriate adsorption energy &#916;GH*, NiCS3 more readily adsorbs hydrogen protons and desorbs molecular hydrogen during the photocatalytic process compared with Pt. Additionally, NiCS3 can effectively inhibit the photo-corrosion effect of CdS itself, ensuring a good stability of HER. These results suggest that NiCS3 is a promising substitute for Pt cocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongbo Shi, Bo Yan, Hao Xu, Haiyuan Li, Yan He, Dingxin Liu, Gongzheng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2023.12.183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly efficient electrocatalysts for seawater electrolysis under high current density: A critical review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/metm.11</link>
      <description>Nutthaphak Kitiphatpiboon, Meng Chen, Changrui Feng, Shasha Li, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan, MetalMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390659500

                Abstract According to the International Energy Agency (IEA) strategy, water electrolysis will be a second priority for hydrogen production by 2030, which can support sustainable development goals (SDGs). However, for the large&#8208;scale application, especially seawater electrolysis at a high current density, cost and durability of the electrocatalytic system need to be taken into account. Herein, fundamental mechanisms of seawater electrolysis in a wide range of pH values, potential electrocatalysts for overall water splitting, recent progress on synthesis electrocatalysts and basic principles for the evaluation of electrocatalysts are reviewed. Subsequently, critical parameters and issues for scaling&#8208;up of seawater electrolyzers are critically discussed. Finally, future prospects for completing sustainable hydrogen production from seawater for sustainable development are outlooked. It is anticipated to offer guidelines for the design and production of innovative electrocatalysts with high electrocatalytic activity and durability for the industrial scale application.</description>
      <author>Nutthaphak Kitiphatpiboon, Meng Chen, Changrui Feng, Shasha Li, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/metm.11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single&#8208;Atoms on Structurally&#8208;Integrated 3D N&#8208;Doped Carbon Tubes Grid for Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309067</link>
      <description>Qijun Pan, Yuguang Wang, Bin Chen, Xiang Zhang, Dou Lin, Sisi Yan, Fangming Han, Huijun Zhao, Guowen Meng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390662432

                Abstract To date, the excellent mass&#8208;catalytic activities of Pt single&#8208;atoms catalysts (Pt&#8208;SACs) toward hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are categorically confirmed; however, their high current density performance remains a challenge for practical applications. Here, a binder&#8208;free approach is exemplified to fabricate self&#8208;standing superhydrophilic&#8208;superaerphobic Pt&#8208;SACs cathodes by directly anchoring Pt&#8208;SAs via Pt&#8208;N x C 4&#8208;x coordination bonds to the structurally&#8208;integrated 3D nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon tubes (N&#8208;CTs) array grid (denoted as Pt@N&#8208;CTs). The 3D Pt@N&#8208;CTs cathode with optimal Pt&#8208;SACs loading is capable of operating at a high current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 with an ultralow overpotential of 157.9 mV with remarkable long&#8208;term stability over 11 days at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . The 3D super&#8208;wettable free&#8208;standing Pt@N&#8208;CTs possess interconnected vertical and lateral N&#8208;CTs with hierarchical&#8208;sized open channels, which facilitates the mass transfer. The binder&#8208;free immobilization adding to the large surface area and 3D&#8208;interconnected open channels endow Pt@N&#8208;CTs cathodes with high accessible active sites, electrical conductivity, and structural stability that maximize the utilization efficiency of Pt&#8208;SAs to achieve ampere&#8208;level current density HER at low overpotentials.</description>
      <author>Qijun Pan, Yuguang Wang, Bin Chen, Xiang Zhang, Dou Lin, Sisi Yan, Fangming Han, Huijun Zhao, Guowen Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification of a Durability Descriptor for Molecular Oxygen Reduction Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03209</link>
      <description>Nagaprasad Reddy Samala, Ariel Friedman, Lior Elbaz, Ilya Grinberg, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390674849

                The development of durable platinum-group-metal-free oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts is a key research direction for enabling the wide use of fuel cells. Here, we use a combination of experimental measurements and density functional theory calculations to study the activity and durability of seven iron-based metallophthalocyanine (MPc) ORR catalysts that differ only in the identity of the substituent groups on the MPcs. While the MPcs show similar ORR activity, their durabilities as measured by the current decay half-life differ greatly. We find that the energy difference between the hydrogenated intermediate structure and the final demetalated structure (&#916;Edemetalation) of the MPcs is linearly related to the degradation reaction barrier energy. Comparison to the degradation data for the previously studied metallocorrole systems suggested that &#916;Edemetalation also serves as a descriptor for the corrole systems and that the high availability of protons at the active site due to the COOH group of the o-corrole decreases the durability.</description>
      <author>Nagaprasad Reddy Samala, Ariel Friedman, Lior Elbaz, Ilya Grinberg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03209</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated de Novo Design of Olefin Metathesis Catalysts: Computational and Experimental Analysis of a Simple Thermodynamic Design Criterion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01649</link>
      <description>Marco Foscato, Giovanni Occhipinti, Sondre H. Hopen Eliasson, Vidar R. Jensen, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390690975

                Methods for computational de novo design of inorganic molecules have paved the way for automated design of homogeneous catalysts. Such studies have so far relied on correlation-based prediction models as fitness functions (figures of merit), but the soundness of these approaches has yet to be tested by experimental verification of de novo-designed catalysts. Here, a previously developed criterion for the optimization of dative ligands L in ruthenium-based olefin metathesis catalysts RuCl2(L)(L&#8242;)(&#9552;CHAr), where Ar is an aryl group and L&#8242; is a phosphine ligand dissociating to activate the catalyst, was used in de novo design experiments. These experiments predicted catalysts bearing an N-heterocyclic carbene (L = 9) substituted by two N-bound mesityls and two tert-butyl groups at the imidazolidin-2-ylidene backbone to be promising. Whereas the phosphine-stabilized precursor assumed by the prediction model could not be made, a pyridine-stabilized ruthenium alkylidene complex (17) bearing carbene 9 was less active than a known leading pyridine-stabilized Grubbs-type catalyst (18, L = H2IMes). A density functional theory-based analysis showed that the unsubstituted metallacyclobutane (MCB) intermediate generated in the presence of ethylene is the likely resting state of both 17 and 18. Whereas the design criterion via its correlation between the stability of the MCB and the rate-determining barrier indeed seeks to stabilize the MCB, it relies on RuCl2(L)(L&#8242;)(&#9552;CH2) adducts as resting states. The change in resting state explains the discrepancy between the prediction and the actual performance of catalyst 17. To avoid such discrepancies and better address the multifaceted challenges of predicting catalytic performance, future de novo catalyst design studies should explore and test design criteria incorporating information from more than a single relative energy or intermediate.</description>
      <author>Marco Foscato, Giovanni Occhipinti, Sondre H. Hopen Eliasson, Vidar R. Jensen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of Interaction of Water above the Methylammonium Lead Iodide Perovskite Nanocluster: Size Effect and Water-Induced Defective States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c02807</link>
      <description>Jie Huang, Bowen Wang, Hejin Yan, Yongqing Cai, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390691552

                Water is often viewed as detrimental to organic halide perovskite stability. However, evidence highlights its efficacy as a solvent during organic perovskite liquid synthesis. This paradox prompts an investigation into water's influence on perovskite nanoclusters. Employing first principle calculations and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations, surprisingly, we discover some subsurface layers of methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI3) nanoclusters exhibit stronger relaxation than surface layers. Moreover, a strong quantum confinement effect enhances the band gap of MAPbI3 as the nanocluster size decreases. Notably, the water molecules above MAPbI3 nanoclusters induce rich localized defect states, generating low-lying shallow states above the valence band for the small amounts of surface water molecules and band-like deep states across the whole gap for large nanoclusters. This work provides insights into water's role in the electronic structure and structural evolution of perovskite nanoclusters, aiding the design of water-resistant layers to protect perovskite quantum dots from ambient humidity.</description>
      <author>Jie Huang, Bowen Wang, Hejin Yan, Yongqing Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c02807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing ReaxFF for molecular dynamics simulations of lithium-ion batteries: an interactive reparameterization protocol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-50978-5</link>
      <description>Paolo de Angelis, Roberta Cappabianca, Matteo Fasano, Pietro Asinari, Eliodoro Chiavazzo, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390696847

                Abstract Lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) have become an essential technology for the green economy transition, as they are widely used in portable electronics, electric vehicles, and renewable energy systems. The solid-electrolyte interphase (SEI) is a key component for the correct operation, performance, and safety of LIBs. The SEI arises from the initial thermal metastability of the anode-electrolyte interface, and the resulting electrolyte reduction products stabilize the interface by forming an electrochemical buffer window. This article aims to make a first&#8212;but important&#8212;step towards enhancing the parametrization of a widely-used reactive force field (ReaxFF) for accurate molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of SEI components in LIBs. To this end, we focus on Lithium Fluoride (LiF), an inorganic salt of great interest due to its beneficial properties in the passivation layer. The protocol relies heavily on various Python libraries designed to work with atomistic simulations allowing robust automation of all the reparameterization steps. The proposed set of configurations, and the resulting dataset, allow the new ReaxFF to recover the solid nature of the inorganic salt and improve the mass transport properties prediction from MD simulation. The optimized ReaxFF surpasses the previously available force field by accurately adjusting the diffusivity of lithium in the solid lattice, resulting in a two-order-of-magnitude improvement in its prediction at room temperature. However, our comprehensive investigation of the simulation shows the strong sensitivity of the ReaxFF to the training set, making its ability to interpolate the potential energy surface challenging. Consequently, the current formulation of ReaxFF can be effectively employed to model specific and well-defined phenomena by utilizing the proposed interactive reparameterization protocol to construct the dataset. Overall, this work represents a significant initial step towards refining ReaxFF for precise reactive MD simulations, shedding light on the challenges and limitations of ReaxFF force field parametrization. The demonstrated limitations emphasize the potential for developing more versatile and advanced force fields to upscale ab initio simulation through our interactive reparameterization protocol, enabling more accurate and comprehensive MD simulations in the future.</description>
      <author>Paolo de Angelis, Roberta Cappabianca, Matteo Fasano, Pietro Asinari, Eliodoro Chiavazzo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-50978-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learning-accelerated design of high-performance platinum intermetallic nanoparticle fuel cell catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44674-1</link>
      <description>Pengfei Yin, Xiangfu Niu, S.T. Li, Kai Chen, Xi Zhang, Ming J. Zuo, Liang Zhang, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390699021

                Abstract Carbon supported PtCo intermetallic alloys are known to be one of the most promising candidates as low-platinum oxygen reduction reaction electrocatalysts for proton-exchange-membrane fuel cells. Nevertheless, the intrinsic trade-off between particle size and ordering degree of PtCo makes it challenging to simultaneously achieve a high specific activity and a large active surface area. Here, by machine-learning-accelerated screenings from the immense configuration space, we are able to statistically quantify the impact of chemical ordering on thermodynamic stability. We find that introducing of Cu/Ni into PtCo can provide additional stabilization energy by inducing Co-Cu/Ni disorder, thus facilitating the ordering process and achieveing an improved tradeoff between specific activity and active surface area. Guided by the theoretical prediction, the small sized and highly ordered ternary Pt 2 CoCu and Pt 2 CoNi catalysts are experimentally prepared, showing a large electrochemically active surface area of ~90 m 2 g Pt &#8210;1 and a high specific activity of ~3.5 mA cm &#8210;2 .</description>
      <author>Pengfei Yin, Xiangfu Niu, S.T. Li, Kai Chen, Xi Zhang, Ming J. Zuo, Liang Zhang, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44674-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A replacement strategy for regulating local environment of single-atom Co-SxN4&#8722;x catalysts to facilitate CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44652-7</link>
      <description>Jiajing Pei, Huishan Shang, Junjie Mao, Zhe Chen, Rui Sui, Xuejiang Zhang, Danni Zhou, Yu Wang, Fang Zhang, Wei Zhu, Tao Wang, Wenxing Chen, Zhongbin Zhuang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390699058

                Abstract The performances of single-atom catalysts are governed by their local coordination environments. Here, a thermal replacement strategy is developed for the synthesis of single-atom catalysts with precisely controlled and adjustable local coordination environments. A series of Co-S x N 4&#8722;x ( x = 0, 1, 2, 3) single-atom catalysts are successfully synthesized by thermally replacing coordinated N with S at elevated temperature, and a volcano relationship between coordinations and catalytic performances toward electrochemical CO 2 reduction is observed. The Co-S 1 N 3 catalyst has the balanced COOH*and CO* bindings, and thus locates at the apex of the volcano with the highest performance toward electrochemical CO 2 reduction to CO, with the maximum CO Faradaic efficiency of 98 &#177; 1.8% and high turnover frequency of 4564 h &#8722;1 at an overpotential of 410 mV tested in H-cell with CO 2 -saturated 0.5 M KHCO 3 , surpassing most of the reported single-atom catalysts. This work provides a rational approach to control the local coordination environment of the single-atom catalysts, which is important for further fine-tuning the catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Jiajing Pei, Huishan Shang, Junjie Mao, Zhe Chen, Rui Sui, Xuejiang Zhang, Danni Zhou, Yu Wang, Fang Zhang, Wei Zhu, Tao Wang, Wenxing Chen, Zhongbin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44652-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Alloy Catalysts for Alkyne Semihydrogenation via Descriptor-Based High-Throughput Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</link>
      <description>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701504

                Although alloying is a common approach to developing catalysts for alkyne selective hydrogenation, the geometric and electronic effects of active sites on the kinetics of alkyne selective hydrogenation are still ambiguous, hindering rational design of alloy catalysts. Herein, we construct structural descriptors to categorize and reorganize the roles of electronic and geometric factors in the kinetics of acetylene semihydrogenation. The prediction model based on our proposed structural descriptors successfully elucidates the activity and selectivity trends among Pd-based alloys and can also be extended to rationalize the kinetics trend among single-atom alloys and Ni-based alloys for semihydrogenation of acetylene and even other alkynes, in good agreement with available experimental references. Aided by thermodynamic stability analysis and structural descriptors, 489 Pd-based bimetallic alloys via a high-throughput screening protocol were evaluated, and finally, Pd1Nb3 and Pd1Hf3 were identified with a high yield of ethylene and inexpensive cost and validated by our experimental studies.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold Nanoparticles for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction: An Optimum Defined by Size and Shape</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10610</link>
      <description>Esperanza Sedano Varo, Rikke Plougmann, Joakim Kryger-Baggesen, Joerg R. Jinschek, Stig Helveg, Ib Chorkendorff, Christian Danvad Damsgaard, Jakob Kibsgaard, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701643

                Understanding the size-dependent behavior of nanoparticles is crucial for optimizing catalytic performance. We investigate the differences in selectivity of size-selected gold nanoparticles for CO2 electroreduction with sizes ranging from 1.5 to 6.5 nm. Our findings reveal an optimal size of approximately 3 nm that maximizes selectivity toward CO, exhibiting up to 60% Faradaic efficiency at low potentials. High-resolution transmission electron microscopy reveals different shapes for the particles and suggests that multiply twinned nanoparticles are favorable for CO2 reduction to CO. Our analysis shows that twin boundaries pin 8-fold coordinated surface sites and in turn suggests that a variation of size and shape to optimize the abundance of 8-fold coordinated sites is a viable path for optimizing the CO2 electrocatalytic reduction to CO. This work contributes to the advancement of nanocatalyst design for achieving tunable selectivity for CO2 conversion into valuable products.</description>
      <author>Esperanza Sedano Varo, Rikke Plougmann, Joakim Kryger-Baggesen, Joerg R. Jinschek, Stig Helveg, Ib Chorkendorff, Christian Danvad Damsgaard, Jakob Kibsgaard</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Prediction of Oer Activity for Pnma Perovskite Via Minimal Structure Relaxation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4690003</link>
      <description>Chanseok Kim, Mina Yoon, Jun Hee Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701865

                This study focuses on exploring alternative catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in renewable fuel production, emphasizing the potential of multi-metal oxides derived from Earth-abundant metals and perovskites. The research integrates traditional experiments with machine learning and theoretical investigations, utilizing descriptors like oxygen p-band center (Op) and metal d-band center (Md). Through high-throughput calculations and crystal graph convolutional neural networks (CGCNN), the study screens a large compositional space of perovskites and predicts Op/Md for 149,952 perovskites, highlighting elemental ratios around Op/Md=0.48 as promising for OER active materials. Notably, an analysis of the elemental ratios around Op/Md=0.48 revealed higher proportions of Ca, Sr, and Ba on the A-site, and Mo, Ni, and Fe on the B-site. This descriptor-based machine learning approach demonstrates its power for predicting promising perovskite OER candidates.</description>
      <author>Chanseok Kim, Mina Yoon, Jun Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4690003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linking CO to Urea Production from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;/NO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; Co-Electrolysis on Transition Metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06279</link>
      <description>Hsien-Chin Li, Yeu-Shiuan Ho, Guo-Lin Yang, Ren-Han Li, Tung-Chun Kuo, Chi-Tien Hsieh, Young-Hyuk Kwon, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390704331

                Electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2ER) has the potential to advance carbon neutrality and renewable energy storage. Advanced CO2ER catalysts can selectively produce a wide array of products. Their importance is amplified when coreducing CO2 with nitrate/nitrite ions (NO3&#8211;/NO2&#8211;) to generate organic compounds containing C&#8211;N bonds, enhancing product diversity and value. Some transition metals effectively catalyze the coreduction of CO2 and NO3&#8211;/NO2&#8211; to yield urea. However, a disparity exists between the experimental observations that underscore the significance of CO production in urea synthesis and the theoretical perspectives that dismiss the role of CO in C&#8211;N bond creation. To reconcile this disparity, we utilized density functional theory combined with a constant electrode potential model to investigate four facile CO2 + *N1 (the intermediates from NO3&#8211;/NO2&#8211; reduction to NH3) couplings&#9472;representing the primary C&#8211;N formation pathways on a range of transition metal surfaces. Our comprehensive study elucidates the relationships among C&#8211;N coupling barriers, *N1, and CO adsorption energies. Notably, we found that while CO is not involved in C&#8211;N formation, a catalyst&#8217;s proficiency in generating CO from CO2ER is indicative of its reduced adsorption strength. This result indicates a heightened reactivity in forming C&#8211;N bonds via the CO2 + *N1 couplings. Our theoretical exploration adeptly bridges the discrepancies observed between earlier experimental and theoretical studies.</description>
      <author>Hsien-Chin Li, Yeu-Shiuan Ho, Guo-Lin Yang, Ren-Han Li, Tung-Chun Kuo, Chi-Tien Hsieh, Young-Hyuk Kwon, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Platinum Group Metal-Free and Durable Catalysts for Direct Borohydride Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02578</link>
      <description>Youngdon Ko, Junkil Park, Xiong Zhang, Liqun Kang, Thi Ha My Pham, Victor Boureau, Cuong Pham&#8208;Huu, Jihan Kim, Liping Zhong, Andreas Z&#252;ttel, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390722093

                Platinum group metal-free catalysts (e.g., Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C and Co&#8211;N&#8211;C) are used as hydrogen peroxide reduction reaction (PRR) catalysts in direct borohydride fuel cells (DBFCs). Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C is more active in the PRR and demonstrates high performance at the beginning of the DBFC test, whereas Co&#8211;N&#8211;C exhibits more stability in long-term operation. In the DBFC-accelerated durability test, Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C displays an activity decline of 18.6%, whereas Co&#8211;N&#8211;C exhibits a more stable performance, with an activity decrease of only 6.7%. In addition, the active site of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C degrades more rapidly than that of Co&#8211;N&#8211;C in terms of demetalation of the central atom, as revealed by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. Furthermore, density functional theory simulations indicate that Co&#8211;N&#8211;C is more stable than Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C in both O2 and H2O2 environments. Overall, this study demonstrates that non-noble transition metal catalysts can fully replace platinum group metal catalysts at the cathode and anode in liquid-fuel-powered DBFC systems.</description>
      <author>Youngdon Ko, Junkil Park, Xiong Zhang, Liqun Kang, Thi Ha My Pham, Victor Boureau, Cuong Pham&#8208;Huu, Jihan Kim, Liping Zhong, Andreas Z&#252;ttel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd-Catalysed asymmetric allylic alkylation of heterocycles: a user's guide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00856h</link>
      <description>Fran&#231;ois Richard, Paul G. Clark, Al Hannam, Thomas Keenan, Alexandre Jean, Stellios Arseniyadis, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390739365

                This review analyses recent advances and strategies employed in the Pd-AAA of nucleophilic prochiral heterocycles. Each section is focused on a specific heterocycle, where optimisation data and reaction scope have been carefully analysed.</description>
      <author>Fran&#231;ois Richard, Paul G. Clark, Al Hannam, Thomas Keenan, Alexandre Jean, Stellios Arseniyadis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00856h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local reaction environment in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00669g</link>
      <description>Chaojie Chen, Huanyu Jin, Pengtang Wang, Xiaohua Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi&#8208;Zhang Qiao, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390744198

                Beyond conventional electrocatalyst engineering, recent studies have unveiled the effectiveness of manipulating the local reaction environment in enhancing the performance of electrocatalytic reactions. The general principles and strategies of local environmental engineering for different electrocatalytic processes have been extensively investigated. This review provides a critical appraisal of the recent advancements in local reaction environment engineering, aiming to comprehensively assess this emerging field. It presents the interactions among surface structure, ions distribution and local electric field in relation to the local reaction environment. Useful protocols such as the interfacial reactant concentration, mass transport rate, adsorption/desorption behaviors, and binding energy are in-depth discussed toward modifying the local reaction environment. Meanwhile, electrode physical structures and reaction cell configurations are viable optimization methods in engineering local reaction environments. In combination with operando investigation techniques, we conclude that rational modifications of the local reaction environment can significantly enhance various electrocatalytic processes by optimizing the thermodynamic and kinetic properties of the reaction interface. We also outline future research directions to attain a comprehensive understanding and effective modulation of the local reaction environment.</description>
      <author>Chaojie Chen, Huanyu Jin, Pengtang Wang, Xiaohua Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi&#8208;Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00669g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction by borophene supported bimetallic catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.051</link>
      <description>Meiling Liu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390766525

                Bimetal atom catalysts (BACs) hold significant potential for various applications as a result of the synergistic interaction between adjacent metal atoms. This interaction leads to improved catalytic performance, while simultaneously maintaining high atomic efficiency and exceptional selectivity, similar to single atom catalysts (SACs). Bimetallic site catalysts (M2&#946;12) supported by &#946;12-borophene were developed as catalysts for electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). The research on density functional theory (DFT) demonstrates that M2&#946;12 exhibits exceptional stability, conductivity, and catalytic activity. Investigating the most efficient reaction pathway for CO2RR by analyzing the Gibbs free energy (&#916;G) during potential determining steps (PDS) and choosing a catalyst with outstanding catalytic performance for CO2RR. The overpotential required for Fe2&#946;12 and Ag2&#946;12 to generate CO is merely 0.05 V. This implies that the conversion of CO2 to CO can be accomplished with minimal additional voltage. The overpotential values for Cu2&#946;12 and Ag2&#946;12 during the formation of HCOOH were merely 0.001 and 0.07 V, respectively. Furthermore, the Rh2&#946;12 catalyst exhibits a relatively low overpotential of 0.51 V for CH3OH and 0.65 V for CH4. The Fe2&#946;12 produces C2H4 through the *CO-*CO pathway, while Ag2&#946;12 generates CH3CH2OH via the *CO-*CHO coupling pathway, with remarkably low overpotentials of 0.84 and 0.60 V, respectively. The study provides valuable insights for the systematic design and screening of electrocatalysts for CO2RR that exhibit exceptional catalytic performance and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Meiling Liu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small difference in the work function induced superior catalytic performance of MoS2/M2CO2 heterostructures for hydrogen evolution reaction: A computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.027</link>
      <description>Siyao Wang, Yu Liu, Fengyu Li, Jingxiang Zhao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 57(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390767960

                Motivated by the unique structures and diverse properties of two-dimensional (2D) heterostructures, herein, we designed a series of heterojunction-based catalysts composed of MoS2 and M2CO2 monolayers (M = Ti, V, Cr, Zr, Nb, Mo, Hf, and Ta) monolayers, and investigated their activities towards HER by means of density functional theory (DFT) computations. The results showed that these van der Waals heterostructures exhibit favorable stability, high stiffness, and versatile electronic properties. Interestingly, MoS2/Nb2CO2 and MoS2/Ta2CO2 candidates were expected to exhibit high HER catalytic activity at low H coverage due to their optimal H* adsorption strength, and the low barrier for H2 release via the Heyrovsky mechanism. More importantly, we for the first time proposed that the difference in the work functions between MoS2 and M2CO2 can be utilized as an ideal descriptor to rationalize the remarkably different HER catalytic activity of these MoS2/M2CO2 hybrid materials. This work not only suggested efficient catalysts for advancing sustainable H2 production, but also opened a new door to further explore the potential of 2D heterostructures in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Siyao Wang, Yu Liu, Fengyu Li, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Oxygen Reduction Reaction Performance of Pt by a N-Doping Strategy and Inducing Tensile Strain of Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03950</link>
      <description>Shujie Xue, Rei&#8208;Cheng Yang, Cong Liu, Jianan Zhao, Shanshan Sun, Qinghong Huang, Qinghong Huang, Yuping Wu, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390776481

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shujie Xue, Rei&#8208;Cheng Yang, Cong Liu, Jianan Zhao, Shanshan Sun, Qinghong Huang, Qinghong Huang, Yuping Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Strategies for Improving the Catalytic Activity of Ultrathin Transition Metal Sulfide Nanosheets Toward the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101492</link>
      <description>Wenda Ma, Dong Yan, Jihong Li, Wang Yang, Tongzhou Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390790097

                Hydrogen is considered as one of the clean secondary energy sources required in industry and daily life. Electrocatalytic hydrogen production is believed to be the most reliable method for converting renewable energy into chemical energy. Two-dimensional (2D) transition metal disulfides (TMDs), as an emerging electrocatalysts, have been widely investigated for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water splitting. Herein, this review summarizes the recent progress and the strategies of ultrathin TMDs for improving the OER electrocatalytic activities. The basic catalytic mechanism of OER is first introduced, and then the catalytic characteristics of 2D TMDs are presented. Importantly, this review specifically concentrates on strategies to improve catalytic activity such as phase engineering, defect/vacancy engineering, heterostructure, doping effect, and catalyst support material. It can be concluded that these regulatory strategies can largely enhance the electrocatalytic performance by increasing the active site exposure and improving the electrocatalytic kinetics. In addition, the challenges and perspectives of 2D TMDs catalysts are presented, which offers valuable guidance in designing efficient and low-cost OER electrocatalysts for future energy applications. We hope that this review will inspire future studies and bridge the gap between strategy design and practical application.</description>
      <author>Wenda Ma, Dong Yan, Jihong Li, Wang Yang, Tongzhou Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A machine-learning-assisted study of propylene adsorption behaviors on transition metals and alloys: Beyond the Dewar-Chatt-Duncanson model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100875</link>
      <description>Yuexin Wang, Min-Hui Li, Ran Cao, Ming Lei, Zhi&#8208;Jun Sui, Xinggui Zhou, De Chen, Yi&#8208;An Zhu, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390796258

                The interactions between propylene and heterogeneous catalysts play a crucial role in determining the catalytic performance in various propylene-related reactions. In this work, density functional theory (DFT) calculations and machine-learning techniques have been used to examine the adsorption behaviors of propylene on elemental transition metals and alloys. To predict propylene adsorption energies without DFT calculations, a set of intrinsic features and the random forest algorithm are employed to train a surrogate model. The analysis of frontier orbitals and density of states is then used to provide a physical interpretation of the observations by machine learning. Our results suggest the transition metal-propylene interactions are not only due to the electron transfer between the d states and the &#960; bonding and &#960;&#8727; antibonding orbitals in the C=C double bond, but they also are influenced by the filling and energy levels of the metal valence s and p orbitals, which is well beyond the Dewar-Chatt-Duncanson model.</description>
      <author>Yuexin Wang, Min-Hui Li, Ran Cao, Ming Lei, Zhi&#8208;Jun Sui, Xinggui Zhou, De Chen, Yi&#8208;An Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes as Electrocatalysts for the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction: Recent Advances and Future Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300598</link>
      <description>Ling Peng Meng, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390829428

                Abstract Electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction (CO 2 RR) is gaining momentum as an effective process to capture and convert CO 2 into valuable chemicals and fuels, as well as to contribute reducing greenhouse gas emissions. Two&#8208;dimensional transition metal carbides and/or nitrides (MXenes) are increasingly attracting attention as CO 2 RR electrocatalysts due to their enhanced chemical activity and selectivity, overcoming limitations of traditional metal CO 2 RR electrocatalysts, and likely breaking the scaling relations of reaction intermediates toward the desired product. The present concept reviews the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art in the computational description of CO 2 RR on MXenes, going from CO 2 activation on pristine models to different surface terminations, and discuss possible ways to tune the catalytic activity and selectivity, including doping, defects, supported single metal atoms, solvent effects, and electric field effects, while putting in the spotlight prospects by including kinetic aspects.</description>
      <author>Ling Peng Meng, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying the distinct roles of dual dopants in stabilizing the platinum-nickel nanowire catalyst for durable fuel cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-44788-0</link>
      <description>Lei Gao, Tulai Sun, Xuli Chen, Zhilong Yang, Mengfan Li, Wenchuan Lai, Wenhua Zhang, Quan Yuan, Hongwen Huang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390841334

                Stabilizing active PtNi alloy catalyst toward oxygen reduction reaction is essential for fuel cell. Doping of specific metals is an empirical strategy, however, the atomistic insight into how dopant boosts the stability of PtNi catalyst still remains elusive. Here, with typical examples of Mo and Au dopants, we identify the distinct roles of Mo and Au in stabilizing PtNi nanowires catalysts. Specifically, due to the stronger interaction between atomic orbital for Ni-Mo and Pt-Au, the Mo dopant mainly suppresses the outward diffusion of Ni atoms while the Au dopant contributes to the stabilization of surface Pt overlayer. Inspired by this atomistic understanding, we rationally construct the PtNiMoAu nanowires by integrating the different functions of Mo and Au into one entity. Such catalyst assembled in fuel cell cathode thus presents both remarkable activity and durability, even surpassing the United States Department of Energy technical targets for 2025.</description>
      <author>Lei Gao, Tulai Sun, Xuli Chen, Zhilong Yang, Mengfan Li, Wenchuan Lai, Wenhua Zhang, Quan Yuan, Hongwen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-44788-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the effects of Vo on the magnetic and photocatalytic properties of bilayer anatase TiO2(001): C/N/S</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.112986</link>
      <description>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390863853

                In this study, we investigated the effect of Vo on the magnetic and photocatalytic properties of bilayer anatase TiO2 (001): C/N/S using first principles within the density functional theory framework. Through research, it has been discovered that the stability and electronic structure of oxygen vacancies can vary depending on their positions, ultimately resulting in diverse photocatalytic performances. When the distance between N and Vo is relatively close, bilayer TiO2(001) system exhibited a relatively low formation energy under Ti-rich conditions, a high cohesive energy, and no virtual frequency formed in the phonon spectrum. Thus, it has good stability. The bilayer Ti24O46N (001) system displayed the most evident red shift in the absorption spectrum, the largest electric dipole moment, the smallest work function, relatively high carrier activity, a notable difference in mobility between electrons and holes, reduced recombination of electrons and holes, an extended carrier lifetime, and superior oxidation reaction capability. Consequently, the bilayer Ti24O46N (001) surface system emerged as the most suitable catalyst for the photo-degradation of water to produce oxygen.</description>
      <author>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.112986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing geometric representations for molecules with equivariant vector-scalar interactive message passing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-43720-2</link>
      <description>Yusong Wang, Tong Wang, Shaoning Li, Xinheng He, Mingyu Li, Zun Wang, Nanning Zheng, Borong Shao, Tie-Yan Liu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390617556

                Abstract Geometric deep learning has been revolutionizing the molecular modeling field. Despite the state-of-the-art neural network models are approaching ab initio accuracy for molecular property prediction, their applications, such as drug discovery and molecular dynamics (MD) simulation, have been hindered by insufficient utilization of geometric information and high computational costs. Here we propose an equivariant geometry-enhanced graph neural network called ViSNet, which elegantly extracts geometric features and efficiently models molecular structures with low computational costs. Our proposed ViSNet outperforms state-of-the-art approaches on multiple MD benchmarks, including MD17, revised MD17 and MD22, and achieves excellent chemical property prediction on QM9 and Molecule3D datasets. Furthermore, through a series of simulations and case studies, ViSNet can efficiently explore the conformational space and provide reasonable interpretability to map geometric representations to molecular structures.</description>
      <author>Yusong Wang, Tong Wang, Shaoning Li, Xinheng He, Mingyu Li, Zun Wang, Nanning Zheng, Borong Shao, Tie-Yan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-43720-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCS3: A cocatalyst surpassing Pt for photocatalytic hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2023.12.183</link>
      <description>Hongbo Shi, Bo Yan, Hao Xu, Haiyuan Li, Yan He, Dingxin Liu, Gongzheng Yang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390533552

                Cocatalysts play a key role in improving photocatalytic performance by enhancing conductivity and providing an enormous number of active sites simultaneously. However, cocatalysts are usually made of noble metals such as Pt, which are expensive and rare. Therefore, cocatalysts derived from cheap and abundant elements are highly desirable. Here, for the first time, we demonstrate that NiCS3, which is made from nickel that is abundant and costs less than 0.04 % of Pt, is an effective substitute for Pt cocatalysts for the photocatalytic activity of CdS nanorods in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Under visible light, the NiCS3/CdS composite with NiCS3 as the cocatalyst achieved an astonishing H2 production of 61.9 mmol&#183;g-1&#183;h-1 while maintaining high stability, which is 14 times higher than that observed when using CdS alone and nearly 2 times higher than that of Pt/CdS. We also established that the metallicity of NiCS3 results in good carrier conductivity, which promotes the electron transfer and the separation of photo-induced carriers. Due to the appropriate adsorption energy &#916;GH*, NiCS3 more readily adsorbs hydrogen protons and desorbs molecular hydrogen during the photocatalytic process compared with Pt. Additionally, NiCS3 can effectively inhibit the photo-corrosion effect of CdS itself, ensuring a good stability of HER. These results suggest that NiCS3 is a promising substitute for Pt cocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongbo Shi, Bo Yan, Hao Xu, Haiyuan Li, Yan He, Dingxin Liu, Gongzheng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2023.12.183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly efficient electrocatalysts for seawater electrolysis under high current density: A critical review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/metm.11</link>
      <description>Nutthaphak Kitiphatpiboon, Meng Chen, Changrui Feng, Shasha Li, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan, MetalMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390659500

                Abstract According to the International Energy Agency (IEA) strategy, water electrolysis will be a second priority for hydrogen production by 2030, which can support sustainable development goals (SDGs). However, for the large&#8208;scale application, especially seawater electrolysis at a high current density, cost and durability of the electrocatalytic system need to be taken into account. Herein, fundamental mechanisms of seawater electrolysis in a wide range of pH values, potential electrocatalysts for overall water splitting, recent progress on synthesis electrocatalysts and basic principles for the evaluation of electrocatalysts are reviewed. Subsequently, critical parameters and issues for scaling&#8208;up of seawater electrolyzers are critically discussed. Finally, future prospects for completing sustainable hydrogen production from seawater for sustainable development are outlooked. It is anticipated to offer guidelines for the design and production of innovative electrocatalysts with high electrocatalytic activity and durability for the industrial scale application.</description>
      <author>Nutthaphak Kitiphatpiboon, Meng Chen, Changrui Feng, Shasha Li, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/metm.11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single&#8208;Atoms on Structurally&#8208;Integrated 3D N&#8208;Doped Carbon Tubes Grid for Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309067</link>
      <description>Qijun Pan, Yuguang Wang, Bin Chen, Xiang Zhang, Dou Lin, Sisi Yan, Fangming Han, Huijun Zhao, Guowen Meng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390662432

                Abstract To date, the excellent mass&#8208;catalytic activities of Pt single&#8208;atoms catalysts (Pt&#8208;SACs) toward hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are categorically confirmed; however, their high current density performance remains a challenge for practical applications. Here, a binder&#8208;free approach is exemplified to fabricate self&#8208;standing superhydrophilic&#8208;superaerphobic Pt&#8208;SACs cathodes by directly anchoring Pt&#8208;SAs via Pt&#8208;N x C 4&#8208;x coordination bonds to the structurally&#8208;integrated 3D nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon tubes (N&#8208;CTs) array grid (denoted as Pt@N&#8208;CTs). The 3D Pt@N&#8208;CTs cathode with optimal Pt&#8208;SACs loading is capable of operating at a high current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 with an ultralow overpotential of 157.9 mV with remarkable long&#8208;term stability over 11 days at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . The 3D super&#8208;wettable free&#8208;standing Pt@N&#8208;CTs possess interconnected vertical and lateral N&#8208;CTs with hierarchical&#8208;sized open channels, which facilitates the mass transfer. The binder&#8208;free immobilization adding to the large surface area and 3D&#8208;interconnected open channels endow Pt@N&#8208;CTs cathodes with high accessible active sites, electrical conductivity, and structural stability that maximize the utilization efficiency of Pt&#8208;SAs to achieve ampere&#8208;level current density HER at low overpotentials.</description>
      <author>Qijun Pan, Yuguang Wang, Bin Chen, Xiang Zhang, Dou Lin, Sisi Yan, Fangming Han, Huijun Zhao, Guowen Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification of a Durability Descriptor for Molecular Oxygen Reduction Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03209</link>
      <description>Nagaprasad Reddy Samala, Ariel Friedman, Lior Elbaz, Ilya Grinberg, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390674849

                The development of durable platinum-group-metal-free oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts is a key research direction for enabling the wide use of fuel cells. Here, we use a combination of experimental measurements and density functional theory calculations to study the activity and durability of seven iron-based metallophthalocyanine (MPc) ORR catalysts that differ only in the identity of the substituent groups on the MPcs. While the MPcs show similar ORR activity, their durabilities as measured by the current decay half-life differ greatly. We find that the energy difference between the hydrogenated intermediate structure and the final demetalated structure (&#916;Edemetalation) of the MPcs is linearly related to the degradation reaction barrier energy. Comparison to the degradation data for the previously studied metallocorrole systems suggested that &#916;Edemetalation also serves as a descriptor for the corrole systems and that the high availability of protons at the active site due to the COOH group of the o-corrole decreases the durability.</description>
      <author>Nagaprasad Reddy Samala, Ariel Friedman, Lior Elbaz, Ilya Grinberg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03209</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated de Novo Design of Olefin Metathesis Catalysts: Computational and Experimental Analysis of a Simple Thermodynamic Design Criterion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01649</link>
      <description>Marco Foscato, Giovanni Occhipinti, Sondre H. Hopen Eliasson, Vidar R. Jensen, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390690975

                Methods for computational de novo design of inorganic molecules have paved the way for automated design of homogeneous catalysts. Such studies have so far relied on correlation-based prediction models as fitness functions (figures of merit), but the soundness of these approaches has yet to be tested by experimental verification of de novo-designed catalysts. Here, a previously developed criterion for the optimization of dative ligands L in ruthenium-based olefin metathesis catalysts RuCl2(L)(L&#8242;)(&#9552;CHAr), where Ar is an aryl group and L&#8242; is a phosphine ligand dissociating to activate the catalyst, was used in de novo design experiments. These experiments predicted catalysts bearing an N-heterocyclic carbene (L = 9) substituted by two N-bound mesityls and two tert-butyl groups at the imidazolidin-2-ylidene backbone to be promising. Whereas the phosphine-stabilized precursor assumed by the prediction model could not be made, a pyridine-stabilized ruthenium alkylidene complex (17) bearing carbene 9 was less active than a known leading pyridine-stabilized Grubbs-type catalyst (18, L = H2IMes). A density functional theory-based analysis showed that the unsubstituted metallacyclobutane (MCB) intermediate generated in the presence of ethylene is the likely resting state of both 17 and 18. Whereas the design criterion via its correlation between the stability of the MCB and the rate-determining barrier indeed seeks to stabilize the MCB, it relies on RuCl2(L)(L&#8242;)(&#9552;CH2) adducts as resting states. The change in resting state explains the discrepancy between the prediction and the actual performance of catalyst 17. To avoid such discrepancies and better address the multifaceted challenges of predicting catalytic performance, future de novo catalyst design studies should explore and test design criteria incorporating information from more than a single relative energy or intermediate.</description>
      <author>Marco Foscato, Giovanni Occhipinti, Sondre H. Hopen Eliasson, Vidar R. Jensen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of Interaction of Water above the Methylammonium Lead Iodide Perovskite Nanocluster: Size Effect and Water-Induced Defective States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c02807</link>
      <description>Jie Huang, Bowen Wang, Hejin Yan, Yongqing Cai, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390691552

                Water is often viewed as detrimental to organic halide perovskite stability. However, evidence highlights its efficacy as a solvent during organic perovskite liquid synthesis. This paradox prompts an investigation into water's influence on perovskite nanoclusters. Employing first principle calculations and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations, surprisingly, we discover some subsurface layers of methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI3) nanoclusters exhibit stronger relaxation than surface layers. Moreover, a strong quantum confinement effect enhances the band gap of MAPbI3 as the nanocluster size decreases. Notably, the water molecules above MAPbI3 nanoclusters induce rich localized defect states, generating low-lying shallow states above the valence band for the small amounts of surface water molecules and band-like deep states across the whole gap for large nanoclusters. This work provides insights into water's role in the electronic structure and structural evolution of perovskite nanoclusters, aiding the design of water-resistant layers to protect perovskite quantum dots from ambient humidity.</description>
      <author>Jie Huang, Bowen Wang, Hejin Yan, Yongqing Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c02807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing ReaxFF for molecular dynamics simulations of lithium-ion batteries: an interactive reparameterization protocol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-50978-5</link>
      <description>Paolo de Angelis, Roberta Cappabianca, Matteo Fasano, Pietro Asinari, Eliodoro Chiavazzo, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390696847

                Abstract Lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) have become an essential technology for the green economy transition, as they are widely used in portable electronics, electric vehicles, and renewable energy systems. The solid-electrolyte interphase (SEI) is a key component for the correct operation, performance, and safety of LIBs. The SEI arises from the initial thermal metastability of the anode-electrolyte interface, and the resulting electrolyte reduction products stabilize the interface by forming an electrochemical buffer window. This article aims to make a first&#8212;but important&#8212;step towards enhancing the parametrization of a widely-used reactive force field (ReaxFF) for accurate molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of SEI components in LIBs. To this end, we focus on Lithium Fluoride (LiF), an inorganic salt of great interest due to its beneficial properties in the passivation layer. The protocol relies heavily on various Python libraries designed to work with atomistic simulations allowing robust automation of all the reparameterization steps. The proposed set of configurations, and the resulting dataset, allow the new ReaxFF to recover the solid nature of the inorganic salt and improve the mass transport properties prediction from MD simulation. The optimized ReaxFF surpasses the previously available force field by accurately adjusting the diffusivity of lithium in the solid lattice, resulting in a two-order-of-magnitude improvement in its prediction at room temperature. However, our comprehensive investigation of the simulation shows the strong sensitivity of the ReaxFF to the training set, making its ability to interpolate the potential energy surface challenging. Consequently, the current formulation of ReaxFF can be effectively employed to model specific and well-defined phenomena by utilizing the proposed interactive reparameterization protocol to construct the dataset. Overall, this work represents a significant initial step towards refining ReaxFF for precise reactive MD simulations, shedding light on the challenges and limitations of ReaxFF force field parametrization. The demonstrated limitations emphasize the potential for developing more versatile and advanced force fields to upscale ab initio simulation through our interactive reparameterization protocol, enabling more accurate and comprehensive MD simulations in the future.</description>
      <author>Paolo de Angelis, Roberta Cappabianca, Matteo Fasano, Pietro Asinari, Eliodoro Chiavazzo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-50978-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learning-accelerated design of high-performance platinum intermetallic nanoparticle fuel cell catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44674-1</link>
      <description>Pengfei Yin, Xiangfu Niu, S.T. Li, Kai Chen, Xi Zhang, Ming J. Zuo, Liang Zhang, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390699021

                Abstract Carbon supported PtCo intermetallic alloys are known to be one of the most promising candidates as low-platinum oxygen reduction reaction electrocatalysts for proton-exchange-membrane fuel cells. Nevertheless, the intrinsic trade-off between particle size and ordering degree of PtCo makes it challenging to simultaneously achieve a high specific activity and a large active surface area. Here, by machine-learning-accelerated screenings from the immense configuration space, we are able to statistically quantify the impact of chemical ordering on thermodynamic stability. We find that introducing of Cu/Ni into PtCo can provide additional stabilization energy by inducing Co-Cu/Ni disorder, thus facilitating the ordering process and achieveing an improved tradeoff between specific activity and active surface area. Guided by the theoretical prediction, the small sized and highly ordered ternary Pt 2 CoCu and Pt 2 CoNi catalysts are experimentally prepared, showing a large electrochemically active surface area of ~90 m 2 g Pt &#8210;1 and a high specific activity of ~3.5 mA cm &#8210;2 .</description>
      <author>Pengfei Yin, Xiangfu Niu, S.T. Li, Kai Chen, Xi Zhang, Ming J. Zuo, Liang Zhang, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44674-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A replacement strategy for regulating local environment of single-atom Co-SxN4&#8722;x catalysts to facilitate CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44652-7</link>
      <description>Jiajing Pei, Huishan Shang, Junjie Mao, Zhe Chen, Rui Sui, Xuejiang Zhang, Danni Zhou, Yu Wang, Fang Zhang, Wei Zhu, Tao Wang, Wenxing Chen, Zhongbin Zhuang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390699058

                Abstract The performances of single-atom catalysts are governed by their local coordination environments. Here, a thermal replacement strategy is developed for the synthesis of single-atom catalysts with precisely controlled and adjustable local coordination environments. A series of Co-S x N 4&#8722;x ( x = 0, 1, 2, 3) single-atom catalysts are successfully synthesized by thermally replacing coordinated N with S at elevated temperature, and a volcano relationship between coordinations and catalytic performances toward electrochemical CO 2 reduction is observed. The Co-S 1 N 3 catalyst has the balanced COOH*and CO* bindings, and thus locates at the apex of the volcano with the highest performance toward electrochemical CO 2 reduction to CO, with the maximum CO Faradaic efficiency of 98 &#177; 1.8% and high turnover frequency of 4564 h &#8722;1 at an overpotential of 410 mV tested in H-cell with CO 2 -saturated 0.5 M KHCO 3 , surpassing most of the reported single-atom catalysts. This work provides a rational approach to control the local coordination environment of the single-atom catalysts, which is important for further fine-tuning the catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Jiajing Pei, Huishan Shang, Junjie Mao, Zhe Chen, Rui Sui, Xuejiang Zhang, Danni Zhou, Yu Wang, Fang Zhang, Wei Zhu, Tao Wang, Wenxing Chen, Zhongbin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-44652-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Alloy Catalysts for Alkyne Semihydrogenation via Descriptor-Based High-Throughput Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</link>
      <description>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701504

                Although alloying is a common approach to developing catalysts for alkyne selective hydrogenation, the geometric and electronic effects of active sites on the kinetics of alkyne selective hydrogenation are still ambiguous, hindering rational design of alloy catalysts. Herein, we construct structural descriptors to categorize and reorganize the roles of electronic and geometric factors in the kinetics of acetylene semihydrogenation. The prediction model based on our proposed structural descriptors successfully elucidates the activity and selectivity trends among Pd-based alloys and can also be extended to rationalize the kinetics trend among single-atom alloys and Ni-based alloys for semihydrogenation of acetylene and even other alkynes, in good agreement with available experimental references. Aided by thermodynamic stability analysis and structural descriptors, 489 Pd-based bimetallic alloys via a high-throughput screening protocol were evaluated, and finally, Pd1Nb3 and Pd1Hf3 were identified with a high yield of ethylene and inexpensive cost and validated by our experimental studies.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold Nanoparticles for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction: An Optimum Defined by Size and Shape</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10610</link>
      <description>Esperanza Sedano Varo, Rikke Plougmann, Joakim Kryger-Baggesen, Joerg R. Jinschek, Stig Helveg, Ib Chorkendorff, Christian Danvad Damsgaard, Jakob Kibsgaard, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701643

                Understanding the size-dependent behavior of nanoparticles is crucial for optimizing catalytic performance. We investigate the differences in selectivity of size-selected gold nanoparticles for CO2 electroreduction with sizes ranging from 1.5 to 6.5 nm. Our findings reveal an optimal size of approximately 3 nm that maximizes selectivity toward CO, exhibiting up to 60% Faradaic efficiency at low potentials. High-resolution transmission electron microscopy reveals different shapes for the particles and suggests that multiply twinned nanoparticles are favorable for CO2 reduction to CO. Our analysis shows that twin boundaries pin 8-fold coordinated surface sites and in turn suggests that a variation of size and shape to optimize the abundance of 8-fold coordinated sites is a viable path for optimizing the CO2 electrocatalytic reduction to CO. This work contributes to the advancement of nanocatalyst design for achieving tunable selectivity for CO2 conversion into valuable products.</description>
      <author>Esperanza Sedano Varo, Rikke Plougmann, Joakim Kryger-Baggesen, Joerg R. Jinschek, Stig Helveg, Ib Chorkendorff, Christian Danvad Damsgaard, Jakob Kibsgaard</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c10610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Prediction of Oer Activity for Pnma Perovskite Via Minimal Structure Relaxation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4690003</link>
      <description>Chanseok Kim, Mina Yoon, Jun Hee Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701865

                This study focuses on exploring alternative catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in renewable fuel production, emphasizing the potential of multi-metal oxides derived from Earth-abundant metals and perovskites. The research integrates traditional experiments with machine learning and theoretical investigations, utilizing descriptors like oxygen p-band center (Op) and metal d-band center (Md). Through high-throughput calculations and crystal graph convolutional neural networks (CGCNN), the study screens a large compositional space of perovskites and predicts Op/Md for 149,952 perovskites, highlighting elemental ratios around Op/Md=0.48 as promising for OER active materials. Notably, an analysis of the elemental ratios around Op/Md=0.48 revealed higher proportions of Ca, Sr, and Ba on the A-site, and Mo, Ni, and Fe on the B-site. This descriptor-based machine learning approach demonstrates its power for predicting promising perovskite OER candidates.</description>
      <author>Chanseok Kim, Mina Yoon, Jun Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4690003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linking CO to Urea Production from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and NO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;/NO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; Co-Electrolysis on Transition Metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06279</link>
      <description>Hsien-Chin Li, Yeu-Shiuan Ho, Guo-Lin Yang, Ren-Han Li, Tung-Chun Kuo, Chi-Tien Hsieh, Young-Hyuk Kwon, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390704331

                Electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2ER) has the potential to advance carbon neutrality and renewable energy storage. Advanced CO2ER catalysts can selectively produce a wide array of products. Their importance is amplified when coreducing CO2 with nitrate/nitrite ions (NO3&#8211;/NO2&#8211;) to generate organic compounds containing C&#8211;N bonds, enhancing product diversity and value. Some transition metals effectively catalyze the coreduction of CO2 and NO3&#8211;/NO2&#8211; to yield urea. However, a disparity exists between the experimental observations that underscore the significance of CO production in urea synthesis and the theoretical perspectives that dismiss the role of CO in C&#8211;N bond creation. To reconcile this disparity, we utilized density functional theory combined with a constant electrode potential model to investigate four facile CO2 + *N1 (the intermediates from NO3&#8211;/NO2&#8211; reduction to NH3) couplings&#9472;representing the primary C&#8211;N formation pathways on a range of transition metal surfaces. Our comprehensive study elucidates the relationships among C&#8211;N coupling barriers, *N1, and CO adsorption energies. Notably, we found that while CO is not involved in C&#8211;N formation, a catalyst&#8217;s proficiency in generating CO from CO2ER is indicative of its reduced adsorption strength. This result indicates a heightened reactivity in forming C&#8211;N bonds via the CO2 + *N1 couplings. Our theoretical exploration adeptly bridges the discrepancies observed between earlier experimental and theoretical studies.</description>
      <author>Hsien-Chin Li, Yeu-Shiuan Ho, Guo-Lin Yang, Ren-Han Li, Tung-Chun Kuo, Chi-Tien Hsieh, Young-Hyuk Kwon, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Platinum Group Metal-Free and Durable Catalysts for Direct Borohydride Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02578</link>
      <description>Youngdon Ko, Junkil Park, Xiong Zhang, Liqun Kang, Thi Ha My Pham, Victor Boureau, Cuong Pham&#8208;Huu, Jihan Kim, Liping Zhong, Andreas Z&#252;ttel, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390722093

                Platinum group metal-free catalysts (e.g., Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C and Co&#8211;N&#8211;C) are used as hydrogen peroxide reduction reaction (PRR) catalysts in direct borohydride fuel cells (DBFCs). Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C is more active in the PRR and demonstrates high performance at the beginning of the DBFC test, whereas Co&#8211;N&#8211;C exhibits more stability in long-term operation. In the DBFC-accelerated durability test, Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C displays an activity decline of 18.6%, whereas Co&#8211;N&#8211;C exhibits a more stable performance, with an activity decrease of only 6.7%. In addition, the active site of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C degrades more rapidly than that of Co&#8211;N&#8211;C in terms of demetalation of the central atom, as revealed by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. Furthermore, density functional theory simulations indicate that Co&#8211;N&#8211;C is more stable than Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C in both O2 and H2O2 environments. Overall, this study demonstrates that non-noble transition metal catalysts can fully replace platinum group metal catalysts at the cathode and anode in liquid-fuel-powered DBFC systems.</description>
      <author>Youngdon Ko, Junkil Park, Xiong Zhang, Liqun Kang, Thi Ha My Pham, Victor Boureau, Cuong Pham&#8208;Huu, Jihan Kim, Liping Zhong, Andreas Z&#252;ttel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd-Catalysed asymmetric allylic alkylation of heterocycles: a user's guide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00856h</link>
      <description>Fran&#231;ois Richard, Paul G. Clark, Al Hannam, Thomas Keenan, Alexandre Jean, Stellios Arseniyadis, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390739365

                This review analyses recent advances and strategies employed in the Pd-AAA of nucleophilic prochiral heterocycles. Each section is focused on a specific heterocycle, where optimisation data and reaction scope have been carefully analysed.</description>
      <author>Fran&#231;ois Richard, Paul G. Clark, Al Hannam, Thomas Keenan, Alexandre Jean, Stellios Arseniyadis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00856h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local reaction environment in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00669g</link>
      <description>Chaojie Chen, Huanyu Jin, Pengtang Wang, Xiaohua Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi&#8208;Zhang Qiao, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390744198

                Beyond conventional electrocatalyst engineering, recent studies have unveiled the effectiveness of manipulating the local reaction environment in enhancing the performance of electrocatalytic reactions. The general principles and strategies of local environmental engineering for different electrocatalytic processes have been extensively investigated. This review provides a critical appraisal of the recent advancements in local reaction environment engineering, aiming to comprehensively assess this emerging field. It presents the interactions among surface structure, ions distribution and local electric field in relation to the local reaction environment. Useful protocols such as the interfacial reactant concentration, mass transport rate, adsorption/desorption behaviors, and binding energy are in-depth discussed toward modifying the local reaction environment. Meanwhile, electrode physical structures and reaction cell configurations are viable optimization methods in engineering local reaction environments. In combination with operando investigation techniques, we conclude that rational modifications of the local reaction environment can significantly enhance various electrocatalytic processes by optimizing the thermodynamic and kinetic properties of the reaction interface. We also outline future research directions to attain a comprehensive understanding and effective modulation of the local reaction environment.</description>
      <author>Chaojie Chen, Huanyu Jin, Pengtang Wang, Xiaohua Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi&#8208;Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00669g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction by borophene supported bimetallic catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.051</link>
      <description>Meiling Liu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390766525

                Bimetal atom catalysts (BACs) hold significant potential for various applications as a result of the synergistic interaction between adjacent metal atoms. This interaction leads to improved catalytic performance, while simultaneously maintaining high atomic efficiency and exceptional selectivity, similar to single atom catalysts (SACs). Bimetallic site catalysts (M2&#946;12) supported by &#946;12-borophene were developed as catalysts for electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). The research on density functional theory (DFT) demonstrates that M2&#946;12 exhibits exceptional stability, conductivity, and catalytic activity. Investigating the most efficient reaction pathway for CO2RR by analyzing the Gibbs free energy (&#916;G) during potential determining steps (PDS) and choosing a catalyst with outstanding catalytic performance for CO2RR. The overpotential required for Fe2&#946;12 and Ag2&#946;12 to generate CO is merely 0.05 V. This implies that the conversion of CO2 to CO can be accomplished with minimal additional voltage. The overpotential values for Cu2&#946;12 and Ag2&#946;12 during the formation of HCOOH were merely 0.001 and 0.07 V, respectively. Furthermore, the Rh2&#946;12 catalyst exhibits a relatively low overpotential of 0.51 V for CH3OH and 0.65 V for CH4. The Fe2&#946;12 produces C2H4 through the *CO-*CO pathway, while Ag2&#946;12 generates CH3CH2OH via the *CO-*CHO coupling pathway, with remarkably low overpotentials of 0.84 and 0.60 V, respectively. The study provides valuable insights for the systematic design and screening of electrocatalysts for CO2RR that exhibit exceptional catalytic performance and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Meiling Liu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small difference in the work function induced superior catalytic performance of MoS2/M2CO2 heterostructures for hydrogen evolution reaction: A computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.027</link>
      <description>Siyao Wang, Yu Liu, Fengyu Li, Jingxiang Zhao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 57(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390767960

                Motivated by the unique structures and diverse properties of two-dimensional (2D) heterostructures, herein, we designed a series of heterojunction-based catalysts composed of MoS2 and M2CO2 monolayers (M = Ti, V, Cr, Zr, Nb, Mo, Hf, and Ta) monolayers, and investigated their activities towards HER by means of density functional theory (DFT) computations. The results showed that these van der Waals heterostructures exhibit favorable stability, high stiffness, and versatile electronic properties. Interestingly, MoS2/Nb2CO2 and MoS2/Ta2CO2 candidates were expected to exhibit high HER catalytic activity at low H coverage due to their optimal H* adsorption strength, and the low barrier for H2 release via the Heyrovsky mechanism. More importantly, we for the first time proposed that the difference in the work functions between MoS2 and M2CO2 can be utilized as an ideal descriptor to rationalize the remarkably different HER catalytic activity of these MoS2/M2CO2 hybrid materials. This work not only suggested efficient catalysts for advancing sustainable H2 production, but also opened a new door to further explore the potential of 2D heterostructures in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Siyao Wang, Yu Liu, Fengyu Li, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Oxygen Reduction Reaction Performance of Pt by a N-Doping Strategy and Inducing Tensile Strain of Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03950</link>
      <description>Shujie Xue, Rei&#8208;Cheng Yang, Cong Liu, Jianan Zhao, Shanshan Sun, Qinghong Huang, Qinghong Huang, Yuping Wu, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390776481

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shujie Xue, Rei&#8208;Cheng Yang, Cong Liu, Jianan Zhao, Shanshan Sun, Qinghong Huang, Qinghong Huang, Yuping Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Strategies for Improving the Catalytic Activity of Ultrathin Transition Metal Sulfide Nanosheets Toward the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101492</link>
      <description>Wenda Ma, Dong Yan, Jihong Li, Wang Yang, Tongzhou Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390790097

                Hydrogen is considered as one of the clean secondary energy sources required in industry and daily life. Electrocatalytic hydrogen production is believed to be the most reliable method for converting renewable energy into chemical energy. Two-dimensional (2D) transition metal disulfides (TMDs), as an emerging electrocatalysts, have been widely investigated for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water splitting. Herein, this review summarizes the recent progress and the strategies of ultrathin TMDs for improving the OER electrocatalytic activities. The basic catalytic mechanism of OER is first introduced, and then the catalytic characteristics of 2D TMDs are presented. Importantly, this review specifically concentrates on strategies to improve catalytic activity such as phase engineering, defect/vacancy engineering, heterostructure, doping effect, and catalyst support material. It can be concluded that these regulatory strategies can largely enhance the electrocatalytic performance by increasing the active site exposure and improving the electrocatalytic kinetics. In addition, the challenges and perspectives of 2D TMDs catalysts are presented, which offers valuable guidance in designing efficient and low-cost OER electrocatalysts for future energy applications. We hope that this review will inspire future studies and bridge the gap between strategy design and practical application.</description>
      <author>Wenda Ma, Dong Yan, Jihong Li, Wang Yang, Tongzhou Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A machine-learning-assisted study of propylene adsorption behaviors on transition metals and alloys: Beyond the Dewar-Chatt-Duncanson model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100875</link>
      <description>Yuexin Wang, Min-Hui Li, Ran Cao, Ming Lei, Zhi&#8208;Jun Sui, Xinggui Zhou, De Chen, Yi&#8208;An Zhu, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390796258

                The interactions between propylene and heterogeneous catalysts play a crucial role in determining the catalytic performance in various propylene-related reactions. In this work, density functional theory (DFT) calculations and machine-learning techniques have been used to examine the adsorption behaviors of propylene on elemental transition metals and alloys. To predict propylene adsorption energies without DFT calculations, a set of intrinsic features and the random forest algorithm are employed to train a surrogate model. The analysis of frontier orbitals and density of states is then used to provide a physical interpretation of the observations by machine learning. Our results suggest the transition metal-propylene interactions are not only due to the electron transfer between the d states and the &#960; bonding and &#960;&#8727; antibonding orbitals in the C=C double bond, but they also are influenced by the filling and energy levels of the metal valence s and p orbitals, which is well beyond the Dewar-Chatt-Duncanson model.</description>
      <author>Yuexin Wang, Min-Hui Li, Ran Cao, Ming Lei, Zhi&#8208;Jun Sui, Xinggui Zhou, De Chen, Yi&#8208;An Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes as Electrocatalysts for the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction: Recent Advances and Future Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300598</link>
      <description>Ling Peng Meng, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390829428

                Abstract Electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction (CO 2 RR) is gaining momentum as an effective process to capture and convert CO 2 into valuable chemicals and fuels, as well as to contribute reducing greenhouse gas emissions. Two&#8208;dimensional transition metal carbides and/or nitrides (MXenes) are increasingly attracting attention as CO 2 RR electrocatalysts due to their enhanced chemical activity and selectivity, overcoming limitations of traditional metal CO 2 RR electrocatalysts, and likely breaking the scaling relations of reaction intermediates toward the desired product. The present concept reviews the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art in the computational description of CO 2 RR on MXenes, going from CO 2 activation on pristine models to different surface terminations, and discuss possible ways to tune the catalytic activity and selectivity, including doping, defects, supported single metal atoms, solvent effects, and electric field effects, while putting in the spotlight prospects by including kinetic aspects.</description>
      <author>Ling Peng Meng, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying the distinct roles of dual dopants in stabilizing the platinum-nickel nanowire catalyst for durable fuel cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-44788-0</link>
      <description>Lei Gao, Tulai Sun, Xuli Chen, Zhilong Yang, Mengfan Li, Wenchuan Lai, Wenhua Zhang, Quan Yuan, Hongwen Huang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390841334

                Stabilizing active PtNi alloy catalyst toward oxygen reduction reaction is essential for fuel cell. Doping of specific metals is an empirical strategy, however, the atomistic insight into how dopant boosts the stability of PtNi catalyst still remains elusive. Here, with typical examples of Mo and Au dopants, we identify the distinct roles of Mo and Au in stabilizing PtNi nanowires catalysts. Specifically, due to the stronger interaction between atomic orbital for Ni-Mo and Pt-Au, the Mo dopant mainly suppresses the outward diffusion of Ni atoms while the Au dopant contributes to the stabilization of surface Pt overlayer. Inspired by this atomistic understanding, we rationally construct the PtNiMoAu nanowires by integrating the different functions of Mo and Au into one entity. Such catalyst assembled in fuel cell cathode thus presents both remarkable activity and durability, even surpassing the United States Department of Energy technical targets for 2025.</description>
      <author>Lei Gao, Tulai Sun, Xuli Chen, Zhilong Yang, Mengfan Li, Wenchuan Lai, Wenhua Zhang, Quan Yuan, Hongwen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-44788-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the effects of Vo on the magnetic and photocatalytic properties of bilayer anatase TiO2(001): C/N/S</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.112986</link>
      <description>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390863853

                In this study, we investigated the effect of Vo on the magnetic and photocatalytic properties of bilayer anatase TiO2 (001): C/N/S using first principles within the density functional theory framework. Through research, it has been discovered that the stability and electronic structure of oxygen vacancies can vary depending on their positions, ultimately resulting in diverse photocatalytic performances. When the distance between N and Vo is relatively close, bilayer TiO2(001) system exhibited a relatively low formation energy under Ti-rich conditions, a high cohesive energy, and no virtual frequency formed in the phonon spectrum. Thus, it has good stability. The bilayer Ti24O46N (001) system displayed the most evident red shift in the absorption spectrum, the largest electric dipole moment, the smallest work function, relatively high carrier activity, a notable difference in mobility between electrons and holes, reduced recombination of electrons and holes, an extended carrier lifetime, and superior oxidation reaction capability. Consequently, the bilayer Ti24O46N (001) surface system emerged as the most suitable catalyst for the photo-degradation of water to produce oxygen.</description>
      <author>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.112986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the axial coordination of cobalt single atom catalysts for efficient photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6411-1</link>
      <description>Ning Kang, Lingwen Liao, Xue Zhang, Zhen He, Bing Yu, Jiahong Wang, Yongquan Qu, Paul K. Chu, Seeram Ramakrishna, Xue&#8208;Feng Yu, Xin Wang, Licheng Bai, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390840023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Kang, Lingwen Liao, Xue Zhang, Zhen He, Bing Yu, Jiahong Wang, Yongquan Qu, Paul K. Chu, Seeram Ramakrishna, Xue&#8208;Feng Yu, Xin Wang, Licheng Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6411-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First-Principles Approach to Modeling Surface Site Stabilities on Multimetallic Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04337</link>
      <description>Shikha Saini, Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Shyam Deo, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390580294

                The study of multimetallic alloys and the multitude of possible surface compositions have sparked a tremendous interest in engineering low-cost materials with high activity and selectivity in heterogeneous catalysis. Multimetallic systems provide complementary functionalities and an unprecedented tunability when designing catalyst formulations. However, due to their immense structural and compositional complexity, the investigation and identification of an optimal catalyst is a tedious and time-consuming process, both experimentally and theoretically. Therefore, theoretical design principles are highly desirable to accelerate the screening of catalyst structures across the vast compositional space. In this paper, we introduce a simple and general model for predicting the site stability of multimetallic surfaces and nanoparticles, which is based on physical principles. The model requires only a small set of density functional theory (DFT) calculations of metal atom binding energies on monometallic and dilute alloy surface slabs to optimize the parameters in the simple model. The resulting model allows for the quantification of the stability of any particular atom site in any conceivable chemical environment across a wide range of morphologies, sizes, and arrangements by interpolating the derived parameters from a monometallic system to a completely diluted alloyed system. Herein, we demonstrate the robustness of the model across an extensive data set of transition metal alloy surfaces and 147-atoms cuboctahedral nanoparticles (NPs) composed of IrRhRu and PtPdRu. Our approach yields mean absolute errors of &#8776;0.15 (IrRhRu), 0.20 (PtPdRu), 0.19 (IrRhRu NP), and 0.26 (PtPdRu NP) eV relative to site binding energies calculated using DFT.</description>
      <author>Shikha Saini, Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Shyam Deo, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Next-Generation Heterogeneous Catalysts: Empowering Surface Reactivity Prediction with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eng.2023.07.021</link>
      <description>Xinyan Li, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng, Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390619178

                Heterogeneous catalysis remains at the core of various bulk chemical manufacturing and energy conversion processes, and its revolution necessitates the hunt for new materials with ideal catalytic activities and economic feasibility. Computational high-throughput screening presents a viable solution to this challenge, as machine learning (ML) has demonstrated its great potential in accelerating such processes by providing satisfactory estimations of surface reactivity with relatively low-cost information. This review focuses on recent progress in applying ML in adsorption energy prediction, which predominantly quantifies the catalytic potential of a solid catalyst. ML models that leverage inputs from different categories and exhibit various levels of complexity are classified and discussed. At the end of the review, an outlook on the current challenges and future opportunities of ML-assisted catalyst screening is supplied. We believe that this review summarizes major achievements in accelerating catalyst discovery through ML and can inspire researchers to further devise novel strategies to accelerate materials design and, ultimately, reshape the chemical industry and energy landscape.</description>
      <author>Xinyan Li, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eng.2023.07.021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Alloy Catalysts for Alkyne Semihydrogenation via Descriptor-Based High-Throughput Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</link>
      <description>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390701504

                Although alloying is a common approach to developing catalysts for alkyne selective hydrogenation, the geometric and electronic effects of active sites on the kinetics of alkyne selective hydrogenation are still ambiguous, hindering rational design of alloy catalysts. Herein, we construct structural descriptors to categorize and reorganize the roles of electronic and geometric factors in the kinetics of acetylene semihydrogenation. The prediction model based on our proposed structural descriptors successfully elucidates the activity and selectivity trends among Pd-based alloys and can also be extended to rationalize the kinetics trend among single-atom alloys and Ni-based alloys for semihydrogenation of acetylene and even other alkynes, in good agreement with available experimental references. Aided by thermodynamic stability analysis and structural descriptors, 489 Pd-based bimetallic alloys via a high-throughput screening protocol were evaluated, and finally, Pd1Nb3 and Pd1Hf3 were identified with a high yield of ethylene and inexpensive cost and validated by our experimental studies.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Wang, Haoxiang Xu, Jian Wu, Fengyu Zhang, Chi&#8208;Ming Che, Jing Zhu, Junting Feng, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c02398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A deep-neural network potential to study transformation-induced plasticity in zirconia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jeurceramsoc.2024.01.007</link>
      <description>Jin-Yu Zhang, Ga&#235;l Huynh, Fu&#8208;Zhi Dai, Tristan Albaret, Shi-Hao Zhang, Shigenobu Ogata, David Rodney, Journal of the European Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390630271

                Zirconia (ZrO2) ceramics uniquely exhibit transformation-induced plasticity, allowing plastic deformation prior to failure, setting them apart from most other ceramics. However, our understanding of ZrO2 plasticity is hindered by the challenge of simulating stress-induced atomic-scale phase transformations, owing to lack of an efficient interatomic potential accurately representing polymorphism and phase changes in ZrO2. In this work, we introduce a novel deep neural network interatomic potential, DP-ZrO2, constructed using a concurrent-learning approach. DP-ZrO2 reproduces properties of various ZrO2 phases, matching their phase diagrams as well as transformation pathways with accuracy comparable to ab initio density functional theory. Leveraging DP-ZrO2, we conducted molecular dynamics simulations of temperature-induced interphase boundary migration and nanocompression. These simulations demonstrate the potential&#8217;s efficiency and applicability in studying deformation microstructures involving phase transformations in ZrO2. Our approach opens the door to large-scale simulations under complex loading conditions, which will shed light on the conditions favouring ZrO2 transformation-induced plasticity.</description>
      <author>Jin-Yu Zhang, Ga&#235;l Huynh, Fu&#8208;Zhi Dai, Tristan Albaret, Shi-Hao Zhang, Shigenobu Ogata, David Rodney</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jeurceramsoc.2024.01.007</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
