<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 01:18:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT and microkinetic modeling study of pressure effects on electroreduction reduction of CO2 to ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161421</link>
      <description>Xiaowen Wang, Fei Ma, Haiqiao Wei, Jiaying Pan, Wenjia Li, Jun Zhao, Xiaotao Yang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403117340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaowen Wang, Fei Ma, Haiqiao Wei, Jiaying Pan, Wenjia Li, Jun Zhao, Xiaotao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic communications between active sites on individual metallic nanoparticles in catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52997-w</link>
      <description>Dongrun Xu, Yaowei Jin, Bowen He, Xue Fang, Guokang Chen, Weiye Qu, Chenxin Xu, Junxiao Chen, Zhen Ma, Liwei Chen, Xingfu Tang, Xi Liu, Guangfeng Wei, Yaxin Chen, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403128752

                Catalytic activity of metal particles is reported to originate from the appearance of nonmetallic states, but conductive metallic particles, as an electron reservoir, should render electron delivery between reactants more favorably so as to have higher activity. We present that metallic rhodium particle catalysts are highly active in the low-temperature oxidation of carbon monoxide, whereas nonmetallic rhodium clusters or monoatoms on alumina remain catalytically inert. Experimental and theoretical results evidence the presence of electronic communications in between vertex atom active sites of individual metallic particles in the reaction. The electronic communications dramatically lower apparent activation energies via coupling two electrochemical-like half-reactions occurring on different active sites, which enable the metallic particles to show turnover frequencies at least four orders of magnitude higher than the nonmetallic clusters or monoatoms. Similar results are found for other metallic particle catalysts, implying the importance of electronic communications between active sites in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Dongrun Xu, Yaowei Jin, Bowen He, Xue Fang, Guokang Chen, Weiye Qu, Chenxin Xu, Junxiao Chen, Zhen Ma, Liwei Chen, Xingfu Tang, Xi Liu, Guangfeng Wei, Yaxin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52997-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bias-dependent surface stress by density functional theory combined with the effective screening medium method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.155409</link>
      <description>Satoshi Hagiwara, Shoji Ishibashi, Minoru Otani, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403130582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Satoshi Hagiwara, Shoji Ishibashi, Minoru Otani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.155409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determining the chemical ordering in nanoalloys by considering atomic coordination types</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214377</link>
      <description>Riccardo Farris, Konstantin M. Neyman, Albert Bruix, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403135114

                The energetically most favorable chemical ordering of bimetallic nanoparticles can be characterized by combining global optimization algorithms and surrogate energy models. The latter approximate the energy of nanoalloys relying on structural descriptors, training models, and data. Here, we systematically evaluate the performance of highly data-efficient topological descriptors [Kozlov et al., Chem. Sci. 6, 3868 (2015)] for predicting the energies of metal nanoalloys with different chemical orderings. We also introduce a new descriptor based on atomic coordination types, which results in a less data-efficient and interpretable approach, but improves the general accuracy and the quantification of orderings in the inner parts of nanoparticles. The capacity of both the original and new approaches in combination with a basin hopping algorithm is illustrated by generating convex hulls of PdZn nanoalloys and predicting the resulting active surface site distribution as a function of particle composition. Finally, we show how these approaches can be combined with machine-learning adsorption models in electrocatalysis studies for a fast evaluation of the reactivity landscape of targeted nanoalloys.</description>
      <author>Riccardo Farris, Konstantin M. Neyman, Albert Bruix</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oriented Crystal Polarization Tuning Bulk Charge and Single&#8208;Site Chemical State for Exceptional Hydrogen Photo&#8208;Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411339</link>
      <description>Zijian Zhu, Jingcong Hu, Cheng Hu, Yue Lu, Shengqi Chu, Fang Chen, Hongwei Huang, Hongwei Huang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140168

                Abstract Rapid bulk charge recombination and mediocre surface catalytic sites harshly restrict the photocatalytic activities. Herein, the aforementioned concerns are well addressed by coupling macroscopic spontaneous polarization and atomic&#8208;site engineering of CdS single&#8208;crystal nanorods for superb H 2 photo&#8208;production. The oriented growth of CdS nanorods along the polar axis, vectorially superimposing substantial polar units with orderly arrangement, renders a strong polarization electric field (20.1 times enhancement), which boosts bulk charge separation with an efficiency up to 72.4% (80.4&#8208;fold). Remarkably, polarization electric field alters the chemical state of Pt single sites by orderly reducing the binding energy of Pt atom with stepwise polarization enhancement of CdS substrate, which increases the onsite electron density of Pt from 10.232 to 10.261e &#8722; and *H key intermediates, providing preponderant Volmer&#8208;Tafel/Volmer&#8208;Heyrovsky reaction pathways with significantly decreased energy barriers for H 2 production. Thus, highly polarized CdS nanorods with atomically dispersed Pt sites perform an outstanding H 2 space&#8208;time yield of 118.5 mmol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 and apparent quantum efficiency of 57.7% at &#955; = 420 nm, and a record&#8208;high H 2 turnover frequency of 57798.4 h &#8722;1 , being one of the best catalysts for photocatalytic H 2 evolution. This work highlights the function of polarization in manipulating charge separation and catalytic reaction.</description>
      <author>Zijian Zhu, Jingcong Hu, Cheng Hu, Yue Lu, Shengqi Chu, Fang Chen, Hongwei Huang, Hongwei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemiresistive triethylamine detection based on the novel Ti3C2Tx/Co-BDC gas sensor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2024.136738</link>
      <description>Huan Liu, Qingcai Chen, Ting Xu, Heng Liu, Miao Lei, Wenhao Liu, Jingwen Cheng, Shu Yin, Chuanyi Wang, Jincai Zhao, Sensors and Actuators B Chemical. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140557

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Liu, Qingcai Chen, Ting Xu, Heng Liu, Miao Lei, Wenhao Liu, Jingwen Cheng, Shu Yin, Chuanyi Wang, Jincai Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2024.136738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Amorphous Structure on CO2 Electrocatalysis with Cu: A Combined Machine Learning Forcefield and DFT Modelling Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145188</link>
      <description>Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Devis Di Tommaso, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140832

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Devis Di Tommaso</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mild and rapid construction of Ti electrodes for efficient and corrosion-resistant oxidative catalysis at industrial-grade intensity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.010</link>
      <description>Rui Xiao, Ding&#8208;Kun Ji, Liugang Wu, Ziyan Fang, Yanhui Guo, Weiju Hao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403144529

                The development of cost-effective and corrosion-resistant catalytic electrodes for chlorine/oxygen evolution reaction (CER/OER) in large-scale industrial applications is a significant challenge. Herein, the sol-gel method is employed to achieve a uniform coating of ruthenium (Ru) doping copper (Cu) on titanium sheet (Ru + 20 %Cu@Ti), and the highly efficient industrial grade stable Ti dimensional stable anode can be quickly constructed at 723.15 K for 2 h. Cu doping reduces the vacancy formation energy of surface oxygen, promotes additional lattice oxygen vacancy assisted hydrolysis dissociation pathway, improves the selectivity and specific activity of CER at high concentration doping, and reduces the binding energy of OER intermediates (e.g., *OH, *O, and *OOH) at adjacent Ru active sites. The overpotentials require to reach the current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Rui Xiao, Ding&#8208;Kun Ji, Liugang Wu, Ziyan Fang, Yanhui Guo, Weiju Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlating structure-activity-stability relationship of high-valent 3d-metal-based MOFs and MOF-derived materials for electrochemical energy conversion and storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216239</link>
      <description>Baghendra Singh, Rakesh Kumar Sharma, Apparao Draksharapu, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 523(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403146622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baghendra Singh, Rakesh Kumar Sharma, Apparao Draksharapu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surgical dissection of ignition behavior of aluminum nanoparticles using molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133316</link>
      <description>Yiming Lu, Lili Ye, Hongxin Luo, Mingshu Bi, Fuel. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403146634

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiming Lu, Lili Ye, Hongxin Luo, Mingshu Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Calculations and Machine Learning of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Activity of Nonmetallic Doped &#946;-Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C Support Pt Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10705</link>
      <description>Minhui Song, Mei Yang, Shuo Yang, Li Wang, Chenyang Cao, Hongfei Li, Xiao&#8208;Xu Wang, Panpan Gao, Ping Qian, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403146651

                The most widely used catalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is Pt, but the high cost and low abundance of Pt need to be urgently addressed. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have been an effective means of improving the utilization of Pt atoms. In this work, we used a nonmetal (NM = B, N, O, F, Si, P, S, Cl, As, Se, Br, Te, and I) doped &#946;-Mo</description>
      <author>Minhui Song, Mei Yang, Shuo Yang, Li Wang, Chenyang Cao, Hongfei Li, Xiao&#8208;Xu Wang, Panpan Gao, Ping Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical-bonding and lattice-deformation mechanisms unifying the stability and diffusion trends of hydrogen in TiN and AlN polymorphs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120447</link>
      <description>Qinsheng He, Tian&#8208;Yu Sun, Liang&#8208;Feng Huang, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403154326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qinsheng He, Tian&#8208;Yu Sun, Liang&#8208;Feng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanohybrids of B- and N-codoped reduced graphene oxide/CeO2&#8211;Co3O4 nanocomposite for efficient water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129984</link>
      <description>Zohreh Shaghaghi, Farnaz Ebrahimi, Sahar Jafari Nivlouei, Materials Chemistry and Physics. 328(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403156921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zohreh Shaghaghi, Farnaz Ebrahimi, Sahar Jafari Nivlouei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pathways and enhancement strategies for magnesium hardness removal in modified induced crystallization softening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122729</link>
      <description>Changgeng Li, Cheng Liu, Yun Han, Weibin Xu, Bing Yan, Aijun Du, Qin Li, Qi Yu, Journal of Environmental Management. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403157311

                Elevated levels of total hardness in drinking water can readily result in scaling, which poses a threat to both the safety of water quality and the convenience of its use. While there is a wealth of research on the removal of calcium hardness, there is a dearth of studies focusing on the removal of magnesium hardness. In light of this, the present study employs modified induced crystallization softening (MICS) to delineate the removal pathways and mechanisms of magnesium hardness, and to investigate viable methods for its enhancement and application. Our research has determined that magnesium hardness can be effectively removed from water through the MICS, with the dosage of softening agents (NaOH) being a significant factor that influences this removal, whereas the fixed bed height within the fluidized bed exerts minimal impact on the process. In the low-dose stage (less than 250 mg/L), when the pH is below 10.0, up to 20% of magnesium hardness can be removed, predominantly through the crystallization of (Ca</description>
      <author>Changgeng Li, Cheng Liu, Yun Han, Weibin Xu, Bing Yan, Aijun Du, Qin Li, Qi Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Area Epitaxy of Gallium Phosphide-Based Nanostructures on Microsphere Lithography-Patterned Si Wafers for Visible Light Optoelectronics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113126</link>
      <description>Vladimir V. Fedorov, Vladimir V. Fedorov, A. V. Pavlov, Sergey Komarov, E. I. Moiseev, Dmitry Miniv, &#1040;. &#1050;. &#1050;&#1072;&#1074;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, A. Smirnov, &#1044;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1040; &#1052; &#1052;&#1086;&#1078;&#1072;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Ivan S. Mukhin, Materials Research Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403157700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vladimir V. Fedorov, Vladimir V. Fedorov, A. V. Pavlov, Sergey Komarov, E. I. Moiseev, Dmitry Miniv, &#1040;. &#1050;. &#1050;&#1072;&#1074;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, A. Smirnov, &#1044;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1040; &#1052; &#1052;&#1086;&#1078;&#1072;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Ivan S. Mukhin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important structural parameter for curvature effect of TM-N4 embeded C70 fullerenes as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction interpreted with machine learning and first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105233</link>
      <description>Aling Ma, Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403168428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aling Ma, Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic oxidation of 1,2-dichlorobenzene over CoxCry oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119975</link>
      <description>Chensheng Tu, Shijie Shao, Wangjia Xi, Hao Zhang, Qiguang Dai, Xingyi Wang, Yanglong Guo, Applied Catalysis A General. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403169200

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chensheng Tu, Shijie Shao, Wangjia Xi, Hao Zhang, Qiguang Dai, Xingyi Wang, Yanglong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Progress in Structure Evolution and Durability Modulation of Ir&#8208; and Ru&#8208;Based OER Catalysts under Acidic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406657</link>
      <description>You Zi, Chengxu Zhang, Jian-Qiang Zhao, Ying Cheng, Jinliang Yuan, Jue Hu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403170675

                Abstract Green hydrogen energy, as one of the most promising energy carriers, plays a crucial role in addressing energy and environmental issues. Oxygen evolution reaction catalysts, as the key to water electrolysis hydrogen production technology, have been subject to durability constraints, preventing large&#8208;scale commercial development. Under the high current density and harsh acid&#8208;base electrolyte conditions of the water electrolysis reaction, the active metals in the catalysts are easily converted into high&#8208;valent soluble species to dissolve, leading to poor structural durability of the catalysts. There is an urgent need to overcome the durability challenges under acidic conditions and develop electrocatalysts with both high catalytic activity and high durability. In this review, the latest research results are analyzed in depth from both thermodynamic and kinetic perspectives. First, a comprehensive summary of the structural deactivation state process of noble metal oxide catalysts is presented. Second, the evolution of the structure of catalysts possessing high durability is discussed. Finally, four new strategies for the preparation of stable catalysts, &#8220;electron buffer (ECB) strategy&#8221;, combination strength control, strain control, and surface coating, are summarized. The challenges and prospects are also elaborated for the future synthesis of more effective Ru/Ir&#8208;based catalysts and boost their future application.</description>
      <author>You Zi, Chengxu Zhang, Jian-Qiang Zhao, Ying Cheng, Jinliang Yuan, Jue Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermosalient Phase Transitions from Machine Learning Interatomic Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.4c00905</link>
      <description>Bruno Mladineo, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403173139

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bruno Mladineo, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.4c00905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening Multicomponent Alloys Using Evidence Theory and High-Throughput DFT Calculations for C2-Selective eCO2RR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04180</link>
      <description>Fumiaki Kuroda, Masaya Ibe, Minoru Otani, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403192715

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fumiaki Kuroda, Masaya Ibe, Minoru Otani</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in MXene-based frameworks towards photocatalytic hydrogen production, carbon dioxide reduction and pollutant degradation: Current challenges and future prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216226</link>
      <description>Zeeshan Ajmal, Asif Hayat, Abdul Qadeer, Yuzeng Zhao, Essam H. Ibrahim, Mahmood Ul Haq, Kanwal Iqbal, Mohd Imran, Mohammed Kuku, Iftikhar Hussain, Hamid Ali, Yasin Orooji, John L. Zhou, Teng Ben, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 523(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403195408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeeshan Ajmal, Asif Hayat, Abdul Qadeer, Yuzeng Zhao, Essam H. Ibrahim, Mahmood Ul Haq, Kanwal Iqbal, Mohd Imran, Mohammed Kuku, Iftikhar Hussain, Hamid Ali, Yasin Orooji, John L. Zhou, Teng Ben</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictive Modeling and Design of Organic Solar Cells: A Data-Driven Approach for Material Innovation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01847</link>
      <description>Bibhas Das, Anirban Mondal, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403196899

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bibhas Das, Anirban Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01847</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Efficiency and Selectivity of Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to C1 Products by Mn-Porphyrin via Axial Ligation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04330</link>
      <description>Hemjot Kaur, Anoop Saraya, Neetu Goel, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403197504

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hemjot Kaur, Anoop Saraya, Neetu Goel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Learning of Boltzmann Samplers and Potential Energies with Quantum Mechanical Accuracy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00506</link>
      <description>Ana Molina-Taborda, Pilar Cossio, Olga Lopez&#8208;Acevedo, Marylou Gabri&#233;, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403199069

                Extracting consistent statistics between relevant free energy minima of a molecular system is essential for physics, chemistry, and biology. Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations can aid in this task but are computationally expensive, especially for systems that require quantum accuracy. To overcome this challenge, we developed an approach combining enhanced sampling with deep generative models and active learning of a machine learning potential (MLP). We introduce an adaptive Markov chain Monte Carlo framework that enables the training of one normalizing flow (NF) and one MLP per state, achieving rapid convergence toward the Boltzmann distribution. Leveraging the trained NF and MLP models, we compute thermodynamic observables such as free energy differences and optical spectra. We apply this method to study the isomerization of an ultrasmall silver nanocluster belonging to a set of systems with diverse applications in the fields of medicine and catalysis.</description>
      <author>Ana Molina-Taborda, Pilar Cossio, Olga Lopez&#8208;Acevedo, Marylou Gabri&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engaging the Concepts of Bimetallicity and Mechanical Strain for N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activation: A Computational Exploration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09691</link>
      <description>Omer Elmutasim, Louai Mahdi Maghrabi, Dattatray S. Dhawale, Kyriaki Polychronopoulou, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403199424

                N</description>
      <author>Omer Elmutasim, Louai Mahdi Maghrabi, Dattatray S. Dhawale, Kyriaki Polychronopoulou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced &lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt; Spectroscopic Techniques for Probing the Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05891</link>
      <description>Suk-Kyoung Hong, Ze&#8208;Cheng Yao, Xing Cheng, Zhe Jiang, Tang Tang, Jin&#8208;Song Hu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403199440

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suk-Kyoung Hong, Ze&#8208;Cheng Yao, Xing Cheng, Zhe Jiang, Tang Tang, Jin&#8208;Song Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of N2 to NH3 using FeP(101)/TiO2 catalysts: A First-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.423</link>
      <description>Nandhini Panjulingam, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 90(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403200020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nandhini Panjulingam, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning-assisted design of transition metal-doped 2D WSn&#8322;N&#8324; electrocatalysts for enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.011</link>
      <description>Guang Wang, Yi Wang, Yingchao Wang, Teng&#8208;Teng Chen, Lei Li, Zhengli Zhang, Zhao Ding, Xiang Guo, Zijiang Luo, Xuefei Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 90(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403203833

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guang Wang, Yi Wang, Yingchao Wang, Teng&#8208;Teng Chen, Lei Li, Zhengli Zhang, Zhao Ding, Xiang Guo, Zijiang Luo, Xuefei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single Atom&#8208;Doped Triphasic VP&#8208;Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;P&#8208;MoP Heterostructure: Unveiling a Breakthrough Electrocatalyst for Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405952</link>
      <description>Ganesh Bhandari, Purna Prasad Dhakal, Duy Thanh Tran, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403213720

                Abstract Enhancement of an alkaline water splitting reaction in Pt&#8208;based single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) relies on effective metal&#8208;support interactions. A Pt single atom (Pt SA )&#8208;immobilized three&#8208;phased Pt SA @VP&#8208;Ni 3 P&#8208;MoP heterostructure on nickel foam is presented, demonstrating high catalytic performance. The existence of Pt SA on triphasic metal phosphides gives an outstanding performance toward overall water splitting. The Pt SA @VP&#8208;Ni 3 P&#8208;MoP performs a low overpotential of 28 and 261 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at a current density of 10 and 25 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The Pt SA @VP&#8208;Ni 3 P&#8208;MoP (+,&#8722;) alkaline electrolyzer achieves a minimum cell voltage of 1.48 V at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for overall water splitting. Additionally, the electrocatalyst exhibits a substantial Faradaic yield of &#8776;98.12% for H 2 and 98.47% for O 2 at a current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . Consequently, this study establishes a connection for understanding the active role of single metal atoms in substrate configuration for catalytic performance. It also facilitates the successful synthesis of SACs, with a substantial loading on transition metal phosphides and maximal atomic utilization, providing more active sites and, thereby enhancing electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Ganesh Bhandari, Purna Prasad Dhakal, Duy Thanh Tran, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molten Salt&#8208;Assisted Synthesis of Ferric Oxide/M&#8211;N&#8211;C Nanosheet Electrocatalysts for Efficient Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401278</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Lu, Weiming Gong, Jinpeng Chen, Peng Guo, Yingxian Zhang, Lan Zhang, Minglei Yan, Chun&#8208;Yi Wu, Mengmeng Sun, Gehong Su, Yan Wang, Yanying Wang, Jianshan Ye, Wenxin Zhu, Jianlong Wang, Hanbing Rao, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403215671

                Abstract Efficient, stable, and low&#8208;cost oxygen reduction catalysts are the key to the large&#8208;scale application of metal&#8211;air batteries. Herein, high&#8208;dispersive Fe 2 O 3 nanoparticles (NPs) with abundant oxygen vacancies uniformly are anchored on lignin&#8208;derived metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) hierarchical porous nanosheets as efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts (Fe 2 O 3 /M&#8211;N&#8211;C, M&#9552;Cu, Mn, W, Mo) based on a general and economical KCl molten salt&#8208;assisted method. The combination of Fe with the highly electronegative O induces charge redistribution through the Fe&#8211;O&#8211;M structure, thereby reducing the adsorption energy of oxygen&#8208;containing substances. The coupling effect of Fe 2 O 3 NPs with M&#8211;N&#8211;C expedites the catalytic activity toward ORR by promoting proton generation on Fe 2 O 3 and transfer to M&#8211;N&#8211;C. Experimental and theoretical calculation further revealed the remarkable electronic structure evolution of the metal site during the ORR process, where the emission density and local magnetic moment of the metal atoms change continuously throughout their reaction. The unique layered porous structure and highly active M&#8211;N 4 sites resulted in the excellent ORR activity of Fe 2 O 3 /Cu&#8211;N&#8211;C with the onset potential of 0.977 V, which is superior to Pt/C. This study offers a feasible strategy for the preparation of non&#8208;noble metal catalysts and provides a new comprehension of the catalytic mechanism of M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Lu, Weiming Gong, Jinpeng Chen, Peng Guo, Yingxian Zhang, Lan Zhang, Minglei Yan, Chun&#8208;Yi Wu, Mengmeng Sun, Gehong Su, Yan Wang, Yanying Wang, Jianshan Ye, Wenxin Zhu, Jianlong Wang, Hanbing Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Floatable Artificial Leaf to Couple Oxygen-Tolerant CO2 Conversion with Water-Purification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5034862/v1</link>
      <description>Hua Sheng, Qian Zhang, Li Wang, Yangen Xie, Tetsuya Takemoto, Qi Zhao, Qing Huang, Xingmiao Huang, Boyang Zhang, Wenjing Song, Chuncheng Chen, Jincai Zhao, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403216551

                Abstract To enable open-environment application of artificial photosynthesis, the direct utilization of environmental CO2 via an oxygen-tolerant reductive procedure is necessary. Herein, we introduce an in-situ growth strategy for fabricating two-dimensional heterojunctions between indium porphyrin metal-organic framework (In-MOF) and single-layer graphene oxide (GO). Upon illumination, the In-MOF/GO heterostructure facilitates a tandem CO2 capture and photocatalytic reduction on its hydroxylated In-node, prioritizing the reduction of dilute CO2 even in the presence of air-level O2. The In-MOF/GO heterostructure photocatalyst was integrated with a porous polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) membrane to construct a floatable artificial leaf. Through a triphase photocatalytic reaction, the floatable artificial leaf can remove aqueous contaminants from real water while efficiently reducing CO2 at low concentrations (10%, approximately the CO2 concentration in combustion flue gases) upon air-level O2. This study provides a scalable approach for the construction of photocatalytic devices for CO2 conversion in open environments.</description>
      <author>Hua Sheng, Qian Zhang, Li Wang, Yangen Xie, Tetsuya Takemoto, Qi Zhao, Qing Huang, Xingmiao Huang, Boyang Zhang, Wenjing Song, Chuncheng Chen, Jincai Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5034862/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via C&#8722;X bond formation: recent progress and perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.32</link>
      <description>Shuaiqiang Jia, Mengke Dong, Qinggong Zhu, Xinchen Kang, Haihong Wu, Buxing Han, Chemical Synthesis. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403219231

                With the depletion of traditional energy sources and growing environmental concerns, it is becoming increasingly urgent to develop green, low-emission renewable energy technologies to replace fossil fuel-driven methods that emit carbon dioxide (CO2). Currently, the electrochemical production of high-value-added chemicals and fuels from CO2 has aroused great interest from scientists. However, to make full use of CO2 for the preparation of chemicals, it is necessary to expand the range of electrosynthesis methods, in particular by expanding reaction pathways through the reaction of CO2 with different substrates. In general, CO2 can form new covalent bonds with substrate molecules through the formation of C&#8722;X bonds, including C&#8722;H, C&#8722;C, C&#8722;N, C&#8722;O, and C&#8722;S bonds, which would expand the range of possible products by diversifying the reaction pathway. In this review, we focus on the research progress in electrochemical conversion of CO2 through C&#8722;X bond formation. We start by examining fundamentals of the reactions and summarizing the reaction modes. Next, we discuss the electrosynthesis of C&#8722;X bonds (C&#8722;H, C&#8722;C, C&#8722;N, C&#8722;O, C&#8722;S) using CO2 and different substrate molecules. Finally, (i) strategies for the design and activity optimization of catalyst materials and (ii) the future development of forming five types of bonds from CO2 and small molecules are discussed, along with an outlook on their future research prospects.</description>
      <author>Shuaiqiang Jia, Mengke Dong, Qinggong Zhu, Xinchen Kang, Haihong Wu, Buxing Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.32</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxide Acidity Modulates Structural Transformations in Hydrogen Titanates during Electrochemical Li-Ion Insertion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08063</link>
      <description>Saeed Saeed, Simon Fleischmann, Takeshi Kobayashi, Z. Jusys, Eugene Mamontov, Naresh C. Osti, Noah P. Holzapfel, Hooyoung Song, Tao Wang, Sheng Dai, De&#8208;en Jiang, Veronica Augustyn, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403223585

                Hydrogen titanates (HTOs) form a diverse group of metastable, layered titanium oxides with an interlayer containing both water molecules and structural protons. We investigated how the chemistry of this interlayer environment influenced electrochemical Li+-insertion in a series of HTOs, H2TiyO2y+1&#183;nH2O (y = 3, 4, and 5). We correlated the electrochemical response with the physical and chemical properties of HTOs using operando X-ray diffraction, in situ differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy, solid-state proton nuclear magnetic resonance, and quasi-elastic neutron scattering. We found that the potential for the first reduction reaction trended with the relative acidity of the structural protons. This mechanism was supported with first-principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations. We propose that the electrochemical reaction involves reduction of the structural protons to yield hydrogen gas and formation of a lithiated hydrogen titanate (H2&#8211;xLixTiyO2y+1). The hydrogen gas is confined within the HTO lattice until the titanate structure expands upon subsequent oxidation. Our work has implications for the electrochemical behavior of insertion hosts containing hydrogen and structural water molecules, where hydrogen evolution is expected at potentials below the hydrogen reduction potential and in the absence of electrolyte proton donors. This behavior is an example of electrochemical electron transfer to a nonmetal element in a metal oxide host, in analogy to anion redox.</description>
      <author>Saeed Saeed, Simon Fleischmann, Takeshi Kobayashi, Z. Jusys, Eugene Mamontov, Naresh C. Osti, Noah P. Holzapfel, Hooyoung Song, Tao Wang, Sheng Dai, De&#8208;en Jiang, Veronica Augustyn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eliminating the Deadwood: A Machine Learning Model for CCS Knowledge-Based Conformational Focusing for Lipids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c01051</link>
      <description>Mithony Keng, Kenneth M. Merz, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403224405

                Accurate elucidation of gas-phase chemical structures using collision cross section (CCS) values obtained from ion-mobility mass spectrometry benefits from a synergism between experimental and in silico results. We have shown in recent work that for a molecule of modest size with a proscribed conformational space we can successfully capture a conformation(s) that can match experimental CCS values. However, for flexible systems such as fatty acids that have many rotatable bonds and multiple intramolecular London dispersion interactions, it becomes necessary to sample a much greater conformational space. Sampling more conformers, however, accrues significant computational cost downstream in optimization steps involving quantum mechanics. To reduce this computational expense for lipids, we have developed a novel machine learning (ML) model to facilitate conformer filtering according to the estimated gas-phase CCS values. Herein we report that the implementation of our CCS knowledge-based approach for conformational sampling resulted in improved structure prediction agreement with experiment by achieving favorable average CCS prediction errors of &#8764;2% for lipid systems in both the validation set and the test set. Moreover, most of the gas-phase candidate conformations obtained by using CCS focusing achieved lower energy-minimum geometries than the candidate conformations without focusing. Altogether, the implementation of this ML model into our modeling workflow has proven to be beneficial for both the quality of the results and the turnaround time. Finally, while our approach is limited to lipids, it can be readily extended to other molecules of interest.</description>
      <author>Mithony Keng, Kenneth M. Merz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c01051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional catalytic activity of anion-doped LaSrCoO &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1098/rsos.240387</link>
      <description>Ittoku Nozawa, Hidehisa Hagiwara, Royal Society Open Science. 11(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403259305

                Here, we synthesized Co-based, anion-incorporated&#8205; &#8204;R&#8204;u&#8204;d&#8204;d&#8204;l&#8204;e&#8204;s-d&#8204;e&#8204;n&#8204;-&#8204;Popper perovskite electrocatalysts (LaSrCoO</description>
      <author>Ittoku Nozawa, Hidehisa Hagiwara</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1098/rsos.240387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the selection of control structures using process operability analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conengprac.2024.106117</link>
      <description>Victor Alves, Fernando V. Lima, Control Engineering Practice. 153(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403155926

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Victor Alves, Fernando V. Lima</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conengprac.2024.106117</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
