<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 01:41:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on one-dimensional carbon nitride doped with transition metal for highly efficient and selective nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137895</link>
      <description>Chenxi Xia, Jianfeng Liu, Hongwei Li, Wei Wei, He Qiu, Lixue Xia, Yan Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410384297

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenxi Xia, Jianfeng Liu, Hongwei Li, Wei Wei, He Qiu, Lixue Xia, Yan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Study of the Mechanism of the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Catalysed by Molybdenum Phosphide in Different Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101141</link>
      <description>Nat&#225;lia Podrojkov&#225;, A. Gub&#243;ov&#225;, M. Stre&#269;kov&#225;, Ren&#225;ta Ori&#328;akov&#225;, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410384426

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nat&#225;lia Podrojkov&#225;, A. Gub&#243;ov&#225;, M. Stre&#269;kov&#225;, Ren&#225;ta Ori&#328;akov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into metal-doped nanostructured hematite catalyst supported by graphene underlayer for photoelectrochemical water splitting applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44344-025-00011-w</link>
      <description>Labanya Bhattacharya, Maytal Caspary Toroker, Discover Catalysis.. 2(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410391383

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Labanya Bhattacharya, Maytal Caspary Toroker</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44344-025-00011-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the C&#8211;C coupling barrier: Surface tailoring for efficient CO2-to-C2+ electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.05.002</link>
      <description>Wasihun Abebe Hika, Asfaw G. Yohannes, Yingjie Guo, Lei Shi, Xiangyang Shi, Shilong Li, Ian D. Gates, Shenlong Zhao, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410397909

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wasihun Abebe Hika, Asfaw G. Yohannes, Yingjie Guo, Lei Shi, Xiangyang Shi, Shilong Li, Ian D. Gates, Shenlong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.05.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT Study: Single Transition Metal Atom Doped MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; as Efficient Electrocatalysts for the Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01644</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Luo, Yu Zhang, Xun Qi, Yanjing Wu, Yiqun Fan, Dan Su, Jie Wen, Arshid Mahmood Ali, Fangli Jing, Hui Zhang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410404233

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Luo, Yu Zhang, Xun Qi, Yanjing Wu, Yiqun Fan, Dan Su, Jie Wen, Arshid Mahmood Ali, Fangli Jing, Hui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01644</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic dipole engineering for enhanced hydrogen evolution of 2D Janus MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0261849</link>
      <description>Zixuan Yang, Tao Huang, Lei Li, Hui Wan, Tao Zhang, X. S. Wang, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang, Journal of Applied Physics. 137(19)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410409153

                Harnessing intrinsic properties to modulate the electronic structure of two-dimensional (2D) materials is essential for clean energy conversion, but challenging. Herein, we demonstrate that tuning intrinsic dipole is an effective strategy to enhance hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity of 2D Janus MXenes, which is exemplified by Mo2C_XY (X/Y = O, F, S, H, OH), using density functional theory calculations. Particularly, Mo2C_OF exhibits four intrinsic dipoles (&#956;S&#8593;, &#956;M&#8593;, &#956;L&#8593;, and &#956;&#8595;), each characterized by distinct magnitudes and/or directions originated from the Mo3+ displacement and its phase change. We propose a single-atom dipole moment to elucidate the underlying mechanism controlling the variation of intrinsic dipole moments in Janus monolayer MXenes. It is found that intrinsic dipole significantly influences the HER activity. Specifically, the adsorption energy of H is reduced when the dipole direction points toward the adsorbed intermediate. Among them, Mo2C_OOH has the Gibbs free energy of &#8722;0.04 eV, surpassing the catalytic performance of commercial Pt. Furthermore, we demonstrate that intrinsic dipoles can be tuned via external strain or electronic doping, providing a pathway for optimizing catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Zixuan Yang, Tao Huang, Lei Li, Hui Wan, Tao Zhang, X. S. Wang, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0261849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of d-electron coupling in dual-atom catalysts for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3362-8</link>
      <description>Bin Li, Y. Ren, Haiyan Wang, Chun Zhu, Jinxia Liang, Jun Li, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410412099

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Li, Y. Ren, Haiyan Wang, Chun Zhu, Jinxia Liang, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3362-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatized Platform for Bandgap Optimization in Diarylethene Derivatives via Structural Substitutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70052</link>
      <description>Edoardo Fabbrini, Linh Thi Hoai Nguyen, Yasuhide Fukumoto, Yu Kaneko, Pierluigi Cesana, International Journal of Quantum Chemistry. 125(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410413212

                ABSTRACT This study presents an automated framework for discovering Diarylethene derivatives with specific HOMO&#8208;LUMO bandgaps by integrating first&#8208;principles calculations with evolutionary optimization algorithms. We develop a protocol for performing automatic, parallel Density Functional Theory calculations using Turbomole, enabled by the Atomic Simulation Environment Python wrapper. This integration allows for fully autonomous evolutionary searches, removing the need for human intervention. To evaluate our platform, we conduct searches within the chemical space of Diarylethene using two optimization strategies: A &#8220;local&#8221; strategy, which explores local neighborhoods, and a &#8220;glocal&#8221; strategy, which combines local exploration with memory of past achievements.</description>
      <author>Edoardo Fabbrini, Linh Thi Hoai Nguyen, Yasuhide Fukumoto, Yu Kaneko, Pierluigi Cesana</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in Ru electrocatalyst design for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01849h</link>
      <description>Yingde Cui, Yan Zhao, Zhen Han, Zeyu Wang, Wenjun Li, Yang Zhang, Zhijun Li, Wanglei Wang, Xiaogang Fu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410414323

                This review surveys recent advances in Ru-based electrocatalysts for the acidic OER, focusing on strategies to enhance activity and stability, mitigate Ru dissolution and performance degradation, and inform the design of robust PEMWE.</description>
      <author>Yingde Cui, Yan Zhao, Zhen Han, Zeyu Wang, Wenjun Li, Yang Zhang, Zhijun Li, Wanglei Wang, Xiaogang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01849h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable Artificial Intelligence Elucidates Synthesis&#8208;Structure&#8208;Property&#8208;Function Relationships in Nanostructured Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202420465</link>
      <description>Manu Suvarna, Marc Eduard Usteri, Frank Krumeich, Sharon Mitchell, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410414327

                Abstract Designing high&#8208;performance catalysts based on supported metal atoms and nanoparticles necessitates rigorous assembly control, which affects reactivity. Yet, attaining synthesis precision to discern catalyst speciation and properties remains challenging. This limitation is tackled by pioneering an eXplainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) methodology that combines a decision tree classifier and a random forest regressor sequentially to elucidate synthesis&#8208;structure&#8208;property&#8208;function relationships in nanostructured catalysts, exemplified for the oxygen evolution (OER) and hydrogen evolution (HER) reactions. The decision tree accurately predicts the formation of single atoms versus nanoparticles for 37 metals anchored on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon, identifying the metal's standard reduction potential and cohesive energy as determinants of speciation. The random forest regressor correlates the electrocatalytic performance of synthesized single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) to intrinsic properties, revealing a volcano&#8208;like relationship of current density with the electronegativity of the active site and metal&#8208;support interaction, providing insights beyond traditional adsorption energy descriptors. The integrated models are validated experimentally with an overall accuracy of over 80%, establishing user confidence. This XAI framework, adaptable to diverse synthetic protocols and material classes is a powerful tool to understand synthesis&#8208;structure&#8208;property&#8208;function relationships and promote data&#8208;informed experiments with reduced characterization efforts.</description>
      <author>Manu Suvarna, Marc Eduard Usteri, Frank Krumeich, Sharon Mitchell, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202420465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy&#8208;Increase Assisted Anti&#8208;Sintering for Synthesis of High&#8208;Loaded Pt Intermetallic Compounds as Electrocatalysts in PEMFCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503628</link>
      <description>Y.B. Pan, Yihe Chen, Yuze Li, Mengyuan Liu, Lulu Yao, Hao Zhao, Xiaoyu Zhao, Zhouying Yue, Song Gui, Yubin Chen, Qingqing Cheng, Hui Yang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410414418

                Abstract High&#8208;loaded Pt intermetallic compounds (IMCs) present the practical application potential in low&#8208;Pt PEM fuel cells while ordering transformation under high temperature inevitably leads to severe sintering of high&#8208;density IMC nanoparticles (NPs), thus the decayed oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance. Herein, an entropy&#8208;increase assisted anti&#8208;sintering concept is proposed to fundamentally reduce the surface energy of NPs by increasing the mixing entropy, thus hindering the migration and coalescence of NPs. Ex/in situ electron microscopy and density functional theory (DFT) corroborate that the higher the entropy of pristine NPs, the lower the surface energy, the smaller the average size, and the more uniform distribution after annealing. The prepared Pt high&#8208;entropy IMC (Pt&#8208;HEI@Pt/C) demonstrates high metal loading (40.53 wt.%) and small particle size (&#8776;3.15 nm), which endow it with an excellent ORR activity with mass activity (MA@0.9V, 0.65 A mg &#8722;1 Pt ) and durability over 20k potential&#8208;cycling. Membrane electrode assembly integrated with this catalyst delivers a peak power density of 0.96 W cm &#8722;2 and an exceptional stability (12.5% decline in MA) under H2&#8208;air condition at 0.1 mg Pt cm &#8722;2 . DFT reveals the reinforced strain regulation effect of the HEI core on the Pt shell, which optimizes the *OOH adsorption and elevates the energy barrier of Pt dissolution, thus simultaneously enhancing the intrinsic ORR activity and durability.</description>
      <author>Y.B. Pan, Yihe Chen, Yuze Li, Mengyuan Liu, Lulu Yao, Hao Zhao, Xiaoyu Zhao, Zhouying Yue, Song Gui, Yubin Chen, Qingqing Cheng, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High strain rate compressive deformation behavior of nickel microparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.05.014</link>
      <description>B. Bell&#243;n, Lalith Kumar Bhaskar, Tobias Brink, Raquel Aymerich&#8208;Armengol, Dipali Sonawane, D. Chatain, Gerhard Dehm, Rajaprakash Ramachandramoorthy, Materials Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410420387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. Bell&#243;n, Lalith Kumar Bhaskar, Tobias Brink, Raquel Aymerich&#8208;Armengol, Dipali Sonawane, D. Chatain, Gerhard Dehm, Rajaprakash Ramachandramoorthy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.05.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ regulating the accessibility and structure of Fe-based catalytic sites to break trade-off between the activity and stability for oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137910</link>
      <description>He Zhang, Jinyan Wu, Chaozhong Guo, Xiaoyu Dong, Chenyang Shu, Liumei Teng, Yao Liu, Hongdian Chen, Rong Jin, Caiyi Jiang, Junjie Zhou, Yujun Si, Honglin Li, Yong Zheng Pang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410421870

                No abstract</description>
      <author>He Zhang, Jinyan Wu, Chaozhong Guo, Xiaoyu Dong, Chenyang Shu, Liumei Teng, Yao Liu, Hongdian Chen, Rong Jin, Caiyi Jiang, Junjie Zhou, Yujun Si, Honglin Li, Yong Zheng Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Atomic-Scale Compressive Strain for Oxime Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03600</link>
      <description>Lubing Qin, Yuping Chen, Ziyi Liu, Mengyao Chen, Qing Tang, Zhenghua Tang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410424796

                Tuning the surface strain is a powerful strategy to enhance the catalytic activity of metal nanocatalysts, yet an atomically precise catalyst with intramolecular strain to unlock the atomic-level strain-structure-activity relationship is still highly desired. Herein, we report the synthesis, structural anatomy, and catalytic performance toward cyclohexanone oxime electrosynthesis of an atomically precise Ag16Cu18(C&#8801;C-C6H11)24 (Ag16Cu18) nanocluster, which has a Cu6 ring in the center. The Cu-Cu distance in the Cu6 ring is only 1.616 &#197; in a single crystal, the shortest Cu-Cu bond in Cu nanomaterials to date. Furthermore, once Ag16Cu18 was loaded onto carbon paper, the ultrashort Cu-Cu bond elongated to &#8764;2.40 &#197;, still showing strong intramolecular compressive strain. Ag16Cu18 exhibited excellent catalytic activity toward oxime electrosynthesis, manifested by a maximal Faradaic efficiency, yield, and yield rate of cyclohexanone oxime reaching 47.4%, 95.4%, and 2.66 mmol&#183;h-1&#183;cm-2 at -0.35 V, respectively. In-situ attenuated total reflection surface-enhanced infrared spectroscopy revealed that the Cu sites adjacent to the Ag atoms primarily reduce NO and stabilize it at the *NH2OH stage, while the Cu sites with compressive strain provide H* for NO reduction and adsorb cyclohexanone to react with *NH2OH, forming cyclohexanone oxime simultaneously. Density functional theory calculations confirmed the presence of compressive strain in the Cu6 ring, which facilitates H* formation and cyclohexanone adsorption, hence significantly contributing to oxime generation. This study not only reports a case of atomically precise clusters with intramolecular compressive strain but also provides an atomic-level understanding for employing bimetallic nanocluster-based catalysts toward the electrosynthesis of valuable organic molecules.</description>
      <author>Lubing Qin, Yuping Chen, Ziyi Liu, Mengyao Chen, Qing Tang, Zhenghua Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03600</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting practical reduction potential of electrolyte solvents via computational hydrogen electrode and interpretable machine-learning models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01582-w</link>
      <description>Zonglin Yi, Yitong Zhou, Huan Liu, Li Li, Yan Zhao, Jiayuan Li, Yixuan Mao, Fangyuan Su, Cheng&#8208;Meng Chen, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410431287

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zonglin Yi, Yitong Zhou, Huan Liu, Li Li, Yan Zhao, Jiayuan Li, Yixuan Mao, Fangyuan Su, Cheng&#8208;Meng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01582-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of palladium hierarchical nanosheet assemblies: unraveling the aggregation-induced synergistic effect for enhanced methanol oxidation reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ce00360a</link>
      <description>Li&#8208;Juan Han, Yuanyuan Min, Yingying Wang, Feng Liu, Maochang Liu, Yiqun Zheng, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410432784

                Hierarchical Pd nanosheet assemblies are prepared, exhibiting enhanced MOR activity arising from the aggregation-induced synergistic effect.</description>
      <author>Li&#8208;Juan Han, Yuanyuan Min, Yingying Wang, Feng Liu, Maochang Liu, Yiqun Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ce00360a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of local electric polarization using graph neural networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.184105</link>
      <description>Yuxing Ma, Yingwei Chen, Binhua Zhang, Yali Yang, Hongyu Yu, Xin-Gao Gong, Yang Zhong, Hongjun Xiang, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(18)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410432848

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxing Ma, Yingwei Chen, Binhua Zhang, Yali Yang, Hongyu Yu, Xin-Gao Gong, Yang Zhong, Hongjun Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.184105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning surface curvature in B and N co-doped CNT-derived Fe, Ru and Ir catalysts for electrochemical hydrogenation of N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp00309a</link>
      <description>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410438560

                Modulating the CNT curvature enhances the catalytic performance of the electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR).</description>
      <author>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp00309a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells: Significant Advances, Major Challenges, and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00903</link>
      <description>Sami Mohammed Alfaifi, Rajkamal Balu, Ken Chiang, Namita Roy Choudhury, Naba K. Dutta, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410443701

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sami Mohammed Alfaifi, Rajkamal Balu, Ken Chiang, Namita Roy Choudhury, Naba K. Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TrIP2: Expanding the Transformer Interatomic Potential Demonstrates Architectural Scalability for Organic Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c00391</link>
      <description>Joshua L. Ebbert, Bryce Hedelius, Jyothish Joy, Daniel H. Ess, Dennis Della Corte, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410451399

                TrIP2 is an advanced version of the transformer interatomic potential (TrIP) trained on the expanded ANI-2x data set, including more diverse molecular configurations with sulfur, fluorine, and chlorine. It leverages the equivariant SE(3)-transformer architecture, incorporating physical biases and continuous atomic representations. TrIP was introduced as a highly promising transferable interatomic potential, which we show here to generalize to new atom types with no alterations to the underlying model design. Benchmarking on COMP6 energy and force calculations, structure minimization tasks, torsion drives, and applications to molecules with unexpected conformational energy minima demonstrates TrIP2's high accuracy and transferability. Direct architectural comparisons demonstrate superior performance against ANI-2x, while holistic model evaluations&#9472;including training data and level-of-theory considerations&#9472;show comparative performance with state-of-the-art models like AIMNet2 and MACE-OFF23. Notably, TrIP2 achieves state-of-the-art force prediction performance on the COMP6 benchmarks and closely approaches DFT-optimized structures in torsion drives and geometry optimization tasks. Without requiring any architectural modifications, TrIP2 successfully capitalizes on additional training data to deliver enhanced generalizability and precision, establishing itself as a robust and scalable framework capable of accommodating future expansions or applications to new domains with minimal reengineering.</description>
      <author>Joshua L. Ebbert, Bryce Hedelius, Jyothish Joy, Daniel H. Ess, Dennis Della Corte</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c00391</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabatier Principle Revisited: The Role of Electronic Properties in Simple Catalytic Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01822</link>
      <description>Ram&#243;n Alain Miranda&#8208;Quintana, Niklas Adebar, Moritz Schulze, Jens Smiatek, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410451410

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ram&#243;n Alain Miranda&#8208;Quintana, Niklas Adebar, Moritz Schulze, Jens Smiatek</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic decomposition mechanism of hydroxyamine nitrate on the Cu(111) surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25259/ajc_86_2024</link>
      <description>Li Men, Tianpeng Li, Xinbao Gao, Yin Huang, Arabian Journal of Chemistry. 0(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410453391

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Men, Tianpeng Li, Xinbao Gao, Yin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25259/ajc_86_2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two different metalloporphyrin composites as promising orr catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.114702</link>
      <description>Sergey M. Kuzmin, Svetlana A. Chulovskaya, Yuliya A. Filimonova, V. I. Parfenyuk, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410459434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sergey M. Kuzmin, Svetlana A. Chulovskaya, Yuliya A. Filimonova, V. I. Parfenyuk</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.114702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical investigation of Ta3N5/BaTaO2N heterostructure for solar water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2025.116511</link>
      <description>Huan Zhang, Yue Liu, Xin Zhou, Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology A Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410461407

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Zhang, Yue Liu, Xin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2025.116511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrahigh Pyrrolic Nitrogen Triggers High-Activity Sites in Carbon Catalysts for Selective Oxygen Reduction to Efficient H2O2 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120450</link>
      <description>Yanan Shi, Menggai Jiao, Chongyang Wang, Lili Zhang, Shaohui Sun, Carbon. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410461573

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Shi, Menggai Jiao, Chongyang Wang, Lili Zhang, Shaohui Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic niobium and manganese co-doping into RuO2 nanocrystal enables PEM water splitting under high current</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59710-5</link>
      <description>Bichen Yuan, Qian Dang, Hai Liu, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Jian Peng, Yameng Fan, Liang Cai, Aiqing Cao, Shiyao Chen, Hui Li, Yun Kuang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410462343

                Low-cost ruthenium-based catalysts with high activity have emerged as promising alternatives to iridium-based counterparts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE), but the poor stability under high current density remains as a key challenge. Here, we utilize the synergistic complementary strategy of introducing earth-abundant Mn and Nb dopants in ruthenium dioxide (RuO2) for Nb0.1Mn0.1Ru0.8O2 nanoparticle electrocatalyst that exhibits a low overpotential of 209 mV at 10 mA cm-2 and good stability of &gt; 400 h at 0.2 A cm-2 in 0.5 M H2SO4. Significantly, a PEMWE device fabricated with Nb0.1Mn0.1Ru0.8O2 anode can operate continuously at least for 1000 h at 0.5 A cm-2 with 59 &#956;V h-1 decay rate. Operando Raman spectroscopy analysis, differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy measurements, X-ray absorption spectroscopy analysis and theoretical calculations indicate that OER reaction on Nb0.1Mn0.1Ru0.8O2 primarily follows the adsorbate evolution mechanism with much favorable energy barrier accompanied by a locally passivated lattice oxygen mechanism (AEM-LPLOM) and the co-existed Nb and Mn in RuO2 crystal lattice could not only stabilize the lattice oxygen, but also relieve the valence state fluctuation of Ru site to stabilize the catalyst during the reaction.</description>
      <author>Bichen Yuan, Qian Dang, Hai Liu, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Jian Peng, Yameng Fan, Liang Cai, Aiqing Cao, Shiyao Chen, Hui Li, Yun Kuang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59710-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly stable and porous triple perovskite oxide as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163928</link>
      <description>Yousuf Ali, Swarit Dwivedi, Masood S. Alivand, A. Sanjid, Akshat Tanksale, Parama Chakraborty Banerjee, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410475868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yousuf Ali, Swarit Dwivedi, Masood S. Alivand, A. Sanjid, Akshat Tanksale, Parama Chakraborty Banerjee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growth of atmospheric freshly nucleated particles: a semi-empirical molecular dynamics study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/ar-3-237-2025</link>
      <description>Yosef Knattrup, Ivo Neefjes, Jakub Kube&#269;ka, Jonas Elm, Aerosol Research. 3(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410477656

                Abstract. When simulating new particle formation rates, collisions in the system are approximated as hard spheres without long-range interactions. This simplification may lead to an underestimation of the actual formation rate. In this study, we employ semi-empirical molecular dynamics (SEMD) at the GFN1-xTB level of theory to probe the sticking process of the monomers sulfuric acid (SA), methanesulfonic acid (MSA), nitric acid (NA), formic acid (FA), ammonia (AM), methylamine (MA), dimethylamine (DMA), and trimethylamine (TMA) onto freshly nucleated particles (FNPs). The FNPs considered are (SA)10(AM)10, (SA)10(MA)10, (SA)10(DMA)10, and (SA)10(TMA)10. In general, we find that the hard-sphere kinetic approximation, which neglects long-range interactions, significantly underestimates the number of collisions leading to sticking. By calculating the sticking coefficient from SEMD simulations, we obtain enhancement factors of 2.3 and 1.5 for the SA + (SA)10(AM)10 and AM + (SA)10(AM)10 collisions, respectively. A comparison with OPLS (optimized potentials for liquid simulations) all-atom force field simulations shows similar enhancement factors of 2.4 and 1.6 for the SA + (SA)10(AM)10 and AM + (SA)10(AM)10 collisions, respectively. Compared to the force field simulations, SEMD exhibits a more isotropic sticking behavior, with the probability remaining near unity for small offsets before rapidly dropping to 0 % beyond a certain offset. In contrast, the force field simulations show a more gradual decline in sticking probability due to certain orientations still leading to sticking. The largest discrepancy between the two methods occurs at lower collision velocities &#8211; below 200 m s&#8722;1 for SA and below 400 m s&#8722;1 for AM &#8211; where force field simulations, even for head-on collisions, predict low or zero sticking probability. This has previously been attributed to periodic repulsions between the rotating collision partners caused by fluctuations in their charge distributions. In contrast, SEMD simulations do not exhibit this behavior. Since these low velocities are not significantly populated in our simulations, both methods yield similar enhancement factors. However, for systems with larger effective masses, where such velocities are more prevalent, we would expect the two methods to diverge.</description>
      <author>Yosef Knattrup, Ivo Neefjes, Jakub Kube&#269;ka, Jonas Elm</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/ar-3-237-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another look at the often ignored role of oxygen functional groups in the oxygen reduction reaction: The promoting effect of carbonyls</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120449</link>
      <description>Rui S. Ribeiro, Krzysztof Biernacki, Marc Florent, Alexandre L. Magalh&#227;es, Teresa J. Bandosz, M.F.R. Pereira, Carbon. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410478367

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui S. Ribeiro, Krzysztof Biernacki, Marc Florent, Alexandre L. Magalh&#227;es, Teresa J. Bandosz, M.F.R. Pereira</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A MoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-incorporated RuAu composite electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01235j</link>
      <description>Jae&#8208;Won Lee, Jinho Oh, Junhyeong Kim, Hee&#8208;Young Park, Sung Jong Yoo, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim, Jong Hyun Jang, Hyun S. Park, Sung Ki Cho, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410479498

                The electrocatalytic activity of RuAu for the hydrogen evolution reaction is improved by the formation of a composite with MoO x through electrodeposition.</description>
      <author>Jae&#8208;Won Lee, Jinho Oh, Junhyeong Kim, Hee&#8208;Young Park, Sung Jong Yoo, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim, Jong Hyun Jang, Hyun S. Park, Sung Ki Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01235j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical reduction of CO2 on S-triazine-based g-C3N4 surface modified with metal and nonmetal atoms: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2025.103123</link>
      <description>Hadis Pirdadeh Beyranvand, Zahra Tavangar, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 97(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410487213

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hadis Pirdadeh Beyranvand, Zahra Tavangar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2025.103123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Dual&#8208;Atom Design to Boost Oxygen Reduction Reaction on Iron&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502102</link>
      <description>Shengping You, Chao Zhang, Mingyu Yu, Xin Tan, Kaian Sun, Yun Zheng, Zewen Zhuang, Wei Yan, Jiujun Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410490249

                Abstract The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is critical for energy conversion technologies like fuel cells and metal&#8211;air batteries. However, advancing efficient and stable ORR catalysts remains a significant challenge. Iron&#8208;based single&#8208;atom catalysts (Fe SACs) have emerged as promising alternatives to precious metals. However, their catalytic performance and stability remain constrained. Introducing a second metal (M) to construct Fe&#9472;M dual&#8208;atom catalysts (Fe&#9472;M DACs) is an effective strategy to enhance the performance of Fe SACs. This review provides a comprehensive overview of the recent advancements in Fe&#8208;based DACs for ORR. It begins by examining the structural advantages of Fe&#9472;M DACs from the perspectives of electronic structure and reaction pathways. Next, the precise synthetic strategies for DACs are discussed, and the structure&#8211;performance relationships are explored, highlighting the role of the second metal in improving catalytic activity and stability. The review also covers in situ characterization techniques for real&#8208;time observation of catalytic dynamics and reaction intermediates. Finally, future directions for Fe&#9472;M DACs are proposed, emphasizing the integration of advanced experimental strategies with theoretical simulations as well as artificial intelligence/machine learning to design highly active and stable ORR catalysts, aiming to expand the application of Fe&#9472;M DACs in energy conversion and storage technologies.</description>
      <author>Shengping You, Chao Zhang, Mingyu Yu, Xin Tan, Kaian Sun, Yun Zheng, Zewen Zhuang, Wei Yan, Jiujun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502102</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI-Driven Transformation in New Materials Manufacturing and the Development of Intelligent Sports</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app15105667</link>
      <description>Fang Wang, Shenhao Jiang, Jun Li, Applied Sciences. 15(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410494090

                The advancement of materials science has had a profound, even revolutionary, impact on sports. Materials are used in the sports field, equipment, and sportswear, each with distinct functionality and safety requirements. Additionally, diverse sport-related data require physical devices for collection, analysis, and storage, which can be crucial in athlete selection, performance assessment, strategy planning, and training optimization. Artificial intelligence, with its strong cognitive abilities, learning capacity, large-scale data processing, and adaptability, can effectively enhance efficiency, reduce errors, and lower costs. The integration of advanced materials and artificial intelligence (AI) has significantly enhanced the efficiency and precision of research and development in sports-related technologies, while also facilitating the innovation of training methodologies through intelligent data analytics. This convergence has initiated a transformative phase in the digitalization of the sports industry. Anchored in both theoretical analysis and practical implementation, this study seeks to construct a systematic cognitive framework that elucidates the interrelationship between material science and AI technologies. The aim is to assist sports professionals in understanding and leveraging this technological shift to support strategic decision-making and to foster sustainable, high-quality development within the field.</description>
      <author>Fang Wang, Shenhao Jiang, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app15105667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting oxygen evolution in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis: controlling the oxidation state of electrochemically fabricated iridium&#8211;cobalt oxide catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.05.012</link>
      <description>Kyeong&#8208;Rim Yeo, Hoyoung Kim, Liangliang Xu, Seongbeen Kim, Jong Hyun Jang, Jinwoo Lee, Soo&#8208;Kil Kim, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410494952

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kyeong&#8208;Rim Yeo, Hoyoung Kim, Liangliang Xu, Seongbeen Kim, Jong Hyun Jang, Jinwoo Lee, Soo&#8208;Kil Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.05.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pathways for martensitic high-pressure phase transitions in bismuth</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.174111</link>
      <description>Tim Schaffrinna, Christopher Schr&#246;ck, Victor Milman, B. Winkler, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410496344

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tim Schaffrinna, Christopher Schr&#246;ck, Victor Milman, B. Winkler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.174111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited Co Crystalline Islands Shelled with Facile Spontaneously Deposited Pt for Improved Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15050490</link>
      <description>Jelena Golubovi&#263;, Lazar Rako&#269;evi&#263;, Vladimir Raji&#263;, Milo&#353; Milovi&#263;, Svetlana &#352;trbac, Catalysts. 15(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410500418

                The cobalt crystalline islands (Cocryst) were electrochemically deposited onto a glassy carbon (GC) support and then modified by a facile spontaneous deposition of platinum. The electrocatalytic activity of the resulting Cocryst-Pt core-shell catalyst was evaluated for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in an alkaline medium. The XRD characterization of the Cocryst-Pt islands revealed that the cobalt core had a hexagonal close-packed (hcp) crystalline structure, and that the platinum shell exhibited a crystalline structure with a preferential (111) orientation. SEM images showed that the average lateral size of the Cocryst islands was 1.17 &#956;m, which increased to 1.32 &#956;m after adding platinum. The XPS analysis indicated that the outer layer of the bulk metallic Cocryst islands was fully oxidized. During the spontaneous deposition of platinum, the outer Co(OH)2 layer was dissolved, leaving the cobalt core in a metallic state, while the platinum shell remained only partially oxidized. The high electrochemically active surface area of the Cocryst-Pt/GC electrode, along with a suitable crystalline structure of the Cocryst-Pt islands, contributes to enhancing its ORR activity by providing a greater number of surface active sites for oxygen adsorption and subsequent reduction. The ORR on the Cocryst-Pt catalyst occurs via a four-electron reaction pathway, with onset and half-wave potentials of 1.07 V and 0.87 V, respectively, which exceed those of polycrystalline platinum and a commercial benchmark Pt/C.</description>
      <author>Jelena Golubovi&#263;, Lazar Rako&#269;evi&#263;, Vladimir Raji&#263;, Milo&#353; Milovi&#263;, Svetlana &#352;trbac</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15050490</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterostructure of Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Confined in Hierarchical Porous Carbon for Interface&#8208;Enhanced Medical&#8208;Grade H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202502388</link>
      <description>Yanan Shi, Lili Zhang, Chongyang Wang, Shaohui Sun, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410502703

                Abstract The electrocatalytic two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e &#8722; ORR) presents an environmentally sustainable approach to produce hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ). Heterostructures coupling non&#8208;noble transition metal oxides (TMOs) with carbon materials hold promise for 2e &#8722; ORR, but face challenges in controlling morphology, phase composition, and active centers. In this study, a hierarchically porous tremella&#8208;like heterojunction characterized by ultrafine cubic Fe 3 O 4 nanoparticles within the amorphous carbon (UFe 3 O 4 @HPAC) is obtained using the integrated platform of green Fe&#8208;based deep eutectic solvent via a two&#8208;step annealing process. UFe 3 O 4 @HPAC exhibits remarkable overall and intrinsic 2e &#8722; ORR activity, delivering 96% H 2 O 2 selectivity and a turnover frequency (TOF) of 67.5 s &#8722;1 . Notably, UFe 3 O 4 @HPAC possesses superior H 2 O 2 production capabilities, showing long&#8208;term stability of 100 h with a H 2 O 2 production rate of 8.1 g L &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 in flow&#8208;cell, while achieving various medical&#8208;grade H 2 O 2 concentrations (3.0&#8211;7.8 wt%). Additionally, integrating on&#8208;site H 2 O 2 production with electro&#8208;Fenton achieved rapid decomposition of contaminants. The unique heterostructure, with the synergistic effect of Fe 3 O 4 and amorphous carbon, enhances electronic conductivity. Moreover, the electronic redistribution at the interface of the heterostructure triggers the thermodynamically favorable multiple active sites of Fe and C centers for the 2e &#8722; ORR. This work offers a new perspective on transition metal&#8208;based materials for H 2 O 2 production.</description>
      <author>Yanan Shi, Lili Zhang, Chongyang Wang, Shaohui Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202502388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Optimization of Interfacial Water Dissociation and Hydroxyl Reductive Desorption of MoCoNi&#8208;Based Catalysts for Superior Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503278</link>
      <description>C.R. Yang, Serhii Makovetskyi, Yanqing Yang, I. J. Hsu, S. Jean Hsieh, Yao&#8208;Chang Lee, Shu&#8208;Chih Haw, Fu&#8208;Te Tsai, Wen&#8208;Feng Liaw, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410506692

                Abstract Nano&#8208;heterointerface serves as a catalytic center for water dissociation promoted by the concerted interaction of *OH on oxide and *H on nitride. Kinetic energetics of water dissociation and hydroxyl (de)stabilization are vital to surface coverage of reactive *H and surface charge for *OH reductive desorption. electron paramagnetic resonance spectra of DMPO&#8208;H and DMPO&#8208;OH unravel radical nature of water&#8208;dissociated *H and *OH. coherent synergism of interfacial ensemble and electronic effects realizes TOF/&#951;&#8722;&#603; d volcano as the net result of work&#8208;function&#8208;directed competition between interfacial water dissociation (covalent control) and *OH reductive desorption (ionic control) kinetics, manifesting that alkaline HER volcano shaped by d&#8208;band descriptor originates from intricate balance guided by work function descriptor. Orchestrated with alkali metal cations on fine&#8208;tuning covalent/ionic interaction between catalyst surface and water&#8208;derived intermediates, microrod&#8208;array N&#8211;MoCoNiAl/NF electrode (NF&#9552;Ni foam) drives 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at overpotential of 10 mV in 1 m KOH. The proposed pathway may provide insight into how the peculiar electronic structure of multi&#8208;site heterojunction and the interfacial hard&#8208;soft covalent/electrostatic interactions impact molecular&#8208;level mechanism for efficient Volmer kinetics.</description>
      <author>C.R. Yang, Serhii Makovetskyi, Yanqing Yang, I. J. Hsu, S. Jean Hsieh, Yao&#8208;Chang Lee, Shu&#8208;Chih Haw, Fu&#8208;Te Tsai, Wen&#8208;Feng Liaw</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of gas purity in catalytic ammonia synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116223</link>
      <description>Simon I. Hansen, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Tejs Vegge, Anker Degn Jensen, Jakob Munkholt Christensen, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410511974

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Simon I. Hansen, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Tejs Vegge, Anker Degn Jensen, Jakob Munkholt Christensen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Design of Cage-like Borophene Single Atom Catalyst for High Efficiency CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c02327</link>
      <description>Meiling Liu, Fu Rao, Chenggong He, Tao Xu, Chao Liu, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410518950

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meiling Liu, Fu Rao, Chenggong He, Tao Xu, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c02327</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissolved Fe species enable a cooperative solid&#8211;molecular mechanism for the oxygen evolution reaction on NiFe-based catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01342-5</link>
      <description>Chunguang Kuai, Liping Liu, Anyang Hu, Yan Zhang, Yuxin Zhang, Dawei Xia, Dennis Nordlund, Dimosthenis Sokaras, Donato Decarolis, Diego Gianolio, Hongliang Xin, Luxi Li, Feng Lin, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410521350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunguang Kuai, Liping Liu, Anyang Hu, Yan Zhang, Yuxin Zhang, Dawei Xia, Dennis Nordlund, Dimosthenis Sokaras, Donato Decarolis, Diego Gianolio, Hongliang Xin, Luxi Li, Feng Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01342-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functionalization of organic amine promoted clay-based solid amine sorbents for efficient and sustainable CO2 capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.133658</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Li, Yanrong Zhao, Haiyang Xue, Chenyu Wang, Zheng Zhou, Kang Peng, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410529814

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Li, Yanrong Zhao, Haiyang Xue, Chenyu Wang, Zheng Zhou, Kang Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.133658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Criteria for Single-Phase Non-Equiatomic Refractory High Entropy Alloys from the Nb-Ti-Zr System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5257209</link>
      <description>Sebastian Lech, Jason Hattrick&#8208;Simpers, Elaf Anber, Michael J. Waters, Howard Joress, Debashish Sur, Emily F. Holcombe, James M. Rondinelli, John R. Scully, Mitra L. Taheri, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410534150

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sebastian Lech, Jason Hattrick&#8208;Simpers, Elaf Anber, Michael J. Waters, Howard Joress, Debashish Sur, Emily F. Holcombe, James M. Rondinelli, John R. Scully, Mitra L. Taheri</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5257209</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triazolotriazine-based carbon nitride framework for hydrogen peroxide photoproduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43246-025-00827-x</link>
      <description>Peng Shang, Xinbo Yang, Xiangbin Zou, Yuchuan Li, Siping Pang, Communications Materials. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410541471

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Shang, Xinbo Yang, Xiangbin Zou, Yuchuan Li, Siping Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43246-025-00827-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability of Single-Atom Centers of MXenes under Anodic Polarization Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01252</link>
      <description>Ling Meng, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, Kai S. Exner, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410543265

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Meng, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01252</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening single/dual-atom oxidation of ammonia electrocatalysts on sulfur functionalized MXene: A first-principles approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.178</link>
      <description>Hengquan Guo, Sung Gu Kang, Seung Geol Lee, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 138(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410544807

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hengquan Guo, Sung Gu Kang, Seung Geol Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Ferroelectricity in 2D Materials: Intralayer and Interlayer Engineering for Enhanced Photocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500284</link>
      <description>Tianqi Zhang, Zhipeng Yu, Jo&#227;o Paulo Cunha, Najeeb ur Rehman Lashari, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Zhaohui Hou, Hong Yin, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410547823

                Abstract Ferroelectric materials exhibit inherent polarization characteristics that render them viable options for improving photocatalytic performance via efficient charge carrier separation. Nonetheless, the majority of two dimensional (2D) materials exhibit an absence of ferroelectric properties owing to their elevated symmetry, which presents obstacles for their utilization in photocatalysis. This study presents two novel strategies for inducing ferroelectricity in 2D materials: intralayer polarization, accomplished by substituting phosphorus atoms in black phosphorus (BP) with elements like nitrogen (N), arsenic (As), or antimony (Sb); and interlayer polarization, realized through a controlled heterostructure design. Density functional theory (DFT) simulations indicate that these tailored materials demonstrate markedly diminished overpotentials for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), with values as low as 1.04 and 1.12 eV, respectively. The materials exhibit competitive Gibbs free energy profiles for the hydrogen evolution process (HER), highlighting their adaptability. The findings provide a framework for utilizing intralayer and interlayer engineering to improve the ferroelectric characteristics of 2D materials, facilitating advanced applications in photocatalysis and renewable energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Tianqi Zhang, Zhipeng Yu, Jo&#227;o Paulo Cunha, Najeeb ur Rehman Lashari, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Zhaohui Hou, Hong Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500284</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Joint Contribution of Potential and Water Molecules to the High CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR Activity of a Single Nickel Atom Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01569</link>
      <description>Siyuan Liu, Zengxuan Chen, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Yiqun Lisa Yin, Huashuo Zhang, Zhaojie Wang, Shuxian Wei, Weifeng Lyu, Xiaoqing L&#252;, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410551641

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siyuan Liu, Zengxuan Chen, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Yiqun Lisa Yin, Huashuo Zhang, Zhaojie Wang, Shuxian Wei, Weifeng Lyu, Xiaoqing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01569</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep CO2 Photoreduction by synergy of K+ doping and defective modulation over TiO2@K2Ti6O13 nanoribbon heterojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117221</link>
      <description>Leiping Wang, Shuai Liu, Zun Man, Xiaorong Dai, Guangsuo Yu, Honglei Zhang, Hang Xiao, Yang Meng, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410553633

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leiping Wang, Shuai Liu, Zun Man, Xiaorong Dai, Guangsuo Yu, Honglei Zhang, Hang Xiao, Yang Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complex Iridate Solid Solutions for Catalyzing Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Comparison of Elemental Leaching and Stability Numbers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00380</link>
      <description>Ki Hyun Park, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Jun Seop Kim, S.-H. Lee, Dongho Kim, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410449369

                As predicted by the Hume-Rothery rules, forming solid solutions of rutile IrO2 with other metal oxides that have different crystal structures is thermodynamically challenging. Consequently, achieving high solubility of foreign elements in Ir-based solid-solution oxides has been significantly limited. We demonstrate that hexagonal-perovskite BaIrO3 can serve as a flexible matrix oxide capable of incorporating a wide spectrum of (post)transition-metal cations with different electronic structures, ranging from d0 to d10 configurations. Among 12 cation solutes, Ta5+, Nb5+, and Zr4+ are found to be stable without substantial leaching during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under acidic condition. Acceptor-type trivalent cations, including Sc3+, In3+, and Fe3+, are identified to leach out gradually from the particle surface while enhancing the OER catalytic activity. Both X-ray absorption spectroscopy and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations consistently show that the robust face-sharing [IrO6] octahedral framework of the solid solutions remains unperturbed unless electrochemical leaching rapidly occurs. As a result, notably high S-numbers, on the order of 106, are achievable at pH = 1. Although our work focuses on single-element incorporation, it is suggested that the solid-solution methodology is an effective strategy for developing stable, long-lasting OER catalysts with further reduced Ir usage for acidic water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Ki Hyun Park, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Jun Seop Kim, S.-H. Lee, Dongho Kim, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing an Unobservable Fe(III)/Fe(IV) Redox Process of the Nonheme Iron N4Py Complex by High-Speed Surface-Enhanced Raman Spectroelectrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01017</link>
      <description>C. Maurits de Roo, W. J. Niels Klement, Dani&#235;l R. Duijnstee, Aleksandar Staykov, Wesley R. Browne, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410510880

                High-valent iron oxido species, central to many enzymatic and biomimetic catalyzed organic oxidative transformations, can be generated by direct electrochemical oxidation, circumventing high-energy O atom donor reagents. Electrochemical generation necessitates knowledge of the redox potentials involved, which is hindered by the lack of well-defined Fe(III)/Fe(IV) redox waves in the voltammetry of many iron-based catalysts. Hence, other approaches including chemical oxidation and bulk spectro(electro)chemical methods need to be taken. In the case of the well-studied oxidation catalyst, [(N4Py)Fe(II)OH2]2+, where N4Py is 1,1-bis(pyridin-2-yl)-N,N-bis(pyridin-2-ylmethyl)methanamine, estimates of the Fe(III/IV) redox potentials range from 0.4 to 1.3 V vs SCE. Here, we show that electrochemical surface-enhanced Raman scattering spectroscopy reveals "hidden" redox waves, and hence redox potentials, when coupled with cyclic voltammetry. Rapid spectral acquisition (&gt;2 Hz) of surface-enhanced Raman spectra at electrochemically roughened gold electrodes enables real-time spectral acquisition during cyclic voltammetry. We show that the Fe(III)/Fe(IV) redox potential of [(N4Py)Fe(II)OH2]2+ is close to that determined earlier by chemical redox titrations (0.85 V vs SCE). Furthermore, comproportionation and adsorption processes are shown to impact the rates of electron transfer observed, which rationalizes the absence of a distinct Fe(III)/Fe(IV) redox wave in its cyclic voltammetry.</description>
      <author>C. Maurits de Roo, W. J. Niels Klement, Dani&#235;l R. Duijnstee, Aleksandar Staykov, Wesley R. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the generality of a preferred orientation at interfaces of crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtadv.2025.100580</link>
      <description>Catherine Zhou, Gregory S. Rohrer, A. Salvador, Materials Today Advances. 26(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410523412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Catherine Zhou, Gregory S. Rohrer, A. Salvador</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtadv.2025.100580</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
