<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 01:19:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Microwave&#8208;assisted control of Pt&#63743;Ni nanoalloy clusters on the nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene oxide for energy conversion with oxygen reduction reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12499</link>
      <description>Seung Geun Jo, Gil&#8208;Ryeong Park, Jemin Kim, D. Ahn, Rahul Ramkumar, Sun&#8208;I Kim, Duck Hyun Lee, Jung Woo Lee, EcoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403822209

                Abstract Research on the production and utilization of hydrogen energy is essential to overcome the environmental issues caused by fossil fuels. Herein, we anchor Pt&#63743;Ni nanoalloy clusters (Pt&#8208;Ni NACs) on nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene oxide (NrGO) by a facile microwave&#8208;assisted synthesis and analyze the variations of catalyst properties based on the Pt&#63743;Ni composition and the presence of nitrogen. Ni inclusion in the Pt matrix can induce lattice strain and change the electronic structure, while the doped nitrogen into the graphene can enhance electron transfer and improve the durability of the catalyst through strong chemical bonding with the alloy clusters. TEM analysis discovers that the NACs are uniformly decorated in a few&#8208;nanometer&#8208;size on the graphene surface, and the formation of the Pt&#63743;Ni NACs and structural changes according to composition are confirmed through XRD and XPS. In addition, the structural changes due to N&#8208;doping and its bonding with the NACs are observed through Raman spectroscopy and XPS. Electrochemical measurements reveal that Pt 2.6 Ni NACs/NrGO exhibits the highest ORR onset potential (0.893 V) and the lowest HER overpotential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 (22 mV) among other catalysts, and those activities are almost unchanged under long&#8208;term durability tests. From these results, Pt 2.6 Ni NACs/NrGO is utilized in a zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB) system, demonstrating better battery performance than commercial Pt and Ir&#8208;based catalysts. Moreover, it is applied to hydrogen collection, showing linear trend in hydrogen production over time, confirming the catalyst's availability in hydrogen production and utilization. image</description>
      <author>Seung Geun Jo, Gil&#8208;Ryeong Park, Jemin Kim, D. Ahn, Rahul Ramkumar, Sun&#8208;I Kim, Duck Hyun Lee, Jung Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbe-electrode interactions on biocathodes are facilitated through tip-enhanced electric fields during CO2-fed microbial electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102262</link>
      <description>Ning Xue, Limin Liu, Richen Lin, Richard O&#8217;Shea, Chen Deng, Xiaoxu Xuan, Rongxin Xia, David Wall, Jerry D. Murphy, Cell Reports Physical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403825161

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Xue, Limin Liu, Richen Lin, Richard O&#8217;Shea, Chen Deng, Xiaoxu Xuan, Rongxin Xia, David Wall, Jerry D. Murphy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Swiss Army Knife of Electrodes: Pillar[6]arene&#8208;Modified Electrodes for Molecular Electrocatalysis Over a Wide pH Range</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413144</link>
      <description>Helena Roithmeyer, Jan B&#252;hler, Olivier Blacque, Isik Tuncay, Thomas Moehl, Cristiano Invernizzi, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, S. David Tilley, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403848771

                Abstract Molecularly&#8208;modified electrode materials that maintain stability over a broad pH range are rare. Typically, each electrochemical transformation necessitates a specifically tuned system to achieve strong binding and high activity of the catalyst. Here, we report the functionalisation of mesoporous indium tin oxide (mITO) electrodes with the macrocyclic host molecule pillar[6]arene (PA[6]). These electrodes are stable within the pH range of 2.4&#8211;10.8 and can be equipped with electrochemically active ruthenium complexes through host&#8211;guest interactions to perform various oxidation reactions. Benzyl alcohol oxidation serves as a model reaction in acidic media, while ammonia oxidation is conducted to assess the systems performance under basic conditions. PA[6]&#8208;modified electrodes demonstrate catalytic activity for both reactions when complexed to different guest molecules and can be reused by reabsorption of the catalyst after its degradation. Furthermore, the system can be employed to perform subsequent reactions in electrolyte with varying pH, enabling the same electrode to be utilised in multiple different electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Helena Roithmeyer, Jan B&#252;hler, Olivier Blacque, Isik Tuncay, Thomas Moehl, Cristiano Invernizzi, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, S. David Tilley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Swiss Army Knife of Electrodes: Pillar[6]arene&#8208;Modified Electrodes for Molecular Electrocatalysis Over a Wide pH Range</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413144</link>
      <description>Helena Roithmeyer, Jan B&#252;hler, Olivier Blacque, Isik Tuncay, Thomas Moehl, Cristiano Invernizzi, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, S. David Tilley, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403848972

                Abstract Molecularly&#8208;modified electrode materials that maintain stability over a broad pH range are rare. Typically, each electrochemical transformation necessitates a specifically tuned system to achieve strong binding and high activity of the catalyst. Here, we report the functionalisation of mesoporous indium tin oxide (mITO) electrodes with the macrocyclic host molecule pillar[6]arene (PA[6]). These electrodes are stable within the pH range of 2.4&#8211;10.8 and can be equipped with electrochemically active ruthenium complexes through host&#8211;guest interactions to perform various oxidation reactions. Benzyl alcohol oxidation serves as a model reaction in acidic media, while ammonia oxidation is conducted to assess the systems performance under basic conditions. PA[6]&#8208;modified electrodes demonstrate catalytic activity for both reactions when complexed to different guest molecules and can be reused by reabsorption of the catalyst after its degradation. Furthermore, the system can be employed to perform subsequent reactions in electrolyte with varying pH, enabling the same electrode to be utilised in multiple different electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Helena Roithmeyer, Jan B&#252;hler, Olivier Blacque, Isik Tuncay, Thomas Moehl, Cristiano Invernizzi, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, S. David Tilley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Ingredients for the Modeling of Single&#8208;Atom Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400476</link>
      <description>Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403849366

                Abstract Single&#8208;atom catalysis is gaining interest also because of its potential applications in a broad spectrum of electrochemical reactions. The reactivity of single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) is typically modeled with first principles approaches taking insight from heterogenous catalysis. An increasing number of studies show that the chemistry of SACs is more complex than often assumed, and shares many aspects in common with coordination chemistry. This evidence raises challenges for computational electrocatalysis of SACs. In this perspective we highlight a few fundamental ingredients that one need to consider to provide reliable predictions on the reactivity of SACs for electrochemical applications. We discuss the role of the local coordination of the metal active phase, the need to use self&#8208;interaction corrected functionals, in particular when systems have magnetic ground states. We highlight the formation of unconventional intermediates with respect to classical metal electrodes, the need to include the stability of SACs in electrochemical conditions and the role of solvation in the analysis of new potential catalytic systems. This brief account can be considered as a tutorial underlining the importance of treating the reactivity of SACs. In fact, neglecting some of these aspects could lead to unreliable predictions failing in the design of new electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective and durable H2O2 electrosynthesis catalyst in acid by selenization induced straining and phasing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53607-5</link>
      <description>Zhiyong Yu, Hao Deng, Qing Yao, Liangqun Zhao, Fei Xue, Tianou He, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Xiaoqing Huang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403852415

                Developing efficient electrocatalysts for acidic electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) holds considerable significance, while the selectivity and stability of most materials are compromised under acidic conditions. Herein, we demonstrate that constructing amorphous platinum&#8211;selenium (Pt&#8211;Se) shells on crystalline Pt cores can manipulate the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) pathway to efficiently catalyze the electrosynthesis of H2O2 in acids. The Se2&#8210;Pt nanoparticles, with optimized shell thickness, exhibit over 95% selectivity for H2O2 production, while suppressing its decomposition. In flow cell reactor, Se2&#8210;Pt nanoparticles maintain current density of 250 mA cm&#8722;2 for 400 h, yielding a H2O2 concentration of 113.2 g L&#8722;1 with productivity of 4160.3 mmol gcat&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 for effective organic dye degradation. The constructed amorphous Pt&#8211;Se shell leads to desirable O2 adsorption mode for increased selectivity and induces strain for optimized OOH* binding, accelerating the reaction kinetics. This selenization approach is generalizable to other noble metals for tuning 2e&#8210; ORR pathway. Developing efficient catalysts for acidic electrosynthesis of H2O2 is desirable, while most materials are compromised in acidic conditions. Here, the authors report that constructing amorphous Pt&#8211;Se shells on crystalline Pt cores can regulate the reaction pathway to efficiently produce H2O2 in acid.</description>
      <author>Zhiyong Yu, Hao Deng, Qing Yao, Liangqun Zhao, Fei Xue, Tianou He, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Xiaoqing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53607-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double-Shell Confinement Strategy Enhancing Durability of PtFeTi Intermetallic Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04779</link>
      <description>Chen Sumin, Lai-Ke Chen, Na Tian, Sheng-Nan Hu, Shuangli Yang, Jun&#8208;Fei Shen, Jing-Xiao Tang, De&#8208;Yin Wu, Mingshu Chen, Zhi&#8208;You Zhou, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403869883

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen Sumin, Lai-Ke Chen, Na Tian, Sheng-Nan Hu, Shuangli Yang, Jun&#8208;Fei Shen, Jing-Xiao Tang, De&#8208;Yin Wu, Mingshu Chen, Zhi&#8208;You Zhou, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elastic constants from charge density distribution in FCC high-entropy alloys using CNN and DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229105</link>
      <description>Hossein Mirzaee, Ramin Soltanmohammadi, Nathan Linton, J. FISCHER, Serveh Kamrava, Pejman Tahmasebi, Dilpuneet S. Aidhy, APL Machine Learning. 2(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403871417

                While high-entropy alloys (HEAs) present exponentially large compositional space for alloy design, they also create enormous computational challenges to trace the compositional space, especially for the inherently expensive density functional theory calculations (DFT). Recent works have integrated machine learning into DFT to overcome these challenges. However, often these models require an intensive search of appropriate physics-based descriptors. In this paper, we employ a 3D convolutional neural network over just one descriptor, i.e., the charge density derived from DFT, to simplify and bypass the hunt for the descriptors. We show that the elastic constants of face-centered cubic multi-elemental alloys in the Ni&#8211;Cu&#8211;Au&#8211;Pd&#8211;Pt system can be predicted from charge density. In addition, using our recent PREDICT approach, we show that the model can be trained only on the charge densities of simpler binary and ternary alloys to effectively predict elastic constants in complex multi-elemental alloys, thereby further enabling easier property-tracing in the large compositional space of HEAs.</description>
      <author>Hossein Mirzaee, Ramin Soltanmohammadi, Nathan Linton, J. FISCHER, Serveh Kamrava, Pejman Tahmasebi, Dilpuneet S. Aidhy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Formation of C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Products Steered by Bridge-Bonded *CO Confined by *OH Domains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08755</link>
      <description>Haibin Ma, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez-Al&#233;, Futian You, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z, Boon Siang Yeo, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403879378

                During the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) on copper catalysts, linear-bonded CO (*COL) is commonly regarded as the key intermediate for the CO-CO coupling step, which leads to the formation of multicarbon products. In this work, we unveil the significant role of bridge-bonded *CO (*COB) as an active species. By combining in situ Raman spectroscopy, gas and liquid chromatography, and density functional theory (DFT) simulations, we show that adsorbed *OH domains displace *COL to *COB. The electroreduction of a 12CO+13CO2 cofeed demonstrates that *COB distinctly favors the production of acetate and 1-propanol, while *COL favors ethylene and ethanol formation. This work enhances our understanding of the mechanistic intricacies of eCO(2)RR and suggests new directions for designing operational conditions by modifying the competitive adsorption of surface species, thereby steering the reaction toward specific multicarbon products.</description>
      <author>Haibin Ma, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez-Al&#233;, Futian You, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z, Boon Siang Yeo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and compositional optimization of bimetallic NiCo alloy nanoparticles for promotion of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235641</link>
      <description>Bishnupad Mohanty, Lingaraj Pradhan, Biswarup Satpati, Parasmani Rajput, Mahdi Ghorbani&#8208;Asl, Yidan Wei, Prashanth W. Menezes, Arkady V. Krasheninnikov, Bikash Kumar Jena, Journal of Power Sources. 625(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885372

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bishnupad Mohanty, Lingaraj Pradhan, Biswarup Satpati, Parasmani Rajput, Mahdi Ghorbani&#8208;Asl, Yidan Wei, Prashanth W. Menezes, Arkady V. Krasheninnikov, Bikash Kumar Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the limitations of layered LiNiO2: Insights from DFT simulations on its viability as a cathode material for aqueous Lithium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235650</link>
      <description>Gibu George, Artur Brotons&#8208;Rufes, Albert Poater, Miquel Sol&#224;, Sergio Posada&#8208;P&#233;rez, Journal of Power Sources. 625(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885407

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gibu George, Artur Brotons&#8208;Rufes, Albert Poater, Miquel Sol&#224;, Sergio Posada&#8208;P&#233;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated water dissociation kinetics by nickel-nickelous hydroxide epitaxial interfaces for superior alkaline hydrogen generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.141</link>
      <description>Ya-Fei Cheng, Yanlong Li, Zhenyu Qiao, Lulu Hu, Hongbo Geng, Huilong Dong, Fan Liao, Mingwang Shao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885965

                The intrinsic performance of an electrocatalyst can be reinforced by constructing appropriate epitaxial interfaces, where the modulated electronic states and adsorption/desorption behaviors are conductive to enhancing electrocatalytic activity. Herein, nickel-nickelous hydroxide epitaxial interface supported on nickel foam (Ni-Ni(OH)</description>
      <author>Ya-Fei Cheng, Yanlong Li, Zhenyu Qiao, Lulu Hu, Hongbo Geng, Huilong Dong, Fan Liao, Mingwang Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-space visualization of atomic displacements in a long-wavelength charge density wave using cryogenic 4D-STEM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.104414</link>
      <description>Haoyang Ni, William R. Meier, H. Miao, Andrew F. May, B. C. Sales, Jian&#8208;Min Zuo, Miaofang Chi, Physical Review Materials. 8(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403888133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoyang Ni, William R. Meier, H. Miao, Andrew F. May, B. C. Sales, Jian&#8208;Min Zuo, Miaofang Chi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.104414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid confinement of Pt-Ni-Co spherical core-shells in multibranched nano-dendrites interspersed on N-doped aerogels for enhanced ORR performance and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177307</link>
      <description>Muhammad Umair Mushtaq, Danni Li, Xiang Shao, Khurram Shahzad Ayub, Ali Shan, Limei Cao, Ji Yang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403898069

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Umair Mushtaq, Danni Li, Xiang Shao, Khurram Shahzad Ayub, Ali Shan, Limei Cao, Ji Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electrochemical Synthesis of Urea on Triatomic Cluster/Cu Catalysts: A Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105349</link>
      <description>Qiang Liu, Jingnan Wang, Yongan Yang, Xi Wang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403902171

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiang Liu, Jingnan Wang, Yongan Yang, Xi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional SnS2/ZrSi2N4 van der Waals heterojunction as a spontaneously enhanced hydrogen evolution photocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110816</link>
      <description>Ying Hu, Feilong Xiong, Chaoyi Xin, Sheng Wang, Zhengquan Li, Kai-Wu Luo, Kejun Dong, Liang Xu, Materials Today Communications. 41(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403904649

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Hu, Feilong Xiong, Chaoyi Xin, Sheng Wang, Zhengquan Li, Kai-Wu Luo, Kejun Dong, Liang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enumeration of surface site nuclearity and shape in a database of intermetallic low-index surface facets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115795</link>
      <description>Unnatti Sharma, A.L. Nguyen, John R. Kitchin, Zachary W. Ulissi, Michael J. Janik, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403909596

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Unnatti Sharma, A.L. Nguyen, John R. Kitchin, Zachary W. Ulissi, Michael J. Janik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of TM-based dual-atom catalysts supported by B,N-doped biphenylene for carbon dioxide reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161651</link>
      <description>Maryam Fallahzadeh, Alireza Kokabi, Zahra Nasiri, Mina Fayazi, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403909620

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maryam Fallahzadeh, Alireza Kokabi, Zahra Nasiri, Mina Fayazi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcycling of waste polyethylene terephthalate (PET) into CoFe@C for highly efficient PV-driven bifunctional seawater splitting via a &#8220;waste materialization&#8221; strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124756</link>
      <description>Qingsong Jiang, Zhijie Chen, Mi Bai, Shan Liu, Xiang-Yang Lou, Wei Ma, Yangzi Shangguan, Xiaosong Gu, Qiang Zeng, Songhe Yang, Lei Zhu, Hong Chen, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. 362(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403912592

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingsong Jiang, Zhijie Chen, Mi Bai, Shan Liu, Xiang-Yang Lou, Wei Ma, Yangzi Shangguan, Xiaosong Gu, Qiang Zeng, Songhe Yang, Lei Zhu, Hong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guinier&#8211;Preston Zones Featuring PtCu Nanocrystals: Coherency Strain Fields Reshaping the Band Structure for Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01485</link>
      <description>Zhiguo Chen, Jingkun Chen, Jingbo Fu, Qiheng Wang, Yonghong Chen, Jingjun Liu, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403913810

                Microstructurally distorted Pt-based nanoalloys with unusual structural defects like Guinier&#8211;Preston (GP) zones with in situ coherency strain fields may be suitable for substantially improving their electrocatalytic performance for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in acidic conditions. Herein, GP zones contributing PtCu nanoalloys were first fabricated by additive manufacturing, starting with the formation of metallic Cu clusters as orderly crystal nuclei on ZIF-8-derived carbon, followed by the additive manufacturing of chemically reduced Pt and Cu on the formed clusters in ethylene glycol at 190 &#176;C. The atomic-scale GP zones give rise to high-level coherent strain fields across the nanocrystals, boosting the ORR kinetics. This catalyst exhibits an ultrahigh oxygen reduction half-wave potential of 0.934 V (vs RHE) and a mass activity (MA) of 0.68 A mgPt&#8211;1. After the accelerated degradation test of 50,000 cycles, the achieved MA improved instead of decreasing, rising from 0.68 to 0.89 A mgPt&#8211;1, surpassing that of commercial Pt/C significantly. The significantly improved activity is attributed to the coherency strain fields reshaping the band structure and reconstructing a favorable charge density for active Pt sites. Importantly, the interface-anchored GP zones, maintaining a completely coherent relationship with the matrix, can effectively impede metal atom migration, segregation, or leaching, thus enhancing long-term stability. Therefore, the novel GP-type alloys may pave another way for designing advanced catalysts in the realm of current energy storage and conversion fields like fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Zhiguo Chen, Jingkun Chen, Jingbo Fu, Qiheng Wang, Yonghong Chen, Jingjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive theoretical study of the effects of facet, oxygen vacancies, and surface strain on iron and cobalt impurities in different surfaces of anatase TiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74423-3</link>
      <description>Danil W. Boukhvalov, V. Yu. Osipov, Anna Baldycheva, Benjamin T. Hogan, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403914609

                Abstract We report the results of systematic ab initio modelling of various configurations of iron and cobalt impurities embedded in the (110), (101), and (100) surfaces of anatase TiO 2 , with and without oxygen vacancies. The simulation results demonstrate that incorporation into interstitial voids at the surface level is significantly more favourable than other configurations for both iron and cobalt. The calculations also demonstrate the crucial effect of the facet as well as the lesser effects of other factors, such as vacancies and strain on the energetics of defect incorporation, magnetic moment, bandgap, and catalytic performance. It is further shown that there is no tendency towards the segregation or clustering of impurities on the surface. The calculated free energies of the hydrogen evolution reaction in acidic media predict that iron impurities embedded in the (101) surface of anatase TiO 2 can be a competitive catalyst for this reaction.</description>
      <author>Danil W. Boukhvalov, V. Yu. Osipov, Anna Baldycheva, Benjamin T. Hogan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74423-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-ray and Photoelectron Spectroscopy of Surface Chemistry; from Bonding via Femtosecond to Operando</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122637</link>
      <description>Anders Nilsson, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403916151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anders Nilsson</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focused Review on the Use of Bimetallic Alloy Nanoparticle Electrocatalysts in Water Splitting Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05903</link>
      <description>Ankur Kumar, Sasanka Deka, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403916783

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ankur Kumar, Sasanka Deka</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moir&#233; Patterns in Pt Overlayers on Gold: A Graph Neural Network Interatomic Potential Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04582</link>
      <description>Trenton J. Wolter, Evangelos Smith, Roberto Schimmenti, Jakob Schi&#248;tz, Karsten W. Jacobsen, Manos Mavrikakis, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403921754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Trenton J. Wolter, Evangelos Smith, Roberto Schimmenti, Jakob Schi&#248;tz, Karsten W. Jacobsen, Manos Mavrikakis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic and Structural Property Comparison of Iridium-Based OER Nanocatalysts Enabled by &lt;i&gt;Operando&lt;/i&gt; Ir L&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Edge X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03562</link>
      <description>Marianne van der Merwe, Romualdus Enggar Wibowo, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Carlos Escudero, Giovanni Agostini, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403922363

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marianne van der Merwe, Romualdus Enggar Wibowo, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Carlos Escudero, Giovanni Agostini, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Electrocatalyst for PEM Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-69051-8_3</link>
      <description>Mehmet Fatih Kaya, Murat K&#305;st&#305;, Bulut H&#252;ner, Emre &#214;zdo&#287;an, Marise Cona&#287;as&#305;, Muhammed Ali Durmaz, Eda Nur &#199;ak&#305;raslan, Tayyar E&#351;iyok, Yakup Og&#252;n S&#252;zen, Akif Ta&#351;k&#305;n, S&#252;leyman Uysal, Nesrin Dem&#239;r, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403923110

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mehmet Fatih Kaya, Murat K&#305;st&#305;, Bulut H&#252;ner, Emre &#214;zdo&#287;an, Marise Cona&#287;as&#305;, Muhammed Ali Durmaz, Eda Nur &#199;ak&#305;raslan, Tayyar E&#351;iyok, Yakup Og&#252;n S&#252;zen, Akif Ta&#351;k&#305;n, S&#252;leyman Uysal, Nesrin Dem&#239;r</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-69051-8_3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exact average many-body interatomic interaction model for random alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commt.2024.100018</link>
      <description>Max Hodapp, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403930872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Max Hodapp</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commt.2024.100018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of a CuCo dual-atom catalyst for nitrogen fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra06077f</link>
      <description>Miaomiao Han, Shouxin Zhang, Chenyu Zhang, RSC Advances. 14(47)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403940197

                The potential for N 2 fixation of the heteronuclear CuCo dual-atom catalyst (DAC) was investigated by DFT calculations.</description>
      <author>Miaomiao Han, Shouxin Zhang, Chenyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra06077f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling activity of transition metal single-atom sites on the graphene-like BC2P monolayer for oxygen evolution reaction: A density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114648</link>
      <description>Xi Fu, Jian Lin, Guangyao Liang, Wenhu Liao, Haixia Gao, Xiaowu Li, Liming Li, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403943389

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xi Fu, Jian Lin, Guangyao Liang, Wenhu Liao, Haixia Gao, Xiaowu Li, Liming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption of Imidazolium&#8208;Based Ionic Liquid On Pt(111) Surface Studied Using Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400458</link>
      <description>Arka Prava Sarkar, Sandeep K. Reddy, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403952421

                Abstract The strength and nature of adsorption of imidazolium&#8208;based tetraflouroborate ionic liquid (IL) on platinum surface has been investigated via first principle&#8208;based density functional theory method. Adsorption of both IL cation and IL ion&#8208;pair as a function of increasing alkyl chain length is taken into consideration. Three different orientations of ionic liquid cations are found to be stable with higher adsorption energy noticed for the alkyl chain parallel to the platinum surface. The anions are found to stabilize the IL cation orientation where the alkyl chain is oriented perpendicular the platinum surface. These results are further corroborated by the charge transfer analysis and electron density difference maps. The significant charge transfer between the ionic liquid pair and the surface indicates electrochemical applications for systems involving electrolytes and metal surface, where electrostatic interactions play a major role. The results of this investigation can be helpful for further analysis of electrode&#8211;electrolyte systems as well as the development of force field parameters for these systems.</description>
      <author>Arka Prava Sarkar, Sandeep K. Reddy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400458</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study on two-dimensional direct Z-scheme g-GeC/MoSe2 heterostructure for overall photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113496</link>
      <description>Yuxi Zhang, Peng Wang, Fangfang Li, Yiliang Cai, Computational Materials Science. 246(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403966198

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxi Zhang, Peng Wang, Fangfang Li, Yiliang Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous NiO nanopyramids with superior electrochromic energ-y storage properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.10.460</link>
      <description>Yingdi Shi, Yong Zhang, Yulei Zheng, Kai Tang, Xiang Ke, Zirong Li, Jing Tang, Zhenzhen Hui, Longqiang Ye, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403968719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingdi Shi, Yong Zhang, Yulei Zheng, Kai Tang, Xiang Ke, Zirong Li, Jing Tang, Zhenzhen Hui, Longqiang Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.10.460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-anchoring synthesis of Pt1Ni1@Pt/C core-shell catalysts for stable oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53808-y</link>
      <description>Jialin Cui, Di Zhang, Zhongliang Liu, Congcong Li, Tingting Zhang, Shixin Yin, Yiting Song, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Chunzhong Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403969270

                Proton-exchange-membrane fuel cells demand highly efficient catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction, and core-shell structures are known for maximizing precious metal utilization. Here, we reported a controllable "carbon defect anchoring" strategy to prepare Pt</description>
      <author>Jialin Cui, Di Zhang, Zhongliang Liu, Congcong Li, Tingting Zhang, Shixin Yin, Yiting Song, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53808-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambient-condition acetylene hydrogenation to ethylene over WS2-confined atomic Pd sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53481-1</link>
      <description>Wangwang Zhang, Kelechi Uwakwe, Jingting Hu, Wei Yan, Juntong Zhu, Wu Zhou, Chao Ma, Liang Yu, Rui Huang, Dehui Deng, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403969537

                Ambient-condition acetylene hydrogenation to ethylene (AC-AHE) is a promising process for ethylene production with minimal additional energy input, yet remains a great challenge due to the difficulty in the coactivation of acetylene and H</description>
      <author>Wangwang Zhang, Kelechi Uwakwe, Jingting Hu, Wei Yan, Juntong Zhu, Wu Zhou, Chao Ma, Liang Yu, Rui Huang, Dehui Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53481-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of strain, pH and oxygen-deficient on catalytic performance of Ruddlesden-Popper oxide Srn+1RunO3n+1 (n=1, 2) for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.405</link>
      <description>Jiahao Zhang, Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403971281

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahao Zhang, Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution enabled by porous Eu-Ni(PO3)2 nanosheet arrays</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.11.001</link>
      <description>Pu Wang, Xiangrui Wu, Meng Li, Xuan Wang, Huiyu Wang, Qiuzi Huang, Hao Li, Yawen Tang, Gengtao Fu, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403978086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pu Wang, Xiangrui Wu, Meng Li, Xuan Wang, Huiyu Wang, Qiuzi Huang, Hao Li, Yawen Tang, Gengtao Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.11.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution in proton exchange membrane electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24062-1.00002-4</link>
      <description>Williane da Silva Freitas, Barbara Mecheri, Alessandra D&#8217;Epifanio, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403978627

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Williane da Silva Freitas, Barbara Mecheri, Alessandra D&#8217;Epifanio</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24062-1.00002-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pH-Mediated Solution-Phase Proton Transfer Drives Enhanced Electrochemical Hydrogenation of Phenol in Alkaline Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04874</link>
      <description>Brianna Markunas, Taber Yim, Joshua Snyder, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403979659

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brianna Markunas, Taber Yim, Joshua Snyder</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overlooked Role of Electrostatic Interactions in HER Kinetics on MXenes: Beyond the Conventional Descriptor &#916;&lt;i&gt;G&lt;/i&gt; &#8764; 0 to Identify the Real Active Site</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02588</link>
      <description>Xiang Huang, Xiangting Hu, Jiong Wang, Hu Xu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403980675

                Understanding the atomic-level mechanism of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) on MXene materials is crucial for developing affordable HER catalysts, while their complex surface terminations present a substantial challenge. Herein, employing constant-potential grand canonical density functional theory calculations, we elucidate the reaction kinetics of the HER on MXenes with various surface terminations by taking experimentally reported Mo</description>
      <author>Xiang Huang, Xiangting Hu, Jiong Wang, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating nonmetal atom doping in two-dimensional VSe2 monolayers for hydrogen and oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232667</link>
      <description>Rabia Hassan, Fei Ma, Yan Li, Rehan Hassan, Muhammad Farhan Qadir, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403981233

                The electrocatalytic performance of VSe2 doped with nonmetals (NMs) was studied using density functional theory, in which NM atoms (C, N, O, P, S, F, Cl, Br, and I) replaced Se or V (denoted as NM@Se or NM@V). Notably, P@V and Br@V monolayers exhibit high catalytic hydrogen evolution reaction activity with the lowest &#916;GH* = 0.08 eV and &#8722;0.03 eV, respectively, surpassing Pt (&#916;GH* = &#8722;0.1 eV). By applying the scaling relationship of &#916;GH* of H*, which is an intermediate for each volcano, the exchange current density diagrams are established. Based on thermodynamic analysis, P@V and Br@V monolayers produce exchange currents of about &#8722;1.42 and &#8722;0.70i0/(A cm&#8722;2), respectively. The oxygen evolution reaction activity of the I@Se monolayer (&#951;OER = 0.95 V) is the best among all the monolayers. Among the oxygen reduction reaction catalysts, the O@Se monolayer displays high activity with a low &#951;ORR (0.82 V), which is even better than that of binary Pt and Pd alloys (0.9&#8211;0.87 V).</description>
      <author>Rabia Hassan, Fei Ma, Yan Li, Rehan Hassan, Muhammad Farhan Qadir</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced N-doping nickel-cobalt phosphides for boosting hydrogen evolution in acid and alkali media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.364</link>
      <description>Kai Liu, Zizai Ma, Zihao Wan, Xiaoguang Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403984177

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Liu, Zizai Ma, Zihao Wan, Xiaoguang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combining graph deep learning and London dispersion interatomic potentials: A case study on pnictogen chalcohalides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237101</link>
      <description>&#199;etin K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, S&#252;meyra G&#252;ler-K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403984284

                Machine-learning interatomic potential models based on graph neural network architectures have the potential to make atomistic materials modeling widely accessible due to their computational efficiency, scalability, and broad applicability. The training datasets for many such models are derived from density-functional theory calculations, typically using a semilocal exchange-correlation functional. As a result, long-range interactions such as London dispersion are often missing in these models. We investigate whether this missing component can be addressed by combining a graph deep learning potential with semiempirical dispersion models. We assess this combination by deriving the equations of state for layered pnictogen chalcohalides BiTeBr and BiTeI and performing crystal structure optimizations for a broader set of V&#8211;VI&#8211;VII compounds with various stoichiometries, many of which possess van der Waals gaps. We characterize the optimized crystal structures by calculating their x-ray diffraction patterns and radial distribution function histograms, which are also used to compute Earth mover&#8217;s distances to quantify the dissimilarity between the optimized and corresponding experimental structures. We find that dispersion-corrected graph deep learning potentials generally (though not universally) provide a more realistic description of these compounds due to the inclusion of van der Waals attractions. In particular, their use results in systematic improvements in predicting not only the van der Waals gap but also the layer thickness in layered V&#8211;VI&#8211;VII compounds. Our results demonstrate that the combined potentials studied here, derived from a straightforward approach that neither requires fine-tuning the training nor refitting the potential parameters, can significantly improve the description of layered polar crystals.</description>
      <author>&#199;etin K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, S&#252;meyra G&#252;ler-K&#305;l&#305;&#231;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-driven sewage sludge electroreforming coupled with biological funnelling to cogenerate green food and hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44221-024-00329-z</link>
      <description>Hu Zhao, Ziying Sun, Chenchen Li, Dan Wu, Li Quan Lee, Dan Lu, Yuanda Lv, Xi Jie Chu, Ying Li, Wenguang Tu, Ovi Lian Ding, Jin Zhou, Zhigang Zou, Yan Zhou, Hong Li, Nature Water. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403984378

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hu Zhao, Ziying Sun, Chenchen Li, Dan Wu, Li Quan Lee, Dan Lu, Yuanda Lv, Xi Jie Chu, Ying Li, Wenguang Tu, Ovi Lian Ding, Jin Zhou, Zhigang Zou, Yan Zhou, Hong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44221-024-00329-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Activity Trends in Electrochemical Dinitrogen Oxidation over Transition Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05036</link>
      <description>Samuel Olusegun, Yue Qi, Nishithan C. Kani, Meenesh R. Singh, Joseph A. Gauthier, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403985663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Samuel Olusegun, Yue Qi, Nishithan C. Kani, Meenesh R. Singh, Joseph A. Gauthier</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Active Sites on Pd/Pt Alloy Nanoparticles by CO Adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c08291</link>
      <description>Daniel Silvan Dolling, Jiachen Chen, Jan&#8208;Christian Schober, Marcus Creutzburg, Arno Jeromin, Vedran Vonk, Dmitry Sharapa, Thomas F. Keller, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Heshmat Noei, Andreas Stierle, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403996395

                We studied the adsorption of CO on Pd/Pt nanoparticles (NPs) with varying compositions using polarization-dependent Fourier transform infrared reflection absorption spectroscopy (FT-IRRAS) and theoretical calculations (DFT). We prepared PtPd alloy NPs via physical vapor codeposition on &#945;-Al</description>
      <author>Daniel Silvan Dolling, Jiachen Chen, Jan&#8208;Christian Schober, Marcus Creutzburg, Arno Jeromin, Vedran Vonk, Dmitry Sharapa, Thomas F. Keller, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Heshmat Noei, Andreas Stierle</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c08291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised representation learning of Kohn&#8211;Sham states and consequences for downstream predictions of many-body effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53748-7</link>
      <description>Bowen Hou, Jinyuan Wu, Diana Y. Qiu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403996728

                Representation learning for the electronic structure problem is a major challenge of machine learning in computational condensed matter and materials physics. Within quantum mechanical first principles approaches, density functional theory (DFT) is the preeminent tool for understanding electronic structure, and the high-dimensional DFT wavefunctions serve as building blocks for downstream calculations of correlated many-body excitations and related physical observables. Here, we use variational autoencoders (VAE) for the unsupervised learning of DFT wavefunctions and show that these wavefunctions lie in a low-dimensional manifold within latent space. Our model autonomously determines the optimal representation of the electronic structure, avoiding limitations due to manual feature engineering. To demonstrate the utility of the latent space representation of the DFT wavefunction, we use it for the supervised training of neural networks (NN) for downstream prediction of quasiparticle bandstructures within the GW formalism. The GW prediction achieves a low error of 0.11 eV for a combined test set of two-dimensional metals and semiconductors, suggesting that the latent space representation captures key physical information from the original data. Finally, we explore the generative ability and interpretability of the VAE representation.</description>
      <author>Bowen Hou, Jinyuan Wu, Diana Y. Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53748-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable photocatalytic hydrogen peroxide production over octonary high-entropy oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53896-w</link>
      <description>Hao Ling, Huacong Sun, Lisha Lu, Jingkun Zhang, Lei Liao, Jianlin Wang, Xiaowei Zhang, Yingying Lan, Renjie Li, Wengang Lu, Lejuan Cai, Xuedong Bai, Wenlong Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404010700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Ling, Huacong Sun, Lisha Lu, Jingkun Zhang, Lei Liao, Jianlin Wang, Xiaowei Zhang, Yingying Lan, Renjie Li, Wengang Lu, Lejuan Cai, Xuedong Bai, Wenlong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53896-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Study of Cl Adsorption on Pt(111) and Pt(100) using Ab Initio Grand-Canonical Monte Carlo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122647</link>
      <description>Eun Mi Kim, Junseok Kim, Kristen A. Fichthorn, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404011693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eun Mi Kim, Junseok Kim, Kristen A. Fichthorn</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122647</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing Key Process Design Considerations for Carbon Capture, Utilization and Storage (CCUS) Towards Decarbonization of Existing Assets Operations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221884-ms</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zakwan Mohd Sahak, Masniroszaime Md Zain, Azila Alias, Muhammad Yazid Bin Zulkifli, Sohrab Rohani, Khairul Rostani, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404014042

                Abstract With the net zero emission (NZE) commitment by 2050 following COP26 being pledged by country and industrial leaders, the technology focus for CCUS has shifted from high-CO2 gas field development to also include capturing CO2 from other industrial emission sources e.g. flaring and gas turbines. With the expanding scopes, careful consideration especially from process design perspective needs to be taken to ensure the overall CCUS conceptual design is techno-commercially feasible and viable to meet the CCUS end target and NZE aspiration in the long term. Process design intent shall start with the input-output specifications, where main input specifications would be looking at source or CCUS fluid (e.g. gas field/flare stack etc.) which will determine the type of CO2 capture technology required. Target output usage (storage/ utilization) will affect the tail-end process design, since both require different process setup. Other considerations would also be: (1) location (onshore vs offshore) which will affect the facilities network and logistics, (2) contaminants such as SOx and NOx which will determine other treatment requirements and affect the final use of the separated CO2-rich stream (utilization, storage strategy), and (3) material selection for the mixed contaminants stream. Depending on the concentration of CO2 in the source, a series of treatment steps may be required to get the optimum recovery for further utilization and storage. The presence of other contaminants is also discussed, which may affect the overall CCUS processes. Method to either utilize the separated CO2 stream or injection to reservoir for storage is also explored. An integrated approach is required to ensure a successful CCUS process design from start to end. Challenges and lesson-learnt from a conceptual CCUS system are analyzed including technology maturation, presence of other contaminants and final use of CO2-based products/storage. The technical and commercial aspects associated with each technology are also addressed. Key design elements are proposed with aspiration of a successful CCUS implementation in reducing future carbon footprint and realizing NZE aspiration and decarbonization goal, requiring planning for end-to-end solutions.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zakwan Mohd Sahak, Masniroszaime Md Zain, Azila Alias, Muhammad Yazid Bin Zulkifli, Sohrab Rohani, Khairul Rostani</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221884-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of graph neural network in computational heterogeneous catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0227821</link>
      <description>Zihao Jiao, Ya Liu, Ziyun Wang, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403984381

                Heterogeneous catalysis, as a key technology in modern chemical industries, plays a vital role in social progress and economic development. However, its complex reaction process poses challenges to theoretical research. Graph neural networks (GNNs) are gradually becoming a key tool in this field as they can intrinsically learn atomic representation and consider connection relationship, making them naturally applicable to atomic and molecular systems. This article introduces the basic principles, current network architectures, and datasets of GNNs and reviews the application of GNN in heterogeneous catalysis from accelerating the materials screening and exploring the potential energy surface. In the end, we summarize the main challenges and potential application prospects of GNNs in future research endeavors.</description>
      <author>Zihao Jiao, Ya Liu, Ziyun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0227821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward AI/ML-assisted discovery of transition metal complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.arcc.2024.10.003</link>
      <description>H.-Q. Jin, Kenneth M. Merz, Annual reports in computational chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403897047

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H.-Q. Jin, Kenneth M. Merz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.arcc.2024.10.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal reduction of CO2 captured by aqueous amine solutions into formate: comparison between in situ generated H2 and gaseous H2 as reductant and evaluation of amine stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100333</link>
      <description>Laura Quintana-G&#243;mez, Luama Ara&#250;jo dos Santos, Fernando Cossio-Cid, V&#237;ctor Ciordia-Asenjo, Miguel Almarza, Alberto Goikoechea, Sergio Ferrero, Celedonio M. &#193;lvarez, Jos&#233; J. Segovia, &#193;ngel Mart&#237;n, M. Dolores Bermejo, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403901788

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Laura Quintana-G&#243;mez, Luama Ara&#250;jo dos Santos, Fernando Cossio-Cid, V&#237;ctor Ciordia-Asenjo, Miguel Almarza, Alberto Goikoechea, Sergio Ferrero, Celedonio M. &#193;lvarez, Jos&#233; J. Segovia, &#193;ngel Mart&#237;n, M. Dolores Bermejo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of anion exchange membrane-based electrochemical CO2 separation cells for direct air capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.10.049</link>
      <description>Ji Eon Chae, Jiseon Choi, Dongkeun Lee, Sunyoup Lee, Seonyeob Kim, Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403905064

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ji Eon Chae, Jiseon Choi, Dongkeun Lee, Sunyoup Lee, Seonyeob Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.10.049</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
