<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 01:27:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Heusler-based topological quantum catalyst Fe2VAl with obstructed surface states for the hydrogen-evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.416773</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404802796

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.416773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Catalytic Activity of i-MXenes for CO2 Reduction Reaction by Ordered Metal Atomic Vacancies: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105535</link>
      <description>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404804106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and challenges in N2O valorization for alkane oxidative dehydrogenation to olefins</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gce.2024.11.005</link>
      <description>Y.M. Wu, Xuanhao Wu, Haiqiang Wang, Zhongbiao Wu, Green Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404812774

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y.M. Wu, Xuanhao Wu, Haiqiang Wang, Zhongbiao Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gce.2024.11.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Rhodium Doping for Photocatalytic Activity of Barium Titanate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.omx.2024.100382</link>
      <description>G. A. Kaptagay, B. M. Satanova, &#1040;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Marina Ko&#326;uhova, Zh.Ye. Zakiyeva, U. Zh. Tolegen, N. Koilyk, &#1060;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Optical Materials X. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404812888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. A. Kaptagay, B. M. Satanova, &#1040;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Marina Ko&#326;uhova, Zh.Ye. Zakiyeva, U. Zh. Tolegen, N. Koilyk, &#1060;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.omx.2024.100382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Open Phosphorized PtNi Nanohexapod/N&#8208;doped Graphene Aerogel for High&#8208;Performance Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404684</link>
      <description>Jing Yang, Jianlan Wang, Ren&#233; H&#252;bner, Xingyu Tao, Yansong Ren, Zhikun Zheng, Wei Liu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404818429

                Abstract Developing cost&#8208;effective, high&#8208;efficiency, and stable electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in alkaline electrolytes is of critical importance for realizing renewable hydrogen technologies. However, the sluggish HER kinetics and unsatisfied stability remain critical challenges for their practical applications. Herein, a hierarchically porous phosphorized Pt&#8208;Ni nanohexapod/N&#8208;doped graphene aerogel (P&#8208;PtNiNH/NGA) constructed by an oxidation&#8208;phosphorization&#8208;controlled reconfiguration strategy is presented. It enables fast water dissociation kinetics for an abundant supply of hydrogen ions, strong electron interaction for optimal intermediate adsorption, and an excellent anchoring effect of the NGA to avoid the aggregation and Ostwald ripening of the PtNiNHs, thus exhibiting superior activity and exceptional stability toward alkaline HER. The P&#8208;Pt 1 Ni 2 NH/NGA exhibits an ultralow overpotential of 15 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , a low Tafel slope of 37 mV dec &#8722;1 , and long&#8208;term stability, which are superior to commercial Pt/C. Moreover, the P&#8208;Pt 1 Ni 2 NH/NGA shows a high mass activity of 13.4 mA &#181;g &#8722;1 and a large TOF value of 13.5 s &#8722;1 at an overpotential of 100 mV, which are 8.8 times and 9.0 times higher than commercial Pt/C (under the same Pt loading of &#8776;9.1 &#181;g cm &#8722;2 ). This work is of high inspiration for catalyst design to obtain ideal alkaline HER performance.</description>
      <author>Jing Yang, Jianlan Wang, Ren&#233; H&#252;bner, Xingyu Tao, Yansong Ren, Zhikun Zheng, Wei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research advances of metal fluoride for energy conversion and storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.630</link>
      <description>Runlin Zhang, Zijin Xu, Zeyu Hao, Zeshuo Meng, Xiufeng Hao, Hongwei Tian, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404820291

                Abstract In recent years, renewable energy sources, which aim to replace rapidly depleting fossil fuels, face challenges due to limited energy storage and conversion technologies. To enhance energy storage and conversion efficiency, extensive research has been conducted in the academic community on numerous potential materials. Among these materials, metal fluorides have attracted significant attention due to their ionic metal&#8211;fluorine bonds and tunable electronic structures, attributed to the highest electronegativity of fluorine in their chemical composition. This makes them promising candidates for future electrochemical applications in various fields. However, metal fluorides encounter various challenges in different application directions. Therefore, we comprehensively review the applications of metal fluorides in the field of energy storage and conversion, aiming to deepen our understanding of their exhibited characteristics in different electrochemical processes. In this paper, we summarize the difficulties and improvement methods encountered in different types of battery applications and several typical electrode optimization strategies in the field of supercapacitors. In the field of water electrolysis, we focus on surface reconstruction and the critical role of fluorine, demonstrating the catalytic performance of metal fluorides from the perspectives of reconstruction mechanism and process analysis. Finally, we provide a summary and outlook for this field, aiming to offer guidance for future breakthroughs in the energy storage and conversion applications of metal fluorides.</description>
      <author>Runlin Zhang, Zijin Xu, Zeyu Hao, Zeshuo Meng, Xiufeng Hao, Hongwei Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.630</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Design for High-Efficiency Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) Catalysts by Triggering Lattice Oxygen Oxidation in Cobalt Spinel Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14158</link>
      <description>Qingming Deng, Hui Li, Ke Pei, Lok Wing Wong, Xiaodong Zheng, Chi Shing Tsang, Honglin Chen, Wenqian Shen, Thuc Hue Ly, Jiong Zhao, Qiang Fu, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404827664

                High-efficiency catalysts with refined electronic structures are highly desirable for promoting the kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and enhancing catalyst durability. This study comprehensively explores strategies involving metal doping and oxygen vacancies for enhancing the acidic OER catalytic activity of Co</description>
      <author>Qingming Deng, Hui Li, Ke Pei, Lok Wing Wong, Xiaodong Zheng, Chi Shing Tsang, Honglin Chen, Wenqian Shen, Thuc Hue Ly, Jiong Zhao, Qiang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Induced vacancy and electronic regulation of nickle phosphides for ampere-level alkaline water/seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157952</link>
      <description>Linbo Jiang, Lintao Jiang, Xu Luo, Ruidong Li, Qingqu Zhou, Sheng Wang, Lei Chen, Shichun Mu, Chemical Engineering Journal. 502(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404838465

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linbo Jiang, Lintao Jiang, Xu Luo, Ruidong Li, Qingqu Zhou, Sheng Wang, Lei Chen, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen and boron coordinating atoms adjust single-atom catalyst anchored on divacancy defect graphene for highly efficient electrochemical oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112540</link>
      <description>Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen, Yu&#8208;Ting Chiou, Tzu-Hui Chen, Hui&#8208;Lung Chen, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404839415

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen, Yu&#8208;Ting Chiou, Tzu-Hui Chen, Hui&#8208;Lung Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple DFT-D3: Library first implementation of the D3 dispersion correction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07169</link>
      <description>Sebastian Ehlert, The Journal of Open Source Software. 9(103)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404839598

                The simulation of chemical reactions or processes provides a fundamental approach to understanding chemistry.The application of Kohn-Sham density functional theory (KSDFT) (Kohn &amp; Sham, 1965) has become an indispensable tool for computational modeling.However, semilocal KS-DFT often fails to accurately describe long-range correlation effects, such as dispersion interactions, in many exchange-correlation functionals (Stefan Grimme et al., 2016).Additive dispersion corrections, like the D3 (S.Grimme et al., 2010) or D4 (Caldeweyher et al., 2019) methods, effectively account for these effects.</description>
      <author>Sebastian Ehlert</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the influence of amino trimethylene phosphonic acid on oxygen reduction reaction on platinum catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158164</link>
      <description>Wenteng Wu, Qingxin Wang, Wen Li, Wen Liu, Di Wang, Jiashuo Fu, Jin Zhang, Yunqi Li, Haining Wang, Shanfu Lu, Yan Xiang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404843658

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenteng Wu, Qingxin Wang, Wen Li, Wen Liu, Di Wang, Jiashuo Fu, Jin Zhang, Yunqi Li, Haining Wang, Shanfu Lu, Yan Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying key intermediates for the oxygen evolution reaction on hematite using ab-initio molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54796-9</link>
      <description>Shuai Xu, Jiarui Yang, Peixian Su, Li Wang, Xiaowei Yang, Zhaohui Zhou, Yuliang Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404849149

                Hematite is a well-known catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction on photoanodes in photoelectrochemical water-splitting cells. However, the knowledge of hematite-water interfaces and water oxidation mechanisms is still lacking, which limits improvements in photoelectrochemical water-splitting performance. Herein, we use the Fe-terminated hematite (0001) surface as a model and propose a comprehensive mechanism for the oxygen evolution reaction on both non-solvated and solvated surfaces. Key reaction intermediates are identified through ab initio molecular dynamics simulations at the density functional theory level with a Hubbard U correction. Several notable intermediates are proposed, and the effects of water solvent on these intermediates and the overall reaction mechanisms are suggested. The proposed mechanisms align well with experimental observations under photoelectrochemical water oxidation conditions. Additionally, we highlight the potential role of O2 desorption in the oxygen evolution reaction on hematite, as O2 adsorption may block reaction sites and increases surface hydrophobicity, leading to an unfavorable pathway for oxygen evolution. Hematite is a promising material for photoelectrochemical water splitting, but its mechanisms are not well understood. Here, the authors report a detailed mechanism, identifying key reaction intermediates and highlighting the influence of solvent water and oxygen desorption on the reaction pathways.</description>
      <author>Shuai Xu, Jiarui Yang, Peixian Su, Li Wang, Xiaowei Yang, Zhaohui Zhou, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54796-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unifying thermochemistry concepts in computational heterogeneous catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00768a</link>
      <description>Bjarne Kreitz, Gabriel S. Gusm&#227;o, Dingqi Nai, Sushree Jagriti Sahoo, Andrew A. Peterson, David H. Bross, C. Franklin Goldsmith, Andrew J. Medford, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404855055

                Thermophysical properties of adsorbates and gas-phase species define the free energy landscape of heterogeneously catalyzed processes and are pivotal for an atomistic understanding of the catalyst performance.</description>
      <author>Bjarne Kreitz, Gabriel S. Gusm&#227;o, Dingqi Nai, Sushree Jagriti Sahoo, Andrew A. Peterson, David H. Bross, C. Franklin Goldsmith, Andrew J. Medford</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00768a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the electronic properties of TiO2 monolayers for solar driven catalysis through transition metal doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115144</link>
      <description>Kati Asikainen, M. Alatalo, Marko Huttula, S. Assa Aravindh, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404865146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kati Asikainen, M. Alatalo, Marko Huttula, S. Assa Aravindh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-function efficient hydrogen evolution reaction electrocatalyst and electrode material for supercapacitors based on ternary composite FeS2/Fe2O3/MoS2 nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109124</link>
      <description>Sumaiya Saleem, Muhammad Salman, Abdallah M. Elgorban, Hind A. AL-Shwaiman, Yihan Ling, Majid Khan, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 187(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404875915

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sumaiya Saleem, Muhammad Salman, Abdallah M. Elgorban, Hind A. AL-Shwaiman, Yihan Ling, Majid Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating catalyst and ionomer interactions to promote oxygen transport in fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124894</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Shilin Zhang, Hao Wang, E Sun, Yanrong Liu, Mingbo Wu, Di&#8208;Jia Liu, Zhongtao Li, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404876429

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Shilin Zhang, Hao Wang, E Sun, Yanrong Liu, Mingbo Wu, Di&#8208;Jia Liu, Zhongtao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive review on the boosted effects of anion vacancy in the photocatalytic and photoelectrochemical water-splitting: Focus on oxygen vacancy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101754</link>
      <description>Mahdieh Rezaei, Alireza Nezamzadeh&#8208;Ejhieh, Ahmad Reza Massah, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404877240

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mahdieh Rezaei, Alireza Nezamzadeh&#8208;Ejhieh, Ahmad Reza Massah</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances on water electrolysis based on nanoscale inorganic metal-oxides and metal-oxyhydroxides for hydrogen energy production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.348</link>
      <description>Muhammad Naeem Ayub, Umer Shahzad, Muhammad Fazle Rabbee, Mohsin Saeed, Mohammad Mizanur Rahman Khan, Mohammed M. Rahman, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 97(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404887585

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Naeem Ayub, Umer Shahzad, Muhammad Fazle Rabbee, Mohsin Saeed, Mohammad Mizanur Rahman Khan, Mohammed M. Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Study on the Electrocatalytic Performance of Defected Monolayer Vanadium Diselenide for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122669</link>
      <description>Rabia Hassan, Rehan Hassan, Fei Ma, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404893517

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rabia Hassan, Rehan Hassan, Fei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoS2 for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-7367-1_13</link>
      <description>Siby Thomas, Minu Mathew, K. P. Priyanka, Dickson D. Babu, Materials horizons. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404901508

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siby Thomas, Minu Mathew, K. P. Priyanka, Dickson D. Babu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-7367-1_13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystallization kinetics in Ge-rich Ge&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e1383" altimg="si3.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;Te alloys from large scale simulations with a machine-learned interatomic potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120608</link>
      <description>Dario Baratella, Omar Abou El Kheir, Marco Bernasconi, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404905566

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dario Baratella, Omar Abou El Kheir, Marco Bernasconi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectral operator representations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01446-9</link>
      <description>Austin Zadoks, Antimo Marrazzo, Nicola Marzari, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404906070

                Machine learning in atomistic materials science has grown to become a powerful tool, with most approaches focusing on atomic geometry, typically decomposed into local atomic environments. This approach, while well-suited for machine-learned interatomic potentials, is conceptually at odds with learning complex intrinsic properties of materials, often driven by spectral properties commonly represented in reciprocal space (e.g., band gaps or mobilities) which cannot be readily partitioned in real space. For such applications, methods that represent the electronic rather than the atomic structure could be more promising. In this work, we present a general framework focused on electronic-structure descriptors that take advantage of the natural symmetries and inherent interpretability of physical models. We apply this framework first to material similarity and then to accelerated screening, where a model trained on 217 materials correctly labels 75% of entries in the Materials Cloud 3D database, which meet common screening criteria for promising transparent-conducting materials.</description>
      <author>Austin Zadoks, Antimo Marrazzo, Nicola Marzari</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01446-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effectively Regulating Electrooxidation of Formic Acid over Bimetallic PtCo Alloys via the Integration of Theory and Experiment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06198</link>
      <description>Zhikeng Zheng, Bin Liu, Jiaxiang Qiu, Shaojun Xu, Yuchen Wang, Man Zhang, Ke Li, Zhongti Sun, Ziang Li, Yangyang Wan, C. Richard A. Catlow, Kai Yan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404831841

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhikeng Zheng, Bin Liu, Jiaxiang Qiu, Shaojun Xu, Yuchen Wang, Man Zhang, Ke Li, Zhongti Sun, Ziang Li, Yangyang Wan, C. Richard A. Catlow, Kai Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation on properties of CuI/InSe heterojunction with Z&#8211;alignment for photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.111142</link>
      <description>Ruyang Yan, Huanming Chen, Yuqi Wang, Zekun Yang, Yi Hou, Nan Zhang, Xiaobo Ma, Xueling Lin, Fengchun Pan, Hongsheng Zhao, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404871468

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruyang Yan, Huanming Chen, Yuqi Wang, Zekun Yang, Yi Hou, Nan Zhang, Xiaobo Ma, Xueling Lin, Fengchun Pan, Hongsheng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.111142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instant prediction of scientific paper cited potential based on semantic and metadata features: Taking artificial intelligence field as an example</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0312945</link>
      <description>Hou Zhu, Li Shuhuai, PLoS ONE. 19(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404914188

                With the continuous increase in the number of academic researchers, the volume of scientific papers is also increasing rapidly. The challenge of identifying papers with greater potential academic impact from this large pool has received increasing attention. The citation frequency of a paper is often used as an objective indicator to gauge the academic influence of the paper. The task of citation frequency prediction based on historical citation data in previous studies can achieve high accuracy. However, it can only be executed after the paper has been published for a period. The delay is not conducive to timely discovery of papers with high citation frequency. In this paper, we propose a novel method for predicting cited potential of a paper based on the metadata and semantic information, which can predict the cited potential of academic paper instantly once it has been published. Specifically, the semantic information, such as abstract, semantic span and semantic inflection, is extracted to enhance the ability of the prediction model based on machine learning. To prove the effectiveness and rationality of cited potential prediction model, we conduct two experiments to validate the model and find the most effective combination of input information. The empirical experiments show that the prediction accuracy of our proposed model can reach 88% for the instant prediction of citation.</description>
      <author>Hou Zhu, Li Shuhuai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0312945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Adsorption at the Electrochemical Metal/Water Interface: Au(111) vs Pt(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06384</link>
      <description>Alexandra M. Dudzinski, Elias Diesen, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa J. Bukas, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404917241

                Reaction mechanisms in heterogeneous electrocatalysis have been known to change through the local field that arises at the electrified metal/liquid interface. First-principles simulations specifically predict that such a field can significantly modify the surface binding of dipolar or polarizable intermediates along a catalytic reaction path. This dependence can then lead to a corresponding dependence upon applied potential even for so-called "chemical" reaction steps that do not involve an explicit proton-coupled electron transfer such as, e.g., O2 adsorption during the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). And yet, such effects are only now starting to be systematically explored at the atomic level. In this study, we directly compare the potential dependence of O2 adsorption as the first ORR step on Au(111) vs Pt(111). Using ab initio molecular dynamics and free energy sampling, we find that the strong dependence previously predicted at Au(111) is specifically lost at Pt(111). By decoupling the O2 potential response into contributions of different physical origin, we explain this contrast through the inherently different reactivity of the two metals. We finally discuss an indirect effect of potential through the surface coverage that can promote a dissociative-type mechanism at Pt(111) by breaking the O&#8211;O bond already during the first step of the ORR mechanism. Our results thus overall suggest a more complex mechanistic picture than hitherto anticipated; one where the local field may manifest in different, yet potentially equally important, ways over different systems.</description>
      <author>Alexandra M. Dudzinski, Elias Diesen, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa J. Bukas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Atomically Dispersed Fe&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and Sn&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Moieties for Durable and More Active Oxygen Electroreduction in Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11121</link>
      <description>Fan Xia, Bomin Li, Bowen An, Michael J. Zachman, Xiaohong Xie, Yahui Liu, Shicheng Xu, Sulay Saha, Qin Wu, Siyuan Gao, Iddrisu B. Abdul Razak, Dennis E. Brown, Vijay Ramani, Rongyue Wang, Tobin J. Marks, Yuyan Shao, Yingwen Cheng, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404920627

                One grand challenge for deploying porous carbons with embedded metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) moieties as platinum group metal (PGM)-free electrocatalysts in proton-exchange membrane fuel cells is their fast degradation and inferior activity. Here, we report the modulation of the local environment at Fe&#8211;N4 sites via the application of atomic Sn&#8211;Nx sites for simultaneously improved durability and activity. We discovered that Sn&#8211;Nx sites not only promote the formation of the more stable D2 FeN4C10 sites but also invoke a unique D3 SnNx&#8211;FeIIN4 site that is characterized by having atomically dispersed bridged Sn&#8211;Nx and Fe&#8211;N4. This new D3 site exhibits significantly improved stability against demetalation and several times higher turnover frequency for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) due to the shift of the reaction pathway from a single-site associative mechanism to a dual-site dissociative mechanism with the adjacent Sn site facilitating a lower overpotential cleavage of the O&#8211;O bond. This mechanism bypasses the formation of the otherwise inevitable intermediate that is responsible for demetalation, where two hydroxyl intermediates bind to one Fe site. As a result, a mesoporous Fe/Sn-PNC catalyst exhibits a positively shifted ORR half-wave potential and more than 50% lower peroxide formation. This, in combination with the stable D3 site and enriched D2 Fe sites, significantly enhanced the catalyst's durability as demonstrated in membrane electrode assemblies using complementary accelerated durability testing protocols.</description>
      <author>Fan Xia, Bomin Li, Bowen An, Michael J. Zachman, Xiaohong Xie, Yahui Liu, Shicheng Xu, Sulay Saha, Qin Wu, Siyuan Gao, Iddrisu B. Abdul Razak, Dennis E. Brown, Vijay Ramani, Rongyue Wang, Tobin J. Marks, Yuyan Shao, Yingwen Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting tripeptide in Pd/C for boosting hydrogen production from formic acid dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01111b</link>
      <description>Yan Gu, Hongli Wang, Yaohao Zhang, Yang Lu, Xiaoshan Liu, Xuesong Li, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404922544

                Ultrafine Pd nanoparticles with lattice strain induced by the incorporation of tripeptide anchored on XC-72R carbon (Pd/C-TPT) show excellent catalytic activity for formic acid dehydrogenation reaction with a TOF of 2102 h &#8722;1 without any additives.</description>
      <author>Yan Gu, Hongli Wang, Yaohao Zhang, Yang Lu, Xiaoshan Liu, Xuesong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01111b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disrupted Spin Degeneracy Promoted C&#8801;C Triple Bond Activation for Efficient Electrochemical Acetylene Semihydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06191</link>
      <description>Menglei Yuan, Hongyu Jiang, Ruyi Jiang, Zhao Wang, Zhihao Zhao, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Jian Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404924221

                Disrupting the spin degeneracy of the electrocatalyst and further manipulating the related orbital electron arrangement are highly desirable for activating acetylene molecules. Herein, a squarate cobalt-based metal&#8211;organic framework (Co-MOF) ([Co3(C4O4)2(OH)2]&#183;3H2O) is post-treated to accelerate the evolution from CoO6 octahedron to CoO5 pentahedron and further utilized for the electrochemical acetylene semihydrogenation reaction. Comprehensive analyses corroborate that the disrupted spin degeneracy of active sites originated from the breakage of the Co&#8211;O bond, which promotes the cleavage of the orbital energy level and the rearrangement of the d-orbital electron. The newly emerged half-occupied dx2&#8211;y2 orbitals and empty dz2 orbitals in CoO5 pentahedron concerted interplay with the bonding and antibonding orbitals of acetylene, which reduces the adsorption energy of acetylene and facilitates the activation of the inert C&#8801;C triple bond. Thus, the defective Co-MOF exhibits the superior ethylene Faradaic efficiency of 96% and partial current density of 128 mA cm&#8211;2 at &#8722;1.0 V vs RHE compared to that of pristine Co-MOF (FEC2H4: 60%; JC2H4: 66 mA cm&#8211;2). This work delivers inspiration for spin-state regulation of active sites and sparks renewed interest in designing highly efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Menglei Yuan, Hongyu Jiang, Ruyi Jiang, Zhao Wang, Zhihao Zhao, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Strain Modulation of Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Monolayer Binary Alloy Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5041641</link>
      <description>Mailde S. Oz&#243;rio, Marcus F. Nygaard, Jan Rossmeisl, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404938815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mailde S. Oz&#243;rio, Marcus F. Nygaard, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5041641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Chemistry of Bimetallic Surfaces - Evolution of an Atomic-scale Picture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122677</link>
      <description>R. J&#252;rgen Behm, Axel Gro&#223;, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404948122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. J&#252;rgen Behm, Axel Gro&#223;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-induced interface engineering of NiCu/Ni3N heterostructures for enhanced alkaline hydrogen oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60142-7</link>
      <description>Jinchi Li, Wanhai Zhou, Shuqi Yu, Qing Chen, Jian He, Liang Zeng, Yao Wang, Yungui Chen, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 67(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404950295

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinchi Li, Wanhai Zhou, Shuqi Yu, Qing Chen, Jian He, Liang Zeng, Yao Wang, Yungui Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60142-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction mechanism on platinum dioxide surfaces based on density functional theory calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115020</link>
      <description>Xiru Cao, Zhibin Tan, Ji Chen, Changwei Pan, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404958222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiru Cao, Zhibin Tan, Ji Chen, Changwei Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping and characterization of the surface structure and electronic properties of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e678" altimg="si103.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;&#946;&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;-Ag&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e683" altimg="si104.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;MoO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e691" &#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105530</link>
      <description>Thiago T. Dorini, Felipe Lipsky, Andr&#233; Rodrigues, Ju&#225;n Andr&#233;s, E. Longo, Miguel A. San&#8208;Miguel, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404958629

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thiago T. Dorini, Felipe Lipsky, Andr&#233; Rodrigues, Ju&#225;n Andr&#233;s, E. Longo, Miguel A. San&#8208;Miguel</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105530</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-free nitrogen-doped carbon-based electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction in microbial fuel cells: Advances, challenges, and future directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110537</link>
      <description>Seyed Masoud Parsa, Zhijie Chen, Siran Feng, Yuanying Yang, Li Luo, Huu Hao Ngo, Wei Wei, Bing&#8208;Jie Ni, Wenshan Guo, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404958697

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seyed Masoud Parsa, Zhijie Chen, Siran Feng, Yuanying Yang, Li Luo, Huu Hao Ngo, Wei Wei, Bing&#8208;Jie Ni, Wenshan Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and Applications of Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage in Civil Engineering: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236046</link>
      <description>D. S. Vijayan, Selvakumar Gopalaswamy, Arvindan Sivasuriyan, Eugeniusz Koda, Wiktor Sitek, Magdalena Daria Vaverkov&#225;, Anna Podlasek, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404960467

                This paper thoroughly examines the latest developments and diverse applications of Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage (CCUS) in civil engineering. It provides a critical analysis of the technology&#8217;s potential to mitigate the effects of climate change. Initially, a comprehensive outline of CCUS technologies is presented, emphasising their vital function in carbon dioxide (CO2) emission capture, conversion, and sequestration. Subsequent sections provide an in-depth analysis of carbon capture technologies, utilisation processes, and storage solutions. These serve as the foundation for an architectural framework that facilitates the design and integration of efficient systems. Significant attention is given to the inventive application of CCUS in the building and construction industry. Notable examples of such applications include using carbon (C) in cement and promoting sustainable cement production. Economic analyses and financing mechanisms are reviewed to assess the commercial feasibility and scalability of CCUS projects. In addition, this review examines the technological advances and innovations that have occurred, providing insight into the potential future course of CCUS progress. A comprehensive analysis of the environmental and regulatory environments is conducted to evaluate the feasibility and compliance with the policies of CCUS technology deployment. Case studies from the real world are provided to illustrate effectiveness and practical applications. It concludes by emphasising the importance of continued research, policy support, and innovation in developing CCUS technologies as a fundamental component of sustainable civil engineering practices. A tenacious stride toward carbon neutrality is underscored.</description>
      <author>D. S. Vijayan, Selvakumar Gopalaswamy, Arvindan Sivasuriyan, Eugeniusz Koda, Wiktor Sitek, Magdalena Daria Vaverkov&#225;, Anna Podlasek</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of ligand chain length on the HER performance of atomically precise Pt&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;(SR)&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03316g</link>
      <description>Lipipuspa Sahoo, Supriti Dutta, Aarti Devi, Rashi, Swapan K. Pati, Amitava Patra, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404962276

                This study investigates the impact of ligand chain length on the electrocatalytic HER performance of atomically precise Pt 6 (thiolate ligand, SR) 12 nanoclusters. Analysis reveals that a shorter ligand chain enhances the electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Lipipuspa Sahoo, Supriti Dutta, Aarti Devi, Rashi, Swapan K. Pati, Amitava Patra</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03316g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Evolution of Stapes Controls the Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Bimetallic Cu&#8208;doped Gold Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408531</link>
      <description>Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez&#8208;Al&#233;, Jiajun Hu, Josep Albero, Laura Simonelli, Carlo Marini, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Noelia Barrab&#233;s, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Sara Goberna&#8208;Ferr&#243;n, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404977497

                Abstract Ligand protected gold nanoclusters have been proposed for electrochemical CO 2 reduction (eCO 2 R) as an alternative to polycrystalline catalysts, showing higher selectivity control due to the tailored composition and precise microenvironment. Here, two gold cluster families are studied with different staple motifs (Au 25 (SR) 18 and Au 144 (SR) 60 , where SR = thiolate) doped with Ag or Cu to understand the interplay between the composition and the performance of these catalysts. Detailed cluster characterization and Density Functional Theory simulations demonstrate that the dynamic aspects involving ligand removal are crucial to unraveling the role of the dopant, the cluster curvature, and the staple structure. The best activity performance toward CO is obtained for Cu&#8208;doped Au 144 (SR) 60 at U = &#8211;0.8 V RHE as ligands are only partially depleted and the staple can bend to stabilize *CO intermediate, while Cu&#8208;containing Au 25 (SR) 18 can produce formate but shows worse CO selectivity. This study points toward the importance of ligand stability during eCO 2 R on bimetallic gold nanoclusters, paving the way for improving the design and operation of this family of catalysts.</description>
      <author>Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez&#8208;Al&#233;, Jiajun Hu, Josep Albero, Laura Simonelli, Carlo Marini, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Noelia Barrab&#233;s, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Sara Goberna&#8208;Ferr&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Intrinsic Effects of Lattice Strain on the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction via Electric-Field-Induced Strain in FePt Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16120</link>
      <description>Hong Hong, Dongxue Liu, Bo Yang, Qingqi Cao, Chaoran Liu, Liqian Wu, Dunhui Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404992503

                Strain engineering has the potential to modify the adsorption process and enhance the electrocatalytic activity, especially in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, the introduction of lattice strain in electrocatalysts is often accompanied by a change in chemical composition, surface morphology, or phase structure to a certain extent, impeding the investigation of the intrinsic strain effect on HER. In this work, the FePt film was deposited on a Pb(Mg</description>
      <author>Hong Hong, Dongxue Liu, Bo Yang, Qingqi Cao, Chaoran Liu, Liqian Wu, Dunhui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic N2 Reduction Driven by Mo-Based Double-Atom Catalysts Anchored on Graphdiyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120879</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Chi, Yaqi Cang, Jianhua Wang, Qing Li, Xing Fan, Haiping Lin, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404993416

                An electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (eNRR) presents an appealing strategy for ammonia (NH3) production at ambient conditions. Through systematic density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the eNRR performance of 23 double-atom catalysts has been investigated. These catalysts are composed of a Mo atom and a transition metal atom anchored on the graphdiyne (GDY), and they are named MoM-GDYs. Among the 23 MoM-GDYs studied, 14 MoM-GDYs highlighted catalytic selectivity by inhibiting a competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and demonstrated commendable eNRR catalytic performance. MoRu-GDY, MoMo-GDY, MoFe-GDY and MoY-GDY exhibited excellent eNRR catalytic activity with limiting potentials of &#8722;0.05 V, &#8722;0.13 V, &#8722;0.21 V and &#8722;0.24 V, respectively. These 14 catalysts favor N2 adsorption compared to H and exhibit less negative UL than the &#8722;0.98 V benchmark of the stepped Ru(0001) surface. Among them, MoRu-GDY has the best catalytic activity with an UL of &#8722;0.05 V. The excellent catalytic performance originates from the synergistic effect of the dual catalytic sites, where the alternation of the consecutive and enzymatic paths effectively reduces the limiting potentials. In addition, the catalytic activity can be evaluated using &#916;G*NH3 &#8722; &#916;G*NH2 as a theoretical descriptor, while UL and the &#916;G*NH3 &#8722; &#916;G*NH2 fit coefficient R2 reached 0.99. These findings not only contribute to the development of dual-atom electrocatalysts for eNRR but also offer a valuable pathway for identifying new eNRR catalysts with high activity and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Chi, Yaqi Cang, Jianhua Wang, Qing Li, Xing Fan, Haiping Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using a Single-Atom FeN4 Catalyst on Defective Graphene for the Efficient Reduction of NO to Alanine: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120876</link>
      <description>Yu Tian, Xiaoxi Yuan, Zexuan Guo, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Tingting Zhao, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404994156

                The use of a single-atom FeN4 catalyst on defective graphene (Fe-NC) has recently emerged as an effective method for the synthesis of amino acids. Herein, we investigated the mechanism of alanine formation on FeN4-doped graphene using comprehensive density functional theory (DFT) computations. The alanine formation reaction begins with the activation of NO molecules on the surface, followed by their reaction with hydrogen atoms provided in the system. The computational results show that NO molecules can be effectively activated on Fe-NC, facilitating the subsequent alanine formation at a relatively lower potential. The potential-limiting step in alanine production involves either the formation of HNO* or HNOH* intermediates on Fe-NG, as the free energy changes (&#916;G) in these two elementary steps are nearly equivalent. Notably, the formation of HNO* exhibits a higher activation energy (Ea) compared to HNOH* formation. This study provides valuable insights into the C&#8211;N coupling reaction and the mechanism of amino acid synthesis on single-atom catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yu Tian, Xiaoxi Yuan, Zexuan Guo, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Tingting Zhao, Zhong&#8208;Min Su</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian optimization of atomic structures with prior probabilities from universal interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.123802</link>
      <description>Peder Lyngby, Casper Larsen, Karsten W. Jacobsen, Physical Review Materials. 8(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404994554

                The optimization of atomic structures plays a pivotal role in understanding and designing materials with desired properties. However, conventional computational methods often struggle with the formidable task of navigating the vast potential energy surface, especially in high-dimensional spaces with numerous local minima. Recent advancements in machine learning-driven surrogate models offer a promising avenue for alleviating this computational burden. In this study, we propose anapproach that combines the strengths of universal machine learning potentials with a Bayesian approach using Gaussian processes. By using the machine learning potentials as priors for the Gaussian process, the Gaussian process has to learn only the difference between the machine learning potential and the target energy surface calculated for example by density functional theory. This turns out to improve the speed by which the global optimal structure is identified across diverse systems for a well-behaved machine learning potential. The approach is tested on periodic bulk materials, surface structures, and a cluster.</description>
      <author>Peder Lyngby, Casper Larsen, Karsten W. Jacobsen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.123802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase transitions of correlated systems from graph neural networks with quantum embedding techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.245111</link>
      <description>Rishi Rao, Li Zhu, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404994847

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rishi Rao, Li Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.245111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>relentless: Transparent, reproducible molecular dynamics simulations for optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0233683</link>
      <description>Adithya N Sreenivasan, C. Levi Petix, Zachary M. Sherman, Michael P. Howard, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405003135

                relentless is an open-source Python package that enables the optimization of objective functions computed using molecular dynamics simulations. It has a high-level, extensible interface for model parameterization; setting up, running, and analyzing simulations natively in established software packages; and gradient-based optimization. We describe the design and implementation of relentless in the context of relative entropy minimization, and we demonstrate its abilities to design pairwise interactions between particles that form targeted structures. relentless aims to streamline the development of computational materials design methodologies and promote the transparency and reproducibility of complex workflows integrating molecular dynamics simulations.</description>
      <author>Adithya N Sreenivasan, C. Levi Petix, Zachary M. Sherman, Michael P. Howard</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0233683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of compositional tuning on Ni-B electrocatalyst for efficient hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118847</link>
      <description>Susmita S. Patil, Aasiya S. Jamadar, Rohit B. Sutar, Reshma V. Khandeker, Tukaram D. Dongale, Jyotiprakash B. Yadav, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405009319

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Susmita S. Patil, Aasiya S. Jamadar, Rohit B. Sutar, Reshma V. Khandeker, Tukaram D. Dongale, Jyotiprakash B. Yadav</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118847</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive insight into the interfacial adsorption mechanism of pyridine derivatives by molecular dynamics simulations, GFN-xTB and first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105567</link>
      <description>Zhaojing Jiang, Jiashun Duan, Wei Xiong, Chaofang Dong, H.F. Liu, G.A. Zhang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405012661

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaojing Jiang, Jiashun Duan, Wei Xiong, Chaofang Dong, H.F. Liu, G.A. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pH Dependence of Noble Metals Dissolution: Iridium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145450</link>
      <description>Matej Zlatar, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Cornelius Simon, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Kevin Stojanovski, Serhiy Cherevko, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405013272

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matej Zlatar, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Cornelius Simon, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Kevin Stojanovski, Serhiy Cherevko</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black-box optimization technique for investigation of surface phase diagram</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229856</link>
      <description>Makoto Urushihara, Kenji Yamaguchi, Ryo Tamura, AIP Advances. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405016963

                Surface phase diagrams are useful in material design for understanding catalytic reactions and deposition processes and are usually obtained by numerical calculations. However, a large number of calculations are required, and a strategy to reduce the computation time is necessary. In this study, we proposed a black-box optimization strategy to investigate the surface phase diagram with the smallest possible number of calculations. Our method was tested to examine the phase diagram in which two types of adsorbates, i.e., oxygen and carbon monoxide, were adsorbed onto a palladium surface. In comparison with a random calculation without using machine learning, we confirmed that the proposed method obtained a surface phase diagram with a small number of calculations. In conclusion, our strategy is a general-purpose method that can contribute to the rapid study of various types of surface phase diagrams.</description>
      <author>Makoto Urushihara, Kenji Yamaguchi, Ryo Tamura</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling activity-stability paradox of reconstructed NiIrOx electrocatalysts by bridged W-O moiety</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54987-4</link>
      <description>Muhammad Imran Abdullah, Fang Yu-sheng, Xiaobing Wu, Meiqi Hu, Jing Shao, Youkun Tao, Haijiang Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405022664

                One challenge remaining in the development of Ir-based electrocatalyst is the activity-stability paradox during acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), especially for the surface reconstructed IrOx catalyst with high efficiency. To address this, a phase selective Ir-based electrocatalyst is constructed by forming bridged W-O moiety in NiIrOx electrocatalyst. Through an electrochemical dealloying process, an nano-porous structure with surface-hydroxylated rutile NiWIrOx electrocatalyst is engineered via Ni as a sacrificial element. Despite low Ir content, NiWIrOx demonstrates a minimal overpotential of 180 mV for the OER at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2. It maintains a stable 300 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 current density during an approximately 300 h OER at 1.8 VRHE and shows a stability number of 3.9 &#215; 105 noxygen &#183; nIr&#8722;1. The resulting W &#8211; O&#8211;Ir bridging motif proves pivotal for enhancing the efficacy of OER catalysis by facilitating deprotonation of OER intermediates and promoting a thermodynamically favorable dual-site adsorbent evolution mechanism. Besides, the phase selective insertion of W-O in NiIrOx enabling charge balance through the W-O-Ir bridging motif, effectively counteracting lattice oxygen loss by regulating Ir-O co-valency. One challenge remaining in the electrocatalysts for acidic water electrolysis is the activity-stability paradox. Here, the authors report a facile approach to tackle the challenge by introducing a bridged W-O moiety in NiIrOx electrocatalyst, enhancing the efficacy and stability simultaneously.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Imran Abdullah, Fang Yu-sheng, Xiaobing Wu, Meiqi Hu, Jing Shao, Youkun Tao, Haijiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54987-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Properties optimisation of nanostructures via machine learning: Progress and perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enganabound.2024.106063</link>
      <description>Nurul Akmal Che Lah, Engineering Analysis with Boundary Elements. 171(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405023212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nurul Akmal Che Lah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enganabound.2024.106063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a unified pH-performance picture of active sites in nitrogen-doped carbon materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124908</link>
      <description>Peiyao Bai, Lang Xu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405024756

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peiyao Bai, Lang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capturing Surface Coverage Effects in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05086</link>
      <description>Alyssa J. R. Hensley, Neeru Chaudhary, Naseeha Cardwell, Isaac G. Onyango, Yong Wang, Di Wu, Jean&#8208;Sabin McEwen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404960710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alyssa J. R. Hensley, Neeru Chaudhary, Naseeha Cardwell, Isaac G. Onyango, Yong Wang, Di Wu, Jean&#8208;Sabin McEwen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Screening Approach for Catalytic Applications through Regulation of Adsorption Energies via Work Function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03385</link>
      <description>Xuhong Zhao, Jianwei Wang, Xiaobin Niu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404913328

                Adsorption energy is critical in catalysis, energy storage, and sensing. Optimal adsorption energy on a catalytic substrate is essential as extreme adsorption energy can reduce the reaction efficiency. Building on our previous research on the influence of work function on adsorption energy (Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2024, 26, 3525&#8211;3530), we examined a range of two-dimensional semiconductor materials, including black phosphorene, boron nitride, and MoS2, as supporting substrates for the construction of silicene&#8211;semiconductor heterojunctions. Furthermore, we analyzed how work function changes impact adsorption energy during O2 adsorption and developed a theoretical model to explain this relationship. The model was validated by demonstrating the regulation of the catalytic reaction barrier in the oxygen reduction reaction and was applied to N2 adsorption via high-throughput screening. Our findings demonstrate that the work function modulates the adsorption energy in van der Waals heterojunctions, enhancing catalytic efficiency. This approach aligns with the Sabatier principle and offers a pathway for optimizing catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xuhong Zhao, Jianwei Wang, Xiaobin Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data efficiency of classification strategies for chemical and materials design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00298a</link>
      <description>Quinn Gallagher, Michael Webb, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404961437

                We benchmark the performance of space-filling and active learning algorithms on classification problems in materials science, revealing trends in optimally data-efficient algorithms.</description>
      <author>Quinn Gallagher, Michael Webb</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00298a</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
